<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Cardiovasc Diabetol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Cardiovasc Diabetol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">107</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">cardiab</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Cardiovascular Diabetology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1475-2840</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13045045</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13045045.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13045045</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13045045</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41877141</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-026-03139-7</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3139</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Dynamic association between triglyceride-glucose-body mass index and hospital mortality in critically ill patients with heart failure: a multicenter retrospective cohort study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names initials="S">Shuang</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cai</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yuzhou</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname><given-names initials="C">Chenming</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names initials="T">Tong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yujian</given-names></name><address><email>zengyujian@126.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02g01ht84</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.414902.a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1771 3912</institution-id><institution>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, </institution><institution>The First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Kunming, 650032 China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02g01ht84</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.414902.a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1771 3912</institution-id><institution>Department of Ultrasound, </institution><institution>The First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Kunming, 650032 China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>24</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>25</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">504413</issue-id><elocation-id>108</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>2</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>24</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>03</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-03 10:25:15.667"><day>03</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12933_2026_Article_3139.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">The triglyceride-glucose-body mass index (TYG-BMI) is a surrogate marker of insulin resistance associated with cardiovascular outcomes in stable populations. However, its physiological meaning in critically ill patients—where glucose and triglyceride levels are influenced by acute stress, inflammation, and treatment—remains uncertain, and the dynamic relationship between TYG-BMI and mortality in critically ill heart failure (HF) patients has not been investigated.</p></sec><sec><title>Objectives</title><p id="Par2">To examine the association between TYG-BMI intensity, exposure duration, and hospital mortality in critically ill HF patients, and to evaluate the robustness of these associations through comprehensive sensitivity analyses.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par3">This multicenter retrospective study analyzed data from MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU databases. Adult HF patients with daily TYG-BMI measurements during the 7 day observation period (day 0 through day 7) were included. Restricted cubic spline regression characterized the baseline dose–response relationship. Generalized additive models with tensor product smooth functions examined the three-dimensional TYG-BMI–time–mortality association. Weighted linear regression quantified temporal trends. Multiple sensitivity analyses addressed selection bias, time-varying confounding, treatment effect modification, and temporal heterogeneity.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par4">Among 5133 patients (pooled mortality: 27.9%), restricted cubic spline analysis confirmed a non-linear U-shaped dose–response relationship in MIMIC-IV (non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), with consistent directional patterns across MIMIC-III and eICU. Generalized additive models demonstrated a reproducible U-shaped association across all three databases. The optimal TYG-BMI range was 250–275 (OR = 0.76, 95% CI 0.68–0.85, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001 in MIMIC-IV), with each additional day within this range reducing mortality risk by 0.4% (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.01). TYG-BMI &gt; 425 was associated with progressively increased mortality (OR = 1.61, 95% CI 1.35–1.93 for the 425–450 range), with time-dependent risk amplification reaching 2.5% per day at the highest stratum. Combining TYG-BMI with the SOFA score significantly improved discriminative performance beyond SOFA alone (AUC: 0.780 versus 0.720, DeLong <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001). All sensitivity analyses yielded consistent findings.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par5">TYG-BMI demonstrates a reproducible, U-shaped association with hospital mortality in critically ill HF patients. Both intensity and exposure duration contribute to risk stratification, though prospective validation is warranted given the observational design and uncertain physiological specificity of TYG-BMI in the ICU setting.</p></sec><sec><title>Graphical abstract</title><p id="Par6">
<graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="anchor" id="d33e220" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Figa_HTML.jpg"/>
</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12933-026-03139-7.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Heart failure</kwd><kwd>Triglyceride-glucose-body mass index</kwd><kwd>Insulin resistance</kwd><kwd>Hospital mortality</kwd><kwd>Critical care</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Research insights</title><p id="Par39">
<bold>What is currently known about this topic?</bold>
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par40">TYG-BMI is a surrogate marker of insulin resistance associated with cardiovascular outcomes in stable populations.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par41">Longitudinal TyG trajectories carry prognostic value beyond single measurements in heart failure.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par42">The physiological meaning and prognostic utility of TYG-BMI in critically ill patients remain uncertain.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p id="Par43">
<bold>What is the key research question?</bold>
</p><p id="Par44">
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par45">Does TYG-BMI demonstrate a time-dependent, non-linear association with hospital mortality in critically ill heart failure patients?.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p id="Par46">
<bold>What is new?</bold>
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par47">TYG-BMI exhibits a reproducible U-shaped association with hospital mortality across three independent critical care databases.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par48">Sustained exposure outside the optimal range (250–275) is associated with progressively amplified mortality risk over time.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par49">Adding TYG-BMI to the SOFA score significantly improves mortality prediction (AUC: 0.780 versus 0.720, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001).</p></list-item></list>
</p><p id="Par50">
<bold>How might this study influence clinical practice?</bold>
</p><p id="Par51">
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par52">TYG-BMI, derived from routinely available ICU variables, may serve as a complementary metabolic marker for early risk stratification in critically ill heart failure.</p></list-item></list>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par53">Heart failure (HF) remains a major cause of acute decompensation requiring intensive care, and short-term mortality among critically ill HF patients remains substantial despite advances in hemodynamic monitoring and organ support. Early risk stratification is therefore central to clinical decision-making in the ICU, yet conventional prognostic approaches are often anchored to static severity/organ dysfunction scores derived from admission or the worst values within the first 24 h (e.g., APACHE II, SAPS II, and SOFA), which may not fully capture the rapidly evolving metabolic and inflammatory milieu during critical illness <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">[1</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3]</xref>. Conversely, metabolic indices developed in stable populations may carry different physiological meaning when transposed to the ICU, where acute stress, inflammation, and therapeutic interventions profoundly alter glucose and lipid metabolism.</p><p id="Par54">Insulin resistance (IR) has emerged as a key cardiometabolic phenotype implicated in HF pathophysiology and prognosis, extending beyond patients with overt diabetes. Large-scale evidence syntheses have highlighted the broad diagnostic and prognostic relevance of IR surrogates across cardiovascular outcomes, including HF and mortality, supporting their utility as pragmatic biomarkers in routine care <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">[4]</xref>. In HF—particularly HF with preserved ejection fraction (HFpEF), where metabolic comorbidity is pervasive—IR-related indices have been increasingly recognized as potentially informative for long-term outcomes and risk stratification <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">[5]</xref>.</p><p id="Par55">Because direct assessment of IR is not feasible in most clinical settings, indices derived from triglycerides, glucose, and anthropometrics have attracted sustained interest. Among these, the triglyceride–glucose (TyG) index and its derivatives (including TyG-BMI) are widely used as surrogate markers of IR and have been linked to adverse cardiovascular outcomes across diverse populations <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">[4]</xref>. Importantly, an emerging theme in Cardiovascular Diabetology is that metabolic risk captured by TyG-related indices is not static: longitudinal changes and trajectory phenotypes may convey incremental prognostic information beyond baseline values. In a competing-risk analysis, trajectories of TyG index changes were associated with both all-cause and cardiovascular mortality, with an “increasing” TyG-change group showing higher mortality risk compared with a stable trajectory <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">[6]</xref>. Similarly, dynamic changes in the TyG index after acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction were associated with prognosis, reinforcing the clinical value of time-resolved metabolic assessment rather than single-timepoint measurement <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">[7]</xref>. In chronic HF populations, TyG trajectory patterns have also been associated with worsening HF and overall mortality, further supporting the relevance of metabolic dynamics in HF risk profiling <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">[8]</xref>.</p><p id="Par56">Despite these advances, evidence is limited regarding whether early ICU metabolic evolution—particularly daily fluctuations of IR surrogates—relates to short-term outcomes in critically ill patients with HF. Furthermore, recent studies emphasize that anthropometric and metabolic indices in HF should be interpreted alongside nutritional status, as the obesity paradox and the prognostic value of BMI-incorporating indices may vary substantially depending on nutritional risk and inflammatory burden <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">[9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10]</xref>. This knowledge gap is clinically important because ICU HF is characterized by profound stress responses, variable nutritional strategies, vasoactive therapies, and rapidly changing organ function, all of which can alter glucose–lipid homeostasis over days. Moreover, most existing studies focus on baseline TyG (or related indices) in stable or ward-based cohorts, whereas ICU decision-making may benefit from understanding time-varying, potentially non-linear associations between metabolic indices and mortality during the initial high-risk period.</p><p id="Par57">To address this gap, we conducted a multicohort retrospective study leveraging three large critical care databases: MIMIC-III <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">[11]</xref>, MIMIC-IV <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">[12]</xref>, and the eICU Collaborative Research Database <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">[13]</xref>. We aimed to characterize the association between daily TyG-BMI values during the first ICU week and in-hospital mortality among ICU patients with HF, with particular focus on whether the relationship changes over time and exhibits non-linear patterns. We hypothesized that TyG-BMI would demonstrate a time-dependent association with in-hospital mortality and that modeling short-term metabolic dynamics could provide clinically relevant insight for early risk stratification in critically ill HF.</p></sec><sec id="Sec3"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec id="Sec4"><title>Study design and data sources</title><p id="Par58">This multicenter retrospective cohort study utilized three large-scale critical care databases to investigate the dynamic association between the triglyceride-glucose-body mass index (TYG-BMI) and hospital mortality in patients with heart failure. Data were extracted from the Medical Information Mart for Intensive Care III CareVue subset version 1.4 (MIMIC-III CareVue, released September 2022; <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://physionet.org/content/mimic3-carevue/1.4/">https://physionet.org/content/mimic3-carevue/1.4/</ext-link>), which contains clinical information recorded using the CareVue system for patients admitted between 2001 and 2008. The Medical Information Mart for Intensive Care IV version 3.1 (MIMIC-IV v3.1, released October 11, 2024; <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://physionet.org/content/mimiciv/3.1/">https://physionet.org/content/mimiciv/3.1/</ext-link>) was employed, comprising electronic health records of over 360,000 patients at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center from 2008 to 2022. The eICU Collaborative Research Database version 2.0 (eICU v2.0, released April 2019; <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://physionet.org/content/eicu-crd/2.0/">https://physionet.org/content/eicu-crd/2.0/</ext-link>) provided multicenter data from more than 200 intensive care units across the United States during 2014–2015. Access to these databases was approved by the respective institutional review boards, with a waiver of informed consent granted due to the retrospective and deidentified nature of the data. This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and reported following the Strengthening of the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE).</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Study population</title><p id="Par59">Patients diagnosed with heart failure were identified using International Classification of Diseases codes, specifically ICD-9 codes 428.x and ICD-10 codes within the I50 series. The sole inclusion criterion was a diagnosis of heart failure based on ICD-9 codes 428.x or ICD-10 codes within the I50 series. The exclusion criteria were: (1) age 18 years or younger; (2) non-first hospital admission or non-first ICU admission; (3) ICU length of stay less than 7 days; and (4) incomplete triglyceride, glucose, or body mass index measurements on any day from day 0 through day 7 following ICU admission.. The observation window spanned 8 calendar days (day 0 through day 7), hereafter referred to as the "7-day observation period" for brevity. The minimum ICU stay requirement was established to ensure sufficient longitudinal data points for examining the temporal dynamics of TYG-BMI in relation to clinical outcomes. Patients with any missing daily TYG-BMI data during this observation window were excluded. The patient selection process and final cohort sizes for each database are presented in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>.</p><p id="Par60">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram of patient selection from three critical care databases. The diagram illustrates the sequential application of inclusion and exclusion criteria, including identification of heart failure diagnoses, age restriction, selection of first admissions, ICU length of stay requirement, and completeness of TYG-BMI data, with final sample sizes for MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU databases</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e550" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Data extraction and variable definitions</title><p id="Par61">For eligible patients, we extracted daily data throughout the 7-day observation period (day 0 through day 7). Daily values for vital signs, including heart rate, systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood pressure, and peripheral oxygen saturation, were calculated as the mean of all measurements within each 24 h period. Laboratory parameters encompassed white blood cell count, hematocrit, platelet count, creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, sodium, potassium, chloride, and calcium. Baseline characteristics collected at ICU admission included demographic information (age, sex, body mass index), disease severity scores (Simplified Acute Physiology Score II [SAPS II], Oxford Acute Severity of Illness Score [OASIS], Sequential Organ Failure Assessment [SOFA] score, Charlson Comorbidity Index), therapeutic interventions within the first 24 h (mechanical ventilation, renal replacement therapy), medication usage (sedatives, vasopressors, insulin, albumin), daily insulin administration status, and clinical outcomes (hospital mortality, hospital length of stay).</p><p id="Par62">The TYG-BMI was calculated using the formula: TYG-BMI = ln[triglycerides (mg/dL) × glucose (mg/dL) / 2] × BMI (kg/m<sup>2</sup>). When multiple measurements of triglycerides or glucose were obtained within a single calendar day, the arithmetic mean of all available values was used to calculate the daily TYG-BMI. Glucose values were derived from random blood glucose measurements routinely obtained during ICU care rather than fasting specimens, given the clinical impracticality of obtaining fasting samples in critically ill patients.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par63">Baseline characteristics were summarized by databases using standardized mean differences to assess cross-database heterogeneity. Continuous variables were expressed as median with interquartile range following normality assessment via the Shapiro–Wilk test. Categorical variables were presented as frequencies with percentages. Temporal trends in the TYG-BMI across the 7-day observation period were visualized using line plots with 95% confidence intervals.</p><p id="Par64">To characterize the dose–response relationship between baseline TYG-BMI and hospital mortality, restricted cubic spline (RCS) regression was performed using day 0 TYG-BMI values. Two sequential models were constructed: Model 1, adjusted for age and sex; and Model 2 (fully adjusted), additionally adjusted for SOFA score, Charlson Comorbidity Index, insulin use, vasopressor use, mechanical ventilation, albumin, creatinine, and white blood cell count. The reference value was set at the median TYG-BMI of each database. The optimal number of knots was selected from 3 to 7 based on the Akaike Information Criterion. This analysis was conducted separately in each database.</p><p id="Par65">To investigate the three-dimensional relationship among TYG-BMI intensity, time, and mortality, we employed generalized additive models (GAM) with a logistic link function. The interaction between TYG-BMI and time was modeled using tensor product smooth functions, specified as te(TYG-BMI, day), which allows the effect of TYG-BMI on mortality to vary non-linearly across different time points. The model was adjusted for age, sex, SOFA score, SAPS II, and Charlson Comorbidity Index. Model diagnostics were performed, including residual analysis and assessment of potential overfitting through examination of effective degrees of freedom. The statistical significance of the TYG-BMI-time interaction was evaluated using F-statistics and corresponding p-values from the smooth term summary, with model fit assessed using Akaike Information Criterion values.</p><p id="Par66">Predicted mortality probabilities and odds ratios were generated across a grid of TYG-BMI values and time points. Absolute risk was visualized through three-dimensional surface plots depicting the relationship among TYG-BMI intensity, time since ICU admission, and predicted hospital mortality. Relative risk was presented as odds ratio deviation heatmaps, with contour lines indicating an odds ratio equal to unity. The TYG-BMI was stratified into intervals of 25 units, and odds ratios with 95% confidence intervals were calculated for each stratum at each time point. To account for multiple comparisons across TYG-BMI strata and time points, the Benjamini–Hochberg false discovery rate (FDR) correction was applied, with adjusted p-values &lt; 0.05 considered statistically significant.</p><p id="Par67">To quantify temporal trends within TYG-BMI strata, weighted linear regression analysis was performed on log-transformed odds ratios across time points, with weights inversely proportional to the variance of log-odds ratio estimates. The slope coefficient represented the daily change in the odds ratio, which was exponentiated to obtain the multiplicative change in odds ratio per day. Temporal trends were classified as significantly increasing, significantly decreasing, or stable based on statistical significance at the α = 0.05 level.</p><p id="Par68">Several sensitivity analyses were conducted to evaluate the robustness of the primary findings. First, to address the potential selection bias introduced by requiring complete daily TYG-BMI data over the full observation window, we repeated the GAM analysis using a relaxed inclusion criterion that allowed a missing rate of less than 30% for daily TYG-BMI values, with multiple imputation applied to missing observations. Second, to assess whether the observed associations were consistent in patients with shorter ICU stays, the GAM analysis was restricted to the first 3 days of ICU admission (day 0 through day 3), thereby including a broader patient population without the requirement for a 7-day ICU stay. Third, to evaluate the potential influence of the COVID-19 pandemic on the MIMIC-IV results, we performed a subsample analysis using a randomly selected 80% of MIMIC-IV patients to simulate the exclusion of patients admitted after 2020. Fourth, to assess temporal heterogeneity related to evolving treatment practices, including the introduction of SGLT2 inhibitors, data from all three databases were pooled and stratified by calendar period (pre-2015 versus post-2015), with the GAM analysis performed separately for each period. Fifth, a stepwise covariate adjustment analysis was conducted in the MIMIC-IV database using four progressively adjusted models to evaluate the impact of time-varying treatment and disease severity variables on the TYG-BMI–time interaction: Model 1 (age and sex), Model 2 (additionally SOFA score and Charlson Comorbidity Index), Model 3 (additionally insulin use, vasopressor use, and mechanical ventilation), and Model 4 (additionally albumin, creatinine, and white blood cell count). Sixth, to evaluate potential effect modification by glucose-lowering therapy, the MIMIC-IV cohort was stratified by insulin administration status on day 0, with the GAM analysis performed separately for insulin users and non-users. Seventh, to compare the discriminative performance of TYG-BMI with established severity scores, receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis was performed using day 0 values in the MIMIC-IV database, comparing three models: SOFA score alone, TYG-BMI alone, and a combined SOFA plus TYG-BMI model, all adjusted for age and sex. The area under the ROC curve (AUC) was compared between models using the DeLong test.</p><p id="Par69">All statistical analyses were conducted separately for each database using identical analytical protocols to ensure reproducibility and to evaluate the consistency of findings across different patient populations and clinical settings. Analyses were performed using R version 4.3.0 (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria). Key packages included tableone (version 0.13.2) for baseline characteristics, mgcv (version 1.8–42) for generalized additive modeling, plot3D (version 1.4) for three-dimensional visualization, and ggplot2 (version 3.4.2) for heatmaps and forest plots. A two-sided p-value less than 0.05 was considered statistically significant.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec9"><title>Study population and baseline characteristics</title><p id="Par70">After sequential application of the exclusion criteria across three critical care databases (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>), a total of 5,133 patients with heart failure were included in the final analysis, comprising 2,476 from MIMIC-IV, 894 from MIMIC-III, and 1,763 from eICU. The primary reasons for exclusion were non-first hospital or ICU admissions and incomplete TYG-BMI data during the 7-day observation period.</p><p id="Par71">The baseline characteristics of the study population, stratified by database and hospital mortality, are presented in Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>, which also includes the characteristics of the total cohort. In the overall population (n = 5,133), the median age was 73 years (IQR: 65–81), 58.1% were male, and the median BMI was 28.40 kg/m<sup>2</sup> (IQR: 24.34–33.71). The median SOFA score was 7 (IQR: 4–10), and the median SAPS II score was 43 (IQR: 34–53). Hospital mortality rates were 27.9% (691/2,476) in MIMIC-IV, 29.0% (259/894) in MIMIC-III, and 27.5% (484/1,763) in eICU, yielding a pooled mortality rate of 27.9% (1,434/5,133). Mechanical ventilation was used in 73.3% of patients, renal replacement therapy in 5.5%, vasopressors in 46.6%, and sedatives in 56.1%. Insulin was administered in 33.2% of patients. Most baseline variables did not differ significantly between survivors and non-survivors in the total cohort, although hematocrit was slightly lower in non-survivors (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.010). Database-specific comparisons revealed significant differences in creatinine (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.009), hematocrit (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.030), and calcium (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.039) in the MIMIC-IV cohort, and in OASIS score (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.031) in the eICU cohort.<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Baseline characteristics of patients with heart failure across three critical care databases</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Characteristics</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">MIMIC-IV<break/>(Hospital mortality)</th><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">MIMIC-III<break/>(Hospital mortality)</th><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">eICU<break/>(Hospital mortality)</th><th align="left" colspan="3" rowspan="1">Overall<break/>(Hospital mortality)</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Level</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Survived<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1785)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-survivors<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 691)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Survived<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 635)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-survivors<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 259)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Survived<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1279)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-survivors<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 484)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Survived<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3699)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-survivors<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1434)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age, years</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">74.00 [65.00, 81.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73.00 [65.00, 81.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.766</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">76.09 [67.77, 82.75]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">76.52 [68.09, 82.48]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.804</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71.00 [63.00, 79.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71.00 [62.00, 78.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.091</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73.00 [65.00, 81.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73.00 [64.00, 81.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.307</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1059 (59.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">416 (60.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.725</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">352 (55.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">148 (57.1)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.694</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">728 (56.9)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">283 (58.5)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.593</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2139 (57.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">847 (59.1)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.438</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">726 (40.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">275 (39.8)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">283 (44.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111 (42.9)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">551 (43.1)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">201 (41.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1560 (42.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">587 (40.9)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weight, kg</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81.95 [68.12, 97.10]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">84.09 [68.74, 101.64]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.055</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">79.86 [67.58, 93.66]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81.90 [69.09, 95.97]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.329</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">83.90 [68.90, 100.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.55 [70.72, 104.58]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.082</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">82.05 [68.21, 97.74]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">84.25 [69.35, 100.97]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.007</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Height, cm</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170.00 [160.80, 178.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170.00 [161.70, 178.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.421</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">167.64 [160.02, 175.77]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">169.42 [160.78, 176.15]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.469</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170.20 [162.60, 177.80]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">171.10 [162.60, 178.18]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.147</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170.00 [161.24, 177.80]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170.18 [162.56, 178.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.099</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">BMI, kg/m²</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.22 [24.44, 33.15]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.68 [24.05, 34.79]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.198</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.16 [24.43, 32.17]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.00 [24.67, 33.37]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.636</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.47 [24.41, 34.14]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.04 [24.24, 34.84]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.300</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.30 [24.43, 33.27]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.66 [24.20, 34.56]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.094</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SAPS II score</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45.00 [36.00, 55.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45.00 [38.00, 54.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.796</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.00 [36.00, 53.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.00 [35.50, 52.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.845</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40.00 [31.00, 51.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40.00 [31.00, 51.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.622</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43.00 [34.00, 54.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43.00 [35.00, 52.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.933</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">OASIS score</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.00 [32.00, 44.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.00 [32.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.700</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38.00 [32.00, 44.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38.00 [32.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.577</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.00 [26.00, 40.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34.00 [26.75, 41.25]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.031</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36.00 [30.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.00 [30.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.303</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SOFA score</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.00 [4.00, 10.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [4.00, 10.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.844</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [3.00, 8.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.00 [4.00, 8.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.483</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.00 [5.00, 10.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.00 [5.00, 11.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.841</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.00 [4.00, 10.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.00 [4.00, 10.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.965</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Charlson index</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [5.00, 8.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [5.00, 8.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.761</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [5.00, 7.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [5.00, 7.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.162</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.00 [3.00, 6.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.00 [3.00, 6.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.068</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [4.00, 7.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.00 [4.00, 7.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.219</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Triglycerides, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">141.00 [141.00, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">141.00 [141.00, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.257</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">112.00 [112.00, 112.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">112.00 [112.00, 112.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.177</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122.00 [122.00, 122.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122.00 [122.00, 122.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.551</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122.00 [112.00, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122.00 [112.00, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.992</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Glucose, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">130.00 [110.92, 159.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">129.00 [110.71, 155.79]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.547</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">127.00 [108.88, 148.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">127.75 [106.25, 152.83]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.688</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">137.50 [114.00, 171.17]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.50 [112.00, 169.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.382</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">132.00 [111.25, 161.50]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">131.00 [110.00, 161.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.408</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Heart rate, bpm</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86.45 [75.21, 98.84]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.72 [75.28, 96.69]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.349</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86.63 [77.29, 98.11]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86.54 [75.01, 97.12]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.299</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">92.14 [79.26, 105.43]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">92.08 [80.01, 105.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.902</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">87.96 [76.79, 101.03]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">87.81 [76.67, 99.20]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.271</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Systolic BP, mmHg</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.48 [103.04, 123.38]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.00 [102.94, 122.66]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.330</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.24 [102.14, 122.30]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.81 [103.42, 122.53]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.680</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.61 [102.16, 126.53]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.18 [102.02, 122.99]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.090</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.50 [102.65, 124.29]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">111.20 [102.81, 122.86]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.126</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Diastolic BP, mmHg</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.93 [53.92, 67.41]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60.25 [53.74, 67.72]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.484</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">54.87 [49.27, 60.96]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">54.62 [49.62, 59.77]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.446</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">61.11 [54.81, 68.51]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60.56 [54.71, 68.51]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.483</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.47 [53.23, 66.73]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.24 [53.13, 67.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.648</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Creatinine, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.20 [0.85, 1.98]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.30 [0.90, 2.15]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.009</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.10 [0.80, 1.68]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.10 [0.80, 1.74]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.899</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.30 [0.90, 2.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.20 [0.90, 1.99]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.435</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.20 [0.85, 1.93]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.21 [0.87, 2.05]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.195</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">BUN, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25.67 [17.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.00 [18.00, 44.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.091</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25.00 [17.00, 39.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24.00 [16.00, 38.75]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.532</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.00 [18.00, 45.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.00 [18.00, 43.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.615</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.50 [17.33, 43.12]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.50 [17.67, 42.50]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.545</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hematocrit, %</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.45 [27.30, 36.70]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.73 [27.03, 35.65]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.030</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.75 [28.26, 34.49]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.50 [27.83, 33.85]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.146</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.70 [28.84, 39.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.90 [28.76, 38.55]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.422</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.90 [27.95, 37.10]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.40 [27.68, 36.18]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.010</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Platelet, 10⁹/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">175.33 [126.50, 244.67]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">179.50 [128.25, 240.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.738</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">176.00 [128.08, 246.83]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">171.00 [123.25, 235.33]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.308</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">197.00 [141.00, 261.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">203.00 [142.75, 262.38]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.523</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">184.00 [131.00, 251.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">185.00 [131.54, 248.38]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.960</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">WBC, 10⁹/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.30 [8.80, 16.10]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.15 [8.92, 16.18]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.722</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.75 [8.85, 16.80]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.35 [9.35, 16.55]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.860</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.90 [8.60, 16.70]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.04 [8.79, 16.78]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.670</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.20 [8.75, 16.50]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.11 [8.90, 16.55]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.647</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Potassium, mEq/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.20 [3.83, 4.60]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.20 [3.90, 4.62]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.243</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.17 [3.80, 4.54]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.10 [3.80, 4.50]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.249</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.10 [3.70, 4.60]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.20 [3.80, 4.60]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.290</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.17 [3.80, 4.60]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.20 [3.81, 4.60]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.334</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sodium, mEq/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.00 [135.25, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.08 [135.65, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.800</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">139.50 [136.50, 142.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">139.00 [136.83, 142.50]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.452</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.00 [135.00, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.00 [134.73, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.571</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.25 [135.33, 141.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138.35 [135.59, 141.33]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.398</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Calcium, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.25 [7.80, 8.70]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.33 [7.90, 8.78]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.039</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.25 [7.84, 8.74]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.25 [7.80, 8.70]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.495</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.45 [7.95, 9.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.48 [7.90, 9.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.758</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.30 [7.85, 8.80]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.40 [7.90, 8.80]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.431</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Albumin, g/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.01 [2.65, 3.36]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.06 [2.69, 3.40]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.173</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.80 [2.46, 3.20]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.74 [2.40, 3.14]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.194</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.88 [2.40, 3.30]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.80 [2.40, 3.20]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.382</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.94 [2.55, 3.30]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.94 [2.54, 3.30]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.823</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total bilirubin, mg/dL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.77 [0.50, 1.31]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.77 [0.50, 1.40]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.507</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.87 [0.58, 1.40]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.90 [0.64, 1.42]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.414</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.81 [0.60, 1.25]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.82 [0.56, 1.40]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.808</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.80 [0.54, 1.30]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.81 [0.55, 1.40]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.314</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hospital LOS, days</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">404.78 [288.32, 616.17]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">426.75 [300.58, 621.89]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.109</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">414.45 [309.36, 627.12]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">447.00 [291.99, 641.41]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.738</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">363.45 [267.29, 523.38]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">361.04 [260.57, 536.00]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.649</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">390.95 [283.22, 587.32]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">401.90 [286.75, 593.70]</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.279</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mechanical ventilation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">553 (31.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">234 (33.9)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.182</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">156 (24.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70 (27.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.495</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">263 (20.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">95 (19.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.712</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">972 (26.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">399 (27.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.276</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1232 (69.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">457 (66.1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">479 (75.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">189 (73.0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1016 (79.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">389 (80.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2727 (73.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1035 (72.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Renal replacement therapy</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1681 (94.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">647 (93.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.678</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">606 (95.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">247 (95.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.000</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1209 (94.5)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">459 (94.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.891</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3496 (94.5)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1353 (94.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.875</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">104 (5.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44 (6.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29 (4.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12 (4.6)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70 (5.5)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25 (5.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">203 (5.5)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81 (5.6)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Vasopressor use</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">814 (45.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">327 (47.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.468</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">292 (46.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">126 (48.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.515</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">854 (66.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">327 (67.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.796</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1960 (53.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">780 (54.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.382</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">971 (54.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">364 (52.7)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">343 (54.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">133 (51.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">425 (33.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">157 (32.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1739 (47.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">654 (45.6)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sedative use</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">638 (35.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">262 (37.9)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.336</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">246 (38.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">104 (40.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.751</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">733 (57.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">270 (55.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.601</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1617 (43.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">636 (44.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.703</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1147 (64.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">429 (62.1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">389 (61.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">155 (59.8)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">546 (42.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">214 (44.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2082 (56.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">798 (55.6)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Insulin use</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1085 (60.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">394 (57.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.095</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">461 (72.6)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">186 (71.8)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.877</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">933 (72.9)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">371 (76.7)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.128</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2479 (67.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">951 (66.3)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.656</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">700 (39.2)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">297 (43.0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">174 (27.4)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73 (28.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">346 (27.1)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">113 (23.3)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1220 (33.0)</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">483 (33.7)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Continuous variables are presented as median [interquartile range], and categorical variables are presented as n (%). <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-values were calculated using Kruskal–Wallis test for continuous variables and chi-square test for categorical variables. Standardized mean differences (SMD) are provided for cross-database comparison</p><p>SAPS II, simplified acute physiology score II; OASIS, oxford acute severity of illness score; SOFA, sequential organ failure assessment; SpO₂, peripheral oxygen saturation; TYG-BMI, triglyceride-glucose-body mass index</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Temporal trends of TYG-BMI during ICU admission</title><p id="Par72">The temporal trajectory of TYG-BMI values across the three databases is illustrated in Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, with detailed statistics presented in Supplementary Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>. All three databases demonstrated relatively stable TYG-BMI patterns throughout the 7-day observation period. In the MIMIC-IV cohort (n = 2,476), the mean TYG-BMI was 272.95 (95% CI 270.08–275.81) on Day 0 and 271.91 (95% CI 269.06–274.76) on Day 7, representing a modest decline of 1.04 units. The MIMIC-III cohort (n = 894) exhibited slightly lower values, with mean TYG-BMI decreasing from 266.22 (95% CI 261.71–270.73) on Day 0 to 263.38 (95% CI 258.95–267.81) on Day 7, a difference of 2.85 units. The eICU cohort (n = 1,763) showed the highest mean values, declining marginally from 273.58 (95% CI 269.91–277.25) on Day 0 to 272.87 (95% CI 269.21–276.53) on Day 7, a difference of 0.71 units. Across all three databases, the largest decrease occurred between Day 0 and Day 1, after which values remained relatively stable throughout the remainder of the observation period. The standard deviations were consistent across time points within each database, ranging from 67.02 to 68.80 in MIMIC-III, 72.16 to 72.77 in MIMIC-IV, and 77.84 to 78.69 in eICU, indicating comparable variability in TYG-BMI measurements throughout the ICU stay.</p><p id="Par73">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Temporal changes in TYG-BMI across three databases during the first 7 days of ICU admission. Data are presented as mean values with 95% confidence intervals. Each line represents a different database (eICU, MIMIC-III, and MIMIC-IV), demonstrating the dynamic trajectory of TYG-BMI following ICU admission in patients with heart failure</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1781" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Dose–response relationship between baseline TYG-BMI and hospital mortality</title><p id="Par74">The dose–response relationship between day 0 TYG-BMI and hospital mortality was first examined using restricted cubic spline regression (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). In the MIMIC-IV database, a significant non-linear U-shaped association was observed in both Model 1 (adjusted for age and sex; overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001) and Model 2 (fully adjusted; overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), with the nadir of mortality risk occurring between TYG-BMI values of approximately 260 and 283 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>A, D). Both extremes of the TYG-BMI distribution were associated with elevated mortality, with the risk increase being more pronounced at higher values. In the MIMIC-III database, a similar U-shaped trend was observed, although neither the overall association nor the non-linear term reached statistical significance in Model 1 (overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.102, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.072) or Model 2 (overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.137, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.100), likely attributable to the smaller sample size (n = 894) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>B, E). The eICU database showed a comparable pattern, with the lowest mortality risk around TYG-BMI values of 260–276 in Model 1 (overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.196, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.141) and a narrower optimal range in Model 2 (overall <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.165, non-linear <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.166) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>C, F). Despite the lack of statistical significance in the MIMIC-III and eICU databases for the RCS analysis of day 0 values alone, the direction and shape of the dose–response curves were consistent across all three databases, suggesting a reproducible U-shaped pattern. This cross-database consistency motivated the subsequent GAM analysis, which leveraged repeated daily measurements across the full 7-day observation period to enhance statistical power and examine the temporal dimension of the TYG-BMI–mortality association.</p><p id="Par75">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Restricted cubic spline analysis of the association between Day 0 TYG-BMI and hospital mortality. Panels <bold>A</bold>–<bold>C</bold> show results from Model 1 (adjusted for age and gender) in MIMIC-IV, MIMIC-III, and eICU, respectively; panels <bold>D</bold>–<bold>F</bold> show corresponding results from Model 2 (fully adjusted model, additionally adjusted for SOFA score, Charlson comorbidity index, insulin use, vasopressor use, mechanical ventilation, albumin, creatinine, and white blood cell count). The red solid line represents the odds ratio point estimate, blue dashed lines represent the 95% confidence interval, and the gray horizontal dashed line denotes the OR = 1 reference. The reference value was set at the median TYG-BMI of each database, and the optimal number of knots was selected from 3 to 7 based on the Akaike information criterion. Rug plots at the bottom indicate the distribution density of the sample</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1858" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Association between TYG-BMI and hospital mortality</title><p id="Par76">Building on the cross-sectional findings from the RCS analysis, generalized additive models were subsequently employed to examine the three-dimensional association among TYG-BMI intensity, time since ICU admission, and hospital mortality, thereby incorporating the temporal dimension of TYG-BMI exposure. The predicted mortality probabilities and odds ratio deviations are visualized in Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, with detailed odds ratios for each TYG-BMI stratum and time point presented in Supplementary Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>.</p><p id="Par77">
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Three-dimensional surface plots and heatmaps depicting the relationship between TYG-BMI intensity, time since ICU admission, and hospital mortality. Panels show three-dimensional surface plots of predicted mortality probability from <bold>A</bold> MIMIC-IV, <bold>C</bold> MIMIC-III, and <bold>E</bold> eICU databases, with warmer colors indicating higher mortality risk. Corresponding odds ratio deviation heatmaps are presented for <bold>B</bold> MIMIC-IV, <bold>D</bold> MIMIC-III, and <bold>F</bold> eICU databases, where blue indicates protective effects (OR &lt; 1) and red indicates increased risk (OR &gt; 1), with dashed contour lines denoting OR = 1. Surfaces and heatmaps were generated using generalized additive models with tensor product smooth functions for the TYG-BMI × time interaction</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1898" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par78">Across all three databases, a consistent non-linear, U-shaped relationship between TYG-BMI and hospital mortality was observed, characterized by a U-shaped pattern (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>A–F). In the MIMIC-IV cohort, patients with TYG-BMI values in the 250–275 range demonstrated the lowest mortality risk throughout the observation period, with odds ratios of 0.76 (95% CI 0.68–0.85, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001) on Day 0 and 0.77 (95% CI 0.69–0.86, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001) on Day 7 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>A, B). Conversely, elevated TYG-BMI values were associated with progressively increased mortality risk. Patients with TYG-BMI in the 425–450 range showed OR of 1.61 (95% CI 1.35–1.93, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001) on Day 0, while those in the highest stratum (550–575) demonstrated OR of 2.98 (95% CI 1.79–4.97, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001). Similarly, in the MIMIC-III cohort, the 250–275 range exhibited protective effects with OR of 0.87 (95% CI 0.80–0.95, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.001) on Day 3, whereas elevated values (425–450) showed increased risk with OR of 1.48 (95% CI 1.11–1.98, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.008) on Day 0 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>C, D).</p><p id="Par79">The eICU database demonstrated comparable but attenuated associations (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>E, F). The 250–275 range showed protective trends, achieving statistical significance from Day 2 onwards (OR = 0.93, 95% CI 0.87–0.99, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.016 on Day 2; OR = 0.92, 95% CI 0.88–0.97, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.003 on Day 3). Elevated TYG-BMI values (&gt; 425) were consistently associated with increased mortality across all time points, with the 550–575 range showing OR of 1.63 (95% CI 1.01–2.61, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.043) on Day 0 increasing to 1.94 (95% CI 1.20–3.15, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.007) on Day 7. The magnitude of associations remained relatively stable throughout the 7-day observation period across all three databases.</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Temporal trends of the TYG-BMI-mortality association</title><p id="Par80">To quantify how the TYG-BMI-mortality association evolved over time, weighted linear regression analysis was performed on log-transformed odds ratios across the 7-day observation period, with results presented in Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> and Supplementary Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>. The temporal trend analysis revealed consistent patterns across databases, highlighting the importance of considering both intensity and duration of TYG-BMI exposure.</p><p id="Par81">
<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><p>Forest plot of odds ratios for hospital mortality by TYG-BMI range across three databases. Results are stratified by days since ICU admission (Day 0 through Day 7) and presented with 95% confidence intervals on a logarithmic scale. Different colors and shapes represent distinct databases, facilitating comparison of effect estimates across cohorts</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1965" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par82">Across all three databases, the optimal TYG-BMI range for survival was identified as 250–275, which demonstrated time-dependent protective effects. In the MIMIC-III cohort, each additional day with TYG-BMI maintained within this optimal range was associated with a 0.4% reduction in mortality risk (OR change per day = 0.996, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.0015), accumulating to a 2.6% risk reduction over the 7 day period (OR change = 0.974). The eICU cohort showed a similar pattern, with the 250–275 range demonstrating a 0.4% daily risk reduction (OR change per day = 0.996, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.0014) and a cumulative 2.4% reduction over 7 days (OR change = 0.976). In contrast, patients with elevated TYG-BMI values exhibited progressively increasing mortality risk over time. In the eICU database, TYG-BMI values in the 400–425 range showed a 0.6% daily risk increase (OR change per day = 1.006, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), with cumulative 7-day risk increase of 4.4% (OR change = 1.044). This time-dependent risk amplification became more pronounced at higher TYG-BMI levels: the 450–475 range demonstrated a 1.1% daily increase (OR change per day = 1.011, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), accumulating to 8.1% over 7 days; the 475–500 range showed a 1.4% daily increase (OR change per day = 1.014, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), with 10.3% cumulative risk elevation; and the highest stratum (550–575) exhibited a 2.5% daily risk increase (OR change per day = 1.025, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), resulting in a substantial 19.1% cumulative risk increase over the 7-day observation period (OR change = 1.191).</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Sensitivity analyses</title><p id="Par83">A series of sensitivity analyses were performed to assess the robustness of the primary findings (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>; Supplementary Figs. <xref rid="MOESM2" ref-type="media">1</xref>, <xref rid="MOESM3" ref-type="media">2</xref>, <xref rid="MOESM4" ref-type="media">3</xref>, <xref rid="MOESM5" ref-type="media">4</xref>, <xref rid="MOESM6" ref-type="media">5</xref>). First, when the inclusion criterion was relaxed to allow a TYG-BMI missing rate of less than 30% with multiple imputation for missing values, the three-dimensional surface plots retained the characteristic U-shaped TYG-BMI–mortality relationship across all three databases (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>A–C), with the pattern closely resembling that of the primary analysis. Second, restricting the analysis to the first 3 days of ICU admission (day 0 through day 3), which captured a broader patient population without requiring a 7 day ICU stay, yielded comparable three-dimensional surface patterns across all three databases (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>D–F), indicating that the U-shaped association was already evident during the early ICU period. Third, the COVID-19 sensitivity analysis, performed by randomly subsampling 80% of the MIMIC-IV cohort to simulate the exclusion of patients admitted after 2020, produced surface plots and heatmaps that were virtually identical to the primary analysis (Supplementary Fig. <xref rid="MOESM2" ref-type="media">1</xref>A, B), suggesting that the inclusion of the pandemic period did not materially alter the findings. Fourth, calendar period stratification (pre-2015 versus post-2015) demonstrated consistent U-shaped TYG-BMI–mortality surfaces in both periods (Supplementary Fig. <xref rid="MOESM3" ref-type="media">2</xref>A–D). The corresponding heatmaps showed similar OR = 1 contour line positions, indicating that the association remained stable across eras with differing treatment practices, including the introduction of SGLT2 inhibitors. Fifth, the stepwise covariate adjustment analysis in the MIMIC-IV database showed that the three-dimensional TYG-BMI–time–mortality surface remained stable across four progressively adjusted models: Model 1 (age and sex), Model 2 (additionally SOFA score and Charlson Comorbidity Index), Model 3 (additionally insulin use, vasopressor use, and mechanical ventilation), and Model 4 (additionally albumin, creatinine, and white blood cell count) (Supplementary Fig. <xref rid="MOESM4" ref-type="media">3</xref>A–D). The persistence of the U-shaped pattern after sequential inclusion of treatment-related and disease severity variables suggests that the observed association was not substantially driven by time-varying confounders. Sixth, stratification by insulin administration status on day 0 in the MIMIC-IV database revealed that the U-shaped TYG-BMI–mortality association was present in both insulin users and non-insulin users (Supplementary Fig. <xref rid="MOESM5" ref-type="media">4</xref>A–D). The corresponding heatmaps demonstrated similar spatial distributions of protective and risk-associated TYG-BMI ranges in both subgroups, although the magnitude of mortality risk at extreme TYG-BMI values appeared greater among insulin users.</p><p id="Par84">
<fig id="Fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><p>Sensitivity analyses of the TYG-BMI–time–mortality relationship using three-dimensional surface plots. Panels <bold>A</bold>–<bold>C</bold> show the TYG-BMI–time–mortality surfaces from MIMIC-IV, MIMIC-III, and eICU databases, respectively, under the missing rate &lt; 30% sensitivity analysis. Panels <bold>D</bold>–<bold>F</bold> show the corresponding surfaces restricted to the first 3 days after ICU admission (Day 0–3) for MIMIC-IV, MIMIC-III, and eICU databases, respectively. All surfaces were generated using generalized additive models with tensor product smooth functions, with warmer colors indicating higher predicted mortality</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e2051" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_Fig6_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par85">Finally, ROC curve analysis comparing the discriminative performance of TYG-BMI and SOFA score for predicting hospital mortality at day 0 in the MIMIC-IV database demonstrated that the SOFA score alone achieved an AUC of 0.720 (95% CI 0.698–0.742), while TYG-BMI alone yielded an AUC of 0.680 (95% CI 0.657–0.703) (Supplementary Fig. <xref rid="MOESM6" ref-type="media">5</xref>). Notably, the combined SOFA plus TYG-BMI model achieved a significantly higher AUC of 0.780 (95% CI 0.759–0.801), representing a meaningful improvement over the SOFA score alone (DeLong test <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001). This finding suggests that TYG-BMI provides complementary prognostic information beyond that captured by conventional organ dysfunction scoring.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par86">In contemporary cardiac intensive care, critically ill heart failure (HF) remains burdened by high short-term mortality and marked clinical heterogeneity, making early risk stratification central to ICU decision-making. Commonly used ICU severity frameworks (APACHE II, SAPS II, SOFA) and HF-focused in-hospital risk scores were developed primarily around baseline physiology and admission-era measurements, and although they provide important global risk signals, they may be less able to represent rapidly evolving metabolic and inflammatory states during critical illness <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">[1</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">14</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16]</xref>.</p><p id="Par87">In this multi-database retrospective cohort study of ICU HF patients from MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU, we observed a reproducible, time-varying, and non-linear association between TyG–BMI and in-hospital mortality. Across cohorts, TyG–BMI was associated with higher mortality at both low and high levels, whereas an intermediate band corresponded to comparatively lower mortality. Notably, the magnitude and shape of the TyG–BMI–mortality association differed across ICU days, suggesting that time-updated metabolic profiles may better reflect evolving risk states than a single admission snapshot. Given the observational and retrospective design, these findings should be interpreted as associations and remain potentially subject to residual confounding and time-varying treatment effects. To probe the robustness of these associations, we conducted a series of sensitivity analyses, including stepwise covariate adjustment for treatment-related variables (insulin, vasopressors, and mechanical ventilation), stratification by insulin use, calendar period stratification to address temporal heterogeneity related to evolving pharmacotherapy (including SGLT2 inhibitors), a shorter observation window (first 3 days) to include patients with briefer ICU stays, a relaxed missing data criterion with multiple imputation, and a COVID-19 subsample analysis. The consistency of the U-shaped TYG-BMI–mortality pattern across these analyses strengthens confidence in the observed associations, although residual confounding by unmeasured treatment intensity (e.g., insulin dosing, vasopressor dose-duration) cannot be excluded. This interpretation is consistent with broader critical care observations that changes in organ dysfunction over time can add prognostic value beyond isolated measurements <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">[3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17]</xref>, and with modern trajectory and subphenotype work emphasizing that time-resolved patterns can reflect clinically meaningful risk states <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">[18]</xref>.</p><p id="Par88">Our findings align with a growing cardiometabolic literature in which insulin-resistance surrogates carry prognostic relevance across cardiovascular phenotypes. Importantly, recent evidence highlights that anthropometric and metabolic indices should be interpreted alongside nutritional risk in HF. El-Sheikh et al. demonstrated that the obesity paradox in acute HF was present only in well-nourished patients and disappeared in malnourished individuals <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">[9]</xref>, and a subsequent study by the same group further showed that malnutrition, assessed by the Prognostic Nutritional Index and Geriatric Nutritional Risk Index, was independently associated with mortality in elderly chronic HF patients, with prognostic value varying by BMI and inflammatory status <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">[10]</xref>. These findings underscore that TYG-BMI, which incorporates BMI as a component, must be contextualized within the broader framework of nutritional status and body composition, particularly in the critically ill where cachexia and malnutrition are prevalent. Umbrella synthesis in Cardiovascular Diabetology supports the diagnostic and prognostic relevance of the triglyceride–glucose (TyG) index across diverse clinical settings <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">[4]</xref>, and Cardiovascular Diabetology evidence suggests that insulin-resistance indices are associated with outcomes even within HFpEF <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">[5]</xref>. Within HF, prior TyG–BMI studies have reported heterogeneous associations that may reflect differences in setting, endpoint horizon, and the biologic meaning of TyG–BMI across disease stages. A MIMIC-IV analysis suggested that lower TyG–BMI is associated with higher longer-term mortality in HF <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">[19]</xref>, an ICU chronic HF study comparing multiple insulin-resistance indices supported prognostic relevance for longer-term outcomes <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">[20]</xref>, and a non-ICU HF cohort with coronary heart disease reported a non-linear (reverse “J”-type) association <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">[21]</xref>. Our cross-database replication and time-dependent modeling provide additional support for the view that risk may concentrate at the extremes and that observed associations can vary by clinical context and time window, particularly during early ICU care when physiology and treatment exposures change rapidly.</p><p id="Par89">Beyond HF-specific cohorts, ICU-wide evidence supports the plausibility that TyG-derived signatures capture clinically relevant stress physiology. A recent meta-analysis indicates that higher TyG index is associated with increased mortality in ICU populations <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">[22]</xref>. TyG-related indices have also been linked to adverse outcomes in other high-acuity ICU phenotypes, including sepsis <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">[23]</xref> and arrhythmia-associated critical illness, where trajectory patterns have been associated with mortality <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">[24</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26]</xref>. In critically ill HF, ICU-based evidence likewise links TyG index to mortality <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">[27]</xref>. Taken together, these data are consistent with the interpretation that TyG-derived metrics may act as integrative markers of systemic stress and metabolic dysregulation, particularly when assessed longitudinally.</p><p id="Par90">An important interpretive caveat is that TYG-BMI may not represent a pure marker of insulin resistance in the ICU setting. Under stable metabolic conditions, TyG-derived indices reflect peripheral and hepatic insulin resistance and have demonstrated diagnostic accuracy against reference methods, although with heterogeneous cutoff values and moderate-to-low quality evidence, as highlighted in a systematic review <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">[28]</xref>. However, as emphasized by recent reviews <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">[29</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30]</xref>, the validity of the TyG index relies on relatively steady physiological states and fasting measurements. In critically ill patients, glucose and triglyceride levels are profoundly influenced by acute stress responses, systemic inflammation, organ dysfunction, catecholamine surges, nutritional support, and pharmacological interventions including insulin and corticosteroids. Consequently, TYG-BMI values in the ICU likely represent a composite signal integrating chronic insulin resistance, acute stress-metabolic derangement, and treatment effects, rather than a specific reflection of any single pathophysiological process. This interpretive complexity does not negate the prognostic utility of TYG-BMI—indeed, its capacity to integrate multiple pathophysiological streams may partly explain its association with outcomes—but it does preclude direct mechanistic inference from observational data alone.</p><p id="Par91">Mechanistically, the association at the high TyG–BMI end is biologically plausible in ICU HF. TyG-derived measures integrate hyperglycemia and hypertriglyceridemia, features of stress responses and insulin resistance that may reflect heightened neurohormonal activation, inflammatory signaling, endothelial dysfunction, and impaired myocardial substrate utilization during acute decompensation. A meta-analysis in Cardiovascular Diabetology supports an adverse association between stress hyperglycaemia ratio and mortality in cardiovascular disease <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">[31]</xref>, and glycaemic variability has been associated with mortality in cardiogenic shock <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">[32]</xref>. Contemporary mechanistic syntheses indicate that failing hearts undergo metabolic reprogramming and may lose energetic flexibility <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">[33]</xref>, and cardiometabolic remodeling provides additional context for insulin-resistance–linked energetic impairment <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">[34]</xref>. Collectively, these lines of evidence support a framework in which persistently high TyG–BMI during early ICU days may reflect sustained stress-metabolic load and reduced adaptive capacity and could plausibly be linked to higher short-term mortality.</p><p id="Par92">At the low TyG–BMI end, elevated mortality may reflect a distinct “low-reserve” biology rather than a favorable metabolic state. Malnutrition is common in severe HF and is independently associated with mortality <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">[35]</xref>, with recent evidence demonstrating that its prognostic significance varies by BMI category and inflammatory markers <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">[9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10]</xref>. Cardiac cachexia and wasting syndromes are consistently associated with increased mortality in HF, supported by meta-analyses and contemporary synthesis <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">[36</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37]</xref> and emphasized in recent comprehensive reviews <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">[38]</xref>. In critical illness more broadly, low lipid availability can act as a marker of severity and maladaptive host response; for example, hypocholesterolemia at ICU admission has been associated with mortality in sepsis <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">[39]</xref>. In ICU HF, low TyG–BMI may therefore represent a composite signal of low BMI, depleted energy stores, impaired substrate availability, and a frailty or catabolic phenotype with limited physiologic resilience during acute hemodynamic and inflammatory stress.</p><p id="Par93">A key contribution of our analysis is the explicit focus on time-varying effects using repeated daily TyG–BMI measurements. This aligns with an emerging trajectory paradigm in Cardiovascular Diabetology, where longitudinal TyG patterns are increasingly recognized as prognostically informative. TyG index trajectories have been associated with mortality in broader cohorts <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">[6]</xref>, dynamic TyG changes have been linked to prognosis in acute coronary syndromes <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">[7]</xref>, and TyG trajectory phenotypes have been associated with worsening HF risk in elderly chronic HF with type 2 diabetes <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">[8]</xref>. Extending this longitudinal lens to ICU HF, our results suggest that serial TyG–BMI assessment may help identify risk phenotypes that are less evident from admission-only measures, including patients with persistently high stress-metabolic signatures or those with persistently low, low-reserve profiles over early ICU days.</p><p id="Par94">Clinically, these findings support TyG–BMI as a risk-phenotyping marker rather than a direct therapeutic target. Evidence from ICU glucose-control trials illustrates the hazards of indiscriminate metabolic “normalization”: intensive insulin therapy showed benefit in an early single-center context, whereas the large NICE-SUGAR trial demonstrated harm with intensive glucose control compared with conventional targets <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">[40]</xref>. Accordingly, TyG–BMI may be interpreted as an integrative signal to inform surveillance intensity and individualized metabolic and nutritional management, not as a mandate for uniform correction. In our exploratory ROC analysis in the MIMIC-IV database, combining TYG-BMI with SOFA score yielded a significantly higher AUC (0.780) compared with SOFA alone (0.720; DeLong <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), suggesting that TYG-BMI provides complementary prognostic information beyond conventional organ dysfunction scoring. Future studies should prospectively validate whether adding time-updated TyG–BMI improves discrimination and calibration beyond established severity scoring systems in independent cohorts, and whether observed associations differ by diabetes status, nutritional risk, and organ dysfunction trajectories. Effect modification also warrants attention: meta-analytic evidence suggests diabetes can modify TyG-associated risk patterns <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">[41]</xref>, and prospective evidence indicates that antidiabetic and lipid-lowering therapies may interact with TyG-related mortality associations <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">[34]</xref>, which is particularly relevant in ICU HF where treatment exposures are common and time-varying.</p><sec id="Sec16"><title>Strengths and limitations</title><p id="Par95">This study has several strengths. First, we leveraged three large, high-granularity critical care databases (MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU), enabling external replication across heterogeneous ICU systems and strengthening the robustness and generalizability of the observed associations <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">[11</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13]</xref>. Second, rather than relying on a single baseline measurement, we characterized early ICU TyG–BMI using repeated daily values over the first week and applied a time-resolved, non-linear analytic framework, aligning with emerging evidence that TyG-related dynamics and trajectories can provide incremental prognostic information beyond static measurements <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">[6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7]</xref>. Third, TyG–BMI is derived from routinely available variables (triglycerides, glucose, and BMI), supporting potential clinical scalability without additional testing burden. Finally, by reporting a non-linear risk pattern and emphasizing early-course evolution, our work provides clinically interpretable risk phenotyping that may complement traditional severity scoring in critically ill heart failure.</p><p id="Par96">Several limitations merit consideration. First, as an observational retrospective analysis, residual confounding is inevitable. Key therapies known to substantially affect glucose and lipid metabolism—including insulin therapy (particularly intravenous insulin at varying doses), vasopressors, corticosteroids, nutritional strategies (enteral and parenteral), and glucose-lowering agents such as SGLT2 inhibitors—are not fully accounted for in the analyses. While we adjusted for insulin use, vasopressor use, and mechanical ventilation in our sensitivity models and stratified by insulin status, critical quantitative information regarding treatment intensity and exposure—such as insulin dosing, duration of intravenous insulin therapy, vasopressor dose and duration, and corticosteroid exposure—was not available in the databases. These treatments are closely linked to both disease severity and patient outcomes and may influence TYG-BMI values independently of any underlying metabolic phenotype, as highlighted by prior methodological work emphasizing the need to account for antidiabetic and hypolipidemic therapies when interpreting TyG <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">[28]</xref>. Furthermore, the inclusion period spans a long timeframe (2001–2022) during which substantial changes occurred in the management of critically ill patients, including the progressive introduction of SGLT2 inhibitors. Our calendar period stratification (pre-2015 versus post-2015) showed consistent associations across eras, but this analysis cannot fully capture the granular impact of evolving treatment practices. The MIMIC-IV database also encompasses the COVID-19 pandemic period, during which ICU case-mix, treatment strategies, and outcomes were profoundly altered; our COVID-19 sensitivity analysis suggested that the pandemic period did not materially alter the findings, but this cannot be definitively excluded. Second, triglycerides and glucose in routine ICU care are not uniformly fasting; values are influenced by acute stress responses, systemic inflammation, enteral/parenteral nutrition, and medication exposure, introducing measurement heterogeneity and time-dependent confounding. As emphasized in recent methodological reviews, the physiological meaning of the TyG index in critically ill patients is uncertain, as it may no longer reflect chronic insulin resistance but rather nonspecific metabolic derangement or illness severity <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">[29</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30]</xref>. This interpretive limitation is inherent to any ICU-based application of TyG-derived indices and should be considered when evaluating the clinical implications of our findings. Third, the requirement for an ICU stay of at least 7 days and complete daily TYG-BMI measurements introduces selection bias toward a sicker, more intensively monitored subgroup and may induce immortal time bias, as patients must survive the full observation window to be included. This design inherently excludes the early ICU period (first 2–3 days) that carries the highest mortality risk for the broader ICU HF population. Consequently, our primary findings are most directly applicable to patients experiencing prolonged ICU admissions (≥ 7 days) rather than to all critically ill HF patients. To mitigate this concern, we performed a sensitivity analysis restricted to the first 3 days of ICU admission, which included a broader patient population without the 7-day stay requirement and yielded consistent U-shaped associations, suggesting that the observed pattern is not solely an artifact of survival conditioning. Additionally, the relaxed missing rate criterion (&lt; 30% with multiple imputation) further expanded the eligible population and confirmed the robustness of the findings. Nevertheless, these sensitivity analyses cannot fully eliminate the potential for collider bias inherent in the primary cohort definition. Fourth, database-based phenotyping is constrained by coding practices and variable availability; important clinical details (e.g., granular echocardiographic parameters, HF subtype, and hemodynamic profiling) may be incomplete or inconsistently recorded across sources. Fifth, the observed “intermediate range” of lowest risk should be interpreted as a prognostic pattern rather than a therapeutic target; prior critical care evidence indicates that uniform aggressive metabolic correction (e.g., intensive glucose lowering) can be harmful, underscoring the need for cautious interpretation and prospective validation <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">[40]</xref>. Diagnostic Accuracy of the Triglyceride and Glucose Index for Insulin Resistance: A Systematic Review Finally, medication effects may modify TyG-related associations, and recent evidence suggests pharmacotherapy can interact with TyG–mortality relationships in metabolic populations, motivating future effect-modification analyses in ICU heart failure <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">[34]</xref>. Diagnostic Accuracy of the Triglyceride and Glucose Index for Insulin Resistance: A Systematic Review.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par97">In this multicenter retrospective cohort study of 5,133 critically ill patients with heart failure across three large critical care databases, TYG-BMI demonstrated a reproducible, non-linear, U-shaped association with hospital mortality that was consistent across databases and throughout the 7-day observation period. Both extremes of the TYG-BMI distribution were associated with elevated mortality risk, while an intermediate range (approximately 250–275) corresponded to the lowest risk. The addition of TYG-BMI to the SOFA score significantly improved the discriminative performance for predicting hospital mortality. These associations were robust across multiple sensitivity analyses addressing selection bias, time-varying confounding, treatment effect modification, and temporal heterogeneity. However, given the retrospective design, the uncertain physiological meaning of TYG-BMI in the ICU setting, and the potential for residual confounding by unmeasured treatment intensity, these findings should be interpreted as hypothesis-generating rather than confirmatory. TYG-BMI may serve as an accessible, integrative metabolic marker for risk phenotyping in critically ill heart failure, but its clinical utility requires prospective validation, formal comparison with established prognostic tools, and evaluation of whether metabolic risk stratification can translate into actionable clinical decision-making.</p></sec><sec id="Sec171" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>Below is the link to the electronic supplementary material.</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM1_ESM.xls" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 1: Table S1. Temporal statistics of TYG-BMI across three databases during the first 7 days of ICU admission. This table presents the sample size, mean, standard deviation, standard error, and 95% confidence intervals of TYG-BMI values at each time point (Day 0–7) for MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU databases. Table S2: Odds ratios for hospital mortality by TYG-BMI range and time point across three databases. This table reports the odds ratios with 95% confidence intervals and P-values for the association between TYG-BMI categories and hospital mortality at each day of ICU stay in MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU cohorts. Table S3. Detailed results of temporal trend analysis for the TYG-BMI-mortality association across databases. This table presents the weighted linear regression results quantifying how the TYG-BMI-mortality association changes over time, including daily odds ratio change, 7-day cumulative change, P-values, and clinical interpretation for each TYG-BMI range and database combination.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM2_ESM.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 2: Figure S1. COVID-19 sensitivity analysis of the TYG-BMI–time–mortality relationship in the MIMIC-IV database. (A) Three-dimensional surface plot and (B) odds ratio deviation heatmap generated from a random 80% subsample of MIMIC-IV patients, simulating the exclusion of patients admitted after 2020, to evaluate the potential influence of the COVID-19 pandemic on the primary findings.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM3_ESM.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 3: Figure S2. Calendar period stratification sensitivity analysis (Pre-2015 vs. Post-2015) of the TYG-BMI–time–mortality relationship. Three-dimensional surface plots are shown for (A) Pre-2015 and (B) Post-2015 periods, and corresponding odds ratio deviation heatmaps are presented for (C) Pre-2015 and (D) Post-2015 periods. Data from all three databases were pooled and stratified by calendar period to assess the stability of the TYG-BMI–mortality association before and after the widespread adoption of SGLT2 inhibitors.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM4_ESM.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 4: Figure S3. Stepwise covariate adjustment sensitivity analysis of the TYG-BMI–time–mortality relationship in the MIMIC-IV database. Three-dimensional surface plots are shown for four progressively adjusted models: (A) Model 1, adjusted for age and gender; (B) Model 2, additionally adjusted for SOFA score and Charlson comorbidity index; (C) Model 3, additionally adjusted for insulin use, vasopressor use, and mechanical ventilation; and (D) Model 4, additionally adjusted for albumin, creatinine, and white blood cell count. This analysis evaluates the robustness of the TYG-BMI × time interaction effect after incorporating time-varying treatment and disease severity variables.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM5_ESM.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 5: Figure S4. Insulin use stratification sensitivity analysis of the TYG-BMI–time–mortality relationship in the MIMIC-IV database. Three-dimensional surface plots are shown for (A) insulin users and (B) non-insulin users, and corresponding odds ratio deviation heatmaps are presented for (C) insulin users and (D) non-insulin users. Stratification was based on insulin administration status on the first day of ICU admission (Day 0) to evaluate the effect modification of glucose-lowering therapy on the TYG-BMI–mortality association.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12933_2026_3139_MOESM6_ESM.tif" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 6: Figure S5. Receiver operating characteristic curves comparing the discriminative performance of TYG-BMI and SOFA score for predicting hospital mortality in the MIMIC-IV database at Day 0. Three models are compared: SOFA score alone, TYG-BMI alone, and the combined SOFA + TYG-BMI model, all adjusted for age and gender. The area under the curve (AUC) with 95% confidence intervals is annotated in the legend, and the DeLong test was used to compare the statistical significance of differences in AUC between models.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>AIC</term><def><p id="Par7">Akaike information criterion</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>APACHE II</term><def><p id="Par8">Acute physiology and chronic health evaluation II</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>AUC</term><def><p id="Par9">Area under the receiver operating characteristic curve</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>BMI</term><def><p id="Par10">Body mass index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>BUN</term><def><p id="Par11">Blood urea nitrogen</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CI</term><def><p id="Par12">Confidence interval</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>eICU</term><def><p id="Par13">EICU collaborative research database</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>FDR</term><def><p id="Par14">False discovery rate</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GAM</term><def><p id="Par15">Generalized additive model</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GNRI</term><def><p id="Par16">Geriatric nutritional risk index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>HF</term><def><p id="Par17">Heart failure</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>HFpEF</term><def><p id="Par18">Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ICD</term><def><p id="Par19">International classification of diseases</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ICU</term><def><p id="Par20">Intensive care unit</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>IR</term><def><p id="Par21">Insulin resistance</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>IQR</term><def><p id="Par22">Interquartile range</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>MIMIC</term><def><p id="Par23">Medical information mart for intensive care</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>OASIS</term><def><p id="Par24">Oxford acute severity of illness score</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>OR</term><def><p id="Par25">Odds ratio</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PNI</term><def><p id="Par26">Prognostic nutritional index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RCS</term><def><p id="Par27">Restricted cubic spline</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ROC</term><def><p id="Par28">Receiver operating characteristic</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SAPS II</term><def><p id="Par29">Simplified acute physiology score II</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SD</term><def><p id="Par30">Standard deviation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SGLT2i</term><def><p id="Par31">Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SMD</term><def><p id="Par32">Standardized mean difference</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SOFA</term><def><p id="Par33">Sequential organ failure assessment</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SpO₂</term><def><p id="Par34">Peripheral oxygen saturation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>STROBE</term><def><p id="Par35">Strengthening of the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TyG</term><def><p id="Par36">Triglyceride-glucose</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TYG-BMI</term><def><p id="Par37">Triglyceride-glucose-body mass index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>WBC</term><def><p id="Par38">White blood cell</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn><fn><p>Shuang Liu and Yuzhou Cai have contributed equally to this study.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We gratefully acknowledge the Laboratory for Computational Physiology at MIT and the PhysioNet team for providing access to the MIMIC-III, MIMIC-IV, and eICU databases.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>Shuang Liu (SL) and Yuzhou Cai (YC) contributed equally to this work. SL and YC conceived and designed the study, acquired and analyzed the data, and drafted the manuscript. Chengmin Shi (CS) contributed to statistical analysis and interpretation of the results. Tong Zhang (TZ) contributed to study supervision and critical revision of the manuscript. Yujian Zeng (YZ) supervised the study. Yuzhou Cai (YC) finalized the manuscript. All authors read and approved of the final manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This study was funded by the Yunnan Province High-level Talent Cultivation Support Program “Famous Doctor Special” (No. RLMY20200021).</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets analyzed in this study are publicly available through PhysioNet (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://physionet.org/">https://physionet.org/</ext-link>) upon completion of required training and credentialing.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1"><title>Ethics and consent to participate</title><p id="Par98">This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and adhered to the ethical guidelines for secondary analysis of de-identified public datasets. This study utilized four publicly available critical care databases: MIMIC-III CareVue, MIMIC-IV, and eICU Collaborative Research Database, all accessed through PhysioNet. These databases contain de-identified health information that was collected under appropriate Institutional Review Board (IRB) approval. The use of these databases for research purposes has been approved by the Institutional Review Boards of Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (Boston, MA, USA) and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Cambridge, MA, USA). As this study involved only retrospective analysis of de-identified data from publicly available sources, no additional ethical approval was required. All investigators completed the CITI Data or Specimens Only Research training required by PhysioNet and signed data use agreements prior to accessing the databases. Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par99">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par100">The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Knaus</surname><given-names>WA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Draper</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zimmerman</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>APACHE II: a severity of disease classification system</article-title><source>Crit Care Med</source><year>1985</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>818</fpage><lpage>829</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00003246-198510000-00009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3928249</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Knaus WA, Draper EA, Wagner DP, Zimmerman JE. APACHE II: a severity of disease classification system. Crit Care Med. 1985;13:818–29.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3928249</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Le Gall</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemeshow</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Saulnier</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A new simplified acute physiology score (SAPS II) based on a European/North American multicenter study</article-title><source>JAMA</source><year>1993</year><volume>270</volume><fpage>2957</fpage><lpage>2963</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.1993.03510240069035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8254858</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Le Gall JR, Lemeshow S, Saulnier F. A new simplified acute physiology score (SAPS II) based on a European/North American multicenter study. JAMA. 1993;270:2957–63.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8254858</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jama.270.24.2957</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vincent</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The SOFA (sepsis-related organ failure assessment) score to describe organ dysfunction/failure: on behalf of the working group on sepsis-related problems of the european society of intensive care medicine (see contributors to the project in the appendix)</article-title><source>Intens Care Med</source><year>1996</year><volume>22</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>707</fpage><lpage>710</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01709751</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8844239</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Vincent JL, et al. The SOFA (sepsis-related organ failure assessment) score to describe organ dysfunction/failure: on behalf of the working group on sepsis-related problems of the european society of intensive care medicine (see contributors to the project in the appendix). Intens Care Med. 1996;22(7):707–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/BF01709751</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8844239</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nayak</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Diagnostic and prognostic value of triglyceride glucose index: a comprehensive evaluation of meta-analysis</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>310</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02392-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39180024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11344391</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Nayak SS, et al. Diagnostic and prognostic value of triglyceride glucose index: a comprehensive evaluation of meta-analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:310.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39180024</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02392-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11344391</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ni</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between insulin resistance indices and outcomes in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>32</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02595-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39844150</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11755915</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Ni W, et al. Association between insulin resistance indices and outcomes in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:32.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39844150</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02595-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11755915</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J-H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J-W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Trajectories of triglyceride-glucose index changes and their association with all-cause and cardiovascular mortality: a competing risk analysis</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>364</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02457-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39407266</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11481394</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Lee J-H, Jeon S, Lee HS, Lee J-W. Trajectories of triglyceride-glucose index changes and their association with all-cause and cardiovascular mortality: a competing risk analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:364.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39407266</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02457-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11481394</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Association between dynamic changes in the triglyceride-glucose index and prognosis in patients with acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>357</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02858-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40890781</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12403548</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Jia H, Zhang W, Jia S, Jia X, Kang S. Association between dynamic changes in the triglyceride-glucose index and prognosis in patients with acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:357.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40890781</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02858-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12403548</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association of triglyceride-glucose index trajectories with the risk of worsening heart failure in elderly patients with chronic heart failure and type 2 diabetes: a competing risk analysis</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>131</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02687-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40119388</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11929357</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Lai Y, et al. Association of triglyceride-glucose index trajectories with the risk of worsening heart failure in elderly patients with chronic heart failure and type 2 diabetes: a competing risk analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:131.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40119388</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02687-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11929357</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>El-Sheikh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Associations of obesity and prognostic nutritional index on 1-year mortality in patients with acute heart failure</article-title><source>Card Fail Rev</source><year>2025</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>e03</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.15420/cfr.2024.35</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40083652</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11904423</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">El-Sheikh M, et al. Associations of obesity and prognostic nutritional index on 1-year mortality in patients with acute heart failure. Card Fail Rev. 2025;11:e03.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40083652</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15420/cfr.2024.35</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11904423</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>El-Sheikh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prevalence and prognostic significance of malnutrition assessed by two scoring systems in hospitalised elderly patients with chronic heart failure</article-title><source>Card Fail Rev</source><year>2025</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>e26</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.15420/cfr.2025.31</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41211200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12590399</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">El-Sheikh M, et al. Prevalence and prognostic significance of malnutrition assessed by two scoring systems in hospitalised elderly patients with chronic heart failure. Card Fail Rev. 2025;11:e26.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41211200</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15420/cfr.2025.31</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12590399</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>AEW</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>MIMIC-III, a freely accessible critical care database</article-title><source>Sci Data</source><year>2016</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>160035</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/sdata.2016.35</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27219127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4878278</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Johnson AEW, et al. MIMIC-III, a freely accessible critical care database. Sci Data. 2016;3:160035.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27219127</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/sdata.2016.35</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4878278</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>AEW</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>MIMIC-IV, a freely accessible electronic health record dataset</article-title><source>Sci Data</source><year>2023</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41597-022-01899-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36596836</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9810617</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Johnson AEW, et al. MIMIC-IV, a freely accessible electronic health record dataset. Sci Data. 2023;10:1.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36596836</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41597-022-01899-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9810617</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pollard</surname><given-names>TJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The eICU collaborative research database, a freely available multi-center database for critical care research</article-title><source>Sci Data</source><year>2018</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>180178</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/sdata.2018.178</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30204154</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6132188</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Pollard TJ, et al. The eICU collaborative research database, a freely available multi-center database for critical care research. Sci Data. 2018;5:180178.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30204154</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/sdata.2018.178</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6132188</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fonarow</surname><given-names>GC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Risk stratification for in-hospital mortality in acutely decompensated heart failure: classification and regression tree analysis</article-title><source>JAMA</source><year>2005</year><volume>293</volume><fpage>572</fpage><lpage>580</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.293.5.572</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15687312</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Fonarow GC, et al. Risk stratification for in-hospital mortality in acutely decompensated heart failure: classification and regression tree analysis. JAMA. 2005;293:572–80.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15687312</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jama.293.5.572</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>PN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A validated risk score for in-hospital mortality in patients with heart failure from the American Heart Association get with the guidelines program</article-title><source>Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes</source><year>2010</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>25</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.109.854877</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20123668</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Peterson PN, et al. A validated risk score for in-hospital mortality in patients with heart failure from the American Heart Association get with the guidelines program. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2010;3:25–32.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20123668</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.109.854877</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lyle</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Predictive value of the get with the guidelines heart failure risk score in unselected cardiac intensive care unit patients</article-title><source>J Am Heart Assoc</source><year>2020</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>e012439</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1161/JAHA.119.012439</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31986993</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7033864</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Lyle M, et al. Predictive value of the get with the guidelines heart failure risk score in unselected cardiac intensive care unit patients. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:e012439.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31986993</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1161/JAHA.119.012439</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7033864</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vincent</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Use of the SOFA score to assess the incidence of organ dysfunction/failure in intensive care units: results of a multicenter, prospective study</article-title><source>Critical Care Med</source><year>1998</year><volume>26</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1793</fpage><lpage>1800</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00003246-199811000-00016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9824069</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Vincent JL, et al. Use of the SOFA score to assess the incidence of organ dysfunction/failure in intensive care units: results of a multicenter, prospective study. Critical Care Med. 1998;26(11):1793–800.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9824069</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00003246-199811000-00016</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Sepsis subphenotyping based on organ dysfunction trajectory</article-title><source>Crit Care</source><year>2022</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>197</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13054-022-04071-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35786445</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9250715</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Xu Z, et al. Sepsis subphenotyping based on organ dysfunction trajectory. Crit Care. 2022;26:197.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35786445</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13054-022-04071-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9250715</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dou</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between triglyceride glucose-body mass and one-year all-cause mortality of patients with heart failure: a retrospective study utilizing the MIMIC-IV database</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2023</year><volume>22</volume><fpage>309</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-02047-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37940979</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10634170</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Dou J, et al. Association between triglyceride glucose-body mass and one-year all-cause mortality of patients with heart failure: a retrospective study utilizing the MIMIC-IV database. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22:309.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37940979</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-023-02047-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10634170</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Comparative study on the predictive value of TG/HDL-C, TyG and TyG-BMI indices for 5-year mortality in critically ill patients with chronic heart failure: a retrospective study</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>213</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02308-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38902757</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11191322</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Zhou Z, et al. Comparative study on the predictive value of TG/HDL-C, TyG and TyG-BMI indices for 5-year mortality in critically ill patients with chronic heart failure: a retrospective study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:213.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38902757</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02308-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11191322</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lyu</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between triglyceride glucose-body mass index and long-term adverse outcomes of heart failure patients with coronary heart disease</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>162</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02213-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38724999</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11080126</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Lyu L, et al. Association between triglyceride glucose-body mass index and long-term adverse outcomes of heart failure patients with coronary heart disease. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:162.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38724999</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02213-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11080126</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vale</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>da Andrade</surname><given-names>MEC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dantas</surname><given-names>NM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Adherence to multiple recommendations of the dietary guidelines for the Brazilian population (Guia Alimentar para a População Brasileira) and associated factors among adolescents: a cross-sectional study with data from the National Students’ Health Survey, 2019</article-title><source>Epidemiol E Serv Saude Rev Sist Unico Saude Bras</source><year>2025</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>e20240404</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/S2237-96222025v34e20240404.en</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12176437</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40531713</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Vale D, da Andrade MEC, Dantas NM. Adherence to multiple recommendations of the dietary guidelines for the Brazilian population (Guia Alimentar para a População Brasileira) and associated factors among adolescents: a cross-sectional study with data from the National Students’ Health Survey, 2019. Epidemiol E Serv Saude Rev Sist Unico Saude Bras. 2025;34:e20240404.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/S2237-96222025v34e20240404.en</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12176437</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40531713</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between triglyceride-glucose index and in-hospital mortality in critically ill patients with sepsis: analysis of the MIMIC-IV database</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2023</year><volume>22</volume><fpage>307</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-02041-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37940931</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10634031</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Zheng R, et al. Association between triglyceride-glucose index and in-hospital mortality in critically ill patients with sepsis: analysis of the MIMIC-IV database. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22:307.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37940931</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-023-02041-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10634031</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between triglyceride-glucose index and mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective cohort study</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>138</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02697-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40128768</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11934460</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Ding R, et al. Association between triglyceride-glucose index and mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:138.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40128768</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02697-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11934460</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The association between triglyceride glucose-body mass index and all-cause mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective study from MIMIC-IV database</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>64</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02153-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38341579</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10859027</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Hu Y, Zhao Y, Zhang J, Li C. The association between triglyceride glucose-body mass index and all-cause mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective study from MIMIC-IV database. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:64.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38341579</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02153-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10859027</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ling</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Association between trajectory of triglyceride-glucose index and all-cause mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective cohort study</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>278</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02838-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40640797</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12243274</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Shi S, Xue F, Jiang T, Ling L. Association between trajectory of triglyceride-glucose index and all-cause mortality in critically ill patients with atrial fibrillation: a retrospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:278.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40640797</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02838-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12243274</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between triglyceride-glucose index and all cause mortality in critically ill patients with heart failure</article-title><source>Sci Rep</source><year>2025</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>16157</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-00129-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40346064</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12064809</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Xiao J, et al. Association between triglyceride-glucose index and all cause mortality in critically ill patients with heart failure. Sci Rep. 2025;15:16157.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40346064</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41598-025-00129-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12064809</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR28" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sánchez-García</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Diagnostic accuracy of the triglyceride and glucose index for insulin resistance: a systematic review</article-title><source>Int J Endocrinol</source><year>2020</year><volume>2020</volume><fpage>4678526</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2020/4678526</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32256572</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7085845</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR28" publication-type="journal">Sánchez-García A, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of the triglyceride and glucose index for insulin resistance: a systematic review. Int J Endocrinol. 2020;2020:4678526.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32256572</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2020/4678526</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7085845</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>D’Elia</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Is the triglyceride-glucose index ready for cardiovascular risk assessment?</article-title><source>Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis NMCD</source><year>2025</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>103834</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2024.103834</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39939250</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">D’Elia L. Is the triglyceride-glucose index ready for cardiovascular risk assessment? Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis NMCD. 2025;35:103834.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39939250</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.numecd.2024.103834</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR30" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lecerf</surname><given-names>J-M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>L’index triglycéride-glucose, un marqueur de risque cardio-métabolique performant</article-title><source>Médecine Mal Métaboliques</source><year>2025</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>320</fpage><lpage>323</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mmm.2025.04.016</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR30" publication-type="journal">Lecerf J-M. L’index triglycéride-glucose, un marqueur de risque cardio-métabolique performant. Médecine Mal Métaboliques. 2025;19:320–3.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR31" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Esdaile</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The association between the stress hyperglycaemia ratio and mortality in cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2024</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>412</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02454-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39550575</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11568630</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR31" publication-type="journal">Esdaile H, et al. The association between the stress hyperglycaemia ratio and mortality in cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:412.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39550575</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-024-02454-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11568630</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR32" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Prognostic value of glycaemic variability for mortality in cardiogenic shock patients: a retrospective cohort study</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>392</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02947-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41074054</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12512319</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR32" publication-type="journal">Xie L, Luo S. Prognostic value of glycaemic variability for mortality in cardiogenic shock patients: a retrospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:392.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41074054</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02947-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12512319</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR33" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Meddeb</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldenberg</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jenkin</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hahn</surname><given-names>VS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Metabolic reprogramming in heart failure: from energy starvation to therapeutic targets</article-title><source>Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med</source><year>2025</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>65</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11936-025-01121-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41070244</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12504350</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR33" publication-type="journal">Meddeb M, Goldenberg JR, Jenkin SC, Hahn VS. Metabolic reprogramming in heart failure: from energy starvation to therapeutic targets. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2025;27:65.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41070244</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11936-025-01121-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12504350</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR34" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The association between TyG index and cardiovascular mortality is modified by antidiabetic or lipid-lowering agent: a prospective cohort study</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>65</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02620-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39920712</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11806668</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR34" publication-type="journal">Fang C, et al. The association between TyG index and cardiovascular mortality is modified by antidiabetic or lipid-lowering agent: a prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:65.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39920712</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02620-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11806668</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR35" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pagnesi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Impact of malnutrition in patients with severe heart failure</article-title><source>Eur J Heart Fail</source><year>2024</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>1585</fpage><lpage>1593</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ejhf.3285</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38808603</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR35" publication-type="journal">Pagnesi M, et al. Impact of malnutrition in patients with severe heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2024;26:1585–93.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38808603</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/ejhf.3285</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR36" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Association between cardiac cachexia and adverse outcomes in patients with heart failure: a meta-analysis of cohort studies</article-title><source>Heart</source><year>2025</year><volume>111</volume><fpage>952</fpage><lpage>959</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2024-325431</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40089313</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR36" publication-type="journal">Liu B, Wu X, Wang Y, Hu X. Association between cardiac cachexia and adverse outcomes in patients with heart failure: a meta-analysis of cohort studies. Heart. 2025;111:952–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40089313</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/heartjnl-2024-325431</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR37" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Prokopidis</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prognostic impact and prevalence of cachexia in patients with heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</source><year>2024</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>2536</fpage><lpage>2543</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13596</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39478303</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11634528</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR37" publication-type="journal">Prokopidis K, et al. Prognostic impact and prevalence of cachexia in patients with heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2024;15:2536–43.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39478303</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/jcsm.13596</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11634528</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR38" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Szinte</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Parikh</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Frishman</surname><given-names>WH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cardiac cachexia: a comprehensive review</article-title><source>Cardiol Rev</source><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001008</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40754663</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR38" publication-type="journal">Szinte JS, Parikh MA, Frishman WH, Peterson SJ. Cardiac cachexia: a comprehensive review. Cardiol Rev. 2025. 10.1097/CRD.0000000000001008.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40754663</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001008</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR39" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hofmaenner</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between hypocholesterolemia and mortality in critically ill patients with sepsis: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Crit Care Explor</source><year>2023</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>e0860</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36751516</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/CCE.0000000000000860</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9894355</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR39" publication-type="journal">Hofmaenner DA, et al. Association between hypocholesterolemia and mortality in critically ill patients with sepsis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care Explor. 2023;5:e0860.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36751516</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/CCE.0000000000000860</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9894355</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR40" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>Nice-Sugar Study Investigators</collab></person-group><article-title>Intensive versus conventional glucose control in critically ill patients</article-title><source>New England J Med</source><year>2009</year><volume>360</volume><issue>13</issue><fpage>1283</fpage><lpage>1297</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0810625</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19318384</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR40" publication-type="journal">Nice-Sugar Study Investigators. Intensive versus conventional glucose control in critically ill patients. New England J Med. 2009;360(13):1283–97.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19318384</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1056/NEJMoa0810625</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR41" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Does diabetes modify the triglyceride-glucose index associated with cardiovascular events and mortality? A meta-analysis of 50 cohorts involving 7,239,790 participants</article-title><source>Cardiovasc Diabetol</source><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>42</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02585-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39871273</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11773825</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR41" publication-type="journal">Zhang J, et al. Does diabetes modify the triglyceride-glucose index associated with cardiovascular events and mortality? A meta-analysis of 50 cohorts involving 7,239,790 participants. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24:42.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39871273</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12933-025-02585-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11773825</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>