<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Strength Cond Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Strength Cond Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2035</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">lwwopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jscr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1064-8011</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1533-4287</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Lippincott Open Access</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13007903</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13007903.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13007903</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13007903</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41359925</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005349</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">JSCR-08-22994</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf" article-version-type="Version of Record">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Normative Data for Physical Activity and Heart Rate Metrics of Recreational Football Among the General Male Population—The Football Cooperative Initiative</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5949-2116</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Everard</surname><given-names initials="E">Eoin</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><email>eoin.everard@setu.ie</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carroll</surname><given-names initials="P">Paula</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><email>paula.carroll@setu.ie</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Doherty</surname><given-names initials="S">Sarah</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><email>dohertysarah12@gmail.com</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names initials="M">Michael</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><email>michael.harrison@setu.ie</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names initials="P">Peter</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">2</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">3</xref><email>pkrustrup@health.sdu.dk</email></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>1</label>Center for Health Behaviour Research, South East Technological University, Waterford, <country>Ireland</country>;</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>2</label>Department of Sports Science and Clinical Biomechanics, Sport and Health Sciences Cluster (SHSC), Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Denmark, Odense, <country>Denmark</country>; and</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>3</label>Danish Institute for Advanced Study (DIAS), University of Southern Denmark, Odense, <country>Denmark</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp>Address correspondence to Eoin Everard, <email>eoin.everard@setu.ie</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>4</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>5</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>40</volume><issue>4</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">509991</issue-id><fpage>e366</fpage><lpage>e372</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>24</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-03-24 11:25:12.460"><day>24</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright © 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the National Strength and Conditioning Association.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND)</ext-link>, where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="jscr-40-e366.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jscr-40-e366.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><p>Everard, E, Carroll, P, Doherty, S, Harrison, M, and Krustrup, P. Normative data for physical activity and heart rate metrics of recreational football among the general male population—the Football Cooperative initiative. <italic toggle="yes">J Strength Cond Res</italic> 40(4): e366–e372, 2026—Owing to established benefits associated with recreational football, there has been increased focus on developing the concept of Football is Medicine. This is leading to the development of more formalized and larger scale recreational football initiatives in general populations, such as the Football Cooperative (FC) in Ireland. The aim of this study was to determine the physical activity and heart rate (HR) metrics of FC games and to compare these metrics between the 2 FC game sites. One hundred two men (age: 37.4 ± 8.5 years, height: 176.2 ± 18.2 cm, body mass: 90.6 ± 21.5 kg) volunteered for this study. The games were 9 vs. 9 and 30 minutes per half on an astroturf pitch (36.5 × 27.5 m). Global Positioning Systems and chest-strap HR monitors were used to measure physical activity and HR metrics, respectively. Subjects ran an average of 6,632 m with 32 accelerations per session. Furthermore, subjects had a HR<sub>mean</sub> of 77% of their peak HR achieved during matches (Match-HRpeak) and played 81% of the time above 70% Match-HRpeak, 52% above 80% Match-HRpeak, and 23% above 90% Match-HRpeak. Despite a mean age difference of 10 years between the 2 sites, the only significant physical activity differences between sites were maximum speed and high-speed running. This was the first study to provide normative data for HR and physical activity metrics related to a 9 vs. 9 recreational football initiative. The results show recreational football provides a training stimulus in relation to HR metrics and distances covered that is to the upper ranges of recommended exercise guidelines.</p></abstract><kwd-group><title>Key Words</title><kwd>GPS</kwd><kwd>heart rate monitoring</kwd><kwd>health promotion</kwd><kwd>soccer metrics</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>The benefits of physical training and physical fitness are now well established in the literature (<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>). Physical training has been widely reported to improve a range of lifestyle-related diseases, such as type 2 diabetes (<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>), obesity (<xref rid="R45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>), hypertension (<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>), and osteoporosis (<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Conventional physical training studies in sedentary populations have focused predominantly on aerobic exercise, such as walking, jogging, running, or cycling (<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>). Other studies have examined strength training as a method of improving muscular endurance, strength, and power (<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>). Most of these studies have reported that engaging in aerobic or strengthening activities improves physical fitness and has a corresponding positive impact on health (<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>,<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>,<xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>). However, there is a segment of the population that is reluctant to engage in traditional forms of individual exercise (<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>). Therefore, other alternative interventions need to be examined that may elicit similar benefits to physical fitness (<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>).</p><p>For more than a decade there has been an increasing focus on recreational football as an alternative form of physical activity to individual exercise (<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>). In their meta-analysis, Milanović et al. (<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>) reported that untrained males experienced an 8–13% improvement in V̇<sc>o</sc><sub>2</sub>max after 12 weeks of recreational football. A 12-week intervention involving a general male population compared the effects of recreational football, resistance training, and a jogging/interval running program on lean body mass (<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>). The study reported that recreational football resulted in a 15% increase in lean body mass, which was similar to gains reported with resistance training and significantly greater than subjects undertaking the jogging/interval running program (<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>). Furthermore, other studies have reported that 12 weeks of recreational football improved thigh bone mass and bone mineral density (<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>).</p><p>Owing to the established benefits associated with recreational football, there has been increased focus on developing the concept of Football is Medicine as part of the larger remit of Exercise is Medicine (<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>). This growing recognition has contributed to the emergence of more structured and large-scale recreational football initiatives targeting the general population (<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>). One such initiative is the Football Cooperative (FC), a recreational football program for adult men, currently hosted at 2 sites in Ireland. The FC has more than 400 registered subjects and is planning to expand throughout the country by 2028 (<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). The FC initiative is similar to other initiatives, such as Football Fitness, Football for Life, and others that operate in Denmark, the Faroe Islands, Norway, Portugal, Italy, and the United States (<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>).</p><p>It is essential to establish a robust evidence base for these initiatives before larger scale roll out (<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). To date, growing evidence shows that the FC effectively engages men at risk of cardiovascular disease (<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>), improves key health metrics and reduces cardiovascular risk (<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>), and generates a social return of €17.60 for every €1 invested (<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>).</p><p>Although the research related to the FC initiative is promising, there remains gaps in the evidence base. One major limitation in the evidence base is that the physical activity metrics (distance covered, number of sprints, high-speed running [HSR] meters) and HR metrics (Match-HRpeak, HR<sub>mean,</sub> HR zones) of these matches have not been fully investigated.</p><p>Global Positioning Systems (GPS) are commonly used for recording physical activity metrics, while HR monitors are commonly used to assess cardiovascular load (<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). Only a limited number of studies have used GPS or HR monitoring in recreational football settings, primarily involving either collegiate populations (<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>) or general populations (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>–<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>), typically with small sample sizes ranging from 10 to 12 subjects. Although previous studies have provided important insights into variations in physical activity and cardiovascular demands across different game formats (team and pitch size) (<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>–<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>), there is a need for large-scale research to establish normative data for recreational football in general male populations.</p><p>The aim of this study was, therefore, to determine the physical activity, and HR metrics of the general male population playing FC recreational football. A secondary aim was to investigate any differences in physical activity and HR metrics between the 2 FC sites, thereby providing preliminary insights into the reproducibility of these metrics across separate locations.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods" id="s2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="s2-1"><title>Experimental Approach to the Problem</title><p>The study was designed to provide normative data for physical activity and HR metrics of a recreational football initiative in a general male population. An a priori power calculation indicated that 40 subjects would provide sufficient power (80% power, alpha &lt; 0.05), therefore, the inclusion of 102 subjects strengthens the normative data set and enhances the precision of reference values. For the secondary aim, the independent variable for this analysis was the sites and the dependent variables were all the physical activity metrics (maximal speed, Total Distance [TD], distance per minute, HSR, number of accelerations, decelerations, and number of sprints) and HR metrics (Match-HRpeak, HR<sub>mean</sub>, HR zones).</p></sec><sec id="s2-2"><title>Subjects</title><p>In total, 102 men (age: 37.4 ± 8.5 years, height: 176.2 ± 18.2 cm, body mass: 90.6 ± 21.5 kg) volunteered to participate in the study and provided written informed consent. All registered FC members who were able to understand English (written and spoken), were 18 years or older, and passed the Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire were eligible for inclusion. Similar to criteria set out (<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>), subjects were excluded from the study if they had sustained an injury that restricted them from training or playing in the previous 30 days or had recent surgery that limited athletic participation. This was undertaken to limit the influence that a recent injury may have on physical activity data obtained (<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>).</p><p>Recruitment occurred through the FC gatekeeper through their WhatsApp group and email database a week before data collection. All subjects were informed of the study procedures, benefits, and risks involved in participation. This study was approved by the institutional research ethics committee, and confirmed by South East Technological University Waterford (SETU2023REC0024) and all procedures followed the Declaration of Helsinki guidelines.</p></sec><sec id="s2-3"><title>Procedures</title><sec id="s2-3-1"><title>Experimental Design</title><p>The FC games consisted of 60-minute matches, played in two 30-minute halves, with a 5-minute half time break. Each match involved 9 vs. 9 subjects on an astroturf pitch (36.5 × 27.5 m) (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>), which corresponds to a pitch area of 56 m<sup>2</sup> per player. Data collected outside of game time were excluded from data analysis (<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). All subjects played the entire 60-minute games as there were no substitutes, however, there were rotating goalkeepers, where players went into goal for approximately 6-minute spells. This time in goal was included in the analysis.</p><p>To avoid any effect of circadian rhythm on the measured variables, all data collection sessions took place between 20:45 and 22:30 hours (<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). Data were collected for a 6-week period on 4 occasions at site 1 (March‒April 2024) and 5 occasions at site 2 (May‒June 2024) with a minimum of 48 hours between each session as according to Randers et al. (<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>). For subjects who wore GPS units on multiple occasions, mean values for all physical activity and HR metrics were calculated to ensure consistency in the data analysis. This provided each subject with 1 score for each of the variables examined, regardless of how many nights they had attended.</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-2"><title>Anthropometric Data</title><p>Anthropometric measures comprised height (cm) using a SECA 213 portable stadiometer (SECA, Hamburg, Germany) and body mass (kg) and computed body mass index (kg·m<sup>−2</sup>) using a SECA 875 digital scales (SECA), which were administered using standard protocols.</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-3"><title>Physical Activity Data</title><p>Activity during games was recorded through GPS tracking; specifically, subjects wore GPS units (StatSports, Louth, Ireland) with a 10-Hz sample rate to measure their movements (<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Each GPS unit was numbered, and the participant–device pairing was recorded. Subjects who participated in multiple sessions were assigned the same GPS unit first whenever possible before fitting new subjects (<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Global Positioning System was chosen for this study because it has been previously determined as reliable (Intraclass Correlation Coefficient: 0.96; Coefficient of Variation: &lt;5%) (Beato et al., 2018) and valid for assessing physical activity demands in sports (<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>).</p><p>Similar to previous studies, this study recorded maximal speed, TD, distance per minute, HSR (defined as speeds between 5.5 and 7 m·s<sup>−1</sup>), number of accelerations and decelerations (increases and decreases of &gt;3 m·s<sup>−1</sup>, respectively, from current speed), and number of sprints (speed greater than 7 m·s<sup>−1</sup>) (<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>). Furthermore, to aid interpretation, total distances covered were categorized into 1,000-meter intervals (0–999 m, 1,000–1,999 m, etc). These categorical groups were included to illustrate the distribution of distances covered across subjects. All metrics were recorded in meters (m) and seconds (s).</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-4"><title>Heart Rate Data</title><p>The HR metrics when playing were recorded by HR monitors (Polar H10 model, Polar Electro, Kempele, Finland) that were placed directly on the skin around the chest of subjects (<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). Players who wore a HR monitor on multiple occasions wore the same monitor (<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). Heart rate was captured at 1-second intervals and HR was reported as maximum HR achieved during the football matches (Match-HRpeak) and mean HR achieved (HR<sub>mean</sub>) (<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>). In addition to Match-HRpeak and HR<sub>mean</sub>, 4 HR zones were calculated: ≤70% Match-HRpeak (Z1), 71–80% Match-HRpeak (Z2), 81–90% Match-HRpeak (Z3), and 91–100% Match-HRpeak (Z4). These zones were similar to previous research (<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>), however, Cvetković et al. (<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>) used Max HR achieved during a maximal incremental fitness test, whereas in this study, we based maximum HR on the highest HR achieved during the matches.</p><p>All HR data were stored by the Polar Team Pro HR monitors and transferred to a Dell Latitude 5,440 Laptop using the Polar Pro Team dock (Polar Electro, Kempele, Finland). All HR metrics are expressed as beats per minute (b·min<sup>−1</sup>).</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-5"><title>Data Processing</title><p>The raw GPS and HR data from the individual units were initially uploaded to Sonra Software (StatSport, Louth, Ireland). Data were then exported to Microsoft Excel (v15.0; Microsoft Corporation; Redmond, WA) before analysis.</p></sec><sec id="s2-3-6"><title>Data Analysis</title><p>SPSS Version 27 (SPSS Inc., Chicago, IL) was used for all statistical analysis. Data were analyzed using descriptive statistics, with all variables reported as mean ± <italic toggle="yes">SD.</italic> Using a Shapiro–Wilk's test, assumptions of normality were verified before parametric statistical analyses were used.</p><p>Two main statistical analyses were performed in this study. First, descriptive statistics were calculated for all chosen variables (TD, HSR distance, accelerations, decelerations, total number of sprints, Match-HRpeak, HR<sub>mean</sub>, and time spent in each HR zone) for all subjects regardless of site. The second analysis involved examining any potential differences between the 2 playing sites for all physical activity and HR metrics. A series of independent <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-tests for each variable was used for this analysis, with Bonferroni adjustments applied to account for multiple comparisons (<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). The significance level was set at <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> ≤ 0.05 for all tests. A Cohen's <italic toggle="yes">d</italic> effect size analysis was completed as described by Hopkins et al. (<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>), where a mean difference of between 0 and 0.29 was small, 0.30 and 0.49 moderate, 0.5 and 0.79 as large, and greater than 0.8 was very large (<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). This was conducted to provide preliminary insights into the reproducibility of physical activity and HR metrics of the 2 sites.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="s3"><title>Results</title><p>A total of 183 complete data sets were collected across 9 sessions from 102 recreational male footballers. Of these, 45 subjects completed 1 session (25 from site 1, 20 from site 2), 39 completed 2 sessions (24 from site 1, 15 from site 2), 9 completed 3 sessions (6 from site 1, 3 from site 2), and 9 completed 4 sessions (4 from site 1, 5 from site 2). Demographic comparisons revealed significant differences between sites (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>), with subjects at site 2 being on average 10 years younger (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01; ES 1.52) and 6 kg heavier (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> 0.012; ES 0.51) than those at site 1.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Age and anthropometric data of the whole cohort and 2 individual sites.<xref rid="tblfn1" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Variable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total cohort (102)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 1 (59)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 2 (43)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean difference (95% CI)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Effect size</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36.5 ± 8.6</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32.1 ± 7.4</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42.5 ± 6.2</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−10.5 (−13.2 to −7.7)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.01</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.52</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Height (cm)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">179.0 ± 18.2</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">178.7 ± 12.2</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">179.2 ± 5.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.5 (−5.2 to 4.3)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.42</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.05</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Body mass(kg)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 ± 21.5</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.2 ± 13.0</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">83.9 ± 11.8</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.3 (1.4 to 11.3)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.01</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.51</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMI (kg·m<sup>−2</sup>)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27.0 ± 3.9</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27.7 ± 14.5</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26.1 ± 3.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.6 (0.7 to 3.1)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.02</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.15</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn1"><label>*</label><p>CI = confidence interval; BMI = body mass index.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><sec id="s3-1"><title>Activity Demands</title><p>The mean distance covered in each session across both sites was 6,632 322,369 m. Furthermore, the stratification of distance covered by subjects ranged from less than 3,000 m to greater than 12,000 m (Figure <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). On average, subjects completed 437.5 ± 598.2 m of HSR and performed 32.5 ± 18.1 accelerations per session.</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Stratification of subjects by distance covered.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jscr-40-e366-g001.jpg"/></fig><p>There were significant differences in HSR and maximum speed between the 2 sites, with site 1 covering 471 m of HSR more than site 2 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> ≤ 0.01; ES = 0.91) and running at 0.66 m·s<sup>−1</sup> faster on average than the cohort at site 2 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> ≤ 0.01; ES = 0.47). There were no other significant differences between the groups for any other physical activity variable (Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Physical activity demands of the whole cohort and 2 individual sites.<xref rid="tblfn2" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Performance variable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total cohort</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean difference (95% CI)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Effect size</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total distance (m)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6,632 ± 2,369</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6,766 ± 2,970</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6,449 ± 1,118</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">317 (−627 to 1,262)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.14</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.08</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Distance per min (m·min<sup>−1</sup>)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.8 ± 26.8</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">73.7 ± 33.2</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.2 ± 13.8</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.5 (−6.18 to 15.2)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.37</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.22</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">High-speed running<xref rid="tblfn3" ref-type="table-fn">†</xref> (m)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">437.5 ± 598.2</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">636.9 ± 710.6</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">163.9 ± 175.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">473.0 (253.0 to 692.9)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.91</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.01</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Accelerations (n)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32.5 ± 18.1</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31.5 ± 19.0</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.7 ± 16.9</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−2.1 (−9.4 to 5.1)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.13</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.22</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Decelerations (n)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30.7 ± 18.2</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.0 ± 18.4</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.2 ± 17.8</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−4.2 (−11.4 to 3.0)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.23</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.44</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Number of sprints (n)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.1 ± 8.0</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.7 ± 9.1</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.7 ± 6.2</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.9 (−4.1 to 2.26)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.11</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.26</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Max speed<xref rid="tblfn3" ref-type="table-fn">†</xref> (m·s<sup>−1</sup>)</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.2 ± 1.4</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.6 ± 1.7</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.9 ± 0.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.7 (0.11 to 1.2)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.47</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.01</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn2"><label>*</label><p>CI = confidence interval.</p></fn><fn id="tblfn3"><label>†</label><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> value of &lt; 0.01.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="s3-2"><title>Heart Rate Metrics</title><p>Subjects achieved a mean heart rate (HRmean) of 137.5 ± 17 b·min<sup>−1</sup> and a Match-HRpeak of 178.9 ± 13.9 b·min<sup>−1</sup>, with HR<sub>mean</sub> corresponding to 77.2 ± 16% of Match-HRpeak. On average, more than 81% of total playing time (48 minutes 36 seconds) was spent at intensities exceeding 70% of Match-HRpeak. Furthermore, on average subjects spent more than 50% (31 minutes 50 seconds) and 20% (14 minutes 24 seconds) of the match duration, respectively, at intensities at or above 81 and 90% of Match-HRpeak (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Heart rate metrics of the whole group and the 2 individual sites.<xref rid="tblfn4" ref-type="table-fn">*</xref></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Variable</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total Cohort (102)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 1 (59)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Site 2 (43)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mean difference (95% CI)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Effect size</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HR<sub>mean</sub></td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">137.5 ± 17.0</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">138.3 ± 17.6</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">136.5 ± 16.2</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.7 (−3.9 to 8.2)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.14</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.85</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Match-HRpeak</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">178.9 ± 14.9</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">178.7 ± 15.4</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">179.2 ± 14.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.55 (−6.5 to 5.4)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.04</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.60</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">≤70% Match-HRpeak<xref rid="tblfn5" ref-type="table-fn">†</xref></td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18.5 ± 5.3</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17.2 ± 5.5</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.2 ± 4.5</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−3.0 (−4.8 to −1.0)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.59</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.005</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">71–80% Match-HRpeak<xref rid="tblfn5" ref-type="table-fn">†</xref></td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28.5 ± 5.9</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27.1 ± 6.6</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30.4 ± 4.2</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">−3.3 (−5.6 to −1.0)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.59</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.005</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">81–90% Match-HRpeak</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.0 ± 6.6</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.6 ± 7.5</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28.2 ± 5.1</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.3 (−1.3 to 3.9)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.20</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.32</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">91–100% Match-HRpeak<xref rid="tblfn5" ref-type="table-fn">†</xref></td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.0 ± 8.4</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26.5 ± 9.1</td><td align="char" char="±" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.1 ± 6.2</td><td align="char" char="(" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.3 (2.1 to 8.6)</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.69</td><td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn4"><label>*</label><p>CI = confidence interval; HR = heart rate.</p></fn><fn id="tblfn5"><label>†</label><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> value of &lt;0.01.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>In addition to the mean scores, examining HR metrics in relation to the individual subjects provides further insights. For time spent above 70% Match-HRpeak, 7 subjects exceeded 54 minutes, 31 subjects were between 48 and 54 minutes, 55 subjects were between 45 and 48 minutes, and the remaining 9 subjects recorded at least 42 minutes.</p><p>For time spent above 90% Match-HRpeak, 8 subjects spent between 24 and 33 minutes in this zone. A further 10 subjects were in the 18–23-minute range, 58 subjects spent 12–18 minutes, and 25 subjects were in the 6–12-minute range. Only 1 subject had less than 6 minutes (4.2 minutes) of intensity above 90% Match-HRpeak.</p><p>There were no significant differences between sites for Match-HRpeak or HR<sub>mean</sub> (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>). There were significant moderate differences between the sites in relation to 3 of the 4% Match-HRpeak zones (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>), with site 1 spending approximately 3% less time at ≤70% Match-HRpeak (Z1: <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.005; ES = 0.59) and 71–80% Match-HRpeak (Z2: <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.005; ES = 0.59), and approximately 5% more time at 91–100% Match-HRpeak (Z4: <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001; ES = 0.69) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref> and Figure <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Heart rate distribution expressed as a percentage of total playing time in selected heart rate zones for the total cohort, site 1 and site 2. *<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> value of &lt;0.01.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jscr-40-e366-g002.jpg"/></fig></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s4"><title>Discussion</title><p>The main findings of this investigation were that those involved in recreational football covered an average distance of 6,632 ± 2,369 m with 437.5 ± 598.2 m of HSR and 32.5 ± 18.1 accelerations per session. The other major finding in this study was that subjects had a HR<sub>mean</sub> of 77 ± 16% of their Match-HRpeak and played 81% of the time (48 minutes 36 seconds) above 70% Match-HRpeak, 52% (31 minutes 50 seconds) above 80% Match-HRpeak, and 23% (14 minutes 24 seconds) above 90% Match-HRpeak.</p><p>The total distances covered per night compares favorably and would be greater than previous recreational studies with similar and even younger cohorts (3,444‒4,042 m) (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). The 71.8 m·min<sup>−1</sup> reported in this study is lower than what is reported in most previous studies; however, it still was not the lowest previously reported score (50‒99.4 m·min<sup>−1</sup>) (<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>).</p><p>The greater overall distance covered in this study compared with previous studies is most likely because of FC games involving 60 minutes of game time in comparison with a range of 36 and 40 minutes of game time in previous studies (<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). This extended duration most likely also explains the lower distance per minute observed in this study compared with previous studies, because it is unrealistic to expect players to sustain the same intensity for 60 minutes as they would for 40 minutes.</p><p>Regarding the HR metrics, a HR<sub>mean</sub> of 77% Match-HRpeak in this study was slightly lower than in previous studies, which have reported approximately 80–85%HR<sub>mean</sub> scores (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). Previous studies have calculated maximum HR through incremental fitness tests, rather than peak HR achieved during recreational matches (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). Póvoas et al. (<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>) reported that peak HR achieved in recreational football matches is approximately 3 beats lower than that achieved through a Yo-Yo Incremental Fitness Test Level 1 and 5 beats lower than the gold standard V̇<sc>o</sc><sub>2</sub> max test (5.15 ± 4.30 b·min<sup>−1</sup>, 95% confidence interval [CI] 4.05‒6.24, <italic toggle="yes">d</italic> = 1.18, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001). Therefore, comparisons between the Match-HRpeak reported in this study and maximum HRs reported in previous studies that are derived from incremental fitness tests should be regarded as indirect and may account for the differences observed (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>).</p><p>In addition to methodological differences, the lower a HR<sub>mean</sub> reported in our study may be because of not excluding goalkeeper data (<xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). As is common in recreational football, FC games involved rolling goalkeepers (changing goalkeepers approximately every 6 minutes in the match). The aim of our study was to capture normative HR and physical activity data for the FC recreational football initiative with a general male population. Rolling goalkeepers is a common occurrence in recreational football, therefore, the authors deemed it pertinent to include these data rather than having fixed goalkeepers and only record outfield players. Previous studies capturing physical activity and HR metrics of recreational football have investigated the influence of pitch size and number of players on HR and physical activity metrics. Therefore, they have designed their studies to have fixed goalkeepers and have not recorded goalkeeper data (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). The HR<sub>mean</sub> being a slightly lower percentage of Match-HRpeak in our study most likely occurs when players are in goal. This rationale is further strengthened by the fact that the percentage of time in HR zones above 70, 80, and 90% of Match-HRpeak is very comparable with the previous studies mentioned (<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>).</p><p>Another plausible reason for the slightly lower %HR<sub>mean</sub> may be the time spent playing. Randers et al. (<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>) involved 4 × 12-minute quarters and Stojanovic et al. (<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>) involved 2 × 20-minute halves. These studies reported relatively higher distance per minute and a similar number of sprints despite less playing time. Therefore, players in our study may have paced themselves more to last a 60-minute match, resulting in a lower %HR<sub>mean</sub> compared with studies involving shorter durations played at higher intensities (<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>).</p><p>The physical activity and HR metrics observed in this study support previous research that have reported that recreational football is a substantial fitness intervention (<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>,<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>). The American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) outlines that adults should be achieving between 20 and 60 minutes of exercise at intensities ranging from 55 to 90% HRmax (<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). Our results highlight that recreational football provides an intensity and duration of exercise that is to the higher range of ACSM's recommendations (Tables <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> and <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>) (<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). Therefore, given the distances (6,632 ± 2,369 m) and high intense actions (HSR: 437.5 ± 598.2 m; accelerations: 32.5 ± 18.1) achieved during recreational football and coupling this with the high HR demands of the games, it is unsurprising that previous research has reported positive improvements in fitness testing scores and the corresponding prevention and treatment of Non-Communicable Diseases (NCDs) with several different populations after recreational football interventions (<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>).</p><p>In this study, there was a wide range in the demographics with subjects at site 1 being 10 years younger but also 6 kg heavier. Subjects at site 1 were significantly faster in relation to maximum speed and HSR (Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). However, there were no significant differences for any other physical activity metric (Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><p>One possible reason for differences in max speed may be because of age (<xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>). Putro et al. (<xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>) reported a similar finding to our study that junior players had significantly greater max speed and HSR than recreational males (mean age 32) but no differences for other physical activity metrics. It is well established in the literature that elite sprint performance—as measured by sprint times—decreases with age (<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>). Examining the kinetics and kinematics of sprinting, Korhonen et al. (<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>) reported that adults aged 17–33 years had greater stride length, greater ground reaction forces, and less ground contact time than adults aged 40–80 years involved in sprinting. Furthermore, younger athletes had significantly greater area of type 2 muscle fibers than the older athletes but similar area of type 1 fibers (<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>).</p><p>The significantly lower HSR at site 2 may explain differences in HR zones between the sites. Subjects at site 2 spent approximately 6% more time in lower intensity zones, ≤70% Match-HRpeak (Z1) and 71–80% Match-HRpeak (Z2), and 5% less time at the highest intensity zone, 91–100% Match-HRpeak (Z4). Given that HSR is associated with spikes in HR (<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>), the greater HSR observed in the younger cohort at site 1 may account for their increased time spent in the upper HR zone (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p>Another possible reason for differences in HSR between the sites is the use of absolute rather than individualized speed thresholds. In football, HSR is currently classified as 5.5–7.0 m·s<sup>−1</sup> regardless of a player's maximum speed capability (<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). Subjects in site 1 made a similar number of accelerations (31) as subjects in site 2 (33). Acceleration is defined as a change in a subject's current speed greater than 3 m·s<sup>−1</sup> (<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). However, although accelerations are relative to the subject's current speed, HSR is based on fixed speed thresholds. This means that slower players may have been sprinting, or running at a high-intensity effort for them, however because their speeds did not exceed 5.5 m·s⁻¹ it would not be classfied as a sprint or HSR. Therefore, if HSR was calculated relative to an individual's maximum speed, the differences between the sites may have been reduced or not significant.</p><p>This argument is further supported by a recent case study by StatSport involving youth football (<xref rid="R44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>). This case study reported that using relative HSR thresholds, based on each individual player's speed, accounted for 15% of total distance covered, whereas using absolute speed thresholds only accounted for 5% of total distance covered (<xref rid="R44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>). With those involved in recreational football being significantly older than the cohort examined by StatSport, the gap between absolute and relative values most likely would be even greater (<xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>). There are a range of health benefits associated with sprinting and high-intensity running (<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>). Future research should use relative HSR thresholds to provide a more accurate picture of the amount of HSR achieved in recreational football, and GPS companies should adjust their HSR thresholds for recreational football based on the results of future studies.</p><p>Although the 95% CI for distance covered was 6,359–7,164 m, the range was a minimum of 1,868 m to a maximum of 12,836 m, highlighting that those of different fitness levels could all participate in the games. A limitation of football as a mode of exercise to improve overall health would be lack of control for intensity. One of the unique features of the FC initiative is the stratification of players so that members of similar abilities play against each other and teams are evenly matched (<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). Despite the differences in distance covered, the HR metrics were similar across sites. All subjects spent at least 42 of the 60 minutes above 70% Match-HRpeak and 76 subjects spent at least 12–33 minutes above 90% Match-HRpeak. This indicates that all subjects, regardless of fitness level or age, achieved a sufficient fitness stimulus (<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>) (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>). Furthermore, these results highlight that recreational football can not only accommodate different levels of fitness or age but also provide desirable cardiovascular (CV) benefits, making it a viable exercise option across the age and fitness spectrum (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p>The main limitations in this study were that it only examined normative physical activity and HR data in recreational football for male subjects. A further limitation in this study was the use of absolute values when determining high-speed running distance and number of sprints. StatSport sets these at speeds between 5.5 and 7.0 m·s<sup>−1</sup> and above 7.0 m·s<sup>−1</sup>, respectively. From analysis, several players did not achieve these speeds despite increasing their relative speed. A final limitation was using the peak HR achieved during matches to give an indication of maximum HR rather than with a prior fitness test, such as the Yo-Yo Intermittent Fitness Test level 1 (<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>).</p><p>Future studies should examine normative physical activity and HR data with female cohorts. Furthermore, examining other metrics, such as Rate of Perceived Exertion and Rating of Physical Activity Enjoyment scores in future studies, will provide further normative data related to large scale recreational football initiatives. Future studies should use relative rather than absolute speed to determine HSR and sprints. This would help to provide guidance on appropriate HSR and sprint ranges for recreational football and enable the development of more accurate normative data for these metrics. Finally, this was a cross-sectional design. Future studies should track the longitudinal progress of these metrics with general populations engaging in recreational football.<boxed-text id="B1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><sec><title>Practical Applications</title><p>To the authors' knowledge, this was the first study to provide normative data for HR and physical activity metrics related to a recreational football initiative in the male general population. The results show that recreational football provides a physiologic training stimulus in relation to HR metrics and distances covered that is to the upper ranges of recommended exercise (<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). The results also demonstrate that these recreational football initiatives can accommodate a wide variety of ages and fitness levels, in particular when players can be matched. This has practical applications for coaches when working with the general population clients who do not wish to engage in more traditional, individual aerobic exercise. The result of this study supports the idea of Football as Medicine and provides a rationale as to why previous studies have reported positive effects related to recreational football as an intervention for prevention and treatment of NCDs. These findings, in addition to those from previous studies on the FC initiative, also provide the evidence base to scale up FC games across Ireland for the benefit of male population health.</p></sec></boxed-text></p></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>StatSport provided the GPS equipment free of charge for use in this study. Fingal Sports Partnership (Ireland) contributed €15,000 to support Sarah Doherty in the data collection for this study. South East Technological University (SETU) Waterford is funding an MSc for Sarah Doherty related to recreational football and the Football Cooperative. Coauthor Paula Carroll received €15,000 from the Football Cooperative in 2023, to facilitate a staff buyout, enabling her to complete the SROI report referenced in the study's introduction. In her research role with SETU Waterford, she currently has a research partnership with Football Cooperative, where they received Health Research Board funding to facilitate researchers to undertake 2 studies looking at the replication of FC up to 12 sites starting in October 2025.</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abt</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lovell</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The use of individualized speed and intensity thresholds for determining the distance run at high-intensity in professional soccer</article-title>. <source>J Sports Sci</source>
<volume>27</volume>: <fpage>893</fpage>–<lpage>898</lpage>, <year>2009</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19629838</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/02640410902998239</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aguiar</surname><given-names>SDS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sousa</surname><given-names>CV</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sales</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Age-related decrease in performance of male masters athletes in sprint, sprint–endurance, and endurance events</article-title>. <source>Sport Sci Health</source>
<volume>16</volume>: <fpage>385</fpage>–<lpage>392</lpage>, <year>2020</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aslan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Salci</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Guvenc</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The effects of weekly recreational soccer intervention on the physical fitness level of sedentary young men</article-title>. <source>Montenegrin J Sports Sci Med</source>
<volume>8</volume>: <fpage>51</fpage>–<lpage>59</lpage>, <year>2019</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aslan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cardiovascular responses, perceived exertion and technical actions during small-sided recreational soccer: Effects of pitch size and number of players</article-title>. <source>J Hum Kinet</source>
<volume>38</volume>: <fpage>95</fpage>–<lpage>105</lpage>, <year>2013</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24233236</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2478/hukin-2013-0049</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3827765</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bastida Castillo</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gómez Carmona</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>De la Cruz Sánchez</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pino Ortega</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Accuracy, intra-and inter-unit reliability, and comparison between GPS and UWB-based position-tracking systems used for time–motion analyses in soccer</article-title>. <source>Eur J Sport Sci</source>
<volume>18</volume>: <fpage>450</fpage>–<lpage>457</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29385963</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/17461391.2018.1427796</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beauchamp</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Russien</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dunlop</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Group-based physical activity for older adults (GOAL) randomized controlled trial: Exercise adherence outcomes</article-title>. <source>Health Psych</source>
<volume>37</volume>: <fpage>451</fpage>–<lpage>462</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1037/hea0000615</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29698019</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bennike</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ottesen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rasmussen</surname><given-names>KG</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The implementation of football fitness</article-title>. In: <source>Football as Medicine</source>. <publisher-loc>London, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>, <year>2019</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bjerre</surname><given-names>ED</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brasso</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jørgensen</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Football compared with usual care in men with prostate cancer (FC prostate community trial): A pragmatic multicentre randomized controlled trial</article-title>. <source>Sports Med</source>
<volume>49</volume>: <fpage>145</fpage>–<lpage>158</lpage>, <year>2019</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30506427</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-018-1031-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6349963</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carroll</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Egan</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Daly</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Football cooperative, a community based physical activity social initiative for men: Protocol paper for a pragmatic feasibility trial</article-title>. <source>J Phys Activity Res</source>
<volume>8</volume>: <fpage>16</fpage>–<lpage>26</lpage>, <year>2023</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cvetković</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stojanović</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stojiljković</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Exercise training in overweight and obese children: Recreational football and high‐intensity interval training provide similar benefits to physical fitness</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>28</volume>: <fpage>18</fpage>–<lpage>32</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29979479</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.13241</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Daly</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Carroll</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Egan</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The pre-adoption characteristics of men in a community-based social initiative: Who wants a game of ball?</article-title>
<source>Int J Health Promot Educ</source>
<volume>62</volume>: <fpage>310</fpage>–<lpage>324</lpage>, <year>2024</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ekstrand</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hägglund</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Waldén</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Injury incidence and injury patterns in professional football: The UEFA injury study</article-title>. <source>Br J Sports Med</source>
<volume>45</volume>: <fpage>553</fpage>–<lpage>558</lpage>, <year>2011</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19553225</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsm.2009.060582</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Everard</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lyons</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Examining the relationship between the functional movement screen and the landing error scoring system in an active, male collegiate population</article-title>. <source>J Strength Cond Res</source>
<volume>31</volume>: <fpage>1265</fpage>–<lpage>1272</lpage>, <year>2017</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27465626</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001582</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fløtum</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ottesen</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mohr</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Evaluating a nationwide recreational football intervention: Recruitment, attendance, adherence, exercise intensity, and health effects</article-title>. <source>BioMed Res Int</source>
<volume>2016</volume>: <fpage>7231545</fpage>–<lpage>7231731</lpage>, <year>2016</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27437401</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2016/7231545</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4942591</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fuller</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Low</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>. <article-title>Reliability and validity of commercially available wearable devices for measuring steps, energy expenditure, and heart rate: Systematic review</article-title>. <source>JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</source>
<volume>8</volume>: <fpage>e18694</fpage>–<lpage>e18703</lpage>, <year>2020</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32897239</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/18694</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7509623</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Giles</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Draper</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Neil</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Validity of the Polar V800 heart rate monitor to measure RR intervals at rest</article-title>. <source>Eur J Appl Physiol</source>
<volume>116</volume>: <fpage>563</fpage>–<lpage>571</lpage>, <year>2016</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26708360</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00421-015-3303-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4751190</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gray</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jenkins</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Andrews</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Taaffe</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Glover</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Validity and reliability of GPS for measuring distance travelled in field-based team sports</article-title>. <source>J Sports Sci</source>
<volume>28</volume>: <fpage>1319</fpage>–<lpage>1325</lpage>, <year>2010</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20859825</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/02640414.2010.504783</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Haskell</surname><given-names>WL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>IM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pate</surname><given-names>RR</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Physical activity and public health: Updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association</article-title>. <source>Circulation</source>
<volume>116</volume>: <fpage>1081</fpage>–<lpage>1093</lpage>, <year>2007</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17671237</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.185649</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Helge</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>TR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational football improves bone mineral density and bone turnover marker profile in elderly men</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>24</volume>: <fpage>98</fpage>–<lpage>104</lpage>, <year>2014</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.12239</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24903207</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hellsten</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nyberg</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cardiovascular adaptations to exercise training</article-title>. <source>Compr Physiol</source>
<volume>6</volume>: <fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>32</lpage>, <year>2015</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26756625</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/cphy.c140080</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hennessy</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jeffreys</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The current use of GPS, its potential, and limitations in soccer</article-title>. <source>Strength Cond J</source>
<volume>40</volume>: <fpage>83</fpage>–<lpage>94</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hopkins</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marshall</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Batterham</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hanin</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science</article-title>. <source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source>
<volume>41</volume>: <fpage>3</fpage>–<lpage>13</lpage>, <year>2009</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19092709</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Korhonen</surname><given-names>MT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Meru</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Markku</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Biomechanical and skeletal muscle determinants of maximum running speed with aging</article-title>. <source>J Med Sci Spor Exer</source>
<volume>41</volume>: <fpage>844</fpage>–<lpage>856</lpage>, <year>2009</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181998366</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19276848</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bangsbo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational football is effective in the treatment of non-communicable diseases</article-title>. <source>Br J Sports Med</source>
<volume>49</volume>: <fpage>1426</fpage>–<lpage>1427</lpage>, <year>2015</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25990758</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094955</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4680157</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Parnell</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Chapter 1- Football is Medicine against Cardiovascular disease</article-title>. <source>Football as Medicine: Prescribing Football for Global Health Promotion</source>. <publisher-loc>London, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>, <year>2019</year>. <comment>In press</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational soccer is an effective health-promoting activity for untrained men</article-title>. <source>Br J Sports Med</source>
<volume>43</volume>: <fpage>825</fpage>–<lpage>831</lpage>, <year>2009</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19098116</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsm.2008.053124</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aagaard</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nybo</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational football as a health promoting activity: A topical review</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>20</volume>: <fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>13</lpage>, <year>2010</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01108.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20210908</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mohr</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The “Football is Medicine” platform—scientific evidence, large‐scale implementation of evidence‐based concepts and future perspectives</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>28</volume>: <fpage>3</fpage>–<lpage>7</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29917263</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.13220</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>29.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lachman</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lipsitz</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lubben</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Castaneda-Sceppa</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jette</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>When adults don't exercise: Behavioral strategies to increase physical activity in sedentary middle-aged and older adults</article-title>. <source>Innov Aging</source>
<volume>2</volume>: <fpage>igy007</fpage>–<lpage>igy214</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30003146</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/geroni/igy007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6037047</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>30.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>MacInnis</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gibala</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Physiological adaptations to interval training and the role of exercise intensity</article-title>. <source>J Physiol</source>
<volume>595</volume>: <fpage>2915</fpage>–<lpage>2930</lpage>, <year>2017</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27748956</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1113/JP273196</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5407969</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Markov</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hauser</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chaabene</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on measures of physical fitness in healthy middle-aged and older adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Sports Med</source>
<volume>53</volume>: <fpage>437</fpage>–<lpage>455</lpage>, <year>2023</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36222981</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-022-01764-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9876872</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>32.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milanović</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Čović</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Helge</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Is recreational soccer effective for improving VO2max A systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>J Sport Med</source>
<volume>45</volume>: <fpage>339</fpage>–<lpage>1353</lpage>, <year>2015</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-015-0361-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4536283</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26210229</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>33.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milanović</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pantelić</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Čović</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Broad-spectrum physical fitness benefits of recreational football: A systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Br J Sports Med</source>
<volume>53</volume>: <fpage>926</fpage>–<lpage>939</lpage>, <year>2019</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29371223</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097885</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6662951</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R34"><label>34.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milanović</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pantelić</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Čović</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational football and bone health: A systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>J Sport Med</source>
<volume>52</volume>: <fpage>3021</fpage>–<lpage>3037</lpage>, <year>2022</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-022-01726-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35852769</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pantelić</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rađa</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Erceg</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Relative pitch area plays an important role in movement pattern and intensity in recreational male football</article-title>. <source>Biol Sport</source>
<volume>36</volume>: <fpage>119</fpage>–<lpage>124</lpage>, <year>2019</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31223188</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5114/biolsport.2019.81113</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6561223</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R36"><label>36.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Póvoas</surname><given-names>SCA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pereira</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Maximal heart rate assessment in recreational football players: A study involving a multiple testing approach</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>29</volume>: <fpage>1537</fpage>–<lpage>1545</lpage>, <year>2019</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31112342</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.13472</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Putro</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Firmansyah</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Apriantono</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Comparison between junior and recreational based on internal and external load response in soccer</article-title>. <source>J Retos: Neuv Persp de Educ</source>
<volume>12</volume>: <fpage>59</fpage>–<lpage>67</lpage>, <year>2024</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R38"><label>38.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Randers</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nybo</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Petersen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Activity profile and physiological response to football training for untrained males and females, elderly and youngsters: Influence of the number of players</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>20</volume>: <fpage>14</fpage>–<lpage>23</lpage>, <year>2010</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20149143</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01069.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R39"><label>39.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Randers</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>TB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rasmussen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Larsen</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of game format on heart rate, activity profile, and player involvement in elite and recreational youth players</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>24</volume>: <fpage>17</fpage>–<lpage>26</lpage>, <year>2014</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24944130</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.12255</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R40"><label>40.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Randers</surname><given-names>MB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ørntoft</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hagman</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krustrup</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Movement pattern and physiological response in recreational small-sided football–effect of number of players with a fixed pitch size</article-title>. <source>J Sports Sci</source>
<volume>36</volume>: <fpage>1549</fpage>–<lpage>1556</lpage>, <year>2018</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29132263</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/02640414.2017.1402552</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R41"><label>41.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sarmento</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Manuel Clemente</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marques</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Recreational football is medicine against non‐communicable diseases: A systematic review</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<volume>30</volume>: <fpage>618</fpage>–<lpage>637</lpage>, <year>2020</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31834941</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.13611</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R42"><label>42.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stojanović</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stojiljković</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stanković</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Game format alters the physiological and activity demands encountered during small-sided football games in recreational players</article-title>. <source>J Exerc Sci Fitness</source>
<volume>19</volume>: <fpage>40</fpage>–<lpage>46</lpage>, <year>2021</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jesf.2020.05.001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7475126</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32922462</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R43"><label>43.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Torres Banduc</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chirosa Ríos</surname><given-names>LJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chirosa Ríos</surname><given-names>IJ</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of different lower limb strengthening protocols on muscle activity, strength and power in sedentary and physically inactive subjects: A systematic review</article-title>. <source>J Nutr Hos</source>
<volume>41</volume>: <fpage>202</fpage>–<lpage>211</lpage>, <year>2024</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.20960/nh.04551</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37534442</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R44"><label>44.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Traynor</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Monitoring high speed running demands in youth soccer players; absolute or individualised thresholds? A Case Study</article-title>. <source>Stat Sport</source>
<volume>6</volume>: <fpage>63</fpage>–<lpage>72</lpage>, <year>2023</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R45"><label>45.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>van Baak</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pramono</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Battista</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of different types of regular exercise on physical fitness in adults with overweight or obesity: Systematic review and meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>Obes Rev</source>
<volume>22</volume>: <fpage>e13239</fpage>, <year>2021</year>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33939229</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/obr.13239</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8365680</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>