<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Discov Oncol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Discov Oncol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">4139</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">discon</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Discover Oncology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2730-6011</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12748487</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12748487.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12748487</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12748487</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41258210</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12672-025-03943-9</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3943</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Bibliometric analysis reveals the current status and future trends of cancer associated fibroblasts research in breast cancer</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jing</surname><given-names initials="S">Shixue</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names initials="S">Siping</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jia</surname><given-names initials="C">Cui</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yongfeng</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cao</surname><given-names initials="H">Hui</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names initials="L">Lushun</given-names></name><address><email>zhangls2012@cmc.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names initials="X">Xinlian</given-names></name><address><email>lxldly@cmc.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01c4jmp52</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.413856.d</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1799 3643</institution-id><institution>Department of Pathology, </institution><institution>The Third Affiliated Hospital of Chengdu Medical College, Chengdu Pidu District People’s Hospital, </institution></institution-wrap>Chengdu, 611730 China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01c4jmp52</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.413856.d</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1799 3643</institution-id><institution>School of Clinical Medicine, </institution><institution>Chengdu Medical College, </institution></institution-wrap>Chengdu, 610500 China </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01c4jmp52</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.413856.d</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1799 3643</institution-id><institution>Department of Pathology and Pathophysiology, </institution><institution>Chengdu Medical College, </institution></institution-wrap>Chengdu, 610500 China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>12</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>16</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">478248</issue-id><elocation-id>2238</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>12</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>24</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>19</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-12-31 00:25:13.470"><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2025</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12672_2025_Article_3943.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Breast cancer is one of the most common and lethal heterogeneous cancers among women worldwide, posing a significant threat to female health. Cancer associated fibroblasts (CAFs) play a critical role in the initiation and progression of breast cancer, and their behavior within the tumor microenvironment profoundly influences disease development. Systematic research on the functions of CAFs in breast cancer remains relatively limited. This study employs bibliometric theories and methods to comprehensively analyze the existing knowledge framework of breast cancer CAFs research, thereby identifying and examining research hotspots and future trends in this field.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">This study retrieved literature related to CAFs in breast cancer from the Science Core Collection (WOSCC) database, covering publications from 2005 to 2025. After rigorous screening, 377 eligible academic papers were included as research subjects. Utilizing software tools such as VOSviewer, Pajek, Scimago Graphica, and CiteSpace, we conducted an in-depth analysis across multiple dimensions, including countries, research institutions, authors, journals, and keywords, to elucidate the knowledge structure of this field and identify research hotspots and developmental trends.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">The findings indicate a general upward trend in annual publications, with particularly rapid growth between 2022 and 2024. China, the United States, and Italy were the most prolific countries, demonstrating strong academic influence. Among institutions, the University of Calabria, Chongqing Medical University, and the University of Manchester contributed the most research output. Notable researchers, including Marcello Maggiolini, Michael P. Lisanti, and Manran Liu, stood out in terms of publication volume and collaborative engagement. Regarding journals, Cancers published the highest number of articles, while Nature Communications had the greatest impact, with a 2023 impact factor of 14.7. This study systematically reviews the origin, activation mechanisms, and heterogeneity of CAFs in breast cancer. The research reveals that CAFs can be activated through various cytokines and signaling pathways and exhibit significant heterogeneity across different breast cancer subtypes. CAFs secrete multiple factors involved in angiogenesis and extracellular matrix (ECM) remodeling, thereby promoting breast cancer cell metastasis and invasion. Additionally, CAFs may suppress the host’s anti-tumor immune response. Current therapeutic strategies targeting CAFs primarily focus on disrupting intercellular communication, degrading the ECM, and overcoming drug resistance. Future research may concentrate on exploring the mechanisms by which immunotherapy regulates CAF activity and the potential of combination therapies. This study provides a comprehensive overview of the current status, hotspots, and cutting-edge advancements in breast cancer CAF research.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par4">Our study systematically examines research hotspots and trends in breast cancer CAF studies, establishing a solid literature-based foundation for defining future research directions and priorities. It highlights the significant potential and importance of targeting CAFs in the breast cancer stroma for therapeutic intervention and tumor progression inhibition. The findings are expected to offer scientific guidance for subsequent research and advance the development of breast cancer CAF studies. Although this study has certain limitations, it provides valuable references for future related research.</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s12672-025-03943-9.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Breast cancer</kwd><kwd>CAFs</kwd><kwd>Tumor microenvironment</kwd><kwd>Bibliometric analysis</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Open Fund of Development and Regeneration Key Laboratory of Sichuan Province</institution></funding-source><award-id>Grant No.23LHPDZYB07; Grant No.23LHPDZZD05</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Xinlian</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>the Chinese Ministry of Education Cooperative Education Project</institution></funding-source><award-id>Grant No.231100882305626</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Xinlian</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>the National College Student Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program Project</institution></funding-source><award-id>Grant No.202413705016</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Xinlian</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© Springer Science+Business Media LLC, part of Springer Nature 2025</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par5">Breast cancer is the most common malignancy with high mortality rates among women worldwide, and its development and progression are closely linked to dynamic interactions within the tumor microenvironment (TME). As a highly heterogeneous disease, breast cancer is widely distributed across the globe and represents a leading cause of cancer-related deaths among women. Its incidence is strongly associated with age and a country’s level of economic development. Analysis based on the Human Development Index indicates that the incidence of breast cancer is significantly higher in developed countries compared to developing nations. Socioeconomic conditions influence key factors such as growth, nutritional status, age at menarche, reproductive history, age at menopause, and obesity rates in women. These factors, in conjunction with genetic determinants, collectively play a significant role in influencing the risk of breast cancer development [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Breast cancer can be classified into molecular subtypes including Luminal A, Luminal B, HER2 positive, and triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Metastasis is the leading cause of death in breast cancer patients, with the TME playing a key role in the mechanisms of metastasis. Both immune and non-immune cells within the TME collaboratively regulate the process of cancer metastasis, and targeted inhibition of relevant signaling pathways can effectively reduce the vascular invasion ability and metastatic potential of tumor cells [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Early diagnosis is crucial for improving patient survival rates; however, more than half of patients are already at an advanced or metastatic stage by the time clinical symptoms appear [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>].</p><p id="Par6">In the TME, cancer-associated fibroblasts (CAFs), as the most predominant stromal cell component, regulate tumor progression, immune evasion, and therapy resistance through multiple mechanisms, making them a critical research target in breast cancer. CAFs are activated, heterogeneous stromal cells that are the most abundant stromal component in the TME and are closely associated with tumor progression. They drive tumor development by promoting ECM deposition and remodeling, mediating immunosuppression, enhancing cancer cell proliferation, inducing angiogenesis, and facilitating therapy resistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. CAFs exhibit high heterogeneity and plasticity, with diverse cellular origins. These primarily include the activation of resident fibroblasts, as well as the transformation of various cell types such as mesenchymal stem cells, adipocytes, and bone marrow derived fibroblasts. Under the mediation of factors like TGF-β, CXCL12, Wnt7a, platelet-derived growth factor (PDGF), and specific miRNAs, these cells differentiate into CAF subsets expressing distinct markers. For instance, transforming growth factor beta (TGF-β) and CXCL12 can induce the formation of α-SMA⁺ CAFs, while mesenchymal stem cells can transform into CAFs through signals such as tumor-derived exosomes and TGF-β. Additionally, adipocytes can give rise to CAFs with an FSP1⁺/α-SMA⁻/FAP⁻ phenotype under the influence of Wnt3a. In contrast, bone marrow derived fibroblasts, which are often recruited into the TME with an α-SMA⁺/PDGFRα⁻ phenotype, contribute to tumor progression.</p><p id="Par7">The activation mechanisms of CAFs are complex and multifaceted, involving cytokine receptor mediated signaling pathways, direct interactions between tumor cells and CAFs, as well as regulation by various physicochemical factors within the TME. Ligands of the TGF-β family are key signaling molecules regulating the transformation of normal fibroblasts (NFs) into CAFs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. In breast cancer, CD26⁺ NFs and CD26 NFs differentiate into inflammatory CAFs and myofibroblastic CAFs, respectively, collaboratively promoting tumor progression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Breast cancer cells activate fibroblasts through autocrine TGF-β and CXCL12, further enhancing their activation and function via a positive feedback loop. The CXCL12/CXCR4 axis, TGF-β/Smad pathway, Wnt signaling, and osteopontin (OPN) are all involved in regulating marker expression and secretory functions of CAFs. Additionally, miRNAs and proteins carried by tumor cell derived exosomes play critical roles in CAF activation and functional remodeling.</p><p id="Par8">CAFs exhibit significant heterogeneity in breast cancer and lack a unified specific marker. Their phenotypes and functions vary considerably depending on the molecular and pathological subtypes of the disease. Systematic analysis based on six CAF biomarkers (FAP, CD29, α-SMA, FSP1, PDGFRβ, and Caveolin) has led to the identification of four well-characterized CAF subtypes (CAF-S1 to CAF-S4) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. The application of single-cell RNA sequencing has greatly advanced the understanding of CAF subtypes, enabling researchers to identify multiple functional subpopulations, including vCAFs, mCAFs, and dCAFs. Among these, the CAF-S1 subtype significantly promotes the establishment of an immunosuppressive microenvironment and therapy resistance by expressing immune-modulatory ligands such as PD-L2 and OX40L. In contrast, FAP⁺ CAFs accelerate tumor progression by regulating extracellular matrix remodeling and metabolic reprogramming. These heterogeneous subpopulations demonstrate diversity in spatial distribution, marker expression, and clinical relevance, profoundly influencing breast cancer biology and patient prognosis. Furthermore, CAFs mediate immunosuppression by secreting immune modulatory cytokines and chemokines, thereby facilitating tumor progression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. It must be emphasized that CAFs are not a homogeneous cell population but rather a highly heterogeneous and plastic group of cells. They primarily originate from the activation of resident fibroblasts but may also derive from other cell types. Their activation is mediated by a complex network of cytokines, growth factors, and tumor cell-derived exosomes, leading to functional diversification into distinct subtypes. Through remodeling the extracellular matrix, modulating immune responses, and supporting cancer cell metabolism, CAFs play a key role in tumor progression, metastasis, and therapy resistance. The complex heterogeneity of CAFs is reflected in their diverse marker expression, which has become a major focus of current research.</p><p id="Par9">To date, there have been no bibliometric studies reported on CAFs in breast cancer. This study employs VOSviewer and CiteSpace for visual analysis, aiming not only to map the knowledge structure and research hotspots in the field of breast cancer CAFs, but also to quantify geographical disparities in research output. Through qualitative and quantitative assessments across multiple dimensions including countries, authors, research institutions, and journals, we seek to elucidate current research trends, provide a theoretical foundation for promoting more inclusive and globally representative future research directions, and reveal the evolving knowledge structure and research frontiers within this complex and dynamic field.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Data sources and search strategy</title><p id="Par10">This study utilized the WOSCC database as the data source, with the index scope limited to SCI EXPANDED and SSCI. The search keywords were “breast cancer” and “CAFs,” and the retrieval strategy was as follows: TS=(“Breast Neoplasm” OR “Breast Tumor” OR “Breast Cancer” OR “Cancer of the Breast” OR “Cancer of Breast” OR “Breast Carcinoma”) AND TS=(“Cancer Associated Fibroblast” OR “Tumor Associated Fibroblast” OR “Cancer Related Fibroblast” OR “Tumor Related Fibroblast” OR “Tumour Associated Fibroblast” OR “Tumour Related Fibroblast”).</p><p id="Par11">The search was conducted for publications from January 1, 2005, to March 13, 2025, with the document types limited to “Article” and “Review Article” and the language restricted to English. Based on the above search strategy, a total of 1,929 publications were retrieved. After evaluating the titles and abstracts, 377 articles highly relevant to the research topic were selected for further analysis.The complete records, including cited references, were exported in plain text format and imported into CiteSpace for bibliometric analysis. The final dataset comprised 377 publications, consisting of 334 research articles and 37 review articles .</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Data analysis and visualization</title><p id="Par12">This study employed bibliometric analysis on the screened 377 publications using tools including WPS Office, VOSviewer, CiteSpace (v6.3.R1), Pajek, and Scimago Graphica. Figure <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> illustrates the literature search and processing workflow.</p><p id="Par13">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e326" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par14">Bibliometrics applies statistical and mathematical methods to quantitatively analyze literature within a specific field, thereby revealing research trends and developmental trajectories. By systematically organizing and analyzing information such as authors, keywords, countries, institutions, and journals, a comprehensive understanding of the knowledge structure and research hotspots in the field can be achieved.</p><p id="Par15">VOSviewer, a freely available bibliometric visualization tool developed by Leiden University in the Netherlands, constructs network maps based on co-occurrence matrices to intuitively display the bibliometric structure of a research domain. In this study, VOSviewer was utilized to generate author collaboration networks, document co-citation networks, and keyword co-occurrence networks. In these network visualizations, node size represents element importance, line thickness indicates connection strength, and node colors distinguish different cluster modules.</p><p id="Par16">CiteSpace, developed by Professor Chaomei Chen’s research team, specializes in collaboration networks and cluster analysis. By identifying and visualizing burst detection of key nodes, CiteSpace reveals pivotal turning points and critical advancements in a research field. Through centrality and burstness analyses, researchers can efficiently grasp the knowledge base, research hotspots, and cutting edge trends within the domain.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec6"><title>Annual publication output and trends</title><p id="Par17">Figure <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> presents the annual and cumulative publication volumes of literature in the field of breast cancer and CAFs from 2005 to 2025. The relatively low number of publications in 2010 indicates that this period had not yet formed a significant research focus. From 2010 to 2020, publications appeared annually with a steady growth rate, reaching the first peak in 2021, suggesting a breakthrough during this phase. Although the number of publications declined between 2021 and 2022, it rebounded rapidly in 2023 and reached its highest level in 2024, demonstrating important advancements during these two years. From 2005 to 2025, the cumulative number of publications in this field amounted to 377, with an average annual output of 19 papers. This trend indicates that research on breast cancer and CAFs has gradually gained attention, with significantly increased activity in recent years, establishing itself as an important direction in oncology research.</p><p id="Par18">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Annual publication volume and its trend</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e351" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Contributions of countries or regions</title><p id="Par19">This study encompasses literature from 129 countries and 1,537 institutions. Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> presents the top ten countries by publication output, along with their respective publication counts, average citation counts, and centrality metrics. The top three countries by publication volume are China (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 143), the United States (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 76), and Italy (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 36). The United Kingdom ranks first in average citations with 97 citations per publication. The top three countries by centrality are the United States (0.52), the United Kingdom (0.28), and China (0.20). The data indicate that the United States, the United Kingdom, and China exhibit substantial research influence in this field.</p><p id="Par20">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Contributions of countries</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Countries/Regions</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Count</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Citations</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Centrality</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Average Citations/Publications</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">China</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">143</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5885</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.32</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41.15</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">USA</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">76</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6259</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.53</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">82.36</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Italy</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2217</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.27</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">61.58</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">United Kingdom</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2231</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.23</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">97.00</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Japan</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">675</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.50</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">South Korea</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">600</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.00</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.29</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">France</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1487</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.11</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">92.94</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Germany</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">649</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">46.36</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sweden</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1198</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.57</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Saudi Arabia</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">349</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.09</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.08</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par21">Using CiteSpace, we analyzed international collaboration networks. Figure <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> presents a geographic visualization map of 20 countries, generated using VOSviewer and Scimago Graphica. The United States occupies a central role in international collaborations, demonstrating the broadest collaborative reach, with strong partnerships established with 13 countries, including China, the United Kingdom, Italy, Spain, and Canada, positioning it as the leader in the collaboration network.</p><p id="Par22">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Geographical distribution map drawn according to the total number of publications in different countriesregions</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e542" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par23">Figure <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, generated using CiteSpace, illustrates inter-country collaboration relationships. Node size represents the publication volume of each country, while the purple outer ring indicates centrality, with thickness reflecting centrality strength. The thickness of connecting lines between nodes denotes collaboration intensity. The United States exhibits the highest collaboration intensity and centrality in the network, followed by the United Kingdom and China. This underscores the United States’ pivotal role in international collaborations within this field, while the United Kingdom and China also demonstrate strong collaborative influence.</p><p id="Par24">
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Visual Analytics of National Collaboration Networks</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e557" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par25">Research output was predominantly concentrated in China, the United States, and Italy (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>; Figs. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> and <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). However, regions with high and growing breast cancer burden, such as Africa and South America, were absent among the major contributing countries. This disparity suggests that the current paradigm in CAF biology and its targeting strategies is primarily shaped by the resources and populations of developed countries, which may limit its applicability in other genetic and environmental contexts.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Institutional contributions</title><p id="Par26">Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref> lists the top 10 institutions by publication output in the field of CAFs research. The University of Calabria (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 20), Chongqing Medical University (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 18), and the University of Manchester (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 13) rank as the top three, demonstrating the highest research productivity in this field.</p><p id="Par27">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Contributions of Institute</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Organization</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Documents</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total Link Strength</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Univ Calabria</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chongqing Med Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Univ Manchester</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Thomas Jefferson Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">King Faisal Specialist Hosp &amp; Res Ctr</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yonsei Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Shanghai Jiao Tong Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Tel Aviv Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lund Univ</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Huazhong Univ Sci &amp; Technol</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par28">Using VOSviewer, we analyzed institutional collaboration networks by setting the minimum co-occurrence threshold to 3. As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>, the collaboration network is divided into three clusters: red, green, and blue. The node size represents the volume of collaborative publications, while the connecting line thickness reflects the strength of collaboration. Within the red cluster, the University of Calabria, Chongqing Medical University, the University of Manchester, and Thomas Jefferson University exhibit larger nodes, indicating their central role in the collaboration network. These institutions maintain extensive connections, with particularly strong collaboration between the University of Manchester and Thomas Jefferson University. The University of Calabria demonstrates the highest collaboration intensity within its cluster, highlighting its pivotal position. At the periphery of the red and blue clusters, as well as between the green and blue clusters, overlapping nodes suggest potential interdisciplinary collaboration. However, the thin connecting lines indicate that these collaborations remain relatively independent. In contrast, the blue cluster shows sparse internal connections, reflecting weaker collaboration among its members.</p><p id="Par29">
<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><p>Visualization map of countries regions for international cooperation</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e713" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Author contributions and co - cited authors</title><p id="Par30">Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref> lists the top 10 authors in the field of CAFs in breast cancer based on publication volume and co-citation frequency, respectively.</p><p id="Par31">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Author contributions</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Author</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Documents</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Average Citations/Publications</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Maggiolini, Marcello</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">152</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lisanti, Michael p.</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">150</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Liu, Manran</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">144</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Aboussekhra, Abdelilah</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">140</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lappano, Rosamaria</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">138</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pestell, Richard g.</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">133</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Whitaker-Menezes, Diana</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Howell, Anthony</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">52</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Martinez-outschoorn, Ubaldo e.</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">47</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chiavarina, Barbara</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par32">In terms of publication count, the top three authors are Maggiolini, Marcello; Lisanti, Michael P; and Liu, Manran. When analyzed by average citations per paper, among the top 10 authors by publication volume, Whitaker-Menezes, Diana (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 152), Pestell, Richard G. (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 150), and Chiavarina, Barbara (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 144) rank highest. This indicates that the research outputs of these three authors are highly cited in the field, likely appearing together in multiple key publications, reflecting their close academic connections and significant influence in breast cancer CAFs research.</p><p id="Par33">Using VOSviewer software, a co-authorship network analysis was conducted on 53 authors with at least four publications, revealing the largest cluster comprising 12 authors to visualize collaborative relationships (Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>). The dense connecting lines among these 12 authors indicate frequent collaborations. Among them, Maggiolini, Marcello has the largest node, representing the highest number of collaborative publications, with the most prominent connecting lines to multiple co-authors, highlighting his central role in the collaboration network. Similarly, Lappano, Rosamaria demonstrates extensive collaborative ties with other researchers.</p><p id="Par34">
<fig id="Fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><p>Network visualization of the relationships among different authors</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e860" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig6_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Journal analysis</title><p id="Par35">This study involved a total of 164 journals. Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref> presents the top 10 journals ranked by publication volume, along with their respective article counts, journal quartiles, and 2023 impact factors. Among these, Cancers ranked first with 19 publications, followed by Oncogene (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 14) and Cancer Research (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 13). Nature Communications had the highest impact factor in the listed journals, reaching 14.7 in 2023.</p><p id="Par36">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Contributions of journal</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Journal</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Count</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">JCR</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IF(2023)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancers</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Oncogene</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancer Research</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frontiers In Oncology</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Breast Cancer Research</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cell Cycle</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q3</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">International Journal Of Molecular Sciences</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Theranostics</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancer Letters</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Nature Communications</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Q1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.7</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par37">Using a minimum publication threshold of 5 articles, this study conducted a citation analysis of 22 journals using VOSviewer, with the results illustrated in Fig. <xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>. In the figure, node size represents co-publication volume, line thickness indicates collaboration strength, and differently colored node connections denote interdisciplinary journal collaborations. The analysis revealed that Cancers had the largest node and maintained dense connections with multiple journals, demonstrating its broad academic influence and collaborative reach. Key journals facilitating interdisciplinary collaboration included Cancers, Cancer Research, Frontiers in Oncology, and Cell Cycle, all of which exhibited extensive collaborative linkages with journals from other disciplinary clusters.</p><p id="Par38">
<fig id="Fig7" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 7</label><caption><p>Visualization map of co - cited journals</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1025" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig7_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Keywords</title><p id="Par39">Through keyword extraction and analysis, this study visualized the research hotspots and frontier directions in the field. Table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref> lists the top 10 most frequently occurring keywords. The high-frequency keywords include “breast cancer” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 164),” microenvironment” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 153), “cancer-associated fibroblasts” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 116), “expression” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 110),” cell” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 83),” metastasis” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 81), “growth” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 79),“stromal fibroblasts” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 74),“progression” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 47), and"activation” (<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 44). The top three keywords in terms of frequency breast cancer, microenvironment, and CAFs indicate that the microenvironment plays a significant role in research related to CAFs in breast cancer.</p><p id="Par40">
<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>Keyword contributions</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Keyword</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Breast Cancer</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">164</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Microenvironment</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">153</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancer-Associated Fibroblasts</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">116</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Expression</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">110</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cells</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">83</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Metastasis</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Growth</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">79</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Stromal Fibroblasts</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">74</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Progression</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">47</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">activation</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par41">Figure <xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref> presents a VOSviewer based visualization of keyword co-occurrence to reveal the distribution of research themes in this field. The keywords were clustered into six distinct groups: red, light blue, blue, green, yellow, and purple clusters. Based on node size, the primary keywords in each cluster are as follows: Red cluster: TGF-β, tumor growth, stem cells, metabolism; Light blue cluster: breast cancer, prognosis, extracellular matrix༛Blue cluster: cell, heterogeneity, resistance༛Green cluster: growth, proliferation, tumor stroma immunotherapy༛Yellow cluster: stromal myofibroblasts, epithelial mesenchymal transition (EMT), microenvironment༛Purple cluster: cancer associated fibroblasts, metastasis.</p><p id="Par42">
<fig id="Fig8" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 8</label><caption><p>Visualization map of keywords</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1169" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig8_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par43">Using CiteSpace, we conducted a burst analysis on keywords and extracted the top 10 key burst terms. By examining the burst start time, duration, and end time of these keywords, we can clearly understand the evolution, frontiers, and latest trends in the research hotspots of this field.</p><p id="Par44">Figure <xref rid="Fig9" ref-type="fig">9</xref> displays the burst start and end times of the keywords. The burst strength reflects the popularity of a keyword in academic research, with the red line segments indicating the trending period of a keyword within a specific historical interval. Light blue nodes represent periods when the keyword had not yet emerged, while dark blue nodes indicate its initial appearance and gradual rise in attention.</p><p id="Par45">
<fig id="Fig9" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 9</label><caption><p>The top 10 keywords with the strongest citation bursts</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1186" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig9_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par46">The analysis reveals that “tumor stroma” exhibits the highest burst strength (6.97), followed by “metastasis” (5.5) and “stromal fibroblasts” (4.6). Between 2005 and 2025, the earliest emerging keywords included “stromal fibroblasts,” “tumor microenvironment,” “aerobic glycolysis,” and “metastasis,” among which “TGF-β” maintained sustained research interest over a prolonged period. In recent years, research hotspots have gradually shifted toward keywords such as “promotion,” “metastasis,” and “mechanism,” indicating that the field has entered a new phase, focusing primarily on tumor drug resistance mechanisms and their regulation.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Literature co-citation analysis</title><p id="Par47">Co-citation analysis is used to reveal the intrinsic relationships between publications. When two or more documents are simultaneously cited by another paper, a co-citation relationship is formed between them. Through co-citation analysis, researchers can gain in depth insights into the knowledge structure and developmental trajectory of a research field. Table <xref rid="Tab6" ref-type="table">6</xref> lists the top 10 most frequently co-cited references. The most highly cited publications are “The prognostic significance of tumor-associated stroma in invasive breast carcinoma” and “Stromal miR-200s contribute to breast cancer cell invasion through CAF activation and ECM remodeling”. The first study demonstrates that CAFs in tumor stroma can serve as a prognostic marker for breast cancer patients, with higher CAF density in TNBC being associated with chemotherapy resistance and reduced survival. The second study reveals, from a molecular perspective, that the miR-200s-ZEB1-MMP axis is a key mechanism through which CAFs promote metastasis, highlighting its potential as a therapeutic target. Together, these two studies underscore the critical role of stromal reprogramming in breast cancer progression.</p><p id="Par48">
<table-wrap id="Tab6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6</label><caption><p>Contributions of co-cited references</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rank</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Title</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Centrality</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Year</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The prognostic significance of tumor-associated stroma in invasive breast carcinoma</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.03</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2018</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Stromal miR-200s contribute to breast cancer cell invasion through CAF activation and ECM remodeling</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.02</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2020</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancer-associated fibroblasts induce high mobility group box 1 and contribute to resistance to doxorubicin in breast cancer cells</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">46</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2016</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">p16(INK4A) represses the paracrine tumor-promoting effects of breast stromal fibroblasts</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2019</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Stroma in breast development and disease</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.02</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2018</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Human breast cancer invasion and aggression correlates with ECM stiffening and immune cell infiltration</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.06</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2018</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cancer-associated fibroblasts release exosomal microRNAs that dictate an aggressive phenotype in breast cancer</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2021</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Paracrine signaling by platelet-derived growth factor-CC promotes tumor growth by recruitment of cancer-associated fibroblasts</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.04</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2020</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Fibroblast Subtypes Regulate Responsivenessof Luminal Breast Cancer to Estrogen</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2017</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Autophagy in cancer associated fibroblasts promotes tumor cell survival: Role of hypoxia, HIF1 induction and NFκB activation in the tumor stromal microenvironment</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.04</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2020</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par49">Conducting bibliographic coupling analysis using VOSviewer bibliographic coupling is used to examine the connections between scientific publications. When two documents are simultaneously cited by a third publication, they form a bibliographic coupling pair, with the coupling strength indicating the similarity of their research topics. In the visualization, each node represents a document, labeled with the first author’s name and publication year.</p><p id="Par50">As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig10" ref-type="fig">10</xref>, this study set a minimum threshold of 183 co-citations, meaning only document pairs that were jointly cited at least 183 times were considered. Based on this criterion, the 20 most strongly coupled documents were identified. Among them, Pelon (2020), Raz (2018), Cohen (2017), Ershaid (2019), and Martinez Outschoorn (2010) exhibited the highest coupling strengths, indicating their substantial influence and representativeness in this research field. By integrating citation frequency, cited frequency, and centrality analysis, key representative documents can be further identified. These publications are not only widely cited within the field but also demonstrate strong connections with other studies through bibliographic coupling relationships. This analysis provides valuable insights into the research hotspots and emerging directions in the discipline.</p><p id="Par51">
<fig id="Fig10" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 10</label><caption><p>Literature Coupling Visualization Analysis</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1349" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig10_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Discussion</title><sec id="Sec14"><title>General information</title><p id="Par52">This study employs bibliometric methods to evaluate the contributions and influence of research on CAFs in breast cancer across dimensions such as countries, institutions, authors, and journals. Since the first publication in this field in 2005, the number of articles has increased significantly from 2020 to 2024, marking a phase of rapid development. Although there was a decline in publications between 2021 and 2022, the upward trend resumed in 2022, reflecting dynamic shifts in research activity and interest. At the national level, China, the United States, and Italy have contributed the highest number of publications, highlighting their research maturity and academic impact in this field.</p><p id="Par53">A total of 164 journals have published research on breast cancer CAFs, with Cancers being the most prolific, followed by Cell Cycle and Cancer Research. These journals provide scholars with the latest advancements and trends in the field. The top three most published authors are Marcello Maggiolini, Michael P. Lisanti, and Manran Liu, who have made significant contributions to breast cancer CAF research. For instance, Marcello Maggiolini uncovered the mechanism by which CAFs mediate therapy resistance in estrogen-rich microenvironments and proposed phytochemical based intervention strategies. Michael P. Lisanti and Diana Whitaker Menezes, long term research collaborators, jointly proposed a novel mechanism for the Warburg effect, demonstrating that stromal fibroblasts undergo aerobic glycolysis to produce and secrete more pyruvate/lactate, which fuels mitochondrial TCA cycles, oxidative phosphorylation, and metabolism in adjacent epithelial cancer cells. In 2014, they further elucidated how altered signaling pathways in cancer cells drive neighboring CAFs to generate reactive oxygen species and autophagy, thereby supporting cancer growth and metastasis. Their work revealed the critical role of CAF metabolism in breast tumor progression and introduced the “metabolic coupling” model, providing a theoretical foundation for targeting CAF metabolism to improve breast cancer treatment.</p><p id="Par54">Among the top ten most published authors, Diana Whitaker Menezes has the highest average citation count. Her research focuses on the TME and CAFs in breast cancer, establishing the central role of CAFs in metabolic support, ECM stiffening, and therapy resistance. U. E. Martinez Outschoorn investigates the complexity of the TME, collaborating with Michael P. Lisanti and Federica Sotgia to explore metabolic interactions between cancer cells and CAFs. A. Orimo’s research demonstrated that fibroblasts constitute the majority of stromal cells in breast cancer and found that stromal fibroblasts in invasive breast cancer promote tumor growth and angiogenesis through high secretion of stromal cell derived factor1. These studies provide a fundamental understanding of CAF’s role in breast cancer and offer new directions for future research and therapeutic strategies.</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Knowledge base</title><p id="Par55">Based on the results of the literature co-citation network analysis, the research foundation of CAFs in breast cancer can be broadly delineated. Among the top 10 most cited publications, the 2nd, 7th, and 8th articles focus on the tumor-promoting role of CAFs, highlighting their facilitation of breast cancer invasion and growth through various signaling molecules. The 4th and 9th articles explore CAF heterogeneity and the functions of different subtypes, particularly the role of the CAF-S1 subset in breast cancer in modulating regulatory T lymphocytes (Tregs). The 3rd and 10th articles summarize CAF-mediated therapy resistance, including chemotherapy resistance induced by activated CAFs via HMGB1 and the protective role of CAF autophagy under hypoxic conditions in shielding tumor cells from stress induced damage. The 5th and 6th articles propose that CAFs influence breast cancer progression through ECM remodeling, while the 1st article mentions the prognostic value of tumor associated stroma, suggesting CAFs as potential prognostic markers for breast cancer.</p><p id="Par56">Bibliometric co-citation analysis revealed that CAF heterogeneity constitutes the core of the knowledge base in this field (Table <xref rid="Tab6" ref-type="table">6</xref>). Among the cited references, the study by Ana Costa et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>] received the highest citation frequency. This research used six protein markers, including FAP and α-SMA, in combination with flow cytometry sorting and population transcriptome analysis to classify human breast cancer CAFs into four functional subtypes, and clarified the immunosuppressive mechanism of the CAF-S1 subtype.</p><p id="Par57">In the same year, Michael Bartoschek, Nikola Oskolkov et al. employed single cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) to perform unbiased clustering based on transcriptomic similarity, identifying three novel subtypes in a mouse model. Although this study did not rank among the top ten most co-cited works, it significantly advanced the understanding of CAF heterogeneity. These works mark a paradigm shift in research from population level analyses toward single-cell resolution, a transition that is now emerging as a new research frontier [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>].</p><p id="Par58">Ana Costa et al. further elucidated the association between breast cancer CAF subsets and immune suppression, demonstrating that CAF-S1 attracts CD4⁺CD25⁺ Tregs via CXCL12 expression and retains them on its surface through ligands TNFSF4/OX40L and PDCD1LG2/PD-L2, as well as the adhesion molecule JAM2. Moreover, compared to CAF-S4, CAF-S1 increases Treg numbers and enhances their ability to suppress effector T cell proliferation, thereby functionally augmenting Treg activity. These mechanisms enable CAF-S1 in breast cancer to mediate immune suppression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>].</p><p id="Par59">Heather M. Brechbuhl’s research revealed that CAF subtypes influence the sensitivity of breast cancer receptors to estrogen, and their expression affects tumor cell responsiveness to chemotherapeutic agents. Understanding the composition of CAFs in breast cancer may aid in predicting treatment response and prognosis, positioning CAFs as potential targets for drug development [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>].</p><p id="Par60">Jan Kiefer et al. uncovered a positive feedback loop between immunosuppressive ECM-myCAF and TGF-β-myCAF (CAF-S1 clusters) and Tregs, which may contribute to immunotherapy resistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Erik Sahai et al. summarized the conceptual framework of CAFs, providing an overview of breast cancer CAF research: fibroblasts are defined as cells negative for epithelial, endothelial, and leukocyte markers, exhibiting an elongated morphology and lacking oncogenic mutations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. CAFs display phenotypic diversity, and their origin involves a process termed “stromagenesis”, wherein resident fibroblasts undergo some form of tissue dysfunction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. While stromal fibroblasts proliferate extensively in tumor bearing patients, this phenomenon is rarely observed [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. The study also summarized key signals for fibroblast activation and mechanisms underlying CAF activation: heat shock factor 1 contributes to CAF generation, IL-1 promotes CAF phenotype formation, TGF-β family ligands and the lipid mediator lysophosphatidic acid activate signaling pathways, Notch signaling drives CAF phenotypes in breast cancer, and physical changes in the ECM can also activate CAFs. Additionally, other stromal cells in the tumor microenvironment participate in CAF generation. For example, macrophage derived granulin promotes the activation of fibrotic environments in liver metastasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>], illustrating the interplay between cancer and inflammatory regulation. The study further outlined CAF functions, including their association with tumor angiogenesis, interactions with other stromal cells, involvement in ECM deposition and remodeling within the tumor microenvironment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], and their role in promoting tumor growth.</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Research trends and hotspots</title><p id="Par61">By analyzing the 10 most frequently cited terms, the research frontiers and hotspots of CAFs in breast cancer were identified, including CAFs, tumor microenvironment, activation, expression, stromal fibroblasts, EMT, metastasis, and diagnostic/therapeutic strategies. Breast cancer CAFs are activated stromal cells, with research focus primarily on their regulatory mechanisms, exploring the origin, activation, and influencing factors of CAFs, as well as analyzing their functional characteristics and heterogeneity in breast cancer.</p><p id="Par62">Additionally, studies emphasize the interaction between CAFs and cancer stem cells, their synergistic effects with other stromal cells in the tumor microenvironment, and their collective role in regulating tumor progression. Research also investigates the association between CAFs and immunosuppressive regulation, where CAFs secrete cytokines to inhibit immune cell function and promote tumor development. Through bibliometric keyword analysis, this study identified a strong citation burst of the term “stromal fibroblasts” and the central position of “heterogeneity” in the co-occurrence network. These findings indicate that utilizing specific biomarkers such as α-SMA, PDGFRβ, and FAP to characterize CAF heterogeneity and elucidate its functional mechanisms has become a major research focus in the field. The core of this direction lies in distinguishing functionally distinct subpopulations by identifying these biomarkers, thereby confirming the value of CAF biomarkers as potential therapeutic targets and providing a basis for developing precise treatment strategies targeting specific CAF subtypes.</p><sec id="Sec17"><title>Basic functions and characteristics of CAFs in breast cancer</title><sec id="Sec18"><title>Origin and activation of CAFs in breast cancer</title><p id="Par63">In breast cancer, CAFs primarily originate from the activation of resident fibroblasts, but may also derive from the transformation of various cell types including mesenchymal stem cells, adipocytes, and bone marrow derived fibroblasts. Resident fibroblasts can differentiate into distinct CAF phenotypes under the influence of factors such as TGF-β, CXCL12, and co-culture with cancer cells. For instance, TGF-β, CXCL12, Wnt7a, miR-125b, miR-9, as well as chemotherapeutic agents, can induce their conversion into α-SMA⁺ CAFs. The combined action of TGF-β and PDGF promotes the formation of FSP1⁺ CAFs. Mesenchymal stem cells can also transform into CAFs under the influence of tumor-derived exosomes and TGF-β, among other factors. Adipocytes differentiate into FSP1⁺/α-SMA⁻/FAP⁻ CAFs upon Wnt3a stimulation. Bone marrow derived fibroblasts, which are often recruited into the TME with an α-SMA⁺/PDGFRα phenotype, contribute to tumor progression. Pericyte derived CAFs express genes associated with vascular regulation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>].</p><p id="Par64">The activation mechanisms of CAFs encompass cytokine mediated signaling pathways, direct interactions between tumor cells and fibroblasts, and influences from the tumor microenvironment. Cytokines play a key role by binding to their respective receptors: breast cancer cells induce the transformation of normal fibroblasts into CAFs through autocrine TGF-β and CXCL12, thereby shaping a microenvironment conducive to tumor growth and invasion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Following binding to CXCR4 on the fibroblast surface, CXCL12 not only activates the cells and upregulates α-SMA expression but also promotes the secretion of TGF-β and CXCL12, establishing a positive feedback loop that further enhances activation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. TGF-β binding to its receptors not only activates fibroblasts and induces α-SMA expression but also regulates metabolic processes such as glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. PDGF binding to its receptor, in synergy with TGF-β, downregulates isocitrate dehydrogenase 3α IDH3α, elevates levels of α-ketoglutarate and hypoxia-inducible factor 1α HIF-1α, thereby enhancing glycolysis and reducing oxidative phosphorylation. Wnt7a, a member of the Wnt family, participates in fibroblast activation by engaging TGF-β receptors. Osteopontin OPN binds to CD44 and integrin αvβ3, upregulating the expression of markers such as α-SMA, FSP-1, and FAP via the AKT and MAPK1 signaling pathways, and promotes the secretion of factors including CXCL1, CXCL2, COX-2, IL-6, OPN, and collagen.</p><p id="Par65">Furthermore, breast cancer cells regulate fibroblast activation through exosome carried miRNAs such as miR-370-3p and proteins like survivin. miR-370-3p can enhance the stemness, migration, and invasion capabilities of cancer cells [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>], while survivin transferred via exosomes upregulates SOD1 expression, thereby inducing CAF transformation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Heterogeneity of CAFs in breast cancer</title><p id="Par66">CAFs are highly heterogeneous and lack a unified marker, as their phenotype and function vary across different subsets and molecular subtypes of breast cancer. Studies have shown that CAFs in HER2-positive breast cancer differ significantly from those in triple-negative and ER-positive breast cancers in terms of genes related to cytoskeleton and integrin signaling [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. For instance, invasive lobular carcinoma exhibits overexpression of FAP, FSP1, and PDGFRβ, whereas ductal carcinoma demonstrates higher expression of prolyl 4-hydroxylase, PDGFRα, and chondroitin sulfate proteoglycan [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. The application of single-cell RNA sequencing scRNA-seq has advanced research on CAF heterogeneity by enabling unbiased clustering based on whole transcriptome expression profiles. This approach has facilitated the identification of subpopulations such as vCAFs, mCAFs, and dCAFs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], thereby refining the CAF classification framework.</p><p id="Par67">CAFs exhibit phenotypic heterogeneity reflected by various biomarkers including PDGFRα/β, CD90/THY1, PDPN, α-SMA, FSP-1, FAP, FN1, VIM, CD29, CD10, and GPR77. The expression of these markers is unique to specific CAF subpopulations and demonstrates tissue-specific variation. Based on α-SMA and FAP expression levels, human breast cancer CAFs can be classified into four subtypes, designated CAF-S1 to CAF-S4. CAF-S1 and CAF-S4 are predominantly enriched within the tumor interior, CAF-S3 is more frequently observed in the peritumoral region, while CAF-S2 is uniformly distributed. The CAF-S1 subtype recruits Tregs and promotes their differentiation through the secretion of CXCL12. It also highly expresses immunomodulatory ligands such as PD-L2 and OX40L, mediating T cell exhaustion and enhanced Treg function, thereby driving immunosuppression and drug resistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. In contrast, the CAF-S4 subtype lacks immunoregulatory capacity. scRNA-seq has further identified FSP-1-positive CAFs and PDPN positive CAFs, whose proportions are associated with BRCA mutations and clinical outcomes in triple-negative breast cancer [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>].</p><p id="Par68">The heterogeneity and plasticity of CAFs profoundly influence the tumor microenvironment and tumor progression. Their differences from normal fibroblasts NFs are evident in the expression of specific protein markers. For instance, α-SMA-positive CAFs provide metabolic support for tumors by producing lactate and pyruvate [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. VIM, a marker of cell structure and migration, contributes to advanced metastasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. FAP accelerates tumor progression through ECM remodeling and fibrosis, and promotes the formation of an immunosuppressive TME [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. Elevated levels of PDGFRα/β are also closely associated with CAF activation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]. Research targeting these biomarkers provides a critical foundation for developing targeted therapeutic strategies for breast cancer.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>CAFs promote breast cancer cell progression</title><p id="Par69">TME is influenced by CAFs, which interact with the TME to modulate breast cancer cell progression. CAFs play a role in interfering with breast cancer cell metastasis, and the extensive proliferation of mammary connective tissue results in CAFs constituting up to 80% of the tumor mass, making them the most prevalent stromal cell component in the breast TME [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]. The complexity of CAF-TME interactions is mutually influential [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>], and the transformation and activation of CAFs are fundamental to cancer progression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. Upon activation, NFs promote cancer cell development through various mechanisms, including the secretion of growth factors, chemokines, and interleukins. Growth factors can directly activate fibroblasts, and CAFs also secrete a multitude of autocrine and paracrine cytokines, as well as other pro-tumor factors, to modulate the environment and create a microclimate conducive to tumor growth and metastasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>].</p><p id="Par70">The most representative growth factor is transforming growth TGF-β, which plays a critical role in breast cancer progression by participating in ECM mechanical sensing and myofibroblast differentiation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>]. In the TME, CAFs secrete substantial amounts of TGF-β, activating the TGF-β/Smad signaling pathway in breast cancer cells and driving tumor progression. The communication between CAFs and tumor cells is bidirectional: tumor cells can secrete TGF-β themselves or mediate the transformation of stromal fibroblasts into CAFs through paracrine signaling, altering the TME and promoting tumor development and dissemination.Studies have shown that Grem1, a bone morphogenetic protein antagonist produced by CAFs, promotes fibroblast activation and breast cancer cell infiltration and extravasation, driving the formation of micrometastases, which is the initial step in the invasion metastasis cascade [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. Additionally, the lack of CAV-1 in fibroblasts leads to increased TGF-β secretion, activating the TGF-β/Smad signaling pathway in breast cancer and promoting tumor metastasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. Other growth factors also participate in remodeling the TME and facilitating cancer cell metastasis. For example, CAF secreted factors such as hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), nerve growth factor, connective tissue growth factor, and basic fibroblast growth factor are all involved in breast cancer metastasis and invasion.Among these, HGF secreted by CAFs exhibits a bidirectional interaction with breast cancer cells: breast cancer cells can reprogram surrounding NFs, transforming them into CAFs or key stage cells; meanwhile, HGF secreted by CAFs plays a significant role in breast cancer progression, with its secretion levels positively correlated with mammary tumorigenesis, cell migration, and invasive capacity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>], thereby driving the metastatic process. Breast cancer cells induce fibroblasts to secrete HGF, further enhancing the pro-tumor effects of CAFs and establishing a mutually reinforcing relationship.</p><p id="Par71">Chemokines and their receptors mediate chemotaxis and are deeply involved in tumorigenesis and progression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>]. The association between CAFs and the chemokine CXCL12 is particularly significant: on one hand, chemokines secreted by CAFs regulate the cytoskeleton of mammary tumor cells, influencing their motility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]; on the other hand, OPN secreted by cancer cells stimulates CAFs to secrete more CXCL12. The increased CXCL12 triggers EMT in tumor cells, enhancing their invasive and metastatic potential [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>]. Additionally, CXCL12 produced by CAFs acts on endothelial cells, modulates the tumor microenvironment, and stimulates tumor cells through inflammatory mechanisms, activating the Notch1 signaling pathway and increasing CXCL8 production, thereby enhancing tumor cell metastatic activity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>] IL-6 is widely present in the tumor microenvironment. Studies have shown that IL-6 reduces the expression of the tumor suppressor HIC1 and promotes breast cancer progression through paracrine or autocrine signaling [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>].</p><p id="Par72">CAFs mediate breast cancer metastasis through exosomes, which are enriched with miRNAs that can be taken up by tumor cells to regulate target gene expression, promoting breast cancer progression and metastasis. Additionally, CAFs interact with stromal cells such as macrophages and TANs, participating in angiogenesis and ECM remodeling. Angiogenesis is critical for the formation of premetastatic niches, while ECM remodeling is a necessary step for tumor cell invasion and metastasis. CAFs primarily promote angiogenesis through the VEGF dependent classical pathway [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>]. The binding of VEGF to VEGFR activates downstream signaling pathways, prompting vascular endothelial cells to develop into mature blood vessels, which supply nutrients to the tumor and remove metabolic waste, thereby facilitating tumor growth and metastasis.The ECM, composed of structural proteins, proteoglycans, and glycoproteins, has mechanical properties closely related to CAFs. Dynamic remodeling of the ECM leads to changes in tumor cell density, tissue stiffness, and structure, causing structural alterations in the TME due to force transmission, which creates conditions for directional cancer cell migration and invasion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>]. CAFs enhance tumor invasion and metastasis by promoting ECM protein deposition, secreting growth factors, and remodeling the ECM.</p></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Targeting CAFs in breast cancer for therapeutic intervention</title><p id="Par73">As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref>, synergistic therapeutic approaches targeting CAFs involve cellular reprogramming to deactivate their pro-tumor functions, combined with natural compounds and chemotherapeutic agents. In terms of immune regulation, the CAF-S1 subpopulation facilitates the recruitment and enhanced infiltration and survival of Tregs within the TME through the secretion of factors such as CXCL12, thereby establishing an immunosuppressive milieu. This process undermines antitumor immune responses and contributes to resistance to immunotherapy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. CAFs induce cytotoxic T cell death in an antigen independent manner by activating apoptotic ligands and LAG-3, further weakening anti-tumor immunity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>]. Studies have identified a senescent CAF population in breast cancer that promotes tumor progression by inhibiting the anti-tumor response of NK cells. senCAFs form physical or chemical barriers that impede NK cell infiltration into tumor cells and interfere with NK cell cytotoxicity through ECM secretion. Eliminating senCAFs significantly delays tumorigenesis, suggesting their potential as a therapeutic target in breast cancer [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>]. As key cells in the TME, CAFs participate in tumor immune escape by communicating with other cells and secreting ECM components, modulating the functions of myeloid and lymphoid cells. Therapeutic strategies targeting CAFs may disrupt this process [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>].</p><p id="Par74">
<fig id="Fig11" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 11</label><caption><p>Synergistic Therapy for Breast Cancer via CAF-Targeting</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1577" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_Fig11_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par75">TME in breast cancer influences cancer cell metastasis, with the transformation of normal stromal fibroblasts into CAFs being a critical step in the transition to a pre-cancerous microenvironment, as confirmed in studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>]. Intervening in the activation state of CAFs is a key strategy to prevent breast cancer stroma formation, including inhibiting CAF activity to limit their functions or reprogramming active CAFs into quiescent fibroblasts. Both approaches may disrupt the formation of breast cancer stroma, offering new insights for early prevention and treatment of breast cancer [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>].</p><p id="Par76">Targeting CAFs for treatment can be achieved by disrupting the breast cancer tumor microenvironment. First, blocking communication between tumor cells and CAFs, such as targeting the TGF-β1/Smad or CXCL1/CXCR12 signaling axes, can inhibit tumor metastasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>]. Disrupting the ECM, which acts as a protective barrier for tumors, is a potential strategy for anti-tumor therapy. Investigating the interactions between CAFs and immune cells, as well as the role of CAFs in anti-angiogenesis and estrogen related mechanisms particularly focusing on CAF hormone resistance in estrogen related breast cancer subtypes, may provide new insights for blocking CAF functions. CAF mediated chemotherapy resistance is a key mechanism by which they protect tumor cells. CAFs increase IFN expression through paracrine signaling, activating the IFN pathway to induce chemotherapy resistance, while IFN blocking antibodies can inhibit this effect. Chemotherapy-resistant breast cancer cells activate CAFs and induce resistance via the TGF-β/p44/42 MAPK signaling axis, and targeting this pathway may reverse CAF-mediated resistance. Additionally, radiotherapy resistance is associated with CAFs, and inhibiting Dll1-mediated Notch signaling post radiotherapy can reduce CAF numbers and enhance tumor cell radiosensitivity.</p></sec><sec id="Sec22"><title>Emerging CAF-targeting strategies</title><p id="Par77">In addition to traditional signaling pathway blockade strategies such as TGF-β and CXCL12/CXCR4 axis, various novel CAF-targeting approaches have emerged in recent years and gradually become research hotspots. The central role of FAP in heterogeneity and drug resistance-related clusters underscores its importance as a therapeutic target, a finding that naturally extends to cutting edge fields such as FAP-directed CAR-T therapy. Similarly, research foci on overcoming drug resistance (blue cluster) and enhancing immunotherapy (green cluster) have found technological solutions in nanoparticle delivery systems. By incorporating chemotherapy drugs into nanoparticle technology to improve targeting efficiency, nanoparticles can simultaneously inhibit CAF formation, enhance therapeutic efficacy, reduce toxicity, and activate the immune microenvironment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>]. Current explorations are actively investigating the use of this technology to eliminate CAFs or disrupt their tumor promoting functions. Although emerging strategies like CAR-T therapy have not yet manifested in bibliometric data due to their novelty, they represent a natural progression of research trends. Specifically, FAP-specific chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy (FAP-CAR-T) has demonstrated in breast cancer models the ability to selectively eliminate FAP⁺ CAFs, thereby disrupting the tumor stromal barrier and enhancing T-cell infiltration and anti-tumor immunity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. The strong co-occurrence of “metabolism” with tumor growth and stemness in the red cluster highlights the importance of targeting CAF metabolic reprogramming to cut off their energy supply to tumors.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec23"><title>Future</title><p id="Par78">With advancements in medical technology, breast cancer treatment has developed mature strategies, including early screening, prevention, diagnosis, chemotherapy, and drug therapy. Targeting the immune regulation mediated by CAFs, the interaction signaling pathways between CAFs and tumor cells, and the metabolic mechanisms involved in breast cancer progression can lead to the development of CAF targeted drugs that block CAF driven tumor progression and overcome chemotherapy and radiotherapy resistance. Currently, CAFs have become a focal point in drug development as a therapeutic target for breast cancer. The heterogeneity of CAFs contributes to immune suppression, weakening anti-tumor immune responses and promoting breast cancer development.</p><p id="Par79">However, the clinical translation of these targeting strategies still faces significant challenges, with most remaining in the exploratory stage: FAP targeted therapies such as FAP-CAR-T cells and antibody-drug conjugates are predominantly in the preclinical or early clinical trial phase .Their development is primarily limited by on-target/off-tumor toxicity, due to low-level FAP expression in bone marrow and healing tissues, as well as the high heterogeneity of the tumor stroma, leading to inconsistent treatment responses and considerable potential risks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>]. PDGFRβ inhibitors, such as imatinib and nintedanib. Although evaluated in multiple clinical trials, their efficacy as monotherapies is generally limited and has not significantly improved patient outcomes. This highlights the redundancy and compensatory capacity of CAF signaling pathways, underscoring the need for future research to explore combination strategies with chemotherapy, targeted therapy, or immunotherapy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>]. α-SMA as a broadly expressed activation marker, directly targeting α-SMA itself is not feasible. Current strategies instead focus on modulating its upstream activation pathways, such as through the use of TGF-β inhibitors, or inhibiting its downstream functional outputs, for instance by interfering with ECM remodeling, thereby indirectly targeting myofibroblast like CAF subsets with high α-SMA expression [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. Bridging the gap between research findings and clinical application remains a major challenge and a key direction for future efforts. Moving forward, research should not only focus on refining immunotherapeutic strategies by modulating CAF activity to revert them to a quiescent fibroblast state but also prioritize: Developing patient stratification strategies based on CAF biomarker profiles to precisely identify populations likely to benefit from specific interventions; Designing innovative clinical trials that combine drugs targeting specific CAF subpopulations with existing therapies such as immunotherapy, chemotherapy, and radiotherapy to test synergistic effects; Leveraging novel delivery systems such as nanotechnology to enhance drug accumulation and specificity within the tumor stroma, overcome resistance mechanisms, and ultimately improve treatment outcomes for patients.</p></sec><sec id="Sec24"><title>Advantages and disadvantages</title><p id="Par80">The data for this study were sourced from the WOSCC, a comprehensive academic literature indexing database that covers renowned multidisciplinary journals and is updated daily. As a literature retrieval tool, WOSCC ensures the credibility and high quality of the literature data, providing a solid foundation for bibliometric analysis. In terms of analytical methods, three bibliometric tools, VOSviewer, CiteSpace, and WPS Office, were employed to conduct visual analysis of the relevant literature. This approach minimizes bias caused by subjective information filtering, ensuring the objectivity and accuracy of the research findings. Compared to traditional reviews, this study, through visual analysis and systematic review, presents a more intuitive and comprehensive overview of the hotspots and frontiers in the field of breast cancer related CAFs.</p><p id="Par81">However, this study has several limitations. Owing to constraints in data sources, literature from non SCI journals or other databases may not have been included, which could affect the comprehensiveness of the findings. Additionally, the assessment of literature relies primarily on citation frequency and publication counts. While useful, these metrics may not fully capture the multidimensional value of research, such as its innovativeness or potential for practical application. Future studies should aim to incorporate broader data sources and additional evaluation metrics to provide a more holistic understanding.</p><p id="Par82">It is also important to note that breast cancer represents a major global health challenge, yet significant geographical disparities exist in research resources and output. High income countries dominate the research agenda on CAFs, whereas regions with high incidence rates and poor prognoses are markedly underrepresented. This geographical bias may lead to a understanding of breast cancer biology that is derived from non-representative populations, thereby limiting the global applicability of research findings. Furthermore, it impedes the translation of knowledge into clinically effective strategies tailored to local contexts, ultimately exacerbating worldwide disparities in prognosis.To address these challenges, we propose the following recommendations: First, international research funding agencies should prioritize supporting substantive collaboration with scholars from high burden regions, rather than engaging in one way data or sample extraction. Second, investment in local research capacity building is essential to cultivate domestic talent and achieve a sustainable research ecosystem. Furthermore, future research designs should intentionally include more diverse populations to ensure the generalizability of findings.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec25"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par83">This study systematically evaluated the current research status of breast CAFs through bibliometric analysis, covering dimensions such as publication date, country, institution, author, and literature source, while also Summarizeing research trends, hotspots, and frontier directions. The results indicate that CAFs in breast cancer originate from diverse sources and play a crucial role in tumor development. CAFs participate in tumor microenvironment remodeling through multiple mechanisms, with angiogenesis and ECM remodeling being key prerequisites for tumor cell progression. In response to the tumor-promoting effects of CAFs, this study proposes strategies to target and block CAF related signaling pathways to inhibit cancer cell metastasis and invasion. The research also explores the interaction mechanisms between CAFs and breast cancer cells, suggesting potential methods to disrupt CAF mediated interference in the tumor microenvironment.</p><p id="Par84">CAFs not only promote tumor cell progression but also protect tumor cells from the effects of anti-cancer drugs by secreting cytokines and growth factors, leading to drug resistance. Therefore, therapeutic strategies targeting CAFs hold promise for overcoming this protective effect and addressing the issue of anti-cancer drug resistance. However, research on CAF targeted therapies for breast cancer remains exploratory, requiring further in depth studies to elucidate their mechanisms of action and clinical application potential.</p></sec><sec id="Sec26" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>Below is the link to the electronic supplementary material.</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12672_2025_3943_MOESM1_ESM.zip" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 1.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn><fn><p>Shixue Jing, Siping Zhou and Cui Jia are contributed equally to this work.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>Not applicable.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>Research conducted by Shixue Jing, Siping Zhou, Lushun Zhang and Xinlian Liu; Data collection, Siping Zhou, Yongfeng Wang and Cui Jia; Visualization by Siping Zhou, Xinlian Liu and Hui Cao; Initial drafting by Siping Zhou, Shixue Jing, Yongfeng Wang and Xinlian Liu; Review and editing by Shinxue Jing, Cui Jia, Hui Cao, Lushun Zhang and Xinlian Liu; Oversight by Hui Cao and Shixue Jing; Funding secured by Lushun Zhang and Xinlian Liu. The published version of the manuscript has been read and approved by all authors.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported by the Open Fund of Development and Regeneration Key Laboratory of Sichuan Province (Grant No.23LHPDZYB07), the Chinese Ministry of Education Cooperative Education Project (Grant No.231100882305626), and the National College Student Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program Project (Grant No.202413705016).</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>All the data generated or analyzed during this study are included in this paper. Further enquiries can be directed to the corresponding author.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar3"><title>Ethics approval</title><p id="Par85">This study is a systematic review and does not involve human or animal subjects. Therefore, ethical approval from an institutional review board was not required.</p></notes><notes id="FPar4"><title>Consent to participate</title><p id="Par86">As this study did not involve direct participation of any human subjects, informed consent was not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar1"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par87">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par88">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wilkinson</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gathani</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Understanding breast cancer as a global health concern</article-title><source>Br J Radiol</source><year>2022</year><volume>95</volume><issue>1130</issue><fpage>20211033</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1259/bjr.20211033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34905391</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8822551</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Wilkinson L, Gathani T. Understanding breast cancer as a global health concern. Br J Radiol. 2022;95(1130):20211033.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34905391</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1259/bjr.20211033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8822551</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Molecular classification of breast cancer: relevance and challenges</article-title><source>Arch Pathol Lab Med</source><year>2023</year><volume>147</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>46</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5858/arpa.2022-0070-RA</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36136295</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Zhang X. Molecular classification of breast cancer: relevance and challenges. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2023;147(1):46–51.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36136295</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5858/arpa.2022-0070-RA</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park M, Kim D, Ko S, Kim A, Mo K, Yoon H. Breast cancer metastasis: mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(12):6806. 10.3390/ijms23126806<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/ijms23126806</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9224686</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35743249</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bhowmick</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Neilson</surname><given-names>EG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moses</surname><given-names>HL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Stromal fibroblasts in cancer initiation and progression</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2004</year><volume>432</volume><issue>7015</issue><fpage>332</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature03096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15549095</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3050735</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Bhowmick NA, Neilson EG, Moses HL. Stromal fibroblasts in cancer initiation and progression. Nature. 2004;432(7015):332–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15549095</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/nature03096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3050735</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sahai</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Astsaturov</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cukierman</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>DeNardo</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Egeblad</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Evans</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A framework for advancing our Understanding of cancer-associated fibroblasts</article-title><source>Nat Rev Cancer</source><year>2020</year><volume>20</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>174</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41568-019-0238-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31980749</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7046529</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Sahai E, Astsaturov I, Cukierman E, DeNardo DG, Egeblad M, Evans RM, et al. A framework for advancing our Understanding of cancer-associated fibroblasts. Nat Rev Cancer. 2020;20(3):174–86.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31980749</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41568-019-0238-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7046529</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalluri</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The biology and function of fibroblasts in cancer</article-title><source>Nat Rev Cancer</source><year>2016</year><volume>16</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>582</fpage><lpage>98</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrc.2016.73</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27550820</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Kalluri R. The biology and function of fibroblasts in cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2016;16(9):582–98.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27550820</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/nrc.2016.73</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>De Wever</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names>QD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Van Hoorde</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bracke</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bruyneel</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gespach</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Tenascin-C and SF/HGF produced by myofibroblasts in vitro provide convergent pro-invasive signals to human colon cancer cells through RhoA and Rac</article-title><source>Faseb J</source><year>2004</year><volume>18</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1016</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1096/fj.03-1110fje</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15059978</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">De Wever O, Nguyen QD, Van Hoorde L, Bracke M, Bruyneel E, Gespach C, et al. Tenascin-C and SF/HGF produced by myofibroblasts in vitro provide convergent pro-invasive signals to human colon cancer cells through RhoA and Rac. Faseb J. 2004;18(9):1016–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15059978</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1096/fj.03-1110fje</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Calvo</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ege</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grande-Garcia</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hooper</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jenkins</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chaudhry</surname><given-names>SI</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mechanotransduction and YAP-dependent matrix remodelling is required for the generation and maintenance of cancer-associated fibroblasts</article-title><source>Nat Cell Biol</source><year>2013</year><volume>15</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>637</fpage><lpage>46</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncb2756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23708000</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3836234</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Calvo F, Ege N, Grande-Garcia A, Hooper S, Jenkins RP, Chaudhry SI, et al. Mechanotransduction and YAP-dependent matrix remodelling is required for the generation and maintenance of cancer-associated fibroblasts. Nat Cell Biol. 2013;15(6):637–46.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23708000</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/ncb2756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3836234</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>CT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gualdrini</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Treisman</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Mutual dependence of the MRTF-SRF and YAP-TEAD pathways in cancer-associated fibroblasts is indirect and mediated by cytoskeletal dynamics</article-title><source>Genes Dev</source><year>2017</year><volume>31</volume><issue>23–24</issue><fpage>2361</fpage><lpage>75</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1101/gad.304501.117</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29317486</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5795783</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Foster CT, Gualdrini F, Treisman R. Mutual dependence of the MRTF-SRF and YAP-TEAD pathways in cancer-associated fibroblasts is indirect and mediated by cytoskeletal dynamics. Genes Dev. 2017;31(23–24):2361–75.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29317486</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1101/gad.304501.117</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5795783</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Houthuijzen</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>de Bruijn</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van der Burg</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Drenth</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wientjens</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Filipovic</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>CD26-negative and CD26-positive tissue-resident fibroblasts contribute to functionally distinct CAF subpopulations in breast cancer</article-title><source>Nat Commun</source><year>2023</year><volume>14</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>183</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-35793-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36635273</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9837080</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Houthuijzen JM, de Bruijn R, van der Burg E, Drenth AP, Wientjens E, Filipovic T, et al. CD26-negative and CD26-positive tissue-resident fibroblasts contribute to functionally distinct CAF subpopulations in breast cancer. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):183.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36635273</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41467-023-35793-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9837080</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Esmaeili</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gopalakrishna-Pillai</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murad</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kumar Reddy</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Human brain metastatic stroma attracts breast cancer cells via chemokines CXCL16 and CXCL12</article-title><source>NPJ Breast Cancer</source><year>2017</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>6</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41523-017-0008-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28649646</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5460196</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Chung B, Esmaeili AA, Gopalakrishna-Pillai S, Murad JP, Andersen ES, Kumar Reddy N, et al. Human brain metastatic stroma attracts breast cancer cells via chemokines CXCL16 and CXCL12. NPJ Breast Cancer. 2017;3:6.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28649646</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41523-017-0008-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5460196</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Costa</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kieffer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scholer-Dahirel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pelon</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bourachot</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cardon</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fibroblast heterogeneity and immunosuppressive environment in human breast cancer</article-title><source>Cancer Cell</source><year>2018</year><volume>33</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>463</fpage><lpage>e7910</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ccell.2018.01.011</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29455927</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Costa A, Kieffer Y, Scholer-Dahirel A, Pelon F, Bourachot B, Cardon M, et al. Fibroblast heterogeneity and immunosuppressive environment in human breast cancer. Cancer Cell. 2018;33(3):463–e7910.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29455927</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ccell.2018.01.011</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bartoschek</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oskolkov</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bocci</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lövrot</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Larsson</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sommarin</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Spatially and functionally distinct subclasses of breast cancer-associated fibroblasts revealed by single cell RNA sequencing</article-title><source>Nat Commun</source><year>2018</year><volume>9</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>5150</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-07582-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30514914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6279758</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Bartoschek M, Oskolkov N, Bocci M, Lövrot J, Larsson C, Sommarin M, et al. Spatially and functionally distinct subclasses of breast cancer-associated fibroblasts revealed by single cell RNA sequencing. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):5150.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30514914</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41467-018-07582-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6279758</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kieffer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hocine</surname><given-names>HR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gentric</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pelon</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bourachot</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Single-Cell analysis reveals fibroblast clusters linked to immunotherapy resistance in cancer</article-title><source>Cancer Discov</source><year>2020</year><volume>10</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1330</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-19-1384</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32434947</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Kieffer Y, Hocine HR, Gentric G, Pelon F, Bernard C, Bourachot B, et al. Single-Cell analysis reveals fibroblast clusters linked to immunotherapy resistance in cancer. Cancer Discov. 2020;10(9):1330–51.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32434947</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-19-1384</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Brechbuhl</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Finlay-Schultz</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gillen</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cittelly</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fibroblast subtypes regulate responsiveness of luminal breast cancer to Estrogen</article-title><source>Clin Cancer Res</source><year>2017</year><volume>23</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1710</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2851</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27702820</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5378660</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Brechbuhl HM, Finlay-Schultz J, Yamamoto TM, Gillen AE, Cittelly DM, Tan AC, et al. Fibroblast subtypes regulate responsiveness of luminal breast cancer to Estrogen. Clin Cancer Res. 2017;23(7):1710–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27702820</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2851</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5378660</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kretzschmar</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weber</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Driskell</surname><given-names>RR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Calonje</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Watt</surname><given-names>FM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Compartmentalized epidermal activation of β-Catenin differentially affects lineage reprogramming and underlies tumor heterogeneity</article-title><source>Cell Rep</source><year>2016</year><volume>14</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>269</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2015.12.041</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26771241</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4713864</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Kretzschmar K, Weber C, Driskell RR, Calonje E, Watt FM. Compartmentalized epidermal activation of β-Catenin differentially affects lineage reprogramming and underlies tumor heterogeneity. Cell Rep. 2016;14(2):269–81.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26771241</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.celrep.2015.12.041</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4713864</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Öhlund</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Handly-Santana</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Biffi</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elyada</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Almeida</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ponz-Sarvise</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Distinct populations of inflammatory fibroblasts and myofibroblasts in pancreatic cancer</article-title><source>J Exp Med</source><year>2017</year><volume>214</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>579</fpage><lpage>96</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1084/jem.20162024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28232471</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5339682</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Öhlund D, Handly-Santana A, Biffi G, Elyada E, Almeida AS, Ponz-Sarvise M, et al. Distinct populations of inflammatory fibroblasts and myofibroblasts in pancreatic cancer. J Exp Med. 2017;214(3):579–96.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28232471</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1084/jem.20162024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5339682</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Quaranta</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Linford</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Emeagi</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rainer</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Santos</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Macrophage-secreted granulin supports pancreatic cancer metastasis by inducing liver fibrosis</article-title><source>Nat Cell Biol</source><year>2016</year><volume>18</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>549</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncb3340</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27088855</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4894551</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Nielsen SR, Quaranta V, Linford A, Emeagi P, Rainer C, Santos A, et al. Macrophage-secreted granulin supports pancreatic cancer metastasis by inducing liver fibrosis. Nat Cell Biol. 2016;18(5):549–60.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27088855</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/ncb3340</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4894551</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Auffray</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dubart</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Izac</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vainchenker</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Coulombel</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A murine stromal cell line promotes the proliferation of the human factor-dependent leukemic cell line UT-7</article-title><source>Exp Hematol</source><year>1994</year><volume>22</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>417</fpage><lpage>24</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7513651</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Auffray I, Dubart A, Izac B, Vainchenker W, Coulombel L. A murine stromal cell line promotes the proliferation of the human factor-dependent leukemic cell line UT-7. Exp Hematol. 1994;22(5):417–24.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7513651</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dumont</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Defilippis</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rabban</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Karnezis</surname><given-names>AN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Breast fibroblasts modulate early dissemination, tumorigenesis, and metastasis through alteration of extracellular matrix characteristics</article-title><source>Neoplasia</source><year>2013</year><volume>15</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>249</fpage><lpage>62</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1593/neo.121950</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23479504</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3593149</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Dumont N, Liu B, Defilippis RA, Chang H, Rabban JT, Karnezis AN, et al. Breast fibroblasts modulate early dissemination, tumorigenesis, and metastasis through alteration of extracellular matrix characteristics. Neoplasia. 2013;15(3):249–62.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23479504</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1593/neo.121950</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3593149</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Madsen</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pedersen</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Venning</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>LB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moeendarbary</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Charras</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hypoxia and loss of PHD2 inactivate stromal fibroblasts to decrease tumour stiffness and metastasis</article-title><source>EMBO Rep</source><year>2015</year><volume>16</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1394</fpage><lpage>408</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.15252/embr.201540107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26323721</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4662858</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Madsen CD, Pedersen JT, Venning FA, Singh LB, Moeendarbary E, Charras G, et al. Hypoxia and loss of PHD2 inactivate stromal fibroblasts to decrease tumour stiffness and metastasis. EMBO Rep. 2015;16(10):1394–408.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26323721</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15252/embr.201540107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4662858</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cancer-associated fibroblasts in breast cancer: challenges and opportunities</article-title><source>Cancer Commun (Lond)</source><year>2022</year><volume>42</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>401</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/cac2.12291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35481621</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9118050</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Hu D, Li Z, Zheng B, Lin X, Pan Y, Gong P, et al. Cancer-associated fibroblasts in breast cancer: challenges and opportunities. Cancer Commun (Lond). 2022;42(5):401–34.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35481621</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/cac2.12291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9118050</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Acar</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eaton</surname><given-names>EN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mellody</surname><given-names>KT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scheel</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ben-Porath</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Autocrine TGF-beta and stromal cell-derived factor-1 (SDF-1) signaling drives the evolution of tumor-promoting mammary stromal myofibroblasts</article-title><source>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</source><year>2010</year><volume>107</volume><issue>46</issue><fpage>20009</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.1013805107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21041659</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2993333</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Kojima Y, Acar A, Eaton EN, Mellody KT, Scheel C, Ben-Porath I, et al. Autocrine TGF-beta and stromal cell-derived factor-1 (SDF-1) signaling drives the evolution of tumor-promoting mammary stromal myofibroblasts. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107(46):20009–14.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21041659</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1073/pnas.1013805107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2993333</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>MicroRNA-370-3p shuttled by breast cancer cell-derived extracellular vesicles induces fibroblast activation through the CYLD/Nf-κB axis to promote breast cancer progression</article-title><source>Faseb J</source><year>2021</year><volume>35</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>e21383</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1096/fj.202001430RR</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33629796</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Ren Z, Lv M, Yu Q, Bao J, Lou K, Li X. MicroRNA-370-3p shuttled by breast cancer cell-derived extracellular vesicles induces fibroblast activation through the CYLD/Nf-κB axis to promote breast cancer progression. Faseb J. 2021;35(3):e21383.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33629796</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1096/fj.202001430RR</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ni</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Survivin in breast cancer-derived exosomes activates fibroblasts by up-regulating SOD1, whose feedback promotes cancer proliferation and metastasis</article-title><source>J Biol Chem</source><year>2020</year><volume>295</volume><issue>40</issue><fpage>13737</fpage><lpage>52</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.RA120.013805</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32709750</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7535909</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Li K, Liu T, Chen J, Ni H, Li W. Survivin in breast cancer-derived exosomes activates fibroblasts by up-regulating SOD1, whose feedback promotes cancer proliferation and metastasis. J Biol Chem. 2020;295(40):13737–52.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32709750</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1074/jbc.RA120.013805</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7535909</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Friedman</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levi-Galibov</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>David</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bornstein</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Giladi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dadiani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cancer-associated fibroblast compositions change with breast cancer progression linking the ratio of S100A4(+) and PDPN(+) CAFs to clinical outcome</article-title><source>Nat Cancer</source><year>2020</year><volume>1</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>692</fpage><lpage>708</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s43018-020-0082-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35122040</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7617059</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Friedman G, Levi-Galibov O, David E, Bornstein C, Giladi A, Dadiani M, et al. Cancer-associated fibroblast compositions change with breast cancer progression linking the ratio of S100A4(+) and PDPN(+) CAFs to clinical outcome. Nat Cancer. 2020;1(7):692–708.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35122040</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s43018-020-0082-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7617059</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Becker</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>O’Connell</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vo</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cain</surname><given-names>MP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tampe</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bizarro</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Epigenetic reprogramming of cancer-Associated fibroblasts deregulates glucose metabolism and facilitates progression of breast cancer</article-title><source>Cell Rep</source><year>2020</year><volume>31</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>107701</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107701</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32492417</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7339325</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Becker LM, O’Connell JT, Vo AP, Cain MP, Tampe D, Bizarro L, et al. Epigenetic reprogramming of cancer-Associated fibroblasts deregulates glucose metabolism and facilitates progression of breast cancer. Cell Rep. 2020;31(9):107701.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32492417</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107701</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7339325</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR28" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vuoriluoto</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Haugen</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kiviluoto</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mpindi</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nevo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gjerdrum</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Vimentin regulates EMT induction by slug and oncogenic H-Ras and migration by governing Axl expression in breast cancer</article-title><source>Oncogene</source><year>2011</year><volume>30</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>1436</fpage><lpage>48</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/onc.2010.509</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21057535</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR28" publication-type="journal">Vuoriluoto K, Haugen H, Kiviluoto S, Mpindi JP, Nevo J, Gjerdrum C, et al. Vimentin regulates EMT induction by slug and oncogenic H-Ras and migration by governing Axl expression in breast cancer. Oncogene. 2011;30(12):1436–48.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21057535</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/onc.2010.509</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kraut</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rettig</surname><given-names>WJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peter</surname><given-names>RU</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fibroblast activation protein: differential expression and Serine protease activity in reactive stromal fibroblasts of melanocytic skin tumors</article-title><source>J Invest Dermatol</source><year>2003</year><volume>120</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>182</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1523-1747.2003.12035.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12542520</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">Huber MA, Kraut N, Park JE, Schubert RD, Rettig WJ, Peter RU, et al. Fibroblast activation protein: differential expression and Serine protease activity in reactive stromal fibroblasts of melanocytic skin tumors. J Invest Dermatol. 2003;120(2):182–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12542520</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1046/j.1523-1747.2003.12035.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR30" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>FAP promotes immunosuppression by Cancer-Associated fibroblasts in the tumor microenvironment via STAT3-CCL2 signaling</article-title><source>Cancer Res</source><year>2016</year><volume>76</volume><issue>14</issue><fpage>4124</fpage><lpage>35</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-15-2973</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27216177</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR30" publication-type="journal">Yang X, Lin Y, Shi Y, Li B, Liu W, Yin W, et al. FAP promotes immunosuppression by Cancer-Associated fibroblasts in the tumor microenvironment via STAT3-CCL2 signaling. Cancer Res. 2016;76(14):4124–35.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27216177</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-15-2973</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR31" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bughda</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dimou</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D’Souza</surname><given-names>RR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klampatsa</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Fibroblast activation protein (FAP)-Targeted CAR-T cells: launching an attack on tumor stroma</article-title><source>Immunotargets Ther</source><year>2021</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/ITT.S291767</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34386436</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8354246</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR31" publication-type="journal">Bughda R, Dimou P, D’Souza RR, Klampatsa A. Fibroblast activation protein (FAP)-Targeted CAR-T cells: launching an attack on tumor stroma. Immunotargets Ther. 2021;10:313–23.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34386436</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/ITT.S291767</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8354246</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR32" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heldin</surname><given-names>CH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Targeting the PDGF signaling pathway in tumor treatment</article-title><source>Cell Commun Signal</source><year>2013</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>97</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1478-811X-11-97</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24359404</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3878225</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR32" publication-type="journal">Heldin CH. Targeting the PDGF signaling pathway in tumor treatment. Cell Commun Signal. 2013;11:97.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24359404</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1478-811X-11-97</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3878225</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR33" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gascard</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tlsty</surname><given-names>TD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Carcinoma-associated fibroblasts: orchestrating the composition of malignancy</article-title><source>Genes Dev</source><year>2016</year><volume>30</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1002</fpage><lpage>19</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1101/gad.279737.116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27151975</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4863733</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR33" publication-type="journal">Gascard P, Tlsty TD. Carcinoma-associated fibroblasts: orchestrating the composition of malignancy. Genes Dev. 2016;30(9):1002–19.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27151975</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1101/gad.279737.116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4863733</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR34" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalluri</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zeisberg</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Fibroblasts in cancer</article-title><source>Nat Rev Cancer</source><year>2006</year><volume>6</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>392</fpage><lpage>401</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrc1877</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16572188</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR34" publication-type="journal">Kalluri R, Zeisberg M. Fibroblasts in cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2006;6(5):392–401.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16572188</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/nrc1877</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ganguly D, Chandra R, Karalis J, Teke M, Aguilera T, Maddipati R et al. Cancer-Associated fibroblasts: versatile players in the tumor microenvironment. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12(9):2652. 10.3390/cancers12092652<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/cancers12092652</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7564346</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32957515</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR36" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Reprogramming of stromal fibroblasts by SNAI2 contributes to tumor desmoplasia and ovarian cancer progression</article-title><source>Mol Cancer</source><year>2017</year><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>163</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12943-017-0732-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29041931</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5645935</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR36" publication-type="journal">Yang Z, Yang X, Xu S, Jin P, Li X, Wei X, et al. Reprogramming of stromal fibroblasts by SNAI2 contributes to tumor desmoplasia and ovarian cancer progression. Mol Cancer. 2017;16(1):163.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29041931</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12943-017-0732-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5645935</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR37" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Peltanova</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Raudenska</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Masarik</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of tumor microenvironment on pathogenesis of the head and neck squamous cell carcinoma: a systematic review</article-title><source>Mol Cancer</source><year>2019</year><volume>18</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>63</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12943-019-0983-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30927923</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6441173</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR37" publication-type="journal">Peltanova B, Raudenska M, Masarik M. Effect of tumor microenvironment on pathogenesis of the head and neck squamous cell carcinoma: a systematic review. Mol Cancer. 2019;18(1):63.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30927923</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12943-019-0983-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6441173</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR38" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Desmoulière</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Geinoz</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gabbiani</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gabbiani</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Transforming growth factor-beta 1 induces alpha-smooth muscle actin expression in granulation tissue myofibroblasts and in quiescent and growing cultured fibroblasts</article-title><source>J Cell Biol</source><year>1993</year><volume>122</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>103</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1083/jcb.122.1.103</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8314838</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2119614</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR38" publication-type="journal">Desmoulière A, Geinoz A, Gabbiani F, Gabbiani G. Transforming growth factor-beta 1 induces alpha-smooth muscle actin expression in granulation tissue myofibroblasts and in quiescent and growing cultured fibroblasts. J Cell Biol. 1993;122(1):103–11.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8314838</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1083/jcb.122.1.103</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2119614</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR39" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smid</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iaria</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Salvatori</surname><given-names>DCF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Dam</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cancer-associated fibroblast-derived Gremlin 1 promotes breast cancer progression</article-title><source>Breast Cancer Res</source><year>2019</year><volume>21</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>109</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13058-019-1194-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31533776</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6751614</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR39" publication-type="journal">Ren J, Smid M, Iaria J, Salvatori DCF, van Dam H, Zhu HJ, et al. Cancer-associated fibroblast-derived Gremlin 1 promotes breast cancer progression. Breast Cancer Res. 2019;21(1):109.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31533776</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13058-019-1194-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6751614</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR40" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>CH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>LD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>QS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>XQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>YM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cancer-associated fibroblasts induce epithelial-mesenchymal transition of breast cancer cells through paracrine TGF-β signalling</article-title><source>Br J Cancer</source><year>2014</year><volume>110</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>724</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/bjc.2013.768</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24335925</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3915130</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR40" publication-type="journal">Yu Y, Xiao CH, Tan LD, Wang QS, Li XQ, Feng YM. Cancer-associated fibroblasts induce epithelial-mesenchymal transition of breast cancer cells through paracrine TGF-β signalling. Br J Cancer. 2014;110(3):724–32.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24335925</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/bjc.2013.768</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3915130</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR41" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tyan</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>WH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>CK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shew</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>KJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Breast cancer cells induce cancer-associated fibroblasts to secrete hepatocyte growth factor to enhance breast tumorigenesis</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2011</year><volume>6</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>e15313</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0015313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21249190</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3020942</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR41" publication-type="journal">Tyan SW, Kuo WH, Huang CK, Pan CC, Shew JY, Chang KJ, et al. Breast cancer cells induce cancer-associated fibroblasts to secrete hepatocyte growth factor to enhance breast tumorigenesis. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(1):e15313.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21249190</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0015313</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3020942</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR42" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Morein</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Erlichman</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ben-Baruch</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Beyond cell motility: the expanding roles of chemokines and their receptors in malignancy</article-title><source>Front Immunol</source><year>2020</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>952</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2020.00952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32582148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7287041</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR42" publication-type="journal">Morein D, Erlichman N, Ben-Baruch A. Beyond cell motility: the expanding roles of chemokines and their receptors in malignancy. Front Immunol. 2020;11:952.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32582148</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fimmu.2020.00952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7287041</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR43" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dvorak</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pettee</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rubinic-Minotti</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Su</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nestor-Kalinoski</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eisenmann</surname><given-names>KM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Carcinoma associated fibroblasts (CAFs) promote breast cancer motility by suppressing mammalian Diaphanous-related formin-2 (mDia2)</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2018</year><volume>13</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>e0195278</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0195278</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29596520</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5875872</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR43" publication-type="journal">Dvorak KM, Pettee KM, Rubinic-Minotti K, Su R, Nestor-Kalinoski A, Eisenmann KM. Carcinoma associated fibroblasts (CAFs) promote breast cancer motility by suppressing mammalian Diaphanous-related formin-2 (mDia2). PLoS ONE. 2018;13(3):e0195278.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29596520</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0195278</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5875872</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR44" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Butti</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nimma</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kundu</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bulbule</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>TVS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gunasekaran</surname><given-names>VP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Tumor-derived osteopontin drives the resident fibroblast to myofibroblast differentiation through Twist1 to promote breast cancer progression</article-title><source>Oncogene</source><year>2021</year><volume>40</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2002</fpage><lpage>17</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41388-021-01663-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33603163</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR44" publication-type="journal">Butti R, Nimma R, Kundu G, Bulbule A, Kumar TVS, Gunasekaran VP, et al. Tumor-derived osteopontin drives the resident fibroblast to myofibroblast differentiation through Twist1 to promote breast cancer progression. Oncogene. 2021;40(11):2002–17.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33603163</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41388-021-01663-2</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR45" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liubomirski</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lerrer</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meshel</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Morein</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rubinstein-Achiasaf</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sprinzak</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Notch-Mediated Tumor-Stroma-Inflammation networks promote invasive properties and CXCL8 expression in Triple-Negative breast cancer</article-title><source>Front Immunol</source><year>2019</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>804</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2019.00804</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31105691</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6492532</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR45" publication-type="journal">Liubomirski Y, Lerrer S, Meshel T, Morein D, Rubinstein-Achiasaf L, Sprinzak D, et al. Notch-Mediated Tumor-Stroma-Inflammation networks promote invasive properties and CXCL8 expression in Triple-Negative breast cancer. Front Immunol. 2019;10:804.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31105691</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fimmu.2019.00804</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6492532</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR46" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Tumor suppressor HIC1 is synergistically compromised by cancer-associated fibroblasts and tumor cells through the IL-6/pSTAT3 axis in breast cancer</article-title><source>BMC Cancer</source><year>2019</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1180</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12885-019-6333-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31795965</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6891969</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR46" publication-type="journal">Sun X, Qu Q, Lao Y, Zhang M, Yin X, Zhu H, et al. Tumor suppressor HIC1 is synergistically compromised by cancer-associated fibroblasts and tumor cells through the IL-6/pSTAT3 axis in breast cancer. BMC Cancer. 2019;19(1):1180.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31795965</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12885-019-6333-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6891969</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR47" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Characteristics and significance of the Pre-metastatic niche</article-title><source>Cancer Cell</source><year>2016</year><volume>30</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>668</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ccell.2016.09.011</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27846389</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR47" publication-type="journal">Liu Y, Cao X. Characteristics and significance of the Pre-metastatic niche. Cancer Cell. 2016;30(5):668–81.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27846389</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ccell.2016.09.011</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR48" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Høye</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Erler</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Structural ECM components in the premetastatic and metastatic niche</article-title><source>Am J Physiol Cell Physiol</source><year>2016</year><volume>310</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>C955</fpage><lpage>67</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00326.2015</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27053524</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR48" publication-type="journal">Høye AM, Erler JT. Structural ECM components in the premetastatic and metastatic niche. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2016;310(11):C955–67.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27053524</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpcell.00326.2015</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hilmi M, Nicolle R, Bousquet C, Neuzillet C. Cancer-Associated fibroblasts: accomplices in the tumor immune evasion. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12(10):2969. 10.3390/cancers12102969<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/cancers12102969</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7602282</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33066357</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR50" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baer</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Faget</surname><given-names>DV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Morikis</surname><given-names>VA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Melam</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Senescent CAFs mediate immunosuppression and drive breast cancer progression</article-title><source>Cancer Discov</source><year>2024</year><volume>14</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1302</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-23-0426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38683161</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11216870</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR50" publication-type="journal">Ye J, Baer JM, Faget DV, Morikis VA, Ren Q, Melam A, et al. Senescent CAFs mediate immunosuppression and drive breast cancer progression. Cancer Discov. 2024;14(7):1302–23.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38683161</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-23-0426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11216870</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR51" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zuo</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hierarchically releasing Bio-Responsive nanoparticles for complete tumor microenvironment modulation via TGF-β pathway Inhibition and TAF reduction</article-title><source>ACS Appl Mater Interfaces</source><year>2021</year><volume>13</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>2256</fpage><lpage>68</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.0c18545</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33423468</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR51" publication-type="journal">Zhang J, Zuo T, Yang J, Hu Z, Wang Z, Xu R, et al. Hierarchically releasing Bio-Responsive nanoparticles for complete tumor microenvironment modulation via TGF-β pathway Inhibition and TAF reduction. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2021;13(2):2256–68.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33423468</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1021/acsami.0c18545</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR52" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meng</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Reversing activity of cancer associated fibroblast for staged glycolipid micelles against internal breast tumor cells</article-title><source>Theranostics</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><issue>23</issue><fpage>6764</fpage><lpage>79</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7150/thno.36334</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31660067</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6815968</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR52" publication-type="journal">Zhu Y, Yu F, Tan Y, Hong Y, Meng T, Liu Y, et al. Reversing activity of cancer associated fibroblast for staged glycolipid micelles against internal breast tumor cells. Theranostics. 2019;9(23):6764–79.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31660067</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7150/thno.36334</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6815968</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR53" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Madison</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wilhelm</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meehan</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gratton</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vosik</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Samuelson</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Ramipril therapy in integrin α1-null, autosomal recessive Alport mice triples lifespan: mechanistic clues from RNA-seq analysis</article-title><source>J Pathol</source><year>2024</year><volume>262</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>296</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/path.6231</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38129319</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10872630</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR53" publication-type="journal">Madison J, Wilhelm K, Meehan DT, Gratton MA, Vosik D, Samuelson G, et al. Ramipril therapy in integrin α1-null, autosomal recessive Alport mice triples lifespan: mechanistic clues from RNA-seq analysis. J Pathol. 2024;262(3):296–309.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38129319</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/path.6231</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10872630</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR54" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Berrell</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sadeghirad</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blick</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bidgood</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Leggatt</surname><given-names>GR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>O’Byrne</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Metabolomics at the tumor microenvironment interface: decoding cellular conversations</article-title><source>Med Res Rev</source><year>2024</year><volume>44</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1121</fpage><lpage>46</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/med.22010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38146814</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR54" publication-type="journal">Berrell N, Sadeghirad H, Blick T, Bidgood C, Leggatt GR, O’Byrne K, et al. Metabolomics at the tumor microenvironment interface: decoding cellular conversations. Med Res Rev. 2024;44(3):1121–46.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38146814</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/med.22010</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR55"><label>55.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR55" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maynard</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McCoach</surname><given-names>CE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rotow</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Haderk</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kerr</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Therapy-Induced evolution of human lung cancer revealed by Single-Cell RNA sequencing</article-title><source>Cell</source><year>2020</year><volume>182</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1232</fpage><lpage>e5122</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.07.017</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32822576</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7484178</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR55" publication-type="journal">Maynard A, McCoach CE, Rotow JK, Harris L, Haderk F, Kerr DL, et al. Therapy-Induced evolution of human lung cancer revealed by Single-Cell RNA sequencing. Cell. 2020;182(5):1232–e5122.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32822576</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cell.2020.07.017</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7484178</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>