<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41522205</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of upper limb sensorimotor training and resistance training in the management of patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>30</StartPage><MedlinePgn>30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">30</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-025-01839-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Type 2 diabetes (T2D) is a major global health concern characterized by chronic hyperglycemia and progressive multisystem involvement. One of its most prevalent complications is diabetic peripheral neuropathy which contributes to impaired neuromuscular function, reduced sensation, diminished motor control and functional disability of the upper limb (UL).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We evaluated the efficacy of sensorimotor training (SMT) and resistance training (RT) on grip strength, manual dexterity and neurophysiological evaluation in patients suffering from T2D. This study might contribute to better management of UL functions in these patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Randomized controlled trial (RCT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">96 T2D patients were allocated into RT group; SMT group; and control group. Primary outcomes i.e. grip strength and manual dexterity as well as secondary outcomes i.e. musculocutaneous nerve latency (MCNL), musculocutaneous nerve action potential amplitude (MCNAPA), axillary nerve latency (ANL) and axillary nerve action potential amplitude (ANAPA) were measured at three-time points. Data was analyzed using repeated-measures ANOVA with post-hoc testing, and a significance level of <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 was adopted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Within-group comparison pointed to a statistically significant improvement for all the variables (grip strength <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, manual dexterity <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, MCNL: <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05; MCNAPA: <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05; ANL: <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05; ANAPA: <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) in both experimental groups. For between-group comparisons, <i>p</i>-value was&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 for grip strength and nerve amplitude in RT group whereas <i>p</i>-value was&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 for manual dexterity and nerve latency in SMT group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Both the experimental groups showed improvement in all the outcome variables. RT was more effective in improving grip strength and nerve amplitude whereas in SMT group, there was more improvement in manual dexterity and nerve latency. Further study was needed to generalize these results as it was a single-centered study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s40200-025-01839-7.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2026. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boora</LastName><ForeName>Mamta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Guru Jambheshwar University of Science and Technology, Hisar, Haryana 125001 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02zpxgh81</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411892.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0500 4297</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaur</LastName><ForeName>Jaspreet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Guru Jambheshwar University of Science and Technology, Hisar, Haryana 125001 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02zpxgh81</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411892.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0500 4297</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sensorimotor training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upper limb</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41522205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12783493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-025-01839-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bawadi H, Alkhatib D, Abu-Hijleh H, Alalwani J, Majed L, Shi Z. Muscle strength and glycaemic control among patients with type 2 diabetes. Nutrients. 2020;12(3):771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MAB, Hashim MJ, King JK, Govender RD, Mustafa H, Al Kaabi J. Epidemiology of type 2 diabetes - global burden of disease and forecasted trends. J Epidemiol Glob Health. 2020;10(1):107&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7310804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32175717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Saeedi P, Karuranga S, Pinkepank M, Ogurtsova K, Duncan BB, et al. IDF diabetes atlas: global, regional and country-level diabetes prevalence estimates for 2021 and projections for 2045. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;183:109119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi SA, Patel VD, Eapen C, Hariharan K. Proportion and distribution of upper extremity musculoskeletal disorders and its association with disability in type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Hand Ther. 2022;35(4):597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34016518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto M, Kato Y, Takeuchi J. Hand function and quality of life in patients with diabetes mellitus before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. Nagoya J Med Sci. 2023;85(4):659&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10751486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung CHC, Au Yeung SL, Fong SSM, Schooling CM. Lean mass, grip strength and risk of type 2 diabetes: a bi-directional Mendelian randomisation study. Diabetologia. 2019;62(5):789&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30798333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putranata H, Hengky A, Hartoko B. Unraveling the role of muscle mass and strength in predicting type 2 diabetes risk: a systematic review. Acta Diabetol. 2025;62(2):157&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39760787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim GH, Song BK, Kim JW, et al. Associations between relative grip strength and type 2 diabetes mellitus: the Yangpyeong cohort of the Korean genome and epidemiology study. PLoS One. 2021;16(8):e0256550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34437604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. Grip strength: an indispensable biomarker for older adults. Clin Interv Aging. 2019;14:1681&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6778477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31631989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahrjerdi S, Bahrpeyma F, Savelberg HHCM, Mohajeri-Tehrani MR. Effect of a 6-week strength-training program on neuromuscular efficiency in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetol Int. 2020;11(4):376&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33088645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidi S, Samad AA. Assessment of nerve conduction velocity slowing and its association with the severity of diabetic polyneuropathy, duration of diabetes and glycemic control in diabetic patients. Pak J Med Sci. 2025;41(3):699&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11911748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40103903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AANEM Professional Practice Committee. Establishing standards for acceptable waveforms in nerve conduction studies. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(3):280&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31674675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz-Novoa M, Kristoffersen MB, Sunnerhagen KS, Naber A, Alt Murphy M, Ortiz-Catalan M. Upper limb stroke rehabilitation using surface electromyography: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16:897870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viswanathan V, Ahmed Khan B, Nachimuthu S, Kumpatla S. Precision of Michigan Neuropathy Screening Instrument (MNSI) tool for the diagnosis of diabetic peripheral neuropathy among people with type 2 diabetes-a study from South India. Int J Low Extrem Wounds. 2025;24(4):1152&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36924005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Lu G. A randomized controlled trial to determine the impact of resistance training versus aerobic training on the management of FGF-21 and related physiological variables in obese men with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(1):495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11366843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39228768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry HA, Roberts MD, Kavazis AN. Human skeletal muscle mitochondrial adaptations following resistance exercise training. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41(6):349&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung DE, Moon DC. Effect of the application of local vibration in scaption on joint stability. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27(1):115&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4305538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25642051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dboba MM, Mohd Nordin NA, Manaf H, Mohd Rasdi HF, Abdul Aziz AF. Constraint-induced movement therapy with or without neuromuscular electrical stimulation versus conventional therapy for upper extremity function in chronic stroke survivors: protocol for a cluster randomized controlled trial. JMIR Res Protoc. 2025;14:e68340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12426565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40874667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi Y, Taghizadeh G, Azad A, Behzadipour S. The effects of supervised and non-supervised upper limb virtual reality exercises on upper limb sensory-motor functions in patients with idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Hum Mov Sci. 2022;85:102977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35932518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad I, Verma S, Noohu MM, Shareef MY, Hussain ME. Sensorimotor and gait training improves proprioception, nerve function, and muscular activation in patients with diabetic peripheral neuropathy: a randomized control trial. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2020;20(2):234&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32481239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Manzano P, Rodriguez-Ayllon M, Acosta FM, Niederseer D, Niebauer J. Beyond general resistance training. Hypertrophy versus muscular endurance training as therapeutic interventions in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2020;21(6):e13007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32067343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Dennis SM, Kiernan MC, Harmer AR. Aerobic exercise training may improve nerve function in type 2 diabetes and pre-diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2019;35(2):e3099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brobakken MF, Krogsaeter I, Helgerud J, Wang E, Hoff J. Abdominal aerobic endurance exercise reveals spot reduction exists: a randomized controlled trial. Physiol Rep. 2023;11(22):e15853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10680576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38010201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butcher NJ, Mew EJ, Monsour A, Chan A-W, Moher D, Offringa M. Guidelines for reporting outcomes in trial reports: the CONSORT-outcomes 2022 extension. JAMA. 2022;328(22):2252&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36511921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halonen JI, Erhola M, Furman E, Haahtela T, Jousilahti P, Barouki R, et al. The Helsinki declaration 2020: Europe that protects. Lancet Planet Health. 2020;4(11):e503&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, Bannuru RR, Brown FM, Bruemmer D, et al. 2. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of care in diabetes-2023. Diabetes Care. 2023;46(1):S19&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;mre E, Ko&#xe7;akg&#xf6;l N, &#x130;mre E. Low handgrip strength is associated with diabetic foot disease in geriatric patients with type 2 diabetes. Turk J Med Sci. 2022;52(6):1854&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10390154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36945977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi Y, Long J, Dan S, et al. Strength training is more effective than aerobic exercise for improving glycaemic control and body composition in people with normal-weight type 2 diabetes: a randomised controlled trial. Diabetologia. 2023;66(10):1897&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10527535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37493759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Zhou X, Wang J, et al. The effect of periodic resistance training on obese patients with type 2 diabetic nephropathy: a 12-week randomized trial. Sci Rep. 2024;14:53333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10837148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38307949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Awan S, Channa H, Ahmed A, Wasay M. Structured exercise regimen in the prevention of peripheral neuropathy in people with type 2 diabetes in a low-middle income country: an open-label, randomized controlled trial. Clin Diabetol. 2023;12(6):336&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo LC, Yang CJ, Lin CF, Jou IM, Yang YC, Yeh CH, et al. Effects of a task-based biofeedback training program on improving sensorimotor function in neuropathic hands in diabetic patients: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2019;55(5):618&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31058475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay MJ, Bridge CA, Greig M, Page RM. Upper-body post-activation performance enhancement for athletic performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis and recommendations for future research. Sports Med. 2022;52(4):873&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34826109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding L, Li Z, Wang M, Li X. Effectiveness of warm-up intervention programs to prevent injuries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;13:895812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9140806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35627873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Lin Y, Dong W, Wen X, Zuo Y. Exploring the relationship between grip strength and diabetic nephropathy among U.S. adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a cross-sectional NHANES analysis. BMC Endocr Disord. 2025;25:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11818093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39934779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoemaker MM, Niemeijer AS, Reynders K, Smits-Engelsman BCM. Validity and reliability of the box and block test for manual dexterity in various populations: a systematic review. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2018;60(11):1093&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochaska E, Vujaklija I, Fruhmann Berger M, Farina D, Gstoettner C, Aszmann OC. A digital box and block test for hand dexterity measurement. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2023;10:e50474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S, Yoon BN, Kim J, Seok JM, Kim K, Kwon K, et al. Nerve conduction studies: basic principal and clinical usefulness. Ann Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;20(2):71&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Andary M, Buschbacher R, et al. Electrodiagnostic reference values for upper and lower limb nerve conduction studies in adult populations. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54(3):371&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27238640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faselis C, Katsimardou A, Imprialos K, Deligkaris P, Kallistratos M, Dimitriadis K. Microvascular complications of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2020;18(2):117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31057114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami F, Khaki R, Mirzaei B, Howatson G. Resistance training improves nerve conduction and arterial stiffness in older adults with diabetic distal symmetrical polyneuropathy: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2021;153:111481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabo CA, Parraca JA, Fernandes O, Nunes P, Mendes C, Espada MC. The impact of sensorimotor training on physical fitness in older women with diabetes: a pilot study [preprint]. Res Square. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12641995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41286627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Li Q, Zhang L, Bo S. Effects of 6-week traditional and functional resistance training on arterial stiffness and muscular strength in healthy young men. Front Physiol. 2022;13:859402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M, Howatson G, Manca A, Deriu F, et al. Functional relevance of resistance training-induced neuroplasticity in health and disease. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2021;122:79&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boora M, Malik M, Kaur J. A systematic review and meta-analysis on effect of different exercise training on grip strength and upper extremity muscle strength in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Physiother Res Int. 2024;29(4):e2130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39291293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boora M, Kaur J. Efficacy of upper limb training on grip strength and muscle activity in individuals with type 2 diabetes: a feasibility study. Comp Exerc Physiol. 2023;19(4):313&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>