<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41811348</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Technical Note on Pickup Acceleration Signal Processing.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e432</StartPage><EndPage>e436</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e432-e436</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005407</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pryer, ME, Cronin, J, Neville, J, Korfist, C, and Uthoff, A. Technical note on pickup acceleration signal processing. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): e432-e436, 2026-Sprint acceleration from dynamic positions (pickup acceleration) is fundamental to team sports performance, yet remains under-researched. This article focuses on customizing methods for extracting step-specific variables from motorized linear position encoder technology to analyze pickup acceleration. Fifteen trained athletes (22.6 &#xb1; 5.3 years) from diverse sporting backgrounds performed 30-m sprints at controlled entry velocities (1.5 and 3.0 m&#xb7;s -1 ). A custom MATLAB script identified critical steps and calculated step velocity, acceleration, horizontal force, and step length. The analysis captured approach steps (-2, -1), transition step (0), and pickup steps (1, 2) across the acceleration phase. Using the methods outlined in this article, it was concluded that a step-by-step analysis of pickup acceleration can be effectively captured in field settings, providing mechanical insights that were previously limited to laboratory environments. This method provides strength and conditioning practitioners with a practical and portable solution for assessing sport-specific sprint mechanics. While low-load resistance (1 kg) and tether oscillation present limitations, the approach enables individualized training prescriptions based on step-specific mechanical profiles. Future research should establish the reliability of step-derived measures and explore targeted interventions for improving pickup acceleration performance in team sport athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pryer</LastName><ForeName>Mark E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9557-5357</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auckland University of Technology, Sports Performance Research Institute, FHES, SPRINZ, Auckland New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cronin</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auckland University of Technology, Sports Performance Research Institute, FHES, SPRINZ, Auckland New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Athlete Training and Health, Katy, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neville</LastName><ForeName>Jono</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auckland University of Technology, Sports Performance Research Institute, FHES, SPRINZ, Auckland New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korfist</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auckland University of Technology, Sports Performance Research Institute, FHES, SPRINZ, Auckland New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uthoff</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auckland University of Technology, Sports Performance Research Institute, FHES, SPRINZ, Auckland New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000054" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acceleration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012815" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061725" MajorTopicYN="Y">Accelerometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">speed development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sprint performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sprinting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team sports</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41811348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aughey RJ. Increased high-intensity activity in elite Australian football finals matches. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 6: 367&#x2013;379, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caekenberghe IV, Segers V, Aerts P, Willems P, De Clercq D. Joint kinematics and kinetics of overground accelerated running versus running on an accelerated treadmill. J R Soc Interface 10: 20130222, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Smet K, Segers V, Lenoir M, De Clercq D. Spatiotemporal characteristics of spontaneous overground walk-to-run transition. Gait Posture 29: 54&#x2013;58, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrich FJ, Warren WH. The dynamics of gait transitions: Effects of grade and load. J Mot Behav 30: 60&#x2013;78, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrich FJ, Warren WH Jr. Why change gaits? Dynamics of the walk-run transition. J Exp Psychol Hum Percept Perform 21: 183&#x2013;202, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude O, Koch T, Meyer T. Straight sprinting is the most frequent action in goal situations in professional football. J Sports Sci 30: 625&#x2013;631, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feser E, Lindley K, Clark KP, et al. Comparison of Two Measurement Devices for Obtaining Horizontal force-velocity Profile Variables During Sprint Running. Intl J of Sports Sci and Coach, 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getchell N, Whitall J. Transitions to and from asymmetrical gait patterns. J Mot Behav 36: 13&#x2013;27, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giest TN, Chang YH. Biomechanics of the human walk-to-run gait transition in persons with unilateral transtibial amputation. J Biomech 49: 1757&#x2013;1764, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen T, Tonnessen E, Hisdal J, Seiler S. The role and development of sprinting speed in soccer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 9: 432&#x2013;441, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hreljac A. Preferred and energetically optimal gait transition speeds in human locomotion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 25: 1158&#x2013;1162, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L. Stability landscapes of walking and running near gait transition speed. J Appl Biomech 16: 428&#x2013;435, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Huet K, Williamson C, et al. A resisted sprint improves rate of force development during a 20-m sprint in athletes. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1531&#x2013;1537, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, McNabb JA, Feito Y, VanDusseldorp TA, Hester GM. Increased resisted sprinting load decreases bilateral asymmetry in sprinting kinetics among rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 35: 3076&#x2013;3083, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryer M, Cronin J, Korfist C, Neville J, Uthoff A. New perspectives in assessing pickup acceleration. Int J Strength Cond 5: 1&#x2013;12, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryer M, Cronin J, Neville J, Uthoff A. Effect of entry velocity on pickup acceleration performance. Int J Strength Cond 5: 1&#x2013;9, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakovic E, Paulsen G, Helland C, Haugen T, Eriksrud O. Validity and reliability of a motorized sprint resistance device. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2335&#x2013;2338, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;kke O. Validation of force-, velocity-, and acceleration-time curves and temporal characteristics as output data from the 1080 sprint. Master&#x2019;s Norwegian Sch Sports Sci 1&#x2013;63, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers V, Aerts P, Lenoir M, De Clercq D. Dynamics of the body centre of mass during actual acceleration across transition speed. J Exp Biol 210: 578&#x2013;585, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers V, Aerts P, Lenoir M, De Clercq D. External forces during actual acceleration across transition speed. J Appl Biomech 24: 340&#x2013;350, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers V, Van Caekenberghe I, De Clercq D, Aerts P. Kinematics and dynamics of burst transitions. J Mot Behav 46: 267&#x2013;276, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers L, Aerts CD. Kinematics of the transition between walking and running when gradually changing speed. Gait Post 26: 349&#x2013;361, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers V, De Smet K, Van Caekenberghe I, Aerts P, De Clercq D. Biomechanics of spontaneous overground walk-to-run transition. J Exp Biol 216: 3047&#x2013;3054, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugisaki N, Tsuchie H, Takai Y, et al. Validity of spatiotemporal and ground reaction force estimates during resisted sprinting with a motorized loading device. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14597-12, 2024. doi:10.1111/sms.14597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Caekenberghe I, De Smet K, Segers V, De Clercq D. Overground vs. treadmill walk-to-run transition. Gait Posture 31: 420&#x2013;428, 2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>