<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41227953</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>21</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Crack Arrest Effect of FeMnNiSi-Inconel625-Ni60 Laminated Structure Prepared by Laser Cladding Additive Manufacturing.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4996</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18214996</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study addresses the technical challenges of cracking and surface crack initiation in Ni60 alloy cladding layers fabricated by laser cladding additive manufacturing on FeMnNiSi alloys. An innovative FeMnNiSi-Inconel625-Ni60 laminate design was proposed, achieving metallurgical bonding of the dissimilar materials through an Inconel625 transition layer. This effectively addresses the interfacial stress concentration issue caused by differences in thermal expansion coefficients in conventional processes. The results demonstrate that the interfacial microstructure is regulated by synergistic Nb-Mo element segregation, promoting the precipitation of &#x3b3;&#x2033; phase and the formation of a nanoscale Laves phase. This phase not only inhibits carbide aggregation and growth, refining grain size, but also deflects crack propagation paths by pinning dislocations, achieving a dual mechanism of stress reduction and crack arrest. The Ni60 cladding layer in the laminated structure exhibits an average surface microhardness of 641.31 HV<sub>0.3</sub>, 3.88 times that of the substrate (165.22 HV<sub>0.3</sub>), while the Inconel625 base layer shows 340.71 HV<sub>0.3</sub>, 2.06 times the substrate's value. Wear testing reveals the laminated cladding layer has a wear volume of 0.086 mm<sup>3</sup> (0.243 mm<sup>3</sup> less than the substrate's 0.329 mm<sup>3</sup>) and a wear rate of 0.86 &#xd7; 10<sup>-2</sup> mm<sup>3</sup>/(N&#xb7;m), 73.86% lower than the substrate's 3.29 &#xd7; 10<sup>-2</sup> mm<sup>3</sup>/(N&#xb7;m), indicating superior wear resistance. The electrochemical test results show that under the same corrosion conditions, the self-corrosion potential and polarization resistance of the FeMnNiSi-Inconel625-Ni60 cladding layer are significantly higher than those of the substrate, while the corrosion current density is significantly lower than that of the substrate. The frequency stability region at the highest impedance modulus |Z| is wider than that of the substrate, and the corrosion rate is 71.86% slower than that of the substrate, demonstrating excellent wear resistance. This study not only reveals the mechanism by which Laves phases improve interfacial properties through microstructural regulation but also provides a scalable interface design strategy for heterogeneous material additive manufacturing, which has important engineering value in promoting the application of laser cladding technology in the field of high-end equipment repair.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Lihong</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Training Center, Jiangsu University of Technology, Changzhou 213001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Advanced Materials Design and Additive Manufacturing, Changzhou 213001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Weining</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Advanced Materials Design and Additive Manufacturing, Changzhou 213001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Jiangsu University of Technology, Changzhou 213001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jufang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Jiangsu University of Technology, Changzhou 213001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>51975264</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>19KJD430004</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Research in Higher Education Institutions in Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corrosion resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crack arrest</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laminated structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laser cladding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wear resistance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41227953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12608038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18214996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18214996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q., Li Z., Yu Z. Optimization of Process Parameters for Laser Cladding FeNiMoCoCrTi High Entropy Alloy Coating on 45 # Steel. Mech. Strength. 2021;2:308&#x2013;312. doi: 10.16579/j.issn.1001.9669.2021.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16579/j.issn.1001.9669.2021.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao P., Gu X., Yan S. The effect of shot blasting pretreatment on gas carburizing efficiency and layer characteristics of 45 steel. Met. Heat Treat. 2022;47:143&#x2013;146. doi: 10.13251/j.issn.0254-6051.2022.11.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13251/j.issn.0254-6051.2022.11.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Zhang D., Sun W., Wang Y., Zhang J. Effect of scanning speed on deformation and microstructure of laser cladding thin high-speed steel plate. Surf. Technol. 2019;48:150&#x2013;157. doi: 10.16490/j.cnki.issn.1001-3660.2019.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16490/j.cnki.issn.1001-3660.2019.09.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong M., Jin K., Huang G., Zhao H., Xuan L., Qiao X., Chen P. Influence of scanning path on residual stress and tribological properties of multi-pass laser cladding layer. China Surf. Eng. 2025;38:75&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1007/s42107-024-01218-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42107-024-01218-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Long H., Qiu C., Wang M., Li D., Dong Z., Gui Y. Multi-Objective Optimization of Process Parameters of 45 Steel Laser Cladding Ni60PTA Alloy Powder. Coatings. 2022;12:939. doi: 10.3390/coatings12070939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings12070939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X., Yao Z., Zhang P., Zhou K. Corrosion resistance of Al-Cr composite reinforcement layer on 45 steel surface. Rare Met. Mater. Eng. 2018;47:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Li S., Dou W., Han F., Lin K. Process optimization and performance study of laser cladding Ni60 alloy coating on 316L stainless steel surface. China Laser. 2024;51:1602207. doi: 10.3788/CJL231232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3788/CJL231232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Yang X., Wang S., Zhang H., Yang L., Qiao Y., Li C. Wear and Corrosion Resistance of Ni60 TiC Ceramic Coating Laser Cladded on 45 Steel Surface. Rare Met. Mater. Eng. 2020;49:611&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Zheng S., Liu W., Zhu X., Zhou M., Jiang H. Optimization of Process Parameters for Laser Cladding Fe35A Alloy on 45 Steel Surface. Adv. Laser Optoelectron. 2021;58:0914007. doi: 10.3788/LOP202158.0914007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3788/LOP202158.0914007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhou H., Wang Z., Xiang N., Cao X. The influence of electromagnetic field on the microstructure and properties of laser cladding nickel based coatings. Surf. Technol. 2024;53:198&#x2013;207. doi: 10.12068/j.issn.1005-3026.2024.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12068/j.issn.1005-3026.2024.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X., Liu X., Yu P., Chen Y. Effects of post heat-treatment on microstructure and tribological properties of Ni60/H-BN self-lubricating anti-wear composite coating on 304 stainless steel by laser cladding. Tribology. 2016;36:49&#x2013;54. doi: 10.16078/j.tribology.2016.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16078/j.tribology.2016.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W., Li S., Xiao Q., Chen D., Wang S., Zhang B. Research Status and Development Trends of Friction reducing and Wear resistant Laser Cladding Coatings. Lubr. Seal. 2023;48:171&#x2013;182. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.0254-0150.2023.04.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.0254-0150.2023.04.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian S., Qiu Y. Research on the microstructure and properties of nickel-based alloy layer remanufactured by laser cladding. Electroplat. Finish. 2024;46:69&#x2013;75. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1001-3849.2024.07.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1001-3849.2024.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La P., Xue Q., Liu W. Effects of boron doping on tribological properties of Ni3Al&#x2013;Cr7C3 coatings under dry sliding. Wear. 2001;249:93&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/S0043-1648(01)00523-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0043-1648(01)00523-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen X., Chen L., Wu Y., Chen C., Zhang X., Zhou W., Ren X. Effect of Substrate Material Properties on Microstructure and Mechanical Properties of Ni60 Coatings Prepared by Extreme High-Speed Laser Cladding. Steel Res. Int. 2024;95:2300531. doi: 10.1002/srin.202300531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/srin.202300531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Sun W., Zhou H., Xing X., Yang K., Yu J. Research on Crack Formation Mechanism and Matching Method of Laser Cladding Nickel based Alloy Coating. Hot Process. Technol. 2022;51:83&#x2013;88. doi: 10.14158/j.cnki.1001-3814.20210774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14158/j.cnki.1001-3814.20210774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Z., Luo F., Yao J., Zhang Q. Effect of transition alloy layer on microstructure and properties of high hardness iron-based multilayer laser cladding thick cladding. Prog. Laser Optoelectron. 2004;41:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Wang A., Zhang X., Qiao X., Huang Z. Microstructure and properties of laser cladding Ni45-CaF2-WS2 self-lubricating coating. J. Chin. Soc. Nonferrous Met. 2008;18:215&#x2013;220. doi: 10.3321/j.issn:1004-0609.2008.02.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3321/j.issn:1004-0609.2008.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou J., Zhang G., Peng Y., Chen W., Zheng Z., Zheng K. Microstructure and abrasive wear behavior of TiC&#x2013;Cr7C3&#x2013;Fe composites fabricated by spark plasma sintering. Int. J. Refract. Met. Hard Mater. 2025;131:107228. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh C.V., Bagui S., Sahoo B.K., Umbare O.S., Tarafder S., Sivaprasad S. Comparison of low cycle fatigue behaviour of additively manufactured and wrought Inconel625 alloys. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2024;903:14. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2024.146682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2024.146682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Wang R., Pan L., Zhou X., Yang K. Effect of LaB6 on Microstructure and High-temperature Oxidation Resistance of Inconel625 Alloy Coating Fabricated by Plasma Transferred Arc Surfacing. Surf. Technol. 2025;54 doi: 10.16490/j.cnki.issn.1001-3660.2025.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16490/j.cnki.issn.1001-3660.2025.06.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Sun Y. Effects of alloying elements Si, V and Ti on microstructure and properties of 40Cr13 martensitic stainless steel. Jinshu Rechuli/Heat Treat. Met. 2024;49:256&#x2013;261. doi: 10.13251/j.issn.0254-6051.2024.03.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13251/j.issn.0254-6051.2024.03.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao G.G., Vasquez V.R. Correction: Micromechanical model to study the deformation behavior and effect of misfits on mechanical properties in Ni-based superalloys&#x2014;A phase-field approach. J. Mater. Res. 2025;40:1745. doi: 10.1557/s43578-025-01625-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1557/s43578-025-01625-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Huang Y., Liu Q., Xie L., Xu Q., Huang J. Effect of Molybdenum Content on the Microstructure and Wear Resistance of CoCrFeNiMo High Entropy Alloy Laser Cladding Coating on Carbon Steel Surface. Electroplat. Coat. 2020;39:1201&#x2013;1208. doi: 10.19289/j.1004-227x.2020.17.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19289/j.1004-227x.2020.17.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J.W., Yu L.M., Liu C.X., Ding R., Liu Y. Synergistic Strengthening of High-Cr Martensitic Heat-Resistant Steel and Application of Thermo-Mechanical Treatments. Acta Metall. Sin. 2024;60:713&#x2013;730. doi: 10.11900/0412.1961.2023.00488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11900/0412.1961.2023.00488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao X., Lu S., Hu P., Huang M. Toughening Method of Laves Intermetallic Compound Cr2Nb. Aerosp. Mater. Technol. 2007;37:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer S.K.M., Ramasamy K., Subramaniam P. Design and development of SS316L/Inconel625 based composite functional gradient materials for high-pressure pneumatic tools. Rare Met. Mater. Eng. 2025;54:363&#x2013;376. doi: 10.12442/j.issn.1002-185X.20240782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12442/j.issn.1002-185X.20240782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aramide B., Pityana S., Sadiku R., Jamiru T., Popoola P. Improving the durability of tillage tools through surface modification&#x2014;A review. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2021;116:83&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1007/s00170-021-07487-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-021-07487-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Cao Z., Wei D., Ge P., Zhou W., Chen G., Zu Y., Fu X. The influence of laser shock surface micro pit texturing on the micro motion wear behavior of diamond-like carbon coatings. China Laser. 2025;52:0402206. doi: 10.3788/CJL240966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3788/CJL240966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B., Jia W., Wang J., Zhou L. Selective electron beam melting of WMoTaNbVFeCoCrNi refractory high-entropy alloy. Mater. Charact. 2022;193:112278. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak M., Nowak W.J., Szala M., Gr&#x105;dzka-Dahlke M., Maciaszek N., Vali&#x161; D., Pasierbiewicz K. Effect of molybdenum addition on microstructure and behavior of AlCoCrFeNi high-entropy alloys in wet environments. Arch. Civ. Mech. Eng. 2025;25:205. doi: 10.1007/s43452-025-01260-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43452-025-01260-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan S., Ren W., Lei W., Wang Y. Study on the microstructure and properties of rail cladding layer after laser quenching. J. Manuf. Process. 2023;108:14. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2023.10.079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2023.10.079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu P., Song R., Li X.J., Deng J., Chen Z.-Y., Li Q.-W., Wang K.-S., Cao W.-C., Liu D.-X., Yu H.-L. Influence of concentrations of chloride ions on electrochemical corrosion behavior of titanium-zirconium-molybdenum alloy. J. Alloys Compd. 2017;708:367&#x2013;372. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.03.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.03.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X.T., Gu H., Zhou S.F., Lei J. Microstructure and Electrochemical Corrosion Behavior of TC4 Titanium Alloy Cladding Layer Prepared with Powder Feeding Laser Additive Manufacturing. Chin. J. Lasers. 2019;46:44&#x2013;53. doi: 10.3788/cjl201946.0302003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3788/cjl201946.0302003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>