<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41493864</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex-Based Performance Differences in Shot Put, Javelin, and Long Jump Among U.S. Youth Athletes Aged 10 Years and Under.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>451</StartPage><EndPage>459</EndPage><MedlinePgn>451-459</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005335</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brown, GA, Shaw, BS, and Shaw, I. Sex-based performance differences in shot put, javelin, and long jump among U.S. youth athletes aged 10 and under. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 451-459, 2026-Controversy currently exists over whether sex-based differences necessitate sex-segregated youth sports. This study examined sex-based performance differences in shot put, javelin throw, and long jump among athletes aged 10 years and under using data from USA Track &amp; Field (USATF) Regional Junior Olympic Championships. Performance records from all 15 USATF regions for the 2022, 2023, and 2024 Regional Junior Olympic Championships were analyzed. Distances recorded in shot put, javelin throw, and long jump for male and female athletes in the 8-and-under and 9-10-year-old age groups were compared using 2-sample t -tests ( p &lt; 0.05). Hedges' g was calculated to determine effect sizes. Percentile analyses (10th-95th) were also conducted for each sex and event. Males significantly outperformed females in all 3 events across both age groups ( p &lt; 0.0001). Effect sizes were large for javelin (Hedges' g = 1.138 and 1.099) and shot put ( g = 0.730 and 0.741), and medium for long jump ( g = 0.429 and 0.473). Male performance advantages ranged from 8 to 55% depending on event and age group. Percentile analyses revealed consistent male advantages across the entire performance distribution, suggesting inherent sex-based trends regardless of ability level. These findings demonstrate clear sex-based performance differences in throwing and jumping events among prepubertal athletes. Although physical activity levels may contribute to these differences, anatomical and physiological factors likely play a significant role. Coaches, parents, and sport governing bodies should consider these sex-based performance trends when developing training programs, setting expectations, and establishing age-group competition structures for youth athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Gregory A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9928-217</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity and Wellness Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sports Science, University of Nebraska at Kearney, Kearney, Nebraska.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Brandon S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Rehabilitation and Exercise Sciences, University of Essex, Wivenhoe Park, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health, University of the Free State, Bloemfontein, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Ina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Rehabilitation and Exercise Sciences, University of Essex, Wivenhoe Park, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health, University of the Free State, Bloemfontein, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Track and Field</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explosive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prepubertal athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">track-and-field performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youth athletics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41493864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amateur Athletic Union. AAU USA Track &amp; Field Results/Rankings. Available at: https://aausports.org/track-and-field/resultsrankings/#nationalrecords . Accessed. May 25, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson MA, James JJ, Quinn ME, Senefeld JW, Hunter SK. Sex differences in track and field elite youth. Med Sci Sports Exerc 56: 1390&#x2013;1397, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcher BR, Berrigan D, Dodd KW, et al. Physical activity in US youth: Effect of race/ethnicity, age, gender, and weight status. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 2211&#x2013;2221, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhargava A, Arnold AP, Bangasser DA, et al. Considering sex as a biological variable in basic and clinical studies: An Endocrine Society Scientific Statement. Endocr Rev 42: 219&#x2013;258, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, Shaw BS, Shaw I. Sex&#x2010;based differences in track running distances of 100, 200, 400, 800, and 1500 m in the 8 and under and 9&#x2013;10&#x2010;year&#x2010;old age groups. Eur J Sport Sci 24: 217&#x2013;225, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, Shaw BS, Shaw I. Sex-based differences in shot put, javelin throw, and long jump in 8-and-under and 9&#x2013;10-year-old athletes. Eur J Sport Sci 25: e12241, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, Shaw BS, Shaw I. Sex-based differences in swimming performance in 10-years-old-and-under athletes in short course national competition. Eur J Sport Sci 25: e12237, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catley MJ, Tomkinson GR. Normative health-related fitness values for children: Analysis of 85347 test results on 9&#x2013;17-year-old Australians since 1985. Br J Sports Med 47: 98&#x2013;108, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caughey RM, Thomas C. Variables associated with high school shot put performance. Int J Exerc Sci 15: 1357&#x2013;1365, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Hammond-Bennett A, Hypnar A, Mason S. Health-related physical fitness and physical activity in elementary school students. BMC Public Health 18: 195, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming SP, Standage M, Loney T, et al. The mediating role of physical self-concept on relations between biological maturity status and physical activity in adolescent females. J Adolesc 34: 465&#x2013;473, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels J, Daniels N. Running economy of elite male and elite female runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc 24: 483&#x2013;489, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dencker M, Thorsson O, Karlsson MK, et al. Gender differences and determinants of aerobic fitness in children aged 8-11 years. Eur J Appl Physiol 99: 19&#x2013;26, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiberg S, Hasselstrom H, Gronfeldt V, et al. Maximum oxygen uptake and objectively measured physical activity in Danish children 6-7 years of age: The Copenhagen school child intervention study. Br J Sports Med 39: 725&#x2013;730, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emeljanovas A, Mieziene B, Cesnaitiene VJ, Fjortoft I, Kjonniksen L. Physical fitness and anthropometric values among Lithuanian primary school children: Population-based cross-sectional study. J Strength Cond Res 34: 414&#x2013;421, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferber R, Davis IM, Williams DS III. Gender differences in lower extremity mechanics during running. Clin Biomech 18: 350&#x2013;357, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Santos JR, Gonzalez-Montesinos JL, Ruiz JR, Jim&#xe9;nez-Pav&#xf3;n D, Castro-Pi&#xf1;ero J. Kinematic analysis of the standing long jump in children 6- to 12-years-old. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci 22: 70&#x2013;78, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gromeier M, Koester D, Schack T. Gender differences in motor skills of the overarm throw. Front Psychol 8: 212, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ. Sex differences in athletic performance emerge coinciding with the onset of male puberty. Clin Endocrinol 87: 68&#x2013;72, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ, Bermon S. Biology and management of male-bodied athletes in elite female sports. Drug Test Anal 17: 1703&#x2013;1714, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hands B. Changes in motor skill and fitness measures among children with high and low motor competence: A five-year longitudinal study. J Sci Med Sport 11: 155&#x2013;162, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huebner M, Perperoglou A. Sex differences and impact of body mass on performance from childhood to senior athletes in Olympic weightlifting. PLoS One 15: e0238369, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Angadi S, Bhargava A, et al. The biological basis of sex differences in athletic performance: Consensus statement for the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 2328&#x2013;2360, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Senefeld JW. Sex differences in human performance. J Physiol 602: 4129&#x2013;4156, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde ET, Omura JD, Fulton JE, et al. Disparities in youth sports participation in the U.S., 2017&#x2013;2018. Am J Prev Med 59: e207&#x2013;e210, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JJ, Hunter SK, Bueckers EP, Joyner MJ, Senefeld JW. Sex-based differences in the representation of top youth athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 57: 1523&#x2013;1529, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Hunter SK, Senefeld JW. Evidence on sex differences in sports performance. J Appl Physiol (1985) 138: 274&#x2013;281, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong A. Sexual dimorphism of the pelvic architecture: A struggling response to destructive and parsimonious forces by natural &amp; mate selection. Mcgill J Med 9: 61&#x2013;66, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong N, Bartlett E. Sex segregation in sports as a public health issue. Cardazzo Law Rev 40: 1813&#x2013;1856, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Leigh S, Yu B. Sequences of upper and lower extremity motions in javelin throwing. J Sports Sci 28: 1459&#x2013;1467, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Cronin JB, Faigenbaum AD, et al. National Strength and Conditioning Association position statement on long-term athletic development. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1491&#x2013;1509, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo MP, Deaner RO. On the evolution of the sex differences in throwing: Throwing is a male adaptation in humans. Q Rev Biol 93: 91&#x2013;119, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Tucker R, McGawley K, et al. The International Olympic Committee framework on fairness, inclusion and nondiscrimination on the basis of gender identity and sex variations does not protect fairness for female athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14581, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martowicz M, Budgett R, Pape M, et al. Position statement: IOC framework on fairness, inclusion and non-discrimination on the basis of gender identity and sex variations. Br J Sports Med 57: 26&#x2013;32, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastalerz A, Sadowski J. Variability of performance and kinematics of different shot put techniques in elite and sub-elite Athletes&#x2014;A preliminary study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 1751, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus AM, Armstrong N. Physiology of elite young female athletes. Med Sport Sci 56: 23&#x2013;46, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millard-Stafford M, Swanson AE, Wittbrodt MT. Nature versus nurture: Have performance gaps between men and women reached an asymptote? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 530&#x2013;535, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuguchi S, Cunanan AJ, Suarez DG, et al. Performance comparisons of youth weightlifters as a function of age group and sex. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 57, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Faigenbaum AD, Ford KR, et al. When to initiate integrative neuromuscular training to reduce sports-related injuries and enhance health in youth? Curr Sports Med Rep 10: 155&#x2013;166, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL. Sex differences in grip strength from birth to age 16: A meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 25: e12268, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD. Sex differences in upper- and lower-limb muscle strength in children and adolescents: A meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 25: e12282, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor MI. Equity360: Gender, race, and ethnicity: Sex and fairness in sports. Clin Orthop Relat Res 481: 1080&#x2013;1083, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safer JD. Fairness for transgender people in sport. J Endocr Soc 6: bvac035, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senefeld JW, Clayburn AJ, Baker SE, et al. Sex differences in youth elite swimming. PLoS One 14: e0225724, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senefeld JW, Hunter SK. Hormonal basis of biological sex differences in human athletic performance. Endocrinology 165: bqae036, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senefeld JW, Lambelet Coleman D, Johnson PW, et al. Divergence in timing and magnitude of testosterone levels between male and female youths. JAMA 324: 99&#x2013;101, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staiano AE, Katzmarzyk PT. Ethnic and sex differences in body fat and visceral and subcutaneous adiposity in children and adolescents. Int J Obes 36: 1261&#x2013;1269, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambalis KD, Panagiotakos DB, Psarra G, et al. Physical fitness normative values for 6-18-year-old Greek boys and girls, using the empirical distribution and the lambda, mu, and sigma statistical method. Eur J Sport Sci 16: 736&#x2013;746, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas JR, Alderson JA, Thomas KT, Campbell AC, Elliott BC. Developmental gender differences for overhand throwing in Aboriginal Australian children. Res Q Exerc Sport 81: 432&#x2013;441, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas JR, French KE. Gender differences across age in motor performance a meta-analysis. Psychol Bull 98: 260&#x2013;282, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomkinson GR, Carver KD, Atkinson F, et al. European normative values for physical fitness in children and adolescents aged 9&#x2013;17 years: Results from 2 779 165 eurofit performances representing 30 countries. Br J Sports Med 52: 1445&#x2013;14563, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker R, Hilton EN, McGawley K, et al. Fair and safe eligibility criteria for women's sport. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14715, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USA Track &amp; Field. USATF National Junior Olympic Track &amp; Field Championships Records (as of 3/27/19). Available at: https://www.usatf.org/resources/statistics/records/championship-meet-records/usatf-national-junior-olympic-track-field-champion . Accessed. May 22, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USA Track &amp; Field. USATF American Records. Available at: https://www.usatf.org/resources/statistics/records/american-records . Accessed. May 30, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USA Track &amp; Field. USATF Rule Books. Available at: https://www.usatf.org/governance/rule-books . Accessed. May 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USA Track &amp; Field. Associations. Available at: https://www.usatf.org/associations . Accessed. May 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandorpe B, Vaeyens R, Vandendriessche JB, et al. The value of a non-sport-specific motor test battery in predicting performance in young female gymnasts. J Sports Sci 30: 497&#x2013;505, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells MS, Arthur-Banning SG. The logic of youth development: Constructing a logic model of youth development through sport. J Park Rec Admin 26: 189&#x2013;202, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K, Tang WT, Liu SH, Pandy MG. Muscle contributions to take-off velocity in the long jump. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 1434&#x2013;1444, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaras N, Stasinaki AN, Terzis G. Biological determinants of track and field throwing performance. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 40, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>