<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41327709</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>48</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risk factors, physical activity behavior, and hand grip strength of adults with atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in Arar city, Saudi Arabia: A cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45977</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45977</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45977</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000045977</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiovascular diseases (CVD) remain the leading cause of global mortality. Risk factors such as diabetes mellitus, hypertension, dyslipidemia, smoking, low physical activity, weak handgrip strength, and high body mass index are commonly associated with CVD. This study explores risk factors, physical activity behaviors, and handgrip strength in adults diagnosed with atherosclerotic CVD in Arar city, Saudi Arabia. A cross-sectional analysis was conducted with 100 patients with CVD admitted to a local cardiac center between August 2023 and April 2024. Participants completed the Godin Leisure-Time Exercise Questionnaire to assess physical activity. Handgrip strength was measured using a handgrip strength dynamometer. Additional clinical, demographic, and anthropometric data, including left ventricle ejection fraction (LVEF) and hemoglobin A1c levels, were retrieved from the center's records. Differences in physical activity and handgrip strength between diabetes groups (normal, prediabetic, and diabetic) and LVEF groups (normal LVEF, mildly reduced LVEF, and reduced LVEF) were analyzed using analysis of variance, while setting P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.05 as the criterion for significant difference. Of the participants (88% men, mean age 55.6&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;11.9 years), 73% were insufficiently active, as per the Godin Leisure-Time Exercise Questionnaire score. Handgrip strength and physical activity scores were higher among non-diabetic and normal LVEF groups compared to the other groups. Nonetheless, differences between groups were not statistically significant (P&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;.05). Most patients exhibited common CVD risk factors, such as increased body mass index, dyslipidemia, and smoking history, with 36% having single vessel disease and 38% reduced LVEF. This study highlights low physical activity levels and weak handgrip strength in CVD patients in Arar city, highlighting a critical need for tailored public health initiatives. Programs promoting physical activity and resistance training may enhance cardiac health and mitigate risk. Region-specific insights inform national strategies to address reducing the risk of CVD in Saudi Arabia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alotaibi</LastName><ForeName>Mansour M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, College of Applied Medical Sciences. Northern Border University, Arar, Northern Border Province, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Research, Northern Border University, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almutairi</LastName><ForeName>Anwar B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Allied Health, Kuwait University, Jabriya, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alhowaish</LastName><ForeName>Manal A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Unit, Prince Abdullah Bin Abdulaziz Bin Musaed of Cardiac Center, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alqahtani</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Therapy, College of Applied Medical Sciences, King Saud bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Abdullah International Medical Research Center, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Services, King Abdulaziz Medical City, Ministry of National Guard Health Affairs, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almutairi</LastName><ForeName>Marzouq K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Applied Medical Sciences, Qassim University, Buraidah, Qassim Province, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siddig</LastName><ForeName>Abubakr S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Dr Sulaiman Al Habib Medical Group, Al Muhmmadiyah Hospital, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alenazi</LastName><ForeName>Wajdan O</ForeName><Initials>WO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Unit, Prince Abdullah Bin Abdulaziz Bin Musaed of Cardiac Center, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alenazi</LastName><ForeName>Amina A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit, Prince Abdullah Bin Abdulaziz Bin Musaed of Cardiac Center, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albanagi</LastName><ForeName>Ansar S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency, North Medical Tower, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alenazi</LastName><ForeName>Aisha S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Catheterization, Prince Abdullah Bin Abdulaziz Bin Musaed of Cardiac Center, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alrashdi</LastName><ForeName>Naif Z</ForeName><Initials>NZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Health Rehabilitation, College of Applied Medical Sciences, Majmaah University, Al-Majmaah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Basic Sciences Research Center, Majmaah University, Al-Majmaah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012529" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Saudi Arabia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050197" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atherosclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082742" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Disease Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Godin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">left ventricle ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41327709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12662383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000045977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202511280-00070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Cardiovascular diseases (CVDs).
Available at: https://www.who.int/health-topics/cardiovascular-diseases#tab=tab_1 [accessed November 14, 2024].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhabib KF, Al-Rasadi K, Almigbal TH, et al. Familial hypercholesterolemia in the Arabian Gulf region: clinical results of the Gulf FH Registry. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0251560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8177652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34086694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmeed WA, Habib M, Villa G, et al. Burden of cardiovascular disease (CVD) for patients with familial hypercholesterolemia (FH) or atherosclerotic CVD (ASCVD) and the impact of low density lipoprotein-cholesterol (LDL-C) lowering in two Middle East countries. Value Health. 2017;20:A610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barquera S, Pedroza-Tob&#xed;as A, Medina C, et al. Global overview of the epidemiology of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Arch Med Res. 2015;46:328&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26135634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Heart Center SHC. Cardiovascular disease: a public health priority.
Available at: https://shc.gov.sa/Arabic/NHC/Activities/Documents/Cardiovascular%20disease%20in%20KSA%20-%20a%20public%20health%20priority.pdf. Published 2022. Accessed January 17, 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alenazi SA, Koura HM, Zaki SM, Mohamed AH. Prevalence of obesity among male adolescents in Arar Saudi Arabia: future risk of cardiovascular disease. Indian J Community Med. 2015;40:182&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4478660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26170543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abukanna AMA, S AAA, N AZA, A AWK, S ASA. Awareness of the general population about the risk factors of cerebrovascular stroke in Arar, Saudi Arabia. Arch Pharm Pract. 2020;11:141&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola C, Parikh NS. Framingham General Cardiovascular Risk Score and cognitive impairment: the power of foresight. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;75:2535&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#x105;k W, Wojtasi&#x144;ska A, Lisi&#x144;ska W, M&#x142;ynarska E, Franczyk B, Rysz J. Pathophysiology of cardiovascular diseases: new insights into molecular mechanisms of atherosclerosis, arterial hypertension, and coronary artery disease. Biomedicines. 2022;10:1938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9405799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36009488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amireault S, Godin G. The Godin-Shephard leisure-time physical activity questionnaire: validity evidence supporting its use for classifying healthy adults into active and insufficiently active categories. Percept Mot Skills. 2015;120:604&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25799030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulati M, Levy PD, Mukherjee D, et al. 2021 AHA/ACC/ASE/CHEST/SAEM/SCCT/SCMR guideline for the evaluation and diagnosis of chest pain: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2021;144:e368&#x2013;454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al. 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2022;145:e895&#x2013;e1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>German CA, Shapiro MD. Assessing atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease risk with advanced lipid testing: state of the science. Eur Cardiol. 2020;15:e56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32742310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WT, Hsu PF, Lin CC, et al. Hemoglobin A1C levels are independently associated with the risk of coronary atherosclerotic plaques in patients without diabetes: a cross-sectional study. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2020;27:789&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7458793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31902804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polanczyk CA, Kuntz KM, Sacks DB, Johnson PA, Lee TH. Emergency department triage strategies for acute chest pain using creatine kinase-MB and troponin I assays: a cost-effectiveness analysis. Ann Intern Med. 1999;131:909&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10610641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YC, Bohannon RW, Li X, Yen SC, Sindhu B, Kapellusch J. Summary of grip strength measurements obtained in the 2011&#x2013;2012 and 2013&#x2013;2014 National Health and Nutrition Examination Surveys. J Hand Ther. 2019;32:489&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29653890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim J, Yoo HJ. Effects of handgrip strength on 10-year cardiovascular risk among the Korean middle-aged population: the Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2014. Healthcare (Basel). 2020;8:458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7712900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33158168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawman HG, Troiano RP, Perna FM, Wang CY, Fryar CD, Ogden CL. Associations of relative handgrip strength and cardiovascular disease biomarkers in U.S. adults, 2011&#x2013;2012. Am J Prev Med. 2016;50:677&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algarni AD, Kamel S, Almatrafi RS, et al. Comparative analysis of lifestyle practices between diabetic patients and healthy non-diabetic individuals in the Saudi population. Cureus. 2024;16:e65501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11345805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39188495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujamammi A, Sabi E, Dakhil A, et al. The knowledge and practice of Saudi type-2 diabetic patients regarding lifestyle habits in Riyadh City. Int J Med Dev Countries. 2023;7:557&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota Y, Evenson KR, Maclehose RF, Roetker NS, Joshu CE, Folsom AR. Physical activity and lifetime risk of cardiovascular disease and cancer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:1599&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5511058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28350711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tasevska N, DeLia D, Lorts C, Yedidia M, Ohri-Vachaspati P. Determinants of sugar-sweetened beverage consumption among low-income children: are there differences by race/ethnicity, age, and sex? J Acad Nutr Diet. 2017;117:1900&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5677590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28495478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Zhang Z, Gregg EW, Flanders WD, Merritt R, Hu FB. Added sugar intake and cardiovascular diseases mortality among US adults. JAMA Intern Med. 2014;174:516&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10910551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tash AA, Al-Bawardy RF. Cardiovascular disease in Saudi Arabia: facts and the way forward. J Saudi Heart Assoc. 2023;35:148&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10405907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallucci G, Tartarone A, Lerose R, Lalinga AV, Capobianco AM. Cardiovascular risk of smoking and benefits of smoking cessation. J Thorac Dis. 2020;12:3866&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altaleb FF, Alshammari OM, Alanazi HM, et al. Pattern and factors associated with cardiovascular diseases among patients attending the cardiac center in Arar City, Northern Saudi Arabia. Electron Physician. 2017;9:5459&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOH. KSA Global Adult Tobacco Survey (GATS) 2019 Fact Sheet.
Ministry of Health. Available at: https://www.moh.gov.sa/en/Ministry/Statistics/Population-Health-Indicators/Documents/KSA_GATS_2019_FactSheet.pdf [accessed November 24, 2024]. Published 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiha J, Mitchell P, Gopinath B, Plant AJH, Kovoor P, Thiagalingam A. Gender differences in the severity and extent of coronary artery disease. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2015;8:161&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5497284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28785696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiteshi AK, Li D, Gao Y, et al. Gender differences in coronary artery diameter are not related to body habitus or left ventricular mass. Clin Cardiol. 2014;37:605&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6649484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25269657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkpatrick CF, Sikand G, Petersen KS, et al. Nutrition interventions for adults with dyslipidemia: a Clinical Perspective from the National Lipid Association. J Clin Lipidol. 2023;17:428&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37271600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raal FJ, Alsheikh-Ali AA, Omar MI, et al. Cardiovascular risk factor burden in Africa and the Middle East across country income categories: a post hoc analysis of the cross-sectional Africa Middle East Cardiovascular Epidemiological (ACE) study. Arch Public Health. 2018;76:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29449941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang BH, Duncan MJ, Cistulli PA, Nassar N, Hamer M, Stamatakis E. Sleep and physical activity in relation to all-cause, cardiovascular disease and cancer mortality risk. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:718&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34187783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evenson KR, Alhusseini N, Moore CC, et al. Scoping review of population-based physical activity and sedentary behavior in Saudi Arabia. J Phys Act Health. 2023;20:471&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodds RM, Syddall HE, Cooper R, Kuh D, Cooper C, Sayer AA. Global variation in grip strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis of normative data. Age Ageing. 2016;45:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4776623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26790455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>