<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41400441</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in Blood Lactate Concentration During a Step Incremental Test Do Not Predict Changes in Substrates Oxidation Through the Training Season.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e224</StartPage><EndPage>e231</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e224-e231</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005316</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ben&#xed;tez-Mu&#xf1;oz, JA, Fleitas-Paniagua, PR, Murias, JM, and Cupeiro, R. Changes in blood lactate concentration during a step incremental test do not predict changes in substrates oxidation through the training season. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): e225-e232, 2026-The aim of the present work was to determine whether changes in blood lactate concentration [La - ] between 2 different points of a training season would allow to predict changes in fat oxidation (FatOx) or carbohydrate oxidation (CHOx) in men and women. Fourteen men and 10 women performed a step incremental exercise test on a cycle ergometer at 2 points of the training season (spring and fall). Blood lactate concentration was measured during the final 30 seconds of each step and immediately after task failure, while mean FatOx and CHOx during the last minute of each stage was estimated using indirect calorimetry. Subsequently, the difference between the 2 points of the training season at each common power output during the incremental test was calculated for [La - ] (&#x394;[La - ]), FatOx (&#x394;FatOx), and CHOx (&#x394;CHOx). The significant level was set at p &lt; 0.05. The results showed [La - ] was strongly and inversely associated with FatOx (men: -0.821 &#xb1; 0.112; women: -0.914 &#xb1; 0.038) and strongly and positively associated with CHOx (men: 0.937 &#xb1; 0.027; women: 0.945 &#xb1; 0.032) at each point of the training season. Contrary, a broad range of correlations were determined for the relationship between &#x394;[La - ] and &#x394;FatOx (men: -0.207 &#xb1; 0.531; women: -0.384 &#xb1; 0.502) or &#x394;CHOx (men: 0.292 &#xb1; 0.427; women: 0.324 &#xb1; 0.475). In conclusion, assessing [La - ] alone might be considered as an effective way to indirectly assess substrate oxidations as long as [La - ], FatOx, and CHOx during the incremental test remain stable throughout the training season. Contrary, the novel and most important finding is changes in [La - ] do not predict changes in substrate oxidations as the training season progresses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ben&#xed;tez-Mu&#xf1;oz</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; Antonio</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LFE Research Group, Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Science (INEF), Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleitas-Paniagua</LastName><ForeName>Pablo R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Canada; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica &#xa8;Nuestra Se&#xf1;ora de la Asunci&#xf3;n&#xa8;, Asunci&#xf3;n, Paraguay.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murias</LastName><ForeName>Juan M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health and Life Sciences, Hamad Bin Khalifa University, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cupeiro</LastName><ForeName>Roc&#xed;o</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LFE Research Group, Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Science (INEF), Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010084" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidation-Reduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002153" MajorTopicYN="N">Calorimetry, Indirect</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050260" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbohydrate Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbohydrate oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic flexibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41400441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Relation between plasma lactate concentration and fat oxidation rates over a wide range of exercise intensities. Int J Sports Med 25: 32&#x2013;37, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed K, Tunaru S, Tang C, et al. An autocrine lactate loop mediates insulin-dependent inhibition of lipolysis through GPR81. Cell Metab 11: 311&#x2013;319, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, Sanchez-Delgado G, Jurado-Fasoli L, et al. Assessment of maximal fat oxidation during exercise: A systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports 29: 910&#x2013;921, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xed;tez-Mu&#xf1;oz JA, Guisado-Cuadrado I, Rojo-Tirado M&#xc1;, et al. Changes in lactate concentration are accompanied by opposite changes in the pattern of fat oxidation: Dose-response relationship. Eur J Sport Sci 24: 1653&#x2013;1663, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xed;tez-Mu&#xf1;oz JA, Guisado-Cuadrado I, Rojo-Tirado M&#xc1;, et al. Females have better metabolic flexibility in different metabolically challenging stimuli. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 50: 1&#x2013;12, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xed;tez-Mu&#xf1;oz JA, Rojo-Tirado M&#xc1;, Benito Peinado PJ, Murias JM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Lamu&#xf1;o D, Cupeiro R. Greater relative first and second lactate thresholds in females compared with males: Consideration for exercise prescription. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 20: 30&#x2013;36, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA. The science and translation of lactate shuttle theory. Cell Metab 27: 757&#x2013;785, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA. Lactate as a fulcrum of metabolism. Redox Biol 35: 101454, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA, Arevalo JA, Osmond AD, Leija RG, Curl CC, Tovar AP. Lactate in contemporary biology: A Phoenix risen. J Physiol 600: 1229&#x2013;1251, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA, Osmond AD, Arevalo JA, et al. Lactate as a major myokine and exerkine. Nat Rev Endocrinol 18: 712, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA, Osmond AD, Arevalo JA, et al. Lactate as a myokine and exerkine: Drivers and signals of physiology and metabolism. J Appl Physiol 134: 529&#x2013;548, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai TQ, Ren N, Jin L, et al. Role of GPR81 in lactate-mediated reduction of adipose lipolysis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 377: 987&#x2013;991, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, MI, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, Minahan CL, de Jonge XAKJ, et al. Methodological considerations for studies in sport and exercise science with women as participants: A working guide for standards of practice for research on women. Sports Med 51: 843&#x2013;861, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frayn KN. Calculation of substrate oxidation rates in vivo from gaseous exchange. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol 55: 628&#x2013;634, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannetta D, Ingram CP, Keir DA, Murias JM. Methodological reconciliation of CP and MLSS and their agreement with the maximal metabolic steady state. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54: 622&#x2013;632, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Wu J, Zhu J, et al. Lactate inhibits lipolysis in fat cells through activation of an orphan G-protein-coupled receptor, GPR81. J Biol Chem 284: 2811&#x2013;2822, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;fberg IE, Karppinen JE, Laatikainen-Raussi I, et al. Peak fat oxidation during submaximal exercise remains consistent across menstrual cycle and combined oral contraceptive phases. Med Sci Sports Exerc 57: 1383&#x2013;1394, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattu AT, Iannetta D, MacInnis MJ, Doyle-Baker PK, Murias JM. Menstrual and oral contraceptive cycle phases do not affect submaximal and maximal exercise responses. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 472&#x2013;484, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogatzki MJ, Ferguson BS, Goodwin ML, Gladden LB. Lactate is always the end product of glycolysis. Front Neurosci 9: 1&#x2013;7, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>San-Mill&#xe1;n I, Brooks GA. Assessment of metabolic flexibility by means of measuring blood lactate, fat, and carbohydrate oxidation responses to exercise in professional endurance athletes and less-fit individuals. Sports Med 48: 467&#x2013;479, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>San-Millan I, Sparagna GC, Chapman HL, et al. Chronic lactate exposure decreases mitochondrial function by inhibition of fatty acid uptake and cardiolipin alterations in neonatal rat cardiomyocytes. Front Nutr 9: 809485, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>