<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41868489</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of task-oriented training on hand functionality in children with cerebral palsy under 18&#x202f;years: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1775810</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1775810</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1775810</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2026.1775810</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Task-oriented training (TOT) is the predominant rehabilitative training approach grounded in motor control theory. The effectiveness of treating hand dysfunction in children with cerebral palsy has not been established. This research conducts a systematic analysis of the rehabilitation treatment effects of TOT on hand dysfunction in children with cerebral palsy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Comprehensive searches were performed in databases including China National Knowledge Infrastructure, Wan Fang Database, Chinese Science and Technology Periodical Databases, SinoMed, PubMed, Web of Science, Embase, and Cochrane Library for randomized controlled trials of TOT utilized in the rehabilitation of hand dysfunction in pediatric patients with cerebral palsy. The control group underwent standard rehabilitation treatment, but the experimental group received TOT alongside the control group treatment. The search time concluded in August 2025, coinciding with the establishment of each database. Two researchers independently performed literature screening and data extraction, while the quality of the literature was assessed using the Cochrane risk of bias assessment tool. A meta-analysis was conducted with Revman 5.4 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sixteen publications were included, encompassing 1,037 children with cerebral palsy. The meta-analysis indicated that the enhancement of hand function in the experimental group surpassed that of the control group [SMD&#x202f;=&#x202f;1.44, 95% CI (1.12, 1.76), <i>p</i>&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.01]. Additionally, the recovery of grip strength and cognitive ability was superior in the experimental group [SMD&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.52, 95% CI (0.17, 0.87), <i>p</i>&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05; MD&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.93, 95% CI (0.60, 1.27), <i>p</i>&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.01]. Furthermore, the WeeFIM Scale score for the experimental group exceeded that of the control group [MD&#x202f;=&#x202f;6.47, 95% CI (5.22, 7.72), <i>p</i>&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.01].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">TOT can boost the manual dexterity of children with cerebral palsy, and improve their grip strength and cognitive abilities. It is also more efficacious in enhancing the functional autonomy of youngsters. It is important to highlight that certain markers of the overall sample size, such as grip strength and IQ, were featured in only three publications, resulting in inadequate statistical power. Future research necessitates further large-sample, high-quality randomized controlled trials to validate the aforementioned conclusions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Xiao, Zhang, Liu, Chen, Wu, Le, Fan, Zhao and Gao.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yuxin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Assistive Devices, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yongfu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Ruifeng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le</LastName><ForeName>Shenglong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Le</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Assistive Devices, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Taihe Hospital Affiliated to Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebral palsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">task-oriented training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41868489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12999552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2026.1775810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez L, Arg&#xfc;elles J, Gonz&#xe1;lez V, Winge K, Iscar M, Olmedillas H, et al. Slackline training in children with spastic cerebral palsy: a randomized clinical trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2020) 17:8649. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17228649,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17228649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33233328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Pediatric Rehabilitation Group of the Chinese Medical Association&#x2019;s Pediatrics Branch . An evidence-based and implementable exercise rehabilitation guide for cerebral palsy: interpretation by Chinese experts (2022 edition). Chin J Phys Med Rehabil. (2023) 45:738&#x2013;43. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2023.08.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2023.08.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitrikas K, Dalton H, Breish D. Cerebral palsy: an overview. Am Fam Physician. (2020) 101:213&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32053326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy-Zaks A, Pollak Y, Ben-Pazi H. Cerebral palsy risk factors and their impact on psychopathology. Neurol Res. (2014) 36:92&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1179/1743132813Y.0000000290,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/1743132813Y.0000000290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnould C, Bleyenheuft Y, Thonnard JL. Hand functioning in children with cerebral palsy. Front Neurol. (2014) 5:48. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2014.00048,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2014.00048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3988367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24782821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimigliano F. Are exercise interventions effective in patients with cerebral palsy? A Cochrane review summary with commentary. Dev Med Child Neurol. (2020) 62:18&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1111/dmcn.14400,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.14400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko EJ, Sung IY, Moon HJ, Yuk JS, Kim HS, Lee NH. Effect of group-task-oriented training on gross and fine motor function, and activities of daily living in children with spastic cerebral palsy. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. (2020) 40:18&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1080/01942638.2019.1642287,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01942638.2019.1642287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31339403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XH, Wang DQ, Bi FL, Chen X, Ren SS, Xu WQ, et al. Research progress on the treatment of motor dysfunction in children with spastic cerebral palsy by repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation. Chin J Phys Med Rehabil. (2021) 43:273&#x2013;5. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2021.03.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2021.03.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YH, Wen CB, Qi YM. The effects of aquatic exercise therapy on the motor, balance function and muscle tone of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Chin J Rehabil Med. (2021) 36:93&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3870/zgkf.2021.02.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3870/zgkf.2021.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Luo DM, Wang CJ, Wang SY. Effect of task-oriented training on developmental coordination disorders in children: a meta-analysis. Chin J Sch Health. (2018) 39:1643&#x2013;7. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2018.11.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2018.11.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z. Related theories of &#x2018;learning through movement&#x2019; and their application in the rehabilitation of cerebral palsy. Chin J Rehabil Med. (2007) 22:652&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenky D, Khan NS. Severe agitation in a teenager with spastic cerebral palsy: a clinical challenge. Pediatr Emerg Care. (2020) 36:e745&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1097/PEC.0000000000002118,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PEC.0000000000002118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32384395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Zhang F, Wen F, Chen F, Zhu T. Effect of biofeedback combined with task-oriented training on hand function, Gesell scale score and balance ability in children with spastic cerebral palsy. Sichuan Da Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. (2020) 51:428&#x2013;33. doi: 10.12182/20200360105,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12182/20200360105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32543155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L. Application of low-frequency electrical stimulation of the head combined with task-oriented training in children with cerebral palsy. Heilongjiang Med Sci. (2020) 43:149&#x2013;50. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1008-0104.2020.01.072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1008-0104.2020.01.072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo N, Crocher V, Spaho E, Ewert C, Fathi M, Hur P, et al. Capturing upper limb gross motor categories using the Kinect&#xae; sensor. Am J Occup Ther. (2019) 73:7304205090p1&#x2013;7304205090p10. doi: 10.5014/ajot.2019.031682,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2019.031682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6638702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XJ, Tang YL, Ma BX, Qin J, Zou LP, Wang JQ. The definition, diagnostic criteria and clinical classification of cerebral palsy. Chin J Pract Pediatr. (2014) 29:1520&#x2013;12. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.issn.2095-428X.2014.19.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.issn.2095-428X.2014.19.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2019) 10:142. doi: 10.1002/14651858.ED000142,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.ED000142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan YB, Wu YX, Yi WC, Wang SY, Hou H. The application of task-oriented games combined with music therapy in the occupational therapy of children with cerebral palsy. Chinese J Rehab Med. (2015) 30:416&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3870/zgkf.2015.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3870/zgkf.2015.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JH, Jung JH, Hahm SC, Cho HY. The effects of task-oriented training on hand dexterity and strength in children with spastic hemiplegic cerebral palsy: a preliminary study. J Phys Ther Sci. (2017) 29:1800&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1589/jpts.29.1800,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.29.1800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29184291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Fan YJ, Li ZJ, Huang YY, Tang LJ, Fan WC. The influence of Bobath therapy combined with task-oriented training on the intelligence of children with cerebral palsy. Matern Child Health Care China. (2018) 33:4653&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Meng FY, Chen MX, Wang L, Xu X, Zhao HB. The effect of task-oriented training on the upper limb function of children with spastic hemiplegia. J Kunming Med Univ. (2018) 39:85&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1003-4706.2018.03.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1003-4706.2018.03.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XJ. The influence of guided health education combined with task-oriented training on the motor function and walking function of children with cerebral palsy. Intern Med. (2019) 14:606&#x2013;8. doi: 10.16121/j.cnki.cn45-1347/r.2019.05.32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16121/j.cnki.cn45-1347/r.2019.05.32</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao XY, Que LS, Liao F, Lin B, Wu ZB, Pan WJ. The practical effect of mirror feedback therapy combined with task-oriented training in children with hemiplegic cerebral palsy. China Med Herald. (2020) 17:101&#x2013;4. doi: 10.20047/j.issn.1673-7210.2020.17.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20047/j.issn.1673-7210.2020.17.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv YB, Zhang L, Shan L, Jia FY. Study on the impact of task-oriented training on the lower limb coordination and balance of young children with spastic cerebral palsy. Matern Child Health Care China. (2020) 35:265&#x2013;7. doi: 10.19829/j.zgfybj.issn.1001-4411.2020.02.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19829/j.zgfybj.issn.1001-4411.2020.02.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XX, Shi QH, Luan LL, Jia FY, Li HH. A study on the effect of task-oriented training on the upper limb function and functional independence of children with spastic cerebral palsy. J Dev Med. (2020) 8:257&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Li HX, Zhao N, Xu X, Luo L, Wang Q, et al. A study on the therapeutic effect of task-oriented training on hand function of children with cerebral palsy. Chin J Woman Child Health. (2021) 32:330&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang WD, Xing LH, Li Q. Task-oriented training combined with biofeedback technology on the balance ability, upper limb function and intelligence of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Chin Pediatr Integr Tradit West Med. (2021) 13:46&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao ZH, Wang H, Yin HW, Du Y, Ruan WC. The influence of task-oriented training combined with hydrotherapy on the motor function of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Zhejiang J Integr Tradit Chin West Med. (2022) 32:248&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan TL, Zhu LY, Dai JE, Xu B, Fan RR, Zou FH. The impact of a family-centered task-oriented training program on the functional independence and quality of life of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Chin J Phys Med Rehabil. (2022) 44:138&#x2013;42. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2022.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-1424.2022.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li L, Yue XY, Su X, Li JF. The influence of task-oriented therapy on the lower limb coordination and balance of children with spastic cerebral palsy. China J Mod Med. (2023) 33:38&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao L, Wang Y, Fu XH, Li FY. The influence of task-oriented training on the gross motor function and mobility of children with spastic diplegia. Harbin Med J. (2023) 43:108&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZH, Wang J, Yue L, Sun SZ, Ma GL, Bai B, et al. A clinical study on the treatment of spastic cerebral palsy using task-oriented training combined with suspension training. Chin J Integr Med Cardio Cerebrovasc Dis. (2024) 22:2280&#x2013;4. doi: 10.12102/j.issn.1672-1349.2024.12.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12102/j.issn.1672-1349.2024.12.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daliri M, Salehi Nasab F, Fatorehchy S, Farzad M, Moradi A. Impact of virtual reality task-oriented training on upper extremity motor function in children with cerebral palsy: a randomised controlled trial. Pediatr Neurol. (2025) 163:85&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2024.12.001,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2024.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39731993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma XW. Progress in the treatment of childhood cerebral palsy. Dev Med Electr J. (2016) 4:252&#x2013;5. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.2095-5340.2016.04.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.2095-5340.2016.04.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak I, Morgan C, Adde L, Blackman J, Boyd RN, Brunstrom-Hernandez J, et al. Early, accurate diagnosis and early intervention in cerebral palsy: advances in diagnosis and treatment. JAMA Pediatr. (2017) 171:897&#x2013;907. doi: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2017.1689,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2017.1689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28715518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnackers M, Beckers L, Janssen-Potten Y, Aarts P, Rameckers E, Burg J, et al. Home-based bimanual training based on motor learning principles in children with unilateral cerebral palsy and their parents (the COAD-study): rationale and protocols. BMC Pediatr. (2018) 18:139. doi: 10.1186/s12887-018-1110-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-018-1110-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5907414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29669522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorsdahl AB, Moe-Nilssen R, Kaale HK, Rieber J, Strand LI. Change in basic motor abilities, quality of movement and everyday activities following intensive, goal-directed, activity-focused physiotherapy in a group setting for children with cerebral palsy. BMC Pediatr. (2010) 10:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1186/1471-2431-10-26,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2431-10-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20423507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au MK, Chan WM, Lee L, Chen TM, Chau RM, Pang MY. Core stability exercise is as effective as task-oriented motor training in improving motor proficiency in children with developmental coordination disorder: a randomized controlled pilot study. Clin Rehabil. (2014) 28:992&#x2013;1003. doi: 10.1177/0269215514527596,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215514527596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S. The impact of task-oriented training on the upper limb and hand functions of children with cerebral palsy. Clin Res. (2018) 26:92&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles J, Gordon AM. Development of hand arm bimanual intensive therapy (HABIT) for improving bimanual coordination in children with hemiplegic cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol. (2006) 48:931&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1017/S0012162206002039,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0012162206002039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17044964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Pang W, Fan YP, Zhao YB. A study on the therapeutic effect of task-oriented training on the mobility function of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Chinese J Child Health Care. (2015) 23:556&#x2013;8. doi: 10.11852/zgetbjzz2015-23-05-35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11852/zgetbjzz2015-23-05-35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang W, Li X, Fan YP, Chen Y. The therapeutic effect of task-oriented training on gross motor function and walking ability of children with spastic cerebral palsy. Chinese J Rehab Med. (2016) 31:30&#x2013;4. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1001-1242.2016.01.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1001-1242.2016.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SQ. Clinical efficacy analysis of acupuncture combined with rehabilitation training in the treatment of cerebral palsy in children. Chinese J Integr Med Cardio-Cerebrovasc Dis. (2015) 13:185&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.16721349.2015.02.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.16721349.2015.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JL. Recent advances in rehabilitation concepts and techniques for cerebral palsy. Chin J Child Health Care. (2017) 25:433&#x2013;6. doi: 10.11852/zgetbjzz2017-25-05-01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11852/zgetbjzz2017-25-05-01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putri DE, Srilestari A, Abdurrohim K, Mangunatmadja I, Wahyuni LK. The effect of laser acupuncture on spasticity in children with spastic cerebral palsy. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. (2020) 13:152&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jams.2020.09.001,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jams.2020.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji JL. The influence of scalp acupuncture combined with task-oriented training on somatosensory evoked potentials and functional recovery in children with spastic cerebral palsy. Sichuan J Physiol Sci. (2023) 45:287&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>