<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41116747</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1226-4512</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Korean journal of physiology &amp; pharmacology : official journal of the Korean Physiological Society and the Korean Society of Pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Physiol Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of rehabilitation exercise programs on respiratory function, muscle strength, and exercise performance ability in individuals with spinal cord injury: a pilot randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>9</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4196/kjpp.25.109</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiopulmonary dysfunction is a critical complication following spinal cord injury (SCI), yet conventional rehabilitation often focuses narrowly on inspiratory training. This study aimed to evaluate a novel, multicomponent program that integrates respiratory, strength, and aerobic training to improve overall cardiopulmonary health in this population. In this randomized controlled trial, 22 individuals with chronic SCI were assigned to an experimental (EXP) or a no-intervention control (CON) group. The EXP group underwent a 4-week supervised program of progressive, integrated exercises. Key outcomes included changes in respiratory function (spirometry), isometric shoulder strength, and exercise capacity (NetVO&#x2082;). The EXP group demonstrated significantly greater improvements than the CON group in all measured domains. Key respiratory outcomes, including maximal inspiratory pressure and peak expiratory flow, increased significantly, with a notable increase in forced vital capacity of 0.5 &#xb1; 0.6 L. Upper limb strength also improved substantially; for example, shoulder flexion strength increased by up to 3.2 &#xb1; 1.2 N. Furthermore, exercise capacity, measured by NetVO&#x2082;, increased by 2.7 &#xb1; 1.3 ml/kg/min (all p &lt; 0.05). A structured, multidimensional exercise program that combines respiratory, strength, and aerobic training is a highly effective strategy for concurrently enhancing cardiopulmonary function, muscle strength, and aerobic capacity in individuals with SCI. These findings advocate for a holistic, integrated approach over single-modality training to optimize functional recovery. Clinical Research Information Service (CRIS; KCT0010320).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Se-Hee</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Korea University School of Medicine, Seoul 02841, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Na Young</ForeName><Initials>NY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Asian Women Sookmyung Women's University, Seoul 04310, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Min-Goo</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Korea University School of Medicine, Seoul 02841, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ux lab for Accessibility, Good Playground Inc., Seoul 04749, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Physiol Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9709505</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-4512</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise tolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory function tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST</b>
. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41116747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12723415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4196/kjpp.25.109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">kjpp.25.109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ashton R. In: Egan's fundamentals of respiratory care. 11th ed. Kacmarek RM, Stoller JK, Heuer AJ, editors. Elsevier Health Sciences; 2017. Neuromuscular and other disease of the chest wall; pp. 650&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchberger I, Cieza A, Biering-S&#xf8;rensen F, Baumberger M, Charlifue S, Post MW, Campbell R, Kovindha A, Ring H, Sinnott A, Kostanjsek N, Stucki G. ICF Core Sets for individuals with spinal cord injury in the early post-acute context. Spinal Cord. 2010;48:297&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1038/sc.2009.128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sc.2009.128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19786973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD. Cardiorespiratory fitness and training in quadriplegics and paraplegics. Sports Med. 1986;3:312&#x2013;330. doi: 10.2165/00007256-198603050-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-198603050-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3529281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haisma JA, Bussmann JB, Stam HJ, Sluis TA, Bergen MP, Dallmeijer AJ, de Groot S, van der Woude LH. Changes in physical capacity during and after inpatient rehabilitation in subjects with a spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87:741&#x2013;748. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2006.02.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2006.02.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16731207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, Carty C, Chaput JP, Chastin S, Chou R, Dempsey PC, DiPietro L, Ekelund U, Firth J, Friedenreich CM, Garcia L, Gichu M, Jago R, Katzmarzyk PT, Lambert E, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:1451&#x2013;1462. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers J, Lee M, Kiratli J. Cardiovascular disease in spinal cord injury: an overview of prevalence, risk, evaluation, and management. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2007;86:142&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0b013e31802f0247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e31802f0247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchholz AC, Martin Ginis KA, Bray SR, Craven BC, Hicks AL, Hayes KC, Latimer AE, McColl MA, Potter PJ, Wolfe DL. Greater daily leisure time physical activity is associated with lower chronic disease risk in adults with spinal cord injury. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2009;34:640&#x2013;647. doi: 10.1139/H09-050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H09-050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19767799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg-Emons RJ, Bussmann JB, Haisma JA, Sluis TA, van der Woude LH, Bergen MP, Stam HJ. A prospective study on physical activity levels after spinal cord injury during inpatient rehabilitation and the year after discharge. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89:2094&#x2013;2101. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2008.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2008.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18996237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehn M, Kroll T. Staying physically active after spinal cord injury: a qualitative exploration of barriers and facilitators to exercise participation. BMC Public Health. 2009;9:168. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-9-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-9-168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2694784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin Ginis KA, J&#xf6;rgensen S, Stapleton J. Exercise and sport for persons with spinal cord injury. PM R. 2012;4:894&#x2013;900. doi: 10.1016/j.pmrj.2012.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2012.08.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23174556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McVeigh SA, Hitzig SL, Craven BC. Influence of sport participation on community integration and quality of life: a comparison between sport participants and non-sport participants with spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. 2009;32:115&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1080/10790268.2009.11760762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2009.11760762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19569458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb TL, Joseph J, Yardley L, Michie S. Using the internet to promote health behavior change: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the impact of theoretical basis, use of behavior change techniques, and mode of delivery on efficacy. J Med Internet Res. 2010;12:e4. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20164043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chushkin M, Popova L, Ots O, Nenasheva O, Struchkov P. Comparison between results of spirometry performed with the ATS/ERS quantitative criteria and simple visual inspection criteria. Eur Respir J. 2017;50(suppl 61):OA3440. doi: 10.1183/1393003.congress-2017.OA3440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/1393003.congress-2017.OA3440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KB, Kim MK, Jeong JR, Lee WH. Reliability of an electronic inspiratory loading device for assessing pulmonary function in post-stroke patients. Med Sci Monit. 2016;22:191&#x2013;196. doi: 10.12659/MSM.895573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.895573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4725617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26782369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutbeyaz ST, Koseoglu F, Inan L, Coskun O. Respiratory muscle training improves cardiopulmonary function and exercise tolerance in subjects with subacute stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2010;24:240&#x2013;250. doi: 10.1177/0269215509358932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215509358932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20156979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragada JA, Magalh&#xe3;es PM, S&#xe3;o-Pedro E, Bartolomeu RF, Morais JE. Net heart rate for estimating oxygen consumption in active adults. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2024;9:66. doi: 10.3390/jfmk9020066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9020066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11036223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paiva DN, Assmann LB, Bordin DF, Gass R, Jost RT, Bernardo-Filho M, Fran&#xe7;a RA, Cardoso DM. Inspiratory muscle training with threshold or incentive spirometry: which is the most effective? Rev Port Pneumol (2006) 2015;21:76&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.rppnen.2014.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rppnen.2014.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald T, Stiller K. Inspiratory muscle training is feasible and safe for patients with acute spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019;42:220&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1080/10790268.2018.1432307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2018.1432307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candace WY, Kennis CK, Evelyn KY, Jeffrey TH, Margaret LY, Hwang SS, Shirley NP. Effect of a 4-week Theraband exercise with PNF pattern on improving mobility, balance and fear of fall in community-dwelling elderly. J Korean Soc Phys Med. 2017;12:73&#x2013;82. doi: 10.13066/kspm.2017.12.4.73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13066/kspm.2017.12.4.73</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavl&#x16f; D, &#x160;kripkov&#xe1; A, P&#xe1;nek D. The effects of elastic band exercises with PNF on shooting speed and accuracy in ball hockey players during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:11391. doi: 10.3390/ijerph182111391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182111391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baiamonte BA, Kraemer RR, Chabreck CN, Reynolds ML, McCaleb KM, Shaheen GL, Hollander DB. Exercise-induced hypoalgesia: pain tolerance, preference and tolerance for exercise intensity, and physiological correlates following dynamic circuit resistance exercise. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1239833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1239833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27712194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TW, An DI, Lee HY, Jeong HY, Kim DH, Sung YH. Effects of elastic band exercise on subjects with rounded shoulder posture and forward head posture. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28:1733&#x2013;1737. doi: 10.1589/jpts.28.1733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.28.1733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4932046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss DE, Ionta MK, Myers BJ. Proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation: patterns and techniques. 3rd ed. M&#xe9;dica Panamericana; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pink M. Contralateral effects of upper extremity proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation patterns. Phys Ther. 1981;61:1158&#x2013;1162. doi: 10.1093/ptj/61.8.1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/61.8.1158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7267706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;191. doi: 10.3758/BF03193146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postma K, Haisma JA, Hopman MT, Bergen MP, Stam HJ, Bussmann JB. Resistive inspiratory muscle training in people with spinal cord injury during inpatient rehabilitation: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2014;94:1709&#x2013;1719. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20140079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20140079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25082923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Kader SM. Impact of respiratory muscle training on blood gases and pulmonary function among patients with cervical spinal cord injury. Electron J Gen Med. 2018;15:em15. doi: 10.29333/ejgm/85190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29333/ejgm/85190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16037698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato M. The study on effective load pressure for the respiratory muscle training. Rigaku Ryohogaku. 2002;29:37&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angane EY, Navare AA. Effects of aerobic exercise on pulmonary function tests in healthy adults. Int J Res Med Sci. 2017;4:2059&#x2013;2063. doi: 10.18203/2320-6012.ijrms20161760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2320-6012.ijrms20161760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CY, Lee JS, Kim HD, Lee DJ. Short-term effects of respiratory muscle training combined with the abdominal drawing-in maneuver on the decreased pulmonary function of individuals with chronic spinal cord injury: a pilot randomized controlled trial. J Spinal Cord Med. 2017;40:17&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1080/10790268.2016.1198576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2016.1198576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5376135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27463071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulroy SJ, Thompson L, Kemp B, Hatchett PP, Newsam CJ, Lupold DG, Haubert LL, Eberly V, Ge TT, Azen SP, Winstein CJ, Gordon J Physical Therapy Clinical Research Network (PTClinResNet), author Strengthening and optimal movements for painful shoulders (STOMPS) in chronic spinal cord injury: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2011;91:305&#x2013;324. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20100182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20100182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lins C, Castro A, Medina GIS, Azevedo ERFBM, Donato BS, Chagas MSS, Tancredo JR, Vargas de Almeida L, Cliquet A., Jr Alternative scapular stabilization exercises to target strength, endurance and function of shoulders in tetraplegia: a prospective non-controlled intervention study. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019;42:65&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1080/10790268.2017.1398943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2017.1398943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6340282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam C, Kaur J, Singh H. Effect of upper limb proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation with resistance training on respiratory muscle strength in quadriplegics: a randomized controlled trial. Exerc Med. 2020;4:2. doi: 10.26644/em.2020.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26644/em.2020.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Seong DH, Liu W, Wang Z, Jeong YW, Kim JC, Kang DR, Lee RJE, Koh JH, Kim SH. Exercise improves muscle mitochondrial dysfunction-associated lipid profile under circadian rhythm disturbance. Korean J Physiol Pharmacol. 2024;28:515&#x2013;526. doi: 10.4196/kjpp.2024.28.6.515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4196/kjpp.2024.28.6.515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39467715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth BE, Haskell WL, Herrmann SD, Meckes N, Bassett DR, Jr, Tudor-Locke C, Greer JL, Vezina J, Whitt-Glover MC, Leon AS. 2011 Compendium of Physical Activities: a second update of codes and MET values. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1575&#x2013;1581. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31821ece12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31821ece12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21681120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins EG, Gater D, Kiratli J, Butler J, Hanson K, Langbein WE. Energy cost of physical activities in persons with spinal cord injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:691&#x2013;700. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181bb902f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181bb902f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder&#xf3;n-Ju&#xe1;rez M, Miller T, Samejima S, Shackleton C, Malik RN, Sachdeva R, Dorey TW, Krassioukov AV. Heart rate variability-based prediction of autonomic dysreflexia after spinal cord injury. J Neurotrauma. 2024;41:1172&#x2013;1180. doi: 10.1089/neu.2023.0583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2023.0583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38214089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea MP, Dunlop SA, Davis GM, Nunn A, Geraghty T, Hsueh YS, Churilov L. Intensive exercise program after spinal cord injury ("Full-On"): study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2013;14:291. doi: 10.1186/1745-6215-14-291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-14-291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3848453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24025260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Straaten MG, Cloud BA, Morrow MM, Ludewig PM, Zhao KD. Effectiveness of home exercise on pain, function, and strength of manual wheelchair users with spinal cord injury: a high-dose shoulder program with telerehabilitation. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014;95:1810&#x2013;1817.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2014.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2014.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24887534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown R, DiMarco AF, Hoit JD, Garshick E. Respiratory dysfunction and management in spinal cord injury. Respir Care. 2006;51:853&#x2013;868.:discussion 869-870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2495152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16867197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West CR, Taylor BJ, Campbell IG, Romer LM. Effects of inspiratory muscle training on exercise responses in Paralympic athletes with cervical spinal cord injury. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:764&#x2013;772. doi: 10.1111/sms.12070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23530708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks AL, Martin KA, Ditor DS, Latimer AE, Craven C, Bugaresti J, McCartney N. Long-term exercise training in persons with spinal cord injury: effects on strength, arm ergometry performance and psychological well-being. Spinal Cord. 2003;41:34&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1038/sj.sc.3101389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.sc.3101389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12494319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>