<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41601813</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>PneuNet: a lightweight convolutional neural network with multiscale feature fusion for automated pneumonia detection from chest X-rays.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1713587</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1713587</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1713587</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2025.1713587</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chest X-rays are a time-consuming, interpretation-heavy, and variable process in diagnosing pneumonia, a respiratory disease. This paper presents PneuNet, our unique convolutional neural network (CNN) structured to improve pneumonia identification by overcoming the challenges posed by chest X-ray interpretation processes. When interpreting pneumonia in a chest X-ray, deep learning, especially CNNs have demonstrated strength in medical imaging, and existing models such as Xception and MobileNet reported high pneumonia identification accuracies, with MobileNet being smaller and designed for use in resource-constrained edge devices. However, pre-trained models often do not adequately identify pneumonia because of a lack of customization. Therefore we designed PneuNet with four targeted innovations: depthwise separable convolutions for computational efficiency, Squeeze-and-Excitation (SE) blocks to emphasize informative channels, Atrous Spatial Pyramid Pooling (ASPP) for multiscale context, and a novel Learnable Pooling layer that replaces fixed global average pooling with trainable spatial weighting (1&#x202f;&#xd7;&#x202f;1 convolution + sigmoid). This enables the model to dynamically focus on pneumonia-relevant lung regions instead of uniformly averaging features. PneuNet was trained and evaluated on the publicly available Chest X-ray Pneumonia Kaggle dataset using a stratified 80-10-10 split. On the training set (4,646 images), PneuNet achieved 97% accuracy. On the independent validation set (586 images) used for hyperparameter tuning and early stopping, it attained 93% accuracy. The final model, selected at the epoch of lowest validation loss, yielded 91% accuracy on the held-out test set (624 images). The modest 2% drop from validation to test performance, combined with a stabilized validation loss of 0.44 after epoch 42, confirms effective generalization and successful overfitting mitigation through dropout (rate&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.3), L2 regularization (<i>&#x3bb;</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.001), and early stopping (patience&#x202f;=&#x202f;7). The accuracy and loss curves provide functional illustrations of the PneuNet model converging effectively, albeit with the possibility of improvements following additional tuning. Methods such as data augmentation, dropout, L2 regularization, tuning hyperparameters could allow PneuNet to become more robust. Although the model did particularly well compared to the baseline, of course there are improvements to be had with further tuning and other architecture search, and ideally transfer learning to establish more real world applications. Certainly increasing the quantity of data would also help for a wider generalization to provide additional features to the data model. Overall, this study demonstrates the possible value of deep learning for automating pneumonia screening, where deep learning introduces a possible efficient and scalable diagnostic tool for augmenting health care professionals, especially in developing nations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Saranyaraj, Shrinaath, Nayak and Vishal.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saranyaraj</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrinaath</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nayak</LastName><ForeName>Ananya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vishal</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ASPP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chest X-ray images</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">convolutional neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pneumonia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41601813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12832688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1713587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kundu R, Das R, Geem ZW, Han GT, Sarkar R. Pneumonia detection in chest X-ray images using an ensemble of deep learning models. PLoS One. (2021) 16:e0256630. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0256630,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0256630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8423280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshan MSA, Gill KS, Anand V, Gupta S, Alshahrani H, Sulaiman A, et al. Detection of pneumonia from chest X-ray images utilizing mobilenet model. Healthcare. (2023) 11:1561. MDPI. doi: 10.3390/healthcare11111561,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11111561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37297701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venu SK. An ensemble-based approach by fine-tuning the deep transfer learning models to classify pneumonia from chest X-ray images. arXiv. (2020) 2020:5543. doi: 10.5220/0010377403900401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5220/0010377403900401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D. Attention-enhanced architecture for improved pneumonia detection in chest X-ray images. BMC Med Imaging. (2024) 24:6. doi: 10.1186/s12880-023-01177-1,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12880-023-01177-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38166579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chouhan V, Singh SK, Khamparia A, Gupta D, Tiwari P, Moreira C, et al. A novel transfer learning based approach for pneumonia detection in chest X-ray images. Appl Sci. (2020) 10:559. doi: 10.3390/app10020559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10020559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan W, Zaki N, Ali L. Intelligent pneumonia identification from chest x-rays: a systematic literature review. IEEE Access. (2021) 9:51747&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3069937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3069937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Guleria K. A systematic literature review on deep learning approaches for pneumonia detection using chest X-ray images. Multimed Tools Appl. (2024) 83:24101&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/s11042-023-16419-1,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-023-16419-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar W, Soomro A, Hussain A, Hussain T, Ali F, Haq MIU, et al. Pneumonia detection: a comprehensive study of diverse neural network architectures using chest X-rays. Int J Appl Math Comput Sci. (2024) 34:45. doi: 10.61822/amcs-2024-0045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61822/amcs-2024-0045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin SU, Taj S, Hussain A, Seo S. An automated chest X-ray analysis for COVID-19, tuberculosis, and pneumonia employing ensemble learning approach. Biomed Signal Process Control. (2024) 87:105408. doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2023.105408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2023.105408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim AU, Ozsoz M, Serte S, Al-Turjman F, Yakoi PS. Pneumonia classification using deep learning from chest X-ray images during COVID-19. Cogn Comput. (2024) 16:1589&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1007/s12559-020-09787-5,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12559-020-09787-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33425044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Guleria K. A deep learning based model for the detection of pneumonia from chest X-ray images using VGG-16 and neural networks. Proc Comput Sci. (2023) 218:357&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.procs.2023.01.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2023.01.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundur NC, Anil BC, Dhulavvagol PM, Ganiger R, Ramadoss B. Pneumonia detection in chest x-rays using transfer learning and tpus. Eng Technol Appl Sci Res. (2023) 13:11878&#x2013;83. doi: 10.48084/etasr.6335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48084/etasr.6335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panwar A, Gupta S. Deep learning models for early detection of pneumonia using chest X-ray images. In: <i>Proceedings of the International Conference on Paradigms of Communication, Computing and Data Sciences: PCCDS 2021</i>, Springer Singapore, pp. 701&#x2013;709. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang L, Tang B, Huang J, Li J. 3D-MRI super-resolution reconstruction using multi-modality based on multi-resolution CNN. Comput Methods Prog Biomed. (2024) 248:108110. doi: 10.1016/j.cmpb.2024.108110,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2024.108110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38452685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Tripathi BK. Pneumonia classification using quaternion deep learning. Multimed Tools Appl. (2022) 81:1743&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1007/s11042-021-11409-7,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-021-11409-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8506489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34658656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A, Shah M. Advancement of deep learning in pneumonia/COVID-19 classification and localization: a systematic review with qualitative and quantitative analysis. Chronic Dis Transl Med. (2022) 8:154&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1002/cdt3.17,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cdt3.17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35572951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi R, Javaid S. Deep learning for pneumonia detection in chest x-ray images: a comprehensive survey. J Imaging. (2024) 10:176. doi: 10.3390/jimaging10080176,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging10080176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39194965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshanketi F, Alharbi A, Kuruvilla M, Mahzoon V, Siddiqui ST, Rana N, et al. Pneumonia detection from chest X-ray images using deep learning and transfer learning for imbalanced datasets. J Imaging Inf Med. (2024) 38:2021&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1007/s10278-024-01334-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-024-01334-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12344030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39557737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asnake NW, Salau AO, Ayalew AM. X-ray image-based pneumonia detection and classification using deep learning. Multimed Tools Appl. (2024) 83:60789&#x2013;807. doi: 10.1007/s11042-023-17965-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-023-17965-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colin J, Surantha N. Interpretable deep learning for pneumonia detection using chest X-ray images. Information. (2025) 16:53. doi: 10.3390/info16010053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info16010053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mabrouk A, Diaz Redondo RP, Dahou A, Abd Elaziz M, Kayed M. Pneumonia detection on chest X-ray images using ensemble of deep convolutional neural networks. Appl Sci. (2022) 12:6448. doi: 10.3390/app12136448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12136448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwendo I, Gikunda K, Maina A. Deep transfer learning for detecting Covid-19, pneumonia and tuberculosis using CXR images--a review. arXiv. (2023) 2023:16754. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2303.16754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2303.16754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni A, Parasnis G, Balasubramanian H, Jain V, Chokshi A, Sonkusare R. Advancing diagnostic precision: leveraging machine learning techniques for accurate detection of covid-19, pneumonia, and tuberculosis in chest x-ray images. arXiv. (2023) 2023:6080. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2310.06080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2310.06080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque MS, Taluckder MS, Shawkat SB, Shahriyar MA, Sayed MA, Modak C. Prediction of pneumonia and COVID-19 using deep neural networks. arXiv. (2023) 2023:10368. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2308.10368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2308.10368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billah MM, Al Rakib A, Ahamed AS, Chowdhury S, Mitro S. A comparative study on the detection of pneumonia in chest X-ray images utilizing deep learning models. Eur J Comput Sci Inf Technol. (2024) 12:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.37745/ejcsit.2013/vol12n7111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37745/ejcsit.2013/vol12n7111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kermany DS, Goldbaum M, Cai W, Valentim CCS, Liang H, Baxter SL, et al. Identifying medical diagnoses and treatable diseases by image-based deep learning. Cell. (2018) 172:1122&#x2013;1131.e9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2018.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2018.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29474911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>