<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41855375</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects on Heart Rate Variability of a European Under-18 Rugby Tournament.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005362</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rugby union is characterized by intermittent efforts combining high and lowintensity actions. In European Under-18 Rugby XV Championship, matches are played every 72 hours, which may hinder adequate recovery. Heart rate variability (HRV) is a noninvasive method that assesses the autonomic nervous system activity, yet its role to measure the rugby players recovery remains underexplored. The purpose of this study was to evaluate HRV responses in elite under-18 rugby players during an European Championship with matches every 72 hours. This prospective study was conducted with 27 players from the Spanish under-18 national rugby team. HRV data were collected daily for 12 days, including pretournament preparation and 3 matches. Measurements were taken in a supine resting position using a Bluetooth chest-strap. Time-domain, frequency-domain, and nonlinear HRV metrics were analyzed. Statistical comparisons were made using Friedman and Wilcoxon tests (p &lt; 0.05). HRV metrics showed no significant differences between pretournament values and the first match day (first MD). However, time-domain, frequency-domain, and nonlinear variables significantly decreased after the first MD compared with the second (second MD) and third match days (third MD) (p &lt; 0.0001). No significant differences were observed between the second MD and third MD. These findings suggest persistent autonomic imbalance and insufficient recovery between matches. Playing matches every 72 hours does not allow for adequate recovery in under-18 rugby players. Daily HRV monitoring provides a valuable tool for assessing fatigue, guiding training load management, and reducing injury risk during competitive tournaments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sol&#xed;s-Menc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>Cristian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez-Herranz</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1680-6178</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Rehabilitation, School of Sport Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Complutense University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cano-Cappellacci</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Department, Universidad de Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibacache-Saavedra</LastName><ForeName>Paulina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Fern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Nursing, Physiotherapy and Podiatry, Complutense University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Sousa-De Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Nursing, Physiotherapy and Podiatry, Complutense University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos Veliz</LastName><ForeName>Rafael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sports, Centro de Estudios Universitario Cardenal Spindola CEU, Sevilla, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Mat&#xed;as-Cid</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical and Sports Education, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports Sciences, University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos-&#xc1;lvarez</LastName><ForeName>Juan Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Rehabilitation, School of Sport Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Complutense University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac-parasympathetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elite athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postmatch</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41855375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aben HGJ, Hills SP, Cooke CB, et al. Profiling the post-match recovery response in Male rugby: A systematic review. J Strength Condit Res 36: 2050&#x2013;2067, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Available at: https://www.rugbyeurope.eu/competitions/u18-championship-2023. Accessed September 09, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Available at: https://www.sixnationsrugby.com/en/u6n/u18-mens/matches/2024. Accessed September 09, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Available at: https://www.sudamerica.rugby/espanol/mucho-rugby-en-el-sudamericano-m18-3?nid=1064. Accessed September 09, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubert AE, Seps B, Beckers F. Heart rate variability in athletes. Sports Med (Auckl NZ) 33: 889&#x2013;919, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross R, Siegler J, Marshall P, Lovell R. Scheduling of training and recovery during the in-season weekly micro-cycle: Insights from team sport practitioners. Eur J Sport Sci 19: 1287&#x2013;1296, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunniffe B, Hore AJ, Whitcombe DM, et al. Time course of changes in immuneoendocrine markers following an international rugby game. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 113&#x2013;122, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmonds RC, Sinclair WH, Leicht AS. Effect of a training week on heart rate variability in elite youth rugby league players. Int J Sports Med 34: 1087&#x2013;1092, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elloumi M, Maso F, Michaux O, Robert A, Lac G. Behaviour of saliva cortisol [C], testosterone [T] and the T/C ratio during a rugby match and during the post-competition recovery days. Eur J Appl Physiol 90: 23&#x2013;28, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst G. Heart-rate variability-more than heart beats? Front Public Health 5: 240, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatisson J, Oswald V, Lalonde F. Influence diagram of physiological and environmental factors affecting heart rate variability: An extended literature overview. Heart Int 11: e32&#x2013;e40, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flatt AA, Howells D, Williams S. Effects of consecutive domestic and international tournaments on heart rate variability in an elite rugby sevens team. J Sci Med Sport 22: 616&#x2013;621, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grainger A, Heffernan S, Waldron M, Sawczuk T. Autonomic nervous system indices of player readiness during elite-level rugby union game-week microcycles. J Strength Cond Res 36: 3173&#x2013;3178, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik M, Bigger JT, Camm AJ, et al. Heart rate variability: Standards of measurement, physiological interpretation, and clinical use. Eur Heart J 17: 354&#x2013;381, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. Markers of postmatch fatigue in professional rugby league players. J Strength Condit Res 25: 1030&#x2013;1039, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mencia CS, Ramos-&#xc1;lvarez JJ, Veliz RR, et al. Epidemiology of the injuries sustained by elite Spanish under-18 and under-20 rugby players. Int J Sports Med 44: 224&#x2013;231, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishica C, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Hynynen E, et al. Relationships between heart rate variability, sleep duration, cortisol and physical training in young athletes. J Sports Sci Med 20: 778&#x2013;788, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales J, Alamo JM, Garc&#xed;a-Mass&#xf3; X, et al. Use of heart rate variability in monitoring stress and recovery in judo athletes. J Strength Condit Res 28: 1896&#x2013;1905, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-L&#xf3;pez A, Naranjo-Orellana J. Individual versus team heart rate variability responsiveness analyses in a national soccer team during training camps. Sci Rep 10: 11726, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira-Silva I, Leicht AS, Moraes MR, et al. Heart rate and cardiovascular responses to commercial flights: Relationships with physical fitness. Front Physiol 7: 648, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarrie KL, Raftery M, Blackie J, et al. Managing player load in professional rugby union: A review of current knowledge and practices. Br J Sports Med 51: 421&#x2013;427, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-L&#xf3;pez C, Till K, Sawczuk T, et al. A multi-nation examination of the fatigue and recovery time course during the inaugural under-18 six nations rugby union competition. J Sports Sci 38: 644&#x2013;651, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Read D, Weaving D, Phibbs P, et al. Movement and physical demands of school and university rugby union match-play in England. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 2: e000147, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SP, Trewartha G, Higgitt RJ, El-Abd J, Stokes KA. The physical demands of elite English rugby union. J Sports Sci 26: 825&#x2013;833, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe G, Darrall-Jones J, Till K, et al. Between-days reliability and sensitivity of common fatigue measures in rugby players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 581&#x2013;586, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solis-Mencia C, Ramos-&#xc1;lvarez JJ, Murias-Lozano R, Aramberri M, Sal&#xf3; JC. Epidemiology of injuries sustained by elite Under-18 rugby players. J Athl Train 54: 1187&#x2013;1191, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley J, Peake JM, Buchheit M. Cardiac parasympathetic reactivation following exercise: Implications for training prescription. Sports Med (Auckl NZ) 43: 1259&#x2013;1277, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares F, Smith TB, Driller M. Fatigue and recovery in rugby: A review. Sports Med (Auckl NZ) 47: 1515&#x2013;1530, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayer JF, Sternberg E. Beyond heart rate variability: Vagal regulation of allostatic systems. Ann N Y Acad Sci 1088: 361&#x2013;372, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari R, Kumar R, Malik S, Raj T, Kumar P. Analysis of heart rate variability and implication of different factors on heart rate variability. Curr Cardiol Rev 17: e160721189770, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weippert M, Kumar M, Kreuzfeld S, et al. Comparison of three mobile devices for measuring R-R intervals and heart rate variability: Polar S810i, Suunto t6 and an ambulatory ECG system. Eur J Appl Physiol 109: 779&#x2013;786, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner GG, Ford BQ, Mauss IB, et al. High cardiac vagal control is related to better subjective and objective sleep quality. Biol Psychol 106: 79&#x2013;85, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DJ, Finn CV, Cunningham DJ, et al. Neuromuscular function, hormonal, and mood responses to a professional rugby union match. J Strength Cond Res 28: 194&#x2013;200, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>