<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41517669</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Precision identification of endometrial malignancy and precancerous lesions: Development of a machine learning model incorporating multidimensional clinical and imaging parameters.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47257</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47257</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47257</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047257</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To develop and validate a machine learning (ML) model integrating multidimensional clinical, pathomic, and ultrasound radiomic parameters for precise identification of endometrial malignancy and precancerous lesions, with a focus on addressing the diagnostic needs of younger patients pursuing fertility preservation. This retrospective study enrolled patients with suspected endometrial lesions from a single institution. Clinical baseline data (e.g., age, body mass index, menopausal status), pathomic features (e.g., cellular atypia, gland density), and ultrasound radiomic parameters (e.g., endometrial thickness, resistance index) were collected. Key predictors were selected using Pearson correlation, SHapley Additive exPlanations analysis, and least absolute shrinkage and selection operator regression. Seven ML models were constructed and optimized via 5-fold cross-validation. Model performance was evaluated using metrics such as ROC-AUC, sensitivity, specificity, and precision-recall performance in training (70%) and testing (30%) sets. A total of 1221 patients (854 in training, 367 in testing) were included. Seven variables including age, body mass index, menopausal status, cellular atypia, gland density, endometrial thickness, and resistance index emerged as robust predictors. Among the 7 ML models, the random forest model showed superior performance, with receiver operating characteristic area under curve of 0.98 in the training set and 0.96 in the testing set (95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.93-0.98). It had balanced sensitivity (0.89, 95% CI: 0.75-0.96) and specificity (0.86, 95% CI: 0.82-0.90) in the testing set. It maintained stability across varying risk thresholds and cost-benefit ratios, outperforming other models in precision-recall balance. Integration of multidimensional data via ML, particularly the random forest model, enhances the precision of endometrial malignancy detection. This approach enables personalized risk stratification, supporting targeted management for younger patients and advancing patient-centered care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Jinpeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Xianning Central Hospital, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hubei University of Science and Technology, Xianning, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Xunya</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Xianning Central Hospital, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hubei University of Science and Technology, Xianning, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Meiling</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Xianning Central Hospital, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hubei University of Science and Technology, Xianning, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-5766-415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Xianning Central Hospital, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hubei University of Science and Technology, Xianning, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endometrial Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011230" MajorTopicYN="Y">Precancerous Conditions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004717" MajorTopicYN="N">Endometrium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012372" MajorTopicYN="N">ROC Curve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endometrial malignancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidimensional parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">random forest</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41517669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12795048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202601090-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gao S, Wang J, Li Z, Wang T, Wang J. Global trends in incidence and mortality rates of endometrial cancer among individuals aged 55 years and above from 1990 to 2021: an analysis of the global burden of disease. Int J Women&#x2019;s Health. 2025;17:651&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11892492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40066179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazidimoradi A, Momenimovahed Z, Khalajinia Z, Allahqoli L, Salehiniya H, Alkatout I. The global incidence, mortality, and burden of uterine cancer in 2019 and correlation with SDI, tobacco, dietary risks, and metabolic risk factors: an ecological study. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7:e1835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38274134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise MR, Jordan V, Lagas A, et al. Obesity and endometrial hyperplasia and cancer in premenopausal women: a systematic review. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2016;214:689.e1&#x2013;689.e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannella L, Cerami LB, Setti T, Bergamini E, Boselli F. Prediction of endometrial hyperplasia and cancer among premenopausal women with abnormal uterine bleeding. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:8598152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6442314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31011581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourou MZ, Matsas A, Vrekoussis T, Mastorakos G, Valsamakis G, Panoskaltsis T. Conservative treatment of endometrial cancer in women of reproductive age (Review). Mol Clin Oncol. 2023;19:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10265581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37323245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakat A, Ismail A, Chattopadhyay S, Davies Q. Endometrial cancer incidence in patients with atypical endometrial hyperplasia according to mode of management. Cancer Diagnos Prognos. 2022;2:564&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9425575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36060021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannella L, Grelloni C, Bernardi M, et al. Atypical endometrial hyperplasia and concurrent cancer: a comprehensive overview on a challenging clinical condition. Cancers. 2024;16:914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10930610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38473276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Wang J, Wu Y, Zhu A, Li X, Wang J. Prediction of a radiomics-based nomogram for complete remission in atypical endometrial hyperplasia and early endometrial cancer patients seeking fertility preservation. Comput Biol Med. 2025;187:109764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39938342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang Y, Wang J, Fan Y, Wang J. Prediction of complete regression in fertility-sparing patients with endometrial cancer and apical hyperplasia: the GLOBAL model in a large Chinese cohort. J Transl Med. 2024;22:127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10837883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38308352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale SG, Riemma G, Carugno J, et al. Hysteroscopy in the management of endometrial hyperplasia and cancer in reproductive aged women: new developments and current perspectives. Transl Cancer Res. 2020;9:7767&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8799018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35117379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace L, Actis S, Mancarella M, et al. Clinical, sonographic, and hysteroscopic features of endometrial carcinoma diagnosed after hysterectomy in patients with a preoperative diagnosis of atypical hyperplasia: a single-center retrospective study. Diagnostics (Basel, Switzerland). 2022;12:3029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9776887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36553034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson I, Black N, Khattak H, Gupta JK, Rimmer MP; UKARCOG Working Group Authors. Diagnosis and management of endometrial hyperplasia: a UK national audit of adherence to national guidance 2012&#x2013;2020. PLoS Med. 2024;21:e1004346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10903889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38421942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacEachern SJ, Forkert ND. Machine learning for precision medicine. Genome. 2021;64:416&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33091314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deo RC. Machine learning in medicine. Circulation. 2015;132:1920&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26572668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corr BR, Erickson BK, Barber EL, Fisher CM, Slomovitz B. Advances in the management of endometrial cancer. BMJ (Clinical research ed). 2025;388:e080978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40044230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passarello K, Kurian S, Villanueva V. Endometrial cancer: an overview of pathophysiology, management, and care. Semin Oncol Nurs. 2019;35:157&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30867105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras NA, Sabadell J, Verdaguer P, Juli&#xe0; C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Montol&#xed; ME. Fertility-sparing approaches in atypical endometrial hyperplasia and endometrial cancer patients: current evidence and future directions. Int J Mol Sci . 2022;23:2531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Sun W, Liu H, Zhang D. Age at menopause and risk of developing endometrial cancer: a meta-analysis. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:8584130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6560333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31275987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong TT, Wang YL, Ma XX. Age at menarche and endometrial cancer risk: a dose-response meta-analysis of prospective studies. Sci Rep. 2015;5:14051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4566123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26360785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forte M, Cecere SC, Napoli M D, et al. Endometrial cancer in the elderly: characteristics, prognostic and risk factors, and treatment options. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2024;204:104533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39442900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdol Manap N, Ng BK, Phon SE, Abdul Karim AK, Lim PS, Fadhil M. Endometrial cancer in pre-menopausal women and younger: risk factors and outcome. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:9059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laskov I, Zilberman A, Maltz-Yacobi L, et al. Effect of BMI change on recurrence risk in patients with endometrial cancer. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2023;33:713&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawachi A, Shimazu T, Budhathoki S, et al. Association of BMI and height with the risk of endometrial cancer, overall and by histological subtype: a population-based prospective cohort study in Japan. Eur J Cancer Prevent. 2019;28:196&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29672353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke MA, Long BJ, Del Mar Morillo A, Arbyn M, Bakkum-Gamez JN, Wentzensen N. Association of endometrial cancer risk with postmenopausal bleeding in women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Internal Med. 2018;178:1210&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6142981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30083701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun MM, Overbeek-Wager EA, Grumbo RJ. Diagnosis and management of endometrial cancer. Am Fam Physician. 2016;93:468&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26977831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale SG, Riemma G, Haimovich S, et al. Risk of endometrial cancer in asymptomatic postmenopausal women in relation to ultrasonographic endometrial thickness: systematic review and diagnostic test accuracy meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2023;228:22&#x2013;35.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35932873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikram SR, Robinson J, Thanawala T, et al. Ultrasound and blind endometrial sampling for detection of endometrial cancer in women with postmenopausal bleeding. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2024;6:CD014568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11187790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39804116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Santos P, Martins Vieira C, Viana Veloso GG, et al. Tailoring endometrial cancer treatment based on molecular pathology: current status and possible impacts on systemic and local treatment. Int J Mol Sci . 2024;25:7742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11276773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39062983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galant N, Krawczyk P, Monist M, et al. Molecular classification of endometrial cancer and its impact on therapy selection. Int J Mol Sci . 2024;25:5893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11172295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38892080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AJ, Bing RS, Ding DC. Endometrial atypical hyperplasia and risk of endometrial cancer. Diagnostics (Basel, Switzerland). 2024;14:2471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11593242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leino A, Nostolahti A, Ahtikoski A, Huvila J. Molecular subtype and mutational profile of endometrial atypical hyperplasia/endometrioid intraepithelial neoplasia. Int J Gynecol Pathol. 2025;11:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40341112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccardi C, Spagnol G, Bonaldo G, Marchetti M, Tozzi R, Noventa M. New light on endometrial thickness as a risk factor of cancer: what do clinicians need to know? Cancer Manage Res. 2022;14:1331&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8985823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35401014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadzade A, Gharibvand MM, Azhine S. Correlation of color Doppler ultrasound and pathological grading in endometrial carcinoma. J Fam Med Primary Care. 2020;9:5188&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7773073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33409186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Cen S, Kang XL, Wang WF, Wang Y, Chen X. Doppler ultrasound measurement of resistance index in the diagnosis of prostate cancer. Tumori. 2015;101:644&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26045118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>