<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41519778</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The imperative of digital competence in healthcare professionals: comparison between the North and South of Europe.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>191</StartPage><MedlinePgn>191</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">191</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-026-14000-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Digital transformation in healthcare increasingly depends on the digitalisation of day-to-day clinical work, in particular on professionals&#x2019; ability to use electronic health records, telemedicine, and data-driven tools. However, gaps in digital competence and uneven access to training persist across Europe. This study examines how healthcare professionals understand and apply digital tools in clinical practice, and compares perceived barriers between Northern and Southern Europe.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a cross-sectional qualitative survey using a digital self-assessment questionnaire administered to 2,048 healthcare professionals from six European countries. The study was theoretically grounded in the European Digital Competence Framework for Citizens 2.0 (DigComp 2.0) and the eHealth Literacy Framework, and employed thematic analysis to interpret open-ended responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Four key thematic areas emerged: remote patient care and monitoring; digital education and health management; transformation of clinical workflows; and data-driven diagnostics. Professionals in Northern Europe&#x2014;especially Finland&#x2014;described integrated digital systems, structured training, and institutional support. Participants in Southern Europe more often reported fragmented infrastructure, limited training opportunities, and organizational resistance. The most frequently cited barriers to digital adoption were lack of training (23%), time constraints (27%), limited resources (24%), and resistance to change (19%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Healthcare professionals widely view digital competence as essential for safe and effective care, but uptake is constrained by structural barriers and regional inequalities. Targeted investment in workforce training, protected time for skill development, and foundational digital infrastructure&#x2014;particularly in Southern Europe and in resource-limited settings&#x2014;is needed to support equitable digital transformation across European health systems.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12913-026-14000-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esperan&#xe7;a</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-0064-2424</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto Universitario de Lisboa ISCTE-IUL, Lisbon, 1649-026, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Logistics, Molde University College, Molde, NO-6410, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Joao C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6662-0806</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto Universitario de Lisboa ISCTE-IUL, Lisbon, 1649-026, Portugal. joao.c.amaro.ferreira@himolde.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Logistics, Molde University College, Molde, NO-6410, Norway. joao.c.amaro.ferreira@himolde.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INESC INOV-Lab, Lisbon, 1000-029, Portugal. joao.c.amaro.ferreira@himolde.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins</LastName><ForeName>Ana Lucia</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8533-6595</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INESC INOV-Lab, Lisbon, 1000-029, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business Research Unit (BRU-IUL), Iscte-University Institute of Lisbon (ISCTE-IUL), Lisbon, 1649-026, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital competencies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital transformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare workforce training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the School of Technologies and Architecture of ISCTE (Comiss&#xe3;o de &#xc9;tica da Escola de Tecnologias e Arquitetura), under approval number CE-ISTA/2025.04. Participation in this study was entirely voluntary. Before completing the questionnaire, all participants were provided with an information sheet detailing the study&#x2019;s purpose, procedures, data confidentiality measures, and their rights as participants. Written informed consent was obtained digitally from all respondents prior to participation. The study ensured anonymity by not collecting identifiable information or participants&#x2019; IP addresses, and no compensation or incentives were offered for participation. All procedures performed in this study were conducted in accordance with the ethical standards of the institutional research committee and with the 1964 Helsinki Declaration and its later amendments. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41519778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-026-14000-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-026-14000-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stoumpos AI, Kitsios F, Talias MA. Digital transformation in healthcare: technology acceptance and its applications. Int J Environ Res Public Health. Feb 2023;20(4):3407. 10.3390/ijerph20043407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannevaara P, et al. Discovering the importance of health informatics education competencies in healthcare practice. A focus group interview. Int J Med Inf. July 2024;187:105463. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2024.105463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaihlanen A-M, Virtanen L, Kainiemi E, Sulosaari V, Heponiemi T. Continuing education in digital skills for healthcare professionals &#x2014; mapping of the current situation in EU member States. Int J Health Policy Manag. June 2024;1. 10.34172/ijhpm.8309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11365066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39099482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xf8;rs G, Larsen MH, H&#xf8;lvold LB, Wahl AK. eHealth literacy among hospital health care providers: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. Oct 2023;23(1). 10.1186/s12913-023-10103-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10599073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods L, Martin P, Khor J, Guthrie L, Sullivan C. The right care in the right place: a scoping review of digital health education and training for rural healthcare workers. BMC Health Serv Res. Sept 2024;24(1):1011. 10.1186/s12913-024-11313-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11370102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39223581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Luque AM, Ramirez-Montoya M-S. Health professionals&#x2019; competencies in the framework of complexity: digital training model for education 4.0. Rev Esp Doc Cient&#xed;fica. June 2024;47(2):e383. 10.3989/redc.2024.2.1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Me&#x17e;narec S N. and, Bogataj D. Advanced health technologies require skills and influence the culture of education: literature review and research agenda. IFAC-Pap. 2021;54:657&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.ifacol.2021.10.526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifacol.2021.10.526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges Do IJ, Nascimento, et al. Barriers and facilitators to utilizing digital health technologies by healthcare professionals. Npj Digit Med. Sept 2023;6(1):161. 10.1038/s41746-023-00899-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10507089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37723240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caton E, Philippou J, Baker E, Lee G. Exploring perceptions of digital technology and digital skills among newly registered nurses and clinical managers. Nurs Manag (Harrow). Feb 2024;31(1):27&#x2013;33. 10.7748/nm.2023.e2101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yl&#xf6;nen M, et al Social services and healthcare personnel&#x2019;s digital competence profiles: a finnish cross-sectional study. Int J Med Inf Jan. 2025;193:105658. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2024.105658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2024.105658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39454327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrela M, Semedo G, Roque F, Ferreira PL, Herdeiro MT. Sociodemographic determinants of digital health literacy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Med Inf. Sept 2023;177:105124. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2023.105124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37329766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oudbier SJ, Souget-Ruff SP, Chen BSJ, Ziesemer KA, Meij HJ, Smets EMA. Implementation barriers and facilitators of remote monitoring, remote consultation and digital care platforms through the eyes of healthcare professionals: a review of reviews. BMJ Open. June 2024;14(6):e075833. 10.1136/bmjopen-2023-075833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38858155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amankwah-Amoah J, Khan Z, Wood G, Knight G. COVID-19 and digitalization: the great acceleration. J Bus Res. Nov 2021;136:602-611. 10.1016/j.jbusres.2021.08.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8437806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34538980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konttila J et al. Mar., Healthcare professionals&#x2019; competence in digitalisation: A systematic review. J Clin Nurs. 2019 Mar;28(5-6):745-761. 10.1111/jocn.14710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarro-Mart&#xed;nez O, Igual-Garc&#xed;a J, Traver-Salcedo V. Bridging the educational gap in terms of digital competences between healthcare institutions&#x2019; demands and professionals&#x2019; needs. BMC Nurs. Apr 2023;22(1):144. 10.1186/s12912-023-01284-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37106389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tegegne MD, et al. Digital literacy level and associated factors among health professionals in a referral and teaching hospital: an implication for future digital health systems implementation. Front Public Health. Apr. 2023;11:1130894. 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1130894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machleid F, et al. Perceptions of digital health education among European medical students: mixed methods survey. J Med Internet Res. Aug 2020;22(8):e19827. 10.2196/19827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham TH, Stewart GL, Solimeo SL. The importance of soft skills development in a hard data world: learning from interviews with healthcare leaders. BMC Med Educ. Dec 2021;21(1):147. 10.1186/s12909-021-02567-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7937235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiferaw KB, Tilahun BC, Endehabtu BF. Healthcare providers&#x2019; digital competency: a cross-sectional survey in a low-income country setting. BMC Health Serv Res. Dec 2020;20(1):1021. 10.1186/s12913-020-05848-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33168002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretti V, Pronzato R. The emotional ambiguities of healthcare professionals&#x2019; platform experiences. Soc Sci Med. Sept 2024;357:117185. 10.1016/j.socscimed.2024.117185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39142145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlakidis Z, Muradyan A, Sargsyan K, editors. Digitalization of medicine in Low- and Middle-Income countries: paradigm changes in healthcare and biomedical research. Sustainable Development Goals Series. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2024. 10.1007/978-3-031-62332-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyanna S, Kaur P, Ractham P, Talwar S, Najmul Islam AKM. Digital transformation of healthcare sector. What is impeding adoption and continued usage of technology-driven innovations by end-users? J Bus Res. Dec 2022;153:150&#x2013;161. 10.1016/j.jbusres.2022.08.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raja M, Kymre IG, Bjerkan J, Galvin KT, Uhrenfeldt L. National digital strategies and innovative eHealth policies concerning older adults&#x2019; dignity: a document analysis in three Scandinavian countries. BMC Health Serv Res. Aug 2023;23(1):848. 10.1186/s12913-023-09867-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10416358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37563599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh T, Xu. Consumer acceptance and use of information technology: extending the unified theory of acceptance and use of technology. MIS Q. 2012;36(1):157. 10.2307/41410412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/41410412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maranguni&#x107; N, Grani&#x107; A. Technology acceptance model: a literature review from 1986 to 2013. Univers Access Inf Soc. Mar 2015;14(1):81&#x2013;95. 10.1007/s10209-014-0348-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission. Joint Research Centre., DigComp 2.0:the digital competence framework for citizens. LU: Publications Office. 2016. Accessed: Oct 28, 2025. [Online]. Available: https://data.europa.eu/doi/10.2791/607218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2791/607218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comission E. Digital competence framework for citizens (DigComp). [Online]. Available: https://joint-research-centre.ec.europa.eu/projects-and-activities/education-and-training/digital-transformation-education/digital-competence-framework-citizens-digcomp_en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comission E. Digital decade 2024: eHealth indicator study, 2024. [Online]. Available: https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/digital-decade-2024-ehealth-indicator-study.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, et al. A nordic perspective on patient online record access and the European health data space. J Med Internet Res. June 2024;26:e49084. 10.2196/49084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11240068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38935430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunady J, Pis&#xe1;r P, Vugec DS, Bach MP. Digital transformation in European Union: North is leading, and South is lagging behind. Int J Inf Syst Proj Manag. Nov 2022;10(4):39&#x2013;56. 10.12821/ijispm100403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Court of Auditors. Special report 25/2024: Digitalisation of healthcare &#x2013; EU support for member states effective overall, but difficulties in using EU funds, 2024. [Online]. Available: https://www.eca.europa.eu/en/publications?ref=SR-2024-25</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>