<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41741809</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1437-7799</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental nephrology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise therapy for kidney transplant recipients: a systematic review and meta-analysis with a focus on exercise type.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10157-026-02836-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise therapy is important for exercise tolerance, for the prevention of frailty or sarcopenia, and to improve quality of life (QOL). Previous studies, including systematic reviews, have shown the efficacy of exercise therapy for kidney transplant recipients (KTRs), but the optimal types of exercise remain unclear. Therefore, we aimed to synthesize the published evidence and compare the efficacy of types of exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We systematically searched for randomized controlled trials of the efficacy of exercise therapy in KTRs on PubMed and Ichushi, then performed a meta-analysis. Exercise was categorized as aerobic training (AT), resistance training (RT), or AT&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT. The risk of bias was assessed using ROB2 and the certainty of the evidence was evaluated using the GRADE approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-five studies were included in the study and 18 in the meta-analysis. Exercise was associated with significant improvements in QOL (SF-36 physical functioning score), cardiorespiratory function (VO<sub>2</sub>peak), physical function (performance in the 6-min walk test (6MWT) and sit/stand test (STS)), and a metabolic index (triglyceride concentration). Kidney function tended to be superior in the exercise group, but the difference was not significant. Other indices of glucose and lipid metabolism and the incidence of hospitalization did not differ between the Exercise and Control groups. AT&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT significantly improved VO<sub>2</sub>peak, 6MWT performance, and the triglyceride concentration, whereas AT alone did not improve VO<sub>2</sub>peak and RT alone did not improve 6MWT performance or the triglyceride concentration. The certainty of the evidence was generally "low" or "very low".</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Exercise therapy improved the QOL, cardiorespiratory function, physical function, and triglyceride concentration of KTRs. The AT&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT combination may be the most effective exercise therapy for such patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Japanese Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kounoue</LastName><ForeName>Noriyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Toho University Faculty of Medicine, Omorinishi 6-11-1, Ota-Ku, Tokyo, 143-8541, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ochiai</LastName><ForeName>Shintaro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Toho University Faculty of Medicine, Omorinishi 6-11-1, Ota-Ku, Tokyo, 143-8541, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yazawa</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Yokohama General Hospital, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, St Marianna University School of Medicine, Kawasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sofue</LastName><ForeName>Tadashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiorenal and Cerebrovascular Medicine, Kagawa University, Kagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Naohiko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Hyogo Prefectural Nishinomiya Hospital, Nishinomiya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saitoh</LastName><ForeName>Masakazu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Science, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narita</LastName><ForeName>Ichiei</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Niigata Institute for Health and Sports Medicine, Niigata Sports Association, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamagata</LastName><ForeName>Kunihiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Faculty of Medicine, Graduate School of Comprehensive Human Sciences, University of Tsukuba and Division of Preventive and Sports Nephrology, University of Tsukuba, Ibaraki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoshino</LastName><ForeName>Junichi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oguchi</LastName><ForeName>Hideyo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7462-3564</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Toho University Faculty of Medicine, Omorinishi 6-11-1, Ota-Ku, Tokyo, 143-8541, Japan. hideyo.oguchi@med.toho-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9709923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1342-1751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise type</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney transplantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors have nothing to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41741809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10157-026-02836-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10157-026-02836-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chan W, Chin SH, Whittaker AC, Jones D, Kaur O, Bosch JA, et al. The associations of muscle strength, muscle mass, and adiposity with clinical outcomes and quality of life in prevalent kidney transplant recipients. J Ren Nutr. 2019;29:536&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jrn.2019.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31416679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanishi M, Tsukaguchi H, Kimura Y, Koito Y, Yoshida K, Seo M, et al. Evaluation of physical activity in sarcopenic conditions of kidney transplantation recipients. Int Urol Nephrol. 2017;49:1779&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11255-017-1661-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28726035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ham ECH, Kooman JP, Schols AMWJ, Nieman FHM, Does JD, Franssen FME, et al. Similarities in skeletal muscle strength and exercise capacity between renal transplant and hemodialysis patients. Am J Transplant. 2005;5:1957&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2005.00944.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15996245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Hemmelder MH, Bos WJW, Snoep JD, de Vries APJ, Dekker FW, et al. Mapping health-related quality of life after kidney transplantation by group comparisons: a systematic review. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2021;36:2327&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfab232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8643597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quint EE, Zogaj D, Banning LBD, Benjamens S, Annema C, Bakker SJL, et al. Frailty and kidney transplantation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transplant Direct. 2021;7:e701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TXD.0000000000001156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8133203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J-Z, Shi W, Zou M, Zeng Q-S, Feng Y, Luo Z-Y, et al. Diagnosis, prevalence, and outcomes of sarcopenia in kidney transplantation recipients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2023;14:17&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36403578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguchi H, Tsujita M, Yazawa M, Kawaguchi T, Hoshino J, Kohzuki M, et al. The efficacy of exercise training in kidney transplant recipients: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Clin Exp Nephrol. 2019;23:275&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10157-018-1633-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30168049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Yu L, Xia B, Zhang X, Liang P, Hu X. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the efficacy of exercise intervention in kidney transplant recipients. World J Urol. 2023;41:3449&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00345-023-04673-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37882807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouidi E, Hanssen H, Anding-Rost K, Cupisti A, Deligiannis A, Grupp C, et al. The role of exercise training on cardiovascular risk factors and heart disease in patients with chronic kidney disease G3-G5 and G5D: a Clinical Consensus Statement of the European Association of Preventive Cardiology of the ESC and the European Association of Rehabilitation in Chronic Kidney Disease. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2024;31:1493&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjpc/zwae130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38593202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiwe S, Jacobson SH. Exercise training for adults with chronic kidney disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;2011:CD003236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10183198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knobbe TJ, Kremer D, Zelle DM, Klaassen G, Dijkema D, van Vliet IMY, et al. Effect of an exercise intervention or combined exercise and diet intervention on health-related quality of life-physical functioning after kidney transplantation: the Active Care after Transplantation (ACT) multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2024;5:100622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanhl.2024.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39270688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor EM, Koufaki P, Mercer TH, Lindup H, Nugent E, Goldsmith D, et al. Long-term pulse wave velocity outcomes with aerobic and resistance training in kidney transplant recipients - a pilot randomised controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2017;12:e0171063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0171063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28158243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5291475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent KR, Braith RW, Feldman RA, Kallas HE, Lowenthal DT. Improved cardiorespiratory endurance following 6 months of resistance exercise in elderly men and women. Arch Intern Med. 2002;162:673&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.162.6.673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11911721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delagardelle C, Feiereisen P, Autier P, Shita R, Krecke R, Beissel J. Strength/endurance training versus endurance training in congestive heart failure. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:1868&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200212000-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Meredith CN, O&#x2019;Reilly KP, Evans WJ. Strength training and determinants of VO2max in older men. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68:329&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1990.68.1.329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2312474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Downes D, van der Touw T, Hada S, Dieberg G, Pearson MJ, et al. The effect of exercise training on blood lipids: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2025;55:67&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02115-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39331324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dienemann T, Ziolkowski SL, Bender S, Goral S, Long J, Baker JF, et al. Changes in body composition, muscle strength, and fat distribution following kidney transplantation. Am J Kidney Dis. 2021;78:816&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2020.11.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8608755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Topp KS, Krasnoff JB, Adey D, Strasner A, Tomlanovich S, et al. Health-related fitness and quality of life following steroid withdrawal in renal transplant recipients. Kidney Int. 2003;63:2309&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1523-1755.2003.00038.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12753323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani M, Einollahi B, Ahmadzad-Asl M, Nafar M, Pourfarziani V, Samadpour A, et al. Hyperlipidemia after renal transplantation and its relation to graft and patient survival. Transplant Proc. 2007;39:1044&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.transproceed.2007.03.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17524887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodle ES, First MR, Pirsch J, Shihab F, Gaber AO, Van Veldhuisen P. A prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multicenter trial comparing early (7 day) corticosteroid cessation versus long-term, low-dose corticosteroid therapy. Ann Surg. 2008;248:564&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0b013e318187d1da</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18936569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Groen PC. Cyclosporine, low-density lipoprotein, and cholesterol. Mayo Clin Proc. 1988;63:1012&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0025-6196(12)64916-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3172850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasiske BL, de Mattos A, Flechner SM, Gallon L, Meier-Kriesche H-U, Weir MR, et al. Mammalian target of rapamycin inhibitor dyslipidemia in kidney transplant recipients: MTOR inhibitor dyslipidemia. Am J Transplant. 2008;8:1384&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2008.02272.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18510633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries APJ, Bakker SJL, van Son WJ, van der Heide JJH, Ploeg RJ, The HT, et al. Metabolic syndrome is associated with impaired long-term renal allograft function; not all component criteria contribute equally. Am J Transplant. 2004;4:1675&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2004.00558.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15367224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amend KL, Landon J, Thyagarajan V, Niemcryk S, McAfee A. Incidence of hospitalized rhabdomyolysis with statin and fibrate use in an insured US population. Ann Pharmacother. 2011;45:1230&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1345/aph.1Q110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Arrigo G, Marino C, Pizzini P, Caridi G, Marino F, Parlongo G, et al. Quality of life and kidney function in CKD patients: a longitudinal study. Clin Kidney J. 2025;18:sfae429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ckj/sfae429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40207096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11976526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor KL, Jamal SA, Zou G, McArthur E, Lam NN, Leslie WD, et al. Fracture incidence in adult kidney transplant recipients. Transplantation. 2016;100:167&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0000000000000808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26154389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrich C, Kanitakis J, Stockfleth E, Euvrard S. Skin cancer in organ transplant recipients--where do we stand today? Am J Transplant. 2008;8:2192&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2008.02386.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18782290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>