<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41802435</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-1236</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sportverletzung Sportschaden : Organ der Gesellschaft fur Orthopadisch-Traumatologische Sportmedizin</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sportverletz Sportschaden</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[The Scientific Usage of GPS Data in Professional Football: Relevance, Norm Values and Practical Recommendations].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>32</StartPage><EndPage>46</EndPage><MedlinePgn>32-46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2777-3728</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The use of GPS data has become an integral part of the work of strength and conditioning coaches as well as data analysts in professional women's and men's football. Coaches should rely on GPS systems with a comparatively high sampling frequency (18 Hz) in order to validly capture short sprint distances with rapid changes of direction. GPS parameters such as total running distance, number of maximal sprints, accelerations, decelerations, and distance covered in speed and high-speed zones are of high practical relevance for athletic performance and injury prevention. Based on these practically relevant GPS parameters, the central challenge lies in capturing the complex interaction between training load and exertion, and in deriving suitable implications for short- (microcycle), medium- (mesocycle), and long-term (macrocycle) training programming. In the future, AI methods may support this process by efficiently analyzing large datasets and identifying patterns in load management. Initial studies provide promising evidence. However, particularly in the highly individualized context of professional football, it remains to be determined whether existing learning algorithms developed from one team's data can be transferred to other teams. In general, the use of GPS data should be contextualized in order to provide coaches with guidance, rather than serving as rigid target parameters for training prescription and load management in football. This article presents literature-based recommendations on the use of GPS data (e.g., acceleration-based parameters) for the design of macro-, meso-, and microcycles, which can guide coaches in football-specific load management. Of additional practical importance is the further development of models capable of predicting increased injury risk during specific phases of the season. While existing approaches such as the Acute:Chronic Workload Ratio (ACWR) provide initial guidance, their methodological limitations are evident. Further research is needed to provide reliable and applicable tools for training management in professional football. In addition, individualized training programming should incorporate not only objective GPS data but also subjective ratings of perceived exertion.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;hl</LastName><ForeName>Hannes</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Exercise and Human Movement Science, Albert-Ludwigs-Universit&#xe4;t Freiburg: Albert-Ludwigs-Universitat Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SV Werder Bremen Frauenfu&#xdf;ball, Bremen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Granacher</LastName><ForeName>Urs</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7095-813X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Exercise and Human Movement Science, Albert-Ludwigs-Universit&#xe4;t Freiburg: Albert-Ludwigs-Universitat Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>ger</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Die wissenschaftsbasierte Nutzung von GPS-Daten im Profifu&#xdf;ball: Relevanz, Orientierungswerte und praktische Empfehlungen.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Sportverletz Sportschaden</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904133</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0932-0555</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040362" MajorTopicYN="Y">Geographic Information Systems</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012016" MajorTopicYN="N">Reference Values</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText>Die Nutzung von GPS-Daten ist heutzutage fester Bestandteil der Arbeit von Athletiktrainer*innen und Datenanalyst*innen im professionellen Frauen- und M&#xe4;nnerfu&#xdf;ball. Trainer*innen sollten auf GPS-Systeme mit vergleichsweise hoher Dateneinzugsfrequenz (18Hz) zur&#xfc;ckgreifen, um kurze Sprintstrecken mit schnellen Richtungswechseln valide abbilden zu k&#xf6;nnen. Eine hohe trainingspraktische Relevanz f&#xfc;r die sportliche Leistung und die Verletzungspr&#xe4;vention haben die GPS-Parameter absolute Laufdistanz, Anzahl der Maximalsprints, Beschleunigungen, Abbremsbewegungen sowie Laufdistanz im Geschwindigkeits- und Hochgeschwindigkeitsbereich. Auf Grundlage trainingspraktisch relevanter GPS-Parameter besteht die zentrale Herausforderung darin, das komplexe Zusammenspiel von Trainingsbelastung und -beanspruchung zu erfassen und daraus geeignete Ableitungen f&#xfc;r die kurz-(Mikrozyklus), mittel- (Mesozyklus) und langfristige (Makrozyklus) Trainingssteuerung zu treffen. Zuk&#xfc;nftig k&#xf6;nnen KI-Methoden diesen Prozess unterst&#xfc;tzen, indem sie gro&#xdf;e Datenmengen effizient auswerten und Muster in der Belastungssteuerung sichtbar machen. Erste Studien liefern vielversprechende Hinweise. Allerdings muss gerade f&#xfc;r den hochindividualisierten Profifu&#xdf;ball gepr&#xfc;ft werden, ob bestehende Lernalgorithmen, die durch die Daten eines Teams zustande gekommen sind, auch auf andere Teams &#xfc;bertragen werden k&#xf6;nnen. Im vorliegenden Beitrag werden literaturbasierte Empfehlungen zur Nutzung von GPS-Daten (z.B. beschleunigungsbasierte Parameter) f&#xfc;r die Gestaltung von Makro-, Meso- und Mikrozyklen pr&#xe4;sentiert. Grunds&#xe4;tzlich sollte der Einsatz von GPS-Daten kontextualisiert erfolgen, sodass sie Trainer*innen als Orientierungshilfe dienen, ohne zu starren Zielgr&#xf6;&#xdf;en der Trainings- und Belastungssteuerung im Fu&#xdf;ball zu werden. Praktisch bedeutsam ist zudem die Weiterentwicklung von Modellen, die ein erh&#xf6;htes Verletzungsrisiko in spezifischen Saisonphasen vorhersagen k&#xf6;nnen. W&#xe4;hrend bestehende Ans&#xe4;tze wie das Acute:Chronic Workload Ratio (ACWR) erste Orientierung bieten, sind ihre methodischen Grenzen offensichtlich. Hier besteht weiterer Forschungsbedarf, um zuverl&#xe4;ssige und anwendungsnahe Instrumente f&#xfc;r die Trainingssteuerung im Profifu&#xdf;ball bereitzustellen. Dar&#xfc;ber hinaus sollten f&#xfc;r die individualisierte Trainingssteuerung neben den objektiven GPS-Daten auch subjektive Anstrengungsskalen zum Einsatz kommen.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Die Autorinnen/Autoren geben an, dass kein Interessenkonflikt besteht.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41802435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2777-3728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>