<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41529037</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring collaborative strategies to improve patient safety in healthcare organizations: A qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0341022</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0341022</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0341022</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0341022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patient safety remains a critical concern in healthcare, necessitating the exploration of collaborative approaches to enhance care quality and outcomes. This qualitative study delves into the significance of interprofessional collaboration, leadership support, patient engagement, and safety culture in driving patient safety initiatives within healthcare settings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative phenomenological approach, involving in-depth interviews and document analysis, was conducted to explore the perspectives of healthcare professionals, administrators, patients, policymakers, and researchers involved in patient safety initiatives. Thematic analysis was employed to identify and organize recurring patterns in the data, while interpretive phenomenological analysis was utilized to gain a deeper understanding of participants' lived experiences. This dual approach revealed key themes related to teamwork, communication, leadership, patient engagement, and best practices in patient safety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study revealed that interprofessional collaboration is widely recognized as vital for patient safety, with participants highlighting the importance of effective communication, shared decision-making, and mutual respect among healthcare professionals. Leadership support, organizational structures, and a culture of safety emerged as key enabling factors. Despite the benefits, challenges such as hierarchy, siloed communication, resource constraints, and resistance to change remain significant barriers. Strategies including regular interdisciplinary training, patient engagement initiatives, leveraging technology, and continuous quality improvement processes were identified as effective ways to strengthen collaborative practices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Promoting interprofessional collaboration, strong leadership, and a robust safety culture are essential for improving patient safety outcomes. Overcoming systemic and interpersonal barriers requires targeted interventions at both individual and organizational levels, with ongoing education, patient participation, and data-driven feedback playing crucial roles in sustaining collaborative efforts. These insights support the adoption of integrated approaches to foster safer and higher-quality care across healthcare settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Hejazi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hejazi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Esmaeil</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tuberculosis and Lung Disease Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alizadeh-Dizaj</LastName><ForeName>Ghasem</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-6794-5443</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Information Technology, School of Management and Medical Informatics, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khoshsirat</LastName><ForeName>Shiva</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Information Technology, School of Management and Medical Informatics, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raoofi</LastName><ForeName>Samira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Evidence-Based Health Management, Maragheh University of Medical Sciences, Maragheh, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javan Biparva</LastName><ForeName>Akbar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Evidence-Based Health Management, Maragheh University of Medical Sciences, Maragheh, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061214" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Safety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003299" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cooperative Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007857" MajorTopicYN="N">Leadership</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007400" MajorTopicYN="N">Interprofessional Relations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003142" MajorTopicYN="N">Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010358" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Participation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41529037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12798996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0341022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-24-53343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almalki MAA, Alanazy AAS, Alenzi SMJ, Alharbi ZDM, Alanazi RG, Alhareth AMDA, et al. Quality assurance and safety culture in a healthcare organization. IJMSCRS. 2023;03(10). doi: 10.47191/ijmscrs/v3-i10-17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47191/ijmscrs/v3-i10-17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenoy A. Patient safety from the perspective of quality management frameworks: a review. Patient Saf Surg. 2021;15(1):12. doi: 10.1186/s13037-021-00286-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13037-021-00286-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33752725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreeramoju PV, Palmore TN, Lee GM, Edmond MB, Patterson JE, Sepkowitz KA, et al. Institutional quality and patient safety programs: an overview for the healthcare epidemiologist. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2021;42(1):6&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1017/ice.2020.409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ice.2020.409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott RA, Camacho E, Jankovic D, Sculpher MJ, Faria R. Economic analysis of the prevalence and clinical and economic burden of medication error in England. BMJ Qual Saf. 2021;30(2):96&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1136/bmjqs-2019-010206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2019-010206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global patient safety action plan 2021&#x2013;2030: towards eliminating avoidable harm in health care. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2021. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240032705</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveson N, Samost A, Dekker S, Finkelstein S, Raman J. A systems approach to analyzing and preventing hospital adverse events. J Patient Saf. 2020;16(2):162&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1097/PTS.0000000000000263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PTS.0000000000000263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26756729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saporta A. Exploring healthcare professionals&#x2019; attitudes toward patient safety and behaviors that foster safe patient care. California State University, Bakersfield. 2024. Available from: https://scholarworks.calstate.edu/concern/theses/ff365c88r</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira FTLDS, Callou RCM, Albuquerque GA, Oliveira RM. Effective communication strategies for managing disruptive behaviors and promoting patient safety. Rev Gaucha Enferm. 2019;40(spe):e20180308. doi: 10.1590/1983-1447.2019.20180308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1983-1447.2019.20180308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31038600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong BM, Baum KD, Headrick LA, Holmboe ES, Moss F, Ogrinc G, et al. Building the bridge to quality: an urgent call to integrate quality improvement and patient safety education with clinical care. Acad Med. 2020;95(1):59&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1097/ACM.0000000000002937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000002937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31397709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steven A, Tella S, Turunen H, Flores Vizcaya-Moreno M, P&#xe9;rez-Ca&#xf1;averas RM, Porras J, et al. Shared learning from national to international contexts: a research and innovation collaboration to enhance education for patient safety. J Res Nurs. 2019;24(3&#x2013;4):149&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1177/1744987118824628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1744987118824628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34394520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalani M, Wytrykowski S, Hogan H. Approaches to improving patient safety in integrated care: a scoping review. BMJ Open. 2023;13(4):e067441. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10083780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss-H&#xe4;necke R, Lauener SK, Sluka C, Deschodt M, Siqeca F, Schwendimann R. Implementation fidelity of a multifactorial in-hospital fall prevention program and its association with unit systems factors: a single center, cross-sectional study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23(1):158. doi: 10.1186/s12913-023-09157-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-09157-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9930071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciardi W, Cascini F. Guidelines and safety practices for improving patient safety. J Transl Sci. 2021;3:3&#x2013;18. doi: 10.29328/journal.jts.1001025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29328/journal.jts.1001025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36315770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domer G, Gallagher TM, Shahabzada S, Sotherland J, Paul EN, Kumar K-N, et al. Patient safety: preventing patient harm and building capacity for patient safety. In: Domer G, editor. Contemporary Topics in Patient Safety-Volume 1. IntechOpen; 2021. pp. 1&#x2013;22. doi: 10.5772/intechopen.94777</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.94777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen KZ, Mesman J. A transactional approach to patient safety: understanding safe care as a collaborative accomplishment. J Interprof Care. 2021;35(4):503&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1080/13561820.2021.1874317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2021.1874317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33653224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Kung L, Gupta S, Ozdemir S. Leveraging big data analytics to improve quality of care in healthcare organizations: a configurational perspective. J Bus Res. 2019;30(2):362&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/j.jbusres.2018.07.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2018.07.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamers SL, Streit J, Pana-Cryan R, Ray T, Syron L, Flynn MA, et al. Envisioning the future of work to safeguard the safety, health, and well-being of the workforce: a perspective from the CDC&#x2019;s National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health. Am J Ind Med. 2020;63(12):1065&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1002/ajim.23134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajim.23134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32926431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman B, Joseph K, Chauhan A, Seale H, Li J, Manias E, et al. Do patient engagement interventions work for all patients? A systematic review and realist synthesis of interventions to enhance patient safety. Health Expect. 2021;24(6):1905&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1111/hex.13343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hex.13343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8628590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agbar F, Zhang S, Wu Y, Mustafa M. Effect of patient safety education interventions on patient safety culture of health care professionals: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Nurs Educ Perspect. 2023;67:103565. doi: 10.1097/01.NEP.0000000000001035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NEP.0000000000001035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink-Samnick E. Leveraging interprofessional team-based care toward case management excellence: part 1, history, fundamentals, evidence. Prof Case Manag. 2019;24(3):130&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1097/NCM.0000000000000344</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCM.0000000000000344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30946250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greilich PE, Kilcullen M, Paquette S, Lazzara EH, Scielzo S, Hernandez J, et al. Team FIRST framework: Identifying core teamwork competencies critical to interprofessional healthcare curricula. J Clin Transl Sci. 2023;7(1):e106. doi: 10.1017/cts.2023.27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2023.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10225264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37250989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boamah SA. Emergence of informal clinical leadership as a catalyst for improving patient care quality and job satisfaction. J Nurs Adm. 2019;75(5):1000&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1097/NNA.0000000000000842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NNA.0000000000000842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30375015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirey MR, White-Williams C, Hites LJ. Integration of authentic leadership lens for building high performing interprofessional collaborative practice teams. Nurs Adm Q. 2019;43(2):101&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1097/NAQ.0000000000000332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NAQ.0000000000000332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30839447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajac S, Woods A, Tannenbaum S, Salas E, Holladay CL. Overcoming challenges to teamwork in healthcare: a team effectiveness framework and evidence-based guidance. Front Psychol. 2021;6:606445. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2015.00644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2015.00644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoo ME, Bringardner J, Chen J-Y, Coyle EJ, Finnegan J, Kim CJ, et al. Breaking down the silos: Innovations for multidisciplinary programs. ASEE Virtual Annual Conference Content Access. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chegini Z, Arab-Zozani M, Shariful Islam SM, Tobiano G, Abbasgholizadeh Rahimi S. Barriers and facilitators to patient engagement in patient safety from patients and healthcare professionals&#x2019; perspectives: A systematic review and meta-synthesis. Nurs Forum. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engle RL, Mohr DC, Holmes SK, Seibert MN, Afable M, Leyson J, et al. Evidence-based practice and patient-centered care: doing both well. J Nurs Care Qual. 2021;46(3):174&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1097/NCQ.0000000000000553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCQ.0000000000000553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8162222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31233424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGillivray TE. Advancing the culture of patient safety and quality improvement. J Med Diagn Case Rep. 2020;16(3):192. doi: 10.4172/2327-5162.1000192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2327-5162.1000192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Anazi AMF, Alanazi ML, Alresheedi AFN, Al-Rashidi AMO, Al-Harbi FS, Al-Mutairi AMA. Healthcare quality improvement: strategies for improving the quality and safety of healthcare delivery in healthcare organizations. J Sci Fin Manag. 2022;9(4):152&#x2013;4. doi: 10.29328/journal.jsfm</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29328/journal.jsfm</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>