<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41339952</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0778-7367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of public health = Archives belges de sante publique</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Community-acquired pneumonia in Indonesian children: insights into diagnosis, treatment compliance, and healthcare provider challenges.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13690-025-01795-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) remains a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in children worldwide. Inappropriate antibiotic use by healthcare workers contributes significantly to the growing problem of antibiotic resistance. This study assessed the knowledge, attitudes, and practices (KAP) of Indonesian primary healthcare workers in diagnosing and treating paediatric CAP, alongside challenges in guideline adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three studies were conducted in Indonesia. The first study reviewed medical records from Riau Islands and Central Java Provinces to assess adherence to CAP guidelines. The second evaluated KAP using pre- and post-tests, and online follow-up. The third used focus group discussions (FGDs) to explore the challenges in diagnosis and management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Out of 921 records, 37.6% of patients were misclassified as having CAP according to the World Health Organization (WHO) guideline, while 53.3% were misclassified based on the Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia (MoH RI) guideline. Antibiotics were prescribed in 89.3% and 87.6% of these cases. Among correctly classified cases, 73.2% were prescribed amoxicillin in line with WHO guideline, but only 11.6% were dosed within the recommended 75-100&#xa0;mg/kg/day range. Furthermore, 74.6% of patients were prescribed antibiotics more frequently, and only 28.3% received the appropriate treatment duration. The training significantly improved KAP among healthcare workers. Separately, nurses and midwives showed better practical application of the guidelines compared to physicians. Qualitative analysis identified themes highlighting diagnostic accuracy, antibiotic prescribing practices, and tailored training programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights significant inconsistencies in paediatric CAP management among healthcare providers in Indonesia and emphasises the need for targeted training to enhance guideline compliance and improve patient outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciptaningtyas</LastName><ForeName>Vincentia Rizke</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia. rizke.ciptaningtyas@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diponegoro National Hospital, Semarang, Indonesia. rizke.ciptaningtyas@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Laboratory of Medical Immunology, Radboudumc Community for Infectious Diseases, Radboudumc Research Institute for Medical Innovation, Radboud university medical center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands. rizke.ciptaningtyas@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sumekar</LastName><ForeName>Tanjung Ayu</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diponegoro National Hospital, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Biomedical Research, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fauzia</LastName><ForeName>Lathifa Putry</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Development Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lestari</LastName><ForeName>Endang Sri</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farida</LastName><ForeName>Helmia</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diponegoro National Hospital, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margawati</LastName><ForeName>Ani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Diponegoro, Semarang, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Mast</LastName><ForeName>Quirijn</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Radboudumc Community for Infectious Diseases, Radboud university medical center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Jonge</LastName><ForeName>Marinus Isa&#xe4;k</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Laboratory of Medical Immunology, Radboudumc Community for Infectious Diseases, Radboudumc Research Institute for Medical Innovation, Radboud university medical center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9208826</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0778-7367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compliance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pneumonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The research was performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. The dataset used for this research was de-identified to ensure participant confidentiality. The Ethical Committee of the Faculty of Medicine Universitas Diponegoro approved the study protocols: No.57/EC/KEPK/FK-UNDIP/III/2023, No. 458/EC/KEPK/FK-UNDIP/IX/2023, No. 548/EC/KEPK/FK-UNDIP/XI/2023. Study participants were informed about the study&#x2019;s objectives, purposes, privacy measures, and confidentiality protocols. They were assured of their right to withdraw from the study at any time without consequence. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior data collection. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41339952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12794261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-025-01795-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13690-025-01795-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smith DK, Kuckel DP, Recidoro AM. Community-acquired pneumonia in children: rapid evidence review. Am Fam Physician. 2021;104(6):618&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhi SA, De Wals P, Grijalva CG, Grimwood K, Grossman R, Ishiwada N, et al. The burden of childhood pneumonia in the developed world: a review of the literature. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32(3):e119&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0b013e3182784b26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23099423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health Republic of Indonesia. Indonesia health profile 2017. Report. Jakarta: Ministry of Health Republic of Indonesia; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Revised WHO classification and treatment of pneumonia in children at health facilities: evidence summaries. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25535631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health Republic of Indonesia. Clinical practice guidelines for Doctors in first level health service facilities. Jakarta: Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha DR, Haste NM, Gluckstein DP. The role of antibiotic stewardship in promoting appropriate antibiotic use. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2019;13(4):376&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1559827617700824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dache A, Dona A, Ejeso A. Inappropriate use of antibiotics, its reasons and contributing factors among communities of Yirgalem town, Sidama regional state, Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. SAGE Open Med. 2021;9:20503121211042461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121211042461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8422824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health Republic of Indonesia. General guideline for use of antibiotics. Jakarta: Ministry of Health Republic of Indonesia; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riau Islands Provincial Health Office. Riau Islands Province Health Profile 2021. Tanjungpinang: Riau Islands Provincial Health Office; 2022. Available from: https://dinkes.riau.go.id/sites/default/files/2023-02/Profil%20Kesehatan%20Provinsi%20Riau%20Tahun%202021.pdf. Accessed 23 Dec 2023. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Java Provincial Health Office. Central Java Province Health Profile 2021. Semarang: Central Java Provincial Health Office; 2022. Available from: https://dinkesjatengprov.go.id/v2018/dokumen/Profil_Kesehatan_2021/mobile/. Accessed 23 Dec 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> Semarang City Health Office. Semarang City Health Profile 2021. Semarang: Semarang City Health Office; 2022. Available from: https://dinkes.semarangkota.go.id/asset/upload/Profil/Profil%202021/FIX_Profil%20Kesehatan%202021.pdf. Accessed 23 Dec 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> Jepara Regency Health Office. Jepara Regency Health Profile 2021. Jepara: Jepara Regency Health Office; 2022. Available from: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sueiNQF2nhXOxtjDaXGms-laZRPi98wd/view. Accessed 23 Dec 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia. Integrated management of childhood illness chart book (Indonesian). Jakarta: Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley JS, Byington CL, Shah SS, Alverson B, Carter ER, Harrison C, et al. The management of community-acquired pneumonia in infants and children older than 3 months of age: clinical practice guidelines by the pediatric infectious diseases society and the infectious diseases society of America. Clin Infect Dis. 2011;53(7):e25&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cir531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Harriet. In: Hughes HK, Kahl LK, editors. Lane handbook: a manual for pediatric house officers. 21 ed. Philadephia: Elsevier; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia. Integrated management of childhood illness chart book (Indonesian). Jakarta: Ministry of Health of the Republic of Indonesia; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007;19(6):349&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guitart C, Esteban E, Becerra J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fanjul J, Cambra FJ, Balaguer M, et al. A training plan to implement lung ultrasound for diagnosing pneumonia in children. Pediatr Res. 2021;92(4):1115&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41390-021-01928-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9586858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34969992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pervaiz F, Hossen S, Chavez MA, Miele CH, Moulton LH, McCollum ED, et al. Training and standardization of general practitioners in the use of lung ultrasound for the diagnosis of pediatric pneumonia. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2019;54(11):1753&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.24477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro DJ, Hall M, Neuman MI, Hersh AL, Cotter JM, Cogen JD, et al. Outpatient antibiotic use and treatment failure among children with pneumonia. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(10):e2441821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.41821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39470638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofto ME, Samuy N, Pass RF. Antibiotic use and outcomes in young children hospitalized with uncomplicated community-acquired pneumonia. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(4):ofac123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofac123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8962753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nightingale R, Colbourn T, Mukanga D, Mankhambo L, Lufesi N, McCollum ED, et al. Non-adherence to community oral-antibiotic treatment in children with fast-breathing pneumonia in Malawi- secondary analysis of a prospective cohort study. Pneumonia. 2016;8:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41479-016-0024-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5471995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>lau J, Islam S, Polischuk E. 215. Appropriateness and accuracy of antimicrobial prescriptions at pediatric emergency department discharge. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7(Supplement1):S109&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofaa439.259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35369760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roumeliotis N, Pullenayegum E, Rochon PA, Taddio A, Parshuram C. A modified delphi to define drug dosing errors in pediatric critical care. BMC Pediatr. 2020;20:488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33087096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye P, Shi J, Guo Z, Yang X, Li Q, Chen K, et al. Piperacillin/tazobactam treatment in children: evidence of subtherapeutic concentrations. Front Pharmacol. 2024;15:1254005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1254005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11255394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39027331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Q, Gao L, Xu T, Chen Y, Yang X, Han M, et al. Amoxicillin administration regimen and resistance mechanisms of <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> established in tissue cage infection model. Front Microbiol. 2019;10:1638.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2019.01638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31396174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarraf DP, Rai D, Rauniar GP. Knowledge, attitude and practices on antibiotic use and resistance among Doctors in B.P. Koirala Institute of health sciences. J Drug Delivery Ther. 2018;8(4):170&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalugama C, Gamage K. Knowledge and confidence on prescribing antibiotics among medical graduates from a Sri Lankan university. Sri Lankan J Infect Dis. 2022;12(2):E28:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh LJ, Ford P, McGuire T, Driel Mv, Hollingworth S. Trends in Australian dental prescribing of antibiotics: 2005&#x2013;2016. Aust Dent J. 2021;66:S1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/adj.12846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshan P, Chaudhary A, Rastogi A, Chauhan S, Syed S, Bansal A. Small Steps, big gains: impact of health promotion in combating viral hepatitis. J Educ Soc Behav Sci. 2021;34(3):12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jesbs/2021/v34i330313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruyneel L, Lesaffre E, Meuleman B, Sermeus W. Power distance and physician&#x2013;nurse collegial relations across 14 European countries: national culture is not merely a nuisance factor in international comparative research. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2019;51(6):708&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnu.12514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peltonen L-M, Siirala E, Junttila K, Lundgr&#xe9;n-Laine H, Vahlberg T, L&#xf6;yttyniemi E, et al. Information needs in day-to-day operations management in hospital units: a cross-sectional national survey. J Nurs Manage. 2018;27(2):233&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.12700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30298534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Yu C, Zheng Z, Wu Q, Zhang J, Jiang P, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practices on COVID-19 prevention and diagnosis among medical workers in the radiology department: a multicenter cross-sectional study in China. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1110893. 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1110893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1110893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10018012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36935704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katwyk SRV, Jones S, Hoffman SJ. Mapping educational opportunities for healthcare workers on antimicrobial resistance and stewardship around the world. Hum Resour Health. 2018;16:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-018-0270-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5799960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>