<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41696472</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-0640</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Network analysis of psychological resilience, personality traits, and depression-anxiety-stress symptoms among military college students in China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1684090</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1684090</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1684090</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyt.2026.1684090</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Non-military-status undergraduate cadets in Chinese military academies face a distinctive combination of academic demands and militarized stressors, which may increase psychological distress and shape resilience-related adaptation. Although personality traits are associated with psychological resilience, systematic evidence is still lacking regarding how resilience and personality jointly relate to depression-anxiety-stress symptoms in quasi-military contexts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional study examined the associations among psychological resilience, Big Five personality traits, and depression-anxiety-stress symptoms in 855 non-military-status undergraduate cadets. Participants completed the 10-item Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC-10), the Chinese Big Five Personality Inventory (CBF-PI-15), and the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales-21 (DASS-21). Network estimation was performed using graphical LASSO with Spearman partial correlations. Centrality indices, including bridge strength and bridge expected influence (BEI), were computed to identify key nodes and their roles in the overall network structure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The gender-stratified CD-RISC-10-CBF-PI-DASS-21 networks were relatively dense, with 19/36 and 25/36 non-zero edges and similar mean edge weights. Network comparison tests indicated significant differences in overall structure (<i>M</i> = 0.12, <i>p</i> &lt;.001) and global strength (3.89 vs. 4.04; <i>S</i> = 1.15, <i>p</i> = .01), suggesting tighter coupling among resilience, personality, and distress indicators in females. In both networks, resilience exhibited the most prominent bridging role, whereas agreeableness functioned as a shared protective bridge node. The strongest positive bridge edge differed by gender. Bridge metrics showed good stability, and bootstrap confidence intervals supported the accuracy of edge-weight estimates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study provides clinically informative, network-based evidence on psychological adaptation in a rarely examined cadet population. The central bridging role of resilience, the protective bridging role of agreeableness, and gender-specific trait-resilience linkages offer actionable, empirically grounded targets for stratified psychological interventions and resilience-promotion programs in high-demand, quasi-military training settings. These findings have important implications for psychological support strategies and mental health promotion in military education environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Hou, Zhang, Mi, Wang and Feng.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Yanqin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Management and Services, Cangzhou Medical College, Hebei,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Guimin</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Management and Services, Cangzhou Medical College, Hebei,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education, Hebei University, Hebei,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mi</LastName><ForeName>Mingdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Affairs Office, Weinan Vocational and Technical College, Weinan,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Buyao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Education and Consultation Center, Tarim University, Alaer,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Tingwei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Military Medical Psychology, Air Force Military Medical University, Xian, Shanxi,&#xa0;China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-0640</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DASS-21</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">big five</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bridge centrality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">military academy students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personality traits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological resilience</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The reviewer DW declared a shared affiliation with the author TF to the handling editor at the time of review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41696472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12894006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2026.1684090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jing K, Feng Z, Xu J, He Y, Tang Q, Zhang Q, et al. The mental health of Chinese military personnel: a cross-sectional epidemiological study. BMC Public Health. (2024) 24:3525. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/s12889-024-20969-w, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-20969-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39695547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Hou G, Lin Y, Sa Z, Yan J, Zhang X, et al. Exploring links between Chinese military recruits&#x2019; psychological stress and coping style from the person-environment fit perspective: The chain mediating effect of self-efficacy and social support. Front Psychol. (2022) 13:996865. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.996865, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.996865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9673819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36405197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson CA, Scott RD, Bhutta ZA, Harris NB, Danese A, Samara M. Adversity in childhood is linked to mental and physical health throughout life. BMJ (Clinical Res ed.). (2020) 371:m3048. doi:&#xa0; 10.1136/bmj.m3048, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33115717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visier-Alfonso ME, Sarabia-Cobo C, Cobo-Cuenca AI, Nieto-L&#xf3;pez M, L&#xf3;pez-Honrubia R, Bartolom&#xe9;-Guti&#xe9;rrez R, et al. Stress, mental health, and protective factors in nursing students: An observational study. Nurse Educ Today. (2024) 139:106258. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.nedt.2024.106258, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2024.106258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38781822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altinok DCA, Rajkumar R, Nie&#xdf;en D, Sbaihat H, Kersey M, Shah NJ, et al. Common neurobiological correlates of resilience and personality traits within the triple resting-state brain networks assessed by 7-Tesla ultra-high field MRI. Sci Rep. (2021) 11:11564. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41598-021-91056-y, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-91056-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34079001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Londero I, da Rocha NS. Personality dimensions, resilience, and depression during COVID-19 pandemic: A one-year longitudinal study. Acta psychologica. (2024) 245:104229. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.actpsy.2024.104229, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actpsy.2024.104229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38493710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen ZA, Almagor Tikotzki M, Kurman J. Psychological resilience: Predictors and measurement among Israel Defense Force combat officer candidates. Military Psychol. (2023) 35:493&#x2013;506. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/08995605.2022.2127986, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08995605.2022.2127986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37903167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader G, Qureshi M, Chaudhary Z, Fischer CE, Graff-Guerrero A, Gerretsen P, et al. Effect of personality traits, psychological resilience and life adversities on lifetime violence trajectories: A novel classification model in schizophrenia. Psychiatry Res. (2024) 339:116044. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.psychres.2024.116044, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2024.116044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38972181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Li F, Sun H. A study on the relationship between self-efficacy, psychological resilience, and job burnout of grassroots civil servants: the moderating role of the big five personality traits. J Occup Environ Med. (2022) 64:889&#x2013;95. doi:&#xa0; 10.1097/JOM.0000000000002600, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35732041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse NY, Ratheesh A, Tian YE, Connolly CG, Davey CG, Ganesan S, et al. A mega-analysis of functional connectivity and network abnormalities in youth depression. Nat Ment Health. (2024) 2:1169&#x2013;82. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s44220-024-00309-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44220-024-00309-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troy AS, Willroth EC, Shallcross AJ, Giuliani NR, Gross JJ, Mauss IB. Psychological resilience: an affect-regulation framework. Annu Rev Psychol. (2023) 74:547&#x2013;76. doi:&#xa0; 10.1146/annurev-psych-020122-041854, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-psych-020122-041854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12009612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Li Y, Xiang X, Xiao ZC, Hu J, Li Y, et al. Stress relief as a natural resilience mechanism against depression-like behaviors. Neuron. (2023) 111:3789&#x2013;3801.e6. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.neuron.2023.09.004, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2023.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37776853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starcevic V, Janca A. Personality dimensions and disorders and coping with the COVID-19 pandemic. Curr Opin Psychiatry. (2022) 35:73&#x2013;7. doi:&#xa0; 10.1097/YCO.0000000000000755, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8654116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell-Sills L, Cohan SL, Stein MB. Relationship of resilience to personality, coping, and psychiatric symptoms in young adults. Behav Res Ther. (2006) 44:585&#x2013;99. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.brat.2005.05.001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2005.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15998508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakaya M, Oshio A, Kaneko H. Correlations for adolescent resilience scale with big five personality traits. psychol Rep. (2006) 98:927&#x2013;30. doi:&#xa0; 10.2466/pr0.98.3.927-930, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2466/pr0.98.3.927-930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16933700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annalakshmi N. Resilience in relation to extraversion-introversion, psychoticism and neuroticism. Indian J Psychometry Educ. (2007) 38:51&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy LB, Moriarty AE. Vulnerability, coping, and growth: From infancy to adolescence. New Haven (CT): Yale University Press; (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annalakshmi N. The resilient individual: A personality analysis. J Indian Acad Appl Psychol. (2008) 34:110&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayombo GA. The relationship between personality traits and psychological resilience among the Caribbean adolescents. J Instructional Psychol. (2010) 37:36&#x2013;43. doi:&#xa0; 10.5539/ijps.v2n2p105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/ijps.v2n2p105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Wang Y, Lu G. The relationship between psychological resilience and positive coping styles among Chinese college students: A cross-sectional study. Chin Ment Health J. (2020) 34:489&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor KM, Davidson JR. Development of a new resilience scale: The Connor&#x2013;Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC). Depression Anxiety. (2003) 18:76&#x2013;82. doi:&#xa0; 10.1002/da.10113, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.10113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12964174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masten AS. Ordinary magic: Resilience processes in development. Am Psychol. (2001) 56:227&#x2013;38. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/0003-066X.56.3.227, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.56.3.227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11315249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southwick SM, Bonanno GA, Masten AS, Panter-Brick C, Yehuda R. Resilience definitions, theory, and challenges: Interdisciplinary perspectives. Eur J Psychotraumatol. (2014) 5:25338. doi:&#xa0; 10.3402/ejpt.v5.25338, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/ejpt.v5.25338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4185134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25317257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baymur F. Genel psikoloji [General Psychology]. 19th ed. Ankara: &#x130;nk&#x131;lap Kitabevi; (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polatc&#x131; S, T&#x131;naz ZD. The relationship between fear of COVID-19 and psychological resilience: The mediating role of perceived stress. Perspect Psychiatr Care. (2021) 58:78&#x2013;85. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/ppc.12794, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppc.12794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33834515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotov R, Gamez W, Schmidt F, Watson D. Linking &#x201c;big&#x201d; personality traits to anxiety, depressive, and substance use disorders: A meta-analysis. psychol Bull. (2010) 136:768&#x2013;821. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/a0020327, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0020327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20804236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furnham A, Monsen J, Ahmetoglu G. Typical intellectual engagement, Big Five personality traits, approaches to learning and cognitive ability predictors of academic performance. Br J Educ Psychol. (2009) 79:769&#x2013;82. doi:&#xa0; 10.1348/978185409X412147, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1348/978185409X412147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19245744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrae RR, Costa PT, Jr. The five-factor theory of personality. In: John OP, Robins RW, Pervin LA, editors. Handbook of personality: Theory and research, 3rd ed. Guilford Press, New York: (2008). p. 159&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saucier G, Srivastava S. What makes a good structural model of personality? Evaluating the Big Five and alternatives. In: Mikulincer M, Shaver PR, Cooper ML, Larsen RJ, editors. APA handbook of personality and social psychology: Volume 4. Personality processes and individual differences. American Psychological Association, Washington, DC: (2015). p. 283&#x2013;305. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/14343-012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/14343-012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle GJ. Critique of the five-factor model of personality. In: Boyle GJ, Matthews G, Saklofske DH, editors. The SAGE handbook of personality theory and assessment: Volume 1&#x2014;Personality theories and models. SAGE Publications Ltd, London: (2008). p. 295&#x2013;312. doi:&#xa0; 10.4135/9781849200462.n14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781849200462.n14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrae RR, Costa PT, Jr. Empirical and theoretical status of the five-factor model of personality traits. In: Boyle GJ, Matthews G, Saklofske DH, editors. The SAGE Handbook of Personality Theory and Assessment: Volume 1&#x2014;Personality Theories and Models. Washington (DC): SAGE Publications Ltd; (2008). p. 273&#x2013;94. doi:&#xa0; 10.4135/9781849200462.n13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781849200462.n13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saucier G, Srivastava S. What makes a good structural model of personality? Evaluating the Big Five and alternatives. In: Mikulincer M, Shaver PR, Cooper ML, Larsen RJ, editors. APA Handbook of Personality and Social Psychology: Volume 4&#x2014;Personality Processes and Individual Differences. American Psychological Association; (2015). p. 283&#x2013;305. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/14343-013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/14343-013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle GJ. Critique of the five-factor model of personality. In: Boyle GJ, Matthews G, Saklofske DH, editors. The SAGE Handbook of Personality Theory and Assessment: Volume 1&#x2014;Personality Theories and Models. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; (2008). p. 295&#x2013;312. doi:&#xa0; 10.4135/9781849200462.n14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781849200462.n14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu T, Zhang D, Wang J. A meta-analysis of the trait resilience and mental health. Pers Individ Dif. (2015) 76:18&#x2013;27. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.paid.2014.11.039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2014.11.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally RJ. Network analysis of psychopathology: controversies and challenges. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. (2021) 17:31&#x2013;53. doi:&#xa0; 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-081219-092850, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-081219-092850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33228401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PJ, Ma R, McNally RJ. Bridge centrality: A network approach to understanding comorbidity. Multivariate Behav Res. (2021) 56:353&#x2013;67. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/00273171.2019.1614898, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2019.1614898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31179765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Wal JM, van Borkulo CD, Deserno MK, Breedvelt JJF, Lees M, Lokman JC, et al. Advancing urban mental health research: from complexity science to actionable targets for intervention. Lancet Psychiatry. (2021) 8:991&#x2013;1000. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00047-X, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00047-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34627532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Ren L, Rotaru K, Liu X, Li K, Yang W, et al. Bridging the links between Big Five personality traits and problematic smartphone use: A network analysis. J Behav Addict. (2023) 12:128&#x2013;36. doi:&#xa0; 10.1556/2006.2022.00093, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/2006.2022.00093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10260210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matz SC, Harari GM. Personality-place transactions: Mapping the relationships between Big Five personality traits, states, and daily places. J Pers Soc Psychol. (2021) 120:1367&#x2013;85. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/pspp0000297, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pspp0000297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32496085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shao J, Weng A, Lian J, Wen F, Fang Q, et al. Nurses&#x2019; Personality traits and perceived work environments during public health emergencies: implications for nursing workforce planning. Risk Manage healthcare Policy. (2024) 17:1199&#x2013;209. doi:&#xa0; 10.2147/RMHP.S458235, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/RMHP.S458235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11088948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38737419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iimura S. Sensory-processing sensitivity and COVID-19 stress in a young population: The mediating role of resilience. Pers Individ Dif. (2022) 184:111183. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.paid.2021.111183, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2021.111183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8496909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34642519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polizzi CP, McDonald CW, Sleight FG, Lynn SJ. Resilience, coping, and the covid-19 pandemic across the globe - an update: what have we learned? Clin neuropsychiatry. (2023) 20:316&#x2013;26. doi:&#xa0; 10.36131/cnfioritieditore20230411, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36131/cnfioritieditore20230411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10544248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37791081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batmaz H, &#xc7;elik E. Examining the mediating role of resilience and life satisfaction in the relationship between anxiety sensitivity and perceived stress. psychol Rep. (2024) 332941241263572. doi:&#xa0; 10.1177/00332941241263572, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00332941241263572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38907633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleidorn W, Schwaba T, Zheng A, Hopwood CJ, Sosa SS, Roberts BW, et al. Personality stability and change: A meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. psychol Bull. (2022) 148:588&#x2013;619. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/bul0000365, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35834197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainio-Theberge S, Armony JL. Antisocial and impulsive personality traits are linked to individual differences in somatosensory maps of emotion. Sci Rep. (2023) 13:675. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41598-023-27880-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-27880-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36635384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye B, Li Y, Bao Z, Gao J. Psychological resilience and frailty progression in older adults. JAMA network Open. (2024) 7:e2447605. doi:&#xa0; 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.47605, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.47605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11589792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39585692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MG, Carr D. Psychological resilience and health among older adults: A comparison of personal resources. journals gerontology. Ser B psychol Sci Soc Sci. (2021) 76:1241&#x2013;50. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/geronb/gbaa116, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geronb/gbaa116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32750146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrague LJ. Psychological resilience, coping behaviours and social support among health care workers during the COVID-19 pandemic: A systematic review of quantitative studies. J Nurs Manage. (2021) 29:1893&#x2013;905. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/jonm.13336, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.13336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prime H, Wade M, Browne DT. Risk and resilience in family well-being during the COVID-19 pandemic. Am Psychol. (2020) 75:631&#x2013;43. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/amp0000660, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/amp0000660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Borsboom D, Fried EI. Estimating psychological networks and their accuracy: A tutorial paper. Behav Res Methods. (2018) 50:195&#x2013;212. doi:&#xa0; 10.3758/s13428-017-0862-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/s13428-017-0862-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5809547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringmann LF, Eronen MI. Don&#x2019;t blame the model: Reconsidering the network approach to psychopathology. psychol Rev. (2018) 125:606&#x2013;15. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/rev0000108, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/rev0000108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29952625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Liang Y, Yang T, Gao R, Zhang G. Validity and longitudinal invariance of the 10-item connor-davidson resilience scale (CD-RISC-10) in chinese left-behind and non-left-behind children. Psychol Rep. (2022) 125:2274&#x2013;91. doi:&#xa0; 10.1177/00332941211013531, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00332941211013531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34034570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang M-C, He L, Luo J, Deng J. The development and psychometric evaluation of the Chinese Big Five Personality Inventory-15. PloS One. (2019) 14:e0221621. doi:&#xa0; 10.1371/journal.pone.0221621, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0221621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6771307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31454383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony MM, Bieling PJ, Cox BJ, Enns MW, Swinson RP. Psychometric properties of the 42-item and 21-item versions of the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales in clinical groups and a community sample. psychol Assess. (1998) 10:176&#x2013;81. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/1040-3590.10.2.176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1040-3590.10.2.176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Fried EI. A tutorial on regularized partial correlation networks. Psychol Methods. (2018) 23:617&#x2013;34. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/met0000167, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/met0000167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29595293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Cramer AOJ, Waldorp LJ, Schmittmann VD, Borsboom D. qgraph: network visualizations of relationships in psychometric data. J Stat Softw. (2012) 48:1&#x2013;18. doi:&#xa0; 10.18637/JSS.V048.I04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/JSS.V048.I04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Borsboom D. Fried E I. Estimating psychological networks and their accuracy: A tutorial paper. Behavior Research Methods. (2016) 50:195&#x2013;212. doi:&#xa0; 10.48550/arXiv.1604.08462, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1604.08462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5809547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren L, Yang Z, Wang YD, Cui LB, Jin YC, Ma ZJ, et al. The relations among worry, meta-worry, intolerance of uncertainty and attentional bias for threat in men at high risk for generalized anxiety disorder: A network analysis. BMC Psychiatry. (2020) 20:452&#x2013;62. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/s12888-020-02849-w, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-020-02849-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried EI, van Borkulo CD, Epskamp S. On the Importance of Estimating Parameter Uncertainty in Network Psychometrics: A Response to Forbes et&#xa0;al. Multivariate Behav Res. (2021) 56:243&#x2013;8. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/00273171.2020.1746903, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2020.1746903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32264714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Waldorp LJ, M&#xf5;ttus R, Borsboom D. The gaussian graphical model in cross-sectional and time-series data. Multivar. Behav Res. (2018) 53:453&#x2013;80. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/00273171.2018.1454823, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2018.1454823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Fried EI, van Borkulo CD, Robinaugh DJ, Marsman M, Dalege J, et al. Investigating the utility of fixed-margin sampling in network psychometrics. Routledge Journals Taylor Francis Ltd. (2021) 56:314&#x2013;28. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/00273171.2018.1489771, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2018.1489771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30463456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang M, Wang X, Feng T, Liu X, Xiao W. Complex associations between anxiety, depression, and resilience in a college student sample: a network analysis. Front Psychiatry. (2025) 16:1502252. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fpsyt.2025.1502252, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2025.1502252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12117827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40438336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao XY, Xu CZ, Chen Y, Peng QL, Ran HL, Che YS, et al. Personality traits and self-harm behaviors among Chinese children and adolescents: The mediating effect of psychological resilience. World J Psychiatry. (2022) 12:494&#x2013;504. doi:&#xa0; 10.5498/wjp.v12.i3.494, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v12.i3.494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35433324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eroglu A, Suzan OK, Hur G, Cinar N. The relationship between fear of COVID-19 and psychological resilience according to personality traits of university students: A PATH analysis. Arch Psychiatr Nurs. (2023) 42:1&#x2013;8. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.apnu.2022.11.001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apnu.2022.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36842819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalin NH. Trauma, resilience, anxiety disorders, and PTSD. Am J Psychiatry. (2021) 178:103&#x2013;5. doi:&#xa0; 10.1176/appi.ajp.2020.20121738, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2020.20121738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33517749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulak H, Kaya F. The relationship between psychological resilience and stress perception in nurses in Turkey during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Nurs research: JNR. (2021) 29:e175. doi:&#xa0; 10.1097/jnr.0000000000000454, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/jnr.0000000000000454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xe1;b&#xf3; V, Csiszar A, Ungvari Z, Purebl G. Psychological resilience and competence: key promoters of successful aging and flourishing in late life. GeroScience. (2023) 45:3045&#x2013;58. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11357-023-00856-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-023-00856-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10643728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37418098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stricker J, Buecker S, Pietrowsky R. Alignment of the personality inventory for ICD-11 with the five-factor model of personality. psychol Assess. (2022) 34:711&#x2013;6. doi:&#xa0; 10.1037/pas0001141, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pas0001141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35511514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang W, Tiego J, Hellyer PJ, Trender W, Grant JE, Chamberlain SR, et al. Validation of an abbreviated Big Five personality inventory at large population scale: Psychometric structure and associations with common psychiatric and neurological disorders. Compr Psychiatry. (2024) 134:152514. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.comppsych.2024.152514, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comppsych.2024.152514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38986399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayad M, Scheer V, Blanco C, Louville P, S&#xe1;nchez-Rico M, Rezaei K, et al. Identifying bridge symptoms between borderline personality disorder and posttraumatic stress disorder: A network analysis from a national cohort. J Clin Psychiatry. (2024) 85:23m15079. doi:&#xa0; 10.4088/JCP.23m15079, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.23m15079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39265057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson C, Palmer L, Leightley D, Pernet D, Chandran D, Leal R, et al. Military veterans and civilians&#x2019; mental health diagnoses: an analysis of secondary mental health services. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. (2023) 58:1029&#x2013;37. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s00127-022-02411-x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-022-02411-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10261174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36547684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golino HF, Epskamp S. Exploratory graph analysis: A new approach for estimating the number of dimensions in psychological research. PloS One. (2017) 12:e0174035. doi:&#xa0; 10.1371/journal.pone.0174035.4, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0174035.4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5465941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28594839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>