<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41372377</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An empirical study of integration models and mechanisms for maternity care in innovative vocational education.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2053</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2053</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2053</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-31951-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Integrated vocational education is increasingly essential for addressing maternal health disparities in under-resourced regions of China. Persistent workforce shortages and fragmented training models have contributed to inconsistent care delivery, particularly in Western provinces. This study evaluated an integrated model that combines simulation-based learning, structured supervision, and early clinical immersion to enhance training effectiveness. A convergent parallel mixed-methods design assessed the model's impact on patient satisfaction, student interaction, and perceived maternal complications. Quantitative data were collected from 300 participants, including students, maternity nurses, clinical instructors, and postnatal patients, and analyzed using SPSS and partial least squares structural equation modeling (SmartPLS). Qualitative insights from 14 semi-structured interviews were analyzed thematically using NVivo. The integrated training model significantly predicted higher patient satisfaction (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.863, R&#xb2; = 0.743), aligning with Kolb's Experiential Learning Theory. However, no significant relationships were found between student interaction, patient satisfaction, or perceived maternal complications. Critically, the staff training construct demonstrated weak psychometric validity (CR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.337; AVE&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.126), warranting cautious interpretation of its statistical strength. Qualitative findings provided essential context, revealing fragmented implementation, unclear student roles, and institutional barriers such as emergency delays and staffing shortages. These systemic constraints help explain the absence of improvement in clinical outcomes despite enhanced satisfaction ratings. In conclusion, integrated vocational education can enhance perceived care quality, but its clinical impact depends on institutional readiness and supervisory fidelity. This study offers actionable insights for policy reforms under the Healthy China 2030 agenda and supports scalable models for maternal health training in low-resource settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Weitai</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Vocational and Technical College of Quality Engineering, Guangxi, China. 548580230@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GXGZJG2025B187</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Vocational Education Teaching Reform Research Project (GXGZJG2025B187) + "Construction of a Demonstration Specialized Talent Training System for Industrial Product Quality Inspection Technology from the Perspective of 'Management and Technology Integration' National Quality Infrastructure (NQI)".</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014829" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vocational Education</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008427" MajorTopicYN="Y">Maternal Health Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perceived maternal complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation-based training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Student&#x2013;patient interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vocational education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41372377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12808121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-31951-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-31951-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Selwi, A. G. &amp; Barkat, A. International and National data on maternal, neonatal, and child mortality rates and policies to reduce the high in the middle East and morocco: a multilevel meta-analysis. <i>J. Bioscience Appl. Res.</i><b>9</b> (4), 261&#x2013;291 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/jbaar.2023.330290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI, Y., Zhang, Y., Yuan, B. &amp; Wang, H. Analysis and thoughts on the settings of sub-campus of public hospitals directly under the National health commission of China. <i>Chin. J. Hosp. Adm.</i>&#xa0;399&#x2013;403 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Liu, Q. &amp; Zhang, R. How the healthy China 2030 policy promotes the construction of a rural telemedicine chronic disease management service system. <i>Stud. Social Sci. Humanit.</i><b>4</b> (2), 37&#x2013;45 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elendu, C. et al. The impact of simulation-based training in medical education: A review. <i>Medicine</i><b>103</b> (27), e38813 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000038813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38968472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. et al. Improved neonatal outcomes by multidisciplinary simulation&#x2014;a contemporary practice in the demonstration area of China. <i>Front. Pead.</i><b>11</b>, 1138633 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2023.1138633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10287162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37360368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W. et al. The evolution of simulation-based medical education research: from traditional to virtual simulations. <i>Heliyon</i>&#xa0;<b>10</b>(15) (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11337719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39170203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamrungsin, P. &amp; Khampirat, B. Improving professional skills of pre-service teachers using online training: applying work-integrated learning approaches through a quasi-experimental study. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b> (7), 4362 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14074362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockdale, S. E. et al. Assessing fidelity to evidence-based quality improvement as an implementation strategy for patient-centered medical home transformation in the veterans health administration. <i>Implement. Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;13 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-020-0979-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7079486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, W. et al. Investigating factors influencing medical practitioners&#x2019; resistance to and adoption of internet hospitals in china: mixed methods study. <i>J. Med. Internet. Res.</i><b>25</b>, e46621 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/46621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10425818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37523226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas, S. K. <i>Understanding User and Investor Perspectives on Robo-Advisors Adoption in Fintech [v&#xe9;d&#xe9;s el&#x151;tt]</i> (Budapesti Corvinus Egyetem, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller, A. B. et al. Monitoring maternal and newborn health outcomes globally: a brief history of key events and initiatives. <i>Tropical Med. Int. Health</i>. <b>24</b> (12), 1342&#x2013;1368 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tmi.13313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6916345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31622524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lux, K. M. <i>Vocational Tertiary Education of Young Adults in Kenya: Model Development</i> (Pepperdine University, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faizan Siddiqui, M. et al. Integration of augmented reality, virtual reality, and extended reality in healthcare and medical education: A glimpse into the emerging horizon in LMICs&#x2014;A systematic review. <i>J. Med. Educ. Curric. Dev.</i><b>12</b>, 23821205251342315 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23821205251342315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12123137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40452894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judd, B., Brentnall, J., Phillips, A. &amp; Aley, M. The practice of simulations as work-integrated learning. In <i>The Routledge International Handbook of Work-Integrated Learning</i> 254&#x2013;270 (Routledge, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satin, A. J. Simulation in obstetrics. <i>Obstet. Gynecol.</i><b>132</b> (1), 199&#x2013;209 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000002682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar, A. The meta-analysis of High-fidelity simulation in undergraduate nursing education. <i>Int. J. Multicult. Educ.</i>&#xa0;<b>25</b>(1) (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, P. M., Mansour, R., Qiu, M. K., Biraro, I. A. &amp; Rabin, T. L. Low-and middle-income country host perceptions of short-term experiences in global health: A systematic review. <i>Acad. Med.</i><b>96</b> (3), 460&#x2013;469 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000003867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh, M. et al. Bridging the gap in training and clinical practice in Sub-Saharan Africa. <i>Curr. Breast Cancer Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 158&#x2013;169 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12609-019-00322-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne, C. J. Assessing the engagement rates and satisfaction levels of various clinical health science student sub-groups using supplementary eLearning resources in an introductory anatomy and physiology unit. <i>Health Educ.</i><b>119</b> (1), 2&#x2013;17 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/HE-04-2018-0020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dub&#xe9;, M., Shultz, J., Barnes, S., Pascal, B. &amp; Kaba, A. Goals, recommendations, and the how-to strategies for developing and facilitating patient safety and system integration simulations. <i>HERD: Health Environ. Res. Des. J.</i><b>13</b> (1), 94&#x2013;105 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1937586719846586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delli Poggi, A. et al. Impact of nursing students on the quality of care perceived by patients. A systematic review of the literature. <i>Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci.</i><b>25</b> (6), 2711&#x2013;2725 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33829457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shongwe, S. S. <i>A Framework for Integrating Simulation into the Bachelor of Nursing Science Programme in Eswatini</i> (University of the Witwatersrand, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health, B. G., Practice, C. &amp; Outcomes, P. o. M. t. I. o. I. E. o. C., Measuring the impact of interprofessional education on collaborative practice and patient outcomes. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, C. J., Smith, S. N. &amp; Pugatch, M. Experimental and quasi-experimental designs in implementation research. <i>Psychiatry Res.</i><b>283</b>, 112452 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.06.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6923620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31255320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;stlund, U., Kidd, L., Wengstr&#xf6;m, Y. &amp; Rowa-Dewar, N. Combining qualitative and quantitative research within mixed method research designs: a methodological review. <i>Int. J. Nurs. Stud.</i><b>48</b> (3), 369&#x2013;383 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2010.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringle, C., Da Silva, D. &amp; Bido, D. Structural equation modeling with the SmartPLS<i>. Braz. J. Mark.</i><b>13</b>(2) (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner, R. &amp; Grimm, M. S. Empirical validation of the 10-times rule for SEM. In <i>State of the Art in Partial Least Squares Structural Equation Modeling (PLS-SEM) Methodological Extensions and Applications in the Social Sciences and Beyond</i> 3&#x2013;7 (Springer, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V. &amp; Clarke, V. To saturate or not to saturate? Questioning data saturation as a useful concept for thematic analysis and sample-size rationales. <i>Qual. Res. Sport Exerc. Health</i><b>13</b>(2), 201&#x2013;216 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2019.1704846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Maskari, T. S., Melville, C. A. &amp; Willis, D. S. Systematic review: cultural adaptation and feasibility of screening for autism in non-English speaking countries. <i>Int. J. Mental Health Syst.</i><b>12</b>, 1&#x2013;19 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13033-018-0200-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29760771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo, G. M., Tomei, P. A., Serra, B. &amp; Mello, S. Differences in the use of 5-or 7-point likert scale: an application in food safety culture. <i>Organizational Cultures</i>. <b>21</b> (2), 1 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18848/2327-8013/CGP/v21i02/1-17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamis, A. et al. The SmartPLS analyzes approach in validity and reliability of graduate marketability instrument. <i>Soc. Psychol. Educ.</i><b>57</b> (8), 987&#x2013;1001 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis, S. E., Shawyer, F., Cayoun, B., Enticott, J. &amp; Meadows, G. N. Group mindfulness-integrated cognitive behavior therapy (MiCBT) reduces depression and anxiety and improves flourishing in a transdiagnostic primary care sample compared to treatment-as-usual: a randomized controlled trial. <i>Front. Psychiatry</i>. <b>13</b>, 815170 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.815170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9193586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35711582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJonckheere, M. &amp; Vaughn, L. M. Semistructured interviewing in primary care research: a balance of relationship and rigour. <i>Family Med. Commun. Health</i><b>7</b>(2), e000057 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/fmch-2018-000057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6910737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32148704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salowi, M. A. et al. A. Exploratory factor analysis as a validation tool in a questionnaire to evaluate the uptake of cataract surgery. <i>medRxiv</i>, 2025.2001. 2029.25321326 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinnaraju, A. <i>Partial Least Squares Structural Equation Modeling (PLS-SEM) in the AI Era</i> (Innovative Methodological Guide and Framework for Business Research, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamranfar, S. et al. A partial least squares structural equation modelling analysis of the primary barriers to sustainable construction in Iran. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b> (18), 13762 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151813762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas-Vargas, H., Vel&#xe1;zquez-Espinoza, N. &amp; Col&#xed;n-Salgado, M. Technological innovation in Colombian small firms: A gender multi-group analysis. <i>Bus. Syst. Research: Int. J. Soc. Adv. Innov. Res. Econ.</i><b>13</b> (1), 46&#x2013;65 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/bsrj-2022-0004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair, J. &amp; Alamer, A. Partial least squares structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM) in second Language and education research: guidelines using an applied example. <i>Res. Methods Appl. Linguistics</i>. <b>1</b> (3), 100027 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmal.2022.100027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabol, M., Hair, J., Cepeda, G., Rold&#xe1;n, J. L. &amp; Chong, A. Y. L. PLS-SEM in information systems: seizing the opportunity and marching ahead full speed to adopt methodological updates. <i>Industrial Manage. Data Syst.</i><b>123</b> (12), 2997&#x2013;3017 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IMDS-07-2023-0429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. K. et al. Using thematic analysis in qualitative research. <i>J. Med. Surg. Public. Health</i>. <b>6</b>, 100198 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glmedi.2025.100198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin, S. N. Inter-coder agreement in qualitative coding: considerations for its use. <i>Am. J. Qualitative Res.</i><b>8</b> (3), 23&#x2013;43 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29333/ajqr/14887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraiwanit, T., Limna, P. &amp; Siripipatthanakul, S. NVivo for social sciences and management studies: A systematic review. <i>Adv. Knowl. Executives</i>. <b>2</b> (3), 1&#x2013;11 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balon, R. et al. <i>Institutional Review Board Approval as an Educational Tool</i> Vol. 43, 285&#x2013;289 (Springer, 2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30706434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sil, A. &amp; Das, N. K. Informed consent process: foundation of the researcher-participant bond. <i>Indian J. Dermatology</i>. <b>62</b> (4), 380&#x2013;386 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijd.IJD_272_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5527718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins, K. M., Onwuegbuzie, A. J., Johnson, R. B. &amp; Frels, R. K. Practice note: using debriefing interviews to promote authenticity and transparency in mixed research. <i>Int. J. Multiple Res. Approaches</i>. <b>7</b> (2), 271&#x2013;284 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5172/mra.2013.7.2.271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caube, J. M., Laspona, A., Pepito, R. J. &amp; Galaura, L. L. Student experiences and academic performance among bachelor of physical education students. <i>Eur. J. Phys. Educ. Sport Sci.</i>&#xa0;<b>12</b>(4) (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shet, S. V., Raut, G., Shet, P., Argade, P. &amp; Piekara, A. From challenges to competencies: informal female entrepreneurship in emerging economies. <i>Journal Small Bus. Enterp. Development</i> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S. F., Burns, E., Salamonson, Y. &amp; Schmied, V. Expectations and experiences of nursing students in supporting new mothers to breastfeed: a descriptive qualitative study. <i>J. Clin. Nurs.</i><b>28</b> (11&#x2013;12), 2340&#x2013;2350 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.14836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30786086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes, C. &amp; Mellanby, E. Debriefing strategies for interprofessional simulation&#x2014;a qualitative study. <i>Adv. Simul.</i><b>7</b> (1), 18 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-022-00214-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9206121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35717254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geddes, E. J. <i>Developing an Understanding of Informal Learning Interactions between Nurses and Final Year Medical Students in the Workplace: an Ethnographic Study</i> (University of Northumbria at Newcastle (United Kingdom), 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liljeholm, U., Argentzell, E. &amp; Bejerholm, U. An integrated mental health and vocational intervention: A longitudinal study on mental health changes among young adults. <i>Nurs. open.</i><b>7</b> (6), 1755&#x2013;1765 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7544838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33072359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heier, L. et al. Interprofessional communication skills training to improve medical students&#x2019; and nursing trainees&#x2019; error communication-quasi-experimental pilot study. <i>BMC Med. Educ.</i><b>24</b> (1), 10 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-023-04997-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomfield, J., Roberts, J. &amp; While, A. The effect of computer-assisted learning versus conventional teaching methods on the acquisition and retention of handwashing theory and skills in pre-qualification nursing students: a randomised controlled trial. <i>Int. J. Nurs. Stud.</i><b>47</b> (3), 287&#x2013;294 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2009.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeke, C. E. et al. Results from a proactive follow-up intervention to improve linkage and retention among people living with HIV in uganda: a pre-/post-study. <i>BMC Health Serv. Res.</i><b>18</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-018-3735-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6282267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos Neto, A. S., Reis, M. R., Coimbra, A. P., Soares, J. C. &amp; Calixto, W. P. Measure of customer satisfaction in the residential electricity distribution service using structural equation modeling. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (3), 746 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15030746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meydan, C. H. &amp; Akka&#x15f;, H. The role of triangulation in qualitative research: Converging perspectives. In <i>Principles of Conducting Qualitative Research in Multicultural Settings</i> 98&#x2013;129 (IGI Global, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz, M. A. &amp; Branham, K. E. Professional learning communities focusing on results and data-use to improve student learning: the right implementation matters. <i>Plann. Chang.</i><b>47</b> (1/2), 37 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tull, A., Hirt, J. B. &amp; Saunders, S. <i>Becoming Socialized in Student Affairs Administration: A Guide for New Professionals and their Supervisors</i> (Taylor &amp; Francis, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergsteiner, H., Avery, G. C. &amp; Neumann, R. Kolb&#x2019;s experiential learning model: critique from a modelling perspective. <i>Stud. Continuing Educ.</i><b>32</b> (1), 29&#x2013;46 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01580370903534355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digenis, C., Salter, A., Cusack, L., Koch, A. &amp; Turnbull, D. Reduced length of hospital stay after caesarean section: a systematic review examining women&#x2019;s experiences and psychosocial outcomes. <i>Midwifery</i><b>91</b>, 102855 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.midw.2020.102855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutroubas, V. &amp; Galanakis, M. Bandura&#x2019;s social learning theory and its importance in the organizational psychology context. <i>Psychology</i><b>12</b> (6), 315&#x2013;322 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner, B. J. A theory of organizational readiness for change. In <i>Handbook on Implementation Science</i> 215&#x2013;232 (Edward Elgar Publishing, 2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak, K., Polikoff, M. S., Desimone, L. M. &amp; Sald&#xed;var Garc&#xed;a, E. The adaptive challenges of curriculum implementation: insights for educational leaders driving standards-based reform. <i>Aera Open.</i><b>6</b> (2), 2332858420932828 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2332858420932828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadling, N. A. &amp; Bhosale, S. Vocational education and training as bridging the skill gap: NEP 2020 perspective. <i>J. East-West Thought (JET) ISSN (O): 2168&#x2013;2259. UGC CARE I</i><b>15</b>(1), 200&#x2013;208 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaston, P. L. <i>Higher Education Accreditation: How it&#x2019;s Changing, Why it Must</i> (Taylor &amp; Francis, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray, W. D. Simulated task environments: the role of high-fidelity simulations, scaled worlds, synthetic environments, and laboratory tasks in basic and applied cognitive research. <i>Cogn. Sci. Q.</i><b>2</b> (2), 205&#x2013;227 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah, J. H., Magno, F. &amp; Cassia, F. <i>Reviewing the SmartPLS 4 Software: the Latest Features and Enhancements</i> (Springer, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylvander, M. <i>Authentic and Meritorious: a Deductive Thematic Analysis of Successful Undergraduate International Application Interviews to Selective US Universities</i> (UCL (University College London), 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, K. <i>Simulation Enhances Mental Health Knowledge, Skills, and Attributes in Enrolled Nursing Students</i> (Swinburne, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaganas, J. C., Ulrich, B. T. &amp; Mancini, M. E. B. <i>Mastering Simulation: a Handbook for Success</i> (Sigma Theta Tau, 2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>