<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41369544</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differences in Anthropometric Characteristics and Physical Fitness Based on Playing Position in Elite Youth Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e41</StartPage><EndPage>e49</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e41-e49</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rites, AA, da Silva, RCF, de Souza, EB, dos Santos, RP, Pinto, VS, Paulucio, D, Miranda, H, Gomes, DV, and Lattari, E. Differences in anthropometric characteristics and physical fitness based on playing position in elite youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): e41-e49, 2026-To examine differences in anthropometric characteristics and physical fitness based on playing position in elite youth soccer players, a comparative cross-sectional study was conducted on 160 male players in the U13-14, U15-16, and U17-20 categories. The players were grouped as lateral defender (LD), central defender (CD), midfielder (MF), and attacker. During the first visit, anthropometric assessments, squat jump (SJ), and countermovement jump (CMJ) were conducted. On the second visit, 48 hours later, a 20-meter sprint test and the Yo-Yo intermittent recovery level 1 test were performed. Height, body mass, lean mass, vertical jumps, 20 m sprint, and V&#x307;o2max all increased with advancing age (p &#x2264; 0.001). A main effect of position (p &#x2264; 0.001) showed that CD had higher stature, body mass, and lean mass than players in other positions. In addition, CD exhibited higher values than LD for SJ and CMJ height (p &lt; 0.05). The U17-20 group exhibited greater SJ and CMJ peak power than the U15-16 and U13-14 groups (p &#x2264; 0.001 for all comparisons). In addition, CDs outperformed all other positions in SJ peak power and showed higher CMJ peak power than LDs and MFs across all age categories. This study demonstrated that height, body mass, lean mass, vertical jump performance, sprint speed, and V&#x307;o2max all increased with advancing age in youth soccer players. Central defender consistently exhibited higher values for these physical characteristics than players in other positions, including LD, particularly in SJ and CMJ performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rites</LastName><ForeName>Alex Ambrosio</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity Biosciences, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva</LastName><ForeName>Ramdel Caldas Ferreira</ForeName><Initials>RCF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Sciences Graduate Program, Salgado de Oliveira University (UNIVERSO), Niter&#xf3;i, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Souza</LastName><ForeName>Elton Bicalho</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Volta Redonda University Center, Volta Redonda, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo Peixoto</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geraldo di Biase University Center, Barra do Pira&#xed;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Ver&#xf4;nica Salerno</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity Biosciences, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paulucio</LastName><ForeName>Dailson</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Sciences Graduate Program, Salgado de Oliveira University (UNIVERSO), Niter&#xf3;i, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Al Nassr Football Club, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miranda</LastName><ForeName>Humberto</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, School of Physical Education and Sports, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LADTEF-Performance, Training and Physical Exercise Laboratory, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomes</LastName><ForeName>Diego Viana</ForeName><Initials>DV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity Biosciences, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lattari</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Sciences Graduate Program, Salgado de Oliveira University (UNIVERSO), Niter&#xf3;i, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000886" MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001827" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Height</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elite youth athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">playing position differences</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202601000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abad C, Cuniyochi R, Kobal R, et al. Effect of detraining on body composition and on vertical jump and sprint performance in young elite Brazilian soccer players. Rev Andal Med Deporte 9: 124&#x2013;130, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abade EA, Goncalves BV, Silva AM, Leite NM, Castagna C, Sampaio JE. Classifying young soccer players by training performances. Percept Mot Skills 119: 971&#x2013;984, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM's Resource Manual for Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 7th ed. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test: A useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. Sports Med 38: 37&#x2013;51, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal-Orozco MF, Posada-Falomir M, Quinonez-Gastelum CM, et al. Anthropometric and body composition profile of young professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1911&#x2013;1923, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boraczy&#x144;ski M, Boraczy&#x144;ski T, Podstawski R, W&#xf3;jcik Z. Relationships between anthropometric traits, body composition and aerobic capacity in male soccer players aged 13&#x2013;15 years. Kinesiol Exer Sci 69: 33&#x2013;40, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A simple method for measurement of mechanical power in jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 50: 273&#x2013;282, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canhadas IL, Silva RLP, Chaves CR, Portes LA. Anthropometric and physical fitness characteristics of young male soccer athletes. Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum 12: 239&#x2013;245, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mezencio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Routledge, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Stewart A, Bloom L, Clarkson B. Relationships between strength, sprint, and jump performance in well-trained youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 173&#x2013;177, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corr&#xea;a GV, M&#xfc;ller CB, David GB, et al. Characterization of the anthropometric profile and physical performance of young soccer athletes. Rev Bras Presc Fisiol Exerc 14: 297&#x2013;303, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha G, Lorenzi T, Sapata K, Lopes AL, Gaya AC, Oliveira &#xc1;. Effect of biological maturation on maximal oxygen uptake and ventilatory thresholds in soccer players: An allometric approach. J Sports Sci 29: 1029&#x2013;1039, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva CD, Bloomfield J, Marins JC. A review of stature, body mass and maximal oxygen uptake profiles of U17, U20 and first division players in Brazilian soccer. J Sports Sci Med 7: 309&#x2013;319, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deprez D, Fransen J, Boone J, Lenoir M, Philippaerts R, Vaeyens R. Characteristics of high-level youth soccer players: Variation by playing position. J Sports Sci 33: 243&#x2013;254, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deprez D, Valente-Dos-Santos J, Coelho-E-Silva MJ, Lenoir M, Philippaerts R, Vaeyens R. Longitudinal development of explosive leg power from childhood to adulthood in soccer players. Int J Sports Med 36: 672&#x2013;679, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>do Nascimento PC, Cetolin T, Teixeira AS, Gugliemo LGA. Anthropometric profile and aerobic and anaerobic performance in young soccer players. Rev Bras Ci&#xea;ncia Mov 22: 57&#x2013;64, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil SM, Gil J, Ruiz F, Irazusta A, Irazusta J. Physiological and anthropometric characteristics of young soccer players according to their playing position: Relevance for the selection process. J Strength Cond Res 21: 438&#x2013;445, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gontarev S, Kalac R, Zivkovic V, Ameti V, Redjepi A. Anthropometrical characteristics and somatotype of young Macedonian soccer players. Int J Morphol 34: 160&#x2013;167, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr 91: 161&#x2013;168, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karahan M. Age-related physical performance differences in male soccer players. Anthropologist 24: 724&#x2013;729, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Mohr M, Amstrup T, et al. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test: Physiological response, reliability, and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 697&#x2013;705, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunz P, Engel FA, Holmberg HC, Sperlich B. A meta-comparison of the effects of high-intensity interval training to those of small-sided games and other training protocols on parameters related to the physiology and performance of youth soccer players. Sports Med Open 5: 7, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lago-Penas C, Casais L, Dellal A, Rey E, Dominguez E. Anthropometric and physiological characteristics of young soccer players according to their playing positions: Relevance for competition success. J Strength Cond Res 25: 3358&#x2013;3367, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leao C, Camoes M, Clemente FM, et al. Anthropometric profile of soccer players as a determinant of position specificity and methodological issues of body composition estimation. Int J Environ Res Public Health 16: 2386, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL, Radnor JM, Rhodes BC, Faigenbaum AD, Myer GD. Relationships between functional movement screen scores, maturation and physical performance in young soccer players. J Sports Sci 33: 11&#x2013;19, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunardi L, Zanini D, Antes DL, Laux RC. Anthropometric profile of youth players from Associa&#xe7;&#xe3;o Chapecoense de Futebol at the beginning of the season. Rev Bras Futsal Fut 12: 256&#x2013;262, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malina RM, Eisenmann JC, Cumming SP, Ribeiro B, Aroso J. Maturity-associated variation in the growth and functional capacities of youth football (soccer) players 13&#x2013;15 years. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 555&#x2013;562, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manna I. Growth development and maturity in children and adolescent: Relation to sports and physical activity. Am J Sports Sci Med 2: 48&#x2013;50, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez-Villanueva A, Buchheit M, Kuitunen S, Poon TK, Simpson B, Peltola E. Is the relationship between sprinting and maximal aerobic speeds in young soccer players affected by maturation? Pediatr Exerc Sci 22: 497&#x2013;510, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Spencer M, Santisteban J, Goiriena JJ, Bishop D. Age-related differences in repeated-sprint ability in highly trained youth football players. J Sports Sci 27: 1581&#x2013;1590, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portella DL, Vidal-Espinoza R, Sulla-Torres J, Castelli Correia de Campos LF, Gomez-Campos R, Cossio-Bola&#xf1;os M. Reference values for body composition and physical fitness of young Brazilian elite soccer players. Front Physiol 14: 1285952, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogol AD, Clark PA, Roemmich JN. Growth and pubertal development in children and adolescents: Effects of diet and physical activity. Am J Clin Nutr 72: 521S&#x2013;528S, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento H, Anguera MT, Pereira A, Araujo D. Talent identification and development in male football: A systematic review. Sports Med 48: 907&#x2013;931, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Harackiewicz DV, Harman EA, Frykman PN, Rosenstein MT. Cross-validation of three jump power equations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 31: 572&#x2013;577, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebastia-Rico J, Soriano JM, Gonzalez-Galvez N, Martinez-Sanz JM. Body composition of Male professional soccer players using different measurement methods: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 15: 1160, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AF, Alvurdu S, Akyildiz Z, Badicu G, Greco G, Clemente FM. Variations of the locomotor profile, sprinting, Change-of-Direction, and jumping performances in youth soccer players: Interactions between playing positions and age-groups. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 998, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: Analysis of methods. Nutrition 9: 480&#x2013;492, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani M, Nikolaidis PT. Anthropometric and physiological characteristics of male soccer players according to their competitive level, playing position and age group: A systematic review. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 59: 141&#x2013;163, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Towlson C, Cobley S, Midgley AW, Garrett A, Parkin G, Lovell R. Relative age, maturation and physical biases on position allocation in elite-youth soccer. Int J Sports Med 38: 201&#x2013;209, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaeyens R, Malina RM, Janssens M, et al. A multidisciplinary selection model for youth soccer: The Ghent Youth Soccer Project. Br J Sports Med 40: 928&#x2013;934, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler MD. Physical changes of puberty. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 20: 1&#x2013;14, 1991.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>