<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41369539</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiologic and Perceptual Responses During Resistance Exercise With Self-Selected and Nonpreferred Music.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><EndPage>15</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9-15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005265</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vinovrski, MF, Moll, R, Odebode, JO, Kenny, DA, Allocco, IN, Patel, YM, Schroeder, BG, and Beyer, KS. Physiologic and perceptual responses during resistance exercise with self-selected and nonpreferred music. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): 9-15, 2026-The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of different music types on physiology, perception, and performance during resistance exercise. Nineteen resistance-trained men (n = 9) and women (n = 10) completed this counterbalanced, crossover study. On visit 1, subjects were assessed for body composition, performed a warm-up, and were estimated for 1 repetition maximum on squat, bench press, deadlift (DL), and bent-over rows. Subjects created a 5-song self-selected music (SSM) playlist and selected their least preferred genre for a nonpreferred (NON) playlist. On 2 subsequent visits, subjects completed 3 sets to failure of each exercise while listening to SSM or NON. Repetitions and rating of perceived exertion were recorded after each set. Blood lactate, focus, energy, fatigue, motivation, and enjoyment were assessed before the warm-up, each exercise, and after the session. Heart rate, muscle activation, ventilation, and muscle oxygenation were measured throughout each workout. Data were analyzed using 3-way analysis of variances with post hoc Bonferroni-adjusted comparisons. A significant trial &#xd7; exercise interaction (p = 0.016) showed greater repetitions for squat (p = 0.005) and DL (p = 0.011) during SSM than during NON. Significant trial &#xd7; time interactions for motivation (p &lt; 0.001) and enjoyment (p &lt; 0.001) revealed no significant changes from pre- to postexercise during SSM, but significant decreases during NON. Main effects for focus (p = 0.023) and energy (p = 0.020) favored SSM. No significant effects were noted for heart rate, muscle oxygen, muscle activation, or ventilation. Furthermore, no effects of sex were observed for any variable. Self-selected music during resistance exercise led to more repetitions without increasing exertion or fatigue, with higher reported focus, energy, enjoyment, and motivation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vinovrski</LastName><ForeName>Madison F</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Resistance Exercise, Physiology, and Sport Laboratory, Health and Exercise Physiology Department, Ursinus College, Collegeville, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moll</LastName><ForeName>Rianne E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Odebode</LastName><ForeName>Joshua O</ForeName><Initials>JO</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenny</LastName><ForeName>David A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allocco</LastName><ForeName>Isabel N</ForeName><Initials>IN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Yash M</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroeder</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin G</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beyer</LastName><ForeName>Kyle S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009146" MajorTopicYN="Y">Music</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="N">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Perception</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057181" MajorTopicYN="N">Pleasure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enjoyment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exertion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motivation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202601000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ballmann CG. The influence of music preference on exercise responses and performance: A review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 33, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballmann CG, Cook GD, Hester ZT, Kopec TJ, Williams TD, Rogers RR. Effects of preferred and non-preferred warm-up music on resistance exercise performance. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 3, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballmann CG, Favre ML, Phillips MT, Rogers RR, Pederson JA, Williams TD. Effect of pre-exercise music on bench press power, velocity, and repetition volume. Percept Mot Skills 128: 1183&#x2013;1196, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballmann CG, Maynard DJ, Lafoon ZN, Marshall MR, Williams TD, Rogers RR. Effects of listening to preferred versus non-preferred music on repeated Wingate anaerobic test performance. Sports 7: 185, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballmann CG, McCullum MJ, Rogers RR, Marshall MR, Williams TD. Effects of preferred vs. nonpreferred music on resistance exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1650&#x2013;1655, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barney D, Gust A, Liguori G. College students' usage of personal music players (PMP) during exercise. ICHPER-SD J Res 7: 23&#x2013;26, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Di Michele R, Merni F. Effects of self-selected music on maximal bench press strength and strength endurance. Percept Mot Skills 120: 714&#x2013;721, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Montesanto P, Lanzoni IM, Gatta G, Cortesi M, Fantozzi S. A comparison between high and low cuff pressures on muscle oxygen saturation and recovery responses following blood-flow restriction resistance exercise. Sensors 22: 9138, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biagini MS, Brown LE, Coburn JW, et al. Effects of self-selected music on strength, explosiveness, and mood. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1934&#x2013;1938, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brupbacher G, Harder J, Faude O, Zahner L, Donath L. Music in CrossFit&#x2014;Influence on performance, physiological, and psychological parameters. Sports 2: 14&#x2013;23, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;Predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance 64: 88&#x2013;90, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow EC, Etnier JL. Effects of music and video on perceived exertion during high-intensity exercise. J Sport Health Sci 6: 81&#x2013;88, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole Z, Maeda H. Effects of listening to preferential music on sex differences in endurance running performance. Percept Mot Skills 121: 390&#x2013;398, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutrufello PT, Benson BA, Landram MJ. The effect of music on anaerobic exercise performance and muscular endurance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 60: 486&#x2013;492, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderi M, Rahimi R, Azarbayjani MA. The effect of motivational and relaxation music on aerobic performance, rating perceived exertion and salivary cortisol in athlete males. South Afr J Res Sport, Phys Educ Recreat 31: 29&#x2013;38, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett R, Lamont A. How do gym members engage with music during exercise? Qual Res Sport Exerc Health 7: 411&#x2013;427, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett R, Lamont A. Music use in exercise: A questionnaire study. Media Psychol 20: 658&#x2013;684, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 10: 361&#x2013;374, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karageorghis CI, Cheek P, Simpson SD, Bigliassi M. Interactive effects of music tempi and intensities on grip strength and subjective affect. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 1166&#x2013;1175, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karageorghis CI, Jones L, Low DC. Relationship between exercise heart rate and music tempo preference. Res Q Exerc Sport 77: 240&#x2013;250, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karageorghis CI, Priest D-L, Terry PC, Chatzisarantis NL, Lane AM. Redesign and initial validation of an instrument to assess the motivational qualities of music in exercise: The Brunel music rating inventory-2. J Sports Sci 24: 899&#x2013;909, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karow MC, Rogers RR, Pederson JA, Williams TD, Marshall MR, Ballmann CG. Effects of preferred and nonpreferred warm-up music on exercise performance. Percept Mot Skills 127: 912&#x2013;924, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;se B. Does motivational music influence maximal bench press strength and strength endurance? Asian J Educ Train 4: 197&#x2013;200, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;se B, Atli A. Effect of different music tempos on aerobic performance and recovery. Prog Nutr 21: 922&#x2013;927, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Robertson RJ. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Cond Res 20: 252&#x2013;256, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laukka P, Quick L. Emotional and motivational uses of music in sports and exercise: A questionnaire study among athletes. Psychol Music 41: 198&#x2013;215, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KA, Hicks G, Nino-Murcia G. Validity and reliability of a scale to assess fatigue. Psychiatry Res 36: 291&#x2013;298, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meglic CE, Orman CM, Rogers RR, Williams TD, Ballmann CG. Influence of warm-up music preference on anaerobic exercise performance in Division I NCAA female athletes. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 64, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss SL, Enright K, Cushman S. The influence of music genre on explosive power, repetitions to failure and mood responses during resistance exercise. Psychol Sport Exerc 37: 128&#x2013;138, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura PM, Pereira G, Papini CB, Nakamura FY, Kokubun E. Effects of preferred and nonpreferred music on continuous cycling exercise performance. Percept Mot Skills 110: 257&#x2013;264, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nixon KM, Parker MG, Elwell CC, Pemberton AL, Rogers RR, Ballmann CG. Effects of music volume preference on endurance exercise performance. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 7: 35, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petro JL, Ferrari G, Cardozo LA, et al. Validity of rating of perceived exertion scales in relation to movement velocity and exercise intensity during resistance-exercise: A systematic review. Sports Health 17: 621&#x2013;628, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasteiro FM, Messias LHD, Scariot PPM, et al. Effects of preferred music on physiological responses, perceived exertion, and anaerobic threshold determination in an incremental running test on both sexes. PLoS One 15: e0237310, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoads KJ, Sosa SR, Rogers RR, Kopec TJ, Ballmann CG. Sex differences in response to listening to self-selected music during repeated high-intensity sprint exercise. Sexes 2: 60&#x2013;68, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva NRDS, Rizardi FG, Fujita RA, Villalba MM, Gomes MM. Preferred music genre benefits during strength tests: Increased maximal strength and strength-endurance and reduced perceived exertion. Percept Mot Skills 128: 324&#x2013;337, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stork MJ, Kwan MY, Gibala MJ, Martin Ginis KA. Music enhances performance and perceived enjoyment of sprint interval exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1052&#x2013;1060, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szmedra L, Bacharach DW. Effect of music on perceived exertion, plasma lactate, norepinephrine and cardiovascular hemodynamics during treadmill running. Int J Sports Med 19: 32&#x2013;37, 1998.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>