<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41528310</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of a Soccer-Specific and Traditional Proprioceptive Training Programs on Change of Direction, Passing Skills, and Balance in Young Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e272</StartPage><EndPage>e280</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e272-e280</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005317</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majki&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Branislav</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, University of Ni&#x161;, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stojanovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Nikola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ran&#x10d;i&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Doroteja</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aleksi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">movement efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youth</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41528310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Altmann S, Spielmann M, Engel FA, et al. Validity of single-beam timing lights at different heights. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1994&#x2013;1999, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes C, Archer DT, Hogg B, Bush M, Bradley P. The evolution of physical and technical performance parameters in the English Premier League. Int J Sports Med 35: 1095&#x2013;1100, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DR, Guskiewicz KM, Clark MA, Padua DA. Systematic review of the balance error scoring system. Sports Health 3: 287&#x2013;295, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caicedo-Parada S, Lago-Pe&#xf1;as C, Ortega-Toro E. Passing networks and tactical action in football: A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 6649, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. New York: Routledge, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellal A, Owen A, Wong DP, Krustrup P, van Exsel M, Mallo J. Technical and physical demands of small vs. large sided games in relation to playing position in elite soccer. Hum Mov Sci 31: 957&#x2013;969, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eraslan M, G&#xfc;rkan AC, Ayd&#x131;n S, et al. The effect of proprioceptive training on technical soccer skills in youth professional soccer. Medicina 61: 252, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falces-Prieto M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez FT, Garc&#xed;a-Delgado G, Silva R, Nobari H, Clemente FM. Relationship between sprint, jump, dynamic balance with the change of direction on young soccer players' performance. Sci Rep 12: 12272, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gidu DV, Badau D, Stoica M, et al. The effects of proprioceptive training on balance, strength, agility and dribbling in adolescent male soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 2028, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-V&#xed;llora S, Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez LM, Guti&#xe9;rrez-D&#xed;az D, Pastor-Vicedo JC. Tactical awareness, decision making and skill in youth soccer players (under-14 years). J Hum Sport Exerc 8: 412&#x2013;426, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Muehlbauer T, Zahner L, Gollhofer A, Kressig RW. Comparison of traditional and recent approaches in the promotion of balance and strength in older adults. Sports Med 45: 505&#x2013;521, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammami R, Chaouachi A, Makhlouf I, Granacher U, Behm DG. Associations between balance and muscle strength, power performance in male youth athletes of different maturity status. Pediatr Exerc Sci 28: 521&#x2013;534, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutlu M, Dogan O. Test-retest reliability and validity of three different agility tests for various team sports in young male athletes. Cent Eur J Sport Sci Med 22: 33&#x2013;38, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Moal E, Rue O, Ajmol A, et al. Validation of the Loughborough soccer passing test in young soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1418&#x2013;1426, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lephart SM, Pincivero DM, Giraldo JL, Fu FH. The role of proprioception in the management and rehabilitation of athletic injuries. Am J Sports Med 25: 130&#x2013;137, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL. The youth physical development model: A new approach to long-term athletic development. Strength Cond J 34: 61&#x2013;72, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado G, Gonz&#xe1;lez-V&#xed;llora S, Sarmento H, Teoldo I. Development of tactical decision-making skills in youth soccer players: Macro-and microstructure of soccer developmental activities as a discriminant of different skill levels. Int J Perform Anal Sport 20: 1072&#x2013;1091, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhlouf I, Chaouachi A, Chaouachi M, Ben Othman A, Granacher U, Behm DG. Combination of agility and plyometric training provides similar training benefits as combined balance and plyometric training in young soccer players. Front Physiol 9: 1611, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AK, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitrousis I, Bourdas DI, Kounalakis S, et al. The effect of a balance training program on the balance and technical skills of adolescent soccer players. J Sports Sci Med 22: 645&#x2013;657, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira N, Alves R, Fernandes R, et al. Effect of proprioceptive training and central stabilization in physical fitness in young soccer players. J Phys Educ Sport 17: 2406&#x2013;2412, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozinga SJ, Linder SM, Koop MM, et al. Normative performance on the balance error scoring system by youth, high school, and collegiate athletes. J Athl Train 53: 636&#x2013;645, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renshaw I, Davids K, O'Sullivan M, Maloney MA, Crowther R, McCosker C. An ecological dynamics approach to motor learning in practice: Reframing the learning and performing relationship in high performance sport. Asian J Sport Exerc Psychol 2: 18&#x2013;26, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva D, Bianchi R, Rocca F, Mamo C. Proprioceptive training and injury prevention in a professional men's basketball team: A six-year prospective study. J Strength Cond Res 30: 461&#x2013;475, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Young WB. Agility literature review: Classifications, training and testing. J Sports Sci 24: 919&#x2013;932, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sporis G, Jukic I, Milanovic L, Vucetic V. Reliability and factorial validity of agility tests for soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 24: 679&#x2013;686, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Wan B, Chen S, et al. A Systematic review of the factors that affect soccer players' short-passing ability&#x2014;based on the Loughborough Soccer Passing Test. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 16: 96, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;lmaz O, Soylu Y, Erkmen N, Kaplan T, Batalik L. Effects of proprioceptive training on sports performance: A systematic review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 16: 149, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>