<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41491263</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of velocity-based vs. percentage-based resistance training on sports performance in trainedindividuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>57</StartPage><MedlinePgn>57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">57</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01504-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This meta-analysis compared the effects of velocity-based training (VBT) and traditional percentage-based training (PBT) on athletic performance, specifically in muscle strength, jump performance, sprint performance, and change-of-direction ability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">Random-effects models in R were employed for the meta-analysis, and study quality was assessed using the Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 17 studies with 348 participants were included in the analysis. The results revealed that VBT produced small but significant improvements in jump performance (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.27, 95% CI: [0.03, 0.51], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and change-of-direction ability (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.45, 95% CI: [0.17, 0.73], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) compared to PBT. However, no significant differences were found in maximal strength (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.21, 95% CI: [-0.01, 0.43], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.064) or sprint performance (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.14, 95% CI: [-0.11, 0.39], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.269).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">VBT shows small but significant advantages over PBT in improving jump performance and change-of-direction ability. Both methods exhibit similar effects on maximal strength and sprint performance. These findings support implementing VBT for sports requiring rapid force production and directional changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The prospero registration number: CRD420251020164.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Shenyang Jianzhu University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Jianguo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Ludong University, Yantai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Donghui</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Shenyang Jianzhu University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Shenyang Jianzhu University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Ludong University, Yantai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Qunzhi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shenyang Medical College, Shenyang, China. luoqunzhi21@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Explosive power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percentage-based training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Velocity-based training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41491263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01504-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01504-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bright TE, Handford MJ, Mundy P, Lake J, Theis N, Hughes JD. Building for the future: A systematic review of the effects of eccentric resistance training on measures of physical performance in youth athletes. Sports Med. 2023;53(6):1219&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01843-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37097414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zouita A, Darragi M, Bousselmi M, Sghaeir Z, Clark CC, Hackney AC, et al. The effects of resistance training on muscular fitness, muscle morphology, and body composition in elite female athletes: A systematic review. Sports Med. 2023;53(9):1709&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01859-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Prieske O, Moran J, Negra Y, Attia A, Granacher U. Effects of resistance training on change-of-direction speed in youth and young physically active and athletic adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50:1483&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01293-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7376516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky VM, Kraemer WJ, Fry AC. Science and practice of strength training: Human kinetics; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovanovi&#x107; M, Flanagan EP. Researched applications of velocity based strength training. J Aust Strength Cond. 2014;22(2):58&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Feng S, Peng R, Li H. The role of velocity-based training (VBT) in enhancing athletic performance in trained individuals: A meta-analysis of controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(15):9252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19159252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi C, Vasiljevic I, Manojlovic M, Trivic T, Ranisavljev M, Stajer V et al. Optimizing strength training protocols in young females: A comparative study of velocity-based and percentage-based training programs. Heliyon. 2024;10(9):e30644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11089354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Hornsby WG, Stone MH. Training for muscular strength: methods for monitoring and adjusting training intensity. Sports Med. 2021;51(10):2051&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01488-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34101157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Torres-Ronda L. The implementation of velocity-based training paradigm for team sports: framework, technologies, practical recommendations and challenges. Sports. 2021;9(4):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9040047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33808302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Mann B, Banyard H, McLaren S, Scott T, Garcia-Ramos A. Velocity-based training: from theory to application. Strength Conditioning J. 2021;43(2):31&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banyard HG, Tufano JJ, Delgado J, Thompson SW, Nosaka K. Comparison of the effects of velocity-based training methods and traditional 1RM-percent-based training prescription on acute kinetic and kinematic variables. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):246&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30080424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orange ST, Metcalfe JW, Robinson A, Applegarth MJ, Liefeith A. Effects of in-season velocity-versus percentage-based training in academy rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;15(4):554&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held S, Hecksteden A, Meyer T, Donath L. Improved strength and recovery after velocity-based training: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(8):1185&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu T, Peng W, Yi M, Chen N, Han Y, Huang J, et al. The effects of Velocity-Versus Percentage-Based resistance training on lower limb explosive power and footwork movement speed in elite university badminton players. Appl Sci. 2025;15(5):2434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15052434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhao X, Wu H. The impact of Velocity-Based strength training on lower extremity explosiveness in butterfly Swimmers. Advances in education. Humanit Social Sci Res. 2024;9(1):92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, Cuadrado-Pe&#xf1;afiel V, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Capelo-Ram&#xed;rez F, Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda LM, et al. Differences between adjusted vs. non-adjusted loads in velocity-based training: consequences for strength training control and programming. PeerJ. 2021;9:e10942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33828909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao K-F, Wang X-X, Han M-Y, Li L-L, Nassis GP, Li Y-M. Effects of velocity based training vs. traditional 1RM percentage-based training on improving strength, jump, linear sprint and change of direction speed performance: A systematic review with meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(11):e0259790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0259790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8601436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34793506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orange ST, Hritz A, Pearson L, Jeffries O, Jones TW, Steele J. Comparison of the effects of velocity-based vs. traditional resistance training methods on adaptations in strength, power, and sprint speed: A systematic review, meta-analysis, and quality of evidence appraisal. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(11):1220&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2022.2059320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35380511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held S, Speer K, Rappelt L, Wicker P, Donath L. The effectiveness of traditional vs. velocity-based strength training on explosive and maximal strength performance: A network meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;13:926972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.926972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9399433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36035476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing Z, Xiali X, Yang W, et al. Effect of Velocity-based training on the maximal strength and explosive power in athletes: A meta analysis. J Chengdu Sport Univ. 2023;49(3):98&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Feng S, et al. The effect of various training variables on developing muscle strength in velocity-based training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Med. 2023;44(12):857&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2095-8254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37196672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale. J Physiotherapy. 2020;66(1):59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31521549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107; E, Risti&#x107; V, McMaster DT, Milanovi&#x107; Z. Effect of plyometric training on vertical jump performance in female athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:975&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0634-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction&#x2014;GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):383&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Alonso-Coello P, Guyatt GH, et al. GRADE guidelines: 19. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences&#x2014;Risk of bias and indirectness. J Clin Epidemiol. 2019;111:94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29452223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banyard HG, Tufano JJ, Weakley JJ, Wu S, Jukic I, Nosaka K. Superior changes in jump, sprint, and change-of-direction performance but not maximal strength following 6 weeks of velocity-based training compared with 1-repetition-maximum percentage-based training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;16(2):232&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32871553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F. Effects of 6-week Velocity-based strength training on lower limb explosive power in college sprinters. Beijing Sport University; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorrell HF, Smith MF, Gee TI. Comparison of velocity-based and traditional percentage-based loading methods on maximal strength and power adaptations. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2020;34(1):46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30946276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong M. The effects of Velocity-based training on lower limb maximal strength and explosive power of female volleyball athletes. Beijing Sport University; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo-P&#xe9;rez A, Alejo LB, Valenzuela PL, Gil-Cabrera J, Talavera E, Lucia A, et al. Traditional versus velocity-based resistance training in competitive female cyclists: a randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2021;12:586113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.586113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7947617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekulovi&#x107; V, Jezdimirovi&#x107;-Stojanovi&#x107; T, Andri&#x107; N, Elizondo-Donado A, Martin D, Miki&#x107; M, et al. Effects of In-Season Velocity-Based vs. Traditional resistance training in elite youth male soccer players. Appl Sci. 2024;14(20):9192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14209192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Y, Ge R, Zhu Z. The effect of 6-week velocity-based training on strength quality in adolescent Sanda athletes. TIYU SHIYOU. 2024;47(3):19&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasiljevic I, Manojlovic M, Bianco A, Maksimovic N, Trivic T, Drid P. Effects of velocity-based training versus percentage-based training programs on neuromuscular performances and markers of muscle damage in young males: a randomized controlled trial. Med Dello Sport. 2024;77(2):183&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhihui W. The effect of velocity-based strength training on the lower limbs power-related athletic abilities of college basketball athletes by back squat. Wuhan: Wuhan Sports University; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Liang X, Huang W, Ding S, Li G, Zhang W, et al. The effects of velocity-based versus percentage-based resistance training on athletic performances in sport-collegiate female basketball players. Front Physiol. 2023a;13:992655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.992655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36703922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Li D, He J, Liang X, Li D, Song W, et al. editors. Effects of velocity-based versus percentage-based resistance training on explosive neuromuscular adaptations and anaerobic power in sport-college female basketball players. Healthcare; 2023b: MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9956169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ. Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 2019:143&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP et al. Introduction to meta-analysis: Wiley 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences: routledge 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. Autoregulated resistance training: does velocity-based training represent the future? Strength Conditioning J. 2019;41(4):34&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Intended rather than actual movement velocity determines velocity-specific training response. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74(1):359&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.74.1.359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8444715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Feng S, Li H. The effect of velocity loss on strength development and related training efficiency: A dose&#x2013;response meta&#x2013;analysis. Healthcare. 2023;11:337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11030337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36766912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x142;odarczyk M, Adamus P, Zieli&#x144;ski J, Kantanista A. Effects of velocity-based training on strength and power in elite athletes&#x2014;a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(10):5257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18105257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34069249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, et al. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(6):1091&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3346-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4875063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26941023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatfield DL, Kraemer WJ, Spiering BA, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Volek JS, Shimano T, Spreuwenberg LP, Silvestre R, Vingren JL, Fragala MS, G&#xf3;mez AL. The impact of velocity of movement on performance factors in resistance exercise. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2006;20(4):760&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baena-Mar&#xed;n M, Rojas-Jaramillo A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Santamar&#xed;a J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Petro JL, Kreider RB, Bonilla DA. Velocity-based resistance training on 1-RM, jump and sprint performance: A systematic review of clinical trials. Sports. 2022;10(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports10010008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, Reyes A, Tran TT, et al. Increases in lower-body strength transfer positively to sprint performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44(12):1693&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0227-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos&#x2019; Santos T, Thomas C, Jones PA, Comfort P. Mechanical determinants of faster change of direction speed performance in male athletes. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2017;31(3):696&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27379954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Newton RU, Nimphius S. Neuromuscular strategies contributing to faster multidirectional agility performance. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2015;25(4):629&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2015.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25956548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>