<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41577337</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5381</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and muscle strength changes in older adults: Risks beyond muscle mass reductions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bph.70355</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gastric inhibitory polypeptide (GIP)/Glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) receptor agonists are increasingly prescribed for the management of obesity and type 2 diabetes, yet research pertinent to their effects on muscle health is limited. Considering the central role of muscle strength as a sarcopenia component, this article summarizes emerging evidence on insulin-based therapies and muscle strength. Short-to-mid-term trials of semaglutide or liraglutide in adults with obesity have shown statistically preserved handgrip strength despite reductions in lean soft tissue mass, suggesting that muscle strength may not decline proportionally to weight loss. Likewise, tirzepatide combined with resistance and aerobic training in young men may not confer additional strength benefits beyond exercise alone. In contrast, longitudinal and retrospective research in older adults with type 2 diabetes have reported reductions in handgrip strength and accelerated sarcopenia with prolonged semaglutide use, raising concerns about potentially detrimental effects on neuromuscular health. Collectively, these findings indicate that lean soft tissue loss is not a reliable predictor of muscle strength change following GIP/GLP-1 agonists. While shorter term studies suggest relative preservation, longer term data in older adults point to possible risk of muscle strength decline. Future randomized, double-blinded trials with adequate sample sizes and longer follow-ups are warranted, particularly in older populations who are at an increased risk of sarcopenia. Their findings could support the integration of muscle strength outcomes into clinical monitoring and trial design to ensure that GIP/GLP-1 agonist-based strategies may not compromise muscle strength in these populations during weight loss.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). British Journal of Pharmacology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prokopidis</LastName><ForeName>Konstantinos</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Musculoskeletal Ageing and Science, Institute of Life Course and Medical Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GLP&#x2010;1 receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41577337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.70355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alexander, S. P. H., Christopoulos, A., Davenport, A. P., Kelly, E., Mathie, A. A., Peters, J. A., Veale, E. L., Armstrong, J. F., Faccenda, E., Harding, S. D., Davies, J. A., Abbracchio, M. P., Abraham, G., Agoulnik, A., Alexander, W., Al&#x2010;Hosaini, K., B&#xe4;ck, M., Baker, J. G., Barnes, N. M., &#x2026; Ye, R. D. (2023). The Concise Guide to PHARMACOLOGY 2023/24: G protein&#x2010;coupled receptors. British Journal of Pharmacology, 180(Suppl 2), S23&#x2013;S144. https://doi.org/10.1111/bph.16177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfaris, N., Waldrop, S., Johnson, V., Boaventura, B., Kendrick, K., &amp; Stanford, F. C. (2024). GLP&#x2010;1 single, dual, and triple receptor agonists for treating type 2 diabetes and obesity: A narrative review. EClinicalMedicine, 75, 102782. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102782</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherzadeh&#x2010;Rahmani, B., Marzetti, E., Karami, E., Campbell, B. I., Fakourian, A., Haghighi, A. H., Mousavi, S. H., Heinrich, K. M., Brazzi, L., Jung, F., Baker, J. S., &amp; Patel, D. I. (2024). Tirzepatide and exercise training in obesity. Clinical Hemorheology and Microcirculation, 87, 465&#x2013;480. https://doi.org/10.3233/CH-242134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart, C., Alcazar, J., Aprahamian, I., Batsis, J. A., Yamada, Y., Prado, C. M., Reginster, J. Y., Sanchez&#x2010;Rodriguez, D., Lim, W. S., Sim, M., von Haehling, S., Woo, J., Duque, G., &amp; Global Leadership Initiative in Sarcopenia (GLIS) group. (2025). Health outcomes of sarcopenia: A consensus report by the outcome working group of the global leadership initiative in sarcopenia (GLIS). Aging Clinical and Experimental Research, 37, 100. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-025-02995-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal, H., Bays, H., Czernichow, S., Udd&#xe9;n Hemmingsson, J., Hjelmes&#xe6;th, J., Hoffmann Morville, T., Koroleva, A., Skov Neergaard, J., V&#xe9;lez S&#xe1;nchez, P., Wharton, S., Wizert, A., Kristensen, L. E., &amp; STEP 9 Study Group. (2024). Once&#x2010;weekly semaglutide in persons with obesity and knee osteoarthritis. New England Journal of Medicine, 391, 1573&#x2013;1583. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2403664</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, T. M., Vasquez, L., Serra, M. C., Robbins, R., Stepanenko, A., Brown, K., Barrus, H., Campos, A., Espinoza, S. E., &amp; Musi, N. (2024). Effect of semaglutide on physical function, body composition, and biomarkers of aging in older adults with overweight and insulin resistance: Protocol for an open&#x2010;labeled randomized controlled trial. JMIR Research Protocols, 13, e62667. https://doi.org/10.2196/62667</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, M. J., Bergenstal, R., Bode, B., Kushner, R. F., Lewin, A., Skj&#xf8;th, T. V., Andreasen, A. H., Jensen, C. B., DeFronzo, R., &amp; NN8022&#x2010;1922 Study Group. (2015). Efficacy of liraglutide for weight loss among patients with type 2 diabetes: The SCALE diabetes randomized clinical trial. Jama, 314, 687&#x2013;699. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.9676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman, R., Jensterle, M., Horvat, S., Lezaic, L., Snoj, Z., Pusnik, I., Goricar, K., C&#xf6;r, A., Pusnik, L., Mlacnik, V., Hanzelic, L., &amp; Janez, A. (2025). Effect of tirzepatide&#x2010;induced weight loss on adipose tissue in obesity: Rationale and design of the randomized placebo&#x2010;controlled Tirzepatide Brown and Beige adipose tissue activation (TABFAT) trial. Trials, 26, 300. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-025-09045-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter Gibble, T., Cao, D., Zhang, X. M., Xavier, N. A., Poon, J. L., &amp; Fitch, A. (2025). Tirzepatide was associated with improved health&#x2010;related quality of life in adults with obesity or overweight and type 2 diabetes: Results from the phase 3 SURMOUNT&#x2010;2 trial. Diabetes Therapy, 16, 977&#x2013;991. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13300-025-01723-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorsal, A., Kistorp, C., Holmager, P., Tougaard, R. S., Nielsen, R., H&#xe4;nselmann, A., Nilsson, B., M&#xf8;ller, J. E., Hjort, J., Rasmussen, J., Boesgaard, T. W., Schou, M., Videbaek, L., Gustafsson, I., Flyvbjerg, A., Wiggers, H., &amp; Tarnow, L. (2017). Effect of liraglutide, a glucagon&#x2010;like peptide&#x2010;1 analogue, on left ventricular function in stable chronic heart failure patients with and without diabetes (LIVE)&#x2014;A multicentre, double&#x2010;blind, randomised, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. European Journal of Heart Failure, 19, 69&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1002/ejhf.657</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakasis, P., Patoulias, D., Fragakis, N., &amp; Mantzoros, C. S. (2025). Effect of glucagon&#x2010;like peptide&#x2010;1 receptor agonists and co&#x2010;agonists on body composition: Systematic review and network meta&#x2010;analysis. Metabolism, 164, 156113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk, B., Cawthon, P. M., Arai, H., &#xc1;vila&#x2010;Funes, J. A., Barazzoni, R., Bhasin, S., Binder, E. F., Bruyere, O., Cederholm, T., Chen, L. K., Cooper, C., Duque, G., Fielding, R. A., Guralnik, J., Kiel, D. P., Landi, F., Reginster, J. Y., Sayer, A. A., Visser, M., &#x2026; Global Leadership Initiative in Sarcopenia (GLIS) group. (2024). The conceptual definition of sarcopenia: Delphi consensus from the global leadership initiative in sarcopenia (GLIS). Age and Ageing, 53, afae052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolotkin, R., Fujioka, K., Wolden, M., Brett, J., &amp; Bjorner, J. (2016). Improvements in health&#x2010;related quality of life with liraglutide 3.0 mg compared with placebo in weight management. Clinical Obesity, 6, 233&#x2013;242. https://doi.org/10.1111/cob.12146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laudisio, A., Giovannini, S., Finamore, P., Loreti, C., Vannetti, F., Coraci, D., Incalzi, R. A., Zuccal, G., Macchi, C., Padua, L., &amp; Mugello Study Working Group. (2020). Muscle strength is related to mental and physical quality of life in the oldest old. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 89, 104109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok, J., Adeleke, M. O., Brown, A., Magee, C. G., Firman, C., Makahamadze, C., Jassil, F. C., Marvasti, P., Carnemolla, A., Devalia, K., Fakih, N., Elkalaawy, M., Pucci, A., Jenkinson, A., Adamo, M., Omar, R. Z., Batterham, R. L., &amp; Makaronidis, J. (2023). Safety and efficacy of liraglutide, 3.0 mg, once daily vs placebo in patients with poor weight loss following metabolic surgery: The BARI&#x2010;OPTIMISE randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surgery, 158, 1003&#x2013;1011. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamasurg.2023.2930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaisar, R., Khan, I. U., Rehman, A., Iqbal, M. S., Ahmad, F., &amp; Karim, A. (2026). Semaglutide use is associated with neuromuscular junction degradation in older adults with type II diabetes mellitus. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology, 92(1), 149&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Q., Zhi, L., &amp; Liu, H. (2025). Semaglutide therapy and accelerated sarcopenia in older adults with type 2 diabetes: A 24&#x2010;month retrospective cohort study. Drug Design, Development and Therapy, 19, 5645&#x2013;5652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawamura, T., Karashima, S., Ohmori, A., Kometani, M., &amp; Yoneda, T. (2025). Impacts of tirzepatide on older patients with diminished &#x3b2;&#x2010;cell function and dementia. Geriatrics &amp; Gerontology International, 25, 630&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap, L. A., Van Schoor, N. M., Lips, P., &amp; Visser, M. (2018). Associations of sarcopenia definitions, and their components, with the incidence of recurrent falling and fractures: The longitudinal aging study Amsterdam. Journals of Gerontology: Series a, 73, 1199&#x2013;1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, D., de Courten, B., &amp; Ebeling, P. R. (2016). Sarcopenia: A potential cause and consequence of type 2 diabetes in Australia's ageing population? Medical Journal of Australia, 205, 329&#x2013;333. https://doi.org/10.5694/mja16.00446</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S., Butler, J., Borlaug, B. A., Davies, M., Kitzman, D. W., Shah, S. J., Petrie, M. C., Barros, E., R&#xf6;nnb&#xe4;ck, C., Vestergaard, L. S., Schou, M., Ezekowitz, J. A., Sharma, K., Patel, S., Chinnakondepalli, K. M., Kosiborod, M. N., &amp; STEP&#x2010;HFpEF Trial Committees and Investigators. (2024). Efficacy of semaglutide by sex in obesity&#x2010;related heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: STEP&#x2010;HFpEF trials. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 84, 773&#x2013;785. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.06.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpe, S., Lisco, G., Racaniello, D., Fanelli, M., Colaianni, V., Vozza, A., Triggiani, V., Sabb&#xe0;, C., Tortorella, C., De Pergola, G., &amp; Piazzolla, G. (2022). Once&#x2010;weekly semaglutide induces an early improvement in body composition in patients with type 2 diabetes: A 26&#x2010;week prospective real&#x2010;life study. Nutrients, 14, 2414. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14122414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, J., Ding, X.&#x2010;Y., Zhang, W., Zhang, J., Zhang, Y.&#x2010;S., Li, Z.&#x2010;M., Xia, N., &amp; Liang, Y. Z. (2023). Clinical effectiveness of semaglutide on weight loss, body composition, and muscle strength in Chinese adults. European Review for Medical &amp; Pharmacological Sciences, 27, 9908&#x2013;9915. https://doi.org/10.26355/eurrev_202310_34169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, S., &amp; Larsson, S. C. (2023). Epidemiology of sarcopenia: Prevalence, risk factors, and consequences. Metabolism, 144, 155533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Ding, X., &amp; Luo, M. (2024). The association between sarcopenia and functional disability in older adults. Journal of Nutrition, Health and Aging, 28, 100016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>