<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41874531</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The External Game Demands of Professional, Male Basketball Players According to Playing Position and Playing Role: A Multiseason Analysis in the Australian National Basketball League.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>460</StartPage><EndPage>467</EndPage><MedlinePgn>460-467</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005330</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shirley, SK, Scanlan, AT, Guy, JH, Bartlett, RJ, Bowe, SJ, and Elsworthy, N. The external game demands of professional, male basketball players according to playing position and playing role: A multiseason analysis in the Australian National Basketball League. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 460-467, 2026-This observational study provides a contemporary and novel analysis of the external game demands experienced by professional, male basketball players competing in the Australian National Basketball League (NBL) and compares these demands between playing roles and playing positions. Twenty-two professional, male basketball players (age: 27.0 &#xb1; 3.3 years) were monitored over 2 competitive seasons between 2021 and 2023 using microsensor technology (T6; Catapult Sports). Players were categorized according to playing role (starting, bench) and playing position (frontcourt, backcourt). Accumulated (total) and relative (per minute) external game demands were calculated for PlayerLoad in addition to total and high-intensity inertial movement analysis variables during live playing time. External game demands were quantified as estimated marginal means (95% confidence limits) and compared between playing roles and playing positions via linear mixed model and Cohen's d effect size analyses. Significance was set at p &#x2264; 0.05. Starting players experienced higher accumulated external game demands than bench players across most variables (p &lt; 0.05, d = 0.30-1.87), whereas relative external game demands were similar between playing roles (p &gt; 0.05, d = 0.01-0.44). Likewise, external game demands were comparable between playing positions across variables (p &gt; 0.05, d = 0.03-1.15). These findings demonstrate that only accumulated external game demands differ between playing roles, whereas homogeneity in external game demands appear to exist between generalized playing positions. These foundation data in the Australian NBL may inform training and recovery protocols among end-users working in this competition to ensure players are optimally prepared for competition according to their specific requirements.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shirley</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3681-8827</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Queensland University, School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cairns Taipans Basketball Club, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scanlan</LastName><ForeName>Aaron T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0750-8697</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Queensland University, School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guy</LastName><ForeName>Joshua H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3000-2747</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Queensland University, School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cairns Taipans Basketball Club, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartlett</LastName><ForeName>Rogan J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0672-0407</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Queensland University, School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cairns Taipans Basketball Club, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowe</LastName><ForeName>Steven J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington, New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elsworthy</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5223-6803</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Queensland University, School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Elevate Scholarship</GrantID><Agency>Cairns Taipans Basketball Club</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Commonwealth Governments Research Training Program</GrantID><Agency>Australian Government</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Elevate Scholarship</GrantID><Agency>Cairns Taipans Basketball Club</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Commonwealth Governments Research Training Program</GrantID><Agency>Australian Government</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001490" MajorTopicYN="Y">Basketball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003163" MajorTopicYN="N">Competitive Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bench</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microsensors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">starter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team sport</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41874531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202604000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bianchi F, Facchinetti T, Zuccolotto P. Role revolution: Towards a new meaning of positions in basketball. Electron J Appl Stat Anal 10: 712&#x2013;734, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown FSA, Fields JB, Jagim AR, Baker RE, Jones MT. Analysis of in-season external load and sport performance in women's collegiate basketball. J Strength Cond Res 38: 318&#x2013;324, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger J, Henze A-S, Voit T, Latzel R, Moser O, Christopher M. Athlete monitoring systems in elite men's basketball: Challenges, recommendations, and future perspectives. Transl Sports Med 2024: 6326566, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Pillitteri G, Palucci Vieira LH, Rabbani A, Zmijewski P, Beato M. Balancing the load: A narrative review with methodological implications of compensatory training strategies for non-starting soccer players. Biol Sport 41: 173&#x2013;185, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson L, McErlain-Naylor SA, Devereux G, Beato M. Practitioner usage, applications, and understanding of wearable GPS and accelerometer technology in team sports. J Strength Cond Res 38: e373-e382, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Stanton R, Sargent C, O'Grady CJ, Scanlan AT. The impact of contextual factors on game demands in starting, semiprofessional, male basketball players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 450&#x2013;456, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Conte D, Stanton R, McLean B, Scanlan AT. The application of accelerometer-derived moving averages to quantify peak demands in basketball: A comparison of sample duration, playing role, and session type. J Strength Cond Res 35: S58&#x2013;S63, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a F, Vazquez-Guerrero J, Castellano J, Casals M, Schelling X. Differences in physical demands between game quarters and playing positions on professional basketball players during official competition. J Sports Sci Med 19: 256&#x2013;263, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a F, Fern&#xe1;ndez D, Mart&#xed;n L. Relationship between game load and player's performance in professional basketball. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 1473&#x2013;1479, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf2;mez M-&#xc1;, Lorenzo A, Ortega E, Sampaio J, Ib&#xe0;&#xf1;ez S-J. Game related statistics discriminating between starters and nonstarters players in Women's National Basketball Association league (WNBA). J Sports Sci Med 8: 278&#x2013;283, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutson CW, Russell JL, Strack D, Coutts AJ, McLean BD. External load fluctuations across an amateur athletic union basketball season. J Strength Cond Res 38: 592&#x2013;598, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay L, Sawczuk T, Jones B, Darrall-Jones J, Clark A, Whitehead S. The reliability of a commonly used (Catapult Vector S7) microtechnology unit to detect movement characteristics used in court-based sports. J Sports Sci 43: 555&#x2013;564, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandic R, Jakovljevic S, Erculj F, Strumbelj E. Trends in NBA and EuroLeague basketball: Analysis and comparison of statistical data from 2000 to 2017. PLoS One 14: e0223524, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newans T, Bellinger P, Drovandi C, Buxton S, Minahan C. The utility of mixed models in sport science: A call for further adoption in longitudinal data sets. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 1289&#x2013;1295, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolella DP, Torres-Ronda L, Saylor KJ, Schelling X, Ardig&#xf2; LP. Validity and reliability of an accelerometer-based player tracking device. PLoS One 13: e0191823, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer J, Wundersitz D, Bini R, Kingsley M. Effect of player role and competition level on player demands in basketball. Sports 9: 38, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson J, Rayner R, Carey DL, O'Grady M, Talpey SW. The influence of contextual variables on training load prescription in basketball: An example of a professional Australian men's basketball team. J Hum Kinet 96: 177&#x2013;186, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernigoni M, Ferioli D, Butautas R, La Torre A, Conte D. Assessing the external load associated with high-intensity activities recorded during official basketball games. Front Psychol 12: 668194, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piedra A, Pe&#xf1;a J, Caparros T. Monitoring training loads in basketball: A narrative review and practical guide for coaches and practitioners. Strength Cond J 43: 12&#x2013;35, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power CJ, Fox JL, Dalbo VJ, Scanlan AT. External and internal load variables encountered during training and games in female basketball players according to playing level and playing position: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 8: 107&#x2013;125, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell JL, McLean BD, Impellizzeri FM, Strack DS, Coutts AJ. Measuring physical demands in basketball: An explorative systematic review of practices. Sports Med 51: 81&#x2013;112, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell JL, McLean BD, Stolp S, Strack D, Coutts AJ. Quantifying training and game demands of a National Basketball Association season. Front Psychol 12: 793216, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar H, Garc&#xed;a F, Svilar L, Castellano J. Physical demands in three different basketball competitions played by the same under-18 players. Montenegrin J Sports Sci Med 10: 59&#x2013;64, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio J, Janeira M, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez S, Lorenzo A. Discriminant analysis of game-related statistics between basketball guards, forwards and centres in three professional leagues. Eur J Sport Sci 6: 173&#x2013;178, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan AT, Dascombe B, Reaburn P. A comparison of the activity demands of elite and sub-elite Australian men's basketball competition. J Sports Sci 29: 1153&#x2013;1160, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan AT, Tucker PS, Dascombe BJ, Berkelmans DM, Hiskens MI, Dalbo VJ. Fluctuations in activity demands across game quarters in professional and semiprofessional male basketball. J Strength Cond Res 29: 3006&#x2013;3015, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan TA, Teramoto M, Delforce M, Dalbo JV. Do better things come in smaller packages? Reducing game duration slows game pace and alters statistics associated with winning in basketball. Int J Perform Anal Sport 16: 157&#x2013;170, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Lockie RG, Knight TJ, Clark AC, Janse de Jonge XAK. A comparison of methods to quantify the in-season training load of professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 195&#x2013;202, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirley SK, Bartlett RJ, Scanlan AT, Guy JH, Bowe SJ, Elsworthy N. Anthropometric and jump profiles according to player position in a professional, male basketball team competing in the Australian National Basketball League. J Austr Strength Cond 33: 6&#x2013;12, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107; E, Stojiljkovi&#x107; N, Scanlan AT, Dalbo V, Berkelmans D, Milanovi&#x107; Z. The activity demands and physiological responses encountered during basketball match-play: A systematic review. Sports Med 48: 111&#x2013;135, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Beanland E, Whitehead S, Sweeting A, Clubb J. Tracking systems in team sports: A narrative review of applications of the data and sport specific analysis. Sports Med Open 8: 15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuttle MC, Power CJ, Dalbo VJ, Scanlan AT. Intensity zones and intensity thresholds used to quantify external load in competitive basketball: A systematic review. Sports Med 54: 2571&#x2013;2596, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Suarez-Arrones L, Casamichana G&#xf3;mez D, Rodas G. Comparing external total load, acceleration and deceleration outputs in elite basketball players across positions during match play. Kinesiology 50: 228&#x2013;234, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Jones B, Fernandez-Valdes B, Moras G, Reche X, Sampaio J. Physical demands of elite basketball during an official U18 international tournament. J Sports Sci 37: 2530&#x2013;2537, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>