<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41922495</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2399-3642</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Communications biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Commun Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>GCNPath: introspecting drug response prediction with pathway-guided graph convolution networks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s42003-026-09957-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Drug response prediction (DRP), accounting for the diverse biological characteristics of cancer types that affect sensitivity or resistance to treatment, is crucial for anticancer drug selection and discovery. Although numerous deep learning models for DRP have been developed, it has not been investigated whether these models can maintain reliable predictive power when applied to omics datasets not used for training, which is crucial for real-world applications. Moreover, they have not been rigorously examined through systematic benchmark tests to investigate the relationships between model architecture and performance. We present a new model, GCNPath, that exploits both graph convolution network (GCN) architectures and pathway-based feature reduction of gene expression data, which have previously been shown to improve DRP model performance. In comprehensive benchmark tests utilizing multiple cell omics platforms, GCNPath shows robust and competitive performances compared with state-of-the-art models including prediction of unseen drugs and the ability to overcome batch effects across various RNA datasets. This study demonstrates the validity of the pathway-level GCN model in DRP and suggests directions for developing DRP models with improved adaptability to diverse and heterogeneous datasets and enhanced usability for practical applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Hyeon Jun</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1823-4705</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Science, Dongguk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Minho</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0168-9546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Science, Dongguk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea. MinhoLee@dgu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RS-2022-NR070510</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RS-2025-18732993</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Commun Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101719179</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2399-3642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41922495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-026-09957-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s42003-026-09957-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dagogo-Jack, I. &amp; Shaw, A. T. Tumour heterogeneity and resistance to cancer therapies. Nat. Rev. Clin. Oncol. 15, 81&#x2013;94 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, W. et al. Genomics of Drug Sensitivity in Cancer (GDSC): A resource for therapeutic biomarker discovery in cancer cells. Nucleic Acids Res. 41, D955&#x2013;D961 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barretina, J. et al. The Cancer Cell Line Encyclopedia enables predictive modelling of anticancer drug sensitivity. Nature 483, 603&#x2013;607 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam, G. et al. Machine learning approaches to drug response prediction: challenges and recent progress. NPJ Precis. Oncol. 4, 19 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firoozbakht, F., Yousefi, B. &amp; Schwikowski, B. An overview of machine learning methods for monotherapy drug response prediction. Brief. Bioinforma. 23, bbab408 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, B. et al. A systematic assessment of deep learning methods for drug response prediction: From in vitro to clinical applications. Brief Bioinform 24, https://doi.org/10.1093/bib/bbac605 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partin, A. et al. Deep learning methods for drug response prediction in cancer: Predominant and emerging trends. Front Med (Lausanne) 10, 1086097 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, P., Li, H., Li, S. &amp; Leung, K. S. Improving prediction of phenotypic drug response on cancer cell lines using deep convolutional network. BMC Bioinforma. 20, 408 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J. et al. Graph neural networks: A review of methods and applications. AI open 1, 57&#x2013;81 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T., Nguyen, G. T. T., Nguyen, T. &amp; Le, D. H. Graph Convolutional Networks for Drug Response Prediction. IEEE/ACM Trans. Comput Biol. Bioinform 19, 146&#x2013;154 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y. et al. TGSA: protein-protein association-based twin graph neural networks for drug response prediction with similarity augmentation. Bioinformatics 38, 461&#x2013;468 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin, J., Piao, Y., Bang, D., Kim, S. &amp; Jo, K. DRPreter: Interpretable anticancer drug response prediction using knowledge-guided graph neural networks and transformer. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 23, https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms232213919 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manica, M. et al. Toward explainable anticancer compound sensitivity prediction via multimodal attention-based convolutional encoders. Mol. Pharm. 16, 4797&#x2013;4806 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, I. &amp; Nam, H. HiDRA: Hierarchical network for drug response prediction with attention. J. Chem. Inf. Model 61, 3858&#x2013;3867 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, Y., Guo, J., Philip Chen, C. &amp; Meng, X.-B. iBT-Net: An incremental broad transformer network for cancer drug response prediction. Brief. Bioinforma. 24, bbad256 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, X., Zhu, C., Zhong, F. &amp; Liu, L. TransCDR: A deep learning model for enhancing the generalizability of drug activity prediction through transfer learning and multimodal data fusion. BMC Biol. 22, 227 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaulton, A. et al. ChEMBL: A large-scale bioactivity database for drug discovery. Nucleic Acids Res 40, D1100&#x2013;D1107 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi-Noghabi, H., Zolotareva, O., Collins, C. C. &amp; Ester, M. MOLI: Multi-omics late integration with deep neural networks for drug response prediction. Bioinformatics 35, i501&#x2013;i509 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koras, K. et al. Feature selection strategies for drug sensitivity prediction. Sci. Rep. 10, 9377 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chawla, S. et al. Gene expression based inference of cancer drug sensitivity. Nat. Commun. 13, 5680 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Y.C. &amp; Gottlieb, A. Explainable drug sensitivity prediction through cancer pathway enrichment. Sci. Rep. 11, 3128 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanzelmann, S., Castelo, R. &amp; Guinney, J. GSVA: Gene set variation analysis for microarray and RNA-seq data. BMC Bioinforma. 14, 7 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menche, J. et al. Uncovering disease-disease relationships through the incomplete interactome. Science 347, 1257601 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlichtkrull, M. et al. in The Semantic Web: 15th International Conference, ESWC 2018, Heraklion, Crete, Greece, June 3&#x2013;7, 2018, Proceedings 15. 593-607 (Springer).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bento, A. P. et al. An open source chemical structure curation pipeline using RDKit. J. Cheminformatics 12, 1&#x2013;16 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk, H., Ozkirimli, E. &amp; &#xd6;zg&#xfc;r, A. A novel methodology on distributed representations of proteins using their interacting ligands. Bioinformatics 34, i295&#x2013;i303 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes-Ciriano, I. et al. Improved large-scale prediction of growth inhibition patterns using the NCI60 cancer cell line panel. Bioinformatics 32, 85&#x2013;95 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello, J. C. et al. A community effort to assess and improve drug sensitivity prediction algorithms. Nat. Biotechnol. 32, 1202&#x2013;1212 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbie, D. A. et al. Systematic RNA interference reveals that oncogenic KRAS-driven cancers require TBK1. Nature 462, 108&#x2013;112 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foroutan, M. et al. Single sample scoring of molecular phenotypes. BMC Bioinforma. 19, 404 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhuva, D. D., Cursons, J. &amp; Davis, M. J. Stable gene expression for normalisation and single-sample scoring. Nucleic Acids Res. 48, e113&#x2013;e113 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Jenkins, D. F., Manimaran, S. &amp; Johnson, W. E. Alternative empirical Bayes models for adjusting for batch effects in genomic studies. BMC Bioinforma. 19, 1&#x2013;15 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang, Q. et al. Molecular subtypes of colorectal cancer in the era of precision oncotherapy: Current inspirations and future challenges. Cancer Med. 13, e70041 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, X., Cheng, H., Bai, Z. &amp; Li, J. Breast cancer cell line classification and its relevance with breast tumor subtyping. J. Cancer 8, 3131 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megyesfalvi, Z. et al. Clinical insights into small cell lung cancer: Tumor heterogeneity, diagnosis, therapy, and future directions. CA Cancer J. Clin. 73, 620&#x2013;652 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q. et al. Proteogenomic characterization of small cell lung cancer identifies biological insights and subtype-specific therapeutic strategies. Cell 187, 184&#x2013;203. e128 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo, O. E. et al. Fibroblast growth factor-2 induces translational regulation of Bcl-XL and Bcl-2 via a MEK-dependent pathway: Correlation with resistance to etoposide-induced apoptosis. J. Biol. Chem. 277, 12040&#x2013;12046 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Tang, C., Luo, H., Wang, H. &amp; Zhou, X. Shp2 confers cisplatin resistance in small cell lung cancer via an AKT-mediated increase in CA916798. Oncotarget 8, 23664 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, A., Lee, N., Moroney, J., Fleming, G. &amp; Challa, S. Exploring the mechanisms of resistance to trastuzumab-deruxtecan in endometrial cancer cells. Gynecol. Oncol. 190, S244 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marengo, B. et al. p38MAPK inhibition: a new combined approach to reduce neuroblastoma resistance under etoposide treatment. Cell Death Dis. 4, e589&#x2013;e589 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, X. -l et al. Salvianolic acid A reverses cisplatin resistance in lung cancer A549 cells by targeting c-met and attenuating Akt/mTOR pathway. J. Pharmacol. Sci. 135, 1&#x2013;7 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seubwai, W. et al. Inhibition of NF-&#x3ba;B activity enhances sensitivity to anticancer drugs in cholangiocarcinoma cells. Oncol. Res. 23, 21 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megyesfalvi, Z. et al. Expression patterns and prognostic relevance of subtype-specific transcription factors in surgically resected small-cell lung cancer: an international multicenter study. J. Pathol. 257, 674&#x2013;686 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gay, C. M. et al. Patterns of transcription factor programs and immune pathway activation define four major subtypes of SCLC with distinct therapeutic vulnerabilities. Cancer cell 39, 346&#x2013;360. e347 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenbaum, D., Colangelo, C., Williams, K. &amp; Gerstein, M. Comparing protein abundance and mRNA expression levels on a genomic scale. Genome Biol. 4, 1&#x2013;8 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Beyer, A. &amp; Aebersold, R. On the dependency of cellular protein levels on mRNA abundance. Cell 165, 535&#x2013;550 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak, M., Lee, S., Sung, I., Koo, B. &amp; Kim, S. Improved drug response prediction by drug target data integration via network-based profiling. Brief. Bioinforma. 24, bbad034 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P. et al. Improving drug response prediction via integrating gene relationships with deep learning. Brief. Bioinforma. 25, bbae153 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y. et al. Ensemble transfer learning for the prediction of anti-cancer drug response. Sci. Rep. 10, 18040 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang, D., Koo, B. &amp; Kim, S. Transfer learning of condition-specific perturbation in gene interactions improves drug response prediction. Bioinformatics 40, i130&#x2013;i139 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha, S. et al. PERCEPTION predicts patient response and resistance to treatment using single-cell transcriptomics of their tumors. Nat. Cancer 5, 938&#x2013;952 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sza&#x142;ata, A. et al. A benchmark for prediction of transcriptomic responses to chemical perturbations across cell types. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 37, 20566&#x2013;20616 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Meer, D. et al. Cell Model Passports-a hub for clinical, genetic and functional datasets of preclinical cancer models. Nucleic Acids Res. 47, D923&#x2013;D929 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberzon, A. et al. The Molecular Signatures Database (MSigDB) hallmark gene set collection. Cell Syst. 1, 417&#x2013;425 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk, D. et al. STRING v11: protein-protein association networks with increased coverage, supporting functional discovery in genome-wide experimental datasets. Nucleic Acids Res. 47, D607&#x2013;D613 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. P., Wu, C., Miao, H. &amp; Wu, H. RegNetwork: an integrated database of transcriptional and post-transcriptional regulatory networks in human and mouse. Database (Oxford) 2015, https://doi.org/10.1093/database/bav095 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unsal-Beyge, S. &amp; Tuncbag, N. Functional stratification of cancer drugs through integrated network similarity. NPJ Syst. Biol. Appl. 8, 11 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csardi, G. &amp; Nepusz, T. The igraph software package for complex network research. InterJournal, complex Syst. 1695, 1&#x2013;9 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa, F. et al. Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python. J. Mach. Learn. Res. 12, 2825&#x2013;2830 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fey, M. &amp; Lenssen, J. E. Fast graph representation learning with PyTorch Geometric. arXiv preprint arXiv:1903.02428 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. et al. PubChem 2023 update. Nucleic Acids Res 51, D1373&#x2013;D1380 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sz&#xf6;cs, E., Stirling, T., Scott, E. R., Scharm&#xfc;ller, A. &amp; Sch&#xe4;fer, R. B. webchem: an R package to retrieve chemical information from the web. J. Stat. Softw. 93, 1&#x2013;17 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan, A. B. et al. The library of integrated network-based cellular signatures NIH program: System-level cataloging of human cells response to perturbations. Cell Syst. 6, 13&#x2013;24 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Z. et al. Getting started with LINCS datasets and tools. Curr. Protoc. 2, e487 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. DGL-LifeSci: An open-source toolkit for deep learning on graphs in life science. ACS Omega 6, 27233&#x2013;27238 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer Genome Atlas Research, N. et al. The cancer genome atlas pan-cancer analysis project. Nat. Genet 45, 1113&#x2013;1120 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colaprico, A. et al. TCGAbiolinks: An R/Bioconductor package for integrative analysis of TCGA data. Nucleic Acids Res 44, e71 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spainhour, J. C. G., Lim, J. &amp; Qiu, P. GDISC: A web portal for integrative analysis of gene-drug interaction for survival in cancer. Bioinformatics 33, 1426&#x2013;1428 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody, S., Alon, U. &amp; Yahav, E. How attentive are graph attention networks? arXiv preprint arXiv:2105.14491 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, G., Muller, M., Thabet, A. &amp; Ghanem, B. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF international conference on computer vision. 9267-9276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G., Liu, Z., Van Der Maaten, L. &amp; Weinberger, K. Q. In Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition. 4700-4708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paszke, A. et al. Pytorch: An imperative style, high-performance deep learning library. Advances in neural information processing systems 32 (2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>