<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41384166</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increase in Bone Mineral Density of the Amputated-Side Femur Following High-Impact Training in a Young Transtibial Amputee: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e96483</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e96483</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e96483</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.96483</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Loss of bone mineral density (BMD) in the amputated limb is a well-documented complication after lower limb amputation, predisposing patients to osteoporosis and fragility fractures. Exercise interventions have been recommended to mitigate this decline, but to date no clinical reports have demonstrated an actual increase in hip BMD following amputation. We describe a young male dockworker who underwent transtibial amputation after severe occupational trauma. A structured rehabilitation program incorporating high-impact and resistance training was delivered for four months during hospitalization, followed by continued self-directed exercise after discharge. Serial dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scans over three years revealed progressive gains in amputated-side hip BMD, with final measurements showing a 17.4-24.3% increase from baseline. This appears to be the first longitudinally documented case of improved hip BMD in an amputated limb following structured rehabilitation with high-impact exercise. The program closely paralleled recent expert recommendations on exercise prescription for amputees, underscoring the potential of targeted progressive loading to preserve skeletal health. However, the relative contribution of exercise intensity versus other factors remains uncertain, and further studies are needed to establish dose-response relationships and generalizability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Toda et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toda</LastName><ForeName>Mitsunori</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine, Hyogo Rehabilitation Center Hospital, Kobe, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chin</LastName><ForeName>Takaaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robot Rehabilitation Center, The Hyogo Institute of Assistive Technology, Kobe, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oshima</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Surgery, Hyogo Rehabilitation Center Hospital, Kobe, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone mineral density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (dxa)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high impact exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower limb amputation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower-limb prosthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical medicine and rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transtibial amputation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41384166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12691890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.96483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bone and joint changes in lower limb amputees. Burke MJ, Roman V, Wright V. Ann Rheum Dis. 1978;37:252&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1000216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">150823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between amputation, arthritis and osteopenia in British male war veterans with major lower limb amputations. Kulkarni J, Adams J, Thomas E, Silman A. Clin Rehabil. 1998;12:348&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9744670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteoporosis: a factor on residual limb pain in traumatic trans-tibial amputations. Yazicioglu K, Tugcu I, Yilmaz B, Goktepe AS, Mohur H. Prosthet Orthot Int. 2008;32:172&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18569885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BMD and bone geometry in transtibial and transfemoral amputees. Sherk VD, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. J Bone Miner Res. 2008;23:1449&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18410229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscle strength and bone mineral density in mine victims with transtibial amputation. Tugcu I, Safaz I, Yilmaz B, G&#xf6;ktepe AS, Taskaynatan MA, Yazicioglu K. Prosthet Orthot Int. 2009;33:299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19961291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute bone changes after lower limb amputation resulting from traumatic injury. Bemben DA, Sherk VD, Ertl WJ, Bemben MG. Osteoporos Int. 2017;28:2177&#x2013;2186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Femoral fractures in patients with lower extremity amputations. Gonzalez EG, Mathews MM. https://europepmc.org/article/med/7377956. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1980;61:276&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7377956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A study of bone mineral density in lower limb amputees at a national prosthetics center. Smith &#xc9;, Comiskey C, Carroll &#xc1;, Ryall N. JPO J Prosthet Orthot. 2011;23:14&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical expenditures for fragility hip fracture in Japan: a study using the nationwide health insurance claims database. Mori T, Komiyama J, Fujii T, et al. Arch Osteoporos. 2022;17:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9001568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35403938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-intensity resistance and impact training improves bone mineral density and physical function in postmenopausal women with osteopenia and osteoporosis: the LIFTMOR randomized controlled trial. Watson SL, Weeks BK, Weis LJ, Harding AT, Horan SA, Beck BR. J Bone Miner Res. 2018;33:211&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of physical exercise on bone density in middle-aged and older men: a systematic review. Bolam KA, van Uffelen JG, Taaffe DR. Osteoporos Int. 2013;24:2749&#x2013;2762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23552825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High impact exercise increased femoral neck bone mineral density in older men: a randomised unilateral intervention. Allison SJ, Folland JP, Rennie WJ, Summers GD, Brooke-Wavell K. Bone. 2013;53:321&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23291565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of exercise on bone mass in young women with anorexia nervosa. Waugh EJ, Woodside DB, Beaton DE, Cot&#xe9; P, Hawker GA. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resistive exercise in astronauts on prolonged spaceflights provides partial protection against spaceflight-induced bone loss. Sibonga J, Matsumoto T, Jones J, et al. Bone. 2019;128:112037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31400472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Developing an exercise intervention to minimise hip bone mineral density loss following traumatic lower limb amputation: a Delphi study. Behan FP, Bull AM, Beck BR, et al. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:1251&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11671889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39227136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Results of prosthetic rehabilitation on managing transtibial vascular amputation with silicone liner after wound closure. Chin T, Toda M. J Int Med Res. 2016;44:957&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5536617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27225860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone mineral density in lower limb amputees: a longitudinal study. Finco G, Mura R, Sainas G, Crisafulli A. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022;2022:3913&#x2013;3920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term changes in hip bone mineral density after lower extremity amputation. Hoellwarth JS, Wood K, Pasquina PF, Potter BK. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18:299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of resistance training or jumping-exercise to increase bone mineral density in men with low bone mass: a 12-month randomized, clinical trial. Hinton PS, Nigh P, Thyfault J. Bone. 2015;79:203&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4503233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>