<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41771933</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gelatin production from red tilapia skin fish using high-pressure processing and its characterisations.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38598-1</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaswir</LastName><ForeName>Irwandi</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Halal Research Centre, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia. irwandi@iium.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Institute for Halal Research and Training (INHART), International Islamic University Malaysia, Jalan Gombak, Kuala Lumpur, 53100, Malaysia. irwandi@iium.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusof</LastName><ForeName>Nurlina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioprocess and Molecular Engineering Research Unit (BPMERU), Faculty of Engineering, International Islamic University Malaysia (IIUM) Gombak, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuliana</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Tourism and Hospitality, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khair</LastName><ForeName>Miftahul</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azhar</LastName><ForeName>Minda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zainul</LastName><ForeName>Rahadian</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lestari</LastName><ForeName>Widya</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Dentistry, International Islamic University Malaysia, Kuantan Campus, Bandar Indera Mahkota, Kuantan, 25200, Pahang, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hendri</LastName><ForeName>Ridar</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Fisheries and Marine Science, Universitas Riau, Pekanbaru, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Komaini</LastName><ForeName>Anton</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Science, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, West Sumatera, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyashita</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hokkaido Bunkyo University, Kogane-chuo 5-196-1, Eniwa City, 061-1449, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salamatullah</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Nutrition, College of Food and Agriculturan Sciences, King Saud University, Riyadh, 11451, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahda</LastName><ForeName>Mustofa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Universitas Ahmad Dahlan, Yogyakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ahmad Dahlan Halal Center, Universitas Ahmad Dahlan, Yogyakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amino acid levels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eco-friendly extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fish gelatin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gel strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41771933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38598-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38598-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fadhlina, A. &amp; Nor, M. M. Halal products in malaysia: a bibliometric analysis. Food Res. 8 (3), 84&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.26656/fr.2017.8(3).305 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazali, M. A., Md Sawari, S. S., Ahmad, S. Y., Awang, M. D. &amp; Jusoh, M. K. A. The potential and Obstacles of malaysia&#x2019;s Halal certification towards global Halal standard. Food Res. 6 (Suppl. (3), 54&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.26656/fr.2017.6(S3).8 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaswir, I. &amp; Ramli, N. Study on Muslim-friendly hospitality in Malaysia. In S. K. A. Manan, F. A. Rahman, M. Sahr, &amp; I (Eds.), Contemporary Issues and Development in the Global Halal Industry: Selected Papers from the International Halal Conference 2014 (pp. 59&#x2013;66). Singapore: Springer, 2016. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Zin, Z. et al. ab Halal and Non-Halal Gelatine as a Potential Animal By-Products in Food Systems: Prospects and Challenges for Muslim Community. Advances in Social Science, Education and Humanities Research, volume 536 Proceedings of the First International Conference on Science, Technology, Engineering and Industrial Revolution (ICSTEIR 2020) (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rather, J. A. et al. A comprehensive review on gelatin: Understanding impact of the sources, extraction methods, and modifications on potential packaging applications, Food Packaging and Shelf Life, Food Packaging and Shelf Life 34 (2022) 100945. (2022). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fpsl.2022.100945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Ma, L., Cai, L., Zhou, M. &amp; Li, J. Effects of acid concentration and the UHP pretreatment on the gelatinisation of collagen and the properties of extracted gelatins. International Journal of Food Science and Technology, 51(2016), 1228&#x2013;1235. (2016). https://doi.org/10.1111/ijfs.13089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. &amp; Regenstein, J. M. Yield and gel strength of gelatin extracted from smoked salmon (Salmo salar) skins. J. Aquat. Food Prod. Technol. 26 (5), 553&#x2013;565. https://doi.org/10.1080/10498850.2016.1236868 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedinia, A. et al. Poultry gelatin: Characteristics, developments, challenges, and future outlooks as a sustainable alternative for mammalian gelatin, Tren in Food Science Technology, 104(2020): 14&#x2013;26. (2020). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tifs.2020.08.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaswir, I., Yusof, N., Jamal, P. &amp; Jami, M. S. Novel method for gelatin extraction of various local fish using high pressure processing (HPP). Int. Food Res. J. 24 (Suppl), S533&#x2013;S539 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, P. S., Chakraborty, S., Kaushik, N., Kaur, B. P. &amp; Hull, N. R. S. High hydrostatic pressure processing of food materials. In (ed Sahu, J. K.) Introduction To Advanced Food Engineering (151&#x2013;186). Florida: CRC (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastogi, N. K., Raghavarao, K. S. M. S., Balasubramaniam, V. M., Niranjan, K. &amp; Knorr, D. Opportunities and challenges in high pressure processing of foods. Crit. Rev. Food Sci. Nutr. 47 (1), 69&#x2013;112. https://doi.org/10.1080/10408390600626420 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva, R. S. G., Bandeira, S., Petry, F. &amp; Pinto, L. A. Effect of bone particle size of carp (Cyprinus Carpio) heads in gelatin extraction. VETOR-Revista De Ci&#xea;ncias Exatas E Engenharias. 21 (2), 34&#x2013;43 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, M. A., Al-Kahtani, H. A., Jaswir, I., AbuTarboush, H. &amp; Ismail, E. A. Extraction and characterization of gelatin from camel skin (potential Halal gelatin) and production of gelatin nanoparticles. Saudi J. Biol. Sci. 27 (6), 1596&#x2013;1601. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sjbs.2020.03.022 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusof, N., Jaswir, I., Jamal, P., Jami, M. S. &amp; Octaviani, F. Optimization of process condition for extraction of gelatin from red tilapia skin (Oreochromis niloticus) by high pressure processing (HPP). Int. Food Res. J. 24 (Suppl), S340&#x2013;S347 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinthusamran, S., Benjakul, S. &amp; Kishimura, H. Molecular characteristics and properties of gelatin from skin of Seabass with different sizes. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 73, 146&#x2013;153. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2014.11.024 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sae-leaw, T. &amp; Benjakul, S. Physico-chemical properties and fishy odour of gelatin from Seabass (Lates calcarifer) skin stored in ice. Food Bioscience. 10, 59&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fbio.2015.02.002 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krug, D. Analytical Profiles of Excipients and Drug Substances (Orange Apple, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of Official Analytical Chemists. Official Methods of Analysis 17th edn (Association of Official Analytical Chemists, 2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gornall, A. G., Bardawill, C. J. &amp; M., D. M Determination of serum proteins by means of the biuret reaction. J. Biol. Chem. 177 (11), 751&#x2013;766 (1949).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GMIA. Standard Testing Methods for Edible gelatin. (I. Official Procedure of the Gelatin Manufacturers Institute of America, Ed.). (Official Procedure of the Gelatin Manufacturers Institute of America, Inc., New York, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Standards Institution. Methods for sampling and testing gelatin (physical and chemical methods), BS, 757(1975). (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Farias, B. S. et al. Influence of gelatin type on physicochemical properties of electrospun nanofibers. Sci. Rep. 13 (1), 15195. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-42472-9 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahda, M., Jaswir, I. &amp; Subara, D. Enhancement of physical properties of gelatin-based film by bovine serum albumin. Carpathian Journal of Food Science and Technology, 2022, 14(4), 160&#x2013;167. (2022). https://doi.org/10.34302/crpjfst/2022.14.4.12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liqing, C., Liang, M., Mengrou, Z., Yi, L. &amp; Yuhao, Z. Effects of pressure on gelatinization of collagen and properties of extracted gelatins. Food Hydrocoll. 36, 316&#x2013;322. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2013.10.012 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. N. et al. A fiber-optic refractive index sensor detect the isoelectric point of gelatin. Cogent Chem. 1466416. https://doi.org/10.1080/23312009.2018.1466416 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haug, I. J. &amp; Draget, K. I. Gelatin. In (eds Phillips, G. O. &amp; Williams, P. A.) Handbook of Food Proteins (92&#x2013;115). Cambridge: Woodhead Publishing Limited (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim, A. A. &amp; Bhat, R. Fish gelatin: Properties, challenges, and prospects as an alternative to mammalian gelatins. Food Hydrocoll. 23 (3), 563&#x2013;576. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2008.07.002 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Ma, L. &amp; Shi, X. Ultra-high pressure-assisted extraction of gelatin from fish skin. Food Sci. 32 (6), 99&#x2013;103 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnesen, J. A. &amp; Gildberg, A. Extraction and characterisation of gelatine from Atlantic salmon (salmo salar) skin. Bioresour. Technol. 98 (1), 53&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2005.11.021 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liqing, C., Yuhao, Z. &amp; Mengrou, Z. Optimization of pretreatment by ultra-high pressure during production of gelatin from pig-skin. Food Sci. 28 (19), 262&#x2013;269 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouqin, Z., Jun, X. &amp; Changzheng, W. High hydrostatic pressure extraction of flavonoids from propolis. J. Chem. Technol. Biotechnol. 80 (1), 50&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1002/jctb.1153 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rendueles, E. et al. Microbiological food safety assessment of high hydrostatic pressure processing: A review. LWT - Food Sci. Technol. 44 (5), 1251&#x2013;1260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lwt.2010.11.001 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sockalingam, K., Nelson, H., Idris, M. I. &amp; Abdullah, H. Z. Effects of pre-treatment durations on properties of black tilapia (Oreochromis Mossambicus) skin gelatin. Mater. Sci. Forum. 840, 146&#x2013;150. https://doi.org/10.4028/www.scientific.net/MSF.840.146 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saidi, G. S., Al-Alawi, A., Rahman, M. S. &amp; Guizani, N. Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopic study of extracted gelatin from Shaari (Lithrinus microdon) skin: effects of extraction conditions. Int. Food Res. J. 19 (3), 1167&#x2013;1173 (2012). (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikoo, M. et al. Physicochemical properties of skin gelatin from farmed Amur sturgeon (Acipenser schrenckii) as influenced by acid pretreatment. Food Bioscience. 5, 19&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fbio.2013.10.004 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cebi, N., Durak, M. Z., Toker, O. S., Sagdic, O. &amp; Arici, M. An evaluation of fourier transforms infrared spectroscopy method for the classification and discrimination of bovine, Porcine and fish gelatins. Food Chem. 190, 1109&#x2013;1115. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2015.06.065 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuan, Y. H., Nafchi, A. M., Huda, N., Ariffin, F. &amp; Karim, A. A. Effects of sugars on the gelation kinetics and texture of Duck feet gelatin. Food Hydrocoll. 58, 267&#x2013;275. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2016.02.025 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rather, J. A. et al. Extraction of gelatin from poultry byproduct: influence of drying method on Structural, Thermal, Functional, and rheological characteristics of the dried gelatin powder. Front. Nutr. 9, 895197. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2022.895197 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedinia, A., Ariffin, F., Huda, N. &amp; Mohammadi Nafchi, A. Preparation and characterization of a novel biocomposite based on Duck feet gelatin as alternative to bovine gelatin. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 109, 855&#x2013;862. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2017.11.051 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matulessy, D. N. et al. Characterization and functional properties of gelatin from goat bone through alcalase and neutrase enzymatic extraction. Vet. World. 14 (9), 2397&#x2013;2409. https://doi.org/10.14202/vetworld.2021.2397-2409 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinthusamran, S., Benjakul, S. &amp; Kishimura, H. Characteristics and gel properties of gelatin from skin of Seabass (Lates calcarifer) as influenced by extraction conditions. Food Chem. 152, 276&#x2013;284. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2013.11.109 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, J. Effect of high pressure on structural and rheological properties of cereals and legume proteins. In (eds Ahmed, J., Ramaswamy, H. S., Kasapis, S. &amp; Boye, J. I.) Novel Food Processing: Effects on Rheological and Functional Properties (225&#x2013;256). Florida: CRC. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng, W., Zheng, H. &amp; Su, W. Characterization of edible films based on tilapia (Tilapia zillii) scale gelatin with different extraction pH. Food Hydrocoll. 41, 19&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2014.03.026 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. et al. Properties and antimicrobial activity of silver carp (Hypophthalmichthys molitrix) skin gelatin-chitosan films incorporated with oregano essential oil for fish preservation. Food Packaging Shelf Life. 2 (1), 7&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fpsl.2014.04.004 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Meligy, M. A., Valachov&#xe1;, K., Jur&#xe1;nek, I., Tamer, T. M. &amp; &#x160;olt&#xe9;s, L. Preparation and physicochemical characterization of Gelatin-Aldehyde derivatives. Molecules 27 (20), 7003. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules27207003 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, M. P., Suguna, P. R., Prasad, K., Vijaylakshmi, J. V. &amp; Renuka, M. Extraction and characterization of gelatin: a functional biopolymer. Int. J. Pharm. Pharm. Sci. 9 (9), 239&#x2013;242 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan, Q. et al. Influences of trypsin pretreatment on the Structures, Composition, and functional characteristics of skin gelatin of Tilapia, grass Carp, and sea perch. Mar. Drugs. 21, 423. https://doi.org/10.3390/md21080423 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mad-Ali, S., Benjakul, S., Prodpran, T. &amp; Maqsood, S. Characteristics and gelling properties of gelatin from goat skin as affected by drying methods. J. Food Sci. Technol. 54 (6), 1646&#x2013;1654. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13197-017-2597-5 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kahtani, H. A. et al. Structural characteristics of camel-bone gelatin by demineralization and extraction. Int. J. Food Prop. 20 (11), 2559&#x2013;2568. https://doi.org/10.1080/10942912.2016.1244543 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall, A. R. Ash analysis. In Food Analysis, 107 (ed. Nielsen, S.) 78&#x2013;93. (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, London, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, R. T. Gelatin: Manufacture and physico-chemical properties. In F. Podczeck &amp; B. E. Jones (Eds.), Pharmaceutical capsules (pp. 23&#x2013;60). United Kingdom: Pharmaceutical Press. (2004). Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?id=VAmbWj9aK_oC&amp;pgis=1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougatef, A. et al. Recovery and physicochemical properties of smooth Hound (mustelus mustelus) skin gelatin. LWT - Food Sci. Technol. 48 (2), 248&#x2013;254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lwt.2012.03.021 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khirzin, H. M. et al. Proximate composition of Duck gelatin produced from several different bone parts using a multilevel extraction method. AIP Conf. Proc. 3068 (050002). https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0206126 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida, P. F., Caetano, S. &amp; Silva, D. A. Extraction and physicochemical characterization of gelatin from chicken by-product. Journal of Food Process Engineering, 36(2013), 824&#x2013;833. (2013). https://doi.org/10.1111/jfpe.12051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See, S. F., Hong, P. K., Ng, K. L., Aida, W., Babji, A. S. &amp; W.M., &amp; Physicochemical properties of gelatins extracted from skins of different freshwater fish species. Int. Food Res. J. 17 (3), 809&#x2013;816 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamilah, B. &amp; Harvinder, K. G. Properties of gelatins from skins of fish - Black tilapia (Oreochromis mossambicus) and red tilapia (Oreochromis nilotica). Food Chem. 77 (1), 81&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0308-8146(01)00328-4 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, L., Regenstein, J. M., Lv, S., Lu, J. &amp; Jiang, S. An overview of gelatin derived from aquatic animals: properties and modification. Trends Food Sci. Technol. 68, 102&#x2013;112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tifs.2017.08.012 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. et al. Study of physicochemical and gelation properties of fish gelatin from different sources. Appl. Sci. 13 (9), 5337. https://doi.org/10.3390/app13095337 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safari, A. &amp; Malek, M. The influence of extraction conditions on Ash content of gelatin obtained from cattle bone by acid process. In 2 International Congress on Food Technology; November 05&#x2013;07, 2014 Ku &#x15f; adas&#x131;/Turkey (ed. Safari, A.). 153 (Association of Food Technology/Turkey &amp; Ankara University/Turkey, Turkey, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, W., Zhang, H. H., Welsh, M. J. &amp; Kaufman, P. B. Gene biotechnology, third edition. Florida: CRC Press, 2016. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammed, A., Ali, M., Kishimura, H. &amp; Benjakul, S. Physicochemical and molecular properties of gelatin from skin of golden carp (Proba Rbus Jullieni) as influenced by acid pretreatment and prior-ultrasonication. Food Hydrocoll. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2018.03.052 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedinia, A., Zambelli, R. A. &amp; Hosseini, E. Chapter 17 - Functional foods for oral and dental health. Unleashing Power Funct. Foods Novel Bioactives. 2025, 337&#x2013;353. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-443-28862-3.00017-0 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incili, G. K. et al. Chapter 3 - Microbial derived biomaterials: fabrication, processing, and food application. Sustainable Mater. Food Packaging Preservation. 2025, 55&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-443-13567-5.00003-4 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua, L. K., Lim, P. K., Thoo, Y. Y., Neo, Y. P. &amp; Tan, T. C. Extraction and characterization of gelatin derived from acetic acid-treated black soldier fly larvae. Food Chem. Adv. 2, 101&#x2013;109 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawant, R. R. et al. Functional properties of gelatin extracted from sole fish. Fishery Technology, 55(January 2017), 34&#x2013;40 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eun, J. B., Shon, J. H., Eo, J. H. &amp; Hun, S. Utilization of collagen and gelatin extracted from skate skin. In (ed Hollingworth, C. S.) Food Hydrocolloids: Characteristics, Properties and Structures (1&#x2013;39). New York: Nova Science Publishers, Inc (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakhar, J. K. et al. Characterization of fish gelatin from blackspotted croaker (Protonibea diacanthus). Archives Appl. Sci. Res. 4 (3), 1353&#x2013;1358 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamlath, S. &amp; Wakeling, L. Trends in high pressure processing of foods: food quality and bioactive components. In (ed Comeau, M. A.) New Topics in Food Engineering (121&#x2013;150). New York: Nova Science Publishers, Inc. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, T. K. et al. Extraction of crude gelatin from Duck skin: effects of heating methods on gelatin yield. Poult. Sci. 99 (1), 590&#x2013;596. https://doi.org/10.3382/ps/pez519 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>