<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41538284</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2152-0895</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of geriatric physical therapy (2001)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Geriatr Phys Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Exercise for Managing Fatigue in Parkinson's Disease: Clinical and Research Recommendations From a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000481</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Fatigue is among the most disabling symptoms of Parkinson's disease (PD), and physical exercise is a promising intervention. This study aimed to evaluate the effects of physical exercise on PD-related fatigue and provide clinical and research recommendations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review and meta-analysis followed the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines. Two independent investigators conducted searches using the "Patient, Intervention, Comparison, Outcome" strategy in PubMed, Cochrane Library, Scopus, Web of Science, Embase, and Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) until August 2024. Randomized clinical trials examining physical exercise and fatigue in PD were included. The standardized mean difference (SMD) was used for effect estimation, and a random-effects model was applied for meta-analysis. Methodological quality was assessed using the PEDro scale, and confidence in cumulative evidence was evaluated with the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-two studies were included. Meta-analysis comparing exercise with nonexercise (usual care) interventions showed a large effect favoring exercise (SMD&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.92, 95% CI: -1.57 to -0.28; 7 studies), with interventions including multimodal training, walking, strengthening, and dance. An overview of all the studies with available data (19 studies) suggested that interventions with greater specificity, intensity, or active engagement had larger effects. However, certain control interventions, such as sleep hygiene, relaxation/education, and stretching, may play a role comparable to some active exercises. Fatigue was primarily measured using the Parkinson's Fatigue Scale and the Fatigue Severity Scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Moderate-certainty evidence supports that physical exercise, particularly active, continuous modalities such as walking, aerobic, resistance, and multimodal training at moderate intensity (at least twice weekly for 20-60&#xa0;minutes), can reduce PD-related fatigue. Future research should distinguish between central and peripheral fatigue, compare high-intensity exercise interventions, and explore combinations of exercise with other promising interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 APTA Geriatrics, An Academy of the American Physical Therapy Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Valton</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2356-7523</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Neurological Rehabilitation Laboratory, Physical Therapy Graduate Program, Physical Therapy Department, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zambetta</LastName><ForeName>Mariana Lara</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gianloren&#xe7;o</LastName><ForeName>Anna Carolyna</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Geriatr Phys Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101142169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1539-8412</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest. This work was supported by the Brazilian Federal Agency for Support and Evaluation of Graduate Education (CAPES)/Ministry of Education of Brazil in the form of graduate scholarships (no grant applies). All data produced from this review, including extracted data tables and spreadsheets, can be made available upon appropriate request to the corresponding author.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41538284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00139143-990000000-00093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Raza C, Anjum R, Shakeel NUA. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: mechanisms, translational models and management strategies. Life Sci. 2019;226:77-90. doi:10.1016/j.lfs.2019.03.057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2019.03.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluger BM, Herlofson K, Chou KL, et al. Parkinson &#x2018;s disease-related fatigue: a case definition and recommendations for clinical research. Mov Disord. 2016;31(5):625-631.doi:10.1002/mds.26511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.26511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi VE, Rizzi L, Somaa F. The role of nutrition on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review. Nutr Neurosci. 2022;26(7):605-628. doi:10.1080/1028415x.2022.2073107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1028415x.2022.2073107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon DK, Tanner CM, Brundin P. Parkinson disease epidemiology, pathology, genetics, and pathophysiology. Clin Geriatr Med. 2020;36(1):1-12. doi:10.1016/j.cger.2019.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cger.2019.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassif DV, Pereira JS. Fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: concepts and clinical approach. Psychogeriatrics. 2018;18(2):143-150. doi:10.1111/psyg.12302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/psyg.12302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano-Due&#xf1;as M, Bravo R, Merch&#xe1;n T, Serrano M. Fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: metric properties of the fatigue impact scale for daily use (d-fis), and its impact on quality of life. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2018;169:12-15. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2018.03.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clineuro.2018.03.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Xiang Y, Song T, et al. Characteristics of fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a longitudinal cohort study. Front Aging Neurosci. 2023;15. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2023.1133705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.1133705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantri S, Klawson E, Albert S, et al. Understanding the lexicon of fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2020;10(3):1185-1193.doi:10.3233/jpd-202029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jpd-202029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbers RG, Verhoef J, Van Wegen EE, Berendse HW, Kwakkel G. Interventions for fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(10). doi:10.1002/14651858.cd010925.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.cd010925.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folkerts A-K, Nielsen J, Gollan R, et al. Physical exercise as a potential treatment for fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease? A systematic review and meta-analysis of pharmacological and non-pharmacological interventions. J Parkinsons Dis. 2023;13(5):659-679.doi:10.3233/jpd-225116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jpd-225116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa V, Suassuna AOB, Brito TSS, Rocha TF, Gianloren&#xe7;o AC. Physical exercise for the management of cognitive symptoms in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Occup Ther Geriatr. 2024;43(1):1-26. doi:10.1080/02703181.2024.2380993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02703181.2024.2380993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa V, Suassuna AOB, Brito TSS, Rocha TF, Gianloren&#xe7;o AC. Physical exercise for treating non-motor symptoms assessed by general Parkinson&#x2019;s disease scales: systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. BMJ Neurol Open. 2023;5(2):e000469. doi:10.1136/bmjno-2023-000469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjno-2023-000469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurens C, Bergouignan A, Moro C. Exercise-released myokines in the control of energy metabolism. Front Physiol. 2020;1111:91. doi:10.3389/fphys.2020.00091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai X, Soh KG, Omar Dev RD, et al. Aerobic exercise combination intervention to improve physical performance among the elderly: a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2022;12:798068. doi:10.3389/fphys.2021.798068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.798068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe S, Ranssen M, Collett J, et al. Physical activity, fatigue, and sleep in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a secondary per protocol analysis from an intervention trial. Parkinsons Dis. 2018;2018(1):1-6. doi:10.1155/2018/1517807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/1517807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. Eribaum; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, Mcauley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (pedro) scale. J Physiother. 2020;66(1):59. doi:10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon S, Sarmento CVM, Steinbacher M, et al. Can Qigong improve non-motor symptoms in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease - A pilot randomized controlled trial? Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101169. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashtipour K, Johnson E, Kani C, et al. Effect of exercise on motor and nonmotor symptoms of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Parkinsons Dis. 2015;2015(1):1-5. doi:10.1155/2015/586378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/586378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abasi A, Raji P, Friedman JH, et al. Effects of vestibular rehabilitation on fatigue and activities of daily living in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a pilot randomized controlled trial study. Parkinsons Dis. 2020;2020(1):1-7. doi:10.1155/2020/8624986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/8624986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao C-M, Zhuang Y-C. Effect of health baduanjin qigong for mild to moderate Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2015;16(8):911-919. doi:10.1111/ggi.12571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ggi.12571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romenets SR, Anang J, Fereshtehnejad S-M, Pelletier A, Postuma R. Tango for treatment of motor and non-motor manifestations in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized control study. Complement Ther Med. 2015;23(2):175-184. doi:10.1016/j.ctim.2015.01.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2015.01.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan T, Ta&#x15f;kiran &#xd6;&#xd6;, Tok&#xe7;aer AB, Karata&#x15f; GK, &#xc7;ali&#x15f;kan AK, Karao&#x11f;lan B. Effects of different percentages of body weight-supported treadmill training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Turk J Med Sci. 2019;49(4):999-1007. doi:10.3906/sag-1812-57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3906/sag-1812-57</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribas CG, Silva LA, Corr&#xea;a MR, Teive HG, Valderramas S. Effectiveness of exergaming in improving functional balance, fatigue and quality of life in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2017;38:13-18. doi:10.1016/j.parkreldis.2017.02.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2017.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deepa S, Kumaresan A, Suganthirabab P, et al. Improving work life balance among female educationists during the COVID-19 lockdown. Work. 2023;75(2):413-421.doi:10.3233/wor-220063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/wor-220063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Cagno A, Buonsenso A, Centorbi M, et al. Whole body-electromyostimulation effects on serum biomarkers, physical performances and fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s patients: a randomized controlled trial. Front Aging Neurosci. 2023;15:1086487. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2023.1086487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.1086487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer A, Roth D, Santer A, et al. Climb up! head up! Climbing improves posture in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. A secondary analysis from a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2023;37(11):1492-1500.doi:10.1177/02692155231174990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02692155231174990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picelli A, Melotti C, Origano F, Neri R, Waldner A, Smania N. Robot-assisted gait training versus equal intensity treadmill training in patients with mild to moderate Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled trial. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2013;19(6):605-610. doi:10.1016/j.parkreldis.2013.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2013.02.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amara AW, Wood KH, Joop A, et al. Randomized, controlled trial of exercise on objective and subjective sleep in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2020;35(6):947-958.doi:10.1002/mds.28009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.28009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y-P, Chen R-S, Chen VC-F, Liu C-H, Chan H-L, Chang Y-J. Effects of lower limb cycling training on different components of force and fatigue in individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2022;10. doi:10.3389/fbioe.2022.829772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2022.829772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Kolk NM, de Vries NM, Kessels RPC, et al. Effectiveness of home-based and remotely supervised aerobic exercise in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a double-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(11):998-1008.doi:10.1016/s1474-4422(19)30285-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(19)30285-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz-Rubio AI, Cabrera-Martos I, Torres-Sanches I, Casilda-L&#xf3;pez J, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez L, Valenza MC. Effects of a resistance training program on balance and fatigue perception in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled trial. Med Clin. 2018;150(12):460-464. doi:10.1016/j.medcli.2017.10.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.medcli.2017.10.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michels K, Dubaz O, Hornthal E, Bega D. &#x201c;Dance therapy&#x201d; as a psychotherapeutic movement intervention in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Complement Ther Med. 2018;40:248-252. doi:10.1016/j.ctim.2018.07.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2018.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winward C, Sackley C, Meek C, et al. Weekly exercise does not improve fatigue levels in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2011;27(1):143-146.doi:10.1002/mds.23966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu PL, Lee M, Wu SL, et al. Effects of home-based exercise on motor, non-motor symptoms and health-related quality of life in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients: a randomized controlled trial. Jpn J Nurs Sci. 2021;18(3):e12418. doi:10.1111/jjns.12418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jjns.12418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cugusi L, Solla P, Serpe R, et al. Effects of a Nordic walking program on motor and non-motor symptoms, functional performance and body composition in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurorehabilitation. 2015;37(2):245-254.doi:10.3233/nre-151257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/nre-151257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solla P, Cugusi L, Bertoli M, et al. Sardinian folk dance for individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled pilot trial. J Altern Complement Med. 2019;25(3):305-316.doi:10.1089/acm.2018.0413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2018.0413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canning CG, Colleen G, Allen N, Dean CM, Goh L, Fung VS. Home-based treadmill training for individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled pilot trial. Clin Rehabil. 2012;26(9):817-826. doi:10.1177/0269215511432652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215511432652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granziera S, Alessandri A, Lazzaro A, Zara D, Scarpa A. Nordic walking and walking in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized single-blind controlled trial. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020;33(4):965-971. doi:10.1007/s40520-020-01617-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-020-01617-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ongre SO, Dalen I, Tysnes O-B, Alves G, Herlofson K. Progression of fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease &#x2013; a 9-year follow-up. Eur J Neurol. 2020;28(1):108-116. doi:10.1111/ene.14520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin I, Edison B, Mantri S, et al. Triggers and alleviating factors for fatigue in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0245285. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0245285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0245285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhen K, Zhang S, Tao X, Li G, Lv Y, Yu L. A systematic review and meta-analysis on effects of aerobic exercise in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. NPJ Parkinsons Dis. 2022;8(1). doi:10.1038/s41531-022-00418-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41531-022-00418-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuchtmann AB, Adak V, Dilbaz S, Handschin C. The role of the skeletal muscle secretome in mediating endurance and resistance training adaptations. Front Physiol. 2021;12. doi:10.3389/fphys.2021.709807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.709807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadish A, Shankaranarayana AM, Natarajan M, Solomon JM. Transcranial direct current stimulation for fatigue in neurological conditions: a systematic scoping review. Physiother Res Int. 2023;29(1). doi:10.1002/pri.2054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.2054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>