<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41606964</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Low-Intensity Blood Flow-Restricted Multi-Joint Exercise Improves Muscle Function in Patients With Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome: A Randomized Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e950516</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e950516</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e950516</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.950516</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND Patellofemoral pain syndrome (PFPS) limits physical activity and quality of life, especially during weight-bearing tasks. Although high-load resistance exercises are recommended for rehabilitation, they may worsen symptoms in pain-sensitive individuals. Low-intensity blood flow restriction (BFR) training has emerged as a potential alternative. However, its effects on functional performance and mechanical properties remain unclear. MATERIAL AND METHODS In this assessor-blinded, randomized controlled trial, 41 individuals with PFPS were randomly assigned to either the experimental group (EG, n=20) or the control group (CG, n=19). The EG performed multi-joint resistance exercises combined with BFR, while the CG performed the same program without BFR. Both groups completed the same multi-joint resistance exercise program twice weekly for 6 weeks. Outcome measures included pressure pain threshold (PPT), muscle mechanical properties such as tone and stiffness in the vastus medialis and vastus lateralis, isometric knee extensor strength, and balance ability. Balance was evaluated using the Y-Balance Test and the stair-descending task. RESULTS The EG showed significantly greater improvements in knee strength, PPT, and balance (P&lt;0.05). Notably, significant increases in muscle tone were observed in the vastus medialis and lateralis muscles, as well as muscle stiffness in the vastus medialis and semitendinosus muscles. CONCLUSIONS Low-intensity BFR multi-joint resistance exercise may be an effective intervention for improving physical function, pain, and mechanical properties in patients with PFPS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jejeong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Sahmyook University Graduate School, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Hyeokhyeon</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Sahmyook University Graduate School, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Yongwoo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9978-1924</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Health and Welfare Sahmyook University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D046788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007719" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017288" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Threshold</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> None declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12866272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.950516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">950516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fick CN, Jim&#xe9;nez-Silva R, Sheehan FT, Grant C. Patellofemoral kinematics in patellofemoral pain syndrome: The influence of demographic factors. J Biomech. 2022;130:110819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34749164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng G, Zhang A, Li C. Biofeedback exercise improved the EMG activity ratio of the medial and lateral vasti muscles in subjects with patellofemoral pain syndrome. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2008;18(1):128&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17070701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannasi R, Rajashekar A, Hegde NS. Association of patellofemoral pain syndrome (PFPS) with quadratus lumborum and lower limb muscle tightness a cross-sectional study. J Orthop. 2023;42:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10319640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37416861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ya&#xf1;ez-&#xc1;lvarez A, Berm&#xfa;dez-Pulgar&#xed;n B, Hern&#xe1;ndez-S&#xe1;nchez S, Albornoz-Cabello M. Effects of exercise combined with whole body vibration in patients with patellofemoral pain syndrome: a randomised-controlled clinical trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21:582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32859183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Jang K-M, Kim E, Rhim HC, Kim H-D. Effects of static and dynamic stretching with strengthening exercises in patients with patellofemoral pain who have inflexible hamstrings: A randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2021;13(1):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willy RW, Hoglund LT, Barton CJ, et al. Patellofemoral pain. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49(9):CPG1&#x2013;CPG95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31475628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis JA, Roddy L, Bottrell J, et al. A systematic review of clinical practice guidelines for physical therapist management of patellofemoral pain. Phys Ther. 2021;101(3):pzab021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neal BS, Bartholomew C, Barton CJ, et al. Six treatments have positive effects at 3 months for people with patellofemoral pain: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52(11):750&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36070427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kultur Y, Harbiyeli E, Botanlioglu H, et al. Evaluation of the results of closed kinetic chain exercises applied in the conservative treatment of patellofemoral pain syndrome by means of shear wave elastography: A randomized controlled trial. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong) 2024;32(3):10225536241280384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39483049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizan S, Sheikhhoseini R, Piri H, Zamankhanpour M. The effect of stretching, foam rolling, and FIFA 11+ warm-ups on performance and pain in athletes with knee pain. J Orthopedic Spine Trauma. 2023;9:69&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford AM, Dillon S, Hartigan K, et al. The effects of McConnell patellofemoral joint and tibial internal rotation limitation taping techniques in people with Patellofemoral pain syndrome. Gait Posture. 2020;82:266&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32987346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud WS, Osailan A, Ahmed AS, et al. Optimal parameters of blood flow restriction and resistance training on quadriceps strength and cross-sectional area and pain in knee osteoarthritis. Isokinetics Exercise Sci. 2021;29(4):393&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 11 ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholomew C, Lack S, Neal B. Altered pain processing and sensitisation is evident in adults with patellofemoral pain: A systematic review including meta-analysis and meta-regression. Scand J Pain. 2019;20(1):11&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31560652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano NR, Baellow A, Saliba S. Physical activity levels in individuals with and without patellofemoral pain. Physical Therapy in Sport. 2017;27:12&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman EN, Elshaar R, Milligan H, et al. Proximal, distal, and contralateral effects of blood flow restriction training on the lower extremities: A randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2019;11(2):149&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot LA, Webb L, Morrell C, et al. Electromyostimulation with blood flow restriction for patellofemoral pain syndrome in active duty military personnel: A randomized controlled trial. Military Med. 2023;188(7&#x2013;8):e1859&#x2013;e68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36807977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namboonlue C, Hamlin MJ, Sirasaporn P, et al. Optimal degree of hypoxia combined with low-load resistance training for muscle strength and thickness in athletes. J Physical Education Sport. 2020;20(2):828&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong W, Wang H, Cheng L, Ni G. Comparing the effect of intermittent blood flow restriction training and high-load resistance training in patients with patellofemoral pain: Study protocol for a randomised trial. BMJ Open. 2023;13(10):e073188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10603463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37865415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Frontiers Physiol. 2019;10:533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roman DP, Burland JP, Fredericks A, et al. Early-and late-stage benefits of blood flow restriction training on knee strength in adolescents after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthopaedic J Sports Med. 2023;11(11):23259671231213034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38035209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles L, Webster KE, McClelland J, Cook JL. Quadriceps strengthening with and without blood flow restriction in the treatment of patellofemoral pain: A double-blind randomised trial. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(23):1688&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28500081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi FM, Guenka LC. Quadriceps strengthening by the Kaatsu Training method in women with patellofemoral pain. Fisioterapia e Pesquisa. 2022;29:210&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhavan Hariri S, Abolahrari-Shirazi S, Abbasi L. Effects of exercise therapy plus quadriceps, gluteus medius and quadratus lumborum muscles self-myofascial release on pain, function, and balance in patients with patellofemoral pain syndrome through telerehabilitation: a study protocol for a randomized clinical trial. J Rehab Sci Res. 2023;10(2):93&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud WSE-d, Kamel EM. The effect of additional balance training program to gluteus medius strengthening exercises on patellofemoral pain syndrome. Int J Therapies Rehab Res. 2015;4(2):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alammari A, Spence N, Narayan A, et al. Effect of hip abductors and lateral rotators&#x2019; muscle strengthening on pain and functional outcome in adult patients with patellofemoral pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Back Musculoskel Rehab. 2023;36(1):35&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35988215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie P, Istv&#xe1;n B, Liang M. The relationship between patellofemoral pain syndrome and hip biomechanics: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Healthcare (Basel) 2022;11(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9818693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36611559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamboti CL, Silva RAd, Gobbi C, et al. Analysis of pain, functional capacity, muscular strength and balance in young women with Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome. Fisioterapia em Movimento. 2017;30(3):433&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Magnusson SP, Rasmussen LR, et al. Muscle performance during maximal isometric and dynamic contractions is influenced by the stiffness of the tendinous structures. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2005;99(3):986&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muraoka T, Muramatsu T, Fukunaga T, Kanehisa H. Influence of tendon slack on electromechanical delay in the human medial gastrocnemius in vivo. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2004;96(2):540&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14527969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramazano&#x11f;lu E, Usgu S, Yakut Y. Assessment of the mechanical characteristics of the lower extremity muscles with myotonometric measurements in healthy individuals. Physiother Quarterly. 2020;28(4):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly J, Kulshreshtha D, Almotiri M, Jog M. Muscle tone physiology and abnormalities. Toxins. 2021;13(4):282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton CJ, Crossley KM. Sharing decision-making between patient and clinician: The next step in evidence-based practice for patellofemoral pain? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(14):833&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Wu L. Effect of instrument-assisted soft tissue mobilization combined with blood flow restriction training on function, pain and strength of patients with patellofemoral joint pain. BMC Musculoskel Dis. 2023;24(1):698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes FR, Barber-Westin SD, Sipes L. Blood flow restriction training can improve peak torque strength in chronic atrophic postoperative quadriceps and hamstrings muscles. Arthroscopy: J Arthroscopic Rel Surg. 2021;37(9):2860&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed RIB, Hangody LR, Frischmann G, et al. Comparative effectiveness of supervised and home-based rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in competitive athletes. J Clin Med. 2024;13(8):2245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11051221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38673520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weon Y-s, Ahn S-h, Kim J-h, et al. Comparison of knee muscle strength and ankle dorsiflexion range of motion between standing workers with and without patellofemoral pain syndrome. Phys Ther Korea. 2020;27(4):241&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Dragonetti AM, Fontanot S, et al. The acute effects of cold water immersion and percussive massage therapy on neuromuscular properties and muscle soreness after exercise in young male soccer players. Sports. 2024;12(6):167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11207944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38921861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris R, Morrison S, Price A, et al. Inline dynamometry provides reliable measurements of quadriceps strength in healthy and ACL-reconstructed individuals and is a valid substitute for isometric electromechanical dynamometry following ACL reconstruction. The Knee. 2024;46:136&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38142660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldager FN, Aslerin S, B&#xc6; S, et al. Interrater, test-retest reliability of the Y balance test: A reliability study including 51 healthy participants. Int J Exercise Sci. 2023;16(4):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10124723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves C, Bezerra P, Clemente FM, et al. Effect of instability and bodyweight neuromuscular training on dynamic balance control in active young adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(23):8879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7729812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisky PJ, Gorman PP, Butler RJ, et al. The reliability of an instrumented device for measuring components of the star excursion balance test. N Am J Sports Phys Ther. 2009;4(2):92&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21509114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin A, Kozol Z. Measures of range of motion and strength among healthy women with differing quality of lower extremity movement during the lateral step-down test. J Orthopaedic Sports Physical Ther. 2010;40(12):792&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emamvirdi M, Hosseinzadeh M, Letafatkar A, et al. Comparing kinematic asymmetry and lateral step-down test scores in healthy, chronic ankle instability, and patellofemoral pain syndrome female basketball players: A cross-sectional study. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):12412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10390571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37524846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravo-S&#xe1;nchez A, Abi&#xe1;n P, S&#xe1;nchez-Infante J, et al. Five-compressions protocol as a valid myotonometric method to assess the stiffness of the lower limbs: A brief report. IntJ Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(21):14425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9654301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stausholm MB, Bjordal JM, Moe-Nilssen R, Naterstad IF. Pain pressure threshold algometry in knee osteoarthritis: Intra- and inter-rater reliability. Physiother Theory Pract. 2023;39(3):615&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35019810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurashina W, Iijima Y, Sasanuma H, et al. Evaluation of muscle stiffness in adhesive capsulitis with Myoton PRO. JSES Int. 2023;7(1):25&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9937826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36820433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roch M, Morin M, Gaudreault N. The MyotonPRO: A reliable tool for quantifying the viscoelastic properties of a trigger point on the infraspinatus in non-traumatic chronic shoulder pain. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2020;24(4):379&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33218538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lettner J, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Ramadanov N, et al. Evaluating the reliability of myotonpro in assessing muscle properties: A systematic review of diagnostic test accuracy. Medicina. 2024;60(6):851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38929468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Wu J, Chen G, et al. Reliability of a portable device for quantifying tone and stiffness of quadriceps femoris and patellar tendon at different knee flexion angles. PLoS One. 2019;14(7):e0220521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6668831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Ku&#x17c;d&#x17c;a&#x142; A, Wilk M, et al. Reliability of MyotonPro in measuring the biomechanical properties of the quadriceps femoris muscle in people with different levels and types of motor preparation. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1453730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11390662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39267811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J App Physiol. 2010;108(5):1199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius TR, Scheuermann BW. Acute neuromuscular and microvascular responses to concentric and eccentric exercises with blood flow restriction. TJ Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2725&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz RB, Gualano B, Rodrigues R, et al. Benefits of resistance training with blood flow restriction in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(5):897&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry M, Baudry S. Age-related changes in leg proprioception: Implications for postural control. J Neurophysiol. 2019;122(2):525&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negahban H, Etemadi M, Naghibi S, et al. The effects of muscle fatigue on dynamic standing balance in people with and without patellofemoral pain syndrome. Gait Posture. 2013;37(3):336&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22947999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes Ferreira C, Barton G, Delgado Borges L, et al. Step down tests are the tasks that most differentiate the kinematics of women with patellofemoral pain compared to asymptomatic controls. Gait Posture. 2019;72:129&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werasirirat P, Yimlamai T, Werasirirat P, Yimlamai T. Effect of supervised rehabilitation combined with blood flow restriction training in athletes with chronic ankle instability: A randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Exercise Rehab. 2022;18(2):123&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9081407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35582686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Patterson SD. The effect of blood flow restriction exercise on exercise-induced hypoalgesia and endogenous opioid and endocannabinoid mechanisms of pain modulation. J App Physiol. 2020;128(4):914&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, O&#x2019;Keeffe R, Shirazi SY, et al. Muscle activity and hypoalgesia in blood flow restricted versus unrestricted effort-matched resistance exercise in healthy adults. Physiol Rep. 2024;12(14):e16037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11260880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39034596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikaili S, Kalantari KK, Zavieh MK, et al. Effect of strengthening exercises in individuals with patellofemoral pain syndrome: A randomised controlled trial. Int J Ther Rehab. 2024;31(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallina A, Wakeling JM, Hodges PW, et al. Regional vastus medialis and vastus lateralis activation in females with patellofemoral pain. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(3):411&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30339659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>