<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41413361</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Exercise on Cytokine Profiles in Breast Cancer Survivors: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02376-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The role of exercise in modulating the immune system and cytokines has garnered increasing attention, particularly in the context of breast cancer survivorship. Breast cancer and its treatments often lead to immunosuppression, which can heighten the risk of infections and recurrence. Emerging evidence suggests that various forms of exercise, including aerobic and resistance exercise, can positively influence cytokine profiles in breast cancer patients. However, the specific effects and underlying mechanisms remain underexplored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to conduct a systematic review of the studies focused on the effects of exercise on cytokine profiles of breast cancer survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The databases of Cochrane Library, PubMed, Science Direct, Scopus, SPORTDiscus, and Web of Science were searched until 31 December 2024, following PRISMA guidelines. Randomized controlled trials were included if they compared breast cancer survivors participating in a structured exercise program with a non-exercise control group and measured cytokine variables both before and after the intervention. The quality of the included studies was rated with the PEDro scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eleven studies with 481 individuals undergoing exercise interventions were included in the analysis and compared to 240 individuals as controls. Participants in these studies ranged in age from early 40s to late 50s. These studies examined the effects of various exercise interventions, including resistance exercise (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2), aerobic exercise (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2), concurrent aerobic&#x2009;+&#x2009;resistance exercise (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;5), tai chi (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1), and yoga (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1). The training period ranged from 8 to 52&#xa0;weeks, with most studies lasting 12-15&#xa0;weeks. The average frequency of training was three sessions per week with a mean session duration of 55&#xa0;min. The quality of the studies showed a mean PEDro score of 6.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.9 points (range 5-8 points). Both aerobic and resistance training alone or in combination impacted several immune indices, including decreases in serum concentrations of interleukin-15 (IL-15), macrophage migration inhibitory factor (MIF), TNF-&#x3b1; expression in NK and NKT cells (NKTNF-&#x3b1;, and NKTTNF-&#x3b1;), and lower IL-10/TNF-&#x3b1; ratio. Other less habitual exercise interventions such as tai chi and yoga also induced positive effects on immune indices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Breast cancer survivors enrolled in several forms of exercise training showed improved cytokine parameters compared with counterparts who did not perform exercise. The benefits of exercise training on cytokine profiles of breast cancer survivors were evident with both aerobic and resistance training, whether performed separately or in combination, and with other training regimens such as tai chi and yoga.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalfoun</LastName><ForeName>Jihen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education, Ksar-Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abderrahman</LastName><ForeName>Abderraouf Ben</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education, Ksar-Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loganathan</LastName><ForeName>Devaraj</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Preventive and Social Medicine, Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research, Puducherry, 605006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammami</LastName><ForeName>Amri</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tunisian Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Science in Sports, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeidi</LastName><ForeName>Ayoub</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Coso</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Sciences Research Centre, Rey Juan Carlos University, 28943, Fuenlabrada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laher</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Pharmacology and Therapeutics, The University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zouhal</LastName><ForeName>Hassane</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6743-6464</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Institute of Sport Sciences (2I2S), 35850, Irodouer, France. hassane.zouhal@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Data availability: All data supporting the findings of this study are available in this published article. Compliance with ethical standards: Not applicable. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this review. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Authors&#x2019; contributions: JK, ABA, and HZ contributed to the conceptualization of the study, selection of studies, data extraction, and quality assessment. DL, AH, AS, JDC, IL, and HZ participated in data analysis and manuscript writing. All authors have reviewed and approved the final version of the manuscript, and have consented to the order of authorship.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41413361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02376-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02376-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Breast cancer fact sheet. Geneva: WHO; 2022. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/breast-cancer .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68(6):394&#x2013;424. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21492 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30207593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel R, DeSantis C, Virgo K, Stein K, Mariotto A, Smith T, et al. Cancer treatment and survivorship statistics, 2012. CA Cancer J Clin. 2012;62(4):220&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21149 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22700443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz K, Courneya K, Matthews C. Erratum: American college of sports medicine roundtable on exercise guidelines for cancer survivors (Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(7):1409&#x2013;26). Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savas P, Salgado R, Denkert C, Sotiriou C, Darcy PK, Smyth MJ, et al. Clinical relevance of host immunity in breast cancer: from TILs to the clinic. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2016;13(4):228&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrclinonc.2015.215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emens LA, Adams S, Cimino-Mathews A, Disis ML, Gatti-Mays ME, Ho AY, et al. Society for Immunotherapy of Cancer (SITC) clinical practice guideline on immunotherapy for the treatment of breast cancer. J Immunother Cancer. 2021;9(8):e002597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2021-002597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigneron N. Human tumor antigens and cancer immunotherapy. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:948501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/948501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26161423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4487697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swann JB, Smyth MJ. Immune surveillance of tumors. J Clin Invest. 2007;117(5):1137&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI31405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17476343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1857231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrand-Rosenberg S. Immune surveillance: a balance between protumor and antitumor immunity. Curr Opin Genet Dev. 2008;18(1):11&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gde.2007.12.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gde.2007.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2699403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson RJ, Kunz H, Agha N, Graff R. Exercise and the regulation of immune functions. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2015;135:355&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.pmbts.2015.08.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.pmbts.2015.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicklas BJ, Brinkley TE. Exercise training as a treatment for chronic inflammation in the elderly. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2009;37(4):165&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3181b7b3d9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2789351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turbitt WJ, Xu Y, Sosnoski DM, Collins SD, Meng H, Mastro AM, et al. Physical activity plus energy restriction prevents 4T1.2 mammary tumor progression, MDSC accumulation, and an immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment. Cancer Prev Res (Phila). 2019;12(8):493&#x2013;506. https://doi.org/10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-17-0233 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-17-0233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lav&#xed;n-P&#xe9;rez AM, Collado-Mateo D, Abbasi S, Ferreira-Junior JB, Hekmatikar AHA. Effects of exercise on immune cells with tumor-specific activity in breast cancer patients and survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2023;31:507. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-023-07968-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-023-07968-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Int J Surg. 2010;8(5):336&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2010.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Deeks JJ. Selecting studies and collecting data. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2008. p. 151&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1002/9780470712184.ch7 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.8.713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2008;11(2):364&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1177/1094428106291059 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1094428106291059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 1992;1(3):98&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-8721.ep10768783 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-8721.ep10768783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W, Marshall S, Batterham A, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PWM, Lonsdale C, Papalia S, Cheema BS, Toben C, et al. The effect of resistance training on markers of immune function and inflammation in previously sedentary women recovering from breast cancer: a randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2016;155(3):471&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-016-3688-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-016-3688-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26820653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KJ, An KO. Impact of high-intensity circuit resistance exercise on physical fitness, inflammation, and immune cells in female breast cancer survivors: a randomized control trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19095463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9102474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairey AS, Courneya KS, Field CJ, Bell GJ, Jones LW, Mackey JR. Randomized controlled trial of exercise and blood immune function in postmenopausal breast cancer survivors. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98(4):1534&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00566.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15772062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairey AS, Courneya KS, Field CJ, Bell GJ, Jones LW, Martin BS, et al. Effect of exercise training on C-reactive protein in postmenopausal breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Brain Behav Immun. 2005;19(5):381&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2005.04.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2005.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15922556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez AM, Mart&#xed;nez C, Fiuza-Luces C, Herrero F, P&#xe9;rez M, Madero L, et al. Exercise training and cytokines in breast cancer survivors. Int J Sports Med. 2011;32(6):461&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0031-1271697 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0031-1271697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21380980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieli-Conwright CM, Parmentier JH, Sami N, Lee K, Spicer D, Mack WJ, et al. Adipose tissue inflammation in breast cancer survivors: effects of a 16-week combined aerobic and resistance exercise training intervention. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2018;168(1):147&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-017-4576-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-017-4576-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29168064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Cook VD, Henson DA, Suttles J, Rejeski WJ, Ribisl PM, et al. Moderate exercise training and natural killer cell cytotoxic activity in breast cancer patients. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16(5):334&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-973015 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-973015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7558532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers LQ, Fogleman A, Trammell R, Hopkins-Price P, Vicari S, Rao K, et al. Effects of a physical activity behavior change intervention on inflammation and related health outcomes in breast cancer survivors: pilot randomized trial. Integr Cancer Ther. 2013;12(4):323&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1177/1534735412449687 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1534735412449687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22831916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers LQ, Vicari S, Trammell R, Hopkins-Price P, Fogleman A, et al. Biobehavioral factors mediate exercise effects on fatigue in breast cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(6):1077&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000000210 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000000210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24212124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4435796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung MN, Loo WTY. Effect of Tai Chi Chuan practice on immune system and pro-metastasis markers in early post-treatment breast cancer survivors. World J Adv Res Rev. 2021;12(1):13&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2021.12.1.0472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Greendale G, Crosswell AD, Garet D, Sternlieb B, Ganz PA, et al. Yoga reduces inflammatory signaling in fatigued breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;43:20&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.01.019 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.01.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24703167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4060606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>