<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41252093</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1869-5760</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ophthalmic inflammation and infection</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multidrug resistant bacteria and associated risk factors of external ocular infections at University of Gondar tertiary hospital in Northwest Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>86</StartPage><MedlinePgn>86</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">86</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12348-025-00541-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multidrug-resistant (MDR) bacteria are an escalating global public health concern and represent a cross-cutting issue affecting multiple sectors. In ophthalmic care, broad-spectrum antimicrobial agents are frequently prescribed empirically by healthcare professionals, often without culture-based evidence. This practice contributes to the development of drug-resistant pathogens. Therefore, routine surveillance of bacterial profiles and multidrug resistance in external ocular infections is crucial for effective treatment, prevention, and control efforts. The primary objective of this study was to determine the prevalence of multidrug resistance among bacterial isolates from external ocular infections and to identify associated risk factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study was conducted among 360 external ocular infection suspected patients between May 1 and July 30, 2023, at the University of Gondar Comprehensive Specialized Hospital's Tertiary Eye Care and Training Center. Systematic random sampling was employed to recruit participants. Sociodemographic and clinical data were collected using structured questionnaires. Ocular specimens were collected aseptically and processed using standard microbiological techniques according to CLSI. Data were entered into EpiData version 25 and analyzed using SPSS version 25. Bivariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were performed to assess the risk factors, with a 95% confidence interval. A p-value of less than 0.05 was considered statistically significant. A total of 360 patients participated in the study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Bacterial pathogens were isolated in 59.7% (215/360) of the external ocular infection samples. Gram-positive bacteria were the most frequently identified, comprising 46.7% (168/222) of isolates. Staphylococcus aureus was the most common isolate (43.7%, 97/222), followed by coagulase-negative Staphylococcus species (29.7%, 66/222), Pseudomonas aeruginosa (10.8%, 24/222), and Escherichia coli (5.4%, 12/222). The prevalence of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) was 21.6%. Overall, multidrug resistance was observed in 62.2% (138/222) of the isolates. Notably, dental infections were significantly associated with the presence of bacterial external ocular infections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights a high prevalence of bacterial and multidrug-resistant organisms in external ocular infections. Gentamicin and ciprofloxacin are effective antimicrobial agents against the isolated pathogens. These findings underscore the need for continuous monitoring of bacterial profiles and antimicrobial susceptibility patterns to support evidence-based antibiotic use and mitigate the rise of antimicrobial resistance in ocular infections.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dereje</LastName><ForeName>Mahliet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Birhanu</LastName><ForeName>Abebe</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-0363-3254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mulu</LastName><ForeName>Meseret</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bitew</LastName><ForeName>Getachew</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demissie</LastName><ForeName>Alemnew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ambachew</LastName><ForeName>Aklilu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dagnew</LastName><ForeName>Mulat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia. dagnewmulat@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101553216</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1869-5760</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">External ocular infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multidrugresistance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical clearance was obtained from the Ethical Review Committee of the School of Biomedical and Laboratory Sciences at the University of Gondar, reference number SBMLS 486. Written informed consent was obtained from each participant before the collection of data and specimens. For children under 16 years of age, both assent and consent were obtained from their parents or legal guardians. For participants who were illiterate, the consent form was read aloud by the data collector, and a thumbprint or signature was secured as evidence of consent. All ethical considerations, including voluntary participation, confidentiality, and privacy, were strictly upheld throughout the study. Laboratory results, including bacterial isolates and drug susceptibility reports, were documented in patient records or communicated directly to healthcare professionals at the University of Gondar Eye Care and Training Center for appropriate clinical management. The research was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication-: not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41252093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12627321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12348-025-00541-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12348-025-00541-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bagiu IC (2018) One year retrospective study of ocular infection in a tertiary care hospital from Timisoara. Rev Chim 69(10):2910&#x2013;2912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37358/RC.18.10.6651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernhardsdottir RR et al (2022) Antibiotic treatment for dry eye disease related to meibomian gland dysfunction and blepharitis &#x2013; a review. Ocul Surf 26:211&#x2013;221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtos.2022.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36210626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manente R (2022) Prevalence and antimicrobial resistance of causative agents to ocular infections. Antibiotics 11(4):463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics11040463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9032492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35453215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das PJ (2020) Clinico pathological study of lacrimal abscess with special reference to bacteriological etiology in Southern part of Assam. Indian J Clin Exp Ophthalmol 6(4):605&#x2013;609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18231/j.ijceo.2020.127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S (2022) Ocular surface infection mediated molecular stress responses: a review. Int J Mol Sci 23(6):3111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23063111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8952005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas W et al (2012) Microbiological etiology and susceptibility of bacterial conjunctivitis isolates from clinical trials with ophthalmic, twice-daily Besifloxacin. Adv Ther 29(5):442&#x2013;455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-012-0023-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22644963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asfaw E (2015) Potential bacterial pathogens of external ocular infections and their antibiotic susceptibility pattern at Hawassa university teaching and referral Hospital, Southern Ethiopia. Afr J Microbiol Res 9:1012&#x2013;1019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJMR2014.7282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aweke T et al (2024) Bacterial pathogens of exterior ocular infections and their antibiotic vulnerability pattern in Southern Ethiopia. Afr J Immunol Res 2:19&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neway S et al (2019) Bacterial profile and antimicrobial susceptibility patterns from external ocular infections and associated risk factors at all Africa leprosy rehabilitation and training center (ALERT), addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Ethio Med J 53(3):67&#x2013;77</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>Conjunctivitis (Pink Eye) | The Canadian Association of Optometrists</i>. Available from: https://opto.ca/eye-health-library/conjunctivitis-pink-eye accessed on July (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeu E, Hauswirth S (2020) A review of the differential diagnosis of acute infectious conjunctivitis: implications for treatment and management. Clin Ophthalmol 14:805&#x2013;813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OPTH.S236571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32210533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bispo PJM, Sahm DF, Asbell PA (2022) A systematic review of multi-decade antibiotic resistance data for ocular bacterial pathogens in the United States. Ophthalmol Ther 11(2):503&#x2013;520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40123-021-00449-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8927494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35113406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M (2021) Epidemiological profiling of mechanical ocular trauma and its analysis using new proposed classification for ocular adnexal injuries. <i>Beyoglu Eye J</i>. ; Available from: https://beyoglueye.com/jvi.aspx?un=BEJ-60252&amp;volume=</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8651016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed NJ (2021) Prescribing trends of medications ophthalmological outpatient department in a public hospital in Alkharj. J Pharm Res Int 33(4):28&#x2013;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei S, Steen D, Amin S (2023) Successful treatment of an extensively drug-resistant pseudomonal ulcer associated with contaminated artificial tears. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 32:101909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajoc.2023.101909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10407592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37560556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshamahi EYA et al (2020) Bacterial causes and antimicrobial sensitivity pattern of external ocular infections in selected Ophthalmology clinics in Sana&#x2019;a city. <i>Univers J Pharm Res</i> 5(3).Available from: https://www.ujpr.org/index.php/journal/article/view/409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuletaw T et al (2021) Clinical and Microbiological Profile of Bacterial and Fungal Suspected Corneal Ulcer at University of Gondar Tertiary Eye Care and Training Centre, Northwest Ethiopia. Parekh M, editor. <i>J Ophthalmol</i>. 2021:1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandepitte J, Verhaegen J, Engbaek K, Rohner P, Piot P, Heuck C (2003) Basic laboratory procedures in clinical bacteriology, 2nd edn. WHO, Geneva. www.who.int/iris/handle/10665/42696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheesbrough M (2006) District laboratory practice in tropical countries part I, 2nd edn. Cambridge University Press, New York</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) (2022) Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing.32nd ed. CLSI supplement M100(ISBN 978-1-68440-134-5[print]; ISBN 978-1-68440-135-2. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute, USA,2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getahun E et al (2017) Bacterial pathogens associated with external ocular infections alongside eminent proportion of multidrug resistant isolates at the university of Gondar hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Ophthalmol 17(1):151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-017-0548-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrillo F et al (2020) Prevalence and antibiotic resistance patterns of ocular bacterial strains isolated from pediatric patients in University Hospital of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy. Int J Microbiol. 2020:1&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye T (2013) Bacterial profile and antimicrobial susceptibility pattern of external ocular infections in Jimma university specialized hospital, southwest Ethiopia. American Journal of Infectious Diseases and Microbiology 1(1):13&#x2013;20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12691/ajidm-1-1-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junior IOD et al (2022) Clinical characteristics of external ocular and periocular infections and their antimicrobial treatment patterns among a Ghanaian ophthalmic Population; A multicenter study. Sci Rep. 12(1):10264. 10.1038/s41598-022-14461-x. PMID: 35715500 ; PMCID: PMC9206014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9206014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35715500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayehubizu Z, Mulu W, Biadglegne F (2021) Common bacterial causes of external ocular infections, associated risk factors and antibiotic resistance among patients at ophthalmology unit of Felege Hiwot referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect 11(1):7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12348-021-00238-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7917034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belyhun Y et al (2018) Ocular bacterial infections and antibiotic resistance patterns in patients attending Gondar teaching Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes 11(1):597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-018-3705-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6098601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30119696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiferaw B (2015) Bacterial isolates and their antimicrobial susceptibility pattern among patients with external ocular infections at Borumeda hospital, Northeast Ethiopia. BMC Ophthalmol 15(1):103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-015-0078-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4535287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26268424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed MM et al (2025) Molecular detection of <i>MecA</i> gene from methicillin-resistant <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> isolated from clinical and environmental samples and its potential inhibition by phytochemicals using in vitro and in silico approach. In Silico Pharmacol 13:26. 10.1007/s40203-024-00297-y
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40203-024-00297-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11811340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39936169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DFJ (2001) Detection of methicillin/oxacillin resistance in Staphylococci. J Antimicrob Chemother 48(1):65&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/48.suppl_1.65</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11420338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muluye D et al (2014) Types and drug susceptibility patterns of bacterial isolates from eye discharge samples at Gondar university hospital, northwest Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes 7(1):292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-7-292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4020315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stapleton F (2023) Tfos lifestyle: impact of societal challenges on the ocular surface. Ocul Surf 28:165&#x2013;199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtos.2023.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10102706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37062429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta DA et al (2023) Awareness about ocular complications due to dental infections among dentists. Pak Heart J 56(2):519&#x2013;523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekmek&#xe7;io&#x11f;lu H, &#xdc;n&#xfc;r M (2017) Eye- related trauma and infection in dentistry. J Istanb Univ Fac Dent 51(3):55&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29114432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>