<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41834314</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6998</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in otolaryngology &amp; head and neck surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thinking outside the (voice) box: considering respiratory function in presbyphonia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOO.0000000000001122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Presbyphonia has long been framed as a laryngeal disorder driven by presbylaryngis, yet emerging evidence suggests that age-related respiratory decline plays a central but under-recognized role in symptomatic vocal aging. This review synthesizes work on respiratory aging, speech-breathing patterns, and respiratory muscle performance in older adults with presbyphonia, and evaluates early attempts to target these systems in rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Laryngeal atrophy and glottic insufficiency are common in aging but do not reliably predict presbyphonia. Age-related reductions in lung elasticity, chest wall compliance, respiratory muscle strength, and respiratory interoception alter speech breathing and may compound glottic inefficiency. Recent studies indicate that "exuberant" voice therapies targeting maximal vocal function outperform gentler, skill-based approaches. Preliminary trials combining these therapies with respiratory muscle strength training, particularly inspiratory training, suggest added benefits for vocal effort, fatigue, and connected speech, though underlying mechanisms remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Respiratory aging appears to meaningfully influence symptom severity in presbyphonia yet remains poorly characterized in the condition. Incorporating respiratory assessment, kinematic measures of speech breathing, and targeted respiratory training may enhance diagnostic precision and optimize therapy outcomes. Future work should clarify how respiratory mechanics and sensory monitoring interact with laryngeal deficits and identify which older adults benefit most from respiration-focused rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saccente-Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Speech and Language Therapy (ENT), Royal National Ear, Nose and Throat and Eastman Dental Hospitals, University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cicely Saunders Institute of Palliative Care, Policy and Rehabilitation, King's College London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govender</LastName><ForeName>Roganie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London, Division of Surgery &amp; Interventional Science.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London Hospital, Head and Neck Centre, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9417024</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1068-9508</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inspiratory muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">presbyphonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">speech breathing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">voice therapy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOO.0000000000001122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00020840-990000000-00239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Living longer: how our population is changing and why it matters. 2018 [cited 2021 Nov 16]. Available at: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/birthsdeathsandmarriages/ageing/articles/livinglongerhowourpopulationischangingandwhyitmatters/2018&#x2013;08-13 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallick AS, Garas G, McGlashan J. Presbylaryngis: a state-of-the-art review. Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2019; 27:168&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend BG, Chen JTH, Wuthrich VM. Barriers and facilitators to social participation in older adults: a systematic literature review. Clin Gerontol 2021; 44:359&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Internet access &#x2013; households and individuals, Great Britain. 2019 [cited 2025 Jan 10]. Available at: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/householdcharacteristics/homeinternetandsocialmediausage/bulletins/internetaccesshouseholdsandindividuals/2019 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninkilampi R, Casey AN, Singh MF, Brodaty H. The association between social engagement, loneliness, and risk of dementia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Alzheimers Dis 2018; 66:1619&#x2013;1633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steptoe A, Shankar A, Demakakos P, Wardle J. Social isolation, loneliness, and all-cause mortality in older men and women. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2013; 110:5797&#x2013;5801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubinski RW, Richard J. Normal aging and environmental effects on communication. Semin Speech Lang 1997; 18:107&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer AD, Carder PC, White DL, et al. The impact of communication impairments on the social relationships of older adults: pathways to psychological well being. J Speech Lang Hear Res 2019; 62:1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy N, Merrill RM, Gray SD, Smith EM. Voice disorders in the general population: prevalence, risk factors, and occupational impact. Laryngoscope 2005; 115:1988&#x2013;1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SM. Self-reported impact of dysphonia in a primary care population: an epidemiological study. Laryngoscope 2010; 120:2022&#x2013;2032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya N. The prevalence of voice problems among adults in the United States. The Laryngoscope 2014; 124:2359&#x2013;2362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy N, Stemple J, Merrill RM, Thomas L. Epidemiology of voice disorders in the elderly: preliminary findings. The Laryngoscope 2007; 117:628&#x2013;633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golub JS, Chen PH, Otto KJ, et al. Prevalence of perceived dysphonia in a geriatric population. J Am Geriatr Soc 2006; 54:1736&#x2013;1739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernambuco L, Espelt A, G&#xf3;is ACB, de Lima KC. Voice disorders in older adults living in nursing homes: prevalence and associated factors. J Voice 2017; 31:510.e15&#x2013;510.e21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turley R, Cohen S. Impact of voice and swallowing problems in the elderly. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2009; 140:33&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LH, Doan TN, Chang FC, et al. Prevalence of voice disorders in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Speech Lang Pathol 2023; 32:1758&#x2013;1769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ara&#xfa;jo Pernambuco L, Espelt A, Balata PMM, De Lima KC. Prevalence of voice disorders in the elderly: a systematic review of population-based studies. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol 2015; 272:2601&#x2013;2609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids T, Klein AM, Johns MM. Current dysphonia trends in patients over the age of 65: is vocal atrophy becoming more prevalent? Laryngoscope 2012; 122:332&#x2013;335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano S, Kimura M, Nito T, et al. Clinical analysis of presbylarynx &#x2013; vocal fold atrophy in elderly individuals. Auris Nasus Larynx 2009; 37:461&#x2013;464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alston M, Saccente-Kennedy B. Audit of referrals to RNTNE SLT ENT, January 2015&#x2013;June 2017. Unpublished; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacks A, Kavookjian H, Kraft S. Comparative evaluation and management of dysphonia between adults&#x200a;&lt;&#x200a;65 and &#x2265;65 years of age. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2021; 165:142&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almutawa D, Lagos-Villaseca A, Albathi M, et al. Geriatric voice: distinctive clinical profiles of working seniors in a tertiary laryngology clinic. J Voice 2024. doi: 10.1016/j.jvoice.2023.12.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvoice.2023.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stradtman M, Etter NM. Reframing aging voice and presbyphonia: what else can we do? Perspect ASHA Spec Interest Groups 2022; 7:1335&#x2013;1346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sund LT, Cameron B, Johns MM, et al. Laryngologists&#x2019; reported decision-making in presbyphonia treatment. J Voice 2021; 38:723&#x2013;730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns MM III, Arviso LC, Ramadan F. Challenges and opportunities in the management of the aging voice. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2011; 145:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galluzzi F, WernerF G. The aging voice: a systematic review of presbyphonia. Eur Geriatr Med 2018; 9:559&#x2013;570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins R, Maria Gon&#xe7;alvez T, Pessin A, Branco A. Aging voice: presbyphonia. 2014;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kost KM, Sataloff RT. The Aging Voice. Curr Otorhinolaryngol Rep 2020; 8 3:321&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdonck-de Leeuw IM, Mahieu HF. Vocal aging and the impact on daily life: a longitudinal study. J Voice 2004; 18:193&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosow DE, Pan DR. Presbyphonia and minimal glottic insufficiency. Otolaryngol Clin North Am 2019; 52:617&#x2013;625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzedimi C, Francesco D, Livi W, Spinosi MC, Felice D. Objective evaluation of presbyphonia: spectroacoustic study on 142 patients with Praat. 2017 [cited 2021 July 29]. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2016.05.022 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstr&#xf6;m E, &#xd6;hlund Wistbacka G, L&#xf6;tvall A, et al. How older adults relate to their own voices: a qualitative study of subjective experiences of the aging voice. Logoped Phoniatr Vocol 2023; 48:163&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young VN. Patients&#x2019; attitudes regarding treatment for vocal fold atrophy. J Voice 2020; 34:763&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etter NM, Stemple JC, Howell DM. Defining the lived experience of older adults with voice disorders. J Voice 2013; 27:61&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama Y. Clinical assessment of elderly vocal folds by laryngoscopy. In: Aging voice. Singapore: Springer; 2017 [cited 2025 Feb 13]. p. 45&#x2013;52. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-10-3698-9_5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos M, Azevedo S, Sousa F, et al. Presbylarynx: is it a sign of the health status of the elderly? 2021 [cited 2021 May 12]. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2020.12.034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta M. Age-related histological changes of the vocal folds. In: Makiyama K, Hirano S, editors. Aging voice. Singapore: Springer; 2017 [cited 2025 Feb 13]. p. 9&#x2013;25. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2013;981&#x2013;10&#x2013;3698&#x2013;9_2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves TM, Helena R, Martins G, et al . Transmission electron microscopy of the presbylarynx in the process of voice aging. 2018 [cited 2021 July 29]. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2016.11.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawley BK, Dehom S, Thiel C, et al. Assessment of clinical and social characteristics that distinguish presbylaryngis from pathologic presbyphonia in elderly individuals. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2018; 144:566&#x2013;571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewoehner DE, Kleinerman J, Liotta L. Elastic behavior of postmortem human lungs: effects of aging and mild emphysema. J Appl Physiol 1975; 39:943&#x2013;949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank NR, Mead J, Ferris BG. The mechanical behavior of the lungs in healthy elderly persons. J Clin Invest 1957; 36:1680&#x2013;1687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens JP, Pache JC, Nicod LP. Physiological changes in respiratory function associated with ageing. Eur Respir J 1999; 13:197&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittman C, Edelman NH, Norris AH, Shock NW. Relationship between chest wall and pulmonary compliance and age. J Appl Physiol 1965; 20:1211&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright PL, Kronmal RA, Manolio TA, et al. Respiratory muscle strength in the elderly: correlates and reference values. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 1994; 149:430&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epiu I, Gandevia SC, Boswell-Ruys CL, et al. Respiratory-related evoked potentials in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and healthy aging. Physiol Rep 2022; 10:e15519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoit JD, Hixon TJ. Age and speech breathing. J Speech Lang Hear Res 1987; 30:351&#x2013;366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoit JD, Hixon TJ, Altman ME, Morgan WJ. Speech breathing in women. J Speech Lang Hear Res 1989; 32:353&#x2013;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber JE. Effects of utterance length and vocal loudness on speech breathing in older adults. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 2008; 164:323&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber JE, Spruill J. Age-related changes to speech breathing with increased vocal loudness. J Speech Lang Hear Res 2008; 51:651&#x2013;668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperry EE, Klich RJ. Speech breathing in senescent and younger women during oral reading. J Speech Lang Hear Res 1992; 35:1246&#x2013;1255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber J, Darling-White M. Longitudinal changes in speech breathing in older adults with and without Parkinson's disease. Semin Speech Lang 2017; 38:200&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Halstead L, Simpson A, et al. The impact of respiratory function on voice in patients with presbyphonia. J Voice 2020; 36:256&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaca M, Cobeta I, Mora E, Reyes P. Clinical assessment of glottal insufficiency in age-related dysphonia. 2017 [cited 2021 July 29]. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2015.12.010 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccente-Kennedy B, Gillies F, Desjardins M, et al. A systematic review of speech-language pathology interventions for presbyphonia using the rehabilitation treatment specification system. J Voice 2024. doi: 10.1016/j.jvoice.2023.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvoice.2023.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaca M, Mora E, Cobeta I. The aging voice: influence of respiratory and laryngeal changes. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2015; 153:409&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon T, An S, Ahn J, et al. Calcium hydroxylapatite injection laryngoplasty for the treatment of presbylaryngis: long-term results. Laryngoscope 2010; 120:326&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avdiyuk A, Garnica P, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Herranz R, et al. In-office hyaluronic acid injection of vocal folds in patients with presbyphonia. J Clin Med 2025; 14:960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Herranz R, Navarro-Mediano A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Garc&#xed;a E, Plaza G. Autologous adipose tissue injection of vocal cords in presbyphonia. Otolaryngol Neck Surg 2022; 167:118&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allensworth JJ, O&#x2019;Dell K, Ziegler A, et al. Treatment outcomes of bilateral medialization thyroplasty for presbylaryngis. J Voice 2019; 33:40&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano S, Sugiyama Y, Kaneko M, et al. Intracordal injection of basic fibroblast growth factor in 100 cases of vocal fold atrophy and scar. Laryngoscope 2021; 131:2059&#x2013;2064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo P, Murry T. Short-term voice improvement after repeated office-based platelet-rich plasma PRP injection in patients with vocal fold scar, sulcus, and atrophy. J Voice 2023; 37:621&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart T, Dijkers MP, Whyte J, et al. A theory-driven system for the specification of rehabilitation treatments. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2019; 100:172&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stemple JC, Lee L, D&#x2019;Amico B, Pickup B. Efficacy of vocal function exercises as a method of improving voice production. J Voice 1994; 8:271&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler A, Verdolini Abbott K, Johns M, et al. Preliminary data on two voice therapy interventions in the treatment of presbyphonia. Laryngoscope 2014; 124:1869&#x2013;1876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AM, Goldfine A. Intrasubject reliability of maximum phonation time. J Voice 2016; 30:775.e1&#x2013;775.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearl Solomon N, Garlitz SJ, Milbrath RL. Respiratory and laryngeal contributions to maximum phonation duration. J Voice 2000; 14:331&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawaya Y, Sato M, Ishizaka M, et al. Maximum phonation time is a useful assessment for older adults requiring long-term care/support. Phys Ther Res 2022; 25:35&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young N, Hapner ER. AAO-HNS Bulletin. 2020 [cited 2026 Jan 15]. Changing the dialogue about aging voice. Available at: https://bulletin.entnet.org/home/article/21247860/changing-the-dialogue-about-aging-voice</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hapner ER, Sund LT. From evaluation to intervention. In: Voice therapy: clinical case studies. 6th ed. Plural Publishing; 2026. p. 59&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Bonilha S, Carolina S. The impact of respiratory exercises on voice outcomes: a systematic review of the literature. J Voice. 2019 [cited 2021 May 19]. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2019.01.011 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angadi V, McMullen C, Andreatta R, et al. Biobehavioral measures of presbylaryngeus. J Voice 2018; 34:415&#x2013;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Halstead L, Simpson A, et al . Voice and respiratory characteristics of men and women seeking treatment for presbyphonia. J Voice. 2020 [cited 2021 May 12]. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2020.08.040 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsky MA, Shelly S, Rothenberger SD, et al. Phonation resistance training exercises (PhoRTE) with and without expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) for patients with presbyphonia: a noninferiority randomized clinical trial. J Voice. 2021 [cited 2021 May 11]. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvoice.2021.02.015 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Halstead L, Simpson A, et al. Respiratory muscle strength training to improve vocal function in patients with presbyphonia. J Voice 2022; 36:344&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao TJ, Ziegler A, Solomon NP. Phonation resistance training exercises and inspiratory muscle strength training improve voice in older adults with presbyphonia: a single-subject experimental study. J Voice 2025. doi: 10.1016/j.jvoice.2025.10.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvoice.2025.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x142;odarczak M, Heldner M. Respiratory constraints in verbal and nonverbal communication. Front Psychol. 2017;8:708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowell SY, Barkmeier-Kraemer JM, Hoit JD, Story BH. Respiratory and laryngeal function during spontaneous speaking in teachers with voice disorders. J Speech Lang Hear Res 2008; 51:333&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapienza CM, Stathopoulos ET, Brown WS. Speech Breathing during Reading in Women With Vocal Nodules. J Voice 1997; 11:195&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaeffer N, Cavallo SA, Wall M, Diakow C. Speech breathing behavior in normal and moderately to severely dysphonic subjects during connected speech. J Med Speech-Lang Pathol 2002; 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundarrajan A, Huber JE, Sivasankar MP. Respiratory and laryngeal changes with vocal loading in younger and older individuals. J Speech Lang Hear Res 2017; 60:2551&#x2013;2556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binazzi B, Lanini B, Gigliotti F, Scano G. Breathing pattern and chest wall kinematics during phonation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease patients. Respiration 2013; 86:462&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loudon RG, Lee L, Holcomb BJ. Volumes and breathing patterns during speech in healthy and asthmatic subjects. J Speech Lang Hear Res 1988; 31:219&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowell SY, Kelley RT, Edwards H, et al. Effects of respiratory lung volume training (RLVT) on speech breathing, voice and vocal function: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Speech Lang Pathol 2025; 34:2115&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belafsky PC, Postma GN, Reulbach TR, et al. Muscle tension dysphonia as a sign of underlying glottal insufficiency. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2002; 127:448&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Jomphe V, Lagadec-Gaulin L, et al. Influence of sensory monitoring on speech breathing planning processes: an exploratory study in aging speakers reporting dyspnea. J Speech Lang Hear Res 2024; 67:2483&#x2013;2498.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>