<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41618326</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of muscle strength assessment in adolescent polycystic ovary syndrome: a case control study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">137</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-026-04275-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is a common endocrine disorder in adolescents characterized by irregular menstrual cycles, hyperandrogenism and metabolic disturbances. While much of the research on PCOS has focused on the hormonal and metabolic effects, the impact of PCOS on physical health, particularly muscle strength, has not been adequately studied. Previous studies suggest that hyperandrogenism may play a role in muscle strength, but the relationship between muscle function and PCOS in adolescents has not been well studied. Understanding this relationship is critical to improving health outcomes and managing the long-term effects of PCOS in adolescents. The aim of this study was to investigate muscle strength in adolescent women with PCOS and its possible association with dietary habits, hormonal markers and metabolic factors such as hyperandrogenism.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The study was conducted on 45 patients with polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) and 44 healthy adolescents who presented to the adolescent outpatient clinic of our hospital between September 2022 and January 2023. PCOS in adolescents was diagnosed according to the Rotterdam Criteria 2018. Free testosterone, follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), insulin, estradiol, sex hormone-binding globulin (SHBG), anti-M&#xfc;llerian hormone (AMH) and 25-OH vitamin D were measured in serum. The free androgen index (FAI) and the homeostatic model of insulin resistance (HOMA-IR) were calculated. The groups were compared using data from the SCOFF scale, the Food Craving Questionnaire-Trait (FCQ-T), the Night Questionnaire, the Eating Questionnaire (NEQ) and the Three-Factor Eating Questionnaire (TFEQ-R18). Hand grip strength was measured using the Jamar hand dynamometer for the dominant and non-dominant hand.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The average age in the study and control groups was 17 years. There was no difference between the two groups in terms of age, body mass index (BMI) and lean BMI (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.164, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.074, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.398). Muscle strength of the dominant hand was statistically higher in the PCOS group (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.037). There was no statistically significant difference between the groups in SCOFF, FCQ-T, NEQ and TFEQ-R18 scores (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). In the regression analysis, free androgen index (FAI), anti-mullerian hormone (AMH) and 25-OH vitamin D were statistically effective in explaining the level of muscle strength (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; &lt;0.001; 0.006). Every 1&#xa0;mg/L increase in AMH level leads to a 1.42&#x2013;2.18&#xa0;kg increase in muscle strength (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and every 1 unit increase in FAI leads to a 0.54&#x2013;0.92&#xa0;kg increase in muscle strength (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our study shows that muscle strength of the dominant hand is higher in adolescent PCOS patients, emphasizing the importance of hyperandrogenism in the pathophysiology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-026-04275-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacinti</LastName><ForeName>Huriye Guvenc</ForeName><Initials>HG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Ankara Etlik Zubeyde Han&#x131;m Women's Health Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, 06010, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibanoglu</LastName><ForeName>Mujde Can</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Ankara Etlik Zubeyde Han&#x131;m Women's Health Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, 06010, Turkey. drmujdecan@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Celik</LastName><ForeName>G&#xfc;lsemin Erturk</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Specialist, Ministry of Youth and Sports, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanisoglu</LastName><ForeName>Yavuz</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m Beyaz&#x131;t University, Atat&#xfc;rk Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ustun</LastName><ForeName>Yaprak Engin</ForeName><Initials>YE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Ankara Etlik Zubeyde Han&#x131;m Women's Health Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, 06010, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Night eating questionnaire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">The food cravings Questionnaire&#x2013;Trait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Three-Factor diet questionnaire</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Approval was obtained by the institutional review board from Ankara Etlik Zubeyde Han&#x131;m Women&#x2019;s Health Training and Research Hospital on 21.09. 2022 # 2022/142. A verbal and written informed consent was obtained from all participants. All authors read and approved the final version of the submitted manuscript. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Consent for publication: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41618326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12933921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-026-04275-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-026-04275-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Qiao J. Association of insulin resistance and elevated androgen levels with polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS): A review of literature. J Healthc Eng. 2022;2022:9240569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9240569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8959968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35356614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen SB, Black MH, Smith N, Martinez MM, Jacobsen SJ, Porter AH, et al. Prevalence of polycystic ovary syndrome in adolescents. Fertil Steril. 2013;100(2):470&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2013.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3813299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23756098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede HJ, Misso ML, Costello MF, Dokras A, Laven J, Moran L, et al. Recommendations from the international evidence-based guideline for the assessment and management of polycystic ovary syndrome. Fertil Steril. 2018;110(3):364&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2018.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6939856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30033227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcaterra V, Rossi V, Massini G, Casini F, Zuccotti G, Fabiano V. Probiotics and polycystic ovary syndrome: A perspective for management in adolescents with obesity. Nutrients. 2023;15(14):3144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15143144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10384396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Zhang J, Cheng X, Nie X, He B. Insulin resistance in polycystic ovary syndrome across various tissues: an updated review of pathogenesis, evaluation, and treatment. J Ovarian Res. 2023;16(1):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-022-01091-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eralp B, Ibanoglu MC, Engin-Ustun Y. Evaluation of pregnancy and neonatal outcomes according to the phenotypic types of polycystic ovary syndrome: A prospective study. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2023 Jun 6. 10.1002/ijgo.14882. PMID: 37278384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huguelet PS, Olson E, Sass A, Bartz S, Hsu S, Cree-Green M. Application of a standard Cross-Specialty workup for diagnosis and metabolic screening of obese adolescents with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Adolesc Health. 2021;68(3):589&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2020.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32819830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshammari G, Khan R, Brameld J, Amer S, Lomax MA. Gene expression of inflammatory markers in adipose tissue between obese women with polycystic ovary and normal obese women. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2017;21(5):1099&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borruel S, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Dur&#xe1;n E, Alpa&#xf1;&#xe9;s M, Mart&#xed; D, Alvarez-Blasco F, Luque-Ram&#xed;rez M, et al. Global adiposity and thickness of intraperitoneal and mesenteric adipose tissue depots are increased in women with polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS). J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98(3):1254&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2012-3698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23386652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovejoy JC, Bray GA, Bourgeois MO, Macchiavelli R, Rood JC, Greeson C, et al. Exogenous androgens influence body composition and regional body fat distribution in obese postmenopausal women&#x2013;a clinical research center study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1996;81(6):2198&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8964851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliskan Guzelce E, Eyupoglu D, Torgutalp S, Aktoz F, Portakal O, Demirel H, et al. Is muscle mechanical function altered in polycystic ovary syndrome? Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2019;300(3):771&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-019-05229-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31263987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber TM, Franks S. Obesity and polycystic ovary syndrome. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2021;95(4):531&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.14421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferriman D, Gallwey JD. Clinical assessment of body hair growth in women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1961;21:1440&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jcem-21-11-1440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13892577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doshi A, Zaheer A, Stiller MJ. A comparison of current acne grading systems and proposal of a novel system. Int J Dermatol. 1997;36(6):416&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-4362.1997.00099.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9248884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atasoy N, Sara&#xe7;l&#x131; &#xd6;, Konuk N, Ankarali H, Guriz SO, Akdemir A, Sevincer G, Atik L. The reliability and validity of Turkish version of the night eating questionnaire in psychiatric outpatient population. Alpha Psychiatry. 2014;15:238&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muftuoglu S, Kiziltan G, Ok MA. The reliability and validity of the Turkish version of food cravings questionnaire (FCQ-T) in major depressive disorder patients. Psychiatry Behav Sci. 2018;8(1):198&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaku&#x15f; S&#x15e;, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m H, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;k&#xf6;zt&#xfc;rk &#x15e;. &#xdc;&#xe7; fakt&#xf6;rl&#xfc; Yeme &#xf6;l&#xe7;e&#x11f;inin T&#xfc;rk k&#xfc;lt&#xfc;r&#xfc;ne uyarlanmas&#x131;: Ge&#xe7;erlik ve g&#xfc;venirlik &#xe7;al&#x131;&#x15f;mas&#x131;. TAF Prev Med Bull. 2016;15(3):229&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lauzon B, Romon M, Deschamps V, Lafay L, Borys JM, Karlsson J, et al. The Three-Factor eating Questionnaire-R18 is able to distinguish among different eating patterns in a general population. J Nutr. 2004;134(9):2372&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/134.9.2372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15333731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan J. Diabetes and eating disorders: update to the NICE guideline. J Diabetes Nurs. 2017;21(3):103&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnell T, Cussen L, McIlroy M, O&#x2019;Reilly MW. Characterizing skeletal muscle dysfunction in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab. 2022;13:20420188221113140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20420188221113140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9297442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi M, Zello G, McBreairty L, Pierson R, Chizen D, Chilibeck P. Sarcopenia is positively associated with poor dietary intakes of women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44:S26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi M, Pierson RA, Parry SA, Kaviani M, Chilibeck PD. Obesity, but not hyperandrogenism or insulin resistance, predicts skeletal muscle mass in reproductive-aged women with polycystic ovary syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis of 45 observational studies. Obes Rev. 2021;22(8):e13255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33855800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soyupek F, Guney M, Eris S, Cerci S, Yildiz S, Mungan T. Evaluation of hand functions in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2008;24(10):571&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09513590802288218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19012100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baioccato V, Quinto G, Rovai S, Conte F, Dassie F, Neunh&#xe4;euserer D, Vecchiato M, Palermi S, Gasperetti A, Bullo V, Camozzi V, Vettor R, Ermolao A, Mioni R. Do androgenic Pattern, insulin state and growth hormone affect cardiorespiratory fitness and strength in young women with PCOS? Biomedicines. 2022;10(9):2176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10092176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9496105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36140277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kogure GS, Silva RC, Miranda-Furtado CL, Ribeiro VB, Pedroso DCC, Melo AS, Ferriani RA, Reis RMD. Hyperandrogenism enhances muscle strength after progressive resistance Training, independent of body Composition, in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(9):2642&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29927897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro VB, Kogure GS, Lopes IP, Silva RC, Pedroso DCC, de Melo AS, de Souza HCD, Ferriani RA, Miranda Furtado CL, Dos Reis RM. Effects of continuous and intermittent aerobic physical training on hormonal and metabolic profile, and body composition in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: A randomized controlled trial. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2020;93(2):173&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.14194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickenlund A, Carlstr&#xf6;m K, Ekblom B, Brismar TB, von Schoultz B, Hirschberg AL. Hyperandrogenicity is an alternative mechanism underlying oligomenorrhea or amenorrhea in female athletes and May improve physical performance. Fertil Steril. 2003;79(4):947&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0015-0282(02)04850-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12749436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson RL, Buckley JD, Moran LJ, Noakes M, Clifton PM, Norman RJ, et al. Comparison of aerobic exercise capacity and muscle strength in overweight women with and without polycystic ovary syndrome. BJOG. 2009;116(9):1242&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1471-0528.2009.02177.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kogure GS, Silva RC, Picchi Ramos FK, Miranda-Furtado CL, Lara LAS, Ferriani RA, et al. Women with polycystic ovary syndrome have greater muscle strength irrespective of body composition. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2015;31(3):237&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09513590.2014.982083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25430509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shechtman O, Gestewitz L, Kimble C. Reliability and validity of the dynex dynamometer. J Hand Ther. 2005;18(3):339&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1197/j.jht.2005.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16059855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirone D, Berbrier DE, Gibbs JC, Usselman CW. Health-related physical fitness in women with polycystic ovary syndrome versus controls: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023 Mar;15. 10.1007/s00404-023-07004-w. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 36920532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36920532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wu W, Li X, Wu H, Wang X, Tian W, Zhang H. Excessively increased skeletal muscle mass of the bilateral lower limbs is associated with hyperuricemia in females with polycystic ovarian syndrome. Reprod Sci. 2023;30(9):2758&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43032-023-01214-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36944907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cetik S, Acikgoz A, Yildiz BO. Investigation of taste function and eating behavior in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Appetite. 2022;168:105776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2021.105776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeanes YM, Reeves S, Gibson EL, Piggott C, May VA, Hart KH. Binge eating behaviours and food cravings in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Appetite. 2017;109:24&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2016.11.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27825940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Tfayli H, Michaliszyn SF, Lee S, Nasr A, Arslanian S. Anti-M&#xfc;llerian hormone in obese adolescent girls with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Adolesc Health. 2017;60(3):333&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2016.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5326592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson S, Seifer DB, Shabanova V, Lynn AY, Howe C, Rowe E, Caprio S, Vash-Margita A. The association between anti-M&#xfc;llerian hormone and vitamin 25(OH)D serum levels and polycystic ovarian syndrome in adolescent females. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2020;18(1):118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12958-020-00676-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7679991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33218348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede HJ, Tay CT, Laven J, Dokras A, Moran LJ, Piltonen TT, Costello MF, Boivin J, Redman M, Boyle LA, Norman J, Mousa RJ, Joham A, International AE. Network. Recommendations from the 2023 international Evidence-based guideline for the assessment and management of polycystic ovary syndrome. Fertil Steril. 2023;120(4):767&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2023.07.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37589624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>