<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41415142</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0976-7800</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of mid-life health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Midlife Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of Physical Activity in Women's Mid-life: Neuroscience, Longevity, and Disease Prevention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>496</StartPage><EndPage>499</EndPage><MedlinePgn>496-499</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jmh.jmh_140_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Physical activity (PA) is vital for managing menopausal symptoms and reducing noncommunicable diseases in middle-aged women. Despite the known benefits, many women do not meet the recommended activity levels and view household tasks as sufficient owing to factors such as time constraints, lack of motivation, or physical limitations. This article explores the significance, forms, and health impacts of PA in menopausal women. Regular PA, including aerobic exercise, resistance training, and yoga, offers several health benefits. Exercise enhances adult neurogenesis, brain structure, learning, memory, and cognitive abilities, potentially preventing age-related declines. PA during mid-life, defined as regular engagement in exercise such as walking, cycling, or resistance training, is linked to successful aging. Successful aging refers to the absence of chronic illnesses, disabilities, or mental health issues. Exercise improves sleep quality and reduces stress through endorphin production. Regular PA reduces the risk of chronic diseases including cancer, cardiovascular disease, and diabetes. Recommendations include cardiorespiratory activities, strength training, and balance exercises. Understanding these benefits can promote better health outcomes in this critical life stage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Mid-life Health.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gangadharan</LastName><ForeName>Shobana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Health Sciences, University of Buraimi, Al Buraimi, Oman.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nisar</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Kashif</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Medical Sciences, College of Health Sciences, University of Buraimi, Al Buraimi, Oman.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Midlife Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101552746</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0976-7800</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">longevity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mid-life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">yoga</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41415142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12711176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jmh.jmh_140_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JMH-16-496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal N, Meeta M, Chawla N. Menopause management: A manual for primary care practitioners and nurse practitioners. J Midlife Health. 2022;13(Suppl 1):S2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlSwayied G, Guo H, Rookes T, Frost R, Hamilton FL. Assessing the acceptability and effectiveness of mobile-based physical activity interventions for midlife women during menopause: Systematic review of the literature. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2022;10:e40271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36485026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aneesh M, Mahanta N. Physical activity levels, motivators and barriers to exercise among men and women aged 30 to 50 years in Rourkela, India. J Midlife Health. 2022;13:278&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10266563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37324789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Townsend MK, Okereke OI, Franco OH, Hu FB, Grodstein F. Physical activity at midlife in relation to successful survival in women at age 70 years or older. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170:194&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dishman RK, Heath GW, Schmidt MD, Lee IM. Physical Activity Epidemiology. Human Kinetics. 2021:673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Let's be Active the Global Action Plan on Physical Activity 2018 &#x2013;2030.  [[Last accessed on 2025 Jun 08]].  Available from: https://www.who.int/initiatives/gappa .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangadharan S, Arulappan J, Matua GA, Bhagavathy MG, Alrahbi H. Effectiveness of yoga on menopausal symptoms and quality of life among menopausal women: A systematic review. Int J Nutr Pharmacol Neurol Dis. 2024;14:300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow ZS, Moreland AT, Macpherson H, Teo WP. The central mechanisms of resistance training and its effects on cognitive function. Sports Med. 2021;51:2483&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw SB, Levy Y, Mizzi A, Herman G, McKinnon MC, Heisz JJ, et al. Combined aerobic exercise and neurofeedback lead to improved task-relevant intrinsic network synchrony. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16:838614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9237564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35774480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki WA. Editorial: Exercise to enhance mental health. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16:1082218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36504630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso JC, Shang A, Elman M, Karmouta R, Suzuki WA. Acute exercise improves prefrontal cortex but not hippocampal function in healthy adults. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2015;21:791&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northey JM, Cherbuin N, Pumpa KL, Smee DJ, Rattray B. Exercise interventions for cognitive function in adults older than 50: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:154&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greendale GA, Han W, Huang M, Upchurch DM, Karvonen-Gutierrez C, Avis NE, et al. Longitudinal assessment of physical activity and cognitive outcomes among women at midlife. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e213227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falck RS, Davis JC, Best JR, Crockett RA, Liu-Ambrose T. Impact of exercise training on physical and cognitive function among older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurobiol Aging. 2019;79:119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31051329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2018;Dolezal BA, Neufeld EV, Boland DM, Martin JL, Cooper CB. Interrelationship between sleep and exercise:a systematic review. Advances in preventive medicine. 2017;2017:1364387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5385214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28458924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams SM, Farmer VL, Taylor BJ, Taylor RW. Do more active children sleep more?A repeated cross-sectional analysis using accelerometry. PLoS One. 2014;9:e93117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3973701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24695112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lardier DT, Coakley KE, Holladay KR, Amorim FT, Zuhl MN. Exercise as a useful intervention to reduce alcohol consumption and improve physical fitness in individuals with alcohol use disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Psychol. 2021;12:675285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8292965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34305729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbrother K, Cartner B, Alley JR, Curry CD, Dickinson DL, Morris DM, et al. Effects of exercise timing on sleep architecture and nocturnal blood pressure in prehypertensives. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2014;10:691&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4270305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25540588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godse AS, Shejwal BR, Godse AA. Effects of suryanamaskar on relaxation among college students with high stress in Pune, India. Int J Yoga. 2015;8:15&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4278130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25558129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooney GM, Dwan K, Greig CA, Lawlor DA, Rimer J, Waugh FR, et al. Exercise for depression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;2013:CD004366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9721454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24026850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dishman RK, O&#x2019;Connor PJ. Lessons in exercise neurobiology: The case of endorphins. Ment Health Phys Act. 2009;2:4&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Strategy on Diet. Physical Activity and Health.  [[Last accessed on 2025 Jun 08]].  Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9241592222 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warburton DE, Bredin SS. Cardiovascular health benefits of physical activity: Time to focus on strengths. Cah Nutr Di&#xe9;t&#xe9;tique. 2021;56:40&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical Activity.  [[Last accessed on 2025 Jun 08]].  Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/physical-activity .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson DH, Jones GR, Rice CL. Ageing and physical activity: Evidence to develop exercise recommendations for older adults. Can J Public Health. 2007;98(Suppl 2):S69&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18213941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart KJ. Exercise training and the cardiovascular consequences of type 2 diabetes and hypertension: Plausible mechanisms for improving cardiovascular health. JAMA. 2002;288:1622&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12350193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McTiernan A, Friedenreich CM, Katzmarzyk PT, Powell KE, Macko R, Buchner D, et al. Physical activity in cancer prevention and survival: A systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1252&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosone CB, Hong CC, Goodwin PJ.  Host factors and risk of breast cancer recurrence: Genetic, epigenetic and biologic factors and breast cancer outcomes. In: Ganz PA, editor. Improving Outcomes for Breast Cancer Survivors: Perspectives on Research Challenges and Opportunities. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2015.  [[Last accessed on 2025 Jun 09]]. pp. 143&#x2013;53. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-16366-6_10 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26059934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Committee Scientific Report</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipil&#xe4; S, T&#xf6;rm&#xe4;kangas T, Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, Aukee P, Kujala UM, Kovanen V, et al. Muscle and bone mass in middle-aged women: Role of menopausal status and physical activity. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2020;11:698&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7296268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32017473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>