<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41512037</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-healing for the long haul: In situ automation delivers century-scale fracture recovery in structural composites.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2523447123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2523447123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2523447123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2523447123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nature's structural composites, such as bone and wood, achieve mechanical performance through hierarchical multimaterial design. Though, their real vantage lies in the exceptional ability to repeatedly heal after damage. Synthetic fiber-reinforced polymer (FRP) composites also leverage material hierarchy via fibrous reinforcement encapsulated within a polymer matrix, maximizing stiffness and strength. However, the layered architecture of laminated FRP composites makes them vulnerable to interlaminar delamination-debonding of fibers from the matrix-which significantly compromises structural integrity. Recently, we introduced a self-healing strategy via in situ heating, where soft yet tough thermoplastic inclusions achieve interlaminar fracture recovery via polymer chain re-entanglement, i.e., thermal remending. Here, in our latest embodiment, by automating in situ thermo-mechanical experiments, we achieve an order-of-magnitude enhancement in self-healing repeatability-reaching an unprecedented 1,000 cycles. Healing begins at 175% and slowly declines to 60% of the mode-I fracture resistance of a plain (nonhealing) composite, revealing unique chemo-physical mechanisms that govern this behavior. Both fiber-debris accumulation in the molten poly(ethylene-co-methacrylic acid) (EMAA) healing agent, and waning interfacial chemical reactions between the EMAA and epoxy matrix, contribute. A Weibull distribution capturing this complex fracture recovery predicts an asymptotic healing limit above 40%, suggesting sustained repair is possible. Translating these newfound thermal remending results into real-world context, a modest quarterly self-healing schedule could maintain interlaminar fracture repair of FRP composites for over 125 y-well beyond the typical design life of many modern structures including aircraft and wind turbines. Thus, this latest self-healing paradigm effectively eliminates delamination as a failure mode.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turicek</LastName><ForeName>Jack S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8661-8466</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27695.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Zachary J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil, Construction, and Environmental Engineering, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27695.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakshatrala</LastName><ForeName>Kalyana B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1744-6338</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of Houston, Houston, TX 77204.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patrick</LastName><ForeName>Jason F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4378-0812</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27695.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil, Construction, and Environmental Engineering, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27695.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>W912HQ21C0044</GrantID><Agency>DOD | Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program (SERDP)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DGE-2137100</GrantID><Agency>NSF | National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship Program (GRFP)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fiber-composites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-healing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The self-healing composite reported in this work has been issued a US patent (11,613,088B2) with J.F.P. listed as an inventor who is also the founding President and Chief Technology Officer of the company Structeryx, Inc. that has licensed this patent from North Carolina State University.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12799153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2523447123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Poundarik A. A., et al. , Dilatational band formation in bone. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 109, 19178&#x2013;19183 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3511118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23129653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes A. N., et al. , Nanostructure of cellulose microfibrils in spruce wood. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 108, E1195&#x2013;E1203 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3223458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22065760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratzl P., Weinkamer R., Nature&#x2019;s hierarchical materials. Prog. Mater. Sci. 52, 1263&#x2013;1334 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegst U. G. K., Bai H., Saiz E., Tomsia A. P., Ritchie R. O., Bioinspired structural materials. Nat. Mater. 14, 23&#x2013;36 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tol A. F., et al. , The mechanoresponse of bone is closely related to the osteocyte lacunocanalicular network architecture. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 117, 32251&#x2013;32259 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7768754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33288694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder A. D., et al. , Prolonged in situ self-healing in structural composites via thermo-reversible entanglement. Nat. Commun. 13, 1&#x2013;12 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9622832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36316323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. K., Sham M. L., Impact and delamination failure of woven-fabric composites. Compos. Sci. Technol. 60, 745&#x2013;761 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisnom M. R., The role of delamination in failure of fibre-reinforced composites. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 370, 1850&#x2013;1870 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22431760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Council N. R., High-Performance Structural Fibers for Advanced Polymer Matrix Composites (The National Academies Press, Washington, DC, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De B., Bera M., Bhattacharjee D., Ray B. C., Mukherjee S., A comprehensive review on fiber-reinforced polymer composites: Raw materials to applications, recycling, and waste management. Prog. Mater. Sci. 146, 101326 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puttegowda M., Rangappa S., Siengchin S., Fiber-Reinforced Polymer Composites: Materials and Manufacturing (Woodhead Publishing, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herakovich C. T., Mechanics of composites: A historical review. Mech. Res. Commun. 41, 1&#x2013;20 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull D., Matrix-dominated properties of polymer matrix composite materials. Mater. Sci. Eng. A 184, 173&#x2013;183 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibo G. A., Hogg P. J., The role of reinforcement architecture on impact damage mechanisms and post-impact compression behaviour. J. Mater. Sci. 31, 1115&#x2013;1137 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamon F., Maragoni L., Carraro P. A., Quaresimin M., Fatigue damage evolution in woven composites with different architectures. Int. J. Fatigue 167, 107365 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talreja R., Assessment of the fundamentals of failure theories for composite materials. Compos. Sci. Technol. 105, 190&#x2013;201 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantwell W. J., Morton J., The significance of damage and defects and their detection in composite materials: A review. J. Strain Anal. Eng. Des. 27, 29&#x2013;42 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giurgiutiu V., &#x201c;Chapter 5 - Damage and failure of aerospace composites&#x201d; in Structural Health Monitoring of Aerospace Composites (Academic Press, 2016), pp. 125&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Zhong S., Lee T. L., Fancey K. S., Mi J., Non-destructive testing and evaluation of composite materials/structures: A state-of-the-art review. Adv. Mech. Eng. 12, 1&#x2013;28 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad M. M., et al. , Failure modes and non-destructive testing techniques for fiber-reinforced polymer composites. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 33, 9519&#x2013;9537 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katnam K. B., Da Silva L. F. M., Young T. M., Bonded repair of composite aircraft structures: A review of scientific challenges and opportunities. Prog. Aerosp. Sci. 61, 26&#x2013;42 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heslehurst R. B., Engineered Repairs of Composite Structures (CRC Press / Taylor &amp; Francis, Boca Raton, ed. 1, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein R. S., Polymer recycling: Opportunities and limitations. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 89, 835&#x2013;838 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC48336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11607263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White S. R., et al. , Autonomic healing of polymer composites. Nature 409, 794&#x2013;797 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11236987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaiszik B. J., et al. , Self-healing polymers and composites. Annu. Rev. Mater. Res. 40, 179&#x2013;211 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diesendruck C. E., Sottos N. R., Moore J. S., White S. R., Biomimetic self-healing. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 54, 10428&#x2013;10447 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26216654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick J. F., Robb M. J., Sottos N. R., Moore J. S., White S. R., Polymers with autonomous life-cycle control. Nature 540, 363&#x2013;370 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown E. N., White S. R., Sottos N. R., Microcapsule induced toughening in a self-healing polymer composite. J. Mater. Sci. 39, 1703&#x2013;1710 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang J. W. C., Bond I. P., A hollow fibre reinforced polymer composite encompassing self-healing and enhanced damage visibility. Compos. Sci. Technol. 65, 1791&#x2013;1799 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trask R. S., Williams G. J., Bond I. P., Bioinspired self-healing of advanced composite structures using hollow glass fibres. J. R. Soc. Interface 4, 363&#x2013;371 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2359865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kousourakis A., Mouritz A. P., The effect of self-healing hollow fibres on the mechanical properties of polymer composites. Smart Mater. Struct. 19, 1&#x2013;9 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qamar I. P., Sottos N. R., Trask R. S., Grand challenges in the design and manufacture of vascular self-healing. Multifunct. Mater. 3, 013001 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chano V., L&#xf3;pez R., Pita P., Collada C., Soto &#xc1;., Proliferation of axial parenchymatic xylem cells is a key step in wound closure of girdled stems in <i>Pinus canariensis</i>. BMC Plant Biol.
15, 64 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohades A., Branfoot C., Rae S., Bond I., Michaud V., Progress in self-healing fiber-reinforced polymer composites. Adv. Mater. Interfaces 5, 1&#x2013;20 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia S. J., Effect of polymer architecture on the intrinsic self-healing character of polymers. Eur. Polym. J. 53, 118&#x2013;125 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordier P., Tournilhac F., Souli&#xe9;-Ziakovic C., Leibler L., Self-healing and thermoreversible rubber from supramolecular assembly. Nature 451, 977&#x2013;980 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18288191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imato K., et al. , Self-healing of chemical gels cross-linked by diarylbibenzofuranone-based trigger-free dynamic covalent bonds at room temperature. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 51, 1138&#x2013;1142 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z., et al. , Self-healing gels based on constitutional dynamic chemistry and their potential applications. Chem. Soc. Rev. 43, 8114&#x2013;8131 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor D. L., M in het Panhuis, Self-healing hydrogels. Adv. Mater. 28, 9060&#x2013;9093 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phadke A., et al. , Rapid self-healing hydrogels. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 109, 4383&#x2013;4388 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22392977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., et al. , A thermally re-mendable cross-linked polymeric material. Science 295, 1698&#x2013;1702 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J. S., Kim H. S., Thomas Hahn H., Healing behavior of a matrix crack on a carbon fiber/mendomer composite. Compos. Sci. Technol. 69, 1082&#x2013;1087 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montarnal D., Capelot M., Tournilhac F., Leibler L., Silica-like malleable materials from permanent organic networks. Science 334, 965&#x2013;968 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22096195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma H., et al. , Self-healable fiber-reinforced vitrimer composites: Overview and future prospects. RSC Adv. 12, 32569&#x2013;32582 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9661690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36425695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes S. A., Zhang W., Branthwaite M., Jones F. R., Self-healing of damage in fibre-reinforced polymer-matrix composites. J. R. Soc. Interface 4, 381&#x2013;387 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2359850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17311783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A. R., Watkins C. A., White S. R., Sottos N. R., Self-healing thermoplastic-toughened epoxy. Polymer 74, 254&#x2013;261 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohades V. M. A., Thermal mending in E-glass reinforced poly(<i>&#x3f5;</i>-caprolactone)/epoxy blends. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf.
99, 129&#x2013;138 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jony S. M. S. R. B., Thapa M., Repeatable self-healing of thermosetting fiber reinforced polymer composites with thermoplastic healant. Smart Mater. Struct. 28, 025037 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin W. H., Turicek J. S., Patrick J. F., Integrated damage sensing and self-healing in polymers and composites: Progress and opportunities. J. Intell. Mater. Syst. Struct. 36, e1045389X251346315 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meure S., Wu D. Y., Furman S., Polyethylene-co-methacrylic acid healing agents for mendable epoxy resins. Acta Mater. 57, 4312&#x2013;4320 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meure S., Wu D. Y., Furman S. A., FTIR study of bonding between a thermoplastic healing agent and a mendable epoxy resin. Vib. Spectrosc. 52, 10&#x2013;15 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meure S., et al. , Confirmation of the healing mechanism in a mendable EMAA-epoxy resin. Eur. Polym. J. 48, 524&#x2013;531 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder A. D., Turicek J. S., Diesendruck C. E., Varley R. J., Patrick J. F., Unraveling chemical and rheological mechanisms of self-healing with EMAA thermoplastics in fiber-reinforced epoxy composites. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 185, 108271 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingkarawat K., Dell&#x2019;Olio C., Varley R. J., Mouritz A. P., Poly(ethylene-co-methacrylic acid) (EMAA) as an efficient healing agent for high performance epoxy networks using diglycidyl ether of bisphenol A (DGEBA). Polymer 92, 153&#x2013;163 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turicek J. S., Snyder A. D., Nakshatrala K. B., Patrick J. F., Topological effects of 3D-printed copolymer interlayers on toughening and in situ self-healing in laminated fiber-composites. Compos. Sci. Technol. 240, 110073 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jony S. M. B., Roy S., Fracture resistance of in-situ healed CFRP composite using thermoplastic healants. Mater. Today Commun. 24, 101067 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang Q., Liu L., Wu Z., Electrothermally self-healing delamination cracks in carbon/epoxy composites using sandwich and tough carbon nanotube/copolymer interleaves. Polymers 14, 4313 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9611350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36297893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turicek J. S., Kamala V., Nakshatrala K. B., Haikal G., Patrick J. F., Tailoring interlaminar shear and mode-I fracture behavior in fiber-composites via soft self-healing thermoplastic inclusions. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 194, 108803 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingkarawat K., Wang C. H., Varley R. J., Mouritz A. P., Self-healing of delamination cracks in mendable epoxy matrix laminates using poly[ethylene-co-(methacrylic acid)] thermoplastic. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 43, 1301&#x2013;1307 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingkarawat K., Wang C. H., Varley R. J., Mouritz A. P., Self-healing of delamination fatigue cracks in carbon fibre-epoxy laminate using mendable thermoplastic. J. Mater. Sci. 47, 4449&#x2013;4456 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingkarawat K., Dell&#x2019;Olio C., Varley R. J., Mouritz A. P., An efficient healing agent for high temperature epoxy composites based upon tetra-glycidyl diamino diphenyl methane. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 78, 201&#x2013;210 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meure S., Furman S., Khor S., Poly[ethylene-co-(methacrylic acid)] healing agents for mendable carbon fiber laminates. Macromol. Mater. Eng. 295, 420&#x2013;424 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International, <i>D5528/D5528M-21: Standard Test Method for Mode I Interlaminar Fracture Toughness of Unidirectional Fiber-Reinforced Polymer Matrix Composites</i> (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick J. F., et al. , Continuous self-healing life cycle in vascularized structural composites. Adv. Mater. 26, 4302&#x2013;4308 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24729175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart K. R., et al. , Repeated healing of delamination damage in vascular composites by pressurized delivery of reactive agents. Compos. Sci. Technol. 151, 1&#x2013;9 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States. Department of Transportation. Bureau of Transportation Statistics, Average age of automobiles and trucks in operation in the united states (2023). https://www.bts.gov/content/average-age-automobiles-and-trucks-operation-united-states. Accessed 18 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiser R. H., Bolinger M., Benchmarking anticipated wind project lifetimes: Results from a survey of U.S. wind industry professionals, Energy markets &amp; policy (2019). https://emp.lbl.gov/publications/benchmarking-anticipated-wind-project. Accessed 18 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States. Department of Transportation. Bureau of Transportation Statistics, Average age of aircraft 2018, Bureau of transportation statistics (2018). https://www.bts.gov/content/average-age-aircraft. Accessed 18 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. D. Trunkey <i>et al</i>., Costs of submarine maintenance at public and private shipyards, Congressional budget office (2019). https://www.cbo.gov/publication/55032. Accessed 18 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x17e;ant Z. P., Size effect on structural strength: A review. Arch. Appl. Mech. 69, 703&#x2013;725 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monticeli F. M., Pitanga M. Y., Cioffi M. O. H., Voorwald H. J. C., Mode I and mode II delamination of carbon/glass/epoxy hybrid composite: A statistics-based analysis. Polym. Compos. 42, 3857&#x2013;3869 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arg&#xfc;elles A., Coronado P., Canteli A. F., Vi&#xf1;a J., Bonhomme J., Using a statistical model for the analysis of the influence of the type of matrix carbon-epoxy composites on the fatigue delamination under modes I and II of fracture. Int. J. Fatigue 56, 54&#x2013;59 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhou M., Prediction of fracture toughness scatter of composite materials. Comput. Mater. Sci. 116, 44&#x2013;51 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang R., Murthy D. N. P., A study of Weibull shape parameter: Properties and significance. Reliab. Eng. Syst. Safety 96, 1619&#x2013;1626 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Aviation Academy, The different types of aviation maintenance checks (2020). https://www.naa.edu/types-of-aviation-maintenance-checks/. Accessed 16 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>v. d. Weide T., Deng Q., Santos B. F., Robust long-term aircraft heavy maintenance check scheduling optimization under uncertainty. Comput. Oper. Res. 141, 105667 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ca Aubin R. V. R. S., Buskohl P. R., Autonomous material systems. MRS Bull. 49, 1070&#x2013;1078 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi S., Kinloch A. J., Williams J. G., Corrections needed in double-cantilever beam tests for assessing the interlaminar failure of fibre-composites. J. Mater. Sci. Lett. 8, 125&#x2013;129 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turicek J. S., Phillips Z. J., Nakshatrala K. B., Patrick J. F., Self-healing for the long haul: In situ automation delivers century-scale fracture recovery in structural composites. Zenodo. https://zenodo.org/records/17845142. Deposited 18 December 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12799153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>