<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41225471</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An analysis of facilitating and hindering factors in effective evidence-based medical education: a study within the context of medical education in Iran.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1588</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1588</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1588</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12909-025-08187-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Evidence-Based Medical Education (EBME) is increasingly recognized as a key strategy for enhancing the quality and relevance of medical training. Despite its global endorsement, its implementation in many low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), including Iran, faces significant challenges. Highlighting the Iranian context is particularly important, as Iran represents a unique case of a rapidly expanding medical education system in a middle-income setting with distinct cultural and institutional dynamics. This study aimed to explore the factors that support or hinder the effective implementation of EBME in Iranian medical universities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative study employed a conventional content analysis approach and was conducted between January and May 2025 across five major academic medical centers in Iran (Tehran, Shiraz, Isfahan, Mashhad, and Iran Universities of Medical Sciences). A purposive sample of 25 participants, including medical educators, curriculum developers, academic leaders, national experts, and senior medical students, was selected to ensure diversity in perspective and role. Data were collected through semi-structured interviews and analyzed using Graneheim and Lundman's content analysis framework. MAXQDA 2022 software supported data management and coding. Trustworthiness was ensured through member checking, audit trails, peer debriefing, and external validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis yielded eight main categories and 30 sub-categories representing barriers to EBME implementation, as well as eight main categories and 33 sub-categories as facilitators. Key barriers included insufficient faculty training, lack of institutional incentives, rigid curricula, cultural resistance, low student motivation, poor access to resources, absence of national policy guidelines, and misaligned assessment systems. For example, many faculty members lacked the necessary training to translate EBME principles into teaching practice, while students often demonstrated low motivation due to limited exposure to evidence-based approaches. Facilitators encompassed faculty competence and motivation, strong leadership support, innovative curriculum design, institutional and national-level professional development programs, active student engagement, improved access to educational technologies, supportive accreditation standards, and international collaboration. Illustratively, the presence of motivated faculty with prior EBME training and institutional support through professional development initiatives were repeatedly highlighted as drivers of successful adoption.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study highlights that effective EBME implementation in Iran requires a systemic approach addressing individual, institutional, and policy-level factors. Strategic investments in faculty development, curriculum reform, student engagement strategies, and the establishment of clear national policy frameworks, such as embedding EBME in accreditation standards and ensuring resource allocation, are essential for sustainable progress. The findings not only provide insights into the unique Iranian setting but also offer actionable strategies for practice and policy, particularly in strengthening EBME through faculty training, curriculum reform, and well-defined national guidelines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusefi</LastName><ForeName>Ali Reza</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Sirjan School of Medical Sciences, Sirjan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dehghani</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry, School of Dentistry, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahardani</LastName><ForeName>Seyedeh Zahra</ForeName><Initials>SZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Educational Research in Medical Sciences (CERMS), Medical Education Department, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramezani</LastName><ForeName>Ghobad</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Education Development Center, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keshavarzi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Hasan</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Education Research Center, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. keshavarzi20014@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088679</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007492" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iran</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003479" MajorTopicYN="N">Curriculum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005180" MajorTopicYN="N">Faculty, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019317" MajorTopicYN="Y">Evidence-Based Medicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence-Based medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Faculty development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Higher education policy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iran</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical curriculum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Student engagement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study is approved by the Shiraz University of Medical Sciences Ethics Committee under ID number IR.SUMS.REC.1403.247. This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. All methods were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. Written informed consent was obtained from all subjects and/or their legal guardians. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41225471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12613663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-08187-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12909-025-08187-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Djulbegovic B, Guyatt G. Evidence-based medicine in times of crisis. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;126:164&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2020.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7348606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecilio-Fernandes D, Sandars J. The frustrations of adopting evidence-based medical education and how they can be overcome! Med Teach. 2021;43(1):108&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2020.1752367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang B, Sandarage R, Chai J, Dawson KA, Dutkiewicz KR, Saad S, et al. A systematic review of evidence-based practices for clinical education and health care delivery in the clinical teaching unit. CMAJ. 2022;194(6):E186&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.202400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yohannan DG, Oommen AM, Umesan KG, Raveendran VL, Sreedhar LS, Anish TS, et al. Overcoming barriers in a traditional medical education system by the stepwise, evidence-based introduction of a modern learning technology. Med Sci Educ. 2019;29(3):803&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40670-019-00759-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8368117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34457545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin MH, Awad MH, Mohamed Ginawi ES, Mohammed AS, Noureldaiem Ibrahim EH, Yassen OY, et al. Investigating the knowledge, attitude, and practice of evidence-based medicine education in Sudanese medical students: a cross-sectional study. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-07510-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12220732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40597992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden RM, Grant J, Buckley G, Hart IR. Best evidence medical education. Adv Health Sci Educ Theory Pract. 2000;5(1):71&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1009896431203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12386477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin AP, Chou YY, Tam KW. Use of simulation scenarios and vote cards in teaching critical appraisal concepts in evidence-based medicine. BMC Med Educ. 2023;23(1):726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-023-04738-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10548740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmady S, Khani H. The situational analysis of teaching-learning in clinical education in Iran: a postmodern grounded theory study. BMC Med Educ. 2022;22(1):520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-022-03577-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanjani N, Tabrizi R, Maghsoudi A. The obstacles of teaching evidence-based medicine in Iran, from the viewpoint of clinical academics and medical students: a qualitative study. Am J Educ Res. 2013;1(4):143&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12691/education-1-4-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone E. Challenges and issues: evidence-based clinical skills teaching and learning: what do we really know? J Vet Med Educ. 2019;46(3):379&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme.0717-094r1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31145646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan SAR, Changiz T, Mirzazadeh T, van Zanten A, Yamani M. The experience of 10 years of institutional and program accreditation in Iran with an emphasis on the strengths and implementation challenges: a qualitative study. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05069-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11817389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39934716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malakouti SK, Karimzadeh F, Minaeian S, Islami A, Rezaei M, Ghods R. The organizational culture of Iran university of medical sciences from the viewpoint of faculty members. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2019;33:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6708085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31456959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi S, Bazrafkan L, Shojaei A, Rakhshani T, Shokrpour N. Faculty development strategies to empower university teachers by their educational role: a qualitative study on faculty members and students&#x2019; experiences at Iranian universities of medical sciences. BMC Med Educ. 2023;23(1):260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-023-04209-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10114459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37076869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalakrishnan S, Catherine AP, Kandasamy S, Ganesan H. Challenges and opportunities in the implementation of competency-based medical education &#x2013; a cross-sectional survey among medical faculty in India. J Educ Health Promot. 2022;11(1):206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_1130_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36003230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhshi SK, Afzal N, Merchant AA, Rahim KA, Shaikh NQ, Noorali AA, et al. Undergraduate medical education curriculum reforms in pakistan: a mixed-methods study of academic leadership perspectives. Acad Med. 2024;99(7):794&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000005683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38442198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri Lankarani K, Kalateh Sadati A, Razavinasab A, Khayamzadeh M. Integration of medical education and research in the healthcare system in Iran: a qualitative study on the positive consequences of the formation of the ministry of health and medical education. Iran J Cult Health Promot. 2023;6(4):603&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elacqua G, Munevar I, Sanchez F, Santos H. The impact of decentralized decision-making on student outcomes and teacher quality: evidence from Colombia. World Dev. 2021;141:105378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2020.105378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadzadeh M, Shirbagi N, Bolandhematan K. Academic freedom: A qualitative analysis of representing the experiences of science stakeholders in Iran. J Sci Technol Policy. 2021;14(2):35-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari H, Talebi B, Khadivi A. The challenges of assessing medical educational policies in Iran: a systematic review. Strides Dev Med Educ. 2020;17(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisz G, Nannestad B. The World Health Organization and the global standardization of medical training, a history. Glob Health. 2021;17(1):96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-021-00733-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8397872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubian A, Nasiripour AA, Tabibi SJ, Bahadori M. Evaluation of facilitators and barriers to implementing evidence-based practice in the health services: a systematic review. Galen Medical Journal. 2020;9:e1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31661/gmj.v9i0.1645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34466560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiekirka-Schwake S, Anders S, Von Steinb&#xfc;chel N, Becker JC, Raupach T. Facilitators of high-quality teaching in medical school: findings from a nation-wide survey among clinical teachers. BMC Med Educ. 2017;17(1):178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-017-1000-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28962568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doja A, Lavin Venegas C, Cowley L, Wiesenfeld L, Writer H, Clarkin C. Barriers and facilitators to program directors&#x2019; use of the medical education literature: a qualitative study. BMC Med Educ. 2022;22(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-022-03104-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehorn A, Fu L, Porritt K, Lizarondo L, Stephenson M, Marin T, et al. Mapping clinical barriers and evidence-based implementation strategies in low-to-middle income countries (LMICs). Worldviews Evid Based Nurs. 2021;18(3):190&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/wvn.12503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33973346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lak S, Ghourchian N, Jamali A. The development model of higher education management in Iranian universities of medical sciences during the COVID-19 pandemic. Sadra Med Sci J. 2023;11(3):257&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi-Bazargani H, Tabrizi JS, Azami-Aghdash S. Barriers to evidence-based medicine: a systematic review. J Eval Clin Pract. 2014;20(6):793&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.12222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25130323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami SA, Khankeh H, Motlagh MK, Zarghi N, Shirazi M. Exploring experience of Iranian medical sciences educators about best evidence medical education: a content analysis. J Educ Health Promot. 2019;8(1):247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6967127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graneheim UH, Lundman B. Qualitative content analysis in nursing research: concepts, procedures and measures to achieve trustworthiness. Nurse Educ Today. 2004;24(2):105&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2003.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enworo OC. Application of Guba and lincoln&#x2019;s parallel criteria to assess trustworthiness of qualitative research on Indigenous social protection systems. Qual Res J. 2023;23(4):372&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/QRJ-08-2022-0116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert Y, Naismith L, Mann K. Faculty development initiatives designed to promote leadership in medical education: a BEME systematic review: BEME guide 19. Med Teach. 2012;34(6):483&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/0142159X.2012.680937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22578043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibli KU, Shibli S. Faculty development in low-and middle-income countries&#x2013;Part I. Anaesth Pain Intensive Care. 2022;26(2):133&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35975/apic.v26i2.1842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Atwa H, Shehata M, Al Ansari A, Deifalla A. Faculty development programmes in medical education in the Eastern Mediterranean region: a systematic review. East Mediterr Health J. 2022;28(5):362&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26719/emhj.22.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35670441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukkurwalla A, Zaidi SJ, Taqi M, Waqar Z, Qureshi A. Exploring medical educators&#x2019; perspectives on teaching effectiveness and student learning. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24:1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-06465-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11653745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39696192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldugieman TZ, Alanezi RS, Alshammari WM, Al-Shamary YW, Alqahtani MM, Alreshidi FS. Knowledge, attitude and perception toward evidence-based medicine among medical students in Saudi Arabia: analytic cross-sectional study. J Family Med Prim Care. 2018;7:1026&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_129_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6259558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30598951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi Kasani H, Shams Mourkani G, Seraji F, Rezaeizadeh M, Abedi H. E-learning challenges in Iran: a research synthesis. Int Rev Res Open Distrib Learn. 2020;21(4):96&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi E. Examining hofstede&#x2019;s cultural dimensions in Iranian and Chinese context: a mixed-methods approach. Innovare J Educ. 2024;12(2):6&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ijoe.2024v12i2.50259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witter S, Sheikh K, Schleiff M. Learning health systems in low-income and middle-income countries: exploring evidence and expert insights. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7(Suppl 7):e008115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-008115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9490579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36130793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghardashi F, Yaghoubi M, Bahadori M, Teymourzadeh E. Innovation capability in medical sciences universities: a qualitative study of Iran. J Educ Health Promot. 2019;8(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6378830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30815487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlina W. Can a flexible medical curriculum promote student learning and satisfaction? Ann Acad Med Singap. 2007;36(9):713&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47102/annals-acadmedsg.V36N9p713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17925978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaziz A, Kassab SE, Abdelnasser A, Hosny S. Medical education in Egypt: historical background, current status, and challenges. Health Prof Educ. 2018;4(4):236&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlFaris E, Abdulgader A, Alkhenizan A. Towards evidence-based medical education in Saudi medical schools. Ann Saudi Med. 2006;26(6):429&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5144/0256-4947.2006.429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6074332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17143017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmati MR, Aziz Malayeri F. Iranian EFL teachers&#x2019; perceptions of obstacles to implementing student-centered learning: a mixed-methods study. Int J Foreign Lang Teach Res. 2022;10(40):133&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amer YS, Wahabi HA, Abou Elkheir MM, Bawazeer GA, Iqbal SM, Titi MA, et al. Adapting evidence-based clinical practice guidelines at university teaching hospitals: a model for the Eastern mediterranean region. J Eval Clin Pract. 2019;25:550&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.12927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi S, Rezai MS. Teaching evidence-based medicine to undergraduate medical students in iran: necessities and challenges. Clin Exc. 2017;7(2):13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotur PF. Introduction of evidence-based medicine in undergraduate medical curriculum for development of professional competencies in medical students. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2012;25:719&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACO.0b013e32835a1112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23103843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Shahrani AS. Development and evaluation of an evidence-based medicine module in the undergraduate medical curriculum. BMC Med Educ. 2020;20:256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-020-02181-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7407438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidbeygi M, Sayehmiri K. Knowledge and attitudes of physicians towards evidence-based medicine in Ilam, Iran. Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2013;15(9):798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ircmj.7204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuyama Y, Nomura O, Oikawa S, Kikukawa M, Shimizu I, Gomi H. Competency-based medical education guidelines are context-based: lessons from national guidelines in five countries. Med Teach. 2024;46(Suppl 1):S38-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39545497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frenk J, Chen L, Bhutta ZA, Cohen J, Crisp N, Evans T, et al. Health professionals for a new century: transforming education to strengthen health systems in an interdependent world. Lancet. 2010;376(9756):1923&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61854-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greysen SR, Dovlo D, Olapade-Olaopa EO, Jacobs M, Sewankambo N, Mullan F. Medical education in sub-Saharan Africa: a literature review. Med Educ. 2011;45(10):973&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2011.04039.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21916938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lujan HL, DiCarlo SE. The paradox of knowledge: why medical students know more but understand less. Med Sci Educ. 2025;35:1761&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40670-025-02379-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12228860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40626000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert Y, Mann K, Anderson B, Barnett BM, Centeno A, Naismith L, et al. A systematic review of faculty development initiatives designed to enhance teaching effectiveness: a 10-year update: BEME guide 40. Med Teach. 2016;38(8):769&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2016.1181851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27420193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia-Lazcano A, Fuentes-&#xc1;lvarez R, Cruz-Sandoval M, Miranda-Hern&#xe1;ndez C, Membrillo-Hern&#xe1;ndez J. Challenge-based learning in biomedical engineering: developing skills for the future. Int J Online Biomed Eng. 2025;21(2):7&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedeilia A, Sotiropoulos MG, Hanrahan JG, Janga D, Dedeilias P, Sideris M. Medical and surgical education challenges and innovations in the COVID-19 era: a systematic review. Vivo. 2020;34(3 Suppl):1603&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/invivo.11950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8378024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qadikolaei MR, Zali N, Soltani A. Spatiotemporal investigation of the digital divide, the case study of Iranian provinces. Environ Dev Sustain. 2024;26(1):869&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-022-02738-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9702755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36465591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilic D, Tepper K, Misso M. Teaching evidence-based medicine literature searching skills to medical students during the clinical years: a randomized controlled trial. J Med Libr Assoc. 2012;100(3):190&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3163/1536-5050.100.3.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maggio LA, Tannery NH, Chen HC, ten Cate O, O&#x2019;Brien B. Evidence-based medicine training in undergraduate medical education: a review and critique of the literature published 2006&#x2013;2011. Acad Med. 2013;88(7):1022&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182951959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23702528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis LL, Bhatarasakoon P, Chaiard J, Walters EM, Nance J, Mittal M. Use of collaborative online international learning to teach evidence-based practice. J Nurse Pract. 2023;19(5):104498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nurpra.2022.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>