<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41287831</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1365</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Drug, healthcare and patient safety</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Drug Healthc Patient Saf</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices on Antibiotic Use and Resistance Among Healthcare Workers in Monrovia, Liberia: A Facility-Based Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>253</StartPage><EndPage>264</EndPage><MedlinePgn>253-264</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/DHPS.S564658</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Globally, healthcare systems are currently facing a significant challenge in terms of antibiotic resistance. Healthcare professionals actively participate in the process of prescribing, dispensing and administering antibiotics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We examined the knowledge, attitudes and practices regarding antibiotic use and antibiotic resistance among healthcare professionals working in a tertiary hospital located in Monrovia, Liberia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A hospital-based cross-sectional survey was carried out from January to June, 2023 involving 61&#xa0;healthcare workers at the ELWA Hospital, Liberia. A purposive sample of healthcare workers across diverse professional roles was surveyed using a structured questionnaire on antibiotic use and resistance. Data were analyzed in SPSS v25 using descriptive statistics to summarize participant characteristics and inferential tests to explore variable associations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants ages ranged from 20 to 60 years (mean = 40.7 &#xb1; 5) and nurses constituted the majority professional group (59%). Most respondents (68.9%) disagreed that antibiotics are effective against viral infections (OR = 0.45; p = 0.020). However, 36.1% believed antibiotics could be stopped when symptoms resolve and 24.6% believed leftover antibiotics could be reused (OR = 0.33; p = 0.002). Majority, 72.1% and 70.5%, reported never using antibiotics for body pain or headaches, respectively (OR = 3.67; p = 0.001 and OR = 4.78; p &lt; 0.001). Despite this, 39.3% admitted to sometimes or always storing leftover antibiotics and 39.3% agreed or strongly agreed that stopping antibiotics early is safe (OR = 0.36; p = 0.016).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study identified persistent gaps in healthcare workers' knowledge, attitudes, and practices regarding antibiotic use and resistance, despite encouraging awareness in some areas. Misconceptions such as premature discontinuation and reuse of leftover antibiotics were common. Findings underscore the need for targeted education and strengthened stewardship programs in Liberia's healthcare settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Shobayo et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shobayo</LastName><ForeName>Bode Ireti</ForeName><Initials>BI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4864-0248</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of Liberia, Louisiana, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health and Medical Research, National Public Health Institute of Liberia, Monrovia, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Victor Saah</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of Liberia, Louisiana, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freeman</LastName><ForeName>Bluefin Masell</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of Liberia, Louisiana, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health and Medical Research, National Public Health Institute of Liberia, Monrovia, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kokro</LastName><ForeName>James Saysay</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health and Medical Research, National Public Health Institute of Liberia, Monrovia, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chea</LastName><ForeName>Sampson K P</ForeName><Initials>SKP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of Liberia, Louisiana, Liberia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Drug Healthc Patient Saf</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101544775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-1365</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>This study looked at how healthcare workers in Monrovia, Liberia understand and use antibiotics. It focused on their knowledge, beliefs, and everyday practices related to antibiotic use and resistance, a growing global health problem. Researchers surveyed 61&#xa0;healthcare workers at ELWA Hospital, a major health facility in Monrovia. Participants included nurses, doctors, pharmacists, lab technicians, and midwives. They answered a structured questionnaire designed to measure what they know, how they feel, and what they do when it comes to antibiotics. The study found that most healthcare workers knew that antibiotics do not work against viruses and should not be used for things like headaches or body pain. However, many still held incorrect beliefs like thinking it is okay to stop antibiotics early or reuse leftover medicine. Nearly 40% admitted to storing leftover antibiotics, and some disposed of them improperly. On the positive side, most participants followed infection prevention guidelines and recognized antibiotic resistance as a serious public health threat. Antibiotic resistance makes infections harder to treat and is especially dangerous in places with limited healthcare resources. Healthcare workers play a key role in preventing resistance, so it is important they have accurate information and follow best practices. The study shows that while awareness is improving, there are still gaps that need to be addressed. Targeted training and stronger hospital policies can help healthcare workers use antibiotics more responsibly and protect public health in Liberia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Shobayo et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liberia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotic resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotic use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attitudes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">practices</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41287831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12640598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DHPS.S564658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">564658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sakeena MHF, Bennett AA, Jamshed S, et al. Investigating knowledge regarding antibiotics and antimicrobial resistance among pharmacy students in Sri Lankan universities. <i>BMC Infect Dis</i>. 2018;18:209. doi: 10.1186/s12879-018-3107-8
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3107-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukwu EE, Oladele DA, Awoderu OB, et al. A national survey of public awareness of antimicrobial resistance in Nigeria. <i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2020;9(1):72. doi: 10.1186/s13756-020-00739-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-020-00739-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marston BJ, Dokubo EK, van Steelandt A, et al. Ebola response impact on public health programs, West Africa, 2014&#x2013;2017. <i>Emerg Infect Dis</i>. 2017;23(Suppl 1):S25. doi: 10.3201/eid2313.170727
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2313.170727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5711323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 10 global health issues to track in 2021. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/spotlight/10-global-health-issues-to-track-in-2021. Accessed October
1, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill J. Tackling drug-resistant infections globally: final report and recommendations. Government of the United Kingdom; 2016. Available from: https://apo.org.au/node/63983. Accessed September
25, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission. EU action on antimicrobial resistance. 2023. Available from: https://health.ec.europa.eu/antimicrobial-resistance/eu-action-antimicrobial-resistance_en. Accessed September
25, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SK, Hussein S, Qurbani K, et al. Antimicrobial resistance: impacts, challenges, and future prospects. <i>J Med Surg Public Health</i>. 2024;2:100081. doi: 10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-resistant infections: a threat to our economic future. World Bank. Available from: https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/health/publication/drug-resistant-infections-a-threat-to-our-economic-future. Accessed July
14, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Burriel M, Keys M, Campillo-Artero C, et al. Impact of multi-drug resistant bacteria on economic and clinical outcomes of healthcare-associated infections in adults: systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2020;15(1):e0227139. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0227139
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0227139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray CJ, Ikuta KS, Sharara F, et al. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in 2019: a systematic analysis. <i>Lancet</i>. 2022;399(10325):629&#x2013;655. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auta A, Hadi MA, Oga E, et al. Global access to antibiotics without prescription in community pharmacies: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>J Infect</i>. 2019;78(1):8&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2018.07.001
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2018.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29981773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayukekbong JA, Ntemgwa M, Atabe AN. The threat of antimicrobial resistance in developing countries: causes and control strategies. <i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2017;6(1):47. doi: 10.1186/s13756-017-0208-x
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-017-0208-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebre M, Uddin MF, Duke T, et al. Perception and experience of clinicians and caregivers in treating childhood severe pneumonia and hypoxemia using bubble continuous positive airway pressure in Ethiopian tertiary and general hospitals. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2022;17(10):e0275952. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0275952
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0275952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9621408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36315509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MS, Hutchison C, Coker RJ, et al. Preventing emergence of drug resistant tuberculosis in Myanmar&#x2019;s transitioning health system. <i>Health Policy Plan</i>. 2017;32(suppl_2):i43&#x2013;i50. doi: 10.1093/heapol/czx093
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czx093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29028228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JT. <i>Assessing the Rational Use of Essential Medicines in Public Health Facilities Montserrado County, Liberia</i>
[Thesis]. Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarding against antimicrobial resistance in Liberia | WHO | regional Office for Africa. 2025. Available from: https://www.afro.who.int/news/guarding-against-antimicrobial-resistance-liberia. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberia Medicines &amp; Health Products, Regulatory Authority (LMHRA). Available from: https://www.lmhra.gov.lr/new/pg_img/25_05_28_PV%20Regulations_LMHRA_JG.pdf. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health. lbr-mn-78-02-guideline-2017-eng-national-standard-therapeutic-guidelines-eml.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaubien J. Startling Statistic: only 8 Patients In Largest Ebola Hospital. TPR; 2014. Available from: https://www.tpr.org/2014-12-03/startling-statistic-only-8-patients-in-largest-ebola-hospital. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anargh V, Singh H, Kulkarni A, Kotwal A, Mahen A. Hand hygiene practices among health care workers (HCWs) in a tertiary care facility in Pune. <i>Med J Armed Forces India</i>. 2013;69(1):54&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/j.mjafi.2012.08.011
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mjafi.2012.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3862659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sample size calculator for needs assessments and KAP surveys. ActivityInfo. Available from: https://www.activityinfo.org/support/docs/sampling/snapshot.html. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawshe CH. A quantitative approach to content validity. <i>Personnel Psychol</i>. 1975;28(4):563&#x2013;575. doi: 10.1111/j.1744-6570.1975.tb01393.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1744-6570.1975.tb01393.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudenda S, Bumbangi FN, Yamba K, et al. Drivers of antimicrobial resistance in layer poultry farming: evidence from high prevalence of multidrug-resistant Escherichia coli and enterococci in Zambia. <i>Vet World</i>. 2023;16(9):1803&#x2013;1814. doi: 10.14202/vetworld.2023.1803-1814
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2023.1803-1814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10583887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cane J, O&#x2019;Connor D, Michie S. Validation of the theoretical domains framework for use in behaviour change and implementation research. <i>Implement Sci</i>. 2012;7(1):37. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-7-37
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-7-37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umscheid CA, Mitchell MD, Doshi JA, Agarwal R, Williams K, Brennan PJ. Estimating the proportion of healthcare-associated infections that are reasonably preventable and the related mortality and costs. <i>Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol</i>. 2011;32(2):101&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1086/657912
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/657912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21460463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Precha N, Sukmai S, Hengbaru M, et al. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices regarding antibiotic use and resistance among health science and non-health science university students in Thailand. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2024;19(1):e0296822. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0296822
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0296822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10769033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38180959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbo LM, Cosgrove SE, Pottinger PS, et al. Medical students&#x2019; perceptions and knowledge about antimicrobial stewardship: how are we educating our future prescribers?
<i>Clinl Infect Dis</i>. 2013;57(5):631&#x2013;638. doi: 10.1093/cid/cit370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cit370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Hayat K, Shi L, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practices of antibiotics and antibiotic resistance among Chinese pharmacy customers: a multicenter survey study. <i>Antibiotics</i>. 2020;9(4):184. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics9040184
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics9040184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32316147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estany-Gestal A, Salgado-Barreira A, Vazquez-Lago JM. Antibiotic use and antimicrobial resistance: a global public health crisis. <i>Antibiotics</i>. 2024;13(9):900. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics13090900
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics13090900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39335073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albadrani RK, Alyenbawi AH, Albalawi M, et al. Assessment of knowledge, attitudes, and practices of antibiotic resistance among university students in Saudi Arabia. <i>BMC Res Notes</i>. 2025;18(1):161. doi: 10.1186/s13104-025-07241-z
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-025-07241-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11992694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40217261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones ASK, Chan AHY, Beyene K, et al. Beliefs about antibiotics, perceptions of antimicrobial resistance, and antibiotic use: initial findings from a multi-country survey. <i>Int J Pharm Pract</i>. 2024;32(1):21&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1093/ijpp/riad089
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ijpp/riad089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38092704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalkidou A, Lambert M, Cordoba G, Taxis K, Hansen MP, Bjerrum L. Misconceptions and knowledge gaps on antibiotic use and resistance in four healthcare settings and five European countries&#x2014;a modified Delphi study. <i>Antibiotics</i>. 2023;12(9):1435. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics12091435
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics12091435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10525245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37760731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah J, Trautner BW, Olmeda K, et al. A survey of patient practices regarding leftover antibiotics reveals a potential source of antibiotic overuse. <i>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</i>. 2024;68(8):e0046924. doi: 10.1128/aac.00469-24
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.00469-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11304717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38975752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell Publishing Ltd., Many families share leftover antibacterial drugs. <i>PharmacoEcon Outcomes News</i>. 2018;816(1):19. doi: 10.1007/s40274-018-5439-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40274-018-5439-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borek A, Ledda A, Pouwels K, et al. Stop antibiotics when you feel better? Opportunities, challenges and research directions. <i>JAC Antimicrob Resist</i>. 2024;6(5):dlae147.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11382136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39253334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antimicrobial resistance. Available from: https://www.who.int/health-topics/antimicrobial-resistance. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisabwe L, Brice H, Umuhire MC, et al. Knowledge and attitudes towards antibiotic use and resistance among undergraduate healthcare students at University of Rwanda. <i>J Pharm Policy Pract</i>. 2020;13:7. doi: 10.1186/s40545-020-00207-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-020-00207-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiener M, Ichura C, Ndenga BA, et al. Antibiotic prescribing patterns at outpatient clinics in Western and Coastal Kenya. <i>PLOS Glob Public Health</i>. 2025;5(1):e0004109. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0004109
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0004109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11698307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39752345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar U, Salman M. Antibiotic use among hospitalized patients in Africa: a systematic review of point prevalence studies. <i>J Racial Ethn Health Disparities</i>. 2024;11(3):1308&#x2013;1329. doi: 10.1007/s40615-023-01610-9
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-023-01610-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37157014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi KJ, Ngumba E, Ahmad A, et al. Contamination of groundwater with sulfamethoxazole and antibiotic resistant Escherichia coli in informal settlements in Kisumu, Kenya. <i>PLoS Water</i>. 2023;2(4):e0000076. doi: 10.1371/journal.pwat.0000076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pwat.0000076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marwa KJ, Mcharo G, Mwita S, Katabalo D, Ruganuza D, Kapesa A. Disposal practices of expired and unused medications among households in Mwanza, Tanzania. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2021;16(2):e0246418. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0246418
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0246418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apreja M, Sharma A, Balda S, Kataria K, Capalash N, Sharma P. Antibiotic residues in environment: antimicrobial resistance development, ecological risks, and bioremediation. <i>Environ Sci Pollut Res</i>. 2022;29(3):3355&#x2013;3371. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-17374-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-17374-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34773239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotics as environmental waste | EBSCO Research Starters. Available from: https://www.ebsco.com/research-starters/environmental-sciences/antibiotics-environmental-waste. Accessed July
6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton RA, Ercolani MG, Aggarwal R, et al. Evaluation of antibiotics returned for safe disposal during and after a community pharmacy antibiotic amnesty campaign. <i>JAC Antimicrob Resist</i>. 2024;6(5):dlae172. doi: 10.1093/jacamr/dlae172
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jacamr/dlae172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11503646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39464859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darboe SMK, Darfour-Oduro SA, Kpene GE, et al. Factors influencing healthcare workers&#x2019; perceived compliance with infection prevention and control standards, North Bank East region, The Gambia, a cross-sectional study. <i>BMC Res Notes</i>. 2025;18(1):43. doi: 10.1186/s13104-025-07101-w
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-025-07101-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11780765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39885582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabego L, Balde T, Barasa D, et al. Analysing the implementation of infection prevention and control measures in health care facilities during the COVID-19 pandemic in the African Region. <i>BMC Infect Dis</i>. 2023;23(1):824. doi: 10.1186/s12879-023-08830-8
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-023-08830-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10668477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa G, Ogongo I, Rabkin M, et al. The East Africa Infection Prevention and Control (IPC) learning network: an approach to improving IPC competencies and practices during the COVID-19 pandemic, 2020&#x2013;2023. <i>Clinl Infect Dis</i>. 2025;81(1):41&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaf245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaf245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12314500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40581363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zingg W, Mutters NT, Harbarth S, Friedrich AW. Education in infection control: a need for European certification. <i>Clin Microbiol Infect</i>. 2015;21(12):1052&#x2013;1056. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2015.09.001
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2015.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26363403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar B, S&#xe1;rv&#xe1;ry A. Knowledge, attitude, and practice on antibiotics use among healthcare workers: a cross-sectional study in Niger state, Nigeria. <i>J Infect Prev</i>. 2023;24(5):206&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1177/17571774231165407
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17571774231165407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10510657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37736128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manga MM, Mohammed Y, Suleiman S, et al. Antibiotic prescribing habits among primary healthcare workers in Northern Nigeria: a concern for patient safety in the era of global antimicrobial resistance. <i>PAMJ One Health</i>. 2021;5:19. doi: 10.11604/pamj-oh.2021.5.19.30847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj-oh.2021.5.19.30847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trikha S, Dalpath SK, Sharma M, Shafiq N. Antibiotic prescribing patterns and knowledge of antibiotic resistance amongst the doctors working at public health facilities of a state in northern India: a cross sectional study. <i>J Family Med Prim Care</i>. 2020;9(8):3937&#x2013;3943. doi: 10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_367_20
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_367_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33110790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nukaly HY, Aljuhani RA, Alhartani MM, et al. Knowledge of antibiotic use and resistance among medical students in Saudi Arabia. <i>Adv Med Educ Pract</i>. 2024;15:501&#x2013;512. doi: 10.2147/AMEP.S462490
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/AMEP.S462490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11149621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38835809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshehri AA, Khawagi WY. Knowledge, awareness, and perceptions towards antibiotic use, resistance, and antimicrobial stewardship among final-year medical and pharmacy students in Saudi Arabia. <i>Antibiotics</i>. 2025;14(2):116. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics14020116
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics14020116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11852200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40001360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maarouf L, Amin M, Evans BA, Abouelfetouh A. Knowledge, attitudes and behaviour of Egyptians towards antibiotic use in the community: can we do better?
<i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2023;12:50. doi: 10.1186/s13756-023-01249-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-023-01249-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10210355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37226221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunita SL, Yang HW, Chen YC, et al. Knowledge and practices related to antibiotic use among women in Malang, Indonesia. <i>Front Pharmacol</i>. 2022;13:1019303. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.1019303
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.1019303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9637850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36353493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baillie EJ, Merlo G, Van Driel ML, Magin PJ, Hall L. Early-career general practitioners&#x2019; antibiotic prescribing for acute infections: a systematic review. <i>J Antimicrob Chemother</i>. 2024;79(3):512&#x2013;525. doi: 10.1093/jac/dkae002
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkae002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10904722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38252922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>