<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41188843</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6831</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC oral health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Oral Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the prevalence and severity of temporomandibular disorders and oral behaviors in a group of Iranian bodybuilders: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1736</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1736</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1736</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12903-025-07067-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Temporomandibular disorders (TMDs) are the most common non-dental orofacial pain conditions. Due to the potential elevated risk of TMD in bodybuilders and the lack of research in the Iranian population, this study aimed to investigate the prevalence and severity of TMDs and oral behaviors and compare associated variables among Iranian bodybuilders for the first time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This cross-sectional study was conducted on 378 bodybuilders aged 18&#x2013;60 years old who had been actively training for at least 6 months. The prevalence and severity of TMD were assessed using the Fonseca questionnaire, while oral parafunctional behaviors were evaluated using an Oral Behaviors Checklist (OBC). Ultimately, the study results were analyzed using the Chi-squared test, Fisher&#x2019;s exact test, and Pearson correlation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The results of the Fonseca questionnaire showed that 48.2% of the participants have TMD. No significant relationship was found between the prevalence and severity of TMD and age, gender, months of bodybuilding, number of training hours per week, the heaviest weight used in the bench press, and Body Mass Index (BMI). According to the results of the OBC, 100.0% of the participants had oral parafunctional behaviors, and a significant relationship was observed between oral parafunctional behaviors and gender (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.047) and the heaviest weight used in the bench press exercise (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002). According to the study, a significant correlation was observed between the prevalence of TMD and the prevalence of oral parafunctional behaviors (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02, <i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.245).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">About half of the bodybuilders have TMD, and all of them have oral parafunctional behaviors.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mortazavi</LastName><ForeName>Hamed</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0778-5299</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, School of Dentistry, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaei</LastName><ForeName>Homa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1096-1265</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, School of Dentistry, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rastkar</LastName><ForeName>Nazli</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4016-5315</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dental Research Center, Research Institute for Dental Sciences, School of Dentistry, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran. nazlirastkar@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zayeri</LastName><ForeName>Farid</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7791-8122</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Proteomics Research Center, Department of Biostatistics, Faculty of Allied Medical Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rastkar</LastName><ForeName>Aliparsa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-4838-2214</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dental Research Center, Research Institute for Dental Sciences, School of Dentistry, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Oral Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6831</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iran</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temporomandibular disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight lifting</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This descriptive cross-sectional study was performed under the World Medical Association&#x2019;s Declaration of Helsinki on experimentation involving human subjects&#x2019; principles. All participants gave informed consent to participate and further utilization of their demographic information prior to inclusion in the study. This study was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of the Research Institute of Dental Sciences at Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences under the approval ID: IR.SBMU.DRC.REC.1402.048. This research did not receive any specific grant from funding agencies in the public, commercial, or not-for-profit sectors. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41188843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12584317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-025-07067-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12903-025-07067-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zwiri AMA, Al-Omiri MK. Prevalence of temporomandibular joint disorder among North Saudi university students. Cranio. 2016;34(3):176&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/2151090315Y.0000000007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25832332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy MK, MacBarb RF, Wong ME, Athanasiou KA. Temporomandibular disorders: a review of etiology, clinical management, and tissue engineering strategies. JOMI. 2013;28(6):e393-414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11607/jomi.te20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4349514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda J, Santos J, Aquino J, Bonato L, Carvalho R, Filho G, et al. Risks of resistance training for the bruxism: a cross-sectional study. REAS. 2022;15:e10882&#x2013;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25248/reas.e10882.2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anbari F, Taghavi F, Khalighi H, Tavakolizadeh S, Khosousi Sani M, Ahmadi S et al. Clinical Features of Temporomandibular Disorders: Validity and Reliability of the Fonseca Anamnestic Index in Persian. J Iran Med Counc; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap AU, Zhang MJ, Lei J, Fu KY. Accuracy of the Fonseca anamnestic index for identifying pain-related and/or intra-articular temporomandibular disorders. Cranio. 2024;42(3):259&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08869634.2021.1954375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34259594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos JA, Carrascosa AC, Bonaf&#xe9; FS, Maroco J. Severity of temporomandibular disorders in women: validity and reliability of the Fonseca anamnestic index. Braz Oral Res. 2014;28:16&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1806-83242013005000026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25000601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa C, Manso MC, Reis T, Soares T, Gavinha S, Ohrbach R. Cultural equivalence, reliability and utility of the Portuguese version of the oral behaviours checklist. J Oral Rehabil. 2018;45(12):924&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joor.12716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30187498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freiwald HC, Schwarzbach NP, Wolowski A. Impact of sports on temporomandibular dysfunction: a comparison of competitive and recreational female athletes as well as female non-athletes. Clin Oral Investig. 2022;26(8):5313&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-022-04499-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9381453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35484356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A, Sayed Abdul N, Bhagawati A, Saikia T, Bhattacharya A, Rajendra Joshi P, et al. Exploring the association between physical fitness (High intensity and low intensity) and the incidence of temporomandibular disorders: A comparative study. Cureus. 2024;16(8):e66047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11366834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39224712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfa;nior MCBL, Goiato MC, de Caxias FP, Turcio KHL, da Silva EVF, Deusdete MS, et al. Masticatory efficiency, bite force and electrical activity of the masseter and temporalis muscles in bodybuilders. J Clin Exp Dent. 2021;13(9):920&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4317/jced.58368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8464386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslamian&#x2e1; L, Madani Z, Fahiminejad N. Evaluation of the relationship between TMD symptoms and family history in orthodontic patients and Controls. I Iran. J Orthod. 2021;16(2):1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Shi L, Lu H, Liu Z, Yu M, Wang Y, et al. Influence of edentulism on the structure and function of temporomandibular joint. Heliyon. 2023;9(10):e20307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10565695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37829806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont S, Garg K, Gokhale A, Heaphy N. Temporomandibular disorder: a practical guide for dental practitioners in diagnosis and management. Aust Dent J. 2020;65(3):172&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/adj.12785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye C, Xiong X, Zhang Y, Pu D, Zhang J, Du S, et al. Psychological profiles and their relevance with temporomandibular disorder symptoms in preorthodontic patients. Pain Res Manag. 2022;2022:1039393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/1039393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman Rubin P, Eli I, Greenbaum T, Shapira K, Emodi-Perelman A, Winocur E. Potential orofacial hazards of resistance training: a controlled comparative study *. Cranio. 2019;37(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08869634.2017.1370566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28876194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemipoor MS, Razavi F, Loran V, Pooyafard A, Ganjaliannasab SA. Investigation of psychometric characteristics of Persian translation of Fonseca index in a sample of Persian-speaking people. JIDS. 2016;12(3):326&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitro V, Caso AR, Sacchi F, Gilli M, Lombardo G, Monarchi G, et al. Fonseca&#x2019;s questionnaire is a useful tool for carrying out the initial evaluation of temporomandibular disorders in dental students. Clin Pract. 2024;14(5):1650&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/clinpract14050132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11417721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39311282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omezli MM, Torul D, Varer Akpinar C. Temporomandibular disorder severity and its association with psychosocial and sociodemographic factors in Turkish adults. BMC Oral Health. 2023;23(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-023-02737-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9862211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36681799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almalki SA, Al Jameel AH, Gowdar IM, Langaliya A, Vaddamanu SK, Di Blasio M, et al. Impact of clear aligner therapy on masticatory musculature and stomatognathic system: a systematic review conducted according to PRISMA guidelines and the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. BMC Oral Health. 2024;24(1):350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-024-04029-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38504207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Wu G, Liu J, Jiao D, Guo J. Assessment of oral parafunctional behaviors and electromyographic activities of the masticatory muscles in young female patients with orthodontic invisalign treatment. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2017;10(11):15323&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemati S, Zardaki F, rad m, Mafi S. Cross-cultural adaptation, validation, and reliability assessment of the Persian version of the oral behaviour checklist for parafunctional habits in Persian-speaking populations. JOHOE. 2025;14(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis I, Watson B, White KM. Internet versus paper-and&#x2010;pencil survey methods in psychological experiments: equivalence testing of participant responses to health&#x2010;related messages. Aust J Psychol. 2009;61(2):107&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00049530802105865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyerson P, Tryon WW. Validating internet research: a test of the psychometric equivalence of internet and in-person samples. Behav Res Methods Instrum Comput. 2003;35(4):614&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03195541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14748506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soltani F, Mafi S, Jamshidy L, Rad M. Validity and reliability of the Persian translation of the diagnostic criteria for temporomandibular disorders questionnaire. J Kermanshah Univ Med Sci. 2023;27(4):e140581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/jkums-140581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi M, Dashti H, Mehrabkhani M, Arghavani M, Daneshvar-Mozafari A. Temporomandibular disorders and related factors in a group of Iranian adolescents: a cross-sectional survey. J Dent Res Dent Clin Dent Prospects. 2011;5(4):123&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3442434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22991620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falahati M, Golmohammadi F, Darabi R, jafari M. Evaluation of temporomandibular joint disorders and related factors in patients referring to dental school of Isfahan Islamic Azad university in 2019. J Res Dent Maxillofac Sci. 2020;5(3):21&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29252/jrdms.5.3.21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghighat A, Salavati M, Haghighat M, Ramezanzade S, Ranjbar A. Prevalence of temporomandibular disorders and some of its risk factors, according to the diagnostic criteria for temporomandibular disorders (DC/TMD). Clin Surg. 2020;5:2784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour Ibrahim Alrowdan A, Sr., Mohsin SF, Ali Shah S, Alkhalifah TS. Frequency and severity of temporomandibular disorders among weightlifters at fitness centers in a subset population of Saudi arabia: A Cross-Sectional observational study. Cureus. 2023;15(11):e49113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10732333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38125229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bicaj T, Shala K, Krasniqi TP, Ahmedi E, Dula L, Lila-Krasniqi Z. Frequency of symptoms of temporomandibular disorders among Prishtina dental students. Open Access Maced J Med Sci. 2017;5(6):781&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2017.165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29104690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steed PA, Wexler GB. Temporomandibular disorders&#x2014;traumatic etiology vs. nontraumatic etiology: a clinical and methodological inquiry into symptomatology and treatment outcomes. Cranio. 2001;19(3):188&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08869634.2001.11746169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11482831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh SB, Shetty SS, Kamath V. Prevalence of temporomandibular disorders and its correlation with stress and salivary cortisol levels among students. Pesqui Bras Odontopediatria Clin Integr. 2021;21:e0120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/pboci.2021.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshahrani AA, Saini RS, Okshah A, Alshadidi AAF, Kanji MA, Vyas R, et al. The association between genetic factors and temporomandibular disorders: a systematic literature review. Arch Oral Biol. 2024;166:106032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archoralbio.2024.106032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38943858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminiecki AKM, Davatz GC. Frequency and severity of temporomandibular disorders symptoms in Crossfit<sup>&#xae;</sup> practitioners: a cross-sectional study Frequ&#xea;ncia e severidade de sintomas de disfun&#xe7;&#xe3;o temporomandibular em praticantes de Crossfit<sup>&#xae;</sup>. Rev Pesq Fisio; 2020. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miettinen O, K&#xe4;mppi A, Tanner T, Anttonen V, Patinen P, P&#xe4;kkil&#xe4; J, et al. Association of temporomandibular disorder symptoms with physical fitness among Finnish conscripts. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(6):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18063032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33809450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchior MO, Mazzetto MO, Fel&#xed;cio CM. Temporomandibular disorders and parafunctional oral habits: an anamnestic study. Dent Press J Orthod. 2012;17:83&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S2176-94512012000200016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty S, Pitti V, Satish Babu CL, Surendra Kumar GP, Deepthi BC. Bruxism: a literature review. J Indian Prosthodont Soc. 2010;10(3):141&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13191-011-0041-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21886404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelotti A, Cioffi I, Festa P, Scala G, Farella M. Oral parafunctions as risk factors for diagnostic TMD subgroups. J Oral Rehabil. 2010;37(3):157&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2842.2009.02033.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20002533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH, Lee KM, Kim T, Hong JP. Psychological factors that influence decision-making regarding trauma-related pain in adolescents with temporomandibular disorder. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):18728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-55274-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6904577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31822745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabicak GO, Hazar Kanik Z. Temporomandibular disorder prevalence and its association with oral parafunctions, neck pain, and neck function in healthcare students: a cross-sectional study. Cranio. 2023;41(1):9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08869634.2020.1862581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li DTS, Leung YY. Temporomandibular disorders: current concepts and controversies in diagnosis and management. Diagnostics. 2021. 10.3390/diagnostics11030459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics11030459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8000442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>