<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41555151</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-2267</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cancer survivorship : research and practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cancer Surviv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recommendations for cancer related fatigue in post-treatment survivorship care: a cross-sectional analysis of guidelines.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11764-026-01973-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Existing guidelines for the management of cancer-related fatigue (CRF) differ in scope, evidence strength, and implementation strategies, limiting consistent integration into post-treatment survivorship care. This study systematically evaluates and compares recommendations to identify best practices, highlight evidence gaps, and provide actionable insights for clinicians and policymakers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search was conducted across PubMed, the Cochrane Library, and professional society websites. Included were all guidelines from professional oncology societies addressing CRF management in adult cancer survivors and published in English between 2000 and December 2024. From 524 references screened, eleven (11) guidelines from eight (8) professional societies met the inclusion criteria and were analysed. The quality of the guidelines was assessed using the Appraisal of Guidelines for Research and Evaluation II (AGREE II) criteria. Recommendations, their strength of evidence and strength of recommendations were extracted and standardized into the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) framework. The screening, grading, and extraction process was performed by two reviewers independently.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The quality of the eleven guidelines was high in three (27%), moderate in seven (64%), and poor in one (9%). Based on a moderate level of evidence, CRF should be screened at every patient encounter by all healthcare providers, with positive screens followed by referral to appropriate professionals for further assessment using one of several validated tools. A strong recommendation based on moderate evidence was for exercise. In particular, aerobic and resistance training of low to moderate intensity, three times per week for 12&#xa0;weeks was recommended. Guidelines consistently issued a strong recommendation for CBT (moderate evidence), and for psychotherapy (variable evidence). CBT was recommended, especially with structured coping strategies or web-based delivery. Guidelines cautiously recommended mind-body interventions such as Yoga, Tai Chi, and Qigong based on variable strength of evidence and recommendation. Education andcounselling (particularly for depression-related fatigue) are mainly based on expert consensus rather than strong clinical trials. Other options may be considered in individual patients but are not supported by strong evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This guideline analysis demonstrates broad support for continued CRF screening during survivorship care, followed by assessment of contributing factors when fatigue is identified. Exercise, especially low- to moderate-intensity aerobic and resistance training, and cognitive behavioral therapy are consistently recommended across guidelines as effective interventions. Psychoeducation and counselling are also beneficial, especially for fatigue linked to mental health conditions. Pharmacological treatments are not recommended due to insufficient evidence and side effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR CANCER SURVIVORS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cancer survivors are encouraged to report ongoing fatigue and seek supportive care, given the availability of effective non-drug interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayoson</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland. Joshua.ayoson@ksb.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trial Unit, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland. Joshua.ayoson@ksb.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Nadine</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trial Unit, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rothschild</LastName><ForeName>Sacha I</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Center for Oncology and Hematology, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gut-Fischer</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Haegler-Laube</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wertli</LastName><ForeName>Maria M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cantonal Hospital of Baden, Baden, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, University Hospital Bern, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cancer Surviv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101307557</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-2259</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer survivorship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer-related fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical practice guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-pharmacological interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: J.A declare no competing interest. N.S declare no competing interest. S.R declare competing interest; Research support from other organizations: Roche, AstraZeneca, Swiss National Foundation and Amgen. K.G-F declare competing interest; Grant from the Kanton Aargau, Switzerland. Funding a pilot project for consultation of cancer survivors. E.H&#x2013;L declare competing interest; Grant from the Kanton Aargau, Switzerland. Funding a pilot project for consultation of cancer survivors. M.M.W declare competing interest; Grant from the Kanton Aargau, Switzerland. Funding a pilot project for consultation of cancer survivors and a Grant from the Stiftung Cardio.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41555151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-026-01973-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11764-026-01973-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wagle NS, Nogueira L, Devasia TP, Mariotto AB, Yabroff KR, Islami F, et al. Cancer treatment and survivorship statistics, 2025. CA Cancer J Clin. 2025;75(4):308&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.70011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.70011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40445120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12223361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross LW, Townsend JS, Rohan EA. Still lost in transition? Perspectives of ongoing cancer survivorship care needs from comprehensive cancer control programs, survivors, and health care providers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(5):3037. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19053037 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19053037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8910165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzorati C, Riva S, Pravettoni G. Who is a cancer survivor? A systematic review of published definitions. J Cancer Educ. 2017;32(2):228&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13187-016-0997-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13187-016-0997-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26854084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naughton MJ, Weaver KE. Physical and mental health among cancer survivors: considerations for long-term care and quality of life. N C Med J. 2014;75(4):283&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.18043/ncm.75.4.283 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18043/ncm.75.4.283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25046097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4503227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfano CM, Ganz PA, Rowland JH, Hahn EE. Cancer survivorship and cancer rehabilitation: revitalizing the link. J Clin Oncol. 2012;30(9):904&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2011.37.1674 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.37.1674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22355063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger AM, Mitchell SA, Jacobsen PB, Pirl WF. Screening, evaluation, and management of cancer-related fatigue: ready for implementation to practice? CA Cancer J Clin. 2015;65(3):190&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25760293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkowski NA, Jones G, Brunet J, Lebel S. An ideal intervention for cancer-related fatigue: qualitative findings from patients, community partners, and healthcare providers. Curr Oncol. 2024;31(8):4357&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.3390/curroncol31080325 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/curroncol31080325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39195308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11353202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanft T, Day AT, Goldman M, Ansbaugh S, Armenian S, Baker KS, et al. NCCN guidelines&#xae; insights: survivorship, version 2.2024. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2024;22(10):648&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.6004/jnccn.2024.0062 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6004/jnccn.2024.0062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39689426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curt GA, Breitbart W, Cella D, Groopman JE, Horning SJ, Itri LM, et al. Impact of cancer-related fatigue on the lives of patients: new findings from the Fatigue Coalition. Oncologist. 2000;5(5):353&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.5-5-353 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.5-5-353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11040270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger AM, Mooney K, Alvarez-Perez A, Breitbart WS, Carpenter KM, Cella D, et al. Cancer-related fatigue, version 2.2015. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2015;13(8):1012&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.6004/jnccn.2015.0122 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6004/jnccn.2015.0122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26285247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5499710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JM, Howell D, Longo C, Olson K, Bedard P, Amir E, et al. The association of cancer-related fatigue on the social, vocational and healthcare-related dimensions of cancer survivorship. J Canc Survivor: Res Pract. 2025;19(1):97&#x2013;108. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11764-023-01451-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-023-01451-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE. Cancer-related fatigue&#x2013;mechanisms, risk factors, and treatments. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2014;11(10):597&#x2013;609. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4664449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prue G, Rankin J, Allen J, Gracey J, Cramp F. Cancer-related fatigue: a critical appraisal. Eur J Cancer (Oxford, England&#x202f;: 1990). 2006;42(7):846&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2005.11.026 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2005.11.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thong MSY, van Noorden CJF, Steindorf K, Arndt V. Cancer-related fatigue: causes and current treatment options. Curr Treat Options Oncol. 2020;21(2):17. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11864-020-0707-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11864-020-0707-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32025928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8660748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, &#x2026; Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ (Clinical research ed.), 2021;372:n71. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP, et al. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147(8):573&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-147-8-200710160-00010 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-147-8-200710160-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson MM, Mertens AC, Yasui Y, Hobbie W, Chen H, Gurney JG, Yeazel M, Recklitis CJ, Marina N, Robison LR, Oeffinger KC, &amp; Childhood Cancer Survivor Study Investigators. Health status of adult long-term survivors of childhood cancer: a report from the Childhood Cancer Survivor Study. JAMA. 2003;290(12):1583&#x2013;1592. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.290.12.1583 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezerra CT, Grande AJ, Galv&#xe3;o VK, Santos DHMD, Atallah &#xc1;N, Silva V. Assessment of the strength of recommendation and quality of evidence: GRADE checklist. A descriptive study. Sao Paulo Medical J = Revista paulista de medicina. 2022;140(6):829&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1590/1516-3180.2022.0043.R1.07042022 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-3180.2022.0043.R1.07042022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwers MC, Kho ME, Browman GP, Burgers JS, Cluzeau F, Feder G, et al. AGREE II: advancing guideline development, reporting and evaluation in health care. J Clin Epidemiol. 2010;63(12):1308&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.07.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen EE, LaMonte SJ, Erb NL, Beckman KL, Sadeghi N, Hutcheson KA, Stubblefield MD, Abbott DM, Fisher PS, Stein KD, Lyman GH, Pratt-Chapman ML. American cancer society head and neck cancer survivorship care guideline. CA: a cancer J Clin. 2016;66(3):203&#x2013;239. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle C, Kushi LH, Byers T, Courneya KS, Demark-Wahnefried W, Grant B, et al. Nutrition and physical activity during and after cancer treatment: an American Cancer Society guide for informed choices. CA Cancer J Clin. 2006;56(6):323&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.3322/canjclin.56.6.323 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/canjclin.56.6.323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17135691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Shami K, Oeffinger KC, Erb NL, Willis A, Bretsch JK, Pratt-Chapman ML, Cannady RS, Wong SL, Rose J, Barbour AL, Stein KD, Sharpe KB, Brooks DD, Cowens-Alvarado RL. American cancer society colorectal cancer survivorship care guidelines. CA: a Cancer J Clin. 2015;65(6):428&#x2013;455. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runowicz CD, Leach CR, Henry NL, Henry KS, Mackey HT, Cowens-Alvarado RL, et al. American Cancer Society/American Society of Clinical Oncology Breast Cancer Survivorship Care Guideline. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34(6):611&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2015.64.3809 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2015.64.3809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, May AM, Schwartz AL, Courneya KS, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(11):2375&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000002116 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8576825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Lacchetti C, Alici Y, Barton DL, Bruner D, Canin BE, et al. Management of Fatigue in Adult Survivors of Cancer: ASCO-Society for Integrative Oncology Guideline Update. J Clin Oncol: Official J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2024;42(20):2456&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.24.00541 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.24.00541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabi A, Bhargava R, Fatigoni S, Guglielmo M, Horneber M, Roila F, Weis J, Jordan K, Ripamonti CI, &amp; ESMO Guidelines Committee. Electronic address: clinicalguidelines@esmo.org. Cancer-related fatigue: ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment. Ann Oncol: Official J Eur Society Med Oncol. 2020;31(6):713&#x2013;723. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.annonc.2020.02.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdonck-de Leeuw I, Dawson C, Licitra L, Eriksen JG, Hosal S, Singer S, et al. European Head and Neck Society recommendations for head and neck cancer survivorship care. Oral Oncol. 2022;133:106047. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oraloncology.2022.106047 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oraloncology.2022.106047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35932637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher MI, Cohn JC, Harrington SE, Lee JQ, Malone D. Screening and assessment of cancer-related fatigue: a clinical practice guideline for health care providers. Phys Ther. 2022;102(9):pzac120. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzac120 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzac120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36179114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9525018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell D, Keshavarz H, Broadfield L, Hack T, Hamel M, Harth T, Jones J, McLeod D, Olson K, Phan S, Sawka A, Swinton N, Ali M. A pan Canadian practice guideline for screening, assessment, and management of cancer-related fatigue in adults (Version 2). Toronto: Canadian Partnership Against Cancer (Cancer Journey Advisory Group) and the Canadian Association of Psychosocial Oncology. 2015; http://www.capo.ca/pdf/CRF_Guideline.pdf . Assessed 24 Nov 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeland CS, Mendoza TR, Wang XS, Chou C, Harle MT, Morrissey M, Engstrom MC. Assessing symptom distress in cancer patients: the M.D. Anderson Symptom Inventory. Cancer. 2000;89(7):1634&#x2013;1646. https://doi.org/10.1002/1097-0142(20001001)89:7&lt;1634::aid-cncr29&gt;3.0.co;2-v</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Bak K, Berger A, Breitbart W, Escalante CP, Ganz PA, Schnipper HH, Lacchetti C, Ligibel JA, Lyman GH, Ogaily MS, Pirl WF, Jacobsen PB, &amp; American Society of Clinical Oncology. Screening, assessment, and management of fatigue in adult survivors of cancer: an American Society of Clinical oncology clinical practice guideline adaptation. J Clin Oncol: Official J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2014;32(17):1840&#x2013;1850 https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2013.53.4495</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Serv-ices. Physical activity guidelines for Ameri-cans. Washington, DC: US Department ofHealth and Human Services; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kangas M, Bovbjerg DH, Montgomery GH. Cancer-related fatigue: a systematic and meta-analytic review of non-pharmacological therapies for cancer patients. Psychol Bull. 2008;134(5):700&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0012825 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0012825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18729569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen PB, Donovan KA, Vadaparampil ST, Small BJ. Systematic review and meta-analysis of psychological and activity-based interventions for cancer-related fatigue. Health Psychol. 2007;26(6):660&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-6133.26.6.660 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0278-6133.26.6.660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18020836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2398706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons CE, Crane C, Parsons LJ, Fjorback LO, Kuyken W. Home practice in mindfulness-based cognitive therapy and mindfulness-based stress reduction: a systematic review and meta-analysis of participants&#x2019; mindfulness practice and its association with outcomes. Behav Res Ther. 2017;95:29&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brat.2017.05.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2017.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5501725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinkead B, Schettler PJ, Larson ER, Carroll D, Sharenko M, Nettles J, et al. Massage therapy decreases cancer-related fatigue: results from a randomized early phase trial. Cancer. 2018;124(3):546&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1002/cncr.31064 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.31064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29044466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xf6;ger W, Galun D, Reif M, Schumann A, Stankovi&#x107; N, Mili&#x107;evi&#x107; M. Quality of life of patients with advanced pancreatic cancer during treatment with mistletoe: a randomized controlled trial. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2014;111(29&#x2013;30):493&#x2013;502. https://doi.org/10.3238/arztebl.2014.0493 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2014.0493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25142075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4150026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter AB, Liu H, Kohli S, Cerhan JL, Sloan J, McMurray RP, et al. Efficacy of treatment with armodafinil for cancer-related fatigue in patients with high-grade glioma: a phase 3 randomized clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2022;8(2):259&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.5948 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.5948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton DL, Liu H, Dakhil SR, Linquist B, Sloan JA, Nichols CR, et al. Wisconsin Ginseng (Panax quinquefolius) to improve cancer-related fatigue: a randomized, double-blind trial, N07C2. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2013;105(16):1230&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1093/jnci/djt181 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djt181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23853057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3888141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauer ER, Long EF, Petersen L, Ganz PA. Current practice patterns and gaps in guideline-concordant breast cancer survivorship care. J Cancer Survivor: Res Pract. 2023;17(3):906&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11764-021-01152-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-021-01152-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlas SJ, Haas JS, Perez GK, Park ER, Peppercorn JM. Engaging patients, oncologists, and primary care clinicians in the care of cancer survivors: a coordinated care model with system-level technology to move the outcomes needle. JCO Oncol Pract. 2025;21(2):123&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1200/OP.23.00818 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/OP.23.00818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39088767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner AS, Wehlen L, Milzer M, Schmidt ME, Kiermeier S, Maatouk I, et al. Physicians&#x2019; perspectives on cancer-related fatigue management and their suggestions for improvements in medical training: a cross-sectional survey study in Germany. Support Care Canc: Official J Multinat Assoc Support Care Canc. 2024;32(12):788. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-024-08978-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-024-08978-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milzer M, Wagner AS, Steindorf K, Kiermeier S, Schmidt ME, Maatouk I. Psycho-oncologists&#x2019; knowledge of cancer-related fatigue and the targets for improving education and training: results from a cross-sectional survey study. Support Care Cancer. 2023;31(7):412. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-023-07882-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-023-07882-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10289967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G, Rutkowski N, Trudel G, St-Gelais C, Ladouceur M, Brunet J, et al. Translating guidelines to practice: a training session about cancer-related fatigue. Curr Oncol (Toronto, Ont). 2020;27(2):e163&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.3747/co.27.5681 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3747/co.27.5681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S, Yang X, Yu X. Digital health interventions to reduce cancer-related fatigue among adolescents and young adults: Scoping review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2025;13:e68834. https://doi.org/10.2196/68834 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/68834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41117758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12539328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marker RJ, Kittelson AJ, Scorsone JJ, Moran IA, Quindry JC, Leach HJ. A novel telehealth exercise program designed for rural survivors of cancer with cancer-related fatigue: single-arm feasibility trial. JMIR Cancer. 2025;11:e59478. https://doi.org/10.2196/59478 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/59478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39793972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11759908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner AS, Milzer M, Steindorf K, Kiermeier S, Nguyen TD, Schmidt ME, et al. An interdisciplinary challenge: responsibilities in German cancer-related fatigue management from the professional and patient perspective. Oncologist. 2025;30(9):oyaf233. https://doi.org/10.1093/oncolo/oyaf233 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oncolo/oyaf233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40720231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12422314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tevaarwerk AJ, Wisinski KB, Buhr KA, Njiaju UO, Tun M, Donohue S, et al. Leveraging electronic health record systems to create and provide electronic cancer survivorship care plans: a pilot study. J Oncol Pract. 2014;10(3):e150&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1200/JOP.2013.001115 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JOP.2013.001115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24520142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4018457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thong MSY, Doege D, Koch-Gallenkamp L, Bertram H, Eberle A, Holleczek B, et al. Fatigue in long-term cancer survivors: prevalence, associated factors, and mortality. A prospective population-based study. Br J Cancer. 2025;133(6):831&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41416-025-03116-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41416-025-03116-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40665014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12449452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow RE, Vogt TM, Boles SM. Evaluating the public health impact of health promotion interventions: the RE-AIM framework. Am J Public Health. 1999;89(9):1322&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.89.9.1322 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.89.9.1322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10474547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1508772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitson A, Harvey G, McCormack B. Enabling the implementation of evidence based practice: a conceptual framework. Qual Health Care: QHC. 1998;7(3):149&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1136/qshc.7.3.149 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/qshc.7.3.149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10185141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2483604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foy R, Skrypak M, Alderson S, Ivers NM, McInerney B, Stoddart J, et al. Revitalising audit and feedback to improve patient care. BMJ (Clinical research ed). 2020;368:m213. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m213 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32107249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpern MT, McCabe MS, Burg MA. The cancer survivorship journey: models of care, disparities, barriers, and future directions. American Society of Clinical Oncology educational book. American Society of Clinical Oncology. Annual Meeting. 2016&#x2019;35:231&#x2013;239 https://doi.org/10.1200/EDBK_156039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems RA, Bolman CA, Mesters I, Kanera IM, Beaulen AA, Lechner L. Short-term effectiveness of a web-based tailored intervention for cancer survivors on quality of life, anxiety, depression, and fatigue: randomized controlled trial. Psychooncology. 2017;26(2):222&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1002/pon.4113 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varesi A, Deumer US, Ananth S, Ricevuti G. The emerging role of gut microbiota in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): current evidence and potential therapeutic applications. J Clin Med. 2021;10(21):5077. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10215077 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10215077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8584653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Perry RJ. Metabolic underpinnings of cancer-related fatigue. Am J Physiol-Endocrinol Metab. 2024;326(3):E290&#x2013;307. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpendo.00378.2023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00378.2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38294698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11901342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Lamkin DM. Inflammation and cancer-related fatigue: mechanisms, contributing factors, and treatment implications. Brain, behavior, and immunity. 2013;30 Suppl(0):S48&#x2013;S57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2012.06.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng LR, Nguyen Q, Ross A, Saligan LN. Evaluating the role of mitochondrial function in cancer-related fatigue. J Visual Exp: JoVE. 2018;135:57736. https://doi.org/10.3791/57736 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/57736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshragh J, Dhruva A, Paul SM, Cooper BA, Mastick J, Hamolsky D, et al. Associations between neurotransmitter genes and fatigue and energy levels in women after breast cancer surgery. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2017;53(1):67-84.e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2016.08.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2016.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27720787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sochocka M, Donskow-&#x141;ysoniewska K, Diniz BS, Kurpas D, Brzozowska E, Leszek J. The gut microbiome alterations and inflammation-driven pathogenesis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease-a critical review. Mol Neurobiol. 2019;56(3):1841&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-018-1188-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-018-1188-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29936690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amidi A, Wu LM. Circadian disruption and cancer- and treatment-related symptoms. Front Oncol. 2022;12:1009064. https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2022.1009064 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2022.1009064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36387255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9650229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinali DP, Brown GM, Pandi-Perumal SR. Chronotherapy. Handbook Clin Neurol. 2021;179:357&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-819975-6.00023-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-819975-6.00023-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello RB, Lentino CV, Boyd CC, O&#x2019;Connell ML, Crawford CC, Sprengel ML, et al. The effectiveness of melatonin for promoting healthy sleep: a rapid evidence assessment of the literature. Nutr J. 2014;13:106. https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2891-13-106 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2891-13-106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25380732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4273450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimee F, Gioxari A, Papandreou P, Amerikanou C, Karageorgopoulou S, Kaliora AC, et al. The effect of melatonin supplementation on cancer-related fatigue during chemotherapy treatment of breast cancer patients: a double-blind, randomized controlled study. Cancers (Basel). 2024;16(4):802. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16040802 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers16040802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boykoff N, Moieni M, Subramanian SK. Confronting chemobrain: an in-depth look at survivors&#x2019; reports of impact on work, social networks, and health care response. J Cancer Surviv. 2009;3(4):223&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11764-009-0098-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-009-0098-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2775113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XM, Walitt B, Saligan L, Tiwari AF, Cheung CW, Zhang ZJ. Chemobrain: a critical review and causal hypothesis of link between cytokines and epigenetic reprogramming associated with chemotherapy. Cytokine. 2015;72(1):86&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cyto.2014.12.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2014.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25573802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4750385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#xf1;i M, Basu N, Murray AD, Waiter GD. Neural indicators of fatigue in chronic diseases: A systematic review of MRI studies. Diagnostics (Basel, Switzerland). 2018;8(3):42. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics8030042 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics8030042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruggeman-Everts FZ, Wolvers MDJ, van de Schoot R, Vollenbroek-Hutten MMR, Van der Lee ML. Effectiveness of two web-based interventions for chronic cancer-related fatigue compared to an active control condition: Results of the &#x201c;Fitter na kanker&#x201d; randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(10):e336. https://doi.org/10.2196/jmir.7180 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5668634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>