<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41508642</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a 12-week combined exercise-nutrition intervention on body composition, physical fitness, and lifestyle disease indicators in women with normal weight obesity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>57</StartPage><EndPage>63</EndPage><MedlinePgn>57-63</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2025.0035</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study investigated the effects of 12 weeks of nutrition education and combined exercise training on body composition, physical fitness, and lifestyle disease indicators in women with normal weight obesity (NWO).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-six women with NWO in their 30s (BMI 18.5-22.9 kg/m2, body fat &#x2265; 30%) were randomly assigned to either a diet education and exercise training group (DE+TR; n = 13) or a diet education only group (DE; n = 13). The DE+TR group performed 80 minutes of combined exercise (40 min aerobic + 40 min resistance) three days per week for 12 weeks with nutrition education. The DE group received nutrition education only. Body composition, physical fitness, and lifestyle disease indicators were measured pre- and post-intervention using two-way repeated measures ANOVA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Body fat mass and body fat percentage decreased significantly in both groups, while fat-free mass increased only in the DE+TR group (p &lt; .05). Physical fitness parameters (grip strength, sit-ups, flexibility, standing long jump, VO2max) and all 1-RM tests improved significantly only in the DE+TR group. Lifestyle disease indicators improved significantly in the DE+TR group: hypertension markers (heart rate, systolic blood pressure, mean arterial pressure, rate pressure product), diabetes markers (fasting glucose, insulin, HOMA-IR), lipid profiles (total cholesterol, triglycerides, LDL-C, HDL-C), and atherosclerosis risk ratios all showed favorable changes (p &lt; .05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Twelve weeks of combined nutrition education and exercise training effectively improves body composition, physical fitness, and lifestyle disease indicators in women with NWO, providing more comprehensive health benefits than nutrition education alone. From a public health perspective, these findings support the implementation of combined exercise-nutrition programs in community health centers and workplace wellness programs for women identified with NWO.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heo</LastName><ForeName>Dasom</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Prescription, Dongseo University, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Man-Gyoon</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Kyung Hee University, Yongin, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Won-Sang</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Senior Exercise Prescription, Dongseo University, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020S1A5B5A17090812</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combined exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">normal weight obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41508642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12784032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2025.0035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2025.0035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Obesity and overweight. WHO Fact Sheet. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Welfare . Korea National Health Statistics. Sejong: Ministry of Health and Welfare; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MK, Han K, Kwon HS, Song KH, Yim HW, Lee WC, Park YM. Normal weight obesity in Korean adults. Clin Endocrinol. 2014;80:214&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23362933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo A, Martinoli R, Vaia F, Di Renzo L. Normal weight obese (NWO) women: An evaluation of a candidate new syndrome. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2006;16:513&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17126766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur P, Mascarenhas SS. Lifestyle diseases: keeping fit for a healthy tomorrow. Int J Clin Biomed Res. 2019;5:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco LP, Morais CC, Cominetti C. Normal-weight obesity syndrome: diagnosis, prevalence, and clinical implications. Nutr Rev. 2016;74:558&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan N, Kantartzis K, Machann J, Schick F, Thamer C, Rittig K, Balletshofer B, Machicao F, Fritsche A, H&#xe4;ring HU. Identification and characterization of metabolically benign obesity in humans. Arch Intern Med. 2013;168:1609&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18695074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappola AR, Bandeen-Roche K, Wand GS, Volpato S, Fried LP. Association of IGF-I levels with muscle strength and mobility in older women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;86:4139&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srikanthan P, Hevener AL, Karlamangla AS. Sarcopenia exacerbates obesity-associated insulin resistance and dysglycemia: findings from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey III. PLoS One. 2016;5:e10805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kyung C, Park JS, Lee SP, Kim HK, Ahn CW, Kim KR, Kang S. Normal-weight obesity is associated with increased risk of subclinical atherosclerosis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2015;14:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4488951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25990248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquitt JL, Pickett K, Loveman E, Frampton GK. Surgery for weight loss in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014:CD003641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25105982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imaz I, Mart&#xed;nez-Cervell C, Garc&#xed;a-Alvarez EE, Sendra-Guti&#xe9;rrez JM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Enr&#xed;quez J. Safety and effectiveness of the intragastric balloon for obesity: a meta-analysis. Obes Surg. 2008;18:841&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18459025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson EL. The effect of exercise on non-exercise physical activity and sedentary behavior in adults. Obes Rev. 2017;18:40&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28164451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petridou A, Siopi A, Mougios V. Exercise in the management of obesity. Metabolism. 2019;92:163&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30385379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Aguirre L, Gurney AB, Waters DL, Sinacore DR, Colombo E, Armamento-Villareal R, Qualls C. Aerobic or resistance exercise, or both, in dieting obese older adults. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:1943&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5552187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28514618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zouhal H, Ben Abderrahman A, Khodamoradi A, Saeidi A, Jayavel A, Hackney AC, Laher I, Algotar AM, Jabbour G. Effects of physical training on anthropometrics, physical and physiological capacities in individuals with obesity: a systematic review. Obes Rev. 2020;21:e13039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason C, Foster-Schubert KE, Imayama I, Kong A, Xiao L, Bain C, Campbell KL, Wang CY, Duggan CR, Ulrich CM, Alfano CM, Blackburn GL, McTiernan A. Dietary weight loss and exercise effects on insulin resistance in postmenopausal women. Am J Prev Med. 2015;41:366&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3185302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21961463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffault A, Czernichow S, Hagger MS, Ferrand M, Erichot N, Carette C, Boujut E, Flahault C. The effects of mindfulness training on weight-loss and health-related behaviours in adults with overweight and obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Res Clin Pract. 2017;11:90&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies KA, Shur NF, Madden LA, Stephens FB. A systematic review of physical activity and nutritional interventions for the management of normal weight and overweight obesity. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;34:1891&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39278737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motevalli M, Drenowatz C, Tanous D, Ruedl G, Kirschner W, Schauer M, Rosemann T, Wirnitzer K. Guideline-Based Digital Exercise Interventions for Reducing Body Weight and Fat and Promoting Physical Activity in Adults With Overweight and Obesity: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Interact J Med Res. 2025;14:e73656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12371298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40773286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine Physical activity and excess body weight and adiposity for adults: ACSM consensus statement. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56:1896&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39277776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotunda W, Rains C, Jacobs SR, Ng V, Lee R, Rutledge S, Evans T, Jones E, Petersen R, Short V. Weight Loss in Short-Term Interventions for Physical Activity and Nutrition Among Adults With Overweight or Obesity: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Prev Chronic Dis. 2024;21:230347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10996390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38573796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kang S, Kang H. Association between normal-weight obesity and bone mineral density in older Korean adults: a population-based cross-sectional study. Maturitas. 2024;180:107891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38006815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Y, Liu W, Zhang X, Chen Y, Zhang S, Wang L, Zhao S, Li R, Xu Y, Xue S, Zhao H, Qiao J. Normal weight obesity is associated with lower AFC and adverse IVF outcomes. Front Endocrinol. 2024;15:1332995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10917978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemiro GM, Rewane A, Algotar AM. Exercise and Fitness Effect on Obesity. In: StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30969715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>