<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41725018</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1758-5996</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetology &amp; metabolic syndrome</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetol Metab Syndr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of high intensity interval training on body composition, metabolic, inflammatory and oxidative stress markers in adolescents with obesity.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">87</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13098-026-02110-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The aim of the study is to evaluate the effects of 12-week high-intensity interval training (HIIT) on body composition, metabolic hormones, insulin resistance, lipid profile, inflammation, and oxidative stress markers in adolescents with obesity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Thirty-two (female&#x2009;=&#x2009;19; male&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) adolescent volunteers with obesity were divided into two groups: training and control. Participants underwent health checks with resting electrocardiogram (ECG) and blood pressure monitoring. Anthropometric measurements, body composition components, and biochemical tests were performed in pre and post-tests of all participants. Serum fasting glucose, insulin, total cholesterol, triglyceride, high and low-density lipoproteins, leptin, adiponectin, High-Sensitivity C-Reactive Protein (hs-CRP), Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha (TNF-&#x3b1;), Interleukin-6 (IL-6), hs-CRP, TNF-alpha, IL-6, prooxidant, and antioxidant parameters were analyzed biochemically. Homeostasis Model Assessment of Insulin Resistance (HOMA-IR) was calculated. The training group participated in a HIIT program for 12&#xa0;weeks, 3&#xa0;days a week, for a total of 36 sessions, after 3&#xa0;weeks of pre-adaptation studies. Heart rate was monitored with a heart rate monitor. The control group was not included in any exercise program during this period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean age of the adolescents with obesity included in the study was 15.28&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.93&#xa0;years and Body Mass Index (BMI) was 33.21&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.98&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup>. Group, sex, and time interaction effects showed that HOMA-IR and triglyceride levels had reduced in the HIIT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The group-time interaction effect was observed in the parameters related to body composition, metabolism, inflammation, and pro-oxidant status (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). BMI, waist and hip circumferences, body fat (%), insulin, glucose, total cholesterol, LDL, triglyceride, and leptin were decreased in the HIIT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). While lean mass, muscle mass, body water and adiponectin were increased in the HIIT intervention group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The inflammation parameters (hs-CRP, TNF-&#x3b1;, and IL-6), and pro-oxidant indicator Advanced Glycation End Products (AGEs) were decreased in the HIIT group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">A 12-week HIIT program in adolescents with obesity has positive effects on body composition, metabolic parameters, inflammation, and oxidative stress markers. These benefits may contribute to healthy growth and developmental processes. HIIT represents a time-efficient, practical, and effective strategy to mitigate obesity-related metabolic and inflammatory disturbances while strengthening antioxidant defenses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atabay Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Gulten</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5298-1459</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Fresenius Schools, Vocational School of Physiotherapy, Minden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasimay</LastName><ForeName>Ozgur</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6294-7174</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bingul</LastName><ForeName>Ilknur</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6432-3541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biochemistry, Basic Medical Sciences, Istanbul Medical Faculty, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gedikbasi</LastName><ForeName>Asuman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7121-6077</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Basic Sciences, Clinical Biochemistry and Genetics, Institute of Child Health, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agopyan</LastName><ForeName>Ani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6407-4648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Movement and Training Sciences, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kucuk Yetgin</LastName><ForeName>Meral</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4916-5661</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Sports Health Sciences, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey. meralkucukyetgin@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Health Science,, Indiana University School of Public Health-Bloomington, 1025 E 7th Street, Suite 111, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA. meralkucukyetgin@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SAG-C-YLP-170419-0140</GrantID><Agency>Marmara University Scientific Research Projects Coordination Unit (BAPKO)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetol Metab Syndr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101488958</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1758-5996</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Marmara University School of Medicine Clinical Research Ethics Review Board approved this study&#x2019;s human subjects components, which followed the Declaration of Helsinki. For every subject, written informed permission was acquired. Consent for publication: All participants gave informed consent for publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41725018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-026-02110-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13098-026-02110-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Nan N, Wei L, Li T, Gao X, Lu D. The effect and safety of high-intensity interval training in the treatment of adolescent obesity: a meta-analysis. Ann Palliat Med. 2021;10(8):8596&#x2013;606. 10.21037/apm-21-757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/apm-21-757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjispyrou S, Dinas PC, Delitheos SM, Koumprentziotis IA, Chryssanthopoulos C, Philippou A. The effect of high-intensity interval training on mitochondrial-associated indices in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Biosci (Landmark Ed). 2023;28(11):281. 10.31083/j.fbl.2811281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.fbl.2811281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38062841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Keating SE, Holland DJ, Finlayson G, King NA, Gomersall SR, et al. High-intensity interval training does not result in short- or long-term dietary compensation in cardiac rehabilitation: results from the FITR heart study. Appetite. 2021;158:105021. 10.1016/j.appet.2020.105021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2020.105021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33161045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noll M, Mendon&#xe7;a CR, Rodrigues APDS, de Almeida AA, Noll PRES. Narrative review of the influence of high-intensity interval training on adolescents&#x2019; bone health: commentary and perspectives. Transl Pediatr. 2021;10(1):160&#x2013;4. 10.21037/tp-20-166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/tp-20-166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33633948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Lan H. The effects of high-intensity interval training on cardiometabolic health in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(4):690&#x2013;706. 10.52082/jssm.2024.690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kranen SH, Oliveira RS, Bond B, Williams CA, Barker AR. The effect of 4 weeks of high-intensity interval training and 2 weeks of detraining on cardiovascular disease risk factors in male adolescents. Exp Physiol. 2023;108(4):595&#x2013;606. 10.1113/EP090340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP090340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martland R, Mondelli V, Gaughran F, Stubbs B. Can high-intensity interval training improve physical and mental health outcomes? A meta-review of 33 systematic reviews across the lifespan. J Sports Sci. 2019;38(4):430&#x2013;69. 10.1080/02640414.2019.1706829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2019.1706829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31889469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morelli M, Gaggini M, Daniele G, Marraccini P, Sicari R, Gastaldelli A. Ectopic fat: the true culprit linking obesity and cardiovascular disease? Thromb Haemost. 2013;110(10):651&#x2013;60. 10.1160/TH13-04-0285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1160/TH13-04-0285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai T, Autieri MV, Scalia R. Adipose tissue inflammation and metabolic dysfunction in obesity. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2021;320(3):375&#x2013;91. 10.1152/ajpcell.00379.2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00379.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33356944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa S, Fujita T, Shimabukuro M, Iwaki M, Yamada Y, Nakajima Y, et al. Increased oxidative stress in obesity and its impact on metabolic syndrome. J Clin Invest. 2004;114(12):1752&#x2013;61. 10.1172/JCI21625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI21625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC535065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15599400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headid IIIRJ, Park SY. The impacts of exercise on pediatric obesity. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2021;64(5):196&#x2013;204. 10.3345/cep.2020.00997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/cep.2020.00997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh H, Safarzade A. High intensity intermittent training induces anti-inflammatory cytokine responses and improves body composition in overweight adolescent boys. Horm Mol Biol Clin Investig. 2019;39(3):20190004. 10.1515/hmbci-2019-0004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hmbci-2019-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole TJ, Bellizzi MC, Flegal KM, Dietz WH. Establishing a standard definition for child overweight and obesity worldwide: International survey. BMJ. 2000;320(7244):1240&#x2013;3. 10.1136/bmj.320.7244.1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.320.7244.1240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly AS, Steinberger J, Olson TP, Dengel DR. In the absence of weight loss, exercise training does not improve adipokines or oxidative stress in overweight children. Metabolism. 2007;56(7):1005&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.metabol.2007.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2007.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17570265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marfell-Jones MJ, Stewart AD, Olds T, de Ridder JH. International Standards for Anthropometric Assessment (ISAK). Lower Hutt, New Zealand; ISBN. 2011.9780620362078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman TG, Hingle M, Going SB. Body composition in children. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2013;25(4):573&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.25.4.573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24214440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenney WL, Wilmore JH, Costill DL. Physiology of sport and exercise. 7th ed. Human Kinetics; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Heart rate monitoring: applications and limitations. Sports Med. 2003;33(7):517&#x2013;38. 10.2165/00007256-200333070-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333070-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin M, Kurtoglu S, Kendirci M, Atabek ME, Yazici C. Homeostasis model assessment is more reliable than the fasting glucose/insulin ratio and quantitative insulin sensitivity check index for assessing insulin resistance among obese children and adolescents. Pediatrics. 2005;115(4):e500&#x2013;3. 10.1542/peds.2004-1921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2004-1921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Joseph JA. Quantifying cellular oxidative stress by dichlorofluorescein assay using microplate reader. Free Radic Biol Med. 1999;27(7&#x2013;8):612&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0891-5849(99)00107-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10490282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buege JA, Aust SD. Microsomal lipid peroxidation. In: Colowick OP, Kaplan NO, editors. Methods in Enzymology. Vol. 52. Academic Press; 1978. pp. 302&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">672633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nch G, Keis R, Wessels A, Riederer P, Bahner U, Heidland A, et al. Determination of advanced glycation end products in serum by fluorescence spectroscopy and competitive ELISA. Eur J Clin Chem Clin Biochem. 1997;35:669&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9352229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzie IF, Strain JJ. The ferric reducing ability of plasma (FRAP) as a measure of &#x201c;antioxidant power&#x201d;: the FRAP assay. Anal Biochem. 1996;239(1):70&#x2013;6. 10.1006/abio.1996.0292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/abio.1996.0292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8660627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence RA, Burk RF. Glutathione peroxidase activity in selenium-deficient rat liver. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1976;71(4):952&#x2013;8. 10.1016/0006-291X(76)90747-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-291X(76)90747-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">971321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedlak J, Lindsay RH. Estimation of total, protein-bound, and nonprotein sulfhydryl groups in tissue with Ellman&#x2019;s reagent. Anal Biochem. 1968;25(1):192&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0003-2697(68)90092-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4973948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay M, Wobbrock JO, Rosenholtz R. ARTool: Aligned rank transform for nonparametric factorial ANOVAs. The R Project for Statistical Computing. 2021. https://cran.r-project.org/package=ARTool</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Li Q, Yang Q, Yu H. The effect of high-intensity interval training on health-related outcomes in obese adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1609818. 10.3389/fphys.2025.1609818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1609818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12403219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40904707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Lee SJ, Rognmo &#xd8;, St&#xf8;len TO, Bye A, Haram PM, et al. Aerobic interval training versus continuous moderate exercise as a treatment for the metabolic syndrome: a pilot study. Circulation. 2008;118(4):346&#x2013;54. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.772822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.772822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18606913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L, Chen J, Yuan W. The effect of HIIT on body composition, cardiovascular fitness, psychological well-being, and executive function of overweight/obese female young adults. Front Psychol. 2023;13:1095328. 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1095328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1095328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9891140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng C, Yucheng T, Shu L, Yu Z. Effects of school-based high-intensity interval training on body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness and cardiometabolic markers in adolescent boys with obesity: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Pediatr. 2022;22(1):112. 10.1186/s12887-021-03079-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-021-03079-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias KA, Green DJ, Ingul CB, Pavey TG, Coombes JS. Exercise and vascular function in child obesity: a meta-analysis. Pediatrics. 2015;136(3):e648&#x2013;59. 10.1542/peds.2015-0616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2015-0616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delfan M, Saeidi A, Supriya R, et al. Enhancing cardiometabolic health: unveiling the synergistic effects of high-intensity interval training with spirulina supplementation on selected adipokines, insulin resistance, and anthropometric indices in obese males. Nutr Metab (Lond). 2024;21:11. 10.1186/s12986-024-00785-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-024-00785-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10921712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38454429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidi A, Saei MA, et al. Supplementation with spinach-derived thylakoid augments the benefits of high intensity training on adipokines, insulin resistance and lipid profiles in males with obesity. Front Endocrinol. 2023;14:1141796. 10.3389/fendo.2023.1141796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1141796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10422041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidi A, Seifi-Ski-Shahr F, Soltani M, Daraei A, Shirvani H, Laher I, et al. Resistance training, gremlin 1 and macrophage migration inhibitory factor in obese men: a randomised trial. Arch Physiol Biochem. 2023;129(3):640&#x2013;8. 10.1080/13813455.2020.1856142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13813455.2020.1856142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33370549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbari-Niaki A, Saeidi A, Kolahdouzi S, Aliakbari-Baydokhty M, Ardeshiri S, Abderrahman A, et al. Effect of <i>Crocus sativus</i> Linnaeus (saffron) supplementations combined with circuit resistance training on total creatine kinase, lactate dehydrogenase and creatine kinase MB levels in young untrained men. Sci Sports. 2019;34(1):e53&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.scispo.2018.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2018.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babraj JA, Vollaard NB, Keast C, Guppy FM, Cottrell G, Timmons JA. Extremely short duration high intensity interval training substantially improves insulin action in young healthy males. BMC Endocr Disord. 2009;9(1):3. 10.1186/1472-6823-9-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6823-9-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2640399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19175906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racil G, Chelly MS, Coquart J, Padulo J, Teodor DF, Russo L. Long- and short-term high-intensity interval training on lipid profile and cardiovascular disorders in obese male adolescents. Children. 2023;10:1180. 10.3390/children10071180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children10071180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10378083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37508677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardar SA, Karaca A, G&#xfc;ldiken S, Palab&#x131;y&#x131;k O, S&#xfc;t N, Demir AM. High-intensity interval training acutely alters plasma adipokine levels in young overweight/obese women. Arch Physiol Biochem. 2018;124(2):149&#x2013;55. 10.1080/13813455.2017.1369998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13813455.2017.1369998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28857629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang L, Su Z. Exercise-induced stress pathways: Crosstalk between AMPK, HSPs, and inflammation. J Invest Med. 2025. 10.1177/10815589251366914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10815589251366914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40778577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend LK, Steinberg GR. AMPK and the Endocrine Control of Metabolism. Endocrine Reviews. 2023;44(5):910&#x2013;33. 10.1210/endrev/bnad012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/endrev/bnad012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37115289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delfan M, Vahed A, Bishop DJ, Amadeh Juybari R, Laher I, Saeidi A, et al. Effects of two workload-matched high intensity interval training protocols on regulatory factors associated with mitochondrial biogenesis in the soleus muscle of diabetic rats. Front Physiol. 2022;13:927969. 10.3389/fphys.2022.927969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.927969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9541894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36213227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaulding HR, Yan Z. AMPK and the adaptation to exercise. Annu Rev Physiol. 2022;84(1):209&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-physiol-060721-095517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiston EM, Eichner NZ, Gilbertson NM, Malin SK. Exercise improves adiposopathy, insulin sensitivity and metabolic syndrome severity independent of intensity. Exp Physiol. 2020;105(4):632&#x2013;40. 10.1113/EP088158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP088158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32020676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domaradzki J, Ko&#x17a;lenia D, Popowczak M. The relative importance of age at peak height velocity and fat mass index in high-intensity interval training effect on cardiorespiratory fitness in adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. Children (Basel). 2022;9(10):1554. 10.3390/children9101554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children9101554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9600318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Wen Z, Deng K, Li R, Yu Q, Xiao M. Relationships of sex hormones with muscle mass and muscle strength in male adolescents at different stages of puberty. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(12):e0260521. 10.1371/journal.pone.0260521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0260521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8638900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamale, R., Rodr&#xed;guez Rond&#xf3;n, A. V., van der Walle, E. E., van den Akker, E. L., &amp; Visser, J. A. Sex differences in leptin levels in children and adolescents with normal weight and overweight/obesity across pubertal stages: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clini Endocrinol Meta. 2025;dgaf621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12819880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41240372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchan DS, Ollis S, Young JD, Thomas NE, Cooper SM, Tong TK, et al. The effects of time and intensity of exercise on novel and established markers of CVD in adolescent youth. Am J Hum Biol. 2011;23(4):517&#x2013;26. 10.1002/ajhb.21166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajhb.21166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21465614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridker PM, Hennekens CH, Buring JE, Rifai N. C-reactive protein and other markers of inflammation in the prediction of cardiovascular disease in women. N Engl J Med. 2000;342(12):836&#x2013;43. 10.1056/NEJM200003233421202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200003233421202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10733371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira &#xc9;, Marinho DA, Neiva HP, Louren&#xe7;o O. Inflammatory effects of high and moderate intensity exercise&#x2014;a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2020;10:489354. 10.3389/fphys.2019.01550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6962351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty S, Harley R, McAuley JJ, Crowe LA, Pedret C, Kirwan PD, et al. The effect of exercise on cytokines: implications for musculoskeletal health: a narrative review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2022;14(1):5. 10.1186/s13102-022-00397-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-022-00397-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34991697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhibi F, Zouhal H, Lira FS, Ouerghi N, Prioux J, Besbes S, et al. Inflammatory cytokines and metabolic responses to high-intensity intermittent training: effect of the exercise intensity. Biol Sport. 2022;39(2):263&#x2013;72. 10.5114/biolsport.2022.104914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2022.104914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lihn AS, Richelsen B, Pedersen SB, Haugaard SB, Rathje GS, Madsbad S, et al. Increased expression of TNF-&#x3b1;, IL-6, and IL-8 in HALS: implications for reduced adiponectin expression and plasma levels. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003;285(5):E1072&#x2013;80. 10.1152/ajpendo.00206.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00206.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12876073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinha JB, Ramis TR, Vieira AF, Macedo RC, Rodrigues-Krause J, Boeno FP, et al. Glycemic, inflammatory and oxidative stress responses to different high-intensity training protocols in type 1 diabetes: a randomized clinical trial. J Diabetes Complications. 2018;32(12):1124&#x2013;32. 10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2018.09.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2018.09.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira-Souza LM, Aidar FJ, Matos DGD, Silva AND, Miguel-dos-Santos R, Santos JLD, et al. Short-term HIIT does not promote oxidative stress or muscle damage. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2021;27(2):138&#x2013;41. 10.1590/1517-8692202127022019_0018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-8692202127022019_0018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa KB, Magalh&#xe3;es SM, Aguiar PF, Ottone V, Tossige-Gomes R, Magalh&#xe3;es F, et al. Modification of blood redox homeostasis by high-intensity interval training. Reactive Oxygen Species. 2018;5(13):56&#x2013;67. https://rosj.org/index.php/ros/article/view/116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reljic D. High-intensity interval training as redox medicine: targeting oxidative stress and antioxidant adaptations in cardiometabolic disease cohorts. Antioxidants. 2025;14(8):937. 10.3390/antiox14080937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox14080937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12382795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40867832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas DA, Soares BA, Nonato LF, Fonseca SR, Martins JB, Mendon&#xe7;a VA, et al. High intensity interval training modulates hippocampal oxidative stress, BDNF and inflammatory mediators in rats. Physiol Behav. 2018;184:6&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.physbeh.2017.10.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2017.10.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29111230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi N, Afrasyabi S, Mohamadi Zadeh MA. The effects of high intensity interval training induced H&#x2082;O&#x2082;, Nrf2 changes on antioxidants factors in type 2 diabetes. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2024;23(2):1829&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s40200-022-01128-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-022-01128-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11599511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39610477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ristow M, Zarse K. How increased oxidative stress promotes longevity and metabolic health: the concept of mitochondrial hormesis (mitohormesis). Exp Gerontol. 2010;45(6):410&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.exger.2010.03.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2010.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20350594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radak Z, Chung HY, Koltai E, Taylor AW, Goto S. Exercise, oxidative stress and hormesis. Ageing Res Rev. 2008;7(1):34&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.arr.2007.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2007.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17869589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samsonov A, Urlacher SS. Oxidative Stress in Children and Adolescents: Insights Into Human Biology. Am J Hum Biol. 2025. 10.1002/ajhb.24200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajhb.24200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11736247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39815753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozovic M, Ostanek B, Kotur-Stevuljevic J, Marc J, Mercantepe F, Klisic A. Oxidative stress in adolescents with overweight/obesity. J Med Bio. 2025. 10.5937/jomb0-59362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5937/jomb0-59362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazeminasab F, Miraghajani M, Khalafi M, Sakhaei MH, Rosenkranz SK, Santos HO. Effects of low-carbohydrate diets, with and without caloric restriction, on inflammatory markers in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2024;78(7):569&#x2013;84. 10.1038/s41430-024-01431-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-024-01431-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38499791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Symonds ME, Akbari A. The impact of exercise training versus caloric restriction on inflammation markers: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2021;62(15):4226&#x2013;41. 10.1080/10408398.2021.1873732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2021.1873732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33506692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira BKS, Oliveira TMS, Andrade PA, Hermsdorff HHM, Rosa CDOB, Franceschini SDCC. Dietary pattern and macronutrients profile on the variation of inflammatory biomarkers: scientific update. Cardiol Res Pract. 2018;1:4762575. 10.1155/2018/4762575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/4762575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldelli S, Aiello G, Mansilla Di Martino E, Campaci D, Muthanna FM, Lombardo M. The role of adipose tissue and nutrition in the regulation of adiponectin. Nutrients. 2024;16(15):2436. 10.3390/nu16152436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16152436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11313710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39125318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>