<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41272920</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early Sport Specialization and Intense Training in Junior Tennis Players: A Sport-Specific Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>67</StartPage><EndPage>72</EndPage><MedlinePgn>67-72</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381251393642</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381251393642</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Early sports participation can provide significant physical, psychosocial, and mental benefits for young athletes. Sports engagement can be via sport sampling or sport specialization. Sport specialization is often encouraged by parents and coaches as it is perceived as a mechanism for achieving elite level play, particularly in tennis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EVIDENCE ACQUISITION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A search on PubMed, Google Scholar, and Science Direct was conducted for pertinent peer-reviewed studies on sport specialization and overuse injuries in youth athletics and junior tennis using key terms including "junior tennis," "youth sports," "sport specialization," and "overuse injury."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Clinical review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 5.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Early sport specialization leads to increased injury risk, decreased athletic career longevity, and higher incidence of burnout without demonstrating significant benefits in terms of improving peak sports performance or the likelihood of reaching elite play.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Youth athletes should avoid specializing in a single sport before age 12, avoid training more hours per week than their age in years, and limit training to 16 hours per week maximum. Specific to tennis, junior players should be at least 12 years old for tournament play, compete in no more than 2 tournaments per month or 12 per year, engage in a maximum of 12 hours per week of organized tennis, a minimum of 2 hours per week of injury prevention training, and consider another off-season sport. Injury may be more likely with early sport specialization, early intense training (before middle or late adolescence) and annual match volume (&gt;40 matches annually). Finally, we provide novel recommendations for safe volumes of training, matches, and tournaments for junior tennis players based on their age and level of play.Strength-of-Recommendation Taxonomy (SORT):B - recommendations based on inconsistent or limited-quality patient-oriented evidence.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thurber</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Mount Sinai Hospital, Department of Orthopedics, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kantrowitz</LastName><ForeName>David E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Mount Sinai Hospital, Department of Orthopedics, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Kevin C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mount Sinai Medical Center, Department of Orthopedics, Miami Beach, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jayanthi</LastName><ForeName>Neeru</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University School of Medicine, Emory Sports Medicine Center, Emory Tennis Medicine, Johns Creek, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colvin</LastName><ForeName>Alexis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Mount Sinai Hospital, Department of Orthopedics, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013715" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tennis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013038" MajorTopicYN="Y">Specialization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012090" MajorTopicYN="N">Cumulative Trauma Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067009" MajorTopicYN="Y">Youth Sports</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003163" MajorTopicYN="N">Competitive Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burnout</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport specialization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training schedule</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youth tennis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the following authors has declared a potential conflict of interest as specified in the Sport Health conflict of interest: A.C. - Chief Medical Officer of USOpen, N. J. - USTA Sport Science Commission.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41272920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12640273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381251393642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmad MF, Low JFL, Nadzalan A, Aziz AA. Developmental practice activities of youth soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(8):4598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barth M, G&#xfc;llich A, Macnamara BN, Hambrick DZ. Predictors of junior versus senior elite performance are opposite: a systematic review and meta-analysis of participation patterns. Sports Med. 2022;52(6):1399-1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9124658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35038142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter-Jones ADG, Maffulli N, TOYA Study Group. Parental influence on sport participation in elite young athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2003;43(2):250-255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barynina I, Vaitsekhovskii S. The aftermath of early sports specialization for highly qualified swimmers. Fitness Sports Rev Int. 1992;27:132-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DR, Snedden TR, Biese KM, et al. Consensus definition of sport specialization in youth athletes using a Delphi approach. J Athl Train. 2021;56(11):1239-1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner JS, Council on Sports Medicine and Fitness. Overuse injuries, overtraining, and burnout in child and adolescent athletes. Pediatrics. 2007;119(6):1242-1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17545398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner JS, LaBotz M, Sugimoto D, Stracciolini A. The psychosocial implications of sport specialization in pediatric athletes. J Athl Train. 2019;54(10):1021-1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31532693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butcher J, Lindner KJ, Johns DP. Withdrawal from competitive youth sport: a retrospective ten-year study. J Sport Behav. 25(2):145-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carder SL, Giusti NE, Vopat LM, et al. The concept of sport sampling versus sport specialization: preventing youth athlete injury: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(11):2850-2857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31961703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson R. The socialization of elite tennis players in Sweden: an analysis of the players&#x2019; backgrounds and development. Sociol Sport J. 1988;5(3):241-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiFiori JP, Benjamin HJ, Brenner JS, et al. Overuse injuries and burnout in youth sports: a position statement from the American Medical Society for Sports Medicine. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(4):287-288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24463910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStefano LJ, Beltz EM, Root HJ, et al. Sport sampling is associated with improved landing technique in youth athletes. Sports Health. 2018;10(2):160-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feeley BT, Agel J, LaPrade RF. When is it too early for single sport specialization? Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(1):234-241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25825379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford PR, Ward P, Hodges NJ, Williams AM. The role of deliberate practice and play in career progression in sport: the early engagement hypothesis. High Ability Studies. 2009;20(1):65-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco MF, Madaleno FO, de Paula TMN, Ferreira TV, Pinto RZ, Resende RA. Prevalence of overuse injuries in athletes from individual and team sports: A systematic review with meta-analysis and GRADE recommendations. Braz J Phys Ther. 2021;25(5):500-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34039519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giusti NE, Carder SL, Vopat L, et al. Comparing burnout in sport-specializing versus sport-sampling adolescent athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(3):232596712090757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould D, Tuffey S, Udry E, Loehr J. Burnout in competitive junior tennis players: I. A quantitative psychological assessment. Sport Psychol. 1996;10(4):322-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxley DJ, O&#x2019;Connor D, Larkin P. The pathway to the top: key factors and influences in the development of Australian Olympic and World Championship track and field athletes. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2017;12(2):264-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi N, Feller E, Smith A. Junior competitive tennis: ideal training and tournament recommendations. J Med Sci Tennis. 2013;18(2):30-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi N, Kleithermes S, Dugas L, Pasulka J, Iqbal S, LaBella C. Risk of injuries associated with sport specialization and intense training patterns in young athletes: a longitudinal clinical case-control study. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(6):232596712092276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi N, Pinkham C, Dugas L, Patrick B, LaBella C. Sports specialization in young athletes: evidence-based recommendations. Sports Health. 2013;5(3):251-257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3658407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24427397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi N, Saffel H, Gabbett T. Training the specialised youth athlete: a supportive classification model to keep them playing. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(22):1248-1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi N, Schley S, Cumming SP, et al. Developmental training model for the sport specialized youth athlete: a dynamic strategy for individualizing load-response during maturation. Sports Health. 2022;14(1):142-153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi NA, LaBella CR, Fischer D, Pasulka J, Dugas LR. Sports-specialized intensive training and the risk of injury in young athletes: a clinical case-control study. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(4):794-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi NA, O&#x2019;Boyle J, Durazo-Arvizu RA. Risk factors for medical withdrawals in United States Tennis Association Junior National Tennis Tournaments: a descriptive epidemiologic study. Sports Health. 2009;1(3):231-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson F, Cools A, Gabbett T, Fernandez-Fernandez J, Skillgate E. Association between spikes in external training load and shoulder injuries in competitive adolescent tennis players: the SMASH cohort study. Sports Health. 2022;14(1):103-110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8655479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34693828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson F, Gabbett T, Svedmark P, Skillgate E. External training load and the association with back pain in competitive adolescent tennis players: results from the SMASH cohort study. Sports Health. 2022;14(1):111-118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8655482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34693813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliethermes SA, Nagle K, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; J, et al. Impact of youth sports specialisation on career and task-specific athletic performance: a systematic review following the American Medical Society for Sports Medicine (AMSSM) Collaborative Research Network&#x2019;s 2019 Youth Early Sport Specialisation Summit. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(4):221-230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31740483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaPrade RF, Agel J, Baker J, et al. AOSSM early sport specialization consensus statement. Orthop J Sports Med. 2016;4(4):232596711664424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4853833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27169132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuine TA, Post EG, Hetzel SJ, Brooks MA, Trigsted S, Bell DR. A prospective study on the effect of sport specialization on lower extremity injury rates in high school athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(12):2706-2712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moesch K, Elbe AM, Hauge MLT, Wikman JM. Late specialization: the key to success in centimeters, grams, or seconds (CGS) sports: talent development, CGS sport, specialization. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(6):e282-e290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21401722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosher A, Fraser-Thomas J, Wilson MJ, Baker J. Proportions of early specializers varies according to methods and skill level. Sports. 2022;10(3):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8954525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35324644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Jayanthi N, Difiori JP, et al. Sport specialization, part I: does early sports specialization increase negative outcomes and reduce the opportunity for success in young athletes? Sports Health. 2015;7(5):437-442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4547120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26502420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otis CL, Hainline B, Harwood C, et al. Differences in career longevity before and after implementation of the Women&#x2019;s Tennis Association Tour Age Eligibility Rule and Player Development Programmes: a 25-year study. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(17):955-960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasulka J, Jayanthi N, McCann A, Dugas LR, LaBella C. Specialization patterns across various youth sports and relationship to injury risk. Phys Sportsmed. 2017;45(3):344-352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28351225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel T, Jayanthi N. Health-related quality of life of specialized versus multi-sport young athletes: a qualitative evaluation. J Clin Sport Psychol. 2018;12(3):448-466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popovi&#x107; B, Gu&#x161;i&#x107; M, Radanovi&#x107; D, et al. Evaluation of gross motor coordination and physical fitness in children: comparison between soccer and multisport activities. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(16):5902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7459711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32823890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post EG, Thein-Nissenbaum JM, Stiffler MR, et al. High school sport specialization patterns of current Division I athletes. Sports Health. 2017;9(2):148-153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27807260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post EG, Trigsted SM, Riekena JW, et al. The association of sport specialization and training volume with injury history in youth athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(6):1405-1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puzzitiello RN, Rizzo CF, Garvey KD, Matzkin EG, Salzler MJ. Early sports specialisation and the incidence of lower extremity injuries in youth athletes: current concepts. J ISAKOS. 2021;6(6):339-343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34230066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raedeke T, Smith A. Development and preliminary validation of an athlete burnout measure. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2001;23(4):281-306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28682196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roetert EP, Woods RB, Jayanthi NA. Los beneficios de la participaci&#xf3;n en m&#xfa;ltiples deportes para los tenistas j&#xf3;venes. ITF Coaching Sport Sci Rev. 2018;26(75):19-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa&#xf1;udo B, S&#xe1;nchez-Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Bernardo-Filho M, Abdi E, Taiar R, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez J. Integrative neuromuscular training in young athletes, injury prevention, and performance optimization: a systematic review. Appl Sci. 2019;9(18):3839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider A, Jayanthi N. Parent child dyad health status of specialized tennis players versus multi-sport adolescent tennis players. J Med Sci. 2016;23(1):28-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieghartsleitner R, Zuber C, Zibung M, Conzelmann A. Science or coaches&#x2019; eye? - Both! beneficial collaboration of multidimensional measurements and coach assessments for efficient talent selection in elite youth football. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18(1):32-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30787649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall M, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; J. Developmental activities that lead to dropout and investment in sport. Phys Educ Sport Pedagog. 2007;12(1):77-87.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>