<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41113487</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-9358</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of diabetes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of resistance exercise in type 1 diabetes pediatric patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111337</StartPage><MedlinePgn>111337</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">111337</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4239/wjd.v16.i10.111337</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) is an autoimmune condition whose prevalence is prominent in children and adolescents, resulting in insulin deficiency with a potential for long-term complications induced by glucotoxicity. As an autoimmune disease where the body's immune system attack insulin-producing beta cells in the pancreas, leading up to complete or near-complete inability to control the blood glucose levels independently. The lack of glycemic control calls for lifelong exogenous insulin administration in conjunction with careful monitoring to control blood sugar levels and prevent acute and chronic health issues complications. Regular physical activity, notably resistance exercise (RE), may be beneficial in the glycemic management of this population, enhancement of muscle strength, and general health for the growing, development and maturation in children. The evidence depicting its benefits and safeguard for RE in pediatric T1DM patients remains underexamined. This mini-review seeks to synthesize qualitatively the current evidence on RE regarding its global effects on the T1DM in children. A search for peer-reviewed papers is carried out through primary databases, centering on publications that examined the physiological, metabolic, and psychosocial consequences of RE in children with T1DM. Emerging evidence indicates that RE is one potential method of safe and efficacious intervention to improve glycemic management, physical capacity, and quality of life. However, there is still some reluctance to this type of training in the pediatric population. The available research has not only refuted the belief that strength training was contraindicated in the pediatric population but also recommends its systematic practice to enjoy its benefits on the three spheres of health. Nevertheless, methodological differences and small population studies pose challenges to drawing firm conclusions. The review underscores other areas, including the need for standardizing protocols for including patients such as follow-ups and greater considerations for psychosocial effects of RE in this population. This minireview underlines the importance of RE in a global approach to pediatric diabetes care by providing practical insight for both clinicians and researchers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin-Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Prevention and Health in the Exercise and Sport (PHES), University of Valencia-Spain, Valencia 46010, Comunidad Valenciana, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alarc&#xf3;n-G&#xf3;mez</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, European University of Madrid, Villacanas 28670, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigo-Mallorca</LastName><ForeName>Dar&#xed;o</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Prevention and Health in the Exercise and Sport (PHES), University of Valencia-Spain, Valencia 46010, Comunidad Valenciana, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saez-Berlanga</LastName><ForeName>Angel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Prevention and Health in the Exercise and Sport (PHES), University of Valencia-Spain, Valencia 46010, Comunidad Valenciana, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gargallo</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, University of Valencia, Valencia 46010, Comunidad Valenciana, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chulvi-Medrano</LastName><ForeName>Iv&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Prevention and Health in the Exercise and Sport (PHES), University of Valencia-Spain, Valencia 46010, Comunidad Valenciana, Spain. ivan.chulvi@uv.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Diabetes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101547524</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-9358</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycemic control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 1 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: Dr. Chulvi-Medrano has nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41113487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12531781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v16.i10.111337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Onkamo P, V&#xe4;&#xe4;n&#xe4;nen S, Karvonen M, Tuomilehto J. Worldwide increase in incidence of Type I diabetes--the analysis of the data on published incidence trends. Diabetologia. 1999;42:1395&#x2013;1403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10651256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Diabetes Collaborators. Global, regional, and national burden of diabetes from 1990 to 2021, with projections of prevalence to 2050: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2023;402:203&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10364581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37356446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, Bannuru RR, Brown FM, Bruemmer D, Collins BS, Hilliard ME, Isaacs D, Johnson EL, Kahan S, Khunti K, Leon J, Lyons SK, Perry ML, Prahalad P, Pratley RE, Seley JJ, Stanton RC, Gabbay RA on behalf of the American Diabetes Association. 2. Classification and Diagnosis of Diabetes: Standards of Care in Diabetes-2023. Diabetes Care. 2023;46:S19&#x2013;S40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36507649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimenez-Perez G, Vlacho B, Navas E, Mata-Cases M, Real J, Cos X, Franch-Nadal J, Mauricio D. Comorbid autoimmune diseases and burden of diabetes-related complications in patients with type 1 diabetes from a Mediterranean area. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;191:110031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesketh KD, Wake MA, Cameron FJ. Health-related quality of life and metabolic control in children with type 1 diabetes: a prospective cohort study. Diabetes Care. 2004;27:415&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Sigal RJ, Yardley JE, Riddell MC, Dunstan DW, Dempsey PC, Horton ES, Castorino K, Tate DF. Physical Activity/Exercise and Diabetes: A Position Statement of the American Diabetes Association. Diabetes Care. 2016;39:2065&#x2013;2079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27926890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. 14. Children and Adolescents: Standards of Care in Diabetes-2025. Diabetes Care. 2025;48:S283&#x2013;S305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11635046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39651980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst A, Bachran R, Kapellen T, Holl RW. Effects of regular physical activity on control of glycemia in pediatric patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2006;160:573&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16754817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton KH, Wiltshire EJ, Elley CR. Pedometers and text messaging to increase physical activity: randomized controlled trial of adolescents with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:813&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donat Ergin B, Ergin I, G&#xf6;k&#x15f;en D. Fear of Hypoglycemia and Longer Disease Duration Associated with Physical Activity Avoidance in Children and Adolescents with Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus. J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2023;15:238&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10448549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe4;rnblad S, Ponsot E, Lepr&#xea;tre PM, Kadi F. Acute effects of aerobic continuous, intermittent, and resistance exercise on glycemia in adolescents males with type 1 diabetes. Pediatr Diabetes. 2021;22:610&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33650298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samora M, Grotle AK, Stone AJ. Altered Cardiovascular Responses to Exercise in Type 1 Diabetes. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2023;51:65&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10033421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36722860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco CMF, Gingrich MA, Hawke TJ. Considering Type 1 Diabetes as a Form of Accelerated Muscle Aging. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2019;47:98&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa JS, Oliver SR, Flores RL, Ngo J, Milne GL, Zaldivar FP, Galassetti PR. Altered inflammatory, oxidative, and metabolic responses to exercise in pediatric obesity and type 1 diabetes. Pediatr Diabetes. 2011;12:464&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2945245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21443585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis C, Srivastava PS, Hawke TJ, Kalaitzoglou E. Diabetic Bone Disease and Diabetic Myopathy: Manifestations of the Impaired Muscle-Bone Unit in Type 1 Diabetes. J Diabetes Res. 2022;2022:2650342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9119786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35601019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salem MA, AboElAsrar MA, Elbarbary NS, ElHilaly RA, Refaat YM. Is exercise a therapeutic tool for improvement of cardiovascular risk factors in adolescents with type 1 diabetes mellitus? A randomised controlled trial. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2010;2:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3238209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnock D, Annibalini G, Le Roux CW, Contarelli S, Krause M, Saltarelli R, Valli G, Stocchi V, Barbieri E, De Vito G. Effects of acute aerobic, resistance and combined exercises on 24-h glucose variability and skeletal muscle signalling responses in type 1 diabetics. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120:2677&#x2013;2691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32909059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petschnig R, Wagner T, Robubi A, Baron R. Effect of Strength Training on Glycemic Control and Adiponectin in Diabetic Children. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52:2172&#x2013;2178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32301853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Abreu de Lima V, de Menezes FJ J&#xfa;nior, da Rocha Celli L, Fran&#xe7;a SN, Cordeiro GR, Mascarenhas LPG, Leite N. Effects of resistance training on the glycemic control of people with type 1 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Endocrinol Metab. 2022;66:533&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10697639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35758833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behringer M, Vom Heede A, Matthews M, Mester J. Effects of strength training on motor performance skills in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2011;23:186&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21633132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Garc&#xed;a M, Jago R, Shield JP, Burren CP. How does physical activity and fitness influence glycaemic control in young people with Type 1 diabetes? Diabet Med. 2012;29:e369&#x2013;e376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22803800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalho AC, de Lourdes Lima M, Nunes F, Cambu&#xed; Z, Barbosa C, Andrade A, Viana A, Martins M, Abrantes V, Arag&#xe3;o C, Tem&#xed;stocles M. The effect of resistance versus aerobic training on metabolic control in patients with type-1 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2006;72:271&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16406128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegelaar SE, de Galan BE. Resistance Training: a Strong Case for People With Type 1 Diabetes? J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2023;108:e491&#x2013;e492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36690414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saki H, Nazem F, Fariba F, Sheikhsharbafan R. A High intensity Interval training (running and swimming) and resistance training intervention on heart rate variability and the selected biochemical factors in boys with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2023;204:110915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37742805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinha JB, Ramis TR, Vieira AF, Macedo RCO, Rodrigues-Krause J, Boeno FP, Schroeder HT, M&#xfc;ller CH, Boff W, Krause M, De Bittencourt PIH Jr, Reischak-Oliveira A. Glycemic, inflammatory and oxidative stress responses to different high-intensity training protocols in type 1 diabetes: A randomized clinical trial. J Diabetes Complications. 2018;32:1124&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, Ratamess NA, Kang J, Bush JA, Rial Rebullido T. May the Force Be with Youth: Foundational Strength for Lifelong Development. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2023;22:414&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38055751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell MC, Peters AL. Exercise in adults with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2023;19:98&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36316391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari M, Shabani R, Dalili S. The effect of concurrent resistance-aerobic training on serum cortisol level, anxiety, and quality of life in pediatric type 1 diabetes. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2020;33:599&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adolfsson P, Riddell MC, Taplin CE, Davis EA, Fournier PA, Annan F, Scaramuzza AE, Hasnani D, Hofer SE. ISPAD Clinical Practice Consensus Guidelines 2018: Exercise in children and adolescents with diabetes. Pediatr Diabetes. 2018;19 Suppl 27:205&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30133095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>