<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41780148</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-1600</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>79</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical therapy in sport : official journal of the Association of Chartered Physiotherapists in Sports Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Ther Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of neuromuscular training strategies on injury rates in adolescent males playing sport - a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101904</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101904</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ptsp.2026.101904</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1466-853X(26)00025-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to investigate the effectiveness of neuromuscular training strategies (NMTS) on injury rates in adolescent male athletes. Nineteen databases were searched from inception to August 2025. Randomised controlled trials (RCT) investigating the effectiveness of NMTS (13-18-year-old male athletes) were included. The JBI tool for RCTs was used for critical appraisal. Meta-analyses (inverse statistical method, random effects, 95% confidence interval (CI)) with pooled point estimate of relative risk (RR) was used for data synthesis. Eighteen studies (8480 participants) were included. Multifaceted warm-up NMTS (RR: 0.69 [95% CI: 0.55, 0.87]; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;7521; I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;80%) reduced number of injuries (moderate certainty). Strength training (RR: 0.13 [95% CI: 0.02, 0.83]; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;72; I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0%) reduced incidence (moderate certainty). The effectiveness of eccentric thigh training was inconclusive. Functional Movement Screening training (RR: 0.25 [95% CI: 0.08, 0.82]; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;71) was described narratively and reduced number of injuries after 12 weeks (high certainty). Overall NMTS reduced number of non-contact (RR: 0.47 [95% CI: 0.34, 0.65]; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;883; I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;41%) injuries and severity. Multifaceted warm-up NMTS reduced injury rates. NMTS reduced number of non-contact- and severity of injuries overall. The varying effects and timeframes should be considered when implementing injury prevention strategies. PROSPERO (CRD42022327047).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olivier</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Cricket Research Hub for Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation, Department of Physiotherapy, School of Therapeutic Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Conacher Block (West), Education Campus, St Andrew's Road, Parktown, Johannesburg, 2193, South Africa. Electronic address: fransomari@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olivier</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Cricket Research Hub for Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation, Department of Physiotherapy, School of Therapeutic Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Conacher Block (West), Education Campus, St Andrew's Road, Parktown, Johannesburg, 2193, South Africa; Centre for Healthy Living Research, Oxford Institute of Applied Health Research, Faculty of Health, Science and Technology, Oxford Brookes University, Headington Rd, Headington, Oxford, OX3 0BP, United Kingdom. Electronic address: benita.olivier@brookes.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swart</LastName><ForeName>J J W</ForeName><Initials>JJW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Cricket Research Hub for Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation, Department of Physiotherapy, School of Therapeutic Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Conacher Block (West), Education Campus, St Andrew's Road, Parktown, Johannesburg, 2193, South Africa. Electronic address: jaco@physiopretoria.co.za.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hohlfeld</LastName><ForeName>A S-J</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cochrane South Africa, South African Medical Research Council, Francie van Zijl Drive, Duiker Street, Parow Valley, Cape Town, 7501, South Africa. Electronic address: ameer.hohlfeld@mrc.ac.za.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacMillan</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Pretoria, South Street, Hatfield, Pretoria, Gauteng, 0083, South Africa. Electronic address: candice.macmillan@up.ac.za.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Ther Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100940513</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1466-853X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular injury prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preventive medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Teenage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Youth sport</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest None of the authors and co-authors had any conflict of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41780148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2026.101904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1466-853X(26)00025-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>