<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41466963</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Revolutionizing Pediatric Endodontics: A Two-Decade Narrative on the Evolution, Efficiency, and Future of Pediatric Rotary Systems.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97892</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97892</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97892</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97892</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Preservation of primary teeth plays a vital role in maintaining arch integrity and guiding the eruption of permanent successors. Pulpectomy remains the treatment of choice for retaining non-vital primary teeth; however, traditional manual instrumentation is often time-consuming and technically demanding because of the complex and resorbing root morphology. Over the past decades, the advent of pediatric-specific nickel-titanium (NiTi) rotary systems has revolutionized endodontic practice in children by offering enhanced precision, safety, and efficiency. This narrative review synthesizes the developmental trajectory, design innovations, metallurgical advancements, and clinical performance of rotary file systems specifically designed for primary teeth. The literature, drawn from major databases spanning 2000-2025, highlights the transformation from modified adult files to pediatric-optimized systems, such as Kedo-S (Kedo Dental, Chennai, India), Kedo-SG Blue (Kedo Dental), Pro AF Baby Gold (Dentobizz, Yavatmal, India), and Fanta AF&#x2122; (Fanta Dental Materials, Shanghai, China), which integrate shorter lengths, variable tapers, and heat-treated or nano-coated NiTi alloys. These systems have demonstrated superior canal shaping, reduced instrumentation time, improved obturation quality, and greater patient cooperation than conventional hand files. Advancements in metallurgy, including controlled memory, gold and blue heat treatments, and nanocoating, have markedly improved file flexibility, fatigue resistance, and cutting control. However, challenges regarding technique sensitivity, cost, and training requirements persist. This review underscores the importance of adhering to precise torque and speed parameters, ensuring correct working length determination, and maintaining irrigation safety to avoid procedural mishaps. Emerging trends, such as artificial intelligence (AI)-assisted imaging, nanotechnology-driven coatings, reciprocating motion systems, and 3D-printed simulation training, promise to further refine future pediatric rotary endodontics. Collectively, these innovations represent a shift toward safer, faster, and more predictable pulpectomy outcomes. Rotary instrumentation has evolved from the adaptation of adult techniques to a specialized, evidence-based cornerstone of contemporary pediatric dental care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Singh et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Antra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saha</LastName><ForeName>Sonali</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhinsa</LastName><ForeName>Kavita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Saraswati Dental College and Hospital, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Navit</LastName><ForeName>Saumya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaiswal</LastName><ForeName>Karishma</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalita</LastName><ForeName>Mitusmita</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarkar</LastName><ForeName>Arunima</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Shreya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Sardar Patel Post Graduate Institute of Dental and Medical Sciences, Lucknow, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Seema</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics, Kothiwal Dental College and Research Centre, Moradabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endodontics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">files</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotary</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41466963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12744313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Recommended procedures for managing carious lesions in primary teeth with pulp involvement-a scoping review. Maldupa I, Al-Yaseen W, Giese J, Ahmed Elagami R, Raggio DP. BDJ Open. 2024;10:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11410820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39294126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of clinical and radiographic success of rotary with manual instrumentation techniques in primary teeth: a systematic review. Natchiyar N, Asokan S, Geetha Priya PR, Yogesh Kumar TD. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2021;14:8&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8311778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34326578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing the influence of conventional and rotary instrumentation techniques on the behavior of the children: a randomized clinical trial. Govindaraju L, Subramanian E, Jeevanandan G. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2021;14:0&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35645475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of rotary and manual instrumentation techniques on cleaning capacity and instrumentation time in deciduous molars. Silva LA, Leonardo MR, Nelson-Filho P, Tanomaru JM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15272656/ J Dent Child (Chic) 2004;71:45&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15272656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedo-S paediatric rotary files for root canal preparation in primary teeth-case report. Jeevanandan G. J Clin Diagn Res. 2017;11:0&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5427458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric rotary endodontic files in primary teeth (2000-2025): a scoping review of design, evidence, and clinical use. Swaminathan K, Palanimuthu SK, Rajendran G, et al. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12248261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40656352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative evaluation of instrumentation time and quality of obturation amongst pediatric rotary endodontic system: an in vivo study. Kohli A, Chhabra J, Sharma K, Katyayan R, Bhatnagar P, Sharma A. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2023;16:338&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10373776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37519962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of thermal pretreatments on the cyclic fatigue resistance of novel reciprocating nickel-titanium files: a comparison of low- and high-temperature modified systems. Schoppmeier CM, Sun L, Janson M, Wittich FK, Barbe AG. Eur Endod J. 2025;10:333&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12303124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40705450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thermal behavior and cyclic fatigue resistance of three contemporary NiTi heat-treated single-file systems: metallurgical study. Alsofi L, Al-Marshadi M, AbuHaimed T, Al-Habib M, Saif R, Bukhari S, Howait M. BMC Oral Health. 2025;25:338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11881276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40038622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evolution and development: engine-driven endodontic rotary nickel-titanium instruments. Liang Y, Yue L. Int J Oral Sci. 2022;14:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8857196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35181648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of nickel-titanium rotary files for root canal preparation in primary teeth. Barr ES, Kleier DJ, Barr NV. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10633522/ Pediatr Dent. 1999;21:453&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10633522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of conventional, rotary, and ultrasonic preparation, different final irrigation regimens, and 2 sealers in primary molar root canal therapy. Canoglu H, Tekcicek MU, Cehreli ZC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17249433/ Pediatr Dent. 2006;28:518&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17249433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of the cleaning capacity of Mtwo and Pro Taper rotary systems and manual instruments in primary teeth. Azar MR, Safi L, Nikaein A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22623929/ Dent Res J (Isfahan) 2012;9:146&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22623929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cone-beam computed tomography evaluation of shaping ability of Kedo-S Square and Fanta AF&#x2122; baby rotary files compared to manual K-files in root canal preparation of primary anterior teeth. El-Desouky SS, El Fahl BN, Kabbash IA, Hadwa SM. Clin Oral Investig. 2024;28:340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11130010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38801642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative evaluation of the efficacy of the Pro AF Baby Gold and Kedo-S pediatric endodontic files for canal instrumentation, transportation, and centering ratio-a systematic review and meta-analysis. Shroff Y, Dutta BN, Verma RK, Sharma V. J Indian Soc Pedod Prev Dent. 2024;42:73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38957903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative evaluation of pediatric endodontic rotary file systems to bending and torsion tests: a finite element analysis. Manivannan H, Haridoss S, K C V, Swaminathan K. J Oral Biol Craniofac Res. 2024;14:692&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11470475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39399143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of cyclic fatigue in three pediatric endodontic rotary file systems in root canals of primary molars: a finite element analysis (FEA) Monika Sri SS, Vignesh KC, Vivek K, Swaminathan K, Haridoss S. J Oral Biol Craniofac Res. 2025;15:310&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11870175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40027856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of cyclic fatigue resistance of four pediatric rotary file systems at body temperature: an in vitro study. Surme K, Akman H, &#xd6;zkan HB, Er K. BMC Oral Health. 2024;24:992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11344432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39180032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing quality of obturation and instrumentation time using Kedo-SG blue, Kedo-SH, and reciprocating hand K-files in primary mandibular molars: a double-blinded randomized controlled trial. Sruthi S, Jeevanandan G, Govindaraju L, Subramanian E. Dent Res J (Isfahan) 2021;18:76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8543121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34760067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative evaluation of cleaning efficiency and apical extrusion of debris using two pediatric rotary endodontic files: an in vitro study. Rathi N, Jain SA, Thosar N, Baliga S, Ahmed F, Mehta J. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2021;14:196&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of rotary file system (Kedo-S-Square) in root canal preparation of primary anterior teeth using cone beam computed tomography (CBCT)-in vitro study. Mohamed RH, Abdelrahman AM, Sharaf AA. BMC Oral Health. 2022;22:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8764846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35042489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotary endodontics in primary teeth-a review. George S, Anandaraj S, Issac JS, John SA, Harris A. Saudi Dent J. 2016;28:12&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4688451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison between the rotary (Hyflex EDM&#xae;) and manual (k-file) technique for instrumentation of primary molars: a 12-month randomized clinical follow-up study. Amorim AC, Caldeira AV, Sampaio SC, et al. J Appl Oral Sci. 2022;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35319604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the efficacy of rotary vs. hand files in root canal preparation of primary teeth in vitro using CBCT. Musale PK, Mujawar SA. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2014;15:113&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23893606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revolutionizing pulpectomy: an observational overview of multigenerational Kedo rotary file systems in primary molars. Suresh B, Jeevanandan G, Ravindran V. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39176360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HyFlex EDM: superficial features, metallurgical analysis and fatigue resistance of innovative electro discharge machined NiTi rotary instruments. Pirani C, Iacono F, Generali L, et al. Int Endod J. 2016;49:483&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26011181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frequency of overinstrumentation with an acceptable radiographic working length. ElAyouti A, Weiger R, L&#xf6;st C. J Endod. 2001;27:49&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11487165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fracture of nickel titanium rotary instrument during root canal treatment and re-treatment: a 5-year retrospective study. Alfouzan K, Jamleh A. Int Endod J. 2018;51:157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28796346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Investigation of the effect of low torque and speed values on postoperative pain after root canal treatment: a randomised clinical trial. Karaa&#x11f;a&#xe7; B, Uygun AD. BMC Oral Health. 2025;25:1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12505691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41063114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence in endodontics: a scoping review. Asgary S. Iran Endod J. 2024;19:85&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10988643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38577001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endodontic treatment outcomes in cone beam computed tomography images-assessment of the diagnostic accuracy of AI. Kazimierczak W, Kazimierczak N, Issa J, Wajer R, Wajer A, Kalka S, Serafin Z. J Clin Med. 2024;13:4116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11278304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39064157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surface coating of nickel-titanium (Ni-Ti) pediatric rotary file using graphene oxide: a scanning electron microscopy analysis. Panja K, Victor SA, Vivek N, Ramar K. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11386944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39258062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyclic fatigue resistance of rotary versus reciprocating endodontic files: a systematic review and meta-analysis. De Pedro-Mu&#xf1;oz A, Rico-Romano C, S&#xe1;nchez-Llobet P, Montiel-Company JM, Mena-&#xc1;lvarez J. J Clin Med. 2024;13:882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10856014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Educational use of patient-specific 3D-printed models in dental operative procedures: enhancing clinical training through technology. Shiezadeh F, Moghadasin M, Mastour H. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25:1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12395827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40883688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>