<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41421418</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-2201</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of allergy and clinical immunology. In practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inpatient Penicillin Allergy Evaluation-Skin Testing Versus Direct Oral Challenge?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-2198(25)01182-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaip.2025.12.012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Penicillin allergy labels are common among patients needing antibiotic treatment. They impact personal treatment outcomes and have public health implications, particularly in the inpatient setting where there is high utilization of antibiotics. Mislabeled allergies often lead to the use of alternative and less effective antibiotics that cause more side effects and contribute to antimicrobial resistance. Penicillin allergy evaluation typically involves 2 main approaches, penicillin skin testing or direct oral challenge. The choice between these strategies is largely driven by risk stratification, availability of resources, health care provider education and training, and patient and provider comfort with testing procedures. Penicillin skin testing is the historical criterion standard diagnostic approach for all-risk phenotypes with an excellent safety record, although it requires specialized training and resources. Direct oral challenge is simpler and is noninferior in low-risk patients, yet it may carry increased risk if patient selection is not rigorous. Both approaches share the common goal of safely "delabeling" penicillin allergies to optimize antibiotic prescribing yet differ in process and have their own limitations. Widespread and routine penicillin allergy evaluation in inpatient care is integral for successful antibiotic stewardship. This article presents the pros and cons for penicillin skin testing versus direct oral challenge for penicillin allergy evaluation in the inpatient setting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 American Academy of Allergy, Asthma &amp; Immunology. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDanel</LastName><ForeName>Deanna L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Immunology, University of Iowa Health Care, Iowa City, Iowa; Department of Pharmacy, Division of Immunology, University of Iowa Health Care, Iowa City, Iowa; Department of Pharmacy Practice and Science, University of Iowa College of Pharmacy, Iowa City, Iowa. Electronic address: deanna-mcdanel@uiowa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitri</LastName><ForeName>Elise A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases and Immunology, Centre for Antibiotic Allergy and Research, Austin Health, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia; Department of Infectious Diseases, The Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia; National Allergy Centre of Excellence (NACE), Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>James T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergic Diseases, Department of Medicine, Mayo, Rochester, Minn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brockow</LastName><ForeName>Knut</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy Biederstein, University Hospital rechts der Isar, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597220</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Beta-lactam allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delabeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug challenge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inpatient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Penicillin allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skin testing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41421418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2025.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-2198(25)01182-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>