<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41340150</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-5908</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Implementation science : IS</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Implement Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing qualitative methods in implementation research: a resource for editors, reviewers, authors, and researchers to dispel ten common misperceptions about qualitative research methods.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13012-025-01474-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Qualitative methods are central to implementation research. Qualitative research provides rich contextual insight into lived experiences of health and illness, healthcare systems and care delivery, and complex implementation processes. However, quantitative methods have historically been favored by editors and reviewers who serve as gatekeepers to scientific knowledge. Thus, we underscore that editors and reviewers must be familiar with the underlying principles and strengths of qualitative methods to avoid perpetuating inappropriate evaluation criteria that hinder qualitative research dissemination and funding opportunities. We aim to help authors and researchers&#xa0;provide sufficient details to dispel misperceptions and editors and reviewers to&#xa0;better evaluate studies using qualitative methods to maximize dissemination for high-impact implementation research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We convened a panel of six researchers with extensive experience in: designing, conducting, and reporting on qualitative research in implementation science and other healthcare research; training and mentoring others on qualitative methods; and serving as journal editors and manuscript/grant peer reviewers. We reviewed existing literature, published and unpublished reviewer critiques of qualitative grants and manuscripts, and discussed challenges facing qualitative methodologists when disseminating findings. Over the course of one year, we identified candidate topics, ranked each by priority, and used a consensus-based process to finalize the inventory and develop written guidance for handling each topic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We identified and dispelled 10 common misperceptions that limit the impact of qualitative methods in implementation research. Five misperceptions were associated with the application of inappropriate quantitative evaluation standards (subjectivity, sampling, generalizability, numbers/statistics, interrater reliability). Five misperceptions were associated with overly prescribed qualitative evaluation standards (saturation, member checking, coding, themes, qualitative data analysis software). For each misperception, we provide guidance on key considerations, responses to common critiques, and citations to appropriate literature.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Unaddressed misperceptions can impede the contributions of qualitative methods in implementation research. We offer a resource for editors, reviewers, authors, and researchers to clarify misunderstandings and promote more nuanced and appropriate evaluation of qualitative methods in manuscripts and grant proposals. This article encourages a balanced assessment of the strengths of qualitative methods to enhance understandings of key problems in implementation research, and, ultimately, to strengthen the impact of qualitative findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. This is a U.S. Government work and not under copyright protection in the US; foreign copyright protection may apply.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nevedal</LastName><ForeName>Andrea L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3859-8493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Center for Clinical Management Research (CCMR), VA Ann Arbor Healthcare System, 2215 Fuller Rd, Mail Stop 152, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA. Andrea.Nevedal@va.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kowalski</LastName><ForeName>Christine P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Center for Clinical Management Research (CCMR), VA Ann Arbor Healthcare System, 2215 Fuller Rd, Mail Stop 152, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finley</LastName><ForeName>Erin P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Health Systems Research Center for the Study of Healthcare Innovation, Implementation, and Policy, VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Medicine and Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Long School of Medicine, UT Health San Antonio, San Antonio, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fix</LastName><ForeName>Gemmae M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Optimization and Implementation Research (CHOIR), VA Bedford and Boston Healthcare Systems, Bedford/Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of General Internal Medicine, Boston University Chobanian and Avedisian School of Medicine, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamilton</LastName><ForeName>Alison B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Health Systems Research Center for the Study of Healthcare Innovation, Implementation, and Policy, VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Biobehavioral Sciences, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koenig</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Communication Studies College of Liberal and Creative Arts, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Cultures Lab, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>QIS 22-234</GrantID><Agency>Quality Enhancement Research Initiative</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>QUE 20-028</GrantID><Agency>Quality Enhancement Research Initiative</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PEC-17-002</GrantID><Agency>Quality Enhancement Research Initiative</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>QUE 20-012</GrantID><Agency>Quality Enhancement Research Initiative</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RCS 21-135</GrantID><Agency>Health Services Research and Development</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Implement Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101258411</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-5908</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="Y">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="Y">Research Design</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Implementation Science</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012108" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evaluation standards</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mixed methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rigor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subjectivity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: Dr. Hamilton is on the editorial board of Implementation Science and an associate editor for Implementation Science Communications. Dr. Finley is on the editorial board of Implementation Science Communications.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41340150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12797730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-025-01474-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13012-025-01474-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shuval K, Harker K, Roudsari B, Groce NE, Mills B, Siddiqi Z, et al. Is Qualitative Research Second Class Science? A Quantitative Longitudinal Examination of Qualitative Research in Medical Journals. Gluud LL, editor. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(2):e16937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3044713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21383987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Annandale E, Ashcroft R, Barlow J, Black N, Bleakley A, et al. An open letter to <i>The BMJ</i> editors on qualitative research. BMJ. 2016;10:i563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26865572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luborsky M, Sankar A. Cultural forces in the acceptance of qualitative research: Advancing mixed method research. In: Improving Aging and Public Health Research: Qualitative &amp; Mixed Methods Research. American Public Health Association. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devers K. How will we know &#x201c;good&#x201d; qualitative research when we see it? Beginning the dialogue in health services research. Health Serv Res. 1999;34(5 Pt 2). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1089058/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1089058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10591278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel R, Devers K. Study design in qualitative research&#x2014;1: Developing questions and assessing resource needs. Educ Health. 2000;13(3). Available from: https://journals.lww.com/EDHE/abstract/2000/13020/Study_Design_in_Qualitative_Research_1__Developing.14.aspx.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14742087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofaer S. Qualitative methods: what are they and why use them? Health Serv Res. 1999;34(5 Pt 2). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1089055/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1089055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10591275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacomini M, Giacomini MK, et al. Users&#x2019; guides to the medical literature XXIII. Qualitative research in health care A. Are the results of the study valid?&#x201d; Jama-Journal of the American Medical Association 284(3): 357&#x2013;362. JAMA. 2000;284(3):357&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10891968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi AR, Dobrow MJ. Paucity of qualitative research in general medical and health services and policy research journals: analysis of publication rates. BMC Health Serv Res. 2011;11(1):268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-11-268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21992238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenberg NE, McAuley WJ. Promoting qualitative research. Gerontologist. 2007;47(5):576&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geront/47.5.576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galdas P. Revisiting Bias in Qualitative Research: Reflections on Its Relationship With Funding and Impact. Int J Qual Methods. 2017;16(1):1609406917748992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406917748992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S. Rapid Response: A new dawn for qualitative research in the BMJ. BMJ. 2023; Available from: https://www.bmj.com/content/381/bmj-2022-074256/rr.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Reconceptualizing qualitative evidence. Qual Health Res. 2006;16(3):415&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732305285488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16449690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheard L. Telling a story or reporting the facts? Interpretation and description in the qualitative analysis of applied health research data: a documentary analysis of peer review reports. SSM. 2022;2:100166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel RM, Cottingham AH. Making meaning matter: an editor&#x2019;s perspective on publishing qualitative research. J Gen Intern Med. 2024;39(2):301&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-023-08361-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10853113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. How do you solve a problem like COREQ? A critique of Tong et al.&#x2019;s (2007) consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research. Methods Psychol. 2024;11:100155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metip.2024.100155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse J. Verification strategies for establishing reliability and validity in qualitative research. Int J Qual Methods. 2002;1(2):13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/160940690200100202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton A, Fix G, Finley E. Pragmatic Healthcare Ethnography: A Guide to Studying and Improving Healthcare. Routledge Press; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer MS, Damschroder L, Hagedorn H, Smith J, Kilbourne AM. An introduction to implementation science for the non-specialist. BMC Psychol. 2015;3(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-015-0089-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4573926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26376626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen D, Crabtree B, Damschroder L, Hamilton A, Heurtin-Roberts S, Leeman J, et al. Qualitative Methods in Implementation Science. NIH National Cancer Institute. Division of Cancer Control &amp; Population Sciences; 2015. Available from: https://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/sites/default/files/2020-09/nci-dccps-implementationscience-whitepaper.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapport F, Storey M, Porter A, Snooks H, Jones K, Peconi J, et al. Qualitative research within trials: developing a standard operating procedure for a clinical trials unit. Trials. 2013;14(1):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-14-54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3599333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Cathain A, Hoddinott P, Lewin S, Thomas KJ, Young B, Adamson J, et al. Maximising the impact of qualitative research in feasibility studies for randomised controlled trials: guidance for researchers. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2015;1(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40814-015-0026-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5154038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forman J, Creswell JW, Damschroder L, Kowalski CP, Krein SL. Qualitative research methods: key features and insights gained from use in infection prevention research. Am J Infect Control. 2008;36(10):764&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2008.03.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18834752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultes MT, Aijaz M, Klug J, Fixsen DL. Competences for implementation science: what trainees need to learn and where they learn it. Adv Health Sci Educ Theory Pract. 2021;26(1):19&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10459-020-09969-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32372393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagaman A, Rhodes EC, Aloe CF, Hennein R, Peng ML, Deyling M, et al. How are qualitative methods used in implementation science research? Results from a systematic scoping review. Implement Res Pract. 2025;6:26334895251367470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26334895251367470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12394868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40894413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton AB, Finley EP. Reprint of: Qualitative methods in implementation research: an introduction. Psychiatry Res. 2020;283:112629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.112629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31735374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reardon CM, Damschroder LJ, Ashcraft LE, Kerins C, Bachrach RL, Nevedal AL, et al. The Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR) User Guide: a five-step guide for conducting implementation research using the framework. Implement Sci. 2025;20(1):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-025-01450-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12357348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40819067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Critical analysis of strategies for determining rigor in qualitative inquiry. Qual Health Res. 2015;25(9):1212&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315588501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26184336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varpio L, Ajjawi R, Monrouxe LV, O&#x2019;Brien BC, Rees CE. Shedding the cobra effect: problematising thematic emergence, triangulation, saturation and member checking. Med Educ. 2017;51(1):40&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.13124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27981658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton G. Reflective practice: Writing and professional development. 2nd ed. SAGE Publications, Inc.; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating C, Robinson T, Clemson B. Reflective inquiry: a method for organizational learning. Learn Organ. 1996;3(4):35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/09696479610126699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HS. Critical reflective inquiry for knowledge development in nursing practice. J Adv Nurs. 1999;29(5):1205&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2648.1999.01005.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10320505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann-Longtin K, Kerr AM, Shaunfield S, Koenig CJ, Bylund CL, Clayton MF. Fostering Interdisciplinary Boundary Spanning in Health Communication: A Call for a Paradigm Shift. Health Commun. 2022;37(5):568&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10410236.2020.1857517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silberzahn R, Uhlmann EL, Martin DP, Anselmi P, Aust F, Awtrey E, et al. Many analysts, one data set: making transparent how variations in analytic choices affect results. Adv Methods Pract Psychol Sci. 2018;1(3):337&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2515245917747646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay L. Qualitative Research: the &#x201c;good,&#x201d; the &#x201c;bad,&#x201d; the &#x201c;ugly.&#x201d; Eur J Qual Res Psychother. 2024;14:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drapeau M. Subjectivity in research: Why not&#x202f;? But&#x2026;. Qual Rep. 2015 Jan 27. Available from: https://nsuworks.nova.edu/tqr/vol7/iss3/3/. Cited 28 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln SY, Guba EG. Naturalistic inquiry. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski CP, Nevedal AL, Finley EP, Young JP, Lewinski AA, Midboe AM, et al. Planning for and Assessing Rigor in Rapid Qualitative Analysis (PARRQA): a consensus-based framework for designing, conducting, and reporting. Implement Sci. 2024;19(1):71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-024-01397-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11468362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39394597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy SJ. Qualitative Quality: Eight &#x201c;Big-Tent&#x201d; Criteria for Excellent Qualitative Research. Qual Inquiry. 2010;16(10):837&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077800410383121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rendle KA, Abramson CM, Garrett SB, Halley MC, Dohan D. Beyond exploratory: a tailored framework for designing and assessing qualitative health research. BMJ Open. 2019;9(8):e030123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-030123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007;19(6):349&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JL, Adkins D, Chauvin S. A review of the quality indicators of rigor in qualitative research. Am J Pharm Educ. 2020;84(1):7120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5688/ajpe7120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7055404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy SJ. Practicing Qualitative Research Under the &#x201c;Big Tent&#x201d;: Origins, Development, and Continuing Relevance of the Eight Big-Tent Framework for Qualitative Quality. Qual Inq. 2025;8:10778004251348168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10778004251348167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennink M, Kaiser BN. Sample sizes for saturation in qualitative research: a systematic review of empirical tests. Soc Sci Med. 2022;292:114523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.114523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malterud K, Siersma VD, Guassora AD. Sample size in qualitative interview studies: guided by information power. Qual Health Res. 2016;26(13):1753&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315617444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tight M. Saturation: an overworked and misunderstood concept? Qual Inquiry. 2024;30(7):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10778004231183948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Reporting guidelines for qualitative research: A values-based approach. Qual Res Psychol 22.2. 2025:399&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Focus on qualitative methods. Sample size in qualitative research. Res Nurs Health. 1995;18:179&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7899572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guetterman T. Descriptions of Sampling Practices Within Five Approaches to Qualitative Research in Education and the Health Sciences. Forum Qual Soc Res. 2015;16(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luborsky MR, Rubinstein RL. Sampling in qualitative research: rationale, issues, and methods. Res Aging. 1995;17(1):89&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0164027595171005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3207270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22058580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest G, Bunce A, Johnson L. How many interviews are enough? An experiment with data saturation and variability. Field Methods. 2006;18(1):59&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1525822X05279903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest G, Namey E, McKenna K. How many focus groups are enough? Building an evidence base for nonprobability sample sizes. Field Methods. 2017;29(1):3&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1525822X16639015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small ML. How many cases do I need?: on science and the logic of case selection in field-based research. Ethnography. 2009;10(1):5&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1466138108099586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palinkas LA, Horwitz SM, Green CA, Wisdom JP, Duan N, Hoagwood K. Purposeful sampling for qualitative data collection and analysis in mixed method implementation research. Adm Policy Ment Health. 2015;42(5):533&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10488-013-0528-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4012002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24193818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Determining Sample Size. Qual Health Res. 2000;10(1):3&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104973200129118183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith B. Generalizability in qualitative research: misunderstandings, opportunities and recommendations for the sport and exercise sciences. Qual Res Sport Exerc Health. 2018;10(1):137&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2017.1393221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw S, Hoeber L. Unclipping our wings: Ways forward in qualitative research in sport management. Sport Manag Rev. 2016;19(3):255&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smr.2016.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guba EG. Criteria for assessing the trustworthiness of naturalistic inquiries. ECTJ. 1981;29(2):75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02766777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elo S, K&#xe4;&#xe4;ri&#xe4;inen M, Kanste O, P&#xf6;lkki T, Utriainen K, Kyng&#xe4;s H. Qualitative Content Analysis: A Focus on Trustworthiness. SAGE Open. 2014;4(1):2158244014522633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2158244014522633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Taylor R. How to read a paper: Papers that go beyond numbers (qualitative research). BMJ. 1997;315(7110):740&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7110.740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9314762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Qualitative generalizability. Qual Health Res. 1999;9(1):5&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104973299129121622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalmeijer RE, Brown MEL, O&#x2019;Brien BC. How to discuss transferability of qualitative research in health professions education. Clin Teach. 2024;18:e13762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tct.13762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38497107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen P. Making sense of implementation theories, models and frameworks. Implement Sci. 2015;10(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-015-0242-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4406164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25895742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills T, Lawton R, Sheard L. Advancing complexity science in healthcare research: the logic of logic models. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19(1):55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0701-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ. Clarity out of chaos: use of theory in implementation research. Psychiatry Res. 2020;283:112461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.06.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31257020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Reardon CM, Widerquist MAO, Lowery J. The updated Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research based on user feedback. Implement Sci. 2022;17(1):75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-022-01245-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9617234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36309746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow RE, Harden SM, Gaglio B, Rabin B, Smith ML, Porter GC, et al. RE-AIM Planning and Evaluation Framework: Adapting to New Science and Practice With a 20-Year Review. Front Public Health. 2019;29(7):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2019.00064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30984733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell JA. Using numbers in qualitative research. Qual Inquiry. 2010;16(6):475&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077800410364740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah DR, Lautsch BA. Counting in qualitative research: why to conduct it, when to avoid it, and when to closet it. J Manage Inq. 2011;20(1):14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1056492610375988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Real qualitative researchers do not count: the use of numbers in qualitative research. Res Nurs Health. 2001;24(3):230&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nur.1025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11526621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski CP, Kawentel LM, Kyriakides TC, Davis L, Bowersox NW, Kilbourne AM, et al. Facilitating future implementation and translation to clinical practice: the implementation planning assessment tool for clinical trials. J Clin Transl Sci. 2022;6(1):e131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2022.467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9794955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36590355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton AB, Finley EP. Qualitative methods in implementation research: an introduction. Psychiatry Res. 2019;280:112516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.112516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7023962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31437661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rattray NA, Miech EJ, True G, Natividad D, Laws B, Frankel RM, et al. Modeling contingency in veteran community reintegration: a mixed methods approach. J Mixed Methods Res. 2023;17(1):70&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15586898211059616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36523449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Miech EJ, Freitag MB, Evans R, Burns JA, Raffa SD, et al. Facility-level program components leading to population impact: a coincidence analysis of obesity treatment options within the Veterans Health Administration. Transl Behav Med. 2022;12(11):1029&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/ibac051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36408955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miech EJ, Freitag MB, Evans RR, Burns JA, Wiitala WL, Annis A, et al. Facility-level conditions leading to higher reach: a configurational analysis of national VA weight management programming. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-06774-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh ML. Interrater reliability: the kappa statistic. Biochem Med. 2012;22(3):276&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11613/BM.2012.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23092060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krippendorff K. On the reliability of unitizing continuous data. Sociol Methodol. 1995;25:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/271061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Perfectly healthy, but dead&#x201d;: the myth of inter-rater reliability. Qual Health Res. 1997;7(4):445&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104973239700700401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts K, Dowell A, Nie JB. Attempting rigour and replicability in thematic analysis of qualitative research data; a case study of codebook development. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19(1):66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0707-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Phan M, Zimmer A, Coury N, Morey B, Montiel Hernandez G, et al. Practical qualitative data analysis for public health research: a guide to a team-based approach with flexible coding. Int J Qual Methods. 2024;23:16094069241289279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069241289279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12021444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40276488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hruschka DJ, Schwartz D, St.John DC, Picone-Decaro E, Jenkins RA, Carey JW. Reliability in coding open-ended data: lessons learned from HIV behavioral research. Field Methods. 2004;16(3):307&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1525822X04266540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevedal AL, Reardon CM, Opra Widerquist MA, Jackson GL, Cutrona SL, White BS, et al. Rapid versus traditional qualitative analysis using the Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR). Implement Sci. 2021;16(1):67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-021-01111-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8252308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumer H. Symbolic interactionism: Perspective and method. University of California Press; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevedal AL, Ayalon L, Briller SH. A Qualitative Evidence Synthesis Review of Longitudinal Qualitative Research in Gerontology. Heyn PC, editor. The Gerontologist. 2019;59(6):e791&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevedal AL, Widerquist MAO, Reardon CM, Arasim M, Jackson GL, White B, et al. Understanding pathways from implementation to sustainment: a longitudinal, mixed methods analysis of promising practices implemented in the Veterans Health Administration. Implement Sci. 2024;19(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-024-01361-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11075255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38715094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salda&#xf1;a J. The coding manual for qualitative researchers. Sage; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacQueen KM, McLellan E, Kay K, Milstein B. Codebook development for team-based qualitative analysis. CAM J. 1998;10(2):31&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1525822X980100020301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser S, Straus A. The discovery of grounded theory: strategies for qualitative research. Mill Valley, CA: Sociology Press; 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Sim J, Kingstone T, Baker S, Waterfield J, Bartlam B, et al. Saturation in qualitative research: exploring its conceptualization and operationalization. Qual Quant. 2018;52(4):1893&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11135-017-0574-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Data were saturated &#x2026;. Qual Health Res. 2015;25(5):587&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315576699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25829508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaDonna KA, Artino AR, Balmer DF. Beyond the guise of saturation: rigor and qualitative interview data. J Grad Med Educ. 2021;13(5):607&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4300/JGME-D-21-00752.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8527935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34721785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey I. Grounding Grounded Theory. San Francisco, CA: Academic Press; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motulsky SL. Is member checking the gold standard of quality in qualitative research? Qual Psychol. 2021;8(3):389&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/qup0000215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell JW, Miller DL. Determining validity in qualitative inquiry. Theory Into Pract. 2000;39(3):124&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15430421tip3903_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon-Woods M. The problem of appraising qualitative research. Qual Saf Health Care. 2004;13(3):223&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/qshc.2003.008714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1743851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15175495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qualitative Research Guidelines Project. Robert Wood Johnson Foundation. Member Checks. Available from: http://www.qualres.org/HomeMemb-3696.html. Cited 15 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallet R. Dangers of Member Checking. In: The role of participants: Ethics, epistemologies and methods. New York, NY: Routledge Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Rigor or rigor mortis: the problem of rigor in qualitative research revisited. Adv Nurs Sci. 1993;16(2):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00012272-199312000-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8311428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candela A. Exploring the Function of Member Checking. Qual Rep. 2019 Mar 24. Available from: https://nsuworks.nova.edu/tqr/vol24/iss3/14/. Cited 27 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay L. Negotiating the swamp: the opportunity and challenge of reflexivity in research practice. Qual Res. 2002;2(2):209&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/146879410200200205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finley EP, Huynh AK, Farmer MM, Bean-Mayberry B, Moin T, Oishi SM, et al. Periodic reflections: a method of guided discussions for documenting implementation phenomena. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-018-0610-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6258449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmaz K. The power of constructivist grounded theory for critical inquiry. Qual Inquiry. 2017;23(1):34&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077800416657105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin J, Strauss A. Basics of Qualitative Research (3rd ed.): Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory [Internet]. 2455 Teller Road,&#xa0;Thousand Oaks&#xa0;California&#xa0;91320&#xa0;United States: SAGE Publications, Inc.; 2008. Available from: https://methods.sagepub.com/book/basics-of-qualitative-research. Cited 15 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. Qualitative Inquiry and Research Design: Choosing Among Five Approaches. 2nd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day M, Jamison T, Ganong L. The utility of participatory family diagramming in qualitative research: multidisciplinary applications and practical advice. J Ethnogr Qual Res. 2023;17(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill JB. Matrix analysis as a complementary analytic strategy in qualitative inquiry. Qual Health Res. 2002;12(6):855&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104973230201200611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12109729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maietta R, Mihas P, Swartout K, Petruzzelli J, Hamilton A. Sort and Sift, Think and Shift: Let the Data Be Your Guide An Applied Approach to Working With, Learning From, and Privileging Qualitative Data. Qual Rep. 2021 Jun 20. Available from: https://nsuworks.nova.edu/tqr/vol26/iss6/20/. Cited 20 Jun 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse J. Why the <i>qualitative health research</i> (QHR) review process does not use checklists. Qual Health Res. 2021;31(5):819&#x2013;21.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732321994114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33733936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale RC, Wu J, Erhardt T, Bounthavong M, Reardon CM, Damschroder LJ, et al. Comparison of rapid vs in-depth qualitative analytic methods from a process evaluation of academic detailing in the Veterans Health Administration. Implement Sci. 2019;14(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-019-0853-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30709368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor B, Henshall C, Kenyon S, Litchfield I, Greenfield S. Can rapid approaches to qualitative analysis deliver timely, valid findings to clinical leaders? A mixed methods study comparing rapid and thematic analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8(10):e019993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-019993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6194404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30297341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen DJ, Crabtree BF. Evaluative Criteria for Qualitative Research in Health Care: Controversies and Recommendations. Ann Fam Med. 2008;6(4):331&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2478498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luborsky MR. The identification and analysis of themes and patterns. In J. F. Gubrium &amp; A. Sankar (Eds.), Qualitative methods in aging research. Sage Publications, Inc.&#xa0;1994.&#xa0;pp. 189&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransom JC. The new criticism. 1948:682&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldick C. Theme. In: The Oxford Dictionary of Literary Terms. Fourth edition. Oxford, United Kingdom&#x202f;; New York, NY: Oxford University Press; 2015. p. 333. (Oxford quick reference).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Can I use TA? Should I use TA? Should I <i>not</i> use TA? Comparing reflexive thematic analysis and other pattern-based qualitative analytic approaches. Couns Psychother Res. 2021;21(1):37&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/capr.12360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh HF, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15(9):1277&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732305276687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaismoradi M, Turunen H, Bondas T. Content analysis and thematic analysis: implications for conducting a qualitative descriptive study. Nurs Health Sci. 2013;15(3):398&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nhs.12048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23480423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. What&#x2019;s in a name? Qualitative description revisited Res Nurs Health. 2010;33(1):77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20014004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Whatever happened to qualitative description? Res Nurs Health. 2000;23(4):334&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1098-240X(200008)23:4&lt;334::AID-NUR9&gt;3.0.CO;2-G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10940958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lofland J, Snow D, Anderson L, Lofland L. Analyzing social settings: A guide to qualitative observation and analysis. Waveland Press; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NVIVO [Internet]. Lumivero; 2023. Available from: www.lumivero.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAXQDA 2022 [computer software]. [Internet]. Berlin, Germany: VERBI Software; 2021. Available from: maxqda.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATLAS.ti Scientific Software. GmBH; 2023. Available from: atlas.ti.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher C, Hadfield M, Hutchings M, De Eyto A. Ensuring Rigor in Qualitative Data Analysis: A Design Research Approach to Coding Combining NVivo With Traditional Material Methods. Int J Qual Methods. 2018;17(1):1609406918786362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406918786362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DL. Exploring the use of artificial intelligence for qualitative data analysis: the case of ChatGPT. Int J Qual Methods. 2023;22:16094069231211248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069231211248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jowsey T, Braun V, Clarke V, Lupton D, Fine M. We reject the use of generative artificial intelligence for reflexive qualitative research. 2025. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=5676462. http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5676462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.5676462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>