<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41401165</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of rice variety and grain form on the development and infestation of Sitophilus oryzae (L.): A comparative analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0338131</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0338131</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0338131</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0338131</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post harvest&#xa0;losses caused by the rice weevil (Sitophilus oryzae L.) pose a severe threat to food security and farmer income in Ethiopia. While both rice variety and grain processing form (paddy, brown, polished) influence susceptibility, their interaction in locally adapted Ethiopian varieties remains unquantified, limiting the development of effective resistance-based storage strategies. A controlled laboratory study was conducted using a three-factor factorial experiment in a completely randomized design (CRD) with seven replicates per treatment (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;7), totaling 126 experimental units. Six Ethiopian rice varieties (Nerica-4, Gumara, Selam, Shaga, Wanzaye, and X-Jigna) were tested across three grain forms. Each replicate consisted of 50 g of grain infested with 20 unsexed adult weevils. Key parameters measured were development time, F&#x2081; progeny emergence (as a measure of fecundity), percentage grain damage, weight loss, and the Dobie Susceptibility Index (DI).Grain form was the dominant factor affecting weevil performance. Polished rice significantly accelerated development (mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;29.86 days) and increased progeny production (mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;40.38 adults) and grain damage (21.83%) compared with brown rice (29.81 progeny, 6.79-13.86% damage) and paddy rice (23.29 progeny, 8.29-16.00% damage). This represents up to a 42.3% reduction in progeny emergence and a 69.9% reduction in grain damage when storing brown rather than polished rice. A significant variety&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;grain form interaction (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) revealed that polished Gumara and X-Jigna were the most susceptible combinations, while brown and paddy Nerica-4 showed the strongest resistance. The Dobie Index was strongly positively correlated with progeny count (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.859, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and negatively correlated with development time (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.912, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), supporting its validity as a resistance metric. Grain width showed a weak but significant negative correlation with weight loss (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.227, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.011). The high susceptibility of polished rice and the strong resistance of Nerica-4 provide a clear strategy for loss reduction. Promoting the storage of paddy or brown rice of resistant varieties like Nerica-4 can significantly mitigate postharvest losses, reduce pesticide reliance, and enhance food security in Ethiopia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Geteneh Mitku Chekol. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chekol</LastName><ForeName>Geteneh Mitku</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3751-8930</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Institute of Agricultural Research (EIAR), Fogera National Rice Research and Training Center, Woreta, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000727890">Sitophilus oryzae</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012275" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oryza</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weevils</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Edible Grain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010935" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plant Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41401165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12707640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0338131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-45374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nascimento V do, Soares J&#xfa;nior MS, Caliari M, Gomes R da R, de Almeida Barros R. Quality of raw and parboiled rice from different production systems in the state of Goi&#xe1;s, Brazil. Pesqui Agropecu Trop. 2015;45:56&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demont M, Ndour M. Upgrading rice value chains: Experimental evidence from 11 African markets. Global Food Security. 2015;5:70&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.gfs.2014.10.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gfs.2014.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollens E. Rice in Africa: Can rice production keep up with population growth? In: FAO Rice Conference 2006 [Internet]. 2006. Available: http://www.fao.org/3/ag088e/ag088e00.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belayneh Y, Tekle A. Review on the role of rice (Oryza sativa L.) in food security in Ethiopia. J Nutr Food Sci. 2017;7:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu D, Thompson J, Assaye A. Rice Commercialisation, Agrarian Change and Livelihood Trajectories: Transformations on the Fogera Plain of Ethiopia. APRA Working Paper 061. Future Agricultures Consortium; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho MO, Passos AM, Mexia A. Insect fauna associated with stored rice in Portugal. In: Proceedings of the 9th International Working Conference on Stored Product Protection. 2004. p. 15&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires EM, Faroni LRDA, Guedes RNC, Miranda MPS. Insect fauna associated with stored grains in Minas Gerais, Brazil. Rev Bras Entomol. 2008;52:621&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waktole S. Rice weevil, Sitophilus oryzae (Coleoptera: Curculionidae): A devastating storage pest in Ethiopia. J Agric Sci Technol. 2012;A2:122&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha RN. The stored-grain ecosystem. In: Sinha RN, Muir WE, editors. Grain Storage: Part of a System. Westport, CT: AVI Publishing Company; 1984. p. 39&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pad&#xed;n S, Dal Bello G, Fabrizio M. Grain loss caused by Tribolium castaneum, Sitophilus oryzae and Acanthoscelides obtectus in stored durum wheat and beans treated with Beauveria bassiana. Journal of Stored Products Research. 2002;38(1):69&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/s0022-474x(00)00046-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-474x(00)00046-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwosu LC, Adedire CO, Ogunwolu EO. Screening for sources of resistance in some Nigerian rice genotypes against Sitophilus oryzae (L.)(Coleoptera: Curculionidae). J Crop Prot. 2020;9:57&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrashekar P, Goud KG. Effect of processing on insect infestation in stored paddy. J Entomol Res. 2010;34:53&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohapatra D, Kumar S, Kotwaliwale N, Singh KK. Critical factors responsible for fungi growth in stored food grains and non-chemical approaches for their control. Ind Food Packer. 2019;71:64&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adetunji JF, Olakojo SA. Effect of processing forms on the infestation of Sitophilus zeamais Motschulsky (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) in three maize varieties. J Stored Prod Postharvest Res. 2013;4:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhusal B, Poudel S, Kharel K, Shrestha J. A review on the mechanism of resistance in rice against insect pests. Grassroots J Nat Resour. 2022;5:112&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinovi&#x107; I, Mari&#x107; I, Martini&#x107; A, Lali&#x107; A, Rozman V. Influence of different rice forms on the development of rice weevil (Sitophilus oryzae L.). J Cent Eur Agric. 2021;22:302&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midega CAO, Pittchar JO, Pickett JA, Hailu GW, Khan ZR. A climate-adapted push-pull system effectively controls fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda (J E Smith), in maize in East Africa. Crop Protection. 2018;105:10&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.cropro.2017.11.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cropro.2017.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain F, Bhuiyan MSR, Nessa B, Hossain MM, Khan MA. Effect of husking and milling on the infestation of Sitophilus oryzae L. in stored rice. J Bangladesh Agric Univ. 2014;12:149&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chekol GM. Understanding the factors behind non-adherence to pesticide safety guidelines among smallholder farmers in Fogera and MEcha districts, northwestern Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes. 2025;18(1):177. doi: 10.1186/s13104-025-07217-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-025-07217-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12004810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40241208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse B, Tadele T. Cause, Magnitude and Management of Post-Harvest Loss Impact in Food Security of Ethiopia- A Review. Food Science and Quality Management. 2022;116:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.7176/fsqm/116-01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7176/fsqm/116-01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CABI. <i>Sitophilus oryzae</i> (rice weevil). In: Invasive Species Compendium [Internet]. Wallingford, UK: CAB International; 2018. Available: https://www.cabi.org/isc/datasheet/50199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur FH, Bautista RC, Bockholt AJ, Cato AJ, Pearlson MN, Phillips TW. Susceptibility of U.S. rice varieties to stored-product insects. J Stored Prod Res. 2013;55:90&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd S. The potential for varietal resistance to reduce postharvest losses from Sitophilus oryzae in Ethiopian rice. Ethiopian Institute of Agricultural Research Annual Review. Addis Ababa. 2021. p. 45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields PG. The control of stored-product insects and mites with extreme temperatures. Journal of Stored Products Research. 1992;28(2):89&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1016/0022-474x(92)90018-l</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-474x(92)90018-l</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead DG. External sex differences in stored-products Coleoptera. Bull Entomol Res. 1963;54:119&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haryadi Y. The development of Sitophilus zeamais Motsch. on grain of five corn varieties. Ilmu Pertan. 1991;7(4):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobie P. The laboratory assessment of the inherent susceptibility of maize varieties to post-harvest infestation by Sitophilus zeamais Motsch. (Coleoptera, Curculionidae). Journal of Stored Products Research. 1974;10(3&#x2013;4):183&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/0022-474x(74)90006-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-474x(74)90006-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wambugu PW, Mathenge PW, Auma EO, van Rheenen HA. Efficacy of traditional maize (Zea mays L.) seed storage methods in western Kenya. Afr J Food Agric Nutr Dev. 2009;9(6):1510&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams JM, Schulten GGM. Losses caused by insects, mites and micro-organisms. In: Harris KL, Lindblad CJ, editors. Postharvest grain loss assessment methods. New York: American Association of Cereal Chemists; 1978. p. 83&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AOAC. Official Methods of Analysis. 18th ed. Gaithersburg, MD: Association of Official Analytical Chemists; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafique M, Chaudhry MA. Resistance of stored grain wheat varieties to stored product insects. Pak J Agric Sci. 2007;44:173&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe F, Tefera T, Mugo S, Beyene Y, Vidal S. Resistance of maize varieties to the maize weevil Sitophilus zeamais (Motsch.) (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). Afr J Biotechnol. 2009;8:5937&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geteneh A, Yewhalaw D, Sori W. Evaluation of some maize genotypes for resistance to the maize weevil, Sitophilus zeamais Motsch. (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). Afr Entomol. 2019;27:69&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogburn RR. Domestic rice varieties: apparent resistance to rice weevils, Sitophilus oryzae. J Econ Entomol. 1974;67:375&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogburn RR, Russell MP. Medfly: Effect of hull condition on resistance of rice to the rice weevil. J Econ Entomol. 1977;70:811&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliano BO. Rice grain properties and resistance to storage insects: a review. IRRI Res Pap Ser. 1981;58:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas E, Riudavets J. Predation of Sitophilus oryzae (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) by Xylocoris flavipes (Hemiptera: Anthocoridae) in different rice processing facilities. J Stored Prod Res. 2000;36:295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hettiarachchi L, Jahan M, Ganguli R. Influence of grain form and type on the susceptibility of rice to stored product insects. J Stored Prod Res. 2020;89:101725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Throne JE, Baker JE, Messina FJ, Kramer KJ, Howard JA. Varietal resistance. In: Subramanyam B, Hagstrum DW, editors. Alternatives to Pesticides in Stored-Product IPM. Boston, MA: Springer US; 2000. p. 165&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajao AM, Adebiyi AO, Oluwadare PO. Resistance of some Nigerian rice varieties to the rice weevil, Sitophilus oryzae (L.) (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). J Crop Prot. 2020;9:195&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavallieratos NG, Athanassiou CG, Vayias BJ, Tomanovi&#x107; &#x17d;. Insecticidal effect of kaolin against three stored-product beetle species on wheat and maize. J Econ Entomol. 2012;105:1008&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen E, Russell MP. Some biochemical and physical factors affecting oviposition by Sitophilus oryzae in rice grains. J Ga Entomol Soc. 1970;5:25&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ofuya TI, Credland PF. Responses of three populations of the seed beetle, Callosobruchus maculatus (F.) (Coleoptera: Bruchidae), to seed resistance in selected varieties of cowpea, Vigna unguiculata (L.) Walp. Journal of Stored Products Research. 1995;31(1):17&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/0022-474x(95)91807-d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-474x(95)91807-d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGaughey WH, Speirs RD, Martin CR. Susceptibility of classes of wheat grown in the United States to stored-grain insects. J Econ Entomol. 1990;83:1122&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro BM, Guedes RNC, Oliveira EE, Santos JP. Insecticidal resistance and resource allocation in Sitophilus zeamais (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). J Econ Entomol. 2012;105:386&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontes DG, Faroni LRD, Pimentel MAG, Sousa AH. Heritability of resistance in maize to the maize weevil (Sitophilus zeamais Motsch.). Rev Bras Milho Sorgo. 2003;2:35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowda D, Shivanna B, Mahadevaswamy M, Pradeep S. Physical and biochemical basis of resistance in sorghum genotypes against the rice weevil, Sitophilus oryzae (L.). J Entomol Zool Stud. 2019;7:682&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link D, Carvalho RP, Waquil JM. Effect of husk fissuring on the resistance of maize to the maize weevil. J Econ Entomol. 1971;64:1544&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haryadi Y, Fleurat-Lessard F. A comparative study of the resistance of paddy and milled rice to the rice weevil Sitophilus oryzae L. (Coleoptera: Curculionidae). In: Highley E, Wright EJ, Banks HJ, Champ BR, editors. Stored Product Protection. Wallingford: CAB International. 1994. p. 882&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>