<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41501867</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of different types of exercise in fibromyalgia syndrome: a network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>66</StartPage><MedlinePgn>66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">66</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01432-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients with fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS) often exhibit poor health and reduced physical function. Exercise interventions can effectively alleviate symptoms and improve function. This study aims to systematically evaluate and compare the efficacy of different exercise interventions on the key clinical outcomes to identify the most effective modality and inform evidence-based exercise recommendations for patients with FMS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study conducted a systematic search of four databases: PubMed, Embase, the Cochrane Library, and Web of Science. The primary outcome measures included health status, pain intensity, the number of tender points (TP), and aerobic capacity. Stata 15.0 and R software were used for network meta-analysis (NMA), and the effect size and its 95% confidence interval were calculated using a random-effects model. The methodological quality of the included studies was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2.0 tool and the TESTEX scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Stretching combined with balance training resulted in the greatest improvement in health status (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;25.13; 95% CI [-&#x2009;33.81, -&#x2009;16.44]). For other symptom-related outcomes, aerobic exercise (AE) combined with strength and stretching showed the highest probability of alleviating pain intensity (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;3.61; 95% CI [-&#x2009;4.40, -&#x2009;2.82]). AE alone was most effective in reducing the number of tender points (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;2.28; 95% CI [-&#x2009;3.57, -&#x2009;1.00]), while whole-body vibration (WBV) produced the largest enhancement in aerobic capacity (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;55.0; 95% CI [26.14, 83.75]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Stretching combined with balance training was found to be most effective in improving health status. AE combined with strength training and stretching demonstrated the greatest efficacy in reducing pain intensity, while AE was most effective in decreasing the number of tender points. WBV appeared to provide the largest improvement in aerobic capacity in patients with FMS. These findings suggest that healthcare providers should combine AE, strength, stretching, balance, WBV, and other exercises based on the individual circumstances of patients with FMS, while further high-quality RCTs are warranted to confirm these results and to standardize exercise protocols.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">CRD420251036473.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Wushu and Chinese Traditional Sports, Tianjin University of Sport, No. 16 Donghai Road, West District of Tuanbo New Town, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of P.E, Qilu LU Normal University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wan</LastName><ForeName>Pengfei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine, Qilu Hospital of Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Party School of the CPC Shandong Provincial Committee, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suo</LastName><ForeName>MingZhu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Wushu and Chinese Traditional Sports, Tianjin University of Sport, No. 16 Donghai Road, West District of Tuanbo New Town, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Pingping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Wushu and Chinese Traditional Sports, Tianjin University of Sport, No. 16 Donghai Road, West District of Tuanbo New Town, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China. wushuchina@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health status</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41501867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01432-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01432-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Srivastava S, et al. Global mapping of physical activity promotion strategies in Fibromyalgia- A comprehensive methodological scoping review protocol. MethodsX. 2025;14:103234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mex.2025.103234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11925516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40115965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivi&#xf1;o Mart&#xed;nez &#xc1;, Solano Ruiz MC, Siles J, Gonz&#xe1;lez. La Cronicidad de La fibromialgia: Una revisi&#xf3;n de La literatura. Enfermer&#xed;a Global. 2014;13(35):273&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsaid NY. Understanding fibromyalgia: A comprehensive review of the literature. Egypt Rheumatologist. 2025;47(2):90&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejr.2025.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavillon G, Maguin P. The 10th revision of the international classification of diseases. Rev Epidemiol Sante Publique. 1993;41(3):253&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8316695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunus MB. Fibromyalgia and overlapping disorders: the unifying concept of central sensitivity syndromes. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2007;36(6):339&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2006.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17350675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benlidayi IC. Role of inflammation in the pathogenesis and treatment of fibromyalgia. Rheumatol Int. 2019;39(5):781&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-019-04251-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30756137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Lavin M. Fibromyalgia and small fiber neuropathy: the plot thickens! Clin Rheumatol. 2018;37(12):3167&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-018-4300-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30238382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor-Mira M-a et al. Motivational determinants of objective physical activity in women with fibromyalgia who attended rehabilitation settings. J Clin Med, 2021;10(23):5547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8658437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34884246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F et al. Fibromyalgia diagnosis and biased assessment: Sex, prevalence and bias. PLoS ONE, 2018;13(9):e0203755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6136749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30212526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasulova K et al. Mitochondrial MiRNAs and fibromyalgia: new biomarker candidates. Mol Biol Rep. 2025;52(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39589649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee LK, et al. Humanistic and economic burden of fibromyalgia in Japan (9, Pg 967, 2016). J Pain Res. 2016;9:p1161&#x2013;1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JPR.S127280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5104297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27853390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giorgi V, et al. Pharmacological treatment of fibromyalgia syndrome: A Practice-Based review. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2024;28(12):1349&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11916-024-01277-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11666752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39042299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Climent-Sanz C, et al. Fibromyalgia pain management effectiveness from the patient perspective: a qualitative evidence synthesis. Disabil Rehabil. 2024;46(20):4595&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2023.2280057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11093884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacasse A, Bourgault P, Choiniere M. Fibromyalgia-related costs and loss of productivity: a substantial societal burden. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2016;17(1):168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couto N et al. Effect of different types of exercise in adult subjects with fibromyalgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised clinical trials. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):10391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9209512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35725780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casanova-Rodriguez D et al. Aerobic exercise prescription for pain reduction in fibromyalgia: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Eur J Pain. 2025;29(2):e4783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11730678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39805734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao S, et al. Effects of traditional Chinese martial arts and stretching exercises on symptoms of fibromyalgia: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Percept Mot Skills. 2024;131(6):2244&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00315125241291080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39451074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J-J, et al. Effect of resistance exercises on function and pain in fibromyalgia. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2024;103(4):275&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37535560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correyero-Leon M, et al. Effectiveness of aquatic training based on aerobic and strengthening exercises in patients with fibromyalgia: systematic review with meta-analysis. Explore-the J Sci Healing. 2024;20(1):27&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37460329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Luo H. Effects of traditional Chinese exercise therapy on pain scores, sleep quality, and anxiety-depression symptoms in fibromyalgia patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10821260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38281020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Han B, Wu C. On the superiority of a combination of aerobic and resistance exercise for fibromyalgia syndrome: A network meta-analysis. Front Psychol. 2022;13:949256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36248603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu G et al. Effects of exercise dosage on the treatment of fibromyalgia: A meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Musculoskelet Care. 2024;22(3)e1918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39004771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M D H. The Effects of Pool-Based Aerobic Exercise Versus Land-Based Aerobic Exercise on Pain for Adults with Fibromyalgia: A Meta-Analysis. California State University, Fresno, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Dom&#xed;nguez &#xc1;. The most effective therapeutic exercises for pain intensity in women with fibromyalgia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Braz J Phys Ther. 2025;29(4):101226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2025.101226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12099910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40319533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network Meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-2385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowans SE, et al. Effect of a randomized, controlled trial of exercise on mood and physical function in individuals with fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 2001;45(6):519&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1529-0131(200112)45:6&lt;519::AID-ART377&gt;3.0.CO;2-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11762686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones KD, et al. A randomized controlled trial of muscle strengthening versus flexibility training in fibromyalgia. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(5):1041&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12022321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King SJ, et al. The effects of exercise and education, individually or combined, in women with fibromyalgia. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(12):2620&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12465163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards SC, Scott DL. <i>Prescribed exercise in people with fibromyalgia: parallel group randomised controlled trial.</i> BMJ (Clinical research ed.), 2002. 325(7357): p. 185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC117444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12142304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schachter CL, et al. Effects of short versus long bouts of aerobic exercise in sedentary women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2003;83(4):340&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.4.340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valim V, et al. Aerobic fitness effects in fibromyalgia. J Rheumatol. 2003;30(5):1060&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altan L, et al. Investigation of the effects of pool-based exercise on fibromyalgia syndrome. Rheumatol Int. 2004;24(5):272&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-003-0371-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14508601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sencan S, et al. A study to compare the therapeutic efficacy of aerobic exercise and Paroxetine in fibromyalgia syndrome. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2004;17(2):57&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-2004-17204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungu&#xed;a-Izquierdo D, Legaz-Arrese A. Exercise in warm water decreases pain and improves cognitive function in middle-aged women with fibromyalgia. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2007;25(6):823&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18173915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooks DS, et al. Group exercise, education, and combination self-management in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized trial. Arch Intern Med. 2007;167(20):2192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.167.20.2192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17998491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomas-Carus P, et al. The fibromyalgia treatment with physical exercise in warm water reduces the impact of the disease on female patients&#x2019; physical and mental health. Reumatologia Clin. 2007;3(1):33&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1699-258X(07)73596-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21794393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomas-Carus P, et al. Aquatic training and detraining on fitness and quality of life in fibromyalgia. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(7):1044&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0b0138059aec4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bircan C, et al. Effects of muscle strengthening versus aerobic exercise program in fibromyalgia. Rheumatol Int. 2008;28(6):527&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-007-0484-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17982749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones KD, et al. A six-month randomized controlled trial of exercise and pyridostigmine in the treatment of fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58(2):612&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.23203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2542941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18240245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungu&#xed;a-Izquierdo D, Legaz-Arrese A. Assessment of the effects of aquatic therapy on global symptomatology in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89(12):2250&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2008.03.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altan L, et al. Effect of pilates training on people with fibromyalgia syndrome: a pilot study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2009;90(12):1983&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2009.06.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19969158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia M, et al. Effects of 2 physiotherapy programs on pain perception, muscular flexibility, and illness impact in women with fibromyalgia: a pilot study. J Manip Physiol Ther. 2009;32(1):84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmpt.2008.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19121466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson JW, et al. A pilot randomized controlled trial of the yoga of awareness program in the management of fibromyalgia. Pain. 2010;151(2):530&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pain.2010.08.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20946990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, et al. A randomized trial of Tai Chi for fibromyalgia. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(8):743&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0912611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20818876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Effects of a prolonged exercise program on key health outcomes in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Rehabil Med. 2011;43(6):521&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-0814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista AS, et al. Effectiveness of dance in patients with fibromyalgia: a randomized, single-blind, controlled study. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2012;30(6 Suppl 74):18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23020850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;nez AM, De Paz JA, M&#xe1;rquez S. Effects of an exercise programme on self-esteem, self-concept and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Rheumatol Int. 2012;32(7):1869&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-011-1892-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21442171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooten MW, et al. Effects of strength vs aerobic exercise on pain severity in adults with fibromyalgia: a randomized equivalence trial. Pain. 2012;153(4):915&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pain.2012.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones KD, et al. A randomized controlled trial of 8-form Tai Chi improves symptoms and functional mobility in fibromyalgia patients. Clin Rheumatol. 2012;31(8):1205&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-012-1996-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5571653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22581278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Rodr&#xed;guez MM, et al. <i>Comparison between aquatic-biodanza and stretching for improving quality of life and pain in patients with fibromyalgia.</i> Atencion primaria /, vol. 44. Sociedad Espanola de Medicina de Familia y Comunitaria; 2012. p. 641&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7025635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22591551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Effects of exercise training and detraining in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: a 3-yr longitudinal study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2012;91(7):561&#x2013;9. quiz 570&#x2010;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e31824faa03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22469880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk-Hustings Y, et al. Challenges in demonstrating the effectiveness of multidisciplinary treatment on quality of life, participation and health care utilisation in patients with fibromyalgia: a randomised controlled trial. Clin Rheumatol. 2013;32(2):199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-012-2100-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavi MB, et al. Strengthening exercises improve symptoms and quality of life but do not change autonomic modulation in fibromyalgia: a randomized clinical trial. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(3):e90767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0090767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24651512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc A, et al. Does aerobic exercise affect the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal hormonal response in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome? J Phys Therapy Sci. 2015;27(7):2225&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.27.2225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26311959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibar S, et al. New approach in fibromyalgia exercise program: A preliminary study regarding the effectiveness of balance training. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;96(9):1576&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2015.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson A, et al. Resistance exercise improves muscle strength, health status and pain intensity in fibromyalgia&#x2013;a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Res Therapy. 2015;17(1):161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-015-0679-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericsson A, et al. Resistance exercise improves physical fatigue in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Res Therapy. 2016;18:176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-016-1073-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddali Bongi S, et al. Efficacy of rehabilitation with Tai Ji Quan in an Italian cohort of patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2016;24:109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2016.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolucci T, et al. A new rehabilitation tool in fibromyalgia: the effects of perceptive rehabilitation on pain and function in a clinical randomized controlled trial. Evidence-based Complement Altern Medicine: eCAM. 2016;2016:p7574589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/7574589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26884794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collado-Mateo D, et al. Exergames for women with fibromyalgia: a randomised controlled trial to evaluate the effects on mobility skills, balance and fear of falling. PeerJ. 2017;5(4):e3211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.3211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5401622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28439471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekici G, et al. Effects of active/passive interventions on pain, anxiety, and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia: randomized controlled pilot trial. Women Health. 2017;57(1):88&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03630242.2016.1153017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26882533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assump&#xe7;&#xe3;o A, et al. Muscle stretching exercises and resistance training in fibromyalgia: which is better? A three-arm randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54(5):663&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.17.04876-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29185675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernberg M, et al. Plasma cytokine levels in fibromyalgia and their response to 15 weeks of progressive resistance exercise or relaxation therapy. Mediat Inflamm. 2018;2018:p3985154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/3985154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29849487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Sieczkowska SM, Vilarino GT. Resistance training improves quality of life and associated factors in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. PM R: J Injury Function Rehabilitation. 2019;11(7):703&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2018.09.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade CP, et al. Effects of aquatic training and detraining on women with fibromyalgia: controlled randomized clinical trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2019;55(1):79&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.18.05041-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes G, et al. A functional exercise program improves pain and health related quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2019;71:350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39449056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao J, et al. Ba-Duan-Jin alleviates pain and fibromyalgia-related symptoms in patients with fibromyalgia: results of a randomised controlled trial. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2019;37(6):953&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva HJA, et al. Sophrology versus resistance training for treatment of women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2019;23(2):382&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2018.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villafaina S, et al. Benefits of 24-Week exergame intervention on Health-Related quality of life and pain in women with fibromyalgia: A Single-Blind, randomized controlled trial. Games Health J. 2019;8(6):380&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/g4h.2019.0023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31259617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan T, Karavelio&#x11f;lu Y. Effectiveness of High-Intensity interval training vs Moderate-Intensity continuous training in patients with fibromyalgia: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;101(11):1865&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2020.05.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho MS, et al. Effects of exergames in women with fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled study. Games Health J. 2020;9(5):358&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/g4h.2019.0108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Alventosa R et al. Low-Intensity physical exercise improves pain catastrophizing and other psychological and physical aspects in women with fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(10):3634 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7277480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento CVM, et al. The therapeutic efficacy of qigong exercise on the main symptoms of fibromyalgia: a pilot randomized clinical trial. Integr Med Res. 2020;9(4):100416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imr.2020.100416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauch Valma&#xf1;a G, et al. Effects of a physical exercise program on patients affected with fibromyalgia. J Prim Care Community Health. 2020;11:2150132720965071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2150132720965071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33084477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villafaina S, et al. Effects of exergames on heart rate variability of women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):5168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-61617-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7083950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido-Ardila EM et al. Effects of physiotherapy vs. Acupuncture in quality of life, pain, stiffness, difficulty to work and depression of women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2021;10(17):3765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernando-Garijo I et al. Immediate effects of a telerehabilitation program based on aerobic exercise in women with fibromyalgia. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(4):2075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33672691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Alventosa R et al. Effectiveness of High-Frequency transcranial magnetic stimulation and physical exercise in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2021;101(10):159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HK, et al. Comparison of core muscle strengthening exercise and stretching exercise in middle-aged women with fibromyalgia: A randomized, single-blind, controlled study. Med (Baltim). 2021;100(50):e27854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000027854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34918634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patru S et al. Influence of multidisciplinary therapeutic approach on fibromyalgia patients. Experimental Therapeutic Med. 2021;21(5):528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro VGC et al. <i>Efficacy of Whole-Body Vibration Training on Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor, Clinical and Functional Outcomes, and Quality of Life in Women with Fibromyalgia Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</i> Journal of Healthcare Engineering, 2021. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8654532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34900203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arroyo-Fern&#xe1;ndez R, et al. Effectiveness of transcranial direct current stimulation combined with exercising in people with fibromyalgia: A randomized Sham-Controlled clinical trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103(8):1524&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2022.02.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35331718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lorena SB, et al. Effects of a physical self-care support program for patients with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2022;35(3):495&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-191820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolak E, Ard&#x131;&#xe7; F, F&#x131;nd&#x131;ko&#x11f;lu G. Effects of different types of exercises on pain, quality of life, depression, and body composition in women with fibromyalgia: A three-arm, parallel-group, randomized trial. Archives of rheumatology. 2022;37(3):444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada-Marc&#xe9;n NC et al. Can an aerobic exercise programme improve the response of the growth hormone in fibromyalgia patients? A randomised controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(3):2261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9915310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36767626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Mansilla J et al. Effects of an exercise for Well-Being and physical training programme on muscle Strength, range of Movement, respiratory capacity and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2023;12(3):774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9918138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36769424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavuz H, et al. A Comparison of the effects of balance- proprioception and aerobic exercises on functional status, Pain, and balance in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome- a randomized controlled study. J Istanbul Fac Medicine-Istanbul Tip Fakultesi Dergisi. 2023;86(4):368&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes G, et al. A functional exercise program improves pain and health related quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Adv Rheumatol (London England). 2024;64(1):p81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42358-024-00422-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39449056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze NBB, et al. The effect of myofascial release of the physiological chains on the pain and health status in patients with fibromyalgia, compared to passive muscle stretching and a control group: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Disabil Rehabil. 2024;46(16):3629&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2023.2255130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37698013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Mansilla J, Mej&#xed;as-Gil A, Garrido-Ardila EM, et al. Effects of non-pharmacological treatment on pain, flexibility, balance and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia: a randomised clinical trial. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2021;10(17):3826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson A, et al. Resistance exercise improves muscle strength, health status and pain intensity in fibromyalgia-a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy. 2015;17(1):161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidonde J et al. Aerobic exercise training for adults with fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst Reviews, 1996;2017(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6481524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28636204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Martinez F et al. Exercise-based interventions on sleep quality in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: an umbrella and mapping review with meta-analysis. Semin Arthritis Rheum, 2023 ; 61:152216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37229847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stove MP, et al. The effectiveness of stretching exercises in patients with fibromyalgia: A systematic review. Clin Rheumatol. 2024;43(10):3039&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-024-07066-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39107536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa BO et al. Effects of a telehealth stretching exercise program on Pain, Sleep, Depression, and functionality of women with fibromyalgia during the COVID-19 pandemic: A randomized clinical trial. Sustainability, 2023 ;15(3):2604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, et al. Chronic effects of stretching on range of motion with consideration of potential moderating variables: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(2):186&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2023.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stove MP et al. The effect of six-week regular stretching exercises on regional and distant pain sensitivity: an experimental longitudinal study on healthy adults. Bmc Sports Sci Med Rehabilitation, 2024 ; 16(1):202 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11437648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39334218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stove MP, Hirata RP, Palsson TS. Regional and widespread pain sensitivity decreases following stretching in both men and women - Indications of stretch-induced hypoalgesia. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2024;39:32&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38876646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tompra N, van Dieen JH, Coppieters MW. Central pain processing is altered in people with Achilles tendinopathy. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(16):1004&#x2013;U79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete DS, et al. Association between balance Disorders, fibromyalgia Severity, and balance confidence: an observational study on fibromyalgia. Rev Med Chil. 2024;152(7):776&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39760547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevgin O et al. <i>Efficacy of different exercises in women with fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomised controlled trial.</i> Clinical and experimental rheumatology, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39946182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolak E, Ardic F, Findikoglu G. Effects of different types of exercises on pain, quality of life, depression, and body composition in women with fibromyalgia: A three-arm, parallel-group, randomized trial. Archives Rheumatol. 2022;37(3):444&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46497/ArchRheumatol.2022.9190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H-K et al. Comparison of core muscle strengthening exercise and stretching exercise in middle-aged women with fibromyalgia: A randomized, single-blind, controlled study. Medicine, 2021;100(50): e27854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34918634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidonde J et al. Mixed exercise training for adults with fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst Reviews, 1996; 2019(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6931522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31124142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsutani LA, et al. Effectiveness of muscle stretching exercises with and without laser therapy at tender points for patients with fibromyalgia. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2007;25(3):410&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17631737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H et al. Effects of traditional Chinese exercises in fibromyalgia syndrome: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Complement Ther Med, 2024. 80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38211633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angel Garcia D, Martinez Nicolas I, Saturno Hernandez PJ. Clinical approach to fibromyalgia: synthesis of Evidence-based recommendations, a systematic review. Reumatologia Clin. 2016;12(2):65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mingorance JA, et al. The therapeutic effects of Whole-Body vibration in patients with Fibromyalgia. A randomized controlled trial. Frontiers in Neurology; 2021. p. 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34149596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos JM et al. Whole-Body vibration training on oxidative stress Markers, Irisin Levels, and body composition in women with fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled trial. Bioengineering-Basel, 2023 ; 10(2):260 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9952264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36829754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanudo B, et al. The effect of a 6-week exercise programme and whole body vibration on strength and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia: a randomised study. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2010;28(6):S40&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21122265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanudo B, et al. Effect of Whole-Body vibration exercise on balance in women with fibromyalgia syndrome: A randomized controlled trial. J Altern Complement Med. 2012;18(2):158&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2010.0881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22321155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adsuar JC, et al. Whole body vibration improves the single-leg stance static balance in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2012;52(1):85&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22327091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, et al. Incidencia Del ejercicio f&#xed;sico y El Entrenamiento vibratorio sobre La amplitud de movimiento de mujeres Con fibromialgia. Revista Andaluza De Med Del Deporte. 2013;6(2):52&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1888-7546(13)70035-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>