<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41833712</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2949-8759</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>186</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of substance use and addiction treatment</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Subst Use Addict Treat</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perspectives from opioid treatment program staff on community pharmacy-based methadone dispensing in North Carolina.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>209942</StartPage><MedlinePgn>209942</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.josat.2026.209942</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2949-8759(26)00062-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Methadone is an effective medication for the treatment of opioid use disorder, yet barriers to treatment access exist. Community pharmacies are more accessible than opioid treatment programs (OTPs) and are utilized in countries other than the United States to observe methadone dosing and dispense take-home doses. The purpose of this study was to assess North Carolina OTP staff perceptions towards community pharmacy-based methadone dispensing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional online survey was used to assess the perceived acceptability, appropriateness, and feasibility of community pharmacy-based methadone dispensing among OTP staff using validated measures. Survey distribution occurred from April to June 2025. Descriptive statistics were used to identify potential benefits, negative consequences, and barriers to pharmacy-based methadone dispensing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The response rate was 72.7% (56 of 77). Perceived acceptability, appropriateness, and feasibility of observed dosing and dispensing methadone take-home doses in the community pharmacy were low among OTP staff. Perceived negative consequences of pharmacy-based methadone dispensing were loss of counseling and care coordination provided by the OTP. Lack of community pharmacist training on methadone dispensing and community pharmacist stigma were the greatest perceived barriers to pharmacy-based dispensing. Over 25% of respondents did not think there were any potential benefits to pharmacy-based methadone dispensing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">OTP staff in North Carolina are, in general, not supportive of pharmacy-based methadone dispensing. With low perceived appropriateness, acceptability, and feasibility of observed methadone dosing and dispensing methadone take-home doses in the community pharmacy, further work to implement pharmacy-based methadone dispensing may be stifled by OTP resistance. If policy-based efforts to increase methadone access through community pharmacies continue to be pursued, researchers and other key informants should seek to mitigate concerns identified by OTP staff to ensure people with OUD can receive high quality, patient-centered care in the pharmacy setting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shubel</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Eshelman School of Pharmacy, 1 University Heights, CPO 2125, Asheville, NC, 28804, United States of America. Electronic address: cms0329@live.unc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marley</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNC Eshelman School of Pharmacy, 301 Pharmacy Ln, Chapel Hill, NC, 27599, United States of America; South East Area Health Education Center, 2511 Delaney Ave, Wilmington, NC, 28403. Electronic address: grace_trull@unc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostrach</LastName><ForeName>Bayla</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNC Eshelman School of Pharmacy, 301 Pharmacy Ln, Chapel Hill, NC, 27599, United States of America; Fruit of Labor Action Research &amp; Technical Assistance, LLC, 625 S. Main St., Marshall, NC, 28753, United States of America. Electronic address: hrresearchappalachia@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carpenter</LastName><ForeName>Delesha</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Eshelman School of Pharmacy, 1 University Heights, CPO 2125, Asheville, NC, 28804, United States of America. Electronic address: dmcarpenter@unc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Subst Use Addict Treat</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918541186406676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2949-8759</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community Pharmacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services Accessibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Methadone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Opioid Use Disorder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41833712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.josat.2026.209942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2949-8759(26)00062-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>