<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41433133</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1466-187X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical teacher</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Teach</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating One Health in human medical curricula: A scoping review of pedagogical strategies and challenges.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>22</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/0142159X.2025.2604244</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Following the COVID-19 pandemic, there has been renewed global attention on One Health (OH) as a framework to address the numerous global health challenges. Despite its growing recognition, the integration of OH into medical education has been limited. Many institutions are still unclear on the best approach to introduce and deliver OH within their academic programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To map the pedagogical strategies, implementation experiences, and challenges in integrating OH into medical curricula.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A scoping review was conducted in accordance with PRISMA-ScR guidelines. PubMed and Scopus databases were searched for peer-reviewed studies published between January 2015 and December 2024. Data were charted using a standardized extraction form and synthesized descriptively through thematic content analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 14 articles were found from institutions across North America, Africa, and Europe, representing initiatives ranging from integrated modules and stand-alone courses to extracurricular activities. Many utilized interactive, interdisciplinary pedagogies such as problem-based learning, simulations, capstone projects, and community outreach programs. The expected competencies ranged from interdisciplinary collaboration to recognizing human-animal-environment interconnectedness to applying OH principles in identifying and managing health conditions. Content areas extended beyond zoonotic diseases and environmental health to include broader aspects of health systems and health policy development. All the initiatives emphasized on fostering collaborative competencies and broadening students' perspectives on health. However, implementation was challenged by institutional constraints such as curriculum overload, limited faculty expertise, and logistical barriers to interdisciplinary teaching. Many institutions encountered epistemological resistance and reluctance to move beyond reductionist, human-centric paradigms, which was a likely factor in students finding it difficult to relate OH concepts to their medical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The review highlights the importance of faculty capacity building, early introduction of systems thinking, and alignment of clinical training with OH principles to ensure a more sustainable integration of OH in medical education.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gunawardena</LastName><ForeName>Sameera A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9562-0533</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Pharmacology, School of Medicine, IMU University, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandraratne</LastName><ForeName>Amalka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Health, Sri Lanka.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jayasekara</LastName><ForeName>Thilinie Inoka</ForeName><Initials>TI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Med Teach</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7909593</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0142-159X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Teaching One Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">curriculum integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interdisciplinary education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systems thinking</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41433133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2025.2604244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>