<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41554510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-4245</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Homeopathy : the journal of the Faculty of Homeopathy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Homeopathy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Under-recognized Role and Potential Benefits of Homeopathy in Companion and Production Animals.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2710-1913</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In Brazil, veterinary homeopathic practice is regulated by the Federal Council of Veterinary Medicine, yet it is the domain mainly of specialized professionals and those aware of its therapeutic benefits. In small animal practice, homeopathy is commonly used for chronic conditions including behavioral disorders, autoimmune diseases and dermatopathies. In livestock, herd-level application has been linked to improved zootechnical indices, nutritional quality, large-scale productivity, animal welfare, and support in controlling metabolic and inflammatory diseases. Despite reported benefits, the consolidation of veterinary homeopathy encounters substantial challenges. The scarcity of controlled clinical studies, the lack of standardized therapeutic protocols, and the limited knowledge of many professionals contribute to skepticism regarding its effectiveness. Moreover, homeopathy is often superficially addressed, or absent, in veterinary college curricula, reinforcing resistance among clinicians and perpetuating misconceptions. Nevertheless, increasing demand for alternative therapies, particularly those based on natural products, has stimulated greater interest among animal owners. Strengthening veterinary homeopathy in Brazil and elsewhere requires rigorous scientific validation, academic training, and dissemination through events and congresses by institutions. These actions are essential to demonstrate its potential contributions, ensuring complementary use alongside conventional veterinary medicine and broader acceptance among professionals and owners.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Faculty of Homeopathy. This article is published by Thieme.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Felipe Gaia de</ForeName><Initials>FG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5078-7820</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Clinic and Surgery, Veterinary School, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santos</LastName><ForeName>Fernanda Marcelo Dos</ForeName><Initials>FMD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Homeopet-Grupo Real H, Campo Grande, Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezende</LastName><ForeName>Patr&#xed;cia Martins de</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Homeopet-Grupo Real H, Campo Grande, Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mendes</LastName><ForeName>Ana Cristina Ribeiro</ForeName><Initials>ACR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beier</LastName><ForeName>Suzane Lilian</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Clinic and Surgery, Veterinary School, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Homeopathy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101140517</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-4916</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41554510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2710-1913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>