<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41267367</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-079X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>77</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pineal research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pineal Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exogenous Melatonin Enhances the Cold Resistance of Pepper (Capsicum annuum L. var. cerasiforme Bailey) by Promoting the Synthesis of Long-Chain Alkanes in the Epicuticular Wax.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70097</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70097</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jpi.70097</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pepper (Capsicum annuum L. var. cerasiforme Bailey) is highly sensitive to low temperatures, limiting its cultivation in cooler regions. While melatonin (MT) is known to enhance plant cold tolerance through antioxidant and hormonal pathways, its role in modulating cuticular wax composition remains unclear. In this study, we demonstrate that exogenous MT application significantly improves cold resistance in pepper seedlings by upregulating the biosynthesis of long-chain alkanes in epicuticular wax. Physiological assessments revealed that MT treatment (100&#x2009;&#x3bc;M) increased photosynthetic rate (P<sub>n</sub>) by 65.66%, enhanced antioxidant enzyme activities (CAT, POD, SOD), and reduced malondialdehyde (MDA) content by 20.88% after 8&#x2009;h at 4&#xb0;C. Transcriptomic and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) analyses identified two key alkane biosynthesis genes, CaCER1-like and CaCER1-like1. The expression of CaCER1-like was specifically induced by exogenous melatonin, while CaCER1-like1 was primarily upregulated by low-temperature stress. This coordinated transcriptional activation enhanced the accumulation of C27, C29, and C31 alkanes. Beyond cold-induced alkane biosynthesis, melatonin treatment provided a further 25.5% increase in total alkane content (MT8 vs. CK8), with a marked 27.5% rise in the critical C31 alkane. These compounds constituted over 57.7% of the wax. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) imaging further showed that MT-induced wax crystallization shifted from lamellar to aggregated structures, with a reduction in epidermal gaps, suggesting a potential reduction in nonstomatal water loss. These findings reveal a novel mechanism by which melatonin enhances cold tolerance via wax modification, providing a potential strategy for improving pepper cultivation in cold climates.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Bingjie</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0230-8290</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ruixin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Minghui</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hengjia</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Kunyang</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Shandong Agricultural University, Taian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Tengfei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Collaborative Innovation Center of Modern Biological Breeding, Henan Institute of Science and Technology, Xinxiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Shangjing</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Qingdao Agricultural University, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ling</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Kexin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Biology, Liaocheng University, Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Qin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Guanfeng Seed Industry Technology Co. Ltd., Liaocheng, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tobacco Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>This work was financially supported by the Scientific Research Foundation for High-level Talented Scholars of Liaocheng Universtiy (No. 318042401), the Natural Science Foundation of Shandong Province (No. ZR2024MC190), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (No. 52269008), the Open Project of Liaocheng Universtiy Landscape Architecture Discipline (319462212), and the Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program for College Students (CXCY2023263).</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Pineal Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8504412</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0742-3098</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>JL5DK93RCL</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008550">Melatonin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000473">Alkanes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014885">Waxes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Capsicum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Melatonin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alkanes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014885" MajorTopicYN="Y">Waxes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003080" MajorTopicYN="N">Cold Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018506" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation, Plant</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Capsicum annuum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cold stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epicuticular wax</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exogenous melatonin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;chain alkanes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41267367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpi.70097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, Z. Zhang, Y. Ai, et al., &#x201c;CaAOS as a Hub Gene Based on Physiological and Transcriptomic Analyses of Cold&#x2010;Resistant and Cold&#x2010;Sensitive Pepper Cultivars,&#x201d; International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 276 (2024): 133961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, L. Zhu, D. Wang, et al., &#x201c;Molecular Regulatory Mechanism of Exogenous Hydrogen Sulfide in Alleviating Low&#x2010;Temperature Stress in Pepper Seedlings,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 24, no. 22 (2023): 16337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Li, K. Pu, D. Ding, et al., &#x201c;Foliar Spraying of Glycine Betaine Alleviated Growth Inhibition, Photoinhibition, and Oxidative Stress in Pepper (Capsicum annuum L.) Seedlings Under Low Temperatures Combined With Low Light,&#x201d; Plants 12, no. 13 (2023): 2563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Jiang, Z. Yang, H. Zhang, J. Xu, and C. Li, &#x201c;Effect of Low Temperature on Photosynthetic Physiological Activity of Different Photoperiod Types of Strawberry Seedlings and Stress Diagnosis,&#x201d; Agronomy 13, no. 5 (2023): 1321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Z. Yu, L. B. Zhaxi, Z. G. Deqing, et al., &#x201c;Advances in Plant Response to Low&#x2010;Temperature Stress,&#x201d; Plant Growth Regulation 105, no. 1 (2025): 167&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. M. Gyalai, L. Helyes, H. G. Daood, F. Kov&#xe1;cs, A. Szarvas, and F. Lantos, &#x201c;Genetic and Seasonal Factors Influence Pungent Pepper Capsaicinoid and Vitamin C Content,&#x201d; Horticulturae 11, no. 3 (2025): 286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, J. M. Xie, J. H. Yu, et al., &#x201c;Transcriptome Sequence and Physiological Analysis Revealed the Roles of Carotenoids and Photosynthesis Under Low Temperature Combined With Low&#x2010;Light Stress on Pepper (Capsicum annuum L.),&#x201d; Photosynthetica 59, no. 1 (2021): 24&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Altaf, Y. Hao, H. Shu, et al., &#x201c;Melatonin Mitigates Cold&#x2010;Induced Damage to Pepper Seedlings by Promoting Redox Homeostasis and Regulating Antioxidant Profiling,&#x201d; Horticultural Plant Journal 10, no. 2 (2024): 532&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. V. Venzhik and I. E. Moshkov, &#x201c;The Role of Ultrastructural Organization of Cells in Adaptation of Winter Wheat to Low Temperature,&#x201d; Russian Journal of Plant Physiology 70, no. 5 (2023): 100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fang, X. Hou, and X. Liang, &#x201c;Response Mechanisms of Plants Under Saline&#x2010;Alkali Stress,&#x201d; Frontiers in Plant Science 12 (2021): 667458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ul Hassan, T. Rasool, C. Iqbal, et al., &#x201c;Linking Plants Functioning to Adaptive Responses Under Heat Stress Conditions: A Mechanistic Review,&#x201d; Journal of Plant Growth Regulation 41, no. 7 (2022): 2596&#x2013;2613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Nawrath, &#x201c;Unraveling the Complex Network of Cuticular Structure and Function,&#x201d; Current Opinion in Plant Biology 9, no. 3 (2006): 281&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Xue, X. Zhang, X. Lu, G. Chen, and Z. H. Chen, &#x201c;Molecular and Evolutionary Mechanisms of Cuticular Wax for Plant Drought Tolerance,&#x201d; Frontiers in Plant Science 8 (2017): 621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Kunst and A. L. Samuels, &#x201c;Biosynthesis and Secretion of Plant Cuticular Wax,&#x201d; Progress in Lipid Research 42, no. 1 (2003): 51&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Kunst and L. Samuels, &#x201c;Plant Cuticles Shine: Advances in Wax Biosynthesis and Export,&#x201d; Current Opinion in Plant Biology 12, no. 6 (2009): 721&#x2013;727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. B. Lee and M. C. Suh, &#x201c;Recent Advances in Cuticular Wax Biosynthesis and Its Regulation in Arabidopsis,&#x201d; Molecular Plant 6 (2013): 246&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Bourdenx, A. Bernard, F. Domergue, et al., &#x201c;Overexpression of Arabidopsis ECERIFERUM1 Promotes Wax Very&#x2010;Long&#x2010;Chain Alkane Biosynthesis and Influences Plant Response to Biotic and Abiotic Stresses,&#x201d; Plant Physiology 156 (2011): 29&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wen, W. Xia, Y. Wang, et al., &#x201c;Pathway Elucidation and Heterologous Reconstitution of the Long&#x2010;Chain Alkane Pentadecane Biosynthesis From Pogostemon cablin,&#x201d; Plant Biotechnology Journal 23, no. 2 (2025): 564&#x2013;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Ni, C. Song, and X. Wang, &#x201c;Investigation on Response Mechanism of Epicuticular Wax on Arabidopsis thaliana Under Cold Stress,&#x201d; Scientia Agricultura Sinica 47 (2014): 252&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Rahman, M. Shao, S. Pahari, et al., &#x201c;Dissecting the Roles of Cuticular Wax in Plant Resistance to Shoot Dehydration and Low&#x2010;Temperature Stress in Arabidopsis,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 22, no. 4 (2021): 1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. P. Lu, X. H. Liu, M. J. Wang, et al., &#x201c;The NAT1&#x2010;bHLH110&#x2010;CER1/CER1L Module Regulates Heat Stress Tolerance in Rice,&#x201d; Nature Genetics 57, no. 2 (2025): 427&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xing, H. Xu, M. Zhu, et al., &#x201c;Gas Chromatography&#x2013;Mass Spectrometry Metabolite Analysis Combined With Transcriptomics Reveals Genes Involved in Wax Biosynthesis in Allium fistulosum L.,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 25, no. 11 (2024): 6106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Gharib, Y. Su, Z. Zuo, et al., &#x201c;Melatonin Enhances Metal Oxide Nanoparticles Tolerance in Rice Seedlings Through Dual Regulation of Antioxidant Defense and Photosynthetic Efficiency,&#x201d; Physiologia Plantarum 176, no. 6 (2024): 70020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Wang, S. Zhang, and F. Ding, &#x201c;Melatonin Mitigates Chilling&#x2010;Induced Oxidative Stress and Photosynthesis Inhibition in Tomato Plants,&#x201d; Antioxidants 9 (2020): 218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Huang, X. Kou, L. Qiao, et al., &#x201c;Maintaining Quality of Postharvest Green Pepper Fruit Using Melatonin by Regulating Membrane Lipid Metabolism and Enhancing Antioxidant Capacity,&#x201d; Food Chemistry 460 (2024): 140671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, L. Zhang, W. Duan, et al., &#x201c;Melatonin Maintained Higher Contents of Unsaturated Fatty Acid and Cell Membrane Structure Integrity in Banana Peel and Alleviated Postharvest Chilling Injury,&#x201d; Food Chemistry 397 (2022): 133836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Ye, D. Y. Wang, R. X. Li, et al., &#x201c;SlAN2 Overexpression Improves Cold Resistance in Tomato (Solanum lycopersicum L.) by Regulating Glycolysis and Ascorbic Acid Metabolism,&#x201d; Genomics 117 (2025): 110978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Y. Ji, Q. Wang, T. T. Lu, H. Ma, and X. Chen, &#x201c;The Effects of Ultrasonication on the Phytochemicals, Antioxidant, and Polyphenol Oxidase and Peroxidase Activities in Coffee Leaves,&#x201d; Food Chemistry 373 (2022): 131480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Song, Q. Ma, Z. Zou, et al., &#x201c;Molecular Link Between Leaf Coloration and Gene Expression of Flavonoid and Carotenoid Biosynthesis in Camellia sinensis Cultivar &#x2bb;Huangjinya&#x2bc;,&#x201d; Frontiers in Plant Science 8 (2017): 803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. S. Cheng, X. D. Zhang, H. M. Mu, et al., &#x201c;Transcriptome Analysis Unravels Differential Genes Involved in Essential Oil Content in Callus and Tissue Culture Seedlings of Lavandula angustifolia,&#x201d; Biotechnology &amp; Biotechnological Equipment 38, no. 1 (2024): 2367097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. J. Livak and T. D. Schmittgen, &#x201c;Analysis of Relative Gene Expression Data Using Real&#x2010;Time Quantitative PCR and the 2&#x2212;&#x394;&#x394;CT Method,&#x201d; Methods 25 (2001): 402&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Y. Wang, M. X. Du, J. Y. Li, et al., &#x201c;Overexpression of GhSWEET42, a SWEET&#x2010;Like Gene From Cotton, Enhances the Oil Content and Seed Size,&#x201d; Biotechnology &amp; Biotechnological Equipment 37, no. 1 (2023): 2266529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Liu, L. Yang, Q. Zheng, et al., &#x201c;Analysis of Cuticular Wax Constituents and Genes That Contribute to the Formation of &#x2bb;Glossy Newhall&#x2bc;, a Spontaneous Bud Mutant From the Wild&#x2010;Type &#x2bb;Newhall&#x2bc; Navel Orange,&#x201d; Plant Molecular Biology 88 (2015): 573&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Liu, J. Tang, Z. Liu, et al., &#x201c;Cgl2 Plays an Essential Role in Cuticular Wax Biosynthesis in Cabbage (Brassica oleracea L. var. capitata),&#x201d; BMC Plant Biology 17 (2017): 223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Tong, G. Yang, B. Aoen, et al., &#x201c;Screening of Salt&#x2010;Tolerant Thinopyrum ponticum Under Two Coastal Region Salinity Stress Levels,&#x201d; Frontiers in Genetics 13 (2022): 832013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Lewandowska, A. Keyl, and I. Feussner, &#x201c;Wax Biosynthesis in Response to Danger: Its Regulation Upon Abiotic and Biotic Stress,&#x201d; New Phytologist 227 (2020): 698&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Ziv, Z. Zhao, Y. G. Gao, and Y. Xia, &#x201c;Multifunctional Roles of Plant Cuticle During Plant&#x2010;Pathogen Interactions,&#x201d; Frontiers in Plant Science 9 (2018): 1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Shepherd and D. Wynne Griffiths, &#x201c;The Effects of Stress on Plant Cuticular Waxes,&#x201d; New Phytologist 171 (2006): 469&#x2013;499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Mohammadian, J. R. Watling, and R. S. Hill, &#x201c;The Impact of Epicuticular Wax on Gas&#x2010;Exchange and Photoinhibition in Leucadendron lanigerum (Proteaceae),&#x201d; Acta Oecologica 31, no. 1 (2007): 93&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Mu, J. K. Oh, K. Perez, et al., &#x201c;Effect of Wax Chain Length on the Adhesion Dynamics and Interfacial Rigidity of Salmonella Typhimurium LT2,&#x201d; Surfaces and Interfaces 44 (2024): 103745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, L. Kong, P. Zhi, and C. Chang, &#x201c;Update on Cuticular Wax Biosynthesis and Its Roles in Plant Disease Resistance,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 21, no. 15 (2020): 5514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Lewandowska, A. Keyl, I. Feussner, et al., &#x201c;Wax Biosynthesis in Response to Danger: Its Regulation Upon Abiotic and Biotic Stress,&#x201d; New Phytologist 227, no. 3 (2020): 698&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ding, G. Wang, M. Wang, and S. Zhang, &#x201c;Exogenous Melatonin Improves Tolerance to Water Deficit by Promoting Cuticle Formation in Tomato Plants,&#x201d; Molecules 23, no. 7 (2018): 1605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Liu, L. Li, Z. Xiong, et al., &#x201c;Trade&#x2010;Offs Between the Accumulation of Cuticular Wax and Jasmonic Acid&#x2010;Mediated Herbivory Resistance in Maize,&#x201d; Journal of Integrative Plant Biology 66, no. 1 (2024): 143&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Watts, S. Kaur, and R. Kariyat, &#x201c;Revisiting Plant Defense&#x2010;Fitness Trade&#x2010;Off Hypotheses Using Solanum as a Model Genus,&#x201d; Frontiers in Ecology and Evolution 10 (2023): 1094961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. J. Li, W. P. Bai, L. B. Liu, et al., &#x201c;Massive Increases in C31 Alkane on Zygophyllum xanthoxylum Leaves Contribute to Its Excellent Abiotic Stress Tolerance,&#x201d; Annals of Botany 131, no. 4 (2023): 723&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhao and S. S. Feng, &#x201c;Effects of Lipid Chain Length on Molecular Interactions Between Paclitaxel and Phospholipid Within Model Biomembranes,&#x201d; Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 274, no. 1 (2004): 55&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Carvajal, A. Castro&#x2010;Cegr&#xed;, R. Jim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;Mu&#xf1;oz, M. Jamilena, D. Garrido, and F. Palma, &#x201c;Changes in Morphology, Metabolism and Composition of Cuticular Wax in Zucchini Fruit During Postharvest Cold Storage,&#x201d; Frontiers in Plant Science 12 (2021): 778745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. L'Haridon, A. Besson&#x2010;Bard, M. Binda, et al., &#x201c;A Permeable Cuticle Is Associated With the Release of Reactive Oxygen Species and Induction of Innate Immunity,&#x201d; PLoS Pathogens 7, no. 7 (2011): e1002148.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>