<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41186016</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prehabilitation enhances functional and structural recovery following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70170</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of an 8-week prehabilitation programme combined with standardized post-operative rehabilitation in improving functional recovery, pain control and structural healing following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective randomized controlled trial was conducted with 90 male patients undergoing primary unilateral ACLR, randomly assigned to either a prehabilitation group (45 patients) or a non-preoperative rehabilitation group (45 patients). The prehabilitation group participated in an 8-week programme including neuromuscular training, strength exercises and education; another group received a home-based exercise programme for 8 weeks, while both groups received identical post-operative rehabilitation. Primary outcomes were measured using the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) score at 12 months, with secondary outcomes including pain levels assessed by the visual analogue scale, Knee injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score, functional performance tests and structural assessments through magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Statistical analyses included repeated-measures analysis of variance, multiple linear regression and Cox proportional hazards models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 12-month follow-up, the prehabilitation group demonstrated significantly better outcomes compared to the non-preoperative group: IKDC scores improved by 11.3 points (92.4 vs. 77.1), pain scores were lower (0.0 vs. 1.0) and thigh muscle asymmetry was reduced (0.8&#x2009;cm vs. 1.5&#x2009;cm). MRI results also showed better structural healing in the preoperative rehabilitation group. The programme was identified as the strongest predictor of improved knee function and reduced recovery time by 2.6 weeks (7.2 weeks vs. 9.8 weeks).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Preoperative rehabilitation is essential for better recovery after ACLR. These findings support incorporating preoperative rehabilitation into standard treatment protocols. Further research should investigate these effects in broader patient populations and examine underlying biological mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">N/A.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Yuping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, General Hospital of Northern Theater Command, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, General Hospital of Northern Theater Command, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>ZiWei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2935-6173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, General Hospital of Northern Theater Command, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, General Hospital of Northern Theater Command, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preoperative rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery time</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41186016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adhitya IPGS, Kurniawati I, Sawa R, Wijaya TF, Dewi N. The risk factors and preventive strategies of poor knee functions and osteoarthritis after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a narrative review. Phys Ther Res. 2023;26(3):78&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briem K, Zebis Mk, Haraldsson B&#xde;, Bencke J, Fernandes L. Rehabilitation guidelines after autograft anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction need more graft&#x2010;specific exercise recommendations&#x2014;a scoping review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1002/ksa.12666</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F. Optimising the &#x2018;Mid&#x2010;Stage&#x2019; training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2020;50(4):657&#x2013;678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Gokeler A, Herrington L, Hughes M, Grassi A, Wadey R, et al. Optimising the early&#x2010;stage rehabilitation process post&#x2010;ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2024;54(1):49&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter HM, Littlewood C, Webster KE, Smith BE. The effectiveness of preoperative rehabilitation programmes on postoperative outcomes following anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction: a systematic review. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21(1):647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinque ME, Dornan GJ, Chahla J, Moatshe G, LaPrade RF. High rates of osteoarthritis develop after anterior cruciate ligament surgery: an analysis of 4108 patients. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(8):2011&#x2013;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins NJ, Misra D, Felson DT, Crossley KM, Roos EM. Measures of knee function: International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) Subjective Knee Evaluation Form, Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score (KOOS), Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score Physical Function Short Form (KOOS&#x2010;PS), Knee Outcome Survey Activities of Daily Living Scale (KOS&#x2010;ADL), Lysholm Knee Scoring Scale, Oxford Knee Score (OKS), Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index (WOMAC), Activity Rating Scale (ARS), and Tegner Activity Score (TAS). Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63(Suppl 11):208&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criss CR, Melton MS, Ulloa SA, Simon JE, Clark BC, France CR, et al. Rupture, reconstruction, and rehabilitation: a multi&#x2010;disciplinary review of mechanisms for central nervous system adaptations following anterior cruciate ligament injury. Knee. 2021;30:78&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran MT, Bedi A, Kujawa M, Palmieri&#x2010;Smith R. A cross&#x2010;sectional examination of quadriceps strength, biomechanical function, and functional performance from 9 to 24 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(10):2438&#x2013;2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eitzen I, Moksnes H, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Risberg MA. A progressive 5&#x2010;week ex ercise therapy program leads to significant improvement in knee function early after anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40:705&#x2013;721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Neuromechanics of human movement (fifth edition), Human Kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Failla MJ, Logerstedt DS, Grindem H, Axe MJ, Risberg MA, Engebretsen L, et al. Does extended preoperative rehabilitation influence outcomes 2 years after ACL reconstruction? A comparative effectiveness study between the MOON and Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohorts. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(10):2608&#x2013;2614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;ltstr&#xf6;m A, Kvist J, Bittencourt N, Mendon&#xe7;a LD, H&#xe4;gglund M. Clinical risk profile for a second anterior cruciate ligament injury in female soccer players after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(6):1421&#x2013;1430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Roos EM, Frobell RB, Roemer F, Ranstam J, Lohmander LS. Delaying ACL reconstruction and treating with exercise therapy alone may alter prognostic factors for 5&#x2010;year outcome: an exploratory analysis of the KANON trial. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1622&#x2013;1629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giesche F, Niederer D, Banzer W, Vogt L. Evidence for the effects of prehabilitation before ACL&#x2010;reconstruction on return to sport&#x2010;related and self&#x2010;reported knee function: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2020;15(10):e0240192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Granan LP, Risberg MA, Engebretsen L, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Eitzen I. How does a combined preoperative and postoperative rehabilitation programme influence the outcome of ACL reconstruction 2 years after surgery? A comparison between patients in the Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL Cohort and the Norwegian National Knee Ligament Registry. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(6):385&#x2013;389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartigan E, Axe MJ, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L. Perturbation training prior to ACL reconstruction improves gait asymmetries in non&#x2010;copers. J Orthop Res. 2009;27:724&#x2013;729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrington L, Wrapson C, Matthews M, Matthews H. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, hamstring versus bone&#x2010;patella tendon&#x2010;bone grafts: a systematic literature review of outcome from surgery. Knee. 2005;12:41&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter DJ, Guermazi A, Lo GH, Grainger AJ, Conaghan PG, Boudreau RM, et al. Evolution of semi&#x2010;quantitative whole joint assessment of knee OA: MOAKS (MRI Osteoarthritis Knee Score). Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2011;19(8):990&#x2013;1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunnicutt JL, McLeod MM, Slone HS, Gregory CM. Quadriceps neuromuscular and physical function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2020;55(3):238&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingelsrud LH, Terwee CB, Terluin B, Granan LP, Engebretsen L, Mills K, et al. Meaningful change scores in the knee injury and osteoarthritis outcome score in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(5):1120&#x2013;1128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irrgang JJ, Anderson AF, Boland AL, Harner CD, Kurosaka M, Neyret P, et al. Development and validation of the international knee documentation committee subjective knee form. Am J Sports Med. 2001;29(5):600&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keays S, Bullock&#x2010;Saxton J, Newcombe P, Bullock M. The effectiveness of a pre&#x2010;operative home&#x2010;based physiotherapy programme for chronic anterior cruciate ligament deficiency. Physiother Res Int. 2006;11:204&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keays SL, Bullock&#x2010;Saxton J, Keays AC. Strength and function before and after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2000;373(373):174&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenze C, Pietrosimone B, Lisee C, Rutherford M, Birchmeier T, Lepley A, et al. Demographic and surgical factors affect quadriceps strength after ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(3):921&#x2013;930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson S, Struglics A, Lohmander LS, Frobell R. Surgical reconstruction of ruptured anterior cruciate ligament prolongs trauma&#x2010;induced increase of inflammatory cytokines in synovial fluid: an exploratory analysis in the KANON trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2017;25(9):1443&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RJ, Margalit A, Nduaguba A, Gunderson MA, Wells L. Obesity and recovery of muscle strength after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in pediatric patients. J Orthop Surg. 2018;26(3):2309499018806631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisee C, Lepley AS, Birchmeier T, O'Hagan K, Kuenze C. Quadriceps strength and volitional activation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Health. 2019;11(2):163&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohmander LS, Englund PM, Dahl LL, Roos EM. The long&#x2010;term consequence of anterior cruciate ligament and meniscus injuries: osteoarthritis. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(10):1756&#x2013;1769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van der Weegen W, van der Horst N. Quadriceps and hamstrings strength reference values for athletes with and without anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction who play popular pivoting sports, including soccer, basketball, and handball: a scoping review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52(3):142&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, Senorski EH, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Prill R. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: decades of change. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(4):1178&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Cingel REH, Brooijmans F, Neeter C, van Tienen T, Hullegie W, et al. Evidence&#x2010;based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1506&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald LS, Boorman&#x2010;Padgett J, Kent R, Stone K, Wickiewicz TL, Pearle AD, et al. ACL deficiency increases forces on the medial femoral condyle and the lateral meniscus with applied rotatory loads. J Bone Jt Surg. 2016;98(20):1713&#x2013;1721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson AL, Schilaty ND, Anderson S, Nagai T, Bates NA. Arthrogenic muscle inhibition after anterior cruciate ligament injury: injured and uninjured limb recovery over time. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1143376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendias CL, Lynch EB, Davis ME, Sibilsky Enselman ER, Harning JA, DeWolf PD, et al. Changes in circulating biomarkers of muscle atrophy, inflammation, and cartilage turnover in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and rehabilitation. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(8):1819&#x2013;1826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir B, Vivekanantha P, Dhillon S, Cotnareanu O, Cohen D, Nagai K, et al. Fear of reinjury following primary anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(6):2299&#x2013;2314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Kopf S, Rabuck S, Becker R, van der Merwe W, Zaffagnini S, et al. Rotatory knee laxity tests and the pivot shift as tools for ACL treatment algorithm. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2012;20:793&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Martin L, Ford KR, Paterno MV, Schmitt LC, Heidt RS, et al. No association of time from surgery with functional deficits in athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: evidence for objective return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport criteria. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40:2256&#x2013;2263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson C, Rajan L, Day J, Hinton R, Bodendorfer BM. Postoperative rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Sports Med Arthrosc. 2021;29(2):63&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholls M, Aspelund T, Ingvarsson T, Briem K. Nationwide study highlights a second peak in ACL tears for women in their early forties. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(2):648&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordenvall R, Bahmanyar S, Adami J, Stenros C, Wredmark T, Fell&#xe4;nder&#x2010;Tsai L. A population&#x2010;based nationwide study of cruciate ligament injury in Sweden, 2001&#x2010;2009: incidence, treatment, and sex differences. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(8):1808&#x2013;1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri&#x2010;Smith RM, Thomas AC, Wojtys EM. Maximizing quadriceps strength after ACL reconstruction. Clin Sports Med. 2008;27:405&#x2013;424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Schmitt LC, Ford KR, Rauh MJ, Myer GD, Huang B, et al. Biomechanical measures during landing and postural stability predict second anterior cruciate ligament injury after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:1968&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Beischer S, Thome&#xe9; R, Hamrin Senorski E. Superior knee self&#x2010;efficacy and quality of life throughout the first year in patients who recover symmetrical muscle function after ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(2):555&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoul T, Klouche S, Guerrier B, El&#x2010;Hariri B, Herman S, Gerometta A, et al. Are athletes able to resume sport at six&#x2010;month mean follow&#x2010;up after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Prospective functional and psychological assessment from the French Anterior Cruciate Ligament Study (FAST) cohort. Knee. 2019;26(1):155&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recht MP, Kramer J, Marcelis S, Pathria MN, Trudell D, Haghighi P, et al. Abnormalities of articular cartilage in the knee: analysis of available MR techniques. Radiology. 1993;187(2):473&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera&#x2010;Brown AM, Frontera WR, Font&#xe1;nez R, Micheo WF. Evidence for isokinetic and functional testing in return to sport decisions following ACL surgery. PM R. 2022;14(5):678&#x2013;690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roewer BD, Di Stasi SL, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L. Quadriceps strength and weight acceptance strategies continue to improve two years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Biomech. 2011;44:1948&#x2013;1953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos EM, Roos HP, Lohmander LS, Ekdahl C, Beynnon BD. Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score (KOOS)&#x2014;development of a self&#x2010;administered outcome measure. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;28(2):88&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelbourne KD, Klootwyk TE, Wilckens JH, De Carlo MS. Ligament stability two to six years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with autogenous patellar tendon graft and participation in accelerated rehabilitation program. Am J Sports Med. 1995;23:575&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur U, Gulati V, Shah J, Tietze D, Chhabra A. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction related complications: 2D and 3D high&#x2010;resolution magnetic resonance imaging evaluation. Skeletal Radiol. 2022;51(7):1347&#x2013;1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiler A, Schmeling A, St&#xf6;hr I, K&#xe4;&#xe4;b MJ, Wagner M. Primary versus single stage revision anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using autologous hamstring tendon grafts: a prospective matched&#x2010;group analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:1643&#x2013;1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JH, Eun SP, Park DH, Kwak HB, Chang E. The effects of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction on individual quadriceps muscle thickness and circulating biomarkers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(24):4895.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakharia A, Zhang K, Al&#x2010;Katanani F, et al. Prehabilitation prior to anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction is a safe and effective intervention for short&#x2010; to long&#x2010;term benefits: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zantop T, Herbort M, Raschke MJ, Fu FH, Petersen W. The role of the anteromedial and posterolateral bundles of the anterior cruciate ligament in anterior tibial translation and internal rotation. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:223&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>