<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41223439</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cerebello-Cerebral Network Dynamic of Basketball Athletes in Motor Control Tasks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>820</StartPage><EndPage>830</EndPage><MedlinePgn>820-830</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003892</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The cerebellum is essential for motor control due to its dynamic interactions with the sensorimotor network (SMN). Within the cerebellum, motor functions are organized into two distinct representations, known as the first motor representation (MRP1) and the second motor representation (MRP2). While long-term training in athletes optimizes motor control, the functional reorganization in the cerebellum and its interaction with the SMN remains unclear. Specifically, the unique contributions of MRP1 and MRP2 to motor expertise remain poorly understood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We utilized task-based functional magnetic resonance imaging and dynamic causal modeling to compare 55 elite basketball athletes with 65 nonathlete controls during two general motor tasks: a grip force task focused on upper-limb control and a leg raise task assessing lower-limb postural control. We examined brain activation and effective connectivity across cerebellar and cortical motor regions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant differences in regional brain activation were found between the groups. Dynamic causal modeling analysis revealed that, compared with nonathletes, athletes' MRP1 showed a significant stronger bidirectional connectivity with effector regions in both tasks. In contrast, athletes' MRP2 exhibited a significant decreased connectivity with effector regions during the leg raise task. Additionally, there was a nonsignificant trend toward increased connectivity from MRP2 to the motor planning regions of SMN in athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that the neural signature of expert motor control is better reflected by refined interactions within the cerebello-cerebral circuit, rather than by heightened neural activation. Athletes demonstrate a reorganization of cerebellar modulation, with MRP1 facilitating automatic motor output and MRP2 showing reduced involvement during complex tasks. These results provide new insights into the neural basis of motor expertise and could inform targeted approaches in sports training and neurorehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Yapeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yihan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Wenxuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Athletic Performance, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xinwei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Athletic Performance, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DU</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Motor Cognitive Assessment and Regulation, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001490" MajorTopicYN="Y">Basketball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002531" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebellum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009048" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Skills</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034941" MajorTopicYN="N">Upper Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CEREBELLUM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DYNAMIC CAUSAL MODELING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FUNCTIONAL MAGNETIC RESONANCE IMAGING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MOTOR EXPERTISE</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41223439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smaers JB, Vanier DR. Brain size expansion in primates and humans is explained by a selective modular expansion of the cortico-cerebellar system. Cortex. 2019;118:292&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bare&#x161; M, Apps R, Avanzino L, et al. Consensus paper: decoding the contributions of the cerebellum as a time machine. From neurons to clinical applications. Cerebellum. 2019;18(2):266&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warthen KG, Walker NC, Wicklund BD, et al. Neuromodulation of the cerebellum for motor applications: a systematic review. J Integr Neurosci. 2024;23(10):195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokolov AA, Miall RC, Ivry RB. The cerebellum: adaptive prediction for movement and cognition. Trends Cogn Sci. 2017;21(5):313&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito M. Cerebellar circuitry as a neuronal machine. Prog Neurobiol. 2006;78(3-5):272&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoodley C, Schmahmann J. Functional topography in the human cerebellum: a meta-analysis of neuroimaging studies. Neuroimage. 2009;44(2):489&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HE, Avraham G, Ivry RB. The psychology of reaching: action selection, movement implementation, and sensorimotor learning. Annu Rev Psychol. 2021;72(1):61&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrichsen J, King M, Hernandez-Castillo C, Sereno M, Ivry RB. Universal transform or multiple functionality? Understanding the contribution of the human cerebellum across task domains. Neuron. 2019;102(5):918&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Davis C, Thomas AM, et al. A cortico-cerebellar loop for motor planning. Nature. 2018;563(7729):113&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spampinato DA, Casula EP, Koch G. The cerebellum and the motor cortex: multiple networks controlling multiple aspects of behavior. Neuroscientist. 2024;30(6):723&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guell X, Schmahmann JD, Gabrieli JD, Ghosh SS. Functional gradients of the cerebellum. Elife. 2018;7:e36652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guell X, Gabrieli JDE, Schmahmann JD. Triple representation of language, working memory, social and emotion processing in the cerebellum: convergent evidence from task and seed-based resting-state fMRI analyses in a single large cohort. Neuroimage. 2018;172:437&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlerf JE, Verstynen TD, Ivry RB, Spencer RMC. Evidence of a novel somatopic map in the human neocerebellum during complex actions. J Neurophysiol. 2010;103(6):3330&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Errante A, Fogassi L. Activation of cerebellum and basal ganglia during the observation and execution of manipulative actions. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):12008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoodley CJ, MacMore JP, Makris N, Sherman JC, Schmahmann JD. Location of lesion determines motor vs. cognitive consequences in patients with cerebellar stroke. Neuroimage Clin. 2016;12:765&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoodley CJ, Schmahmann JD. Functional topography of the human cerebellum. In: Manto M, Huisman T, editors. Handbook of Clinical Neurology: Elsevier; 2018. pp. 59&#x2013;70. [cited 2025 May 12] Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/B9780444639561000047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Errante A, Gerbella M, Mingolla GP, Fogassi L. Activation of cerebellum, basal ganglia and thalamus during observation and execution of mouth, hand, and foot actions. Brain Topogr. 2023;36(4):476&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillat Y, Bazin P-L, van der Zwaag W. Whole-body somatotopic maps in the cerebellum revealed with 7T fMRI. Neuroimage. 2020;211:116624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kipping JA, Grodd W, Kumar V, Taubert M, Villringer A, Margulies DS. Overlapping and parallel cerebello-cerebral networks contributing to sensorimotor control: an intrinsic functional connectivity study. Neuroimage. 2013;83:837&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E K, Chen SA, Ho MR, Desmond JE. A meta&#x2010;analysis of cerebellar contributions to higher cognition from PET and fMRI studies. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35(2):593&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habas C, Axelrad H, Cabanis E-A. The cerebellar second homunculus remains silent during passive bimanual movements. Neuroreport. 2004;15(10):1571&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito M. Historical review of the significance of the cerebellum and the role of Purkinje cells in motor learning. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;978(1):273&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Jeong J. Dribble accuracy and arm coordination pattern according to motor expertise and tempo. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(10):5788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robalo RAM, Diniz AMFA, Fernandes O, Passos PJM. The role of variability in the control of the basketball dribble under different perceptual setups. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(4):521&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawers A, Allen JL, Ting LH. Long-term training modifies the modular structure and organization of walking balance control. J Neurophysiol. 2015;114(6):3359&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park IS, Lee YN, Kwon S, Lee NJ, Rhyu IJ. White matter plasticity in the cerebellum of elite basketball athletes. Anat Cell Biol. 2015;48(4):262&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Park JW, Tae WS, Rhyu IJ. Cerebral cortex changes in basketball players. J Korean Med Sci. 2022;37(11):e86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu F, Pi Y, Liu K, et al. Neural efficiency in basketball players is associated with bidirectional reductions in cortical activation and deactivation during multiple-object tracking task performance. Biol Psychol. 2019;144:28&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan X-Y, Pi Y-L, Wang J, et al. Morphological and functional differences between athletes and novices in cortical neuronal networks. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017;10:660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L-L, Pi Y-L, Shen C, et al. Expertise-level-dependent functionally plastic changes during motor imagery in basketball players. Neuroscience. 2018;380:78&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JA, Tain R, Sharp KG, et al. Identifying the neural correlates of anticipatory postural control: a novel fMRI paradigm. Hum Brain Mapp. 2023;44(10):4088&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casiraghi L, Alahmadi AAS, Monteverdi A, et al. I see your effort: force-related BOLD effects in an extended action execution&#x2013;observation network involving the cerebellum. Cereb Cortex. 2019;29(3):1351&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aglioti SM, Cesari P, Romani M, Urgesi C. Action anticipation and motor resonance in elite basketball players. Nat Neurosci. 2008;11(9):1109&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabarkapa D, Fry AC, Cabarkapa DV, Myers CA, Jones GT, Deane MA. Kinetic and kinematic characteristics of proficient and non-proficient 2-point and 3-point basketball shooters. Sports (Basel). 2021;10(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield RC. The assessment and analysis of handedness: the Edinburgh inventory. Neuropsychologia. 1971;9(1):97&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan CG, Wang XD, Zuo XN, Zang YF. DPABI: data processing &amp; analysis for (resting-state) brain imaging. Neuroinformatics. 2016;14(3):339&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jezzini A, Caruana F, Stoianov I, Gallese V, Rizzolatti G. Functional organization of the insula and inner perisylvian regions. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2012;109(25):10077&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quirmbach F, Limanowski J. A crucial role of the frontal operculum in task-set dependent visuomotor performance monitoring. eNeuro. 2022;9(2):ENEURO.0524-21.2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg G. Supplementary motor area structure and function: review and hypotheses. Behav Brain Sci. 1985;8(4):567&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt BA. Midcingulate cortex: structure, connections, homologies, functions and diseases. J Chem Neuroanat. 2016;74:28&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung K, Friston KJ, Pae C, et al. Effective connectivity during working memory and resting states: a DCM study. Neuroimage. 2018;169:485&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calmels C. Neural correlates of motor expertise: extensive motor training and cortical changes. Brain Res. 2020;1739:146323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke JU, Pakan JM. Disynaptic cerebrocerebellar pathways originating from multiple functionally distinct cortical areas. Elife. 2020;9:e59148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano TJ, Dhanerawala ZM, Kislin M, et al. Homologous organization of cerebellar pathways to sensory, motor, and associative forebrain. Cell Rep. 2021;36(12):109721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manto M, Bower JM, Conforto AB, et al. Consensus paper: roles of the cerebellum in motor control&#x2014;the diversity of ideas on cerebellar involvement in movement. Cerebellum. 2012;11(2):457&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmahmann JD. The cerebellum and cognition. Neurosci Lett. 2019;688:62&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haar S, Donchin O. A revised computational neuroanatomy for motor control. J Cogn Neurosci. 2020;32(10):1823&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonini F, Burle B, Li&#xe9;geois-Chauvel C, R&#xe9;gis J, Chauvel P, Vidal F. action monitoring and medial frontal cortex: leading role of supplementary motor area. Science. 2014;343(6173):888&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bretas RV, Taoka M, Suzuki H, Iriki A. Secondary somatosensory cortex of primates: beyond body maps, toward conscious self-in-the-world maps. Exp Brain Res. 2020;238(2):259&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayan E, Cohen LG. Neuroplasticity subserving motor skill learning. Neuron. 2011;72(3):443&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon V, Uddin LQ. Saliency, switching, attention and control: a network model of insula function. Brain Struct Funct. 2010;214(5-6):655&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>