<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41168668</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interindividual Variability of Acute Cardiovascular Responses to Low-Load Resistance Exercise with Different Methods of Blood Flow Restriction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>527</StartPage><EndPage>537</EndPage><MedlinePgn>527-537</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003886</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to determine if acute cardiovascular responses to low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction (BFR) exhibit true and repeatable interindividual variability, and whether responses differ between absolute and relative pressure application methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In a replicate crossover design, 82 healthy adults (21 [3] yr) were randomly assigned to an absolute (100&#x2009;mm Hg; n = 42) or relative (80% arterial occlusion pressure [~128&#x2009;mm Hg]; n = 40) pressure group and completed two exercise and two control trials (randomized order). Exercise involved two sets of 30% one-repetition maximum unilateral knee extensions under the assigned pressure, with repetitions individually prescribed as 70% maximum achieved during pretesting. Systolic blood pressure (SBP), diastolic blood pressure (DBP), and heart rate (HR) were measured pre- and posttrial, and control-adjusted responses were calculated. Within-participant linear mixed models (covariate adjusted) and random-effects meta-analyses quantified interindividual variability, while Pearson correlations assessed reproducibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">BFR exercise increased SBP (18.0&#x2009;mm Hg), DBP (12.8&#x2009;mm Hg), and HR (4.5 bpm) versus control (all P &lt; 0.001), with greater increases in SBP (4.9&#x2009;mm Hg) and DBP (4.1&#x2009;mm Hg) for the relative group ( P &#x2264; 0.001). Participant-by-treatment interactions indicated true interindividual variability for all outcomes except HR in the absolute group. Correlations between replicates were significant for all outcomes under relative pressures ( P &#x2264; 0.018), but only for SBP ( P &lt; 0.001) in the absolute group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Acute cardiovascular responses to BFR exercise are variable between and reproducible within individuals, particularly under relative pressures. Whether these differences are attributable to BFR or reflect inherent variability to low-load resistance exercise remains unknown.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammert</LastName><ForeName>William B</ForeName><Initials>WB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Yujiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kataoka</LastName><ForeName>Ryo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Nutrition, Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Southern Mississippi, Hattiesburg, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sallberg</LastName><ForeName>Robert W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metcalf</LastName><ForeName>Emily E</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loenneke</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, Kevser Ermin Applied Physiology Laboratory, The University of Mississippi, University, MS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007717" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">INDIVIDUAL DIFFERENCES</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KAATSU</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REPLICATE CROSSOVER TRIAL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REPRODUCIBILITY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RESISTANCE EXERCISE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RESPONSE VARIABILITY</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41168668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202603000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Brandner CR. The role of blood flow restriction training for applied practitioners: a questionnaire-based survey. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(2):123&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Hammert WB, Kataoka R, Yamada Y, Abe T. Twenty-five years of blood flow restriction training: what we know, what we don&#x2019;t, and where to next? J Sports Sci. 2025;43(19):2115&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spranger MD, Krishnan AC, Levy PD, O&#x2019;Leary DS, Smith SA. Blood flow restriction training and the exercise pressor reflex: a call for concern. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2015;309(9):H1440&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spranger MD. Commentary: Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2020;11:599592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristina-Oliveira M, Meireles K, Spranger MD, O&#x2019;Leary DS, Roschel H, Pe&#xe7;anha T. Clinical safety of blood flow-restricted training? A comprehensive review of altered muscle metaboreflex in cardiovascular disease during ischemic exercise. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2020;318(1):H90&#x2013;H109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs ME, Hackney KJ, Martin D, et al. Acute vascular and cardiovascular responses to blood flow&#x2013;restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(8):1489&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandner CR, Kidgell DJ, Warmington SA. Unilateral bicep curl hemodynamics: low-pressure continuous vs high-pressure intermittent blood flow restriction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(6):770&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Perceptual and arterial occlusion responses to very low load blood flow restricted exercise performed to volitional failure. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2019;39(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Credeur DP, Jones R, Stanford D, Stoner L, McCoy S, Jessee M. Central cardiovascular hemodynamic response to unilateral handgrip exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(10):2255&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xe7;anha T, De Brito LC, Fecchio RY, et al. Metaboreflex activation delays heart rate recovery after aerobic exercise in never&#x2010;treated hypertensive men. J Physiol. 2016;594(21):6211&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Leary DS, Mannozzi J. Mechanisms mediating muscle metaboreflex control of cardiac output during exercise: impaired regulation in heart failure. Exp Physiol. 2025;110(5):675&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. Mastering variation: variance components and personalised medicine. Stat Med. 2016;35(7):966&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. Statistical pitfalls of personalized medicine. Nature. 2018;563(7733):619&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Sackett D, Taylor DW, Chong J, Roberts R, Pugsley S. Determining optimal therapy - randomized trials in individual patients. N Engl J Med. 1986;314(14):889&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstr&#xf6;m J, Lind L, Nowrouzi S, et al. Heterogeneity in blood pressure response to 4 antihypertensive drugs: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2023;329(14):1160&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuel JP, Bell CS, Samuels JA, et al. N-of-1 trials vs. usual care in children with hypertension: a pilot randomized clinical trial. Am J Hypertens. 2023;36(2):126&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, Loenneke JP. Letter to the editor: applying the blood flow restriction pressure: the elephant in the room. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2016;310(1):H132&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanford DM, Chatlaong MA, Miller WM, Mouser JG, Dankel SJ, Jessee MB. A comparison of variability between absolute and relative blood flow restriction pressures. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2022;42(4):278&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouser JG, Ade CJ, Black CD, Bemben DA, Bemben MG. Brachial blood flow under relative levels of blood flow restriction is decreased in a nonlinear fashion. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38(3):425&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motykie GD, Zebala LP, Caprini JA, et al. A guide to venous thromboembolism risk factor assessment. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2000;9(3):253&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Hammert WB, Kataoka R, et al. The role of the muscle metaboreflex on cardiovascular responses to submaximal resistance exercise with different pressures and modes of blood flow restriction. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2025;50:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammert WB, Song JS, Yamada Y, et al. Blood flow restriction augments exercise-induced pressure pain thresholds over repetition and effort matched conditions. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(1):73&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammert WB, Dankel SJ, Kataoka R, et al. Methodological considerations when studying resistance-trained populations: ideas for using control groups. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(12):2164&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goltz FR, Thackray AE, King JA, Dorling JL, Atkinson G, Stensel DJ. Interindividual responses of appetite to acute exercise: a replicated crossover study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(4):758&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goltz FR, Thackray AE, Atkinson G, et al. True interindividual variability exists in postprandial appetite responses in healthy men but is not moderated by the FTO genotype. J Nutr. 2019;149(7):1159&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen T, Thackray AE, King JA, et al. Are there interindividual responses of cardiovascular disease risk markers to acute exercise? A replicate crossover trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56(1):63&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Thackray AE, Shen T, et al. A replicate crossover trial on the interindividual variability of sleep indices in response to acute exercise undertaken by healthy men. Sleep. 2025;48(3):zsae250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez JT, Lolli L, Veasey RC, et al. Are there interindividual differences in the reactive hypoglycaemia response to breakfast? A replicate crossover trial. Eur J Nutr. 2024;63(8):2897&#x2013;909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. The analysis of continuous data from n-of-1 trials using paired cycles: a simple tutorial. Trials. 2024;25(1):128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lolli L, Gonzalez J, Shannon O, et al. Understanding treatment response heterogeneity using crossover and n-of-1 randomised controlled trials in exercise and nutrition research: a Primer. 2025. [cited 27 Apr 2025]. Available from: https://osf.io/6879e_v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IntHout J, Ioannidis JP, Borm GF. The Hartung-Knapp-Sidik-Jonkman method for random effects meta-analysis is straightforward and considerably outperforms the standard DerSimonian-Laird method. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14(1):25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veroniki AA, Jackson D, Viechtbauer W, et al. Methods to estimate the between-study variance and its uncertainty in meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2016;7(1):55&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langan D, Higgins JPT, Jackson D, et al. A comparison of heterogeneity variance estimators in simulated random&#x2010;effects meta-analyses. Res Synth Methods. 2019;10(1):83&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills HL, Higgins JPT, Morris RW, et al. Detecting heterogeneity of intervention effects using analysis and meta-analysis of differences in variance between trial arms. Epidemiology. 2021;32(6):846&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedenhofen B, Musch J. cocor: a comprehensive solution for the statistical comparison of correlations. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):e0121945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou GY. Toward using confidence intervals to compare correlations. Psychol Methods. 2007;12(4):399&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo A, Julious S, Senn S. Understanding variation in sets of n-of-1 trials. PLoS One. 2016;11(12):e0167167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes E, Alhulaefi S, Siervo M, et al. Inter-individual differences in the blood pressure lowering effects of dietary nitrate: a randomised double-blind placebo-controlled replicate crossover trial. Eur J Nutr. 2025;64(2):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee M, Dankel S, Buckner S, Mouser J, Mattocks K, Loenneke J. The cardiovascular and perceptual response to very low load blood flow restricted exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2017;38(08):597&#x2013;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, et al. Cardiovascular and perceptual responses to blood-flow-restricted resistance exercise with differing restrictive cuffs. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2012;32(5):331&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Counts BR, et al. The effects of upper body exercise across different levels of blood flow restriction on arterial occlusion pressure and perceptual responses. Physiol Behav. 2017;171:181&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thomee R. Effects of vascular occlusion on muscular endurance in dynamic knee extension exercise at different dubmaximal loads. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(2):372&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitschen PJ, Kistler BM, Jeong JH, et al. Perceptual effects and efficacy of intermittent or continuous blood flow restriction resistance training. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2014;34(5):356&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norbury R, Grant I, Woodhead A, Hughes L, Tallent J, Patterson SD. Acute hypoalgesic, neurophysiological and perceptual responses to low-load blood flow restriction exercise and high-load resistance exercise. Exp Physiol. 2024;109(5):672&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Kataoka R, Hammert WB, et al. Perceptual and hypoalgesic responses to submaximal knee extension exercise with different pressures and modes of blood flow restriction: effect of estimated muscle metabolites. Physiol Int. 2025;112(3):351&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitz RW, Wong V, Bell ZW, et al. Blood flow restricted exercise and discomfort: a review. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(3):871&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JS, Kataoka R, Yamada Y, et al. The hypoalgesic effect of low-load exercise to failure is not augmented by blood flow restriction. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2023;94(4):1084&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JS, Yamada Y, Wong V, et al. Hypoalgesia following isometric handgrip exercise with and without blood flow restriction is not mediated by discomfort nor changes in systolic blood pressure. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(5):518&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobrega ACL, O&#x2019;Leary D, Silva BM, Marongiu E, Piepoli MF, Crisafulli A. Neural regulation of cardiovascular response to exercise: role of central command and peripheral afferents. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:478965.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>