<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41416841</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8257</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Movement disorders : official journal of the Movement Disorder Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mov Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Respiratory Function in Friedreich's Ataxia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mds.70162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Friedreich's ataxia (FA) is a neurodegenerative disorder often accompanied by respiratory dysfunction, but detailed respiratory profiles remain understudied.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate pulmonary parameters and respiratory muscle strength in individuals with FA compared with healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sixteen FA patients and 20 age-matched healthy controls underwent spirometry, maximal inspiratory and expiratory pressure measurements, sniff nasal inspiratory pressure (SNIP), phrenic nerve conduction study, peripheral oxygen saturation (SpO<sub>2</sub>), and end-tidal CO2 (ETCO2). Respiratory parameters were analyzed using Student's t-test or Mann-Whitney test, and linear or quantile regression adjusted for body mass index and smoking status. Ataxia severity was assessed using the Scale for the Assessment and Rating of Ataxia (SARA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">FA patients exhibited significantly reduced forced vital capacity (FVC) and forced expiratory volume in 1&#x2009;s (FEV<sub>1</sub>), alongside decreased maximal respiratory pressures (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). A restrictive ventilatory pattern predominated. Peripheral oxygen saturation was lower in the FA group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Respiratory impairment appears mostly subclinical, suggesting that FA patients may be vulnerable to pulmonary infections and ventilatory failure. This dysfunction may reflect both neuromuscular weakness and impaired respiratory coordination. Early and regular respiratory assessment, together with preventive and rehabilitative strategies integrated into multidisciplinary care, may improve quality of life and potentially prolong survival in individuals with FA. &#xa9; 2025 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viana</LastName><ForeName>Celiana Figueiredo</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Neurology and Ataxia Unit, Department of Neurology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo-Escola Paulista de Medicina, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaques</LastName><ForeName>Cristina Saade</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2196-3151</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Neurology and Ataxia Unit, Department of Neurology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo-Escola Paulista de Medicina, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bezerra</LastName><ForeName>Marcio Luiz Escorcio</ForeName><Initials>MLE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Neurology and Ataxia Unit, Department of Neurology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo-Escola Paulista de Medicina, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barsottini</LastName><ForeName>Orlando Graziani Povoas</ForeName><Initials>OGP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Neurology and Ataxia Unit, Department of Neurology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo-Escola Paulista de Medicina, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedroso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; Luiz</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Neurology and Ataxia Unit, Department of Neurology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo-Escola Paulista de Medicina, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mov Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-3185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Friedreich's ataxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phrenic nerve conduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spirometry</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41416841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.70162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kebschull JM, Casoni F, Consalez GG, et al. Cerebellum lecture: the cerebellar nuclei&#x2014;Core of the cerebellum. Cerebellum 2023;23(2):620&#x2013;677. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12311-022-01506-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinante E, Colombo E, Paparella G, Martinuzzi M, Martinuzzi A. Respiratory function in Friedreich's ataxia. Children 2022;9(9):1319. https://doi.org/10.3390/children9091319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campuzano V, Montermini L, Molt&#xf2; MD, et al. Friedreich's ataxia: autosomal recessive disease caused by an intronic GAA triplet repeat expansion. Science 1996;271(5254):1423&#x2013;1427. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.271.5254.1423</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook A, Giunti P. Friedreich's ataxia: clinical features, pathogenesis and management. Br Med Bull 2017;124(1):19&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1093/bmb/ldx034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrah&#xe3;o A, Pedroso JL, Braga&#x2010;Neto P, Bor&#x2010;Seng&#x2010;Shu E, de Carvalho Aguiar P, Barsottini OGP. Milestones in Friedreich ataxia: more than a century and still learning. Neurogenetics 2015;16(3):151&#x2013;160. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10048-015-0439-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezende Filho FM, Vale TC, Pedroso JL, Braga&#x2010;Neto P, Barsottini OG. Facial grimacing and clinical correlates in spinocerebellar ataxia type 3. J Neurol Sci 2019;397:138&#x2013;140. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2019.01.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado DS, Viana CF, Pedroso JL, et al. Prevalence and diagnostic journey of Friedreich's ataxia in the state of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. Cerebellum 2024;23(5):1916&#x2013;1922. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12311-024-01687-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bureau MA, Ngassam P, Lemieux B, Trias A. Pulmonary function studies in Friedreich's ataxia. Can J Neurol Sci 1976;3(4):343&#x2013;347. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0317167100025579</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsou AY, Paulsen EK, Lagedrost SJ, et al. Mortality in Friedreich ataxia. J Neurol Sci 2011;307(1&#x2013;2):46&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2011.05.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reetz K, Lischewski SA, Dogan I, et al. Friedreich's ataxia&#x2014;a rare multisystem disease. Lancet Neurol 2025;24(7):614&#x2013;624. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(25)00175-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rummey C, Flynn JM, Corben LA, et al. Scoliosis in Friedreich's ataxia: longitudinal characterization in a large heterogeneous cohort. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2021;8(6):1239&#x2013;1250. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon AL, Meyblum J, Roche B, et al. Scoliosis in patients with Friedreich ataxia: results of a consecutive prospective series. Spine Deformity 2019;7(5):812&#x2013;821. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jspd.2019.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reetz K, Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Labrada R, Dogan I, et al. Brain atrophy measures in preclinical and manifest spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2018;5(2):128&#x2013;137. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delatycki MB, Corben LA. Clinical features of Friedreich ataxia. J Child Neurol 2012;27(9):1133&#x2013;1137. https://doi.org/10.1177/0883073812448230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corben LA, Collins V, Milne S, et al. Clinical management guidelines for Friedreich ataxia: best practice in rare diseases. Orphanet J Rare Dis 2022;17(1):415. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-022-02568-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu F, Frazier DT. Role of the cerebellar deep nuclei in respiratory modulation. Cerebellum 2002;1(1):35&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1080/147342202753203078</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga&#x2010;Neto P, Godeiro&#x2010;Junior C, Dutra LA, Pedroso JL, Barsottini OGP. Translation and validation into Brazilian version of the Scale of the Assessment and Rating of Ataxia (SARA). Arq Neuropsiquiatr 2010;68(2):228&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.1590/S0004-282X2010000200014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira CADC, Sato T, Rodrigues SC. Novos valores de refer&#xea;ncia para espirometria for&#xe7;ada em brasileiros adultos de ra&#xe7;a branca. J Bras Pneumol 2007;33(4):397&#x2013;406. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1806-37132007000400008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, et al. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur Respir J 2019;53:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albuquerque ALPD, Berton DC, Campos EVMF&#xc1;S, et al. New spirometry recommendations from the Brazilian Thoracic Association &#x2013; 2024 update. J Bras Pneumol 2024;e20240169. https://doi.org/10.36416/1806-3756/50(6):e20240169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neder JA, Andreoni S, Lerario MC, Nery LE. Reference values for lung function tests: II. Maximal respiratory pressures and voluntary ventilation. Braz J Med Biol Res 1999;32(6):719&#x2013;727. https://doi.org/10.1590/S0100-879X1999000600007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black LF, Hyatt RE. Maximal static respiratory pressures in generalized neuromuscular disease. Am Rev Respir Dis 1971;103(5):641&#x2013;650. https://doi.org/10.1164/arrd.1971.103.5.641</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo PRS, Resqueti VR, Nascimento JJ, et al. Valores de refer&#xea;ncia da press&#xe3;o inspirat&#xf3;ria nasal em indiv&#xed;duos saud&#xe1;veis no Brasil: estudo multic&#xea;ntrico. J Bras Pneumol 2012;38(6):700&#x2013;707. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1806-37132012000600004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedini M, Froutan R, Bagheri Moghaddam A, Mazloum S. Comparison of &#x201c;cough peak expiratory flow measurement&#x201d; and &#x201c;cough strength measurement using the white card test&#x201d; in extubation success: a randomized controlled trial. J Res Med Sci 2020;25(1):52. https://doi.org/10.4103/jrms.JRMS_939_19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR. Management of Patients with Neuromuscular Disease. Philadelphia, PA: Hanley &amp; Belfus; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilozni D, Lavie M, Sarouk I, Levi Y, Alcaneses Ofek MR, Efrati O. Cough ability measurements and recurrent respiratory symptoms in individuals with ataxia telangiectasia. J Asthma 2016;53(1):37&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.3109/02770903.2015.1032304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston DC, Shapiro BE. Electromyography and Neuromuscular Disorders: Clinical&#x2010;Electrophysiologic&#x2010;Ultrasound Correlations. Fourth ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatehi F, Grapperon A&#x2010;M, Fathi D, Delmont E, Attarian S. The utility of motor unit number index: a systematic review. Neurophysiol Clin 2018;48(5):251&#x2013;259. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neucli.2018.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Nandedkar S, St&#xe5;lberg E, et al. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): a novel neurophysiological marker for neuromuscular disorders; test&#x2013;retest reliability in healthy volunteers. Clin Neurophysiol 2011;122(9):1867&#x2013;1872. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2011.02.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Braun N, Claeys KG, et al. Implementing motor unit number index (MUNIX) in a large clinical trial: real world experience from 27 centres. Clin Neurophysiol 2018;129(8):1756&#x2013;1762. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2018.04.614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra ML, Abrahao A, Santos&#x2010;Neto D, de Oliveira Braga NI, Oliveira ASB, Manzano GM. Why averaging multiple MUNIX measures in the longitudinal assessment of patients with ALS? Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128(12):2392&#x2013;2396. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2017.09.104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra ML, Abrahao A, de Castro I, et al. MUNIX: reproducibility and clinical correlations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2016;127(9):2979&#x2013;2984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, St&#xc5;lberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): principle, method, and findings in healthy subjects and in patients with motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve 2010;42(5):798&#x2013;807. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.21824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrieri MC, Miranda B, Gromicho M, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Reliability of phrenic nerve conduction study: in healthy controls and in patients with primary lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131(5):994&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yetki&#x307;n NA, Yetki&#x307;N MF, Ketenci&#x307;O&#x11f;lu BB, et al. Evaluation of diaphragm functions with diaphragm ultrasound and pulmonary function tests in individuals with Friedreich's ataxia. Turk J Med Sci 2023;53(5):1301&#x2013;1311. https://doi.org/10.55730/1300-0144.5696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana CF, Jaques CS, Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra ML, Pedroso JL, Barsottini OGP. Respiratory evaluation in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Cerebellum 2025;24(4):98. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12311-025-01845-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas DD, El Haddad L, Sethi R, et al. Neuro&#x2010;respiratory pathology in spinocerebellar ataxia. J Neurol Sci 2022;443:120493. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2022.120493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mello NM, Zonta MB, Teive HAG, et al. Assessment of ventilatory function in patients with spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Arq Neuropsiquiatr 2020;78(2):96&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriranjini SJ, Pal PK, Krishna N, Sathyaprabha TN. Subclinical pulmonary dysfunction in spinocerebellar ataxias 1, 2 and 3. Acta Neurol Scand 2010;122:323&#x2013;328. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2009.01306.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso P, Albuquerque ALPD, Santana PV, et al. Diagnostic methods to assess inspiratory and expiratory muscle strength. J Bras Pneumol 2015;41(2):110&#x2013;123. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1806-37132015000004474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;b U, Brunt ER, Petrasch&#x2010;Parwez E, et al. Degeneration of ingestion&#x2010;related brainstem nuclei in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2, 3, 6 and 7. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2006;32(6):635&#x2013;649. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2990.2006.00772.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keage MJ, Delatycki MB, Gupta I, Corben LA, Vogel AP. Dysphagia in Friedreich ataxia. Dysphagia 2017;32(5):626&#x2013;635. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-017-9804-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folker JE, Murdoch BE, Rosen KM, et al. Differentiating profiles of speech impairments in Friedreich's ataxia: a perceptual and instrumental approach. Intl J Lang Commun Disord 2012;47(1):65&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-6984.2011.00078.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cisn&#xe9;ros E, Braun CM. Diadococin&#xe9;sies vocales et respiratoires dans l'ataxie de friedreich et leurs corr&#xe9;lats neuropathologiques. Rev Neurol (Paris) 1995;151(2):113&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCool FD, Tzelepis GE. Dysfunction of the diaphragm. N Engl J Med 2012;366(10):932&#x2013;942. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1007236</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;rk K. Friedreich ataxia: current status and future prospects. Cerebellum Ataxias 2017;4:4. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40673-017-0062-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlman SL. Symptomatic and disease&#x2010;modifying therapy for the progressive ataxias. Neurologist 2004;10(5):275&#x2013;289. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.nrl.0000141651.35193.67</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi D, Neuwirth C, Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra ML, et al. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): updated technical standards from the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology and the European Academy of Neurology. Clin Neurophysiol Pract 2023;8:90&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cnp.2023.01.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyronnard JM, Lapointe L, Bouchard JP, Lamontagne A, Lemieux B, Barbeau A. Quebec cooperative study of Friedreich's ataxia: nerve conduction studies and electromyography in Friedreich's ataxia. Can J Neurol Sci 1976;3(4):313&#x2013;317. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0317167100025518</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen BK, Pandit A. Phrenic nerve conduction study in the early stage of Guillain&#x2013;Barre syndrome as a predictor of respiratory failure. Ann Indian Acad Neurol 2018;21:57&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.4103/aian.AIAN_345_17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrah&#xe3;o A, Phung L, Fam D, et al. Motor unit number index of the upper trapezius: a meta&#x2010;analysis and cross&#x2010;sectional study of its reliability. Can J Neurol Sci 2024;51:129&#x2013;133. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2023.20</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>