<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41599483</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determination of Mechanical Properties of Single and Double-Layer Intraply Hybrid Composites Manufactured by Hand Lay-Up Method.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">188</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym18020188</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study experimentally evaluates the mechanical and microstructural performance of single- and double-layer intraply hybrid composite (IRC) laminates produced using the hand lay-up method, focusing on Glass-Aramid (GA), Aramid-Carbon (AC), and Carbon-Glass (CG) configurations. Tensile, flexural, compressive, and density tests were conducted in accordance with relevant ASTM standards to assess the influence of hybrid type and layer number under field-representative manufacturing conditions. Microstructural investigations were performed using optical microscopy and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) to identify fabrication-induced imperfections and their relationship to mechanical behavior. The results demonstrate that increasing the laminate configuration from single to double layer significantly enhances mechanical performance across all hybrid types. Double-layer AC laminates exhibited the highest tensile strength (330.4 MPa) and Young's modulus (11.93 GPa), corresponding to improvements of approximately 85% and 59%, respectively, compared to single-layer counterparts. In flexural loading, the highest strength was observed in double-layer CG laminates (97.14 MPa), while compressive strength was maximized in double-layer AC laminates (34.01 MPa), indicating improved stability and resistance to compression-driven failure. Statistical analysis confirmed that layer number is the dominant parameter governing mechanical response, exceeding the influence of hybrid configuration alone. Microstructural observations revealed fiber misorientation, incomplete resin impregnation, and localized voids inherent to manual fabrication. However, these imperfections were consistently distributed across all specimens and did not obscure comparative mechanical trends. Coefficients of variation generally remained below 10%, indicating acceptable repeatability despite non-ideal manufacturing conditions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shams</LastName><ForeName>Mohsen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0047-7899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Gebze Technical University, 41400 Kocaeli, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cakir</LastName><ForeName>Ferit</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9641-2004</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Gebze Technical University, 41400 Kocaeli, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SEM analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fiber-reinforced polymers (FRP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand lay-up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intraply hybrid composites (IRC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructural characterization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Ferit Cakir is owner of SFO Engineering and Consultancy CO. The authors declare that this study received funding from SFO Engineering and Consultancy CO. The funder was not involved in the study design, collection, analysis, interpretation of data, the writing of this article or the decision to submit it for publication. The remaining author declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41599483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym18020188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym18020188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cakir F., Acar V., Aydin M.R., Aksar B., Yildirim P. Strengthening of reinforced concrete beams without transverse reinforcement by using intraply hybrid composites. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2021;15:e00700. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin M.R., Acar V., Cakir F., Gundogdu O. Effect of manufacturing parameters on low-velocity impact behavior of aramid, carbon and glass fiber reinforced polymer composites using Taguchi Experimental Design. Appl. Compos. Mater. 2025;32:849&#x2013;877. doi: 10.1007/s10443-024-10298-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10443-024-10298-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin M.R. A comprehensive experimental and numerical analysis on free vibration and axial buckling behavior of hybrid composites. Fibers Polym. 2025;26:4069&#x2013;4086. doi: 10.1007/s12221-025-01071-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12221-025-01071-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raci Aydin M., Acar V., Cakir F., G&#xfc;ndo&#x11f;du &#xd6;., Akbulut H. Comparative dynamic analysis of carbon, aramid and glass fiber reinforced interply and intraply hybrid composites. Compos. Struct. 2022;291:115595. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2022.115595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2022.115595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakir F., Raci Aydin M., Acar V., Aksar B., Cem Akkaya H. An experimental study on RC beams shear-strengthened with intraply hybrid U-Jackets Composites monitored by Digital Image Correlation (DIC) Compos. Struct. 2023;323:117503. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2023.117503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2023.117503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakir F., Aydin M.R., Acar V., Yildirim P. Impact of hybrid and non-hybrid fiber reinforced polymers on mechanical performance of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;451:138806. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altaee M.A., Mostafa N.H. Mechanical properties of interply and intraply hybrid laminates based on jute-glass/epoxy composites. J. Eng. Appl. Sci. 2023;70:121. doi: 10.1186/s44147-023-00293-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44147-023-00293-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junaedi H., Sebaey T.A. Carbon-aramid fiber/epoxy hybrid composite laminates with the presence of defect: An experimental study. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2024;2805:012008. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2805/1/012008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2805/1/012008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal P., Bundela A.S., Choudhary P., Pai Y., Pai D.G. Effect of carbon-kevlar intraply surface layers on the mechanical and vibrational properties of basalt reinforced polymer composites. Cogent Eng. 2024;11:2403704. doi: 10.1080/23311916.2024.2403704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311916.2024.2403704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M.Z., Amiri A., Ulven C.A. Fatigue behavior comparison of inter-ply and intra-ply hybrid flax-carbon fiber reinforced polymer matrix composites. J. Compos. Sci. 2021;5:184. doi: 10.3390/jcs5070184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcs5070184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Norton M., Joosten M.W. Investigating the mode one interlaminar performance of semi-woven 3D printed hybrid composites. Compos. Struct. 2025;354:118802. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2024.118802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2024.118802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu P., Zhang H., Sfarra S., Sarasini F., Usamentiaga R., Steenackers G., Ibarra-Castanedo C., Maldague X. A comprehensive evaluation of the low-velocity impact behaviour of intraply hybrid flax/basalt composites using infrared thermography and terahertz time-domain spectroscopy techniques. NDT E Int. 2025;154:103361. doi: 10.1016/j.ndteint.2025.103361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ndteint.2025.103361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbek &#xd6;., O&#x11f;uz Z.A., Bozkurt &#xd6;.Y., Erkli&#x11f; A. Crashworthiness characteristics of hydrothermally aged intraply glass/basalt composite pipes. Mar. Struct. 2024;97:103656. doi: 10.1016/j.marstruc.2024.103656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marstruc.2024.103656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyaguru S., Thiagamani S.M., Krishnasamy S., Muthukumar C., Siengchin S., Hashem M., Fouad H. Experimental investigation on the thermal characteristics of Kevlar/hemp intraply hybrid composites: Influence of various weaving designs. Ind. Crops Prod. 2024;221:119280. doi: 10.1016/j.indcrop.2024.119280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2024.119280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim N., Majid D.L., Mahdi E.-S., Zahari R., Yidris N. Effect of fiber loading directions on the low cycle fatigue of intraply carbon-kevlar reinforced epoxy hybrid composites. Compos. Struct. 2019;212:476&#x2013;483. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2019.01.036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2019.01.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brands D., Haanappel S.P., Grouve W.J.B., Wijskamp S., Akkerman R. Critical evaluation of torsion rheometry to characterize the anisotropic intraply shear resistance of unidirectional thermoplastic composites in melt. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2025;190:108661. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong C. Carbon and glass fibre-reinforced hybrid composites in flexure. Hybrid Adv. 2025;10:100471. doi: 10.1016/j.hybadv.2025.100471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hybadv.2025.100471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Zhang L., Liu X., Dong X., Yang L., Wu Z., Wang Z., Dong S. Basalt flake/epoxy resin nacre-inspired bulk composite fabricated by vacuum-assisted resin transfer molding technique. Mater. Lett. 2025;384:138122. doi: 10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar U.S., Chavan S.S., Mohite D.D., Thorat Y.V. Development of lightweight and high-strength natural fiber hybrid composites using vacuum-assisted resin transfer molding process. Mater. Today Proc. 2024. in press .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoresta F.S., Nhut P.V., Nakamoto D., Matsumoto Y. Enhancing buckling capacity of angle steel using unbonded CFRP laminates processed by vacuum-assisted resin transfer molding (VaRTM) Structures. 2022;41:173&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2022.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2022.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abusrea M.R., Han S.-W., Arakawa K., Choi N.-S. Bending strength of CFRP laminated adhesive joints fabricated by vacuum-assisted resin transfer molding. Compos. Part B Eng. 2019;156:8&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.08.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.08.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasudevan A., Kumar B.N., Depoures M.V., Maridurai T., Mohanavel V. Tensile and flexural behaviour of glass fibre reinforced plastic&#x2013;aluminium hybrid laminate manufactured by vacuum resin transfer moulding technique (VARTM) Mater. Today Proc. 2021;37:2132&#x2013;2140. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.07.573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.07.573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toldy A., Pom&#xe1;zi &#xc1;., Szolnoki B. The effect of manufacturing technologies on the flame retardancy of carbon fibre reinforced epoxy resin composites. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2020;174:109094. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2020.109094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2020.109094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajjar T., Shah D.B., Joshi S.J., Patel K.M. Carbon fiber permeability characterization using VARTM process. Mater. Today Proc. 2021;44:1560&#x2013;1563. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.11.775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.11.775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo S., Liang Y., Wu Y., Ge S., Shi J., Ma X., Cai L., Li J., Lam S.S., Xia C. Using environmentally friendly technology for fabricating special plywood with ultra-high strength. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;396:136462. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.136462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.136462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehkordi M.T., Nosraty H., Shokrieh M.M., Minak G., Ghelli D. Low velocity impact properties of intra-ply hybrid composites based on basalt and nylon woven fabrics. Mater. Des. 2010;31:3835&#x2013;3844. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2010.03.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2010.03.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Tensile Properties of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Methods for Flexural Properties of Unreinforced and Reinforced Plastics and Electrical Insulating Materials. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Compressive Properties of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials with Unsupported Gage Section by Shear Loading. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Methods for Density and Specific Gravity (Relative Density) of Plastics by Displacement. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>