<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41704457</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lignin phosphorylation to enhance mechanical and physical properties and reduce formaldehyde emissions in plywood panels.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9092</StartPage><EndPage>9107</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9092-9107</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d6ra00104a</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lignin is gaining more attention for its potential use in adhesives for wood-based composites owing to its accessibility, molecular structure, barrier properties, and potential for chemical modification. In order to assess the physical, thermal, and mechanical performances of alkaline lignin (AL) and its ability to reduce formaldehyde emissions in synthetic phenol formaldehyde (PF) adhesives used to glue plywood panels, AL was surface-modified by a phosphorylation treatment to produce phosphorylated alkali lignin. In this study, lignin was isolated from alkali-treated powdered argan shells and subsequently phosphorylated to obtain phosphorylated lignin (P-AL). The isolated lignin was characterized by two-dimensional (2D-<sup>1</sup>H and <sup>13</sup>C NMR) heteronuclear single quantum coherence (HSQC) spectra to confirm its successful isolation from argan shells. Both AL and P-AL were then subjected to a series of analytical techniques, including Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, scanning electron microscopy (SEM) with elemental mapping, X-ray fluorescence (XRF) spectrometry, phosphorus nuclear magnetic resonance (<sup>31</sup>P NMR) spectroscopy, conductimetric titration (to determine the phosphorylation rate), thermogravimetric and derivative thermogravimetric analysis (TGA/DTG) and X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis. Afterwards, P-AL was formulated with PF resin and applied to plywood panels, following characterizations to evaluate mechanical properties, such as bond strength (BS), modulus of rupture (MOR), modulus of elasticity (MOE), shear strength (SS), and formaldehyde emission (FE). Results showed that lignin phosphorylation had a significantly positive effect on plywood adhesion, especially in terms of FE, which decreased from 2.5 to 1.89 mg<sup>-1</sup> m<sup>-2</sup> h<sup>-1</sup>, while maintaining higher mechanical properties, including an MOE of 4144 MPa and an MOR of 66 MPa.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maarir</LastName><ForeName>Hafida</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Processes and Applied Materials Team, Polydisciplinary Faculty, Sultan Moulay Slimane University BP 592 Beni Mellal Morocco Hafida.maarir@usms.ac.ma a.moubarik@usms.ma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Khayat Driaa</LastName><ForeName>Yassine</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Processes and Applied Materials Team, Polydisciplinary Faculty, Sultan Moulay Slimane University BP 592 Beni Mellal Morocco Hafida.maarir@usms.ac.ma a.moubarik@usms.ma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de technologie de Compi&#xe8;gne, ESCOM, TIMR (Integrated Transformations of Renewable Matter), Centre de recherche Royallieu CS 60319 - 60203 Compi&#xe8;gne Cedex France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charii</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Chemistry, Biochemistry, Environment, Nutrition and Health Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, University Hassan II 20000 Casablanca Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boussetta</LastName><ForeName>Abdelghani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher School of Education and Training, Sultan Moulay Slimane University Beni-Mellal Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mennani</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Science, Energy and Nanoengineering (MSN) Department, Mohammed VI Polytechnic University Lot 660, Hay Moulay Rachid 43150 Ben Guerir Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimi</LastName><ForeName>Nabil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de technologie de Compi&#xe8;gne, ESCOM, TIMR (Integrated Transformations of Renewable Matter), Centre de recherche Royallieu CS 60319 - 60203 Compi&#xe8;gne Cedex France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moubarik</LastName><ForeName>Amine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5821-3218</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Processes and Applied Materials Team, Polydisciplinary Faculty, Sultan Moulay Slimane University BP 592 Beni Mellal Morocco Hafida.maarir@usms.ac.ma a.moubarik@usms.ma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41704457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12907796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d6ra00104a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d6ra00104a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Boussetta A. Benhamou A. A. Barba F. J. EL Idrissi M. Grimi N. Valorization of Solanum Elaeagnifolium Cavanilles Weeds as a New Lignocellulosic Source for the Formulation of Lignin-Urea-Formaldehyde Wood Adhesive. J. Adhes. 2023;99:34&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa N. A. Pereira J. Ferra J. Cruz P. Martins J. Magalh&#xe3;es F. D. Mendes A. Carvalho L. H. Scavengers for achieving zero formaldehyde emission of wood-based panels. Wood Sci. Technol. 2013;47:1261&#x2013;1272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawalerczyk J. Siuda J. Mirski R. Dziurka D. Hemp flour as a formaldehyde scavenger for melamine-urea-formaldehyde adhesive in plywood production. Bioresources. 2020;15:4052&#x2013;4064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmil&#xe4; V. Adamopoulos S. Karlsson O. Kumar A. Development of sustainable bio-adhesives for engineered wood panels-A Review. RSC Adv. 2017;7:38604&#x2013;38630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siahkamari M. Emmanuel S. Hodge D. B. Nejad M. Lignin-Glyoxal: A Fully Biobased Formaldehyde-Free Wood Adhesive for Interior Engineered Wood Products. ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2022;10:3430&#x2013;3441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawalerczyk J. Dziurka D. Mirski R. Grze&#x15b;kowiak W. The effect of veneer impregnation with a mixture of potassium carbonate and urea on the properties of manufactured plywood. Drewno. 2019;62:107&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziurka D. Mirski R. Svojstva teku&#x107;e i polikondenzirane UF smole modificirane s pMDI. Drvna Ind. 2014;65:115&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertella S. Luterbacher J. S. Lignin Functionalization for the Production of Novel Materials. Chem. 2020;2:440&#x2013;453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins D. Nuruddin M. Hosur M. Tcherbi-Narteh A. Jeelani S. Extraction and characterization of lignin from different biomass resources. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2015;4:26&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. J. Um B. H. Delignification from Geodae-Uksae1 using soda-pulping followed by evaluation on recycling of liquid-liquid extraction solvent. Biomass Bioenergy. 2018;109:23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen Thoresen P. Lange H. Crestini C. Rova U. Matsakas L. Christakopoulos P. Characterization of Organosolv Birch Lignins: Toward Application-Specific Lignin Production. ACS Omega. 2021;6:4374&#x2013;4385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33623848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y. Asada C. Sasaki C. Nakamura Y. Effects of Hydrothermal Methods such as Steam Explosion and Microwave Irradiation on Extraction of Water Soluble Antioxidant Materials from Garlic Husk. Waste Biomass Valoriz. 2019;10:3397&#x2013;3402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khayat Driaa Y. Maarir H. Mennani M. Grimi N. Moubarik A. Boussetta N. Ultrasound, pulsed electric fields, and high-voltage electrical discharges assisted extraction of cellulose and lignin from walnut shells. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;292:139319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39740712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S. Wu J. Q. Zhang Y. Yuan T. Q. Sun R. C. Preparation of lignin-phenol-formaldehyde resin adhesive based on active sites of technical lignin. J. Biobased Mater. Bioenergy. 2015;9:266&#x2013;272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L. Gao Q. Ding J. Xiong Z. Chen S. Li X. Li D. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;309:6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40180084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H. M. Wang B. Yuan T. Q. Zheng L. Shi Q. Wang S. F. Song G. Y. Sun R. C. Tunable, UV-shielding and biodegradable composites based on well-characterized lignins and poly(butylene adipate-: Co-Terephthalate) Green Chem. 2020;22:8623&#x2013;8632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z. Zeng J. Dong Z. Chen Y. Yang H. Chen H. Insight into the mechanism of lignin amination pretreatment on lignin structure and its pyrolysis property for lignin valorization. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;499:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X. Xiao L. P. Meng B. W. Li W. J. Sun R. C. Mechanochemical treatment boosted microwave-assisted sulfonation of softwood lignin for the fabrication of dye dispersant. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;512:162552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graglia M. Pampel J. Hantke T. Fellinger T. P. Esposito D. Nitro Lignin-Derived Nitrogen-Doped Carbon as an Efficient and Sustainable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction. ACS Nano. 2016;10:4364&#x2013;4371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26986215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieur B. Meub M. Wittemann M. Klein R. Bellayer S. Fontaine G. Bourbigot S. Phosphorylation of lignin: characterization and investigation of the thermal decomposition. RSC Adv. 2017;7:16866&#x2013;16877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>feng Lin C. Karlsson O. Myronycheva O. Das O. Mensah R. A. Mantanis G. I. Jones D. Antzutkin O. N. F&#xf6;rsth M. Sandberg D. Phosphorylated and carbamylated Kraft lignin for improving fire- and biological-resistance of Scots pine wood. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2024;276:133734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39002903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maarir H. Boussetta A. Charii H. El Y. Driaa K. Grimi N. Moubarik A. Phosphorylated lignin: recent advances in synthesis through chemical functionalization, structural properties , and emerging applications: a review. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2026;338:149691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41407234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieur B. Meub M. Wittemann M. Klein R. Bellayer S. Fontaine G. Bourbigot S. Phosphorylation of lignin to flame retard acrylonitrile butadiene styrene (ABS) Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2016;127:32&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W. Yuan H. Zhang P. Yang H. Song L. Hu Y. Functionalized lignin for halogen-free flame retardant rigid polyurethane foam: Preparation, thermal stability, fire performance and mechanical properties. J. Polym. Res. 2013;20:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charii H. Boussetta A. Benali K. Essifi K. Mennani M. Benhamou A. A. El Zakhem H. Sehaqui H. El Achaby M. Grimi N. Boutoial K. Ablouh E. H. Moubarik A. Phosphorylated chitin from shrimp shell waste: A robust solution for cadmium remediation. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2024;268:131855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38679259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhari T. Rajagopalan N. Dam-Johansen K. Lignin Phosphate: A Biobased Substitute for Zinc Phosphate in Corrosion-Inhibiting Coatings. ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2024;12:7813&#x2013;7830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bykov G. L. Ershov B. G. A sorbent based on phosphorylated lignin. Russ. J. Appl. Chem. 2010;83:316&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavijo L. Coniglio R. Berm&#xfa;dez F. Rodao J. M. Passarella D. Dieste A. Phenol &#x2013; Formaldehyde Adhesives Modified with Eucalyptus Lignin: The Advantages of Soda Lignin. Polymers. 2025;17:3319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12736474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41470994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paez J. Fatehi P. Incorporation of lignin into adhesives&#x202f;: a review. Green Chem. 2025;27:12499&#x2013;12537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anter N. Chennani A. Guida M. Dual-functionalized lignin as a sustainable modifier for high-performance phenol-formaldehyde adhesives in plywood production. RSC Adv. 2025;15:32118&#x2013;32130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12412671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40918316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moubarik A. Grimi N. Boussetta N. Pizzi A. Isolation and characterization of lignin from Moroccan sugar cane bagasse: Production of lignin-phenol-formaldehyde wood adhesive. Ind. Crops Prod. 2013;45:296&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koksharov S. Aleeva S. Lepilova O. Kalinin E. Kornilova N. How to transform lignin into a useful component of flax fiber for composite materials. Ind. Crops Prod. 2023;192:116088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. Song J. Feng Y. Cao Y. Fu B. Zhang Z. Ma N. Li Q. Hu T. Wang Y. Yang P. Osmotic stress-induced lignin synthesis is regulated at multiple levels in alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.) Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2023;246:125501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37348591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L. Larsson A. Moldin A. Edlund U. Comparison of lignin distribution, structure, and morphology in wheat straw and wood. Ind. Crops Prod. 2022;187:115432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charrouf Z. Guillaume D. Argan oil: Occurrence, composition and impact on human health. Eur. J. Lipid Sci. Technol. 2008;110:632&#x2013;636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursoniu S. Sahebkar A. Serban M. C. Banach M. The impact of argan oil on plasma lipids in humans: Systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phytother Res. 2018;32:377&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29130532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iswanto A. H. Manurung H. Sohail A. Hua L. S. Antov P. Nawawi D. S. Latifah S. Kayla D. S. Kusumah S. S. Lubis M. A. R. Osvaldov&#xe1; L. M. Hussin M. H. Selvasembian R. Chen L. W. Nurcahyani P. R. Kim N. H. Fatriasari W. Thermo-Mechanical, Physico-Chemical, Morphological, and Fire Characteristics of Eco-Friendly Particleboard Manufactured with Phosphorylated Lignin Addition. J. Renewable Mater. 2024;12:1311&#x2013;1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boussetta A. Benhamou A. A. Barba F. J. El Idrissi M. Grimi N. Moubarik A. Valorization of Solanum Elaeagnifolium Cavanilles Weeds as a New Lignocellulosic Source for the Formulation of Lignin-Urea-Formaldehyde Wood Adhesive. J. Adhes. 2023;99:34&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maarir H. El Y. Driaa K. Charii H. Boussetta A. Grimi N. Moubarik A. International Journal of Adhesion and Adhesives Argan shell-derived phosphorylated lignocellulose : A sustainable pathway in wood adhesive formulation. Int. J. Adhes. Adhes. 2026;145:104212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait Benhamou A. Kassab Z. Nadifiyine M. Salim M. H. Sehaqui H. Moubarik A. El Achaby M. Extraction, characterization and chemical functionalization of phosphorylated cellulose derivatives from Giant Reed Plant. Cellulose. 2021;28:4625&#x2013;4642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charii H. Boussetta A. Ait Benhamou A. Mennani M. Essifi K. Ablouh E. H. EL Zakhem H. Grimi N. Boutoial K. Moubarik A. Exploring the potential of chitin and chitosan extracted from shrimp shell waste in enhancing urea-formaldehyde wood adhesives. Int. J. Adhes. Adhes. 2024;129:103599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moubarik A. Barba F. J. Grimi N. Understanding the physicochemical properties of olive kernel to be used as a potential tool in the development of phenol-formaldehyde wood adhesive. Int. J. Adhes. Adhes. 2015;61:122&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait Benhamou A. Boussetta A. Kassab Z. Nadifiyine M. Hamid Salim M. Grimi N. EL Achaby M. Moubarik A. Investigating the characteristics of cactus seeds by-product and their use as a new filler in phenol formaldehyde wood adhesive. Int. J. Adhes. Adhes. 2021;110:102940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moubarik A. Pizzi A. Allal A. Charrier F. Charrier B. Cornstarch and tannin in phenol-formaldehyde resins for plywood production. Ind. Crops Prod. 2009;30:188&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro F. Bigando R. Ruffinatto F. Zanuttini R. Technical Assessment of the Bonding Quality of Composite Plywood with a Thin Cork Core. Forests. 2022;13:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EN 310, European Norm. Wood-based panels: Determination of bending strength and modulus of elasticity, European Committee for Standardization, 1993</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa A. H. Madduluri V. R. Roslan R. Rahim H. A. Lignin extractions from oil palm empty fruit bunch under pressurized and inert conditions. Int. J. Chem. Biochem. Sci. 2024;25:158&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moubarik A. Grimi N. Boussetta N. Pizzi A. Isolation and characterization of lignin from Moroccan sugar cane bagasse : Production of lignin &#x2013; phenol-formaldehyde wood adhesive. Ind. Crops Prod. 2013;45:296&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusmirovi&#x107; J., Dani&#x10d;i&#x107; D., Kova&#x10d;evi&#x107; T., Bogosavljevi&#x107; M., Brzi&#x107; S., Marinkovi&#x107; A. and Stevanovi&#x107; T., Phosphorylated kraft lignin based flame retardant: Efficient method for improvement of lignin flame retardancy and mechanical action in polyester, 8th International Scientific Conference of Defensive Technologies, VTI-Belgrade, 2018, pp. , pp. 538&#x2013;543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S. Zhao Z. Umemura K. Further exploration of sucrose-citric acid adhesive: Synthesis and application on plywood. Polymers. 2019;11:1875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6918132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31766262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y. Fu S. Song P. Luo X. Jin Y. Lu F. Wu Q. Ye J. Functionalized lignin by grafting phosphorus-nitrogen improves the thermal stability and flame retardancy of polypropylene. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2012;97:541&#x2013;546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charii H. Benali K. Boussetta A. Ouaddari A. E. L. Ablouh E. H. Grimi N. Ibenmoussa S. Moubarik A. Enhancing adhesive properties with unmodified and phosphate-modified chitin in particleboard production. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;311:144025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40345280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chollet B. Lopez-Cuesta J. M. Laoutid F. Ferry L. Lignin nanoparticles as a promising way for enhancing lignin flame retardant effect in polylactide. Materials. 2019;12:2132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31269752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukind S. Bouaouina J. Bouras H. Ait A. Ablouh E. Kassab Z. Khouloud M. El M. Sehaqui H. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules Powerful cellulose phosphorylation by fertilizer-grade phosphate enables excellensorbentt methylene blue paper. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2022;219:949&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podko&#x15b;cielna B. Wnuczek K. Goliszek M. Klepka T. Dziuba K. Flammability Tests and Investigations of Properties of Lignin-Containing Polymer Composites Based on Acrylates. Molecules. 2020;25:5947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W. Feng Y. Lu J. Khan M. Guo J. Biomimetic surface modification of polycarbonateurethane film via phosphorylcholine-graft for resisting platelet adhesion. Macromol. Res. 2012;20:1063&#x2013;1069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bykov G. L. Ershov B. G. Sorption of uranyl ions on phosphorylated lignin. Radiochemistry. 2009;51:292&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadhoni B. Rifathin A. Yuliati F. Phosphorylation of Alkaline Lignin in Methanesulfonic Acid Solvent and the Use thereof as Flame Retardant of Epoxy. J. Inst. Eng. (India): Ser. D. 2024;105:1695&#x2013;1702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozano-Peral D. Arango-D&#xed;az A. Mart&#xed;n-de-las-Heras S. Rubio L. Thermogravimetric analysis of teeth for forensic purposes. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2020;139:1121&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S. Song L. Hu Y. Preparation and Characterization of Chitosan-Based Flame Retardant and Its Thermal and Combustible Behavior on Polyvinyl Alcohol. Polym. Plast. Technol. Eng. 2013;52:393&#x2013;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonino L. D. Gouveia J. R. de Sousa J&#xfa;nior R. R. Garcia G. E. S. Gobbo L. C. Tavares L. B. Dos Santos D. J. Reactivity of aliphatic and phenolic hydroxyl groups in kraft lignin towards 4,4&#x2032; mdi. Molecules. 2021;26:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illy N. Fache M. M&#xe9;nard R. Negrell C. Caillol S. David G. Phosphorylation of bio-based compounds: The state of the art. Polym. Chem. 2015;6:6257&#x2013;6291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C. Zhou L. Yao S. Qin C. Fatehi P. Phosphorylated kraft lignin with improved thermal stability. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2020;162:1642&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melro E. Antunes F. E. Valente A. J. M. Duarte H. Romano A. Medronho B. On the Development of Phenol-Formaldehyde Resins Using a New Type of Lignin Extracted from Pine Wood with a Levulinic-Acid Based Solvent. Molecules. 2022;27:2825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9105709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35566176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younesi-Kordkheili H. Pizzi A. Properties of plywood panels bonded with ionic liquid-modified lignin&#x2013;phenol&#x2013;formaldehyde resin. J. Adhes. 2018;94:143&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>