<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41925039</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5687</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of gastroenterology &amp; hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of home-based exercise in patients with sarcopenia complicated by liver cirrhosis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MEG.0000000000003188</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Sarcopenia is a common complication in patients with liver cirrhosis and is associated with reduced quality of life and poor prognosis. Exercise and nutritional therapy are recommended; however, their efficacy in patients with cirrhosis-associated sarcopenia remains unclear. This study evaluated the efficacy and safety of a home-based exercise program in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective, single-arm study, 20 patients with cirrhosis and sarcopenia underwent a 12-week home-based program combining elastic band resistance training, walking, and nutritional therapy. The primary outcome was a change in 6-m walking speed at a normal pace. Secondary outcomes included handgrip strength, skeletal muscle index, short physical performance battery (SPPB) score, adherence, and safety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Seventeen participants completed the intervention. In the overall cohort, no significant improvements were observed in the walking speed, handgrip strength, skeletal muscle index, or SPPB score. In an exploratory post-hoc analysis of participants with greater than or equal to 80% adherence (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;12), improvements were observed in handgrip strength (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.034) and SPPB score (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.016), with a trend toward improved walking speed (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.077). Factors associated with high adherence included better lower limb function and a lower prevalence of severe sarcopenia. No serious exercise-related adverse events were observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The 12-week home-based exercise and nutritional intervention did not demonstrate clinically meaningful improvements in the overall cohort. Exploratory post-hoc analyses suggest potential functional benefits among participants with high adherence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugiyama</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiaki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Komaki City Hospital, Komaki.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishizu</LastName><ForeName>Yoji</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Shinya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Kenta</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Takanori</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imai</LastName><ForeName>Norihiro</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamura</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishikawa</LastName><ForeName>Takuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furukawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Honda</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawashima</LastName><ForeName>Hiroki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-691X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver cirrhosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41925039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MEG.0000000000003188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042737-990000000-00686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tandon P, Montano-Loza AJ, Lai JC, Dasarathy S, Merli M. Sarcopenia and frailty in decompensated cirrhosis. J Hepatol 2021; 75:S147&#x2013;S162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantai X, Liu Y, Yeo YH, Praktiknjo M, Mauro E, Hamaguchi Y, et al. Effect of sarcopenia on survival in patients with cirrhosis: a meta-analysis. J Hepatol 2022; 76:588&#x2013;599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando Y, Ishigami M, Ito T, Ishizu Y, Kuzuya T, Honda T, et al. Sarcopenia impairs health-related quality of life in cirrhotic patients. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2019; 31:1550&#x2013;1556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Rojo A, Ruiz-Marg&#xe1;in A, Monta&#xf1;o-Loza AJ, Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez RU, Ferrando A, Kim WR. Exercise and physical activity for patients with end-stage liver disease: improving functional status and sarcopenia while on the transplant waiting list. Liver Transpl 2018; 24:122&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon P, Ismond KP, Riess K, Duarte-Rojo A, Al-Judaibi B, Dunn MA, et al. Exercise in cirrhosis: translating evidence and experience to practice. J Hepatol 2018; 69:1164&#x2013;1177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung TW, Chou MY, Iijima K, et al. Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2020; 21:300&#x2013;307.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merli M, Berzigotti A, Zelber-Sagi S, Dasarathy S, Montagnese S, Genton L, et al. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines on nutrition in chronic liver disease. J Hepatol 2019; 70:172&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenith L, Meena N, Ramadi A, Yavari M, Harvey A, Carbonneau M, et al. Eight weeks of exercise training increases aerobic capacity and muscle mass and reduces fatigue in patients with cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2014; 12:1920&#x2013;1926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda Y. Investigation of the freely available easy-to-use software &#x2018;EZR&#x2019; for medical statistics. Bone Marrow Transplant 2013; 48:452&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger C, McNeely ML, Bailey RJ, Yavari M, Abraldes JG, Carbonneau M, et al. Home exercise training improves exercise capacity in cirrhosis patients: role of exercise adherence. Sci Rep 2018; 8:99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes JSS, Machado AF, Micheletti JK, de Almeida AC, Cavina AP, Pastre CM. Corrigendum to &#x201c;effects of training with elastic resistance versus conventional resistance on muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis&#x201d;. SAGE Open Med 2020; 8:2050312120961220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikesky AE, Topp R, Wigglesworth JK, Harsha DM, Edwards JE. Efficacy of a home-based training program for older adults using elastic tubing. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 1994; 69:316&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li A, Sun Y, Li M, Wang D, Ma X. Effects of elastic band resistance training on the physical and mental health of elderly individuals: a mixed methods systematic review. PLoS One 2024; 19:e0303372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fosstveit SH, Lohne-Seiler H, Feron J, Lucas SJE, Ivarsson A, Berntsen S. The intensity paradox: a systematic review and meta-analysis of its impact on the cardiorespiratory fitness of older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2024; 34:e14573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao W, Sun Y, Zhang T, Zou L, Wu X, Wang D, Chen Z. Exercise programs for muscle mass, muscle strength and physical performance in older adults with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Aging Dis 2020; 11:863&#x2013;873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair M, Chapman B, Hoermann R, Angus PW, Testro A, Scodellaro T, Gow PJ. Handgrip strength adds more prognostic value to the model for end-stage liver disease score than imaging-based measures of muscle mass in men with cirrhosis. Liver Transpl 2019; 25:1480&#x2013;1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansano-Nadal O, Gin&#xe9;-Garriga M, Brach JS, Wert DM, Jerez-Roig J, Guerra-Balic M, et al. Exercise-based interventions to enhance long-term sustainability of physical activity in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2019; 16:2527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubans DR, Sheaman C, Callister R. Exercise adherence and intervention effects of two school-based resistance training programs for adolescents. Prev Med 2010; 50:56&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai JC, Dodge JL, Kappus MR, Wong R, Mohamad Y, Segev DL, McAdams-DeMarco M. A multicenter pilot randomized clinical trial of a home-based exercise program for patients with cirrhosis: the strength training intervention (STRIVE). Am J Gastroenterol 2021; 116:717&#x2013;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro MA, Martins MA, Carvalho CR. The role of physician counseling in improving adherence to physical activity among the general population. Sao Paulo Med J 2007; 125:115&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutzer KA, Graves BS. Barriers and motivations to exercise in older adults. Prev Med 2004; 39:1056&#x2013;1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewsey SC, Weiss K, Sch&#xe4;r M, Zhang Y, Bottomley PA, Samuel TJ, et al. Exercise intolerance and rapid skeletal muscle energetic decline in human age-associated frailty. JCI Insight 2020; 5:e141246.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>