<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41708500</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9774</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Computers, informatics, nursing : CIN</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Comput Inform Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Knowledge, Skills, and Attitudes of Nursing Students Toward Artificial Intelligence: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001415</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study mapped the scientific evidence on the knowledge, skills, and attitudes of nursing students regarding artificial intelligence (AI), analyzing trends, challenges, and curricular opportunities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a scoping review conducted according to the Joanna Briggs Institute methodology, with a protocol registered in the Open Science Framework and reported following the PRISMA-ScR extension. The search strategy included 6 sources of information, as well as gray literature, covering publications without language or year restrictions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The findings from the 51 analyzed studies showed a significant increase in publications in recent years, with 2024 accounting for 45.1% of the materials. Most studies were published in English (96.1%), with the United States leading (23.5%). Students demonstrated general knowledge about artificial intelligence and positive attitudes toward its use but faced gaps in practical experience and ethical training. Tools such as chatbots and virtual reality proved effective in developing technical and psychosocial skills, including clinical reasoning, decision-making, and empathy. However, barriers such as inadequate infrastructure, high costs, and cultural resistance still hinder the widespread implementation of these technologies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It is concluded that artificial intelligence offers significant opportunities for nursing education, requiring educational strategies that promote digital literacy, ethical debates, and the curricular integration of technological tools.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junior</LastName><ForeName>Waldecy Lopes</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5948-0633</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing at the Federal University of Alfenas; and Nursing Graduate Program at the Federal University of Alfenas; Integrative Community Therapist Certified by the CAIFCOM/ABRATECOM Institute, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madeira</LastName><ForeName>Isadora De Lima</ForeName><Initials>IL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3634-3728</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Federal University of Alfenas; and Coronel Ant&#xf4;nio Domingos Ribeiro State Schoolzil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do Nascimento</LastName><ForeName>Francini Castilha</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7860-0493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing at the Federal University of Alfenas; Nursing Graduate Program at the Federal University of Alfenas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Da Silva</LastName><ForeName>P&#xe2;mela Cristina Martins</ForeName><Initials>PCM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-5038-8113</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing from the Federal University of Alfenas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terra</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio De Souza</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8322-3039</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Alfenas; Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto School of Nursing at the University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (EERP/USP); Jos&#xe9; do Ros&#xe1;rio Vellano University;. Undergraduate Nursing Program, the Graduate Program in Nursing at the Master's and Doctoral levels, and the Residency Programs (Obstetric Nursing and Multiprofessional Family Health), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do Nascimento</LastName><ForeName>Murilo C&#xe9;sar</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3436-2654</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Alfenas (UNIFAL-MG); UNIFAL-MG (2007), a specialization in Occupational Nursing; and Community Health from the Department of Social Medicine at the Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto Medical School, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (USP); Faculty member in the Graduate Program in Nursing (PPGENF); Health Care Network Management Within the Brazilian Unified Health System (SUS) and Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto School of Nursing, USP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle Cristinne Pinto</ForeName><Initials>ICP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2611-8643</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Para&#xed;ba (UFPB); Palliative Care and Pain, and Public Health; Federal University of Alfenas (UNIFAL-MG); Graduate Program in Nursing at UNIFAL-MG; Faculty member of the Obstetric Residency Program at UNIFAL-MG, and Palliative Care Specialization Program at CCS/UFPB.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Comput Inform Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101141667</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1538-2931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subject headings</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41708500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00024665-990000000-00483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almeida JR de. Artificial Intelligence and Nursing Education: A New Educational Paradigm [dissertation]. Belo Horizonte, MG: Federal University of Minas Gerais; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Parliament. Directorate General for Parliamentary Research Services. Artificial intelligence: how does it work, why does it matter, and what we can do about it? LU Publications Office; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartneck C, L&#xfc;tge C, Wagner A, et al. An Introduction to Ethics in Robotics and AI. 1st edn. Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2021. (Springer Briefs in Ethics). Accessed September 9, 2024. http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-3-030-51110-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parreira A, Lehmann L, Oliveira M. The challenge of artificial intelligence technologies in education: Teachers&#x2019; perception and evaluation. Ensaio Eval Public Policies Educ 2021;29(113):975&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Boulay B. Artificial Intelligence in Education and Ethics. RE@D. 2023:e202303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations (UN). Quality Education Sustainable Development Goal 4: Quality Education United Nations in Brazil; 2023. Accessed September 14, 2024. https://brasil.un.org/pt-br/sdgs/4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir-Kaymak Z, Y&#x131;lmaz M, Ayd&#x131;n N, et al. Effects of midwifery and nursing students&#x2019; readiness about medical artificial intelligence on artificial intelligence anxiety. Nurse Educ Pract 2024;78:103994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNESCO - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. Reimagining our futures together: A new social contract for education. Accessed September 14, 2024. https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000386693?locale=en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira Aydogdu AL. Artificial intelligence and nursing: Reflection on the use of technologies in the care process. Rev Enferm UFJF 2022;6(2):e37017. Accessed September 30, 2024. https://periodicos.ufjf.br/index.php/enfermagem/article/view/37017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Pereira M, Figueredo-Borda N, Morales EO. Artificial intelligence in care: a challenge for nursing. Enferm Cuid Humaniz 2023;12(1):e567871655. Accessed September 9, 2024. https://core.ac.uk/download/pdf/567871655.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Dong C, Yang Y, et al. Developing a professional competence framework for the master of nursing specialist degree program in China: a modified Delphi study. Nurse Educ Today 2022;118:105524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakken S, Dreisbach C, Kisselev S, Reading Turchioe M. Advancing data science competencies for nursing PhD students. Stud Health Technol Inform 2024;315:515&#x2013;519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Godfrey C, McInerney P, et al. Scoping reviews. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. JBI; 2024. Accessed May 16, 2024. https://synthesismanual.jbi.global.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes W, da Silva PCM, Nascimento FC, et al. Knowledge, skills, and attitudes of nursing students regarding Artificial Intelligence (AI): A scoping review. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock D, Tricco AC, Peters MDJ, et al. Methodological quality, guidance, and tools in scoping reviews: a scoping review protocol. JBI Evid Synth 2022;20(4):1098&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aromataris E, Lockwood C, Porritt K, Pilla B, Jordan Z. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis JBI; 2024. Accessed September 9, 2024. https://synthesismanual.jbi.global 10.46658/JBIMES-24-01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Gerich H, Moen H, Block LJ, et al. Artificial intelligence-based technologies in nursing: a scoping literature review of the evidence. Int J Nurs Stud 2022;127:104153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bughin J, Hazan E, Ramaswamy S, et al. Artificial intelligence: The next digital frontier. McKinsey Global Institute; 2017. Accessed November 26, 2024. http://dln.jaipuria.ac.in:8080/jspui/bitstream/123456789/14268/1/MGI-artificial-intelligence-discussion-paper.pdf &#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubaker Bagabir S, Ibrahim NK, Abubaker Bagabir H, Hashem Ateeq R. Covid-19 and artificial intelligence: genome sequencing, drug development and vaccine discovery. J Infect Public Health 2022;15(2):289&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwalbe N, Wahl B. Artificial intelligence and the future of global health. Lancet 2020;395(10236):1579&#x2013;1586. Accessed November 26, 2024. https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(20)30226-9/fulltext.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira Aydogdu AL. Artificial intelligence and nursing: reflections on the use of technologies in the care process. Rev Enferm UFJF 2022;6(2):e37017. doi:10.34019/2446-5739.2020.v6.37017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34019/2446-5739.2020.v6.37017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvares S. Does science speak English? In times of change. Nascer e Crescer 2016;25(3):133&#x2013;135; Accessed November 25, 2024. https://revistas.rcaap.pt/nascercrescer/article/download/10074/7339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro RA, Oliveira L, Furtado CC. English as a lingua franca of science. In: Proceedings of the 28th Brazilian Congress of Librarianship, Documentation, and Information Science &#x2013; FEBAB. 2019. Accessed November 25, 2024. https://portal.febab.org.br/cbbd2019/article/view/2407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finardi KR, Fran&#xe7;a C. English in the internationalization of Brazilian scientific production: evidence from the field of language and linguistics. Rev Interseccoes 2016;9(19):234&#x2013;250; Accessed November 26, 2024. https://revistas.anchieta.br/index.php/RevistaInterseccoes/article/view/1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunawan J, Aungsuroch Y, Montayre J. ChatGPT integration within nursing education and its implications for nursing students: a systematic review and text network analysis. Nurse Educ Today 2024;141:106323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchanan C, Howitt ML, Wilson R, Booth RG, Risling T, Bamford M. Predicted influences of artificial intelligence on nursing education: A scoping review. JMIR Nurs 2021;4(1):e23933; Accessed November 26, 2024. https://nursing.jmir.org/2021/1/e23933/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Gagne JC. Values clarification exercises to prepare nursing students for artificial intelligence integration. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2023;20(14):6409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalcinkaya T, Ergin E, Yucel SC. Exploring nursing students&#x2019; attitudes and readiness for artificial intelligence: a cross-sectional study. Teach Learn Nurs 2024;19(4):e722&#x2013;e728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S, Ang E, Ng ED, et al. Communication skills training using virtual reality: a descriptive qualitative study. Nurse Educ Today 2020;94:104592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yigit D, Acikgoz A. Evaluation of future nurses&#x2019; knowledge, attitudes and anxiety levels about artificial intelligence applications. J Eval Clin Pract 2024;30(7):1319&#x2013;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Hashish EA, Alnajjar H. Digital proficiency: assessing knowledge, attitudes, and skills in digital transformation, health literacy, and artificial intelligence among university nursing students. BMC Med Educ 2024;24(1):508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon J, Pitt V, Summons P, Inder KJ. Use of artificial intelligence and virtual reality within clinical simulation for nursing pain education: A scoping review. Nurse Educ Today 2021;97:104700. doi:10.1016/j.nedt.2020.104700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2020.104700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Arrastia M, Martinez-Ortigosa A, Ruiz-Gonzalez C, et al. Experiences and perceptions of final-year nursing students of using a chatbot in a simulated emergency situation: a qualitative study. J Nurs Manag 2022;30(8):3874&#x2013;3884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castonguay A, Farthing P, Davies S, et al. Revolutionizing nursing education through AI integration: a reflection on the disruptive impact of ChatGPT. Nurse Educ Today 2023;129:105916.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>