<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41305241</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>4D Pointwise Terrestrial Laser Scanning Calibration: Radiometric Calibration of Point Clouds.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7035</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s25227035</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Terrestrial Laser Scanners (TLS), as monostatic LiDAR systems, emit and receive laser pulses through a single aperture, which ensures the simultaneous measurement of signal geometry and intensity. The relative intensity of a signal, defined as the ratio of received to transmitted power, directly describes the strength and quality of the reflected signal and the corresponding radiometric uncertainty of individual points. The LiDAR range equation provides the physical connection for characterizing signal strength as a function of reflectivity and other spatial parameters. In this research, theoretical developments of the texture-dependent LiDAR range equation, in conjunction with a neural network method, are presented. The two-step approach aims to improve the accuracy of signal intensities by enhancing signal reflectivity estimation and the precision of signal intensities by reducing their sensitivity to variations in spatial characteristics-range and incidence angle. This establishes the intensity as the standard fourth dimension of the 3D point cloud based on the inherent target quality. For validation, four terrestrial laser scanners-Leica ScanStation P50, Leica ScanStation C10, Leica RTC360, and Trimble X9-are evaluated. Results demonstrate significant improvements of at least 40% in accuracy and 97% in precision for the color intensities of individual points across the devices. This research enables a 4D TLS point cloud calibration framework for further investigations on other internal and external geometries of targets (target materials, roughness, albedo, and edgy and tilted surfaces), which allows the standardization of radiometric values.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabzali</LastName><ForeName>Mansoor</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8942-2957</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surveying Discipline, School of Engineering, University of Newcastle, Newcastle, NSW 2308, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilgrim</LastName><ForeName>Lloyd</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surveying Discipline, School of Engineering, University of Newcastle, Newcastle, NSW 2308, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Australian Government Research Training Program (RTP) Scholarship</GrantID><Agency>This research was funded by an Australian Government Research Training Program (RTP) Scholarship.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">4D pointwise TLS radiometric calibration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LiDAR range equation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">color</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural network method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">precision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">range</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41305241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12656309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25227035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s25227035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mcmanamon P.F. Field Guide to Lidar. SPIE Library; Bellingham, WA USA: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Research Council (NRC) Laser Radar: Progress and Opportunities in Active Electro-Optical Sensing. The National Academies Press; Washington, DC, USA: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshetyuk Y. Ph.D. Thesis. KTH University; Stockholm, Sweden: 2009. Self-Calibration and Direct Georeferencing in Terrestrial Laser Scanning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudarissanane S., Ree J.V., Bucksch A., Lindenbergh R. Proc. of the 10. Anwendungsbezogener Workshop zur Erfassung, Modellierung, Verarbeitung und. Gesellschaft zur Forderung Angewandter Informatik; Berlin, Germany: 2006. Error Budget of Terrestrial Laser Scanning: Influence of the Incidence Angle on the Scan Quality.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudarissanane S., Lindenbergh R., Gorte B. Reducing the errors in terrestrial laser scanning by optimizing the measurement set-up; Proceedings of the International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Sciences; Beijing, China. 3&#x2013;11 July 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabzali M., Pilgrim L. Hybrid Atmospheric Modeling of Refractive Index Gradients in Long-Range TLS-Based Deformation Monitoring. Remote Sens. 2025;17:3513. doi: 10.3390/rs17213513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs17213513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan K., Cheng X. Intensity data correction based on incidence angle and distance for terrestrial laser scanner. J. Appl. Remote Sens. 2015;9:094094. doi: 10.1117/1.JRS.9.094094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/1.JRS.9.094094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaasalainen S., Jaakkola A., Kaasalainen M., Krooks A., Kukko A. Analysis of Incidence Angle and Distance Effects on Terrestrial Laser Scanner Intensity: Search for Correction Methods. Remote Sens. 2011;3:2207&#x2013;2221. doi: 10.3390/rs3102207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs3102207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudarissananae S., Lindenbergh R., Menenti M., Teunissen P. Incidence Angle Influence on the Quality of Terrestrial Laser Scanning Points; Proceedings of the Laser Scanning 2009; Paris, France. 1&#x2013;2 September 2009; Bretar, F., Pierrot-Deseillignay, M., Vosselman, G., Eds.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krooks A., Kaasalainen S., Hakala T.K.H. Correction of intensity incidence angle effect in terrestrial laser scanning; Proceedings of the ISPRS Workshop Laser Scanning; Antalya, Turkey. 11&#x2013;13 November 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudarissanane S., Lindenbergh R.C. Optimizing terrestrial laser scanning measurement set-ups; Proceedings of the International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Sciences; Calgary, AB, Canada. 29&#x2013;31 August 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudarissanane S., Lindenbergh R., Menenti M., Teunissen P. Scanning geometry: Influencing factor on the quality of terrestrial laser scanning points. ISPRS J. Photogram. Remote Sens. 2011;66:389&#x2013;399. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2011.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2011.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeifer N., Dorininger P., Haring A., Fan H. Investigating terrestrial laser scanning intensity data: Quality and functional relations; Proceedings of the International Conference on Optical 3-D Measurement Techniques VIII; Zurich, Switzerland. 9&#x2013;12 July 2007;  [(accessed on 15 September 2025)]. pp. 328&#x2013;337. Available online:  http://hdl.handle.net/20.500.12708/42100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voisin S., Foufou S., Truchetet F., Paage D. Abidi Sttudy of ambient light influence for three-dimensional scanners based on structured light. Opt. Eng. 2007;46:030502. doi: 10.1117/1.2717126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/1.2717126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark J., Robson S. Accuracy of measurements made with a Cyrax 2500 Laser Scanner against surfaces of known color. Surv. Rev. 2004;37:626&#x2013;638. doi: 10.1179/sre.2004.37.294.626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/sre.2004.37.294.626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolkas D., Martinez A. Effect of target color and scanning geometry on terrestrial LiDAR point-cloud noise and plane fitting. J. Appl. Geod. 2017;12:109&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1515/jag-2017-0034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jag-2017-0034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaman A., Yilmaz H.M. The effects of object surface colors on terrestrial laser scanners. Int. J. Eng. Geosci. 2017;2:68&#x2013;74. doi: 10.26833/ijeg.296835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26833/ijeg.296835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stal C., De Maeyer P., De Ryck M., De Wulf A., Goossens R., Nutten T. Comparison of Geometric and Radiometric Information from Photogrammetry and Color-Enriched Laser Scanning; Proceedings of the FIG Working Week 2011: Bridging the Gap Between Cultures; Murrakech, Morocco. 18&#x2013;22 May 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wujanz D. Intensity calibration method for 3D laser scanner. J. N. Z. Institute Surv. 2009;299:7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julin A., Kurkela M., Rantanen T., Virtanen J.P., Maksimainen M., Kukko A., Kaartinen H., Vaaja M.T., Hyyppa J., Hyyppa H. Evaluating the Quality of TLS Point Cloud Colorization. Remote Sens. 2020;12:2748. doi: 10.3390/rs12172748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12172748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Varga M., Medic T., Wieser A. Assessing the alignment between geometry and colors in TLS colored point clouds; Proceedings of the ISPRS Annals of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Science; Cairo, Egypt. 2&#x2013;7 September 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaguer-Puig M., Molada-Tebar A., Marques-Mateu A., Lerma J.L. Characterization of Intensity Values on Terrestrial Laser Scanning for Recording Enhancement; Proceedings of the International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Science; Ottawa, ON, Canada. 28 August&#x2013;1 September 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabzali M., Pilgrim L. New Parametrization of Bundle Block Adjustment for Self-Calibration of Terrestrial Laser Scanner (TLS) Photogrammetric Rec. 2025;40:40009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichti D.D., Harvey B.R. The effects of reflecting surface material properties on time-of-flight laser scanner measurements; Proceedings of the Symposium on Geospatial theory, Processing and Applications; Ottawa, ON, Canada. 8&#x2013;12 July 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonietto L., Gonzaga L.J., Veronez M.R., Kazmierczak C.D.S., Arnold D.C.C., Costa C.A.D. New Method for Evaluating Surface Roughness Parameters Acquired by Laser Scanning. Nature. 2019;9:15038. doi: 10.1038/s41598-019-51545-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-51545-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6803717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31636338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger A.B. State of the art in surface reconstruction from point clouds. Eurographics Star Rep. 2014;1:161&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah J., Samson C., McKinnon S.D., Tibodeau D. 3D laser imaging for surface roughness analysis. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2013;58:111&#x2013;117. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2012.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2012.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreau N., Roudet C., Gentil C. Study and Comparison of Surface Roughness Measurements. In Journ&#xe9;es du Groupe de Travail en, Lyon, 2014.  [(accessed on 15 September 2025)].  Available online:  https://hal.science/file/index/docid/1068988/filename/articleGTMG2014_Moreau_09_03_soir.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva B.B.D., Braga A.C., Braga C.C., Olivera L.M.M.D., Montenegro S.M.G.L., Junior B.B. Procedure for calculation of the albedo with OLI-Landsat 8 images: Application to Brazilian semi-arid. Rev. Bras. Eng. Agric. Ambient. 2016;20:3&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1590/1807-1929/agriambi.v20n1p3-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-1929/agriambi.v20n1p3-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maar H., Zogg H.M. WFD-Wave Form Digitizer Technology White Paper. Leica Geosystem, 2021.  [(accessed on 15 September 2025)].  Available online:  https://naic.nrao.edu/arecibo/phil/hardware/theodolites/leicaDoc/Leica%20Nova%20Documentation/White%20Paper/WFD%20Technology/Leica_Nova_MS50_WFD-Wave_Form_Digitizer_Technology_en.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan K., Cheng X., Cheng X. Modeling hemispherical reflectance for natural surfaces based on terrestrial laser scanning backscattered intensity data. Opt. Soc. Am. 2016;24:22971&#x2013;22988. doi: 10.1364/OE.24.022971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/OE.24.022971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27828363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan K., Zhang W., Shen F., Cheng X. Investigation of TLS Intensity Data and Distance Measurement Errors from Target Specular Reflections. J. Remote Sens. 2018;10:1077. doi: 10.3390/rs10071077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs10071077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcmanamon P.F. LiDAR Technologies and Systems. SPIE Press Book; Bellingham, WA, USA: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenn D. Radar and Laser Cross Section Engineering. American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronomy; Reston, VA, USA: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C. Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rishi S. The Guide to the Expression of Uncertainty in Measurement (GUM)&#x2014;The New Approach. IOP Publishing Ltd.; Bristol, UK: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton T. Ph.D. Thesis. Arizona State University; Tempe, AZ, USA: 2020. Harnessing Multiscale Non-imaging Optics for Automotive Flash LiDAR and Heterogenous Semiconductor Integration.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman O.J., Williamson C.A. Visualizing the trade-offs between laser eye protection and laser eye dazzle. J. Laser Appl. 2020;32:012008. doi: 10.2351/1.5132601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2351/1.5132601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>