<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41250233</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing physical fitness in older adults: a six-month medium intensity training intervention yields significant improvements.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>338</StartPage><MedlinePgn>338</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">338</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01401-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Maintaining physical fitness in older adults is crucial for preventing functional decline. This study aimed to examine the effects of a 6-month medium-intensity training (MIT) programme on physical fitness components in older adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomized controlled trial, 72 older adults aged 60-70 years in Indonesia were randomly assigned to either an exercise group (EG; n = 36) or a control group (CG; n = 36). The EG participated in MIT sessions (60 minutes, 3 times per week). Each session consisted of a warm-up with joint mobility and flexibility exercises, followed by 15-20 minutes of moderate-intensity walking performed at 55-70% of maximum heart rate, a strength training phase targeting major muscle groups with 8-10 repetitions per movement using bodyweight or light resistance, and a cooldown phase incorporating stretching for major muscle groups. Physical fitness was assessed using the Senior Fitness Test at baseline and post-intervention. Group &#xd7; time interaction effects were analyzed using repeated measures ANOVA. Effect sizes were calculated using partial eta squared (partial &#x3b7;&#xb2;), with 95% confidence intervals (CI) reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant group &#xd7; time interaction effects were observed for lower-limb strength (post-intervention: EG = 13.40 &#xb1; 3.22 vs. CG = 10.55 &#xb1; 2.20 reps; partial &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.167, 95% CI [0.041, 0.296], p = 0.02, upper-body strength (15.55 &#xb1; 2.88 vs. 11.37 &#xb1; 1.71 reps; partial &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.223, 95% CI [0.085, 0.352], p= 0.00), lower-body flexibility (3.69 &#xb1; 2.93 vs. 2.50 &#xb1; 4.04 cm; partial &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.101, 95% CI [0.013, 0.229], p= 0.01), and aerobic endurance (468.26 &#xb1; 88.49 vs. 417.50 &#xb1; 33.72 m; partial &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.325, 95% CI [0.172, 0.460], p&lt; 0.001). No significant interactions were found for upper-body flexibility or agility (p&gt;0.05). All values in parentheses represent post-intervention means &#xb1; standard deviations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A structured 6-month MIT programme significantly improved key physical fitness domains in older adults, particularly muscular strength and aerobic capacity. These findings underscore the importance of implementing regular, moderate-intensity exercise as a practical strategy to support healthy aging and reduce functional limitations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The trial was registered at Thai Clinical Trials Registry no TCTR20250407006 (date of registration on April 7, 2025).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hidayat</LastName><ForeName>Rahmat</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fundamental Education, Qilu Institute of Technology, Jinan, Shandong, China. rahmamatt@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Wangang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports Coach, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Danyang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports Coach, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodall</LastName><ForeName>Stuart</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise, and Rehabilitation, Northumbria University, Newcastle Upon Tyne, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medium intensity training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older people</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical fitness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All experimental procedures followed the principles of the Helsinki Declaration and were approved by Wuhan Sports University (ID: WHSU 2022013). This research study followed the guidelines set by CONSORT for randomized controlled trials and was duly registered in TCTR of Clinical Trials (TCTR20250407006). All participants provided their written informed consent before the study started. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41250233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12625375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01401-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01401-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Demurtas J, Schoene D, Torbahn G, et al. Physical activity and exercise in mild cognitive impairment and dementia: an umbrella review of intervention and observational studies. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:1415&#x2013;e14226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2020.08.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson LT, Fox KT, Keenan A, Behm DG, Stuart S, Goodall S, et al. Comparison of low-dose maximal-intent versus controlled-tempo resistance training on quality-of-life, functional capacity, and strength in untrained healthy adults: a comparative effectiveness study. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00847-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10961002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38521946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Liu HY, Cheng YC, Su CH. Exercise dosage in reducing the risk of dementia development: mode, duration, and intensity&#x2014;a narrative review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182413331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8703896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MR, Hankinson J, Brusasco V, et al. Standardisation of spirometry. Eur Respir J. 2005;26:319&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.05.00034805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16055882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opondo MA, Sarma S, Levine BD. The cardiovascular physiology of sports and exercise. Clin Sports Med. 2015;34:391&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csm.2015.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26100417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Blackwell J, Boraxbekk C, et al. Copenhagen consensus statement 2019 : physical activity and ageing. Br J Sport Med. 2019;2:856&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-100451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Lavoie KL, Bacon SL. Taking up physical activity in later life and healthy ageing : the english longitudinal study of ageing. Br J Sport Med. 2014;2:239&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert P, Sculthorpe N, Baker JS, Grace FM. Exercising caution: prolonged recovery from a single session of high-intensity interval training in older men. Res Sport Med. 2015;23:115&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2015.1005294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chueh-Lung Hwang M, Jeung-Ki Yoo B, Han-Kyul Kim B, Moon-Hyon Hwang P, Eileen M, Handberg ARNPP, John W, Petersen M, Christou DD. Novel All-Extremity High-Intensity interval training improves aerobic Fitness, cardiac function and insulin resistance in healthy older adults. Gerontology. 2017;176:112&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4975154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27346646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern G, Psycharakis SG, Phillips SM. Effect of high-intensity interval training on functional movement in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;9:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angius L, Ansdell P, &#x160;karabot J, Goodall S, Thomas K. Anodal tDCS improves neuromuscular adaptations to short-term resistance training of the knee extensors in healthy individuals. 2024;132:1793&#x2013;1804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11687829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39475491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Chen WC, Liu CW, Huang WY, Lu I, Lin CW. Is moderate resistance training adequate for older adults with sarcopenia? A systematic review and network meta &#x2013; analysis of RCTs. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2023;4:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38030985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, Izquierdo M, Kraemer WJ, Peterson MD, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;8:2019&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari L, Bochicchio G, Bottari A, Scarton A, Cavedon V, Milanese C, et al. Feasibility and effectiveness of a 6-month, home-based, resistance exercise delivered by a remote technological solution in healthy older adults. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2024;127:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2024.105559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39018967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manas A, G&#xb4;omez-Redondo P, Valenzuela PL, Morales JS, Luc&#xed;a A, Ara I. Unsupervised home-based resistance training for community-dwelling older adults : A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ageing Res Rev. 2021;69:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2021.101368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahjur M, Norasteh AA. The effect of unsupervised home-based exercise training on physical functioning outcomes in older adults&#x202f;: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Biol Res Nurs. 2021;9:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33525908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-L&#xf3;pez L, Olivares-Corichi IM, Mart&#xed;nez-Arellanes LY, Mej&#xed;a-Mu&#xf1;oz E, Polanco-Fierro JA, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez JR. A moderate intensity exercise program improves physical function and oxidative damage in older women with and without sarcopenic obesity. Exp Gerontol. 2021;150:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2021.111360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33878422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brightwell CR, Markofski MM, Moro T, Fry CS, Porter C, Volpi E, et al. Moderate-intensity aerobic exercise improves skeletal muscle quality in older adults. Transl Sports Med. 2019;2:109&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.70</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhammer B, Stanghelle JK. The senior fitness test. J Physiother. 2015;61(3):163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2015.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar AJ, Distefano LJ, Brown CN, Herman DC, Guskiewicz KM A, PD. Adynamic Warm-up Model Increases Quadriceps Strength and Hamstring Flexibility. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;4:1130&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31822e58b6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22446678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Chaouachi A. A review of the acute effects of static and dynamic stretching on performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2633&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1879-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21373870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson ME, Rejeski WJ, Blair SN, Duncan PW, Judge JO, King AC, et al. Physical activity and public health in older adults: recommendation from the American college of sports medicine and the American heart association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;7:1435&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3180616aa2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellish RL, Goslin BR, Olson RE, Mcdonald A, Russi GD, Moudgil VK. Longitudinal modeling of the relationship between age and maximal heart rate. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;7:822&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/mss.0b013e31803349c6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She J, Nakamura H, Makino K, Ohyama Y, Hashimoto H. Selection of suitable maximum-heart-rate formulas for use with Karvonen formula to calculate exercise intensity. Int J Autom Comput. 2015;12:62&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11633-014-0824-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Id TIG, Jeon JY, Lindsay T, et al. PLOS ONE resting heart rate is a population-level biomarker of cardiorespiratory fitness : the Fenland study. PLoS ONE. 2023;11:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10174582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37167327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Bautmans I, Coudyzer W, Boen F, Delecluse C. Low- and high-resistance exercise: long-term adherence and motivation among older adults. Gerontology. 2015;61:551&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000381473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25997778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winke MR, Jones NB, Berger CG, Yates JW. Moderate static stretching and torque production of the knee flexors. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:706&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c7c557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20145556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman SL, Smith DT. Four-week dynamic stretching warm-up intervention elicits longer-term performance benefits. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1286&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318173da50</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Sullivan K, Murray E, Sainsbury D. The effect of warm-up, static stretching and dynamic stretching on hamstring flexibility in previously injured subjects. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2009;10:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2679703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19371432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guralnik J, Bandeen-roche K, Bhasin SAR, et al. Clinically Meaningful change for Physical PERFORMANCE: Perspectives of the ICFSR task force. J Frailty Aging. 2020;9:9&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jfa.2019.33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera S, Mody SH, Woodman RC, Studenski SA. Meaningful change and responsiveness in common physical performance measures in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2006;54:743&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2006.00701.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16696738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klempel N, Blackburn NE, McMullan IL, Wilson JJ, Smith L, Cunningham C, et al. The effect of chair-based exercise on physical function in older adults: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18041902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7920319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikai S, Uchida H, Mizuno Y, Tani H, Nagaoka M, Tsunoda K, et al. Effects of chair yoga therapy on physical fitness in patients with psychiatric disorders: a 12-week single-blind randomized controlled trial. J Psychiatr Res. 2017;17:1&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28750232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetrovsky T, Steffl M, Stastny P, Tufano JJ. The efficacy and safety of lower &#x2013; limb plyometric training in older adults&#x202f;: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2019;49:113&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-1018-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30387072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei G, Shang Z, Li Y, Wu Y, Zhang L. Effects of lower-limb active resistance exercise on mobility, physical function, knee strength and pain intensity in patients with total knee arthroplasty&#x202f;: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-024-07845-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11395693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39267026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, He X, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y. Effects of resistance training in healthy older people with sarcopenia&#x202f;: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2021;18:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-021-00277-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8588688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Mao L, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y, Chen N. Effects of different exercise training modes on muscle strength and physical performance in older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-021-02642-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerage AM, Janu&#xe1;rio RSB, Nascimento MA, do, Pina FLC, Serpeloni C. Impact of 12 weeks of resistance training on physical and functional fitness in elderly women. Brazilian J KINANTHROPOMETRY Hum Perform. 2012;8:145&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todde F, Melis F, Mura R, Pau M, Fois F, Magnani S, et al. A 12-week vigorous exercise protocol in a healthy group of persons over 65&#x202f;: study of physical function by means of the senior fitness test. Biomed Res Int. 2016;10:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/7639842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4868891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27243035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirwan RP, Mazidi M, Garc&#xed;a CR, Lane KE, Jafari A, Butler T. Protein interventions augment the effect of resistance exercise on appendicular lean mass and handgrip strength in older adults&#x202f;: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Am J Clin Nutr. 2022;115:897&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqab355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34673936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larumbe-zabala E, Jim A, Puente-fern J, Liguori G. Impact of combining multi-ingredient supplementation with exercise on body composition and physical performance, in healthy middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Gerontol. 2023;172:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36587797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namsawang J, Srijunto W, Werasirirat P, Snieckus A, Bradauskiene K, Kamandulis S, et al. The effects of 6-week home-based static stretching, dynamic stretching, or eccentric exercise interventions on muscle-tendon properties and functional performance in older women. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2024;22:117&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2024.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10820338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38283890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiacchiero M, Dresely B, Silva U, DeLosReyes R, Vorik B. The relationship between range of Movement, Flexibility, and balance in the Elderly - See more at. Top Geriatr Rehabil. 2010;26:148&#x2013;55. http://www.nursingcenter.com/lnc/JournalArticle?Article_ID=1017528#sthash.ZMuORz1x.dpuf.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TGR.0b013e3181e854bc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreside JM, Mcgill SM. Hip joint range ofmotion improvements using three different interventions. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:1265&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824f2351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Baranda PS, Ayala F. Chronic flexibility improvement after 12 week of stretching program utilizing the ACSM recommendations: hamstring flexibility. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31:389&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0030-1249082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20309785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Zahiri A, Anvar SH, Goudini R, Hicks JP, et al. Resistance training induces improvements in range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:707&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos E, Rhea M, Sim&#xe3;o R, Dias I, De Salles BF, Novaes J, et al. Influence of moderately intense strength training on flexibility in sedentary young women. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:3144&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e38027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20940647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stathokostas L, Mcdonald MW, Little RMD, Paterson DH. Flexibility of older adults aged 55&#x2013;86 years and the influence of physical activity. J Aging Res. 2013;2013:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/743843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3703899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23862064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KV, Hung CY, Li CM, Lin YH, Wang TG, Tsai KS, et al. Reduced flexibility associated with metabolic syndrome in community-dwelling elders. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4304714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25614984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzuca-nassr GN, Artigas-arias M, Olea A, et al. High-intensity interval training on body composition, functional capacity and biochemical markers in healthy young versus older people. Exp Gerontol. 2020;2:1&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32971179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toots A, Lundin-Olsson L, Nordstr&#xf6;m P, Gustafson Y, Rosendahl E. Exercise effects on backward walking speed in people with dementia: a randomized controlled trial. Gait Posture. 2021;85:65&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2020.12.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33517038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie EG, Bray NW, Raza SZ, Newell CJ, Murphy HM, Ploughman M. Age-related differences in agility are related to both muscle strength and corticospinal tract function. Physiol Rep. 2025;13:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.70223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11845323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39985143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang KH, White KN, Hayes WC, Snow CM. Agility and balance differ between older community and retirement facility residents. J Appl Gerontol. 2004;23:457&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0733464804271275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papalia GF, Papalia R, Balzani LAD, Torre G, Zampogna B, Vasta S, et al. The effects of physical exercise on balance and prevention of falls in older people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2020;9:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9082595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherrington C, Tiedemann A, Fairhall N, Close JCT, Lord SR. Exercise to prevent falls in older adults: an updated meta-analysis and best practice recommendations. N S W Public Health Bull. 2011;22:78&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/NB10056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21632004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Li W, Wang J. Effects of six months of combined aerobic and resistance training for elderly patients with a long history of type 2 diabetes. J Sport Sci Med. 2012;11:495&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado I, Ferreira J, Magalh&#xe3;es C, Sousa P, Dias L, Santar&#xe9;m D, et al. Six-month combined aerobic and resistance exercise program enhances 6-minute walk test and physical fitness in people with peripheral arterial disease: a pilot study. J Vasc Nurs. 2024;42:145&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvn.2024.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39244325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang CL, Chien CL, Wu YT. Resistance training increases 6-minute walk distance in people with chronic heart failure: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2010;56:87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1836-9553(10)70038-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20482475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud M, Maquestiaux F, Joncas S, Kergoat MJ, Bherer L. The effect of three months of aerobic training on response preparation in older adults. Front Aging Neurosci. 2010;2:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2010.00148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21151355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudlaugsson J, Gudnason V, Aspelund T, Siggeirsdottir K, Olafsdottir AS, Jonsson PV, et al. Effects of a 6-month multimodal training intervention on retention of functional fitness in older adults: a randomized-controlled cross-over design. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2012;9:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-9-107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22963328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollenberg M, Yang J, Haight TJ, Tager IB. Longitudinal changes in aerobic capacity: implications for concepts of aging. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:851&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/61.8.851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letnes JM, Nes BM, Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Age-related decline in peak oxygen uptake: cross-sectional vs. longitudinal findings. A review. International Journal of Cardiology Cardiovascular Risk and Prevention. 2023. 10.1016/j.ijcrp.2023.200171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcrp.2023.200171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9975246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36874046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleg JL, Morrell CH, Bos AG, Brant LJ, Talbot LA, Wright JG, et al. Accelerated longitudinal decline of aerobic capacity in healthy older adults. Circulation. 2005;112:674&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.545459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16043637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Phelan D, Shah AB, Emery MS. Exercise-induced cardiovascular adaptations and approach to exercise and cardiovascular disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78:1453&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemi OJ, Haram PM, Loennechen JP, Osnes J, Skomedal T, Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Ellingsen &#xd8;. Moderate vs. high exercise intensity : differential effects on aerobic fitness, cardiomyocyte contractility, and endothelial function. Cardiovasc Res. 2005;67:161&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cardiores.2005.03.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15949480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>