<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896212</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rapid subsurface warming in the subpolar North Atlantic from freshening.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70635-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Over recent decades, the Arctic has warmed four times faster than the global average, associated with a decline in sea ice and accelerating Greenland Ice Sheet mass loss, which has contributed to episodic freshening of the subpolar North Atlantic. Here, we show that a 0.05 Sv North Atlantic meltwater flux induces &#xa0;~&#xa0;1&#xb0;C subsurface warming within a decade in Baffin Bay, Hudson Strait, and along Greenland's southern and western coasts. This warming arises from enhanced stratification, weakened deep convection in the subpolar gyre, and a weaker Labrador Current. Freshening also alters horizontal density gradients, strengthening cyclonic circulation in the Nordic Seas and causing transient regional warming. The temperature response significantly depends on the location of deep-ocean convection, highlighting the need for simulations with accurate deep-ocean convection. This warming may create a positive feedback, accelerating Greenland and Arctic glacier melt with implications for ice-sheet stability and the strength of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menviel</LastName><ForeName>Laurie C</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5068-1591</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Climate Change Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. l.menviel@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Australian Centre for Excellence in Antarctic Science, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. l.menviel@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pontes</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4397-4238</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Climate Change Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Australian Centre for Excellence in Antarctic Science, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Earth and Environment, University of Leeds, Leeds, West Yorkshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapeze</LastName><ForeName>Mathieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Climate Change Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Energy and Process Engineering, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saini</LastName><ForeName>Himadri</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Climate Change Research Centre, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geography, Earth and Atmospheric Sciences, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SR200100008</GrantID><Agency>Department of Education and Training | Australian Research Council (ARC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DP220102134</GrantID><Agency>Department of Education and Training | Australian Research Council (ARC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SR200100008</GrantID><Agency>Department of Education and Training | Australian Research Council (ARC)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70635-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70635-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stroeve, J. &amp; Notz, D. Changing state of arctic sea ice across all seasons. Environ. Res. Lett. 13, 103001 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier, W. N. &amp; Stroeve, J. An updated assessment of the changing arctic sea ice cover. Oceanography 35, 10&#x2013;19 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocquet, M., Fleury, S., R&#xe9;my, F. &amp; Piras, F. Arctic and antarctic sea ice thickness and volume changes from observations between 1994 and 2023. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 129, e2023JC020848 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rantanen, M. et al. The Arctic has warmed nearly four times faster than the globe since 1979. Commun. Earth Environ. 3, 168 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otosaka, I. N. et al. Mass balance of the greenland and Antarctic ice sheets from 1992 to 2020. Earth Syst. Sci. Data 15, 1597&#x2013;1616 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn, A. &amp; Laiho, R. Forced changes in the arctic freshwater budget emerge in the early 21st century. Geophys. Res. Lett. 47, e2020GL088854 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson, B. et al. Rapid freshening of the deep North Atlantic Ocean over the past four decades. Nature 416, 832&#x2013;837 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curry, R. &amp; Mauritzen, C. Dilution of the Northern North Atlantic Ocean in recent decades. Science 308, doi:10.1126/science1109477 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabe, B. et al. Arctic ocean basin liquid freshwater storage trend 1992-2012. Geophys. Res. Lett. 41, 961&#x2013;968 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molodtsov, S. et al. North Atlantic temperature and salinity changes are driven by external forcing, underestimated by CMIP6 models. Npj Clim. Atmos. Sci. 8, 332 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chomiak, L. N., Volkov, D. L., Johns, W. E., V, J. A. H. &amp; Smith, R. H. Deep ocean cooling and freshening from Subpolar North Atlantic reaches Subtropics at 26.5&#xb0;N. Commun. Earth Environ. 6, 235 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proshutinsky, A. et al. Analysis of the beaufort gyre freshwater content in 2003-2018. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 124, 9658&#x2013;9689 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen, S. An arctic source for the great salinity anomaly: A simulation of the arctic ice-ocean system for 1955-1975. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 98, 16397&#x2013;16410 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holliday, N., Bersch, M. &amp; Berx, B. et al. Ocean circulation causes the largest freshening event for 120 years in eastern subpolar North Atlantic. Nat. Commun. 11, 585 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox, A. D. et al. Exceptional freshening and cooling in the eastern subpolar north atlantic caused by reduced labrador sea surface heat loss. Ocean Sci. 18, 1507&#x2013;1533 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamber, J. L. et al. Land ice freshwater budget of the Arctic and North Atlantic Oceans: 1. data, methods, and results. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 123, 1827&#x2013;1837 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igneczi, A. &amp; Bamber, J. L. A high-resolution pan-Arctic meltwater discharge dataset from 1950 to 2021. Earth Syst. Sci. Data 17, 3203&#x2013;3218 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notz, D. &amp; Community, S. Arctic Sea Ice in CMIP6. Geophys. Res. Lett. 47, e2019GL086749 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozier, M. S. et al. A sea change in our view of overturning in the subpolar north atlantic. Science 363, 516&#x2013;521 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit, T., Lozier, M. S., Josey, S. A. &amp; Cunningham, S. A. Atlantic deep water formation occurs primarily in the Iceland basin and Irminger Sea by local buoyancy forcing. Geophys. Res. Lett. 47, e2020GL091028 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caesar, L., McCarthy, G., Thornalley, D., Cahill, N. &amp; Rahmstorf, S. Current Atlantic meridional overturning circulation weakest in last millennium. Nat. Geosci. 14, 118&#x2013;120 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmstorf, S. et al. Exceptional twentieth-century slowdown in Atlantic Ocean overturning circulation. Nat. Clim. Change 5, 475&#x2013;480 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caesar, L., Rahmstorf, S., Robinson, A., Feulner, G. &amp; Saba, V. Observed fingerprint of a weakening Atlantic Ocean overturning circulation. Nature 556, 191&#x2013;196 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moat, B. I. et al. Pending recovery in the strength of the meridional overturning circulation at 26&#xb0; N. Ocean Sci. 16, 863&#x2013;874 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Q., Xie, S., Peng, Q., Li, Y. &amp; Wang, F. Equatorial Atlantic mid-depth warming indicates Atlantic meridional overturning circulation slowdown. Commun. Earth Environ. 6, 819 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontes, G. &amp; Menviel, L. Weakening of the Atlantic meridional overturning circulation driven by subarctic freshening since the mid-twentieth century. Nat. Geosci. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01568-1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, C. et al. A North Atlantic warming hole without Ocean circulation. Geophys. Res. Lett. 49, e2022GL100420 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns, W. et al. Towards two decades of Atlantic Ocean mass and heat transports at 26.5&#xb0;N. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A 381, 20220188 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkov, D. et al. Florida Current transport observations reveal four decades of steady state. Nat. Commun. 15, 7780 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R, B. et al. Increased risk of near term global warming due to a recent AMOC weakening. Nat. Commun. 12, 6108 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terhaar, J., Vogt, L. &amp; Foukal, N. Atlantic overturning inferred from air-sea heat fluxes indicates no decline since the 1960s. Nat. Commun. 16, 222 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y. &amp; McManus, J. Heinrich event ice discharge and the fate of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation. Science 384, 983&#x2013;986 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry, L. et al. North Atlantic ocean circulation and abrupt climate change during the last glaciation. Science 353, 470&#x2013;474 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menviel, L. C. et al. Enhanced mid-depth southward transport in the Northeast Atlantic at the last glacial maximum despite a weaker AMOC. Paleoceanogr. Paleoclimatol. 35, e2019PA003793 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matero, I., Gregoire, L., Ivanovic, R., Tindall, J. &amp; Haywood, A. The 8.2 ka cooling event caused by Laurentide ice saddle collapse. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 473, 205&#x2013;214 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stouffer, R. et al. Investigating the causes of the response of the thermohaline circulation to past and future climate changes. J. Clim. 19, 1365&#x2013;1387 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama, M. et al. Climatic impacts of fresh water hosing under Last Glacial Maximum conditions: a multi-model study. Clim. Past 9, 935&#x2013;953 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, L. et al. Global and European climate impacts of a slowdown of the AMOC in a high resolution GCM. Clim. Dyn. 45, 3299&#x2013;3316 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaude, Q. et al. A factor two difference in 21st-century greenland ice sheet surface mass balance projections from three regional climate models under a strong warming scenario (SSP5-8.5). Geophys. Res. Lett. 51, e2024GL111902 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziehn, T. et al. The australian earth system model: Access-esm1.5. J. Southern Hemisph. Earth Syst. Sci. https://doi.org/10.1071/ES19035 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiss, A. E. et al. ACCESS-OM2 v1.0: a global ocean&#x2013;sea ice model at three resolutions. Geosci. Model Dev. 13, 401&#x2013;442 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene, C. A., Gardner, A., Wood, M. &amp; Cuzzone, J. Ubiquitous acceleration in Greenland Ice Sheet calving from 1985 to 2022. Nature 625, 523&#x2013;528 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahlves, C., Goelzer, H., Born, A. &amp; Langebroek, P. M. Historically consistent mass loss projections of the Greenland ice sheet. Cryosphere, 19, 1205&#x2013;1220 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziehn, T. et al. Access-esm1.5 model output prepared for cmip6 &#x2019;scenariomip&#x2019;. http://hdl.handle.net/102.100.100/422391?index=1 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonan, D. et al. Observational constraints imply limited future Atlantic meridional overturning circulation weakening. Nat. Geosci. 18, 479&#x2013;487 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbj&#xf8;rnsen, H., &#xc5;rthun, M., Skagseth, &#xd8; &amp; Eldevik, T. Mechanisms of ocean heat anomalies in the norwegian sea. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 124, 2908&#x2013;2923 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, T. &amp; Biastoch, A. On the ocean&#x2019;s response to enhanced Greenland runoff in model experiments: relevance of mesoscale dynamics and atmospheric coupling. Ocean Sci. 19, 141&#x2013;167 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijer, W., Cheng, W., Garuba, O. A., Hu, A. &amp; Nadiga, B. T. CMIP6 Models predict significant 21st century decline of the atlantic meridional overturning circulation. Geophys. Res. Lett.47, e2019GL086075 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swingedouw, D. et al. On the risk of abrupt changes in the North Atlantic subpolar gyre in CMIP6 models. Annal. New York Acad. Sci. 1504, 187&#x2013;201 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, C. et al. North Atlantic subsurface temperature response controlled by effective freshwater input in &#x201c;Heinrich" events. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 539, 116247 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boyer Mont&#xe9;gut, C. Mixed layer depth climatology computed with a density threshold criterion of 0.03 kg/m3 from 10 m depth value, SEANOE data set.https://doi.org/10.17882/91774 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;rthun, M., Asbj&#xf8;rnsen, H., Chafik, L., Johnson, H. &amp; V&#xe5;ge, K. Future strengthening of the Nordic Seas overturning circulation. Nat. Commun. 14, 2065 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heuz&#xe9;, C. North atlantic deep water formation and amoc in cmip5 models. Ocean Sci. 13, 609&#x2013;622 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treguier, A. M. et al. The mixed-layer depth in the Ocean Model Intercomparison Project (OMIP): impact of resolving mesoscale eddies. Geosci. Model Dev. 16, 3849&#x2013;3872 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker, S. et al. Icebergs not the trigger for North Atlantic cold events. Nature 520, 333&#x2013;336 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goelzer, H. et al. The future sea-level contribution of the Greenland ice sheet: a multi-model ensemble study of ISMIP6. Cryosphere 14, 3071&#x2013;3096 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curry, W. &amp; Oppo, D. Glacial water mass geometry and the distribution of &#x3b4;<sup>13</sup>C of &#x3a3;CO<sub>2</sub> in the western Atlantic Ocean. Paleoceanography 20, https://doi.org/10.1029/2004PA001021 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolo, F. S., Fricker, H. A. &amp; Padman, L. Volume loss from antarctic ice shelves is accelerating. Science 348, 327&#x2013;331 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochtitzky, W. &amp; Copland, L. Retreat of Northern hemisphere marine-terminating glaciers, 2000-2020. Geophys. Res. Lett. 49, e2021GL096501 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foss, &#xd8; et al. Ocean warming drives immediate mass loss from calving glaciers in the high Arctic. Nat. Commun. 15, 10460 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellouin, N. et al. The hadgem2 family of met office unified model climate configurations. Geosci. Model Dev. 4, 723&#x2013;757 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalczyk, E. et al. The land surface model component of access: description and impact on the simulated surface climatology. Aust. Meteorol. Oceanogr. J. 63, 65&#x2013;82 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffies, S. Elements of the Modular Ocean Model (MOM): 2012 release (GFDL Ocean Group Technical Report No. 7). (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunke, E. C., Lipscomb, W. H., Turner, A. K., Jeffery, N., &amp; Elliott, S. Cice: The Los Alamos Sea Ice Model Documentation and Software User&#x2019;s Manual, Version 4.1, LA-CC-06-012. (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsujino, H. et al. JRA-55 based surface dataset for driving ocean-sea-ice models (JRA55-do). Ocean Model. 130, 79&#x2013;139 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackallah, C. et al. ACCESS datasets for CMIP6: methodology and idealised experiments. J. South. Hemisph. Earth Syst. Sci. 72, 93&#x2013;116 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziehn, T. et al. Csiro access-esm1.5 model output prepared for cmip6 cmip esm-picontrol. version 20210316. Earth Syst. Grid Federation https://doi.org/10.22033/ESGF/CMIP6.4248 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyring, V. et al. Overview of the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 (CMIP6) experimental design and organization. Geosci. Model Dev. 9, 1937&#x2013;1958 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira Matos, F. D. A. et al. Diagnosing the atlantic meridional overturning circulation in density space is critical in warmer climates. EGUsphere 2025, 1&#x2013;26 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locarnini, R. et al. World Ocean Atlas 2013, vol. 1, chap. Temperature, 40 (Ed. NOAA Atlas NESDIS 73, U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, D.C., 2013).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>