<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41682461</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SE-MTCAELoc: SE-Aided Multi-Task Convolutional Autoencoder for Indoor Localization with Wi-Fi.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">945</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26030945</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Indoor localization finds wide-ranging applications in user navigation and intelligent building systems. Nevertheless, signal interference within complex indoor environments and challenges regarding localization generalization in multi-building and multi-floor scenarios have restricted the performance of traditional localization methods based on Wi-Fi fingerprinting. To tackle these issues, this paper presents the SE-MTCAELoc model, a multi-task convolutional autoencoder approach that integrates a squeeze-excitation (SE) attention mechanism for indoor positioning. Firstly, the method preprocesses Wi-Fi Received Signal Strength (RSSI) data. In the UJIIndoorLoc dataset, the 520-dimensional RSSI features are extended to 576 dimensions and reshaped into a 24 &#xd7; 24 matrix. Meanwhile, Gaussian noise is introduced to enhance the robustness of the data. Subsequently, an integrated SE module combined with a convolutional autoencoder (CAE) is constructed. This module aggregates channel spatial information through squeezing operations and learns channel weights via excitation operations. It dynamically enhances key positioning features and suppresses noise. Finally, a multi-task learning architecture based on the SE-CAE encoder is established to jointly optimize building classification, floor classification, and coordinate regression tasks. Priority balancing is achieved using weighted losses (0.1 for building classification, 0.2 for floor classification, and 0.7 for coordinate regression). Experimental results on the UJIIndoorLoc dataset indicate that the accuracy of building classification reaches 99.57%, the accuracy of floor classification is 98.57%, and the mean absolute error (MAE) for coordinate regression is 5.23 m. Furthermore, the model demonstrates exceptional time efficiency. The cumulative training duration (including SE-CAE pre-training) is merely 9.83 min, with single-sample inference taking only 0.347 milliseconds, fully meeting the requirements of real-time indoor localization applications. On the TUT2018 dataset, the floor classification accuracy attains 98.13%, with an MAE of 6.16 m. These results suggest that the SE-MTCAELoc model can effectively enhance the localization accuracy and generalization ability in complex indoor scenarios and meet the localization requirements of multiple scenarios.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yongfeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-3998-1306</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Data Science, City University of Macau, Macau, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Technology, Zhuhai 519088, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Short-Range Radio Equipment Testing and Evaluation, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Zhuhai 519088, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Technology, Zhuhai 519088, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Data Science, City University of Macau, Macau, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Technology, Zhuhai 519088, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Binghua</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Technology, Zhuhai 519088, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021ZDZX3012</GrantID><Agency>Provincial Key Platforms and Major Research Projects of Universities in Guangdong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023ZDZX1044)</GrantID><Agency>Provincial Key Platforms and Major Research Projects of Universities in Guangdong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RSSI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SE attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WiFi fingerprint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">convolutional autoencoder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">indoor localization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-task learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41682461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12900147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26030945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26030945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sesyuk A., Ioannou S., Raspopoulos M. A survey of 3D indoor localization systems and technologies. Sensors. 2022;22:9380. doi: 10.3390/s22239380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22239380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9735771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36502083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallik M., Panja A.K., Chowdhury C. Paving the way with machine learning for seamless indoor&#x2013;outdoor positioning: A survey. Inf. Fusion. 2023;94:126&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1016/j.inffus.2023.01.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2023.01.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy P., Chowdhury C. A survey of machine learning techniques for indoor localization and navigation systems. J. Intell. Robot. Syst. 2021;101:63. doi: 10.1007/s10846-021-01327-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-021-01327-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N., Choe S., Punmiya R. Machine learning based indoor localization using Wi-Fi RSSI fingerprints: An overview. IEEE Access. 2021;9:127150&#x2013;127174. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3111083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3111083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli L., Jensen C.S. Towards fully organic indoor positioning; Proceedings of the Fifth ACM SIGSPATIAL International Workshop on Indoor Spatial Awareness; Orlando, FL, USA. 5 November 2013; pp. 16&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahsari P.S., Farahzadi A., Rezazadeh J., Bagheri A. A Survey on Indoor Positioning Systems for IoT-Based Applications. IEEE Internet Things J. 2022;9:7680&#x2013;7699. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2022.3149048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2022.3149048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nessa A., Adhikari B., Hussain F., Fernando X.N. A survey of machine learning for indoor positioning. IEEE Access. 2020;8:214945&#x2013;214965. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3039271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3039271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Zhou Z.M., Liu Y.H. From RSSI to CSI: Indoor Localization via Channel Response. ACM Comput. Surv. 2014;46:1&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1145/2543581.2543592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/2543581.2543592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Zeng X., Zhang M., Cumanan K., Waraiet A., Chu Z., Xu K. LCVAE-CNN: Indoor Wi-Fi Fingerprinting CNN Positioning Method Based on LCVAE. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12:33395&#x2013;33410. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3575904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3575904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Zhou G., Lin Y. Cross-Domain WiFi Sensing with Channel State Information: A Survey. ACM Comput. Surv. 2023;55:1&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1145/3570325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3570325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocamora J.M., Ho I.W.-H., Mak W.-M., Lau A.P.-T. Survey of CSI fingerprinting-based indoor positioning and mobility tracking systems. IET Signal Process. 2020;14:407&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1049/iet-spr.2020.0028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-spr.2020.0028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Q., Fan X., Bie H., Puthal D., Wu T., Song X., Fang G. SE-Loc: Security-Enhanced Indoor Localization with Semi-Supervised Deep Learning. IEEE Trans. Netw. Sci. Eng. 2023;10:2964&#x2013;2977. doi: 10.1109/TNSE.2022.3174674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2022.3174674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng T., Liu Y., Yu Y., Chen L., Chen R. CrowdLOC-S: Crowdsourced seamless localization framework based on CNN-LSTM-MLP enhanced quality indicator. Expert Syst. Appl. 2024;243:122852. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerdjidj O., Himeur Y., Sohail S.S., Amira A., Fadli F., Atalla S., Mansoor W., Copiaco A., Gawanmeh A., Miniaoui S., et al. Uncovering the Potential of Indoor Localization: Role of Deep and Transfer Learning. IEEE Access. 2024;12:73980&#x2013;74010. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3402997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3402997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao X., Luo Z., Luo Y., Yi Y., Lei G., Cao Y. MFFALoc: CSI-based multifeatures fusion adaptive device-free passive indoor fingerprinting localization. IEEE Internet Things J. 2023;11:14100&#x2013;14114. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2023.3339797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3339797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Wang H., Gravina R., Sun F. WIO-EKF: Extended Kalman filtering-based Wi-Fi and inertial odometry fusion method for indoor localization. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:23592&#x2013;23603. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3386889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3386889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong X., Wan Y., Li Q., Tian X., Wang X. CSI Fingerprinting Localization with Low Human Efforts. IEEE ACM Trans. Netw. 2021;29:372&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1109/TNET.2020.3035210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNET.2020.3035210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha J., Lim E. A hierarchical auxiliary deep neural network architecture for large-scale indoor localization based on Wi-Fi fingerprinting. Appl. Soft Comput. 2022;120:108624. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2022.108624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2022.108624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowicki M., Wietrzykowski J. Proceedings of the International Conference Automation. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2017. Low-effort place recognition with WiFi fingerprints using deep learning; pp. 575&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K.S., Lee S., Huang K. A scalable deep neural network architecture for multi-building and multi-floor indoor localization based on Wi-Fi fingerprinting. Big Data Anal. 2018;3:4. doi: 10.1186/s41044-018-0031-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41044-018-0031-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L., Huang H., Li X., Ding S., Zhao H., Han Z. An accurate and robust approach of device-free localization with convolutional autoencoder. IEEE Internet Things J. 2019;6:5825&#x2013;5840. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2019.2907580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2019.2907580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin F., Zuo T., Wang X. Ccpos: Wifi fingerprint indoor positioning system based on cdae-cnn. Sensors. 2021;21:1114. doi: 10.3390/s21041114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21041114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kargar-Barzi A., Farahmand E., Chatrudi N.T., Mahani A., Shafique M. An edge-based wifi fingerprinting indoor localization using convolutional neural network and convolutional auto-encoder. IEEE Access. 2024;12:85050&#x2013;85060. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3412676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3412676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez N., Parra I., Corrales H., Izquierdo R., Ballardini A.L., Salinas C., Garc&#xed;a I. WiFiNet: WiFi-based indoor localisation using CNNs. Expert Syst. Appl. 2021;177:114906. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2021.114906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2021.114906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton G.E., Salakhutdinov R.R. Reducing the dimensionality of data with neural networks. Science. 2006;313:504&#x2013;507. doi: 10.1126/science.1127647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1127647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang J.-W., Hong S.-N. Indoor localization with WiFi fingerprinting using convolutional neural network; Proceedings of the 2018 Tenth International Conference on Ubiquitous and Future Networks (ICUFN); Prague, Czech Republic. 3&#x2013;6 July 2018; pp. 753&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha R.S., Hwang S.-H. Comparison of CNN applications for RSSI-based fingerprint indoor localization. Electronics. 2019;8:989. doi: 10.3390/electronics8090989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics8090989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alitaleshi A., Jazayeriy H., Kazemitabar J. EA-CNN: A smart indoor 3D positioning scheme based on Wi-Fi fingerprinting and deep learning. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2023;117:105509. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2022.105509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2022.105509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masci J., Meier U., Cire&#x219;an D., Schmidhuber J. Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks, Espoo, Finland, 14&#x2013;17 June 2011. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2011. Stacked convolutional auto-encoders for hierarchical feature extraction; pp. 52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutakamale A.S., Myburgh H.C., De Freitas A. RSSI-based fingerprint localization in LoRaWAN networks using CNNs with squeeze and excitation blocks. Ad Hoc Netw. 2024;159:103486. doi: 10.1016/j.adhoc.2024.103486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.adhoc.2024.103486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Duan W., Li J., Wu M., Pedrycz W., Hirota K. Attention-Based Deep Neural Network Combined Local and Global Features for Indoor Scene Recognition. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2024;20:12684&#x2013;12693. doi: 10.1109/TII.2024.3424197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2024.3424197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu D., Wang Y., Guo J., Meng L. WiFi Fingerprint Localization Model Based on Multi-Scale Residual Convolution and Self-Attention Mechanism; Proceedings of the 2025 5th International Symposium on Computer Technology and Information Science (ISCTIS); Xi&#x2019;an, China. 11&#x2013;13 July 2025; pp. 277&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Sospedra J., Montoliu R., Mart&#xed;nez-Us&#xf3; A., Avariento J.P., Arnau T.J., Benedito-Bordonau M., Huerta J. UJIIndoorLoc: A new multi-building and multi-floor database for WLAN fingerprint-based indoor localization problems; Proceedings of the 2014 International Conference on Indoor Positioning and Indoor Navigation (IPIN); Busan, Republic of Korea. 27&#x2013;30 October 2014; pp. 261&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohan E.S., Torres-Sospedra J., Lepp&#xe4;koski H., Richter P., Peng Z., Huerta J. Wi-Fi crowdsourced fingerprinting dataset for indoor positioning. Data. 2017;2:32. doi: 10.3390/data2040032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/data2040032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza-Silva G.M., Richter P., Torres-Sospedra J., Lohan E.S., Huerta J. Long-term WiFi fingerprinting dataset for research on robust indoor positioning. Data. 2018;3:3. doi: 10.3390/data3010003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/data3010003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J., Patwari N. Radio tomographic imaging with wireless networks. IEEE Trans. Mob. Comput. 2010;9:621&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1109/TMC.2009.174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2009.174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Shen L., Sun G. Squeeze-and-excitation networks; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018; pp. 7132&#x2013;7141.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>