<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41458865</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perioperative Multidisciplinary Intervention Led to Complete Minimally Invasive Transthoracic Esophagectomy for a Patient With Severe Lung Dysfunction: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97931</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97931</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97931</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97931</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Risk factors for postoperative pneumonia after esophagectomy include smoking, severe lung dysfunction, and sarcopenia. Heavy smokers often have chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), which is associated with poor physical activity and low muscle strength. Sarcopenia is also associated with decreased physical function and malnutrition. These factors lead to a close relationship between&#xa0;COPD and sarcopenia. This report describes the case of a 74-year-old man who presented with dysphagia and was diagnosed with advanced esophageal cancer with lymph node metastasis. Preoperative respiratory function testing showed a forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) of 0.76 L because of his past smoking and COPD. Multidisciplinary intervention was started, along with neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Preoperative management improved his physical function. Robot-assisted thoracoscopic subtotal esophagectomy with the patient in the prone position was performed with curative resection and no severe postoperative complications.&#xa0;The perioperative multidisciplinary intervention improved physical functions and enabled safe robot-assisted thoracoscopic esophagectomy for the patient with severe lung dysfunction in the prone position. This case highlights that not only respiratory status but also physical parameters should be taken into account when considering whether a patient can tolerate surgery safely.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Matsumoto et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashimoto</LastName><ForeName>Masashi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawasaki</LastName><ForeName>Kento</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunitomo</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyoshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maeda</LastName><ForeName>Naoaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanabe</LastName><ForeName>Shunsuke</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noma</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujiwara</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyoshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry, and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">copd</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">esophagectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative multidisciplinary intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory function training and rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">severe pulmonary dysfunction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41458865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12743499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenia and short-term outcomes after esophagectomy: a meta-analysis. Wang PY, Xu LD, Chen XK, et al. Ann Surg Oncol. 2020;27:3041&#x2013;3051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32040700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary complications after esophagectomy. Avendano CE, Flume PA, Silvestri GA, King LB, Reed CE. Ann Thorac Surg. 2002;73:922&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11899202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The evaluation of the association between preoperative sarcopenia and postoperative pneumonia and factors for preoperative sarcopenia in patients undergoing thoracoscopic-laparoscopic esophagectomy for esophageal cancer. Fukushima T, Watanabe N, Okita Y, et al. Surg Today. 2023;53:782&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36625918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Improvement in short-term outcomes after esophagectomy with a multidisciplinary perioperative care team. Watanabe M, Mine S, Nishida K, et al. Esophagus. 2016;13:337&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okayama University Hospital: Perioperative Management Center&#xff08;PERIO)  [
Nov;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.okayama-u.ac.jp/user/hospital/en/index180.html https://www.okayama-u.ac.jp/user/hospital/en/index180.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postoperative pneumonia causes the loss of skeletal muscle volume and poor prognosis in patients undergoing esophagectomy for esophageal cancer. Fujishima S, Tsujimoto H, Nagata K, et al. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2021;69:84&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiley-Blackwell. Chichester, UK: Wiley Blackwell/John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.; 2017. TNM Classification of Malignant Tumours, 8th edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, et al. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:300&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative prognostic nutritional index predicts long-term surgical outcomes in patients with esophageal squamous cell carcinoma. Hirahara N, Tajima Y, Fujii Y, et al. World J Surg. 2018;42:2199&#x2013;2208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis, prevalence, and clinical impact of sarcopenia in COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sep&#xfa;lveda-Loyola W, Osadnik C, Phu S, Morita AA, Duque G, Probst VS. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2020;11:1164&#x2013;1176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32862514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal muscle loss in the postoperative acute phase after esophageal cancer surgery as a new prognostic factor. Maeda N, Shirakawa Y, Tanabe S, Sakurama K, Noma K, Fujiwara T. World J Surg Oncol. 2020;18:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32591002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Significance of comprehensive analysis of preoperative sarcopenia based on muscle mass, muscle strength, and physical function for the prognosis of patients with esophageal cancer. Kanemura T, Takeoka T, Sugase T, et al. Ann Surg Oncol. 2024;31:818&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37989955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of prehabilitation during neoadjuvant therapy for patients with esophageal or gastroesophageal junction cancer: a systematic review. Ikeda T, Toyama S, Harada T, Noma K, Hamada M, Kitagawa T. Esophagus. 2024;21:283&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38411724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early intervention of the perioperative multidisciplinary team approach decreases the adverse events during neoadjuvant chemotherapy for esophageal cancer patients. Shirakawa Y, Noma K, Maeda N, et al. Esophagus. 2021;18:797&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33999305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of unimodal or multimodal prehabilitation on patients undergoing surgery for esophagogastric cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zhao B, Zhang T, Chen Y, Zhang C. Support Care Cancer. 2023;32:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38060053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of nutrition-based prehabilitation on the postoperative outcomes of patients with esophagogastric cancer undergoing surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Shen Y, Cong Z, Ge Q, et al. Cancer Med. 2024;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11245637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39001679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise capacity and physical activity in COPD patients treated with a LAMA/LABA combination: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Miravitlles M, Garc&#xed;a-Rivero JL, Ribera X, Galera J, Garc&#xed;a A, Palomino R, Pomares X. Respir Res. 2022;23:347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9753337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36522735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prognostic and functional impact of perioperative LAMA/LABA inhaled therapy in patients with lung cancer and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Azuma Y, Sano A, Sakai T, et al. BMC Pulm Med. 2021;21:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of diaphragmatic breathing exercise, volume and flow incentive spirometry, on diaphragm excursion and pulmonary function in patients undergoing laparoscopic surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Alaparthi GK, Augustine AJ, Anand R, Mahale A. Minim Invasive Surg. 2016;2016:1967532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4972934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27525116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of postoperative pulmonary complications through intensive preoperative respiratory rehabilitation in patients with esophageal cancer. Inoue J, Ono R, Makiura D, et al. Dis Esophagus. 2013;26:68&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22409435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of the surgical invasiveness and short-term outcomes between thoracoscopic and pneumatic mediastinoscopic esophagectomy for esophageal cancer. Sasaki K, Tsuruda Y, Shimonosono M, et al. Surg Today. 2022;52:1759&#x2013;1765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35552816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>