<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41321460</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-2360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systematic review of sensory-based interventions for children and youth (2015-2024).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1720179</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1720179</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1720179</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fped.2025.1720179</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Children with developmental disorders often benefit from interventions supporting participation, including sensory interventions, which should be grounded and informed by evidence. The purpose of this systematic review was to evaluate and summarize current evidence on the effectiveness of sensory-based interventions (SBIs) on functional outcomes to guide interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Searches were performed in Medline (OVID), CINAHL Complete, PsycINFO, OTSeeker, Cochrane Reviews, and ERIC. Inclusion criteria included the following: published in English between May 2015 and January 2024; participants aged 0-21 years with sensory integration/processing challenges; level I and II studies as classified by Johns Hopkins Nursing Evidence-Based Practice Model; functional outcomes indicated. The review followed the guidelines of Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-one studies were included. Strong strength of evidence supported use of deep pressure tactile input and caregiver training on the use of sensory strategies. Moderate strength of evidence supported that alternative seating did not improve attention. Additionally moderate strength of evidence supported targeting a variety of sensory systems is more effective than targeting only one system. There is a lack of evidence on the impact of sensory environmental modifications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">SBIs may be useful for improving functional outcomes and participation. Further research is needed to clarify effectiveness for specific outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Piller, McHugh Conlin, Glennon, Andelin, Auld-Wright, Teng and Tarver.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piller</LastName><ForeName>Aimee</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Piller Child Development, LLC, Phoenix, AZ, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McHugh Conlin</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy 360, Sergant Bluff, IA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glennon</LastName><ForeName>Tara J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Therapy, Quinnipiac University, Hamden, CT, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andelin</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Therapy, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Auld-Wright</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Therapy, Keck Graduate Institute, Claremont, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teng</LastName><ForeName>Krysti</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Science Library, UCLA Lab School, Los Angeles, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarver</LastName><ForeName>Talicia</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Therapy, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615492</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">developmental disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory-based intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>AP was employed by Piller Child Development, LLC. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41321460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12658592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2025.1720179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ben-Sasson A, Carter AS, Briggs-Gowan MJ. Sensory over-responsivity in elementary school: prevalence and social&#x2013;emotional correlates. J Abnorm Child Psychol. (2009) 37:705&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s10802-008-9295-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10802-008-9295-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5972374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jussila K, Junttila M, Kielinen M, Ebeling H, Joskitt L, Moilanen I, et al. Sensory abnormality and quantitative autism traits in children with and without autism spectrum disorder in an epidemiological population. J Autism Dev Disord. (2020) 50:180&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s10803-019-04237-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-019-04237-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6946727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31583623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaaf RC, Mailloux Z, Ridgway E, Berruti AS, Dumont RL, Jones EA, et al. Sensory phenotypes in autism: making a case for the inclusion of sensory integration functions. J Autism Dev Disord. (2023) 53(12):4759&#x2013;71. 10.1007/s10803-022-05763-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-022-05763-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36167886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurek L, Duchier A, Gauld C, H&#xe9;nault L, Giroudon C, Fourneret P, et al. Sensory processing in individuals with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder compared with control populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2025) 64(10):1132&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.jaac.2025.02.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2025.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40250555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jirikowic TL, Thorne JC, McLaughlin SA, Waddington T, Lee AKC, Astley Hemingway SJ. Prevalence and patterns of sensory processing behaviors in a large clinical sample of children with prenatal alcohol exposure. Res Dev Disabil. (2020) 100:103617. 10.1016/j.ridd.2020.103617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ridd.2020.103617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32203885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isralowitz EB, Sideris J, Stein Duker LI, Baranek GT, Cermak SA. Comparing sensory processing in children with down syndrome to a mental age matched sample of children with autism, other developmental disabilities, and typically developing children. Res Dev Disabil. (2023) 134:104421. 10.1016/j.ridd.2022.104421</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ridd.2022.104421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36638671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman D, O&#x2019;Connell-Killen T, Doyle JK, Kavanagh M, Day A, Azevedo J. The Adult Autism Assessment Handbook: A Neurodiversity Affirming Approach. London: Jessica Kingsley Publishers; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean EE, Little LM, Wallisch A, Dunn W. Sensory processing in everyday life. In: Boyt Schell BA, Gillen G, editors. Willard and Spackman&#x2019;s Occupational Therapy. 13th ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; (2018). p. 942&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills CJ, Michail E, Bye RA. A survey of occupational therapists on a new tool for sensory processing. Occup Ther Int. (2020) 2020:5909347. 10.1155/2020/5909347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/5909347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32190013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Occupational Therapy Association. Position statement: sensory integration approaches for children and youth within occupational therapy practice. Am J Occup Ther. (2023) 77(Suppl. 3):7713410230. 10.5014/ajot.2023.77S3004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2023.77S3004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38175825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case-Smith J, Weaver LL, Fristad MA. A systematic review of sensory processing interventions for children with autism spectrum disorders. Autism. (2015) 19:133&#x2013;48. 10.1177/1362361313517762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361313517762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundy A, Lane S. Sensory integration: a. Jean Ayres&#x2019; theory revisited. In: Bundy A, Lane S, editors. Sensory Integration: Theory and Practice. 3rd ed. Philadelphia: F. A. Davis; (2020). p. 2&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parham LD, Roley SS, May-Benson TA, Koomar J, Brett-Green B, Burke JP, et al. Development of a fidelity measure for research on the effectiveness of the Ayres sensory integration&#xae; intervention. Am J Occup Ther. (2011) 65(2):133&#x2013;42. 10.5014/ajot.2011.000745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2011.000745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21476360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watling R, Hauer S. Effectiveness of Ayres sensory integration&#xae; and sensory-based interventions for people with autism spectrum disorder: a systematic review. Am J Occup Ther. (2015) 69:6905180030p1&#x2013;12. 10.5014/ajot.2015.018051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2015.018051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodison SC, Parham LD. Specific sensory techniques and sensory environmental modifications for children and youth with sensory integration difficulties: a systematic review. Am J Occup Ther. (2018) 72:7201190040. 10.5014/ajot.2018.029413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2018.029413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29280714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller-Kuhaneck H, Watling R. Parental or teacher education and coaching to support function and participation of children and youth with sensory processing and sensory integration challenges: a systematic review. Am J Occup Ther. (2018) 72(1):7201190030p1&#x2013;11. 10.5014/ajot.2018.029017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2018.029017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29280713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watling R, Miller Kuhaneck H, Parham LD, Schaaf R. Occupational Therapy Practice Guidelines for Children and Youth with Challenges in Sensory Integration and Sensory Processing. Bethesda: AOTA Press; (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patten Koenig K. A strength-based frame of reference for autistic individuals. In: Kramer P, Hinojosa J, Howe T, editors. Frames of References for Pediatric Occupational Therapy. 4th ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; (2020). p. 496&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. (2009) 6:e1000097. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang D, Dearholt S, Bissett K, Ascenzi J, Whalen M. Johns Hopkins Evidence-Based Practice for Nurses and Healthcare Professionals: Model and Guidelines. 4th ed. Indianapolis: Sigma Theta Tau International; (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan LR, Hickman RR, Harris SR, Heriza CB. Single-subject research design: recommendations for levels of evidence and quality rating. Dev Med Child Neurol. (2008) 50(2):99&#x2013;103. 10.1111/j.1469-8749.2007.02005.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.2007.02005.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18201299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Occupational Therapy Association. Guidelines for systematic reviews. Am J Occup Ther. (2020). Available online at:
https://research.aota.org/DocumentLibrary/AOTA_AJOT_systematic%20reviews%20instructions.pdf (Accessed January 21, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Boutron I, et al. A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomized trials. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2016) 2016(10 Suppl. 1):29&#x2013;31. 10.1002/14651858.CD201601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD201601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Heart Lung and Blood Institute. Quality Assessment Tool for Before&#x2013;After (Pre&#x2013;Post) Studies with no Control Group. (2014). Available online at:
https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health-topics/study-quality-assessment-tools (Accessed February 10, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>*L&#xf6;nn M, Svedberg P, Nygren J, Jarbin H, Aili K, Larsson I. The efficacy of weighted blankets for sleep in children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder&#x2014;a randomized controlled crossover trial. J Sleep Res. (2024) 33(2):e13990. 10.1111/jsr.13990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.13990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Lu WP, Tsai WH, Lin LY, Hong RB, Hwang YS. The beneficial effects of massage on motor development and sensory processing in young children with developmental delay: a randomized control trial study. Dev Neurorehabil. (2019) 22:487&#x2013;95. 10.1080/17518423.2018.1537317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17518423.2018.1537317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Nielsen AN, la Cour K, Brandt &#xc5;. Teachers&#x2019; and parents&#x2019; assessment of challenges in children exhibiting sensory seeking behavior and possible effects of the use of ball vests: a pre&#x2013;post study. Children. (2023) 10(11):1800. 10.3390/children10111800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children10111800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10670564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38002891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Spira G. A sensory intervention to improve sleep behaviours and sensory processing behaviours of children with sensory processing disorders. Irish J Occup Ther. (2021) 49(1):11&#x2013;20. 10.1108/IJOT-09-2020-0014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJOT-09-2020-0014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TM. The Comprehensive Developmental Inventory for Infants and Toddlers: Manual. Taipei, Taiwan: Special Education Division, Ministry of Education; (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiresuk TJ, Sherman RE. Goal attainment scaling: a general method of evaluating comprehensive community mental health programs. Community Ment Health J. (1968) 4(6):443&#x2013;53. 10.1007/BF01530764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01530764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24185570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens JA, Spirito A, McGuinn M. The children&#x2019;s sleep habits questionnaire CSHQ): psychometric properties of a survey instrument or school-aged children. Sleep. (2000) 23(8):1043&#x2013;51. 10.1093/sleep/23.8.1d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/23.8.1d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11145319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Benson JD, Morgus K, Donoso Brown E, Smitsky D. The effect of alternate seating on improving attention and in-seat behavior of preschoolers with autism: a pilot study. J Occup Ther Sch Early Interv. (2019) 12:455&#x2013;65. 10.1080/19411243.2019.1672606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19411243.2019.1672606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Krombach T, Miltenberger R. The effects of stability ball seating on the behavior of children with autism during instructional activities. J Autism Dev Disord. (2020) 50:551&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s10803-019-04283-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-019-04283-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31676916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Macphee FL, Merrill BM, Altszuler AR, Ramos MC, Gnagy EM, Greiner AR, et al. The effect of weighted vests and stability balls with and without psychostimulant medication on classroom outcomes for children with ADHD. Sch Psych Rev. (2019) 48:276&#x2013;89. 10.17105/SPR-2017-0151.V48-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17105/SPR-2017-0151.V48-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Benson JD, Donoso Brown EV, Blough A, Smitsky D. The effect of sensorimotor strategies on attention and in-seat behavior in preschoolers with autism spectrum disorder: a pilot study. J Occup Ther Sch Early Interv. (2020) 13:236&#x2013;49. 10.1080/19411243.2020.1732262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19411243.2020.1732262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Benson JD, Blaskowitz MG, Collins A, Smitsky D, Chippich E, Connell C. The effect of a sensory activity schedule (SAS) on the on-task behaviors of children with autism spectrum disorders. J Occup Ther Sch Early Interv. (2022) 15:439&#x2013;54. 10.1080/19411243.2021.2003734</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19411243.2021.2003734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Koshy NM, Sugi S, Rajendran K. A study to identify prevalence and effectiveness of sensory integration on toilet skill problems among sensory processing disorder. Indian J Occup Ther. (2018) 50(3):86&#x2013;91. 10.4103/0445-7706.244548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0445-7706.244548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Pingale V, Fletcher TS, Candler C, Pickens N, Dunlap K. Effects of sensory diets: a single subject study. J Occup Ther Sch Early Interv. (2022) 15:165&#x2013;80. 10.1080/19411243.2021.1941492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19411243.2021.1941492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Voola SI, Kumari VM. Sensory garden: piloting an affordable nature-based intervention for function behavior of children with attention deficit hyper activity disorder (ADHD). Curr Pediatr Res. (2022) 26:1381&#x2013;5. 10.35841/0971-9032.26.4.1381-1385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35841/0971-9032.26.4.1381-1385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss MD. Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale. Vancouver: University of British Columbia; (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law M, Baptiste S, Carswell A, McColl MA, Polatajko H, Pollock N. Canadian Occupational Performance Measure. 5th ed. Ottawa: CAOT Publications ACE; (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Durgut E, Orengul AC, Algun ZC. Comparison of the effects of treadmill and vibration training in children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a randomized controlled trial. NeuroRehabilitation. (2020) 47:121&#x2013;31. 10.3233/NRE-203040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NRE-203040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Graziano PA, Garcia AM, Landis TD. To fidget or not to fidget, that is the question: a systematic classroom evaluation of fidget spinners among young children with ADHD. J Atten Disord. (2020) 24(1):163&#x2013;71. 10.1177/1087054718770009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1087054718770009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29676193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Ikuta N, Iwanaga R, Tokunaga A, Nakane H, Tanaka K, Tanaka G. Effectiveness of earmuffs and noise-cancelling headphones for coping with hyper-reactivity to auditory stimuli in children with autism spectrum disorder: a preliminary study. Hong Kong J Occup Ther. (2016) 28(1):24&#x2013;32. 10.1016/j.hkjot.2016.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hkjot.2016.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6091992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30186064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni JW, Seid M, Kurtin PS. PedsQL&#x2122; 4.0: reliability and validity of the pediatric quality of life inventory&#x2122; version 4.0 generic core scales in healthy and patient populations. Med Care. (2001) 39(8):800&#x2013;12. 10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11468499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gioia GA, Isquith PK, Guy SC, Kenworthy L. Behavior Rating Inventory of Executive Function. Lutz, FL: Psychological Assessment Resources; (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conners CK. Conners. 3rd ed. Toronto: Multi-Health Systems; (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaka&#x15f; S, Erdo&#x11f;an E, Sak L, Soysal A&#x15e;, Ulusoy T, Ulusoy &#x130;Y, et al. Stroop test TBAG form: standardisation for Turkish culture, reliability and validity. J Clin Psychol. (1999) 2(2):75&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Heyburn K, Shaw D, Carbert K, Thompson-Hodgetts S. &#x201c;Sensory in-service&#x201d;: an exploratory evaluation of a group-based, caregiver intervention for children with sensory processing difficulties. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. (2023) 43:228&#x2013;42. 10.1080/01942638.2022.2104151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01942638.2022.2104151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35920254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Mah JW, Doherty M. Sensorimotor intervention group for children with ADHD and sensory processing difficulties: a feasibility study. J Child Fam Stud. (2021) 30:447&#x2013;59. 10.1007/s10826-021-01900-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10826-021-01900-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Mah JW, Gill H, Doherty M. Feasibility and efficacy of the alert program&#xae; for children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. (2023) 28:924&#x2013;36. 10.1177/13591045231162680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13591045231162680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Padmanabha H, Singhi P, Sahu JK, Malhi P. Home-based sensory interventions in children with autism spectrum disorder: a randomized controlled trial. Indian J Pediatr. (2019) 86:18&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s12098-018-2747-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12098-018-2747-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Pashazadeh Azari ZP, Hosseini SA, Rassafiani M, Samadi SA, Hoseinzadeh M, Dunn W. Contextual intervention adapted for autism spectrum disorder: an RCT of a parenting program with parents of children diagnosed with ASD. Iran J Child Neurol. (2019) 13(4):19&#x2013;35. 10.22037/ijcn.v13i4.21156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/ijcn.v13i4.21156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6789080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31645864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer D, Gould MS, Brasic J, Ambrosini P, Fisher P, Bird H, et al. A children&#x2019;s global assessment scale (CGAS). Arch Gen Psychiatry. (1983) 40(11):1228&#x2013;31. 10.1001/archpsyc.1983.01790100074010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1983.01790100074010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6639293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamali Nejad R. Psychometric characteristics of parenting self-efficacy measurement (PSEM) among families of preschool children in mashad (Master of science thesis). Ferdosi University; (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>*Kim G, Carrico C, Ivey C, Wunsch PB. Impact of sensory adapted dental environment on children with developmental disabilities. Spec Care Dentist. (2019) 39:180&#x2013;7. 10.1111/scd.12360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/scd.12360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30729554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankl SN, Shiere FR, Fogels HR. Should the parent remain with the child in the dental operatory? J Dent Child. (1962) 29:150&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan B, Jegatheesan D, Viecelli A, Pascoe E, Hubbard R. Goal attainment scaling as an outcome measure for randomised controlled trials: a scoping review. BMJ Open. (2022) 12(7):e063061. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-063061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-063061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9316030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenbeek D, Ketelaar M, Galama K, Gorter JW. Goal attainment scaling in paediatric rehabilitation: a critical review of the literature. Dev Med Child Neurol. (2007) 49(7):550&#x2013;6. 10.1111/j.1469-8749.2007.00550.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.2007.00550.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17593130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds S, Costanza S, Odom M, Lane S, Meeley L, Owen A, et al. Effect of engagement in sensory-based tasks on autonomic nervous system activity and attention. Am J Occup Ther. (2015) 69(Suppl. 1):6911520072p1. 10.5014/ajot.2015.69S1-RP101B</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2015.69S1-RP101B</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HY, Yang H, Chi HJ, Chen HM. Physiological effects of deep touch pressure on anxiety alleviation: the weighted blanket approach. J Med Biol Eng. (2013) 33:463&#x2013;70. 10.5405/jmbe.1043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5405/jmbe.1043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman F, Tyszka AC. Supporting participation for children with sensory processing needs and their families: community-based action research. Am J Occup Ther. (2017) 71(4):7104100010p1&#x2013;9. 10.5014/ajot.2017.025544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2017.025544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28661377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn W, Brown C, McGuigan A. The ecology of human performance: a framework for considering the effect of context. Am J Occup Ther. (1994) 48(7):595&#x2013;607. 10.5014/ajot.48.7.595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.48.7.595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7943149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanless SB, McClelland MM, Acock AC, Ponitz CC, Son SH, Lan X, et al. Measuring behavioral regulation in four societies. Psychol Assess. (2011) 23(2):364. 10.1037/a0021768</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0021768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3076895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21381840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayres AJ. Sensory Integration and the Child. Los Angeles: Western Psychological Services; (1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranberri Ruiz A, Nevado B, Migueles Seco M, Aritzeta G. Heart rate variability biofeedback intervention programme to improve attention in primary schools. Appl Psychophysiol Biofeedback. (2024) 49(6):651&#x2013;64. 10.1007/s10484-024-09659-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10484-024-09659-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11588880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39179947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonawane U, Kasetti P. How valid are cortisol and galvanic skin responses in measuring student stress during training? JMIR Med Educ. (2023) 9:e45340. 10.2196/45340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/45340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10474504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37594784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derb&#xe4;ck M, Coyne I, Harder M. The importance of including both a child perspective and the child&#x2019;s perspective within health care settings to provide truly child-centered care. J Child Health Care. (2011) 15(2):99&#x2013;106. 10.1177/1367493510397624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1367493510397624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21685225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>