<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41928401</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2410-8650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Kaohsiung journal of medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kaohsiung J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Triglyceride-Glucose Index-Based Nomogram for Predicting Short-Term Mortality in Sepsis Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70199</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70199</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/kjm2.70199</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The triglyceride-glucose (TyG) index, a marker of insulin resistance, is associated with outcomes in critical illness; however, its predictive role for 28-day mortality in Asian patients with sepsis has not been established. To address this, the current investigation was designed to evaluate its prognostic significance and to construct a risk prediction model for short-term mortality. This retrospective study analyzed sepsis patients admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) of the Second Hospital of Lanzhou University from January 1, 2018 to December 31, 2023. Participants were randomly split into training/validation cohorts (7:3 ratio). Multivariate logistic regression identified independent predictors. A nomogram was constructed by these predictors and it was validated using ROC curves (ROC), calibration plots, and decision curve analysis (DCA). A nomogram integrating seven variables-age, respiratory failure within 48&#x2009;h, multiple organ dysfunction syndrome (MODS) within 48&#x2009;h, international normalized ratio (INR), lactate level, prognostic nutrition index (PNI), and TyG index-predicted 28-day mortality with AUCs of 0.855 (training, 95% CI: 0.818-0.891) and 0.826 (validation, 95% CI: 0.764-0.887), outperforming SOFA and APACHE II scores. Calibration curves confirmed alignment with actual outcomes, and DCA demonstrated broad clinical utility. The TyG index is an independent predictor of 28-day sepsis mortality. The validated nomogram based on the TyG index enhances risk stratification, aiding clinicians in early decision-making to improve patient outcomes and care quality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Kaohsiung Journal of Medical Sciences published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Kaohsiung Medical University.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, The Second Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical School, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Jing</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, The Second Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical School, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Ting</ForeName><Initials>YT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1084-8359</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, The Second Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical School, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tong-Qin</ForeName><Initials>TQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, The Second Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical School, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, The Second Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical School, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82560378</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24JRRA930</GrantID><Agency>Gansu Provincial Department of Science and Technology (Gansu Provincial Joint Scientific Research Fund)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China (Republic : 1949- )</Country><MedlineTA>Kaohsiung J Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100960562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1607-551X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sepsis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">triglyceride&#x2010;glucose index</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41928401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/kjm2.70199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>M. Singer, C. S. Deutschman, C. W. Seymour, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Third International Consensus Definitions for Sepsis and Septic Shock (Sepsis&#x2010;3),&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 315, no. 8 (2016): 801&#x2013;810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. E. Rudd, S. C. Johnson, K. M. Agesa, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global, Regional, and National Sepsis Incidence and Mortality, 1990&#x2010;2017: Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study,&#x201d; Lancet 395, no. 10219 (2020): 200&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xie, H. Wang, Y. Kang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Epidemiology of Sepsis in Chinese ICUs: A National Cross&#x2010;Sectional Survey,&#x201d; Critical Care Medicine 48, no. 3 (2020): e209&#x2013;e218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. La Via, G. Sangiorgio, S. Stefani, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Global Burden of Sepsis and Septic Shock,&#x201d; Epidemiologia (Basel) 5, no. 3 (2024): 456&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, L. Zhang, F. Xu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Establishment of a Prognostic Model for Patients With Sepsis Based on SOFA: A Retrospective Cohort Study,&#x201d; Journal of International Medical Research 49, no. 9 (2021): 3000605211044892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Guerrero&#x2010;Romero, L. E. Simental&#x2010;Mend&#xed;a, M. Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Ortiz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Product of Triglycerides and Glucose, a Simple Measure of Insulin Sensitivity. Comparison With the Euglycemic&#x2010;Hyperinsulinemic Clamp,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism 95, no. 7 (2010): 3347&#x2013;3351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. Kang, S. K. Kim, Y. S. Kim, and M. S. Park, &#x201c;Risk Prediction of the Metabolic Syndrome Using TyG Index and SNPs: A 10&#x2010;Year Longitudinal Prospective Cohort Study,&#x201d; Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry 478, no. 1 (2023): 39&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Cai, J. Xu, X. Wu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association Between Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index and All&#x2010;Cause Mortality in Critically Ill Patients With Ischemic Stroke: Analysis of the MIMIC&#x2010;IV Database,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 22, no. 1 (2023): 138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zheng, S. Qian, Y. Shi, C. Lou, H. Xu, and J. Pan, &#x201c;Association Between Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index and In&#x2010;Hospital Mortality in Critically Ill Patients With Sepsis: Analysis of the MIMIC&#x2010;IV Database,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 22, no. 1 (2023): 307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Du, G. Yuan, M. Zhang, X. Zhou, X. Sun, and X. Yu, &#x201c;Clinical Usefulness of Lipid Ratios, Visceral Adiposity Indicators, and the Triglycerides and Glucose Index as Risk Markers of Insulin Resistance,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 13 (2014): 146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, L. Wang, X. Zhou, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index Correlates With the Occurrence and Prognosis of Acute Myocardial Infarction Complicated by Cardiogenic Shock: Data From Two Large Cohorts,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 23, no. 1 (2024): 337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Deng, K. Song, W. Xu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association of Higher Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index and Triglyceride&#x2010;To&#x2010;High&#x2010;Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol Ratio With Early Neurological Deterioration After Thrombolysis in Acute Ischemic Stroke Patients,&#x201d; Frontiers in Neurology 15 (2024): 1421655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Park, S. P. Shin, S. K. Cho, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Triglyceride and Glucose (TyG) Index Is an Effective Biomarker to Identify Severe Acute Pancreatitis,&#x201d; Pancreatology 20, no. 8 (2020): 1587&#x2013;1591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, Y. Zhang, W. Wang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;An Inflammation&#x2010;Based Model for Identifying Severe Acute Pancreatitis: A Single&#x2010;Center Retrospective Study,&#x201d; BMC Gastroenterology 24, no. 1 (2024): 63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liao, R. Zhang, S. Shi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index Linked to All&#x2010;Cause Mortality in Critically Ill Patients: A Cohort of 3026 Patients,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 21, no. 1 (2022): 128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. R. P. Markus, S. Rospleszcz, T. Ittermann, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Glucose and Insulin Levels Are Associated With Arterial Stiffness and Concentric Remodeling of the Heart,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 18, no. 1 (2019): 145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Ormazabal, S. Nair, O. Elfeky, C. Aguayo, C. Salomon, and F. A. Zu&#xf1;iga, &#x201c;Association Between Insulin Resistance and the Development of Cardiovascular Disease,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 17, no. 1 (2018): 122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, D. Zhang, Y. Chen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Acute Glycemic Variability and Risk of Mortality in Patients With Sepsis: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Diabetology and Metabolic Syndrome 14, no. 1 (2022): 59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Ren, Y. Yang, F. Wang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association of the Insulin Resistance Marker TyG Index With the Severity and Mortality of COVID&#x2010;19,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 19, no. 1 (2020): 58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lou, Z. Xiang, X. Zhu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Retrospective Study Utilized MIMIC&#x2010;IV Database to Explore the Potential Association Between Triglyceride&#x2010;Glucose Index and Mortality in Critically Ill Patients With Sepsis,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 14, no. 1 (2024): 24081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. M. Reddy, S. Suthana, A. Karthikeyan, A. Kulkarni, S. M. Aslam, and K. M. Suhail, &#x201c;Prognostic Nutritional Index (PNI) and Systemic Immune&#x2010;Inflammatory Index (SII) as Markers of Severity Among Patients Having COVID&#x2010;19 Infection,&#x201d; Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care 13, no. 8 (2024): 3203&#x2013;3208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Fang, Y. Lin, L. Zhao, X. Zhao, and J. Huang, &#x201c;Prognostic Nutritional Indices Predict 60 Day Mortality in ICU Patients With Sepsis,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 15, no. 1 (2025): 45733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Xie, L. Huang, L. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association Between Prognostic Nutritional Index and 90&#x2010;Day Mortality in Septic Patients: A Retrospective Cohort Study,&#x201d; BMC Nutrition 11, no. 1 (2025): 232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Dong, R. Chen, X. Song, Z. Guo, and W. Sun, &#x201c;Quality of Life and Mortality in Older Adults With Sepsis After One&#x2010;Year Follow Up: A Prospective Cohort Study Demonstrating the Significant Impact of Frailty,&#x201d; Heart &amp; Lung 60 (2023): 74&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Bellani, J. G. Laffey, T. Pham, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Epidemiology, Patterns of Care, and Mortality for Patients With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Intensive Care Units in 50 Countries,&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 315, no. 8 (2016): 788&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Gao, Q. H. Xu, L. N. Ma, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Trophoblast&#x2010;Derived Lactic Acid Orchestrates Decidual Macrophage Differentiation via SRC/LDHA Signaling in Early Pregnancy,&#x201d; International Journal of Biological Sciences 18, no. 2 (2022): 599&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Iba, J. Helms, M. Levi, and J. H. Levy, &#x201c;Thromboinflammation in Acute Injury: Infections, Heatstroke, and Trauma,&#x201d; Journal of Thrombosis and Haemostasis 22, no. 1 (2024): 7&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Bakker, M. W. Nijsten, and T. C. Jansen, &#x201c;Clinical Use of Lactate Monitoring in Critically Ill Patients,&#x201d; Annals of Intensive Care 3, no. 1 (2013): 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Charoentanyarak, B. Sawunyavisuth, S. Deepai, and K. Sawanyawisuth, &#x201c;A Point&#x2010;Of&#x2010;Care Serum Lactate Level and Mortality in Adult Sepsis Patients: A Community Hospital Setting,&#x201d; Journal of Primary Care &amp; Community Health 12 (2021): 21501327211000233.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>