<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41284168</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Relationship Between Running Load, Strength, Muscle Architecture and Hamstring Strain Injury Across Two Seasons of Elite Male Australian Football: A Prospective Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>146</StartPage><MedlinePgn>146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">146</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00944-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Previous research has demonstrated a relationship between modifiable (e.g. hamstring strength, muscle fascicle length and high-speed running load), non-modifiable factors (e.g. age, previous injury) and hamstring strain injury (HSI) risk. However, these factors have mostly been assessed in isolation and no study to date has investigated the associations between running load, strength and muscle architecture with HSI risk. The study aim was to explore the interactions between modifiable HSI risk factors that are commonly assessed within elite Australian footballers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective cohort study design. Eccentric knee flexor strength and biceps femoris long head (BFlh) fascicle lengths were measured in 299 unique elite-level Australian Football players (age 24&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4 years, height 188&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8&#xa0;cm, and weight 87&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;9&#xa0;kg) during two pre-seasons. Data from wearable micro-sensor units (high-speed running at &#x2265;&#x2009;24k/hr and total distance) were collected over two seasons of elite Australian Football.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across 408 player-seasons there were 67 HSIs (16.4%), which took an average of 17&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10 days and 23&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;12 days to return to full training and competitive matches, respectively. Univariate analysis showed that BFlh pennation angle (OR 1.6, 95% CI 1.2-2.2), fascicle length (OR 0.6, 95% CI 0.5-0.9), weekly high-speed running distance (OR 1.7, 95% CI 1.2-2.4), weekly change in total distance (OR 1.5, 95% CI 1.1-2.2) and weekly change in high-speed running distance (OR 1.6, 1.2-2.2) were significantly different between the injured and uninjured group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Combining strength and architectural variables of BFlh pennation angle, fascicle length and peak force was able to explain 12% of variance in the risk of sustaining a HSI. The addition of running load exposure variables of weekly distance and change in weekly distance to the multivariate model increased the explained variance to 20%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Combining measures of running load exposure with hamstring strength and architecture, increases the variance explained by multivariate models for determining HSI risk. Despite this, there was still approximately 80% of unexplained variance in sustaining a HSI in this study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breed</LastName><ForeName>Ray</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9267-8390</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Education, Arts and Community, Federation University, Berwick, VIC, Australia. r.breed@federation.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia. r.breed@federation.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia. r.breed@federation.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Biostatistics, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, VIC, Australia. r.breed@federation.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Opar</LastName><ForeName>David A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8354-6353</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>Rich D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6618-2853</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research Centre (CARR), Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds Beckett University, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hickey</LastName><ForeName>Jack T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2764-698X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Nutrition, Maynooth University, County Kildare, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Morgan D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences and Social Work, Griffith University, Gold Coast, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VALD Performance, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maniar</LastName><ForeName>Nirav</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6180-6003</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmins</LastName><ForeName>Ryan G</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4964-1848</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: This study was approved by the Australian Catholic University Research Ethics Committee (No: 2017&#x2013;208&#xa0;H). The study was performed in accordance with the ethical standards as laid down in the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments. Each player provided written informed consent prior to participation in this study. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Competing Interests: Ray Breed, Rich Johnston, Jack Hickey, Nirav Maniar and Ryan Timmins declare that they have no conflicts of interest. Prof David Opar is listed as a co-inventor on a patent (PCT/AU2012/001041.2012), filed by the Queensland University of Technology (QUT), for a field-testing device of eccentric hamstring strength, which is now known commercially as the NordBord. Prof Opar has received revenue distributions from QUT based on revenue that QUT has generated through the commercialisation of his intellectual property. Prof Opar is a minority shareholder in Vald Performance Pty Ltd, the company responsible for commercialization of the NordBord, which is investigated as part of the current study. Prof Opar has received research funding from Vald Performance, for work unrelated to the current manuscript. Prof Opar was previously the Chair of the Vald Performance Research Committee, a role that was unpaid. Prof Opar has family members who are minor shareholders and/or employees of Vald Performance. Prof Opar was partly responsible for the design of the current study as well as reviewing drafts of the manuscript. A/Prof Morgan Williams, is employed by VALD Performance Pty Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41284168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12644382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00944-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00944-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maniar N, Carmichael DS, Hickey JT, Timmins RG, San Jose AJ, Dickson J, et al. Incidence and prevalence of hamstring injuries in field-based team sports: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 5952 injuries from over 7 million exposure hours. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(2):109&#x2013;16. 10.1136/bjsports-2021-104936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-104936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breed R, Opar D, Maniar N, Pizzari T. Epidemiology of hamstring strain injuries in elite male Australian football players: an analysis of 773 injuries over 7 seasons. JOSPT Open. 2024;2(4):1&#x2013;8. 10.2519/josptopen.2024.0359. https://www.jospt.org/doi/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/josptopen.2024.0359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey J, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Opar DA. The financial cost of hamstring strain injuries in the Australian football league. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(8):729&#x2013;30. 10.1136/bjsports-2013-092884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24124035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman DT, Dwyer DB, Bowe SJ, Clifton P, Gastin PB. Is injury associated with team performance in elite Australian football? 20 years of player injury and team performance data that include measures of individual player value. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(8):475&#x2013;9. 10.1136/bjsports-2018-100029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-100029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31242988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Murray NB, Austin DJ, Duthie G. Peak movement and technical demands of professional Australian football competition. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(10):2818&#x2013;23. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000003241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing C, Hart NH, Ma&#x2019;ayah F, Nosaka K. Evaluating match running performance in elite Australian football: a narrative review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehab. 2021;13(1):1&#x2013;136. 10.1186/s13102-021-00362-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-021-00362-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34702361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duhig S, Shield AJ, Opar D, Gabbett TJ, Ferguson C, Williams M. Effect of high-speed running on hamstring strain injury risk. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1536&#x2013;40. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27288515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumanov ES, Schache AG, Heiderscheit BC, Thelen DG. Hamstrings are most susceptible to injury during the late swing phase of sprinting. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(2):90. 10.1136/bjsports-2011-090176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2011-090176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21727236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielsson A, Horvath A, Senorski C, Alentorn-Geli E, Garrett WE, Cugat R, et al. The mechanism of hamstring injuries - a systematic review. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21(1):641. 10.1186/s12891-020-03658-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-020-03658-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramah C, Mendiguchia J, Dos&#x2019;Santos T, Morin J-B. Exploring the role of sprint biomechanics in hamstring strain injuries: A current opinion on existing concepts and evidence. Sports Med. 2024;54(4):783&#x2013;93. 10.1007/s40279-023-01925-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01925-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11052868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman BW, Talpey SW, James LP, Young WB. Sprinting and hamstring strain injury: beliefs and practices of professional physical performance coaches in Australian football. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;48:12&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.12.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy JD, Pollard CW, Timmins RG, Williams MD, Shield AJ, Opar DA. Running exposure is associated with the risk of hamstring strain injury in elite Australian footballers. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(14):919&#x2013;28. 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27884865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogalski B, Dawson B, Heasman J, Gabbett TJ. Training and game loads and injury risk in elite Australian footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16(6):499&#x2013;503. 10.1016/j.jsams.2012.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23333045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colby MJ, Dawson B, Peeling P, Heasman J, Rogalski B, Drew MK, et al. Multivariate modelling of subjective and objective monitoring data improve the detection of non-contact injury risk in elite Australian footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(12):1068&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.jsams.2017.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2017.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28595869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulin BT, Gabbett TJ, Lawson DW, Caputi P, Sampson JA. The acute:chronic workload ratio predicts injury: high chronic workload May decrease injury risk in elite rugby league players. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(4):231&#x2013;6. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-094817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26511006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri DR, Thom ML, Harlow ER, Gabbett TJ, Geletka BJ, Hsu JJ, et al. Wearable technology and analytics as a complementary toolkit to optimize workload and to reduce injury burden. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;2:630576. 10.3389/fspor.2020.630576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.630576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33554111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting AJ, Cormack SJ, Morgan S, Aughey RJ. When is a sprint a sprint? A review of the analysis of team-sport athlete activity profile. Front Physiol. 2017;8:432. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5476778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28676767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualtieri A, Rampinini E, Dello Iacono A, Beato M. High-speed running and sprinting in professional adult soccer: current thresholds definition, match demands and training strategies. A systematic review. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1116293. 10.3389/fspor.2023.1116293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1116293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9968809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie D, Hopkins WG, Buchheit M, Cordy J, Bartlett JD. Quantification of training and competition load across a season in an elite Australian football club. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(4):474&#x2013;9. 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaney JA, Thornton HR, Burgess DJ, Dascombe BJ, Duthie GM. Duration-specific running intensities of Australian football match-play. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(7):689&#x2013;94. 10.1016/j.jsams.2016.11.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28131505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumanov ES, Heiderscheit BC, Thelen DG. The effect of speed and influence of individual muscles on hamstring mechanics during the swing phase of sprinting. J Biomech. 2007;40(16):3555&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2007.05.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2007.05.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17659291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegyi A, Gon&#xc7;Alves BAM, Finni T, Cronin NJ. Individual region- and muscle-specific hamstring activity at different running speeds. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(11):2274&#x2013;85. 10.1249/mss.0000000000002060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000002060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31634294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Conceicao F, Edouard P, Fonseca M, Pereira R, Lopes H, et al. Sprint versus isolated eccentric training: comparative effects on hamstring architecture and performance in soccer players. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(2):1&#x2013;19. 10.1371/journal.pone.0228283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7012429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32045411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman BW, Young WB, Talpey SW, Smyth AM, Pane CL, Carlon TA. The effects of sprint training and the nordic hamstring exercise on eccentric hamstring strength and sprint performance in adolescent athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2019;59(7):1119&#x2013;25. 10.23736/s0022-4707.18.08703-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/s0022-4707.18.08703-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31332988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Settembre M, Hader K, McHugh D. Exposures to near-to-maximal speed running bouts during different turnarounds in elite football: association with match hamstring injuries. Biol Sport. 2023;40(4):1057&#x2013;67. 10.5114/biolsport.2023.125595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.125595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37867737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalkhoven JT, Watsford ML, Coutts AJ, Edwards WB, Impellizzeri FM. Training load and injury: causal pathways and future directions. Sports Med. 2021;51(6):1137&#x2013;50. 10.1007/s40279-020-01413-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01413-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33400216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew MK, Finch CF. The relationship between training load and injury, illness and soreness: A systematic and literature review. Sports Med. 2016;46(6):861&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s40279-015-0459-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0459-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26822969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone S, Roe M, Doran DA, Gabbett TJ, Collins K. High chronic training loads and exposure to bouts of maximal velocity running reduce injury risk in elite Gaelic football. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(3):250&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.jsams.2016.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27554923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar DA, Williams MD, Timmins RG, Hickey J, Duhig SJ, Shield AJ. Eccentric hamstring strength and hamstring injury risk in Australian footballers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(4):857&#x2013;65. 10.1249/mss.0000000000000465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000000465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25137368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green B, Bourne MN, van Dyk N, Pizzari T. Recalibrating the risk of hamstring strain injury (HSI): A 2020 systematic review and meta-analysis of risk factors for index and recurrent hamstring strain injury in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(18):1081&#x2013;8. 10.1136/bjsports-2019-100983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32299793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JWY, Mok KM, Chan HCK, Yung PSH, Chan KM. Eccentric hamstring strength deficit and poor hamstring-to-quadriceps ratio are risk factors for hamstring strain injury in football: A prospective study of 146 professional players. J Sci Med Sport. 2018;21(8):789&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.jsams.2017.11.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2017.11.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29233665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne MN, Opar DA, Williams MD, Shield AJ. Eccentric knee flexor strength and risk of hamstring injuries in rugby union: A prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(11):2663&#x2013;70. 10.1177/0363546515599633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515599633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26337245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar DA, Ruddy JD, Williams MD, Maniar N, Hickey JT, Bourne MN, et al. Screening hamstring injury risk factors multiple times in a season does not improve the identification of future injury risk. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54(2):321&#x2013;9. 10.1249/mss.0000000000002782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000002782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Bourne MN, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Lorenzen C, Opar DA. Short biceps femoris fascicles and eccentric knee flexor weakness increase the risk of hamstring injury in elite football (soccer): a prospective cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1524&#x2013;35. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huygaerts S, Cos F, Cohen DD, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Pruna R, Alcaraz PE, et al. Does muscle-tendon unit structure predispose to hamstring strain injury during running? A critical review. Sports Med. 2021;51(2):215&#x2013;24. 10.1007/s40279-020-01385-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01385-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith NA, Franettovich Smith MM, Bourne MN, Barrett RS, Hides JA. A prospective study of risk factors for hamstring injury in Australian football league players. J Sports Sci. 2021;39(12):1395&#x2013;401. 10.1080/02640414.2021.1875613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2021.1875613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33508205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonesson S, Lindblom H, H&#xe4;gglund M. Higher age and present injury at the start of the season are risk factors for in-season injury in amateur male and female football players&#x2014;a prospective cohort study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(10):4618&#x2013;30. 10.1007/s00167-023-07517-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-023-07517-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10471640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freckleton G, Pizzari T. Risk factors for hamstring muscle strain injury in sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(6):687&#x2013;91. 10.1136/bjsports-2011-090664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2011-090664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22763118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicens-Bordas J, Esteve E, Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A, Clausen MB, Bandholm T, Opar D, et al. Eccentric hamstring strength is associated with age and duration of previous season hamstring injury in male soccer players. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(2):246&#x2013;53. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7134347/.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7134347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen J, Thorborg K, Nielsen MB, Budtz-Jorgensen E, Holmich P. Preventive effect of eccentric training on acute hamstring injuries in men&#x2019;s soccer: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39(11):2296&#x2013;303. 10.1177/0363546511419277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546511419277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21825112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Attar WSA, Soomro N, Sinclair PJ, Pappas E, Sanders RH. Effect of injury prevention programs that include the nordic hamstring exercise on hamstring injury rates in soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(5):907&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s40279-016-0638-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0638-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Alvares JB, Marques VB, Vaz MA, Baroni BM. Four weeks of nordic hamstring exercise reduce muscle injury risk factors in young adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(5):1254&#x2013;62. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim A, Timmins RG, Ruddy JD, Shen H, Liao K, Maniar N, et al. Hamstring strain injury risk factors in Australian football change over the course of the season. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56(2):297&#x2013;306. 10.1249/mss.0000000000003297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000003297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37707490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar DA, Piatkowski T, Williams MD, Shield AJ. A novel device using the nordic hamstring exercise to assess eccentric knee flexor strength: a reliability and retrospective injury study. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2013;43(9):636&#x2013;40. 10.2519/jospt.2013.4837. https://www.jospt.org/doi/.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2013.4837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodge C, Tobin D, O&#x2019;Rourke B, Thorborg K. Reliability and validity of a new eccentric hamstring strength measurement device. Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl. 2019;2(1):100034. 10.1016/j.arrct.2019.100034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arrct.2019.100034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33543063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Ruddy JD, Presland J, Maniar N, Shield AJ, Williams MD, et al. Architectural changes of the biceps femoris long head after concentric or eccentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(3):499&#x2013;508. 10.1249/mss.0000000000000795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000000795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26460634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presland JD, Timmins RG, Bourne MN, Williams MD, Opar DA. The effect of nordic hamstring exercise training volume on biceps femoris long head architectural adaptation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(7):1775&#x2013;83. 10.1111/sms.13085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29572976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Dow C, Timmins RG, Ruddy JD, Williams MD, Maniar N, Hickey JT, et al. Prediction of hamstring injuries in Australian football using biceps femoris architectural risk factors derived from soccer. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(13):3687&#x2013;95. 10.1177/03635465211041686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211041686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34591711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Lorenzen C, Opar DA. Biceps femoris long head architecture: A reliability and retrospective injury study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(5):905&#x2013;13. 10.1249/mss.0000000000000507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000000507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25207929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crang ZL, Duthie G, Cole MH, Weakley J, Hewitt A, Johnston RD. The validity and reliability of wearable microtechnology for intermittent team sports: A systematic review. Sports Med. 2021;51(3):549&#x2013;65. 10.1007/s40279-020-01399-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01399-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Alvares JB, Dornelles MP, Fritsch CG, de Lima-E-Silva FX, Medeiros TM, Severo-Silveira L, et al. Prevalence of hamstring strain injury risk factors in professional and under-20 male football (soccer) players. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;29(3):339&#x2013;45. 10.1123/jsr.2018-0084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith NA, Bourne MN, Franettovich Smith MM, Barrett RS, Hides JA. Nordic strength and history of hamstring injury in Australian football league players. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;57:11&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Debunking the Myths about training load, injury and performance: empirical evidence, hot topics and recommendations for practitioners. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(1):58&#x2013;66. 10.1136/bjsports-2018-099784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30366966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey DL, Ong K, Whiteley R, Crossley KM, Crow J, Morris ME. Predictive modelling of training loads and injury in Australian football. Int J Comp Sci Sport. 2018;17(1):49&#x2013;66. 10.48550/arXiv.1706.04336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1706.04336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahr R. Why screening tests to predict injury do not work &#x2013; and probably never will&#x2026; a critical review. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):776&#x2013;80. 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertelt T, Gronwald T. Hamstring injury risk factors in elite sports: the role of muscle geometry and function. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2019;227(1):e13253. 10.1111/apha.13253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E. Intra- and inter-muscular variations in hamstring architecture and mechanics and their implications for injury: A narrative review. Sports Med. 2018;48(10):2271&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s40279-018-0975-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0975-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30117053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally T, Edwards S, Halaki M, O&#x2019;Dwyer N, Pizzari T, Blyton S. Quantifying demands on the hamstrings during high-speed running: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(12):2423&#x2013;43. 10.1111/sms.14478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37668346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara A, Nagano Y, Ono T, Fukubayashi T. Differences in activation properties of the hamstring muscles during overground sprinting. Gait Posture. 2015;42(3):360&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edouard P, Lahti J, Nagahara R, Samozino P, Navarro L, Guex K, et al. Low horizontal force production capacity during sprinting as a potential risk factor of hamstring injury in football. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(15):7827. 10.3390/ijerph18157827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18157827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franettovich Smith MM, Bonacci J, Mendis MD, Christie C, Rotstein A, Hides JA. Gluteus medius activation during running is a risk factor for season hamstring injuries in elite footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(2):159&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.jsams.2016.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27526636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuermans J, Van Tiggelen D, Palmans T, Danneels L, Witvrouw E. Deviating running kinematics and hamstring injury susceptibility in male soccer players: cause or consequence? Gait Posture. 2017;57:270&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2017.06.268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2017.06.268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28683419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Galanis N, Natsis K, Kapetanos G. Validity of architectural properties of the hamstring muscles: correlation of ultrasound findings with cadaveric dissection. J Biomech. 2009;42(15):2549&#x2013;54. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2009.07.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2009.07.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19646698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>