<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41779424</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6238</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating Physical Activity Into Routine Psychiatric Care: A Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2026.0026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adults with severe mental illness (SMI) face a 10- to 20-year reduction in life expectancy, largely due to heightened cardiometabolic diseases. Low levels of physical activity (PA) and prolonged sedentary behavior (SB) are modifiable risk factors that contribute to this mortality gap. Although strong evidence demonstrates that PA is safe and effective in improving psychiatric and physical outcomes, systematic integration into clinical practice remains limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBSERVATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Individuals with SMI are among the most physically inactive groups in society, often spending more than 10 hours per day sedentary and rarely meeting recommended PA recommendations. Low PA and high SB exacerbate neuroinflammatory, neuroendocrine, and cardiometabolic pathways implicated in psychiatric morbidity. Recent meta-analyses show that structured PA, that is, exercise, produces moderate to large reductions in depressive and psychotic symptoms, as well as benefits for cognition, quality of life, and cardiometabolic health. Evidence also suggests that mentally passive SB, such as prolonged television viewing, are associated with poorer mental health outcomes. Physical activity should be individualized to each person's capabilities and preferences, emphasizing forms they find enjoyable. Two sessions of strength training weekly are advised, and greater mental health benefits typically arise from leisure or active travel PA. To guide translation into care, the 5A framework (Ask, Assess, Advise, Assist, Arrange) provides a structured, pragmatic approach: clinicians can screen for PA and SB, assess readiness and safety, provide tailored advice, support motivation and goal setting, and arrange follow-up, referral, and community support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PA should be considered a core component of psychiatric care. By systematically promoting PA and reducing prolonged SB through structured clinical frameworks, psychiatrists and other mental health professionals can improve symptoms, enhance physical and cognitive health, and help narrow the life expectancy gap experienced by people with SMI.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stubbs</LastName><ForeName>Brendon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychological Medicine, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience (IoPPN), King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Division of Social Psychiatry, Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comprehensive Centre for Clinical Neurosciences and Mental Health, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Ruimin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychological Medicine, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience (IoPPN), King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teychenne</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kinnafick</LastName><ForeName>Florence</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mossaheb</LastName><ForeName>Nilufar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Division of Social Psychiatry, Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comprehensive Centre for Clinical Neurosciences and Mental Health, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korman</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metro South Addiction and Mental Health Services, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Centre of Mental Health Research, Wacol, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Medicine and Behavioural Sciences, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trott</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metro South Addiction and Mental Health Services, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Centre of Mental Health Research, Wacol, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Medicine and Behavioural Sciences, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenbaum</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition, Exercise and Social Equity Research Group, Discipline of Psychiatry and Mental Health, School of Clinical Medicine, University of New South Wales, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuch</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Methods and Techniques, Federal University of Santa Maria, Santa Maria, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychiatry, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma de Chile, Provid&#xea;ncia, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Firth</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Psychology and Mental Health, University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Manchester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Greater Manchester Mental Health NHS Foundation Trust, Manchester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vancampfort</LastName><ForeName>Davy</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Psychiatric Centre, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589550</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-622X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41779424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2026.0026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2845751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>