<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41591377</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reactive Training in Enhancing Technical Performance and Modulating Cortisol Biomarkers in Competitive Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005390</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Centorbi, M, Medoro, A, Modolo, L, Di Claudio, G, Di Martino, G, Della Valle, C, Buonsenso, A, Marziliano, N, Davinelli, S, Calcagno, G, di Cagno, A, and Fiorilli, G. Reactive training in enhancing technical performance and modulating cortisol biomarkers in competitive soccer players. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-In soccer, the ability to perceive, process, and integrate external and internal stimuli is crucial for the development of players' technical, physical, and tactical skills. This study aimed to assess the effectiveness of an Experimental Warm-Up (EWU) protocol for enhancing soccer-specific technical and physical skills while optimizing cortisol levels in elite soccer players. Thirty-two male soccer players (age: 24.7 &#xb1; 3.1 years) from 2 elite teams were assigned to an experimental group (EG; n = 18) or a control group (CG; n = 14). During the 12 weeks, along with their regular warm-up (WU), the EG performed an EWU consisting of 4 progressive coordination exercises, 4 times per week. The CG maintained their usual WU schedule. Technical abilities were assessed pre- and postintervention using the Y-Planned and Y-React, React Index (Y-REACT minus Y-PLAN), Illinois Change of Direction with and without ball (ICODT-BALL and ICODT), Technical Index (ICODT-BALL minus ICODT), and Loughborough Soccer Shooting (SHOT) tests. Urine samples were collected before and after the 12-week intervention to measure cortisol levels. The RM-ANOVA revealed significant improvements from pre- to postassessment in the EG for the ICODT-BALL, Technical Index, Y-REACT, React Index, and SHOT (p &lt; 0.001). These improvements were significantly greater than those in the CG. In addition, the EG showed a significant reduction in cortisol levels from pre- to postintervention (p = 0.0007) and compared with the CG (p = 0.003). These findings indicate that incorporating coordinative training into WU improves technical performance and agility in soccer, supporting better regulation of cortisol levels in elite players.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Centorbi</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medoro</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Modolo</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Italian Football Association (FIGC), Friuli-Venezia Giulia, Palmanova (UD), Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Claudio</LastName><ForeName>Gloria</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Martino</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Della Valle</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buonsenso</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Theoretical and Applied Sciences, eCampus University, Novedrate, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marziliano</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davinelli</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calcagno</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>di Cagno</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences, Guglielmo Marconi University, Rome, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement, Human and Health Sciences, University of Rome "Foro Italico", Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiorilli</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06690853</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hormonal response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shooting precision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skill acquisition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41591377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baccouch R, Borji R, Ayed H, et al. Effects of specific dual task training on change of direction ability, cognitive flexibility, and inhibition in young soccer players. Percept Mot Skills 131(5): 1720&#x2013;1742, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;chel D, Gokeler A, Heuvelmans P, Baumeister J. Increased cognitive demands affect agility performance in female athletes&#x2014;Implications for testing and training of agility in team ball sports. Percept Mot Skills 129: 1074&#x2013;1088, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonsenso A, Centorbi M, Iuliano E, et al. A systematic review of flywheel training effectiveness and application on sport specific performances. Sports 11: 76, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnevale D, Elferink-Gemser M, Filgueiras A, et al. Executive functions, physical abilities, and their relationship with tactical performance in young soccer players. Percept Mot Skills 129: 1477&#x2013;1491, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caso S, van der Kamp J. Variability and creativity in small-sided conditioned games among elite soccer players. Psychol Sport Exerc 48: 101645, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Cagno A, Iuliano E, Buonsenso A, et al. Effects of accentuated eccentric training vs plyometric training on performance of young elite fencers. J Sports Sci Med 19: 703&#x2013;713, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, Ceruso R, D'Isanto T. Evaluation of some quantitative aspects in the young soccer players training process during puberty. J Phys Educ Sport 19: 1777&#x2013;1783, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo J, Felix P, Costa L, Moreno JC, Santos CP. Gait event detection in controlled and real-life situations: Repeated measures from healthy subjects. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 26: 1945&#x2013;1956, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo T, de Salles BF, Trajano GS, et al. Maximal strength performance and cortisol response before and after a moderate-volume upper-body resistance exercise session in recreationally trained men: Does the rest interval between sets matter? Front Physiol 9: 668, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorilli G, Iuliano E, Mitrotasios M, et al. Are change of direction speed and reactive agility useful for determining the optimal field position for young soccer players? J Sports Sci Med 16: 247&#x2013;253, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorilli G, Quinzi F, Buonsenso A, et al. Does warm-up type matter? A comparison between traditional and functional inertial warm-up in young soccer players. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 5: 84, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friebe D, Banzer W, Giesche F, et al. Effects of 6-Week motor-cognitive agility training on football test performance in adult amateur players&#x2014;A three-armed randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci Med 23: 276&#x2013;288, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein DS, Kopin IJ. Evolution of concepts of stress. Stress 10: 109&#x2013;120, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic I, Mikulic P. Negative effects of mental fatigue on performance in the Yo-Yo test, loughborough soccer passing and shooting tests: A meta-analysis. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 7: 10, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inglis P, Bird S. Reactive agility tests: Review and practical applications. J Aust Strength Cond 24: 57&#x2013;64, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo-Trivi&#xf1;o D, Garc&#xed;a-Calvo T, Manzano-Rodr&#xed;guez D, et al. Examining tactical sprint actions and distribution among playing positions attending to match status in soccer: Implications for specific training. PLoS One 19: e0301925, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackala K, Michalik K, Makaruk H. Sports diagnostics&#x2014;Maximizing the results or preventing injuries. Int J Environ Res Public Health 20: 2470, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann DT, Williams AM, Ward P, Janelle CM. Perceptual-cognitive expertise in sport: A meta-analysis. J Sport Exerc Psychol 29: 457&#x2013;478, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara CF, Carton C, Wilson F, et al. Overtraining syndrome: A practical guide. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 3: e000261, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohendra Y, Sin TH, Arsil A, Andika H. Leg muscle explosive power, foot coordination and concentration can influence the accuracy of goal shooting. Active J Phys Educ Sport Health Recreat 13: 56&#x2013;60, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgans R, Oliveira R, Rhodes D, et al. Does elite European match-play affect salivary immunoglobulin-A and cortisol in soccer players? The influence of playing status and match outcome. Front Physiol 15: 1253417, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natsuhara T, Matsutake T, Sasaki R, et al. Decision-making while passing and visual search strategy during ball receiving in team sport play. Percept Mot Skills 127: 468&#x2013;489, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negra Y, Chaabene H, Amara S, Jaric S, Hammami M, Hachana Y. Evaluation of the Illinois change of direction test in youth elite soccer players of different age. J Hum Kinet 58: 215&#x2013;224, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolaides NC, Kyratzi E, Lamprokostopoulou A, Chrousos GP, Charmandari E. Stress, the stress system and the role of glucocorticoids. Neuroimmunomodulation 22: 6&#x2013;19, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul DJ, Gabbett TJ, Nassis GP. Agility in team sports: Testing, training and factors affecting performance. Sports Med 46: 421&#x2013;442, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springham M, Williams S, Waldron M, McLellan C, Newton RU. Summated training and match load predictors of salivary immunoglobulin-A, alpha-amylase, testosterone, cortisol and T:C profile changes in elite-level professional football players: A longitudinal analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 22: 1156&#x2013;1166, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trajkovi&#x107; N, Gu&#x161;i&#x107; M, Molnar S, Ma&#x10d;ak D, Madi&#x107; DM, Bogataj &#x160;. Short-term FIFA 11+ improves agility and jump performance in young soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 2017, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Willey B. Analysis of a reactive agility field test. J Sci Med Sport 13: 376&#x2013;378, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Dawson B, Henry GJ. Agility and change-of-direction speed are independent skills: Implications for training for agility in invasion sports. Int J Sports Sci Coach 10: 159&#x2013;169, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zioga T, Ferentinos A, Konsolaki E, Nega C, Kourtesis P. Video game skills across diverse genres and cognitive functioning in early adulthood: Verbal and visuospatial short-term and working memory, hand-eye coordination, and empathy. Behav Sci (Basel) 14: 874, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>