<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41769287</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2008-9872</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>80</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of Razi Institute</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Razi Inst</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Detection of Antibiotic Residues of Tetracycline, Oxytetracycline and Chlortetracycline in Animals' Raw Milk in Hamedan Province, Iran in 2022 Using the Four-Plate Test, ELISA, and HPLC Techniques.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>703</StartPage><EndPage>710</EndPage><MedlinePgn>703-710</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.32592/ARI.2025.80.3.703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antibiotic resistance has become a health concern as it is associated with the death of numerous people worldwide. Milk safety is one factor that guarantees the quality of dairy products. This study was designed to determine Tetracycline (TC), Oxytetracycline (OTC), and Chlortetracycline (CTC) residues in raw milk from animals in Hamedan, Iran using a four-plate test (FPT), enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) and high-performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) techniques. Over a two -year Period a cross-sectional sampling was conducted, during which 246 unprocessed raw milk samples were collected from dairy farms and milk collection centers in different regions of Hamedan, the western part of Iran. FPT was used as the initial screening tool for the presence of antibiotics. Positive samples were subsequentlyanalyzed for antibiotic residue using ELISA. Finally, the HPLC method was applied to identify the type and quantity of Tetracycline residues. In the primary evaluation, forty-seven samples (19.11 %) tested positive for antimicrobial residues using FPT. ELISA analysis indicated that 29.79 % (14/47) of these samples contained TCs residues higher than the maximum residue limit (MRL) suggested by EU (100 &#xb5;g/L). The average TCs residue in positive samples was 98.43&#xb1;6.86 &#xb5;g/Land the lowest and highest levels were 100.59 &#xb5;g/L and 129.56 &#xb5;g/L, respectively. Having used HPLC, the overall average of TCs level was calculated as 105.73&#xb1;7.25 &#xb5;g/L (TC=100.67, OTC=103.38, and CTC=107.11 &#x3bc;g/L). The detection of antibiotic residues in animal products highlights the need for monitoring these residues in milk and other animal-derived food products. Training farmers on the correct use of drugs, especially antibiotics, is recommended. Additionally, acomprehensive protocol for regularly evaluating livestock products is necessary to prevent high-contamination products from entering the production cycle.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maryam</LastName><ForeName>Adabi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases Research Center, Hamadan University of Medical Sciences, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Ophthalmologic Research Center, Ahvaz Jundishapour University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freshteh</LastName><ForeName>Mehri</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Health Research Center, Hamadan University of Medical Sciences, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marzieh</LastName><ForeName>Varasteh-Shams</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases Research Center, Hamadan University of Medical Sciences, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manoochehr</LastName><ForeName>Karami</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jamal</LastName><ForeName>Gharekhani</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Sciences, Iranian Veterinary Organization (IVO), Hamedan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Razi Inst</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0365-3439</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WCK1KIQ23Q</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002751">Chlortetracycline</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>X20I9EN955</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010118">Oxytetracycline</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>F8VB5M810T</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013752">Tetracycline</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008892" MajorTopicYN="Y">Milk</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007492" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iran</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002851" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, High Pressure Liquid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004350" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Residues</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002751" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chlortetracycline</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oxytetracycline</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013752" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tetracycline</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005506" MajorTopicYN="Y">Food Contamination</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotic Residue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iran</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Milk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tetracycline</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41769287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12936607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32592/ARI.2025.80.3.703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ARI-80-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bahramian B, Sani MA, Parsa-Kondelaji M, Hosseini H, Khaledian Y, Rezaie M. Antibiotic residues in raw and pasteurized milk in Iran: A systematic review and meta-analysis. AIMS Agriculture and Food. 2022;7(3):500&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aalipour F, Mirlohi M, Jalali M, Azadbakht L. Dietary exposure to tetracycline residues through milk consumption in Iran. Journal of Environmental Health Science and Engineering. 2015;13(1):80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4655496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26600942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landers TF, Cohen B, Wittum TE, Larson EL. A review of antibiotic use in food animals: perspective, policy, and potential. Public health reports. 2012;127(1):4&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3234384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22298919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haiping L, Jiangyue W, Fanping M, Aifeng L. Immunochromatographic assay for the detection of antibiotics in animal-derived foods: A review. Food Control. 2021;130:108356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolaei H, Abdollahi M, Safarirad M, Berizi E, Yousefi MH, Noori SMA. Prevalence of antibiotic residues in milk consumed in Iran: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Health Sciences &amp; Surveillance System. 2023;11(4):696&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos T. The European Union Directive on Takeover Bids: Directive 2004/25/EC. International and Comparative Corporate Law Journal. 2008;6(3):13&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Ning J, Peng D, Chen T, Ahmad I, Ali A, et al. Current advances in immunoassays for the detection of antibiotics residues: A review. Food and Agricultural Immunology. 2020;31(1):268&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachi S, Ferdous J, Sikder MH, Hussani SAK. Antibiotic residues in milk: Past, present, and future. Journal of advanced veterinary and animal research. 2019;6(3):315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6760505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31583228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaale E, Chambuso M, Kitwala J. Analysis of residual oxytetracycline in fresh milk using polymer reversed-phase column. Food Chemistry. 2008;107(3):1289&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pikkemaat MG, Rapallini ML, Oostra-van Dijk S, Elferink JA. Comparison of three microbial screening methods for antibiotics using routine monitoring samples. Analytica chimica acta. 2009;637(1-2):298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19286043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okerman L, Hoof Jv, Debeuckelaere W. Evaluation of the European four-plate test as a tool for screening antibiotic residues in meat samples from retail outlets. Journal of AOAC International. 1998;81(1):51&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9477562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer M, Bumgarner J, Varns JL, Daughtridge J, Thurman E, Hostetler KA. Use of radioimmunoassay as a screen for antibiotics in confined animal feeding operations and confirmation by liquid chromatography/mass spectrometry. Science of the Total Environment. 2000;248(2-3):181&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10805238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemati Niko Z, Jahed Khaniki G, Alikord M, MolaeeAghaee E. ELISA and Copan based evaluation and analysis of antibiotic residues in cattle milk in Qazvin, Iran. Infection Epidemiology and Microbiology. 2020;6(3):219&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi MM, Babaei H, Ansarin M, Nemati M. Simultaneous determination of tetracyclines residues in bovine milk samples by solid phase extraction and HPLC-FL method. Advanced Pharmaceutical Bulletin. 2011;1(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24312754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnassrallah MN, Alzoman NZ, Almomen A. Qualitative immunoassay for the determination of tetracycline antibiotic residues in milk samples followed by a quantitative improved HPLC-DAD method. Scientific reports. 2022;12(1):14502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9411586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazi Y, Ahmadi F, Karami N. Screening, determination and confirmation of tetracycline residues in chicken tissues using four-plate test, ELISA and HPLC-UV methods: comparison between correlation results. Food and Agricultural Immunology. 2015;26(6):821&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinquina A, Longo F, Anastasi G, Giannetti L, Cozzani R. Validation of a high-performance liquid chromatography method for the determination of oxytetracycline, tetracycline, chlortetracycline and doxycycline in bovine milk and muscle. Journal of chromatography A. 2003;987(1-2):227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12613816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratinova S, Raffael B, Simoneau C. Guidelines for performance criteria and validation procedures of analytical methods used in controls of food contact materials. Publication office of the European Union. 2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasi H, AfsharMogaddam M, Khandaghi J. Application of a new extraction method coupled to high performance liquid chromatography for tetracyclines monitoring in cow milk. Journal of food science and technology (Iran) 2021;18(113):339&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassouli A, Abdolmaleki Z, Bokaee S, Kamkar A, Shams G. A cross sectional study on Oxytetracycline and Tetracycline residues in pasteurized milk supplied in Tehran by an HPLC method. Int J Vet Res. 2010;4(1):1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadam MM, Amiri M, Riabi HRA, Riabi HRA. Evaluation of antibiotic residues in pasteurized and raw milk distributed in the South of Khorasan-e Razavi Province, Iran. Journal of Clinical and Diagnostic Research: JCDR. 2016;10(12):FC31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28208877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlemper V, Sachet AP. Antibiotic residues in pasteurized and unpasteurized milk marketed in southwest of Paran&#xe1;, Brazil. Ci&#xea;ncia Rural. 2017;47:e20170307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabrite S, Bou-Mitri C, Fares JEH, Hassan HF, Boumosleh JM. Identification and dietary exposure assessment of tetracycline and penicillin residues in fluid milk, yogurt, and labneh: A cross-sectional study in Lebanon. Veterinary world. 2019;12(4):527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6515823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31190707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghaddam AD, Tayebi L, Falahatpisheh H, Mahmoudian M, Kowsari N, Akbarein H, et al. Evaluation of the tetracycline residues in pasteurized milks distributed in Tehran by HPLC method. Annals of Military and Health Sciences Research. 2013;11(4)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>