<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41879914</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>One of These Things Is Not Like the Others: Disentangling the Concepts of Range of Motion Versus Flexibility, and Flexibility Training Versus Stretching.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02425-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this Current Opinion, we revisit key terminological distinctions in sports sciences, emphasizing the implications of conflating related but distinct concepts, particularly range of motion (ROM) versus flexibility and flexibility training versus stretching. While often used interchangeably, these terms represent nuanced constructs with distinct physiological and practical implications. ROM encompasses both modifiable (e.g., soft tissue extensibility, neural control) and non-modifiable factors (e.g., bone structure), whereas flexibility is only one of several trainable components of ROM, largely referring to the extensibility of periarticular soft tissues. Misunderstanding these distinctions risks erroneous assessments and inappropriate exercise prescriptions. We also challenge the common practice of equating flexibility training with stretching. While stretching is effective to enhance flexibility, other methods, such as strength training at long muscle lengths and foam rolling, produce comparable chronic ROM gains. Furthermore, stretching has a diverse array of effects that extend beyond flexibility, including strength development and neural modulation. Mischaracterizing flexibility training as synonymous with stretching perpetuates myths and constrains innovation in training practices. By differentiating these terms, we advocate for clearer language in research and practice to avoid miscommunication and ensure effective training interventions. In summary, we propose that flexibility is only one component of ROM, and that flexibility training and stretching should not be equated. We hope this Current Opinion paper generates a healthy discussion within the sports science and medicine communities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afonso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2038-393X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Centre of Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), University of Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blazevich</LastName><ForeName>Anthony J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1664-1614</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behm</LastName><ForeName>David George</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9406-6056</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tilp</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6644-2712</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Science, Sports and Health, University of Graz, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warneke</LastName><ForeName>Konstantin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4964-2867</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Science, Sports and Health, University of Graz, Graz, Austria. konstantin.warneke@uni-jena.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sustainability Education and Psychology, Department for Research Methods and Evaluation, Leuphana University L&#xfc;neburg, L&#xfc;neburg, Germany. konstantin.warneke@uni-jena.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CIFI2D is financed by the Portuguese Foundation for Science</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Technology</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>under the DOI https://doi.org/10.54499/UIDB/05913/2020</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Registration and Protocol: Not applicable. Competing Interests: The authors have no competing interests. We are, however, deeply invested in the topic of stretching, which may conceivably bias our perspectives. Regardless, we sincerely believe we have delivered a balanced perspective on the topic, even considering that this is an opinion paper. Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Data Availability: Not applicable. Author Contributions: J.A. devised the original idea. J.A. and K.W. elaborated the initial draft. All authors were actively involved in the further conception, structuring, and writing of the manuscript. All authors read and reviewed the manuscript critically for important intellectual content. All authors read and approved the final article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41879914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02425-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02425-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>NSCA. NSCA&#x2019;s guide to tests and assessments. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 11th ed. Wolters Kluwer; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NASM. NASM essentials of personal fitness training. 6th ed. Jones &amp; Bartlett Learning; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakthivadivel V, Geetha J, Gaur A, Kaliappan A. Performance-oriented mobility assessment test and timed up and go test as predictors of falls in the elderly - a cross-sectional study. J Fam Med Prim Care. 2022;11(11):7294&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1294_22 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_1294_22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn LJ, Stewart JC, Morgan B, Metts ST, Magnuson JM, Iglowski NJ, et al. Instrument-assisted soft tissue mobilization and proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation techniques improve hamstring flexibility better than static stretching alone: a randomized clinical trial. J Man Manip Ther. 2019;27(1):15&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1080/10669817.2018.1475693 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10669817.2018.1475693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30692839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke J, Macchi V, De Caro R, Stecco C. Fascia thickness, aging and flexibility: is there an association? J Anat. 2019;234(1):43&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1111/joa.12902 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.12902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayorga-Vega D, Merino-Marban R, Viciana J. Criterion-related validity of sit-and-reach tests for estimating hamstring and lumbar extensibility: a meta-analysis. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24570599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3918544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa TO, Buzzichelli CA. Periodization: theory and methodology of training. 6th ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5040/9781718225435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7719906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubbs RS, Shoja MM, Loukas M. Bergman&#x2019;s comprehensive encyclopedia of human anatomic variation. Wiley Blackwell; 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781118430309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnar M, Kopp L, Baba V, Rammelt S. Accessory bones at the foot and ankle: a comprehensive review. Fu&#xdf; &amp; Sprunggelenk. 2023;21(2):121&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuspru.2023.05.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuspru.2023.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigg SD, Schroeder JD, Hulsopple C. Femoroacetabular impingement syndrome. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2020;19(9):360&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1249/jsr.0000000000000748 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/jsr.0000000000000748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrell SL, Olson GE, Lynch J. Therapeutic exercise approaches to nonoperative and postoperative management of femoroacetabular impingement syndrome. J Athl Train. 2021;56(1):31&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-0488.19 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-0488.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33112956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7863596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siqueira CM, Rossi A, Shimamoto C, Tanaka C. Balance highly influences flexibility measured by the toe-touch test. Hum Mov Sci. 2018;62:116&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.humov.2018.10.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2018.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Zahiri A, Anvar SH, Goudini R, Hicks JP, et al. Resistance training induces improvements in range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(3):707&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9935664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Mosc&#xe3;o J, Rocha T, Zacca R, Martins A, et al. Strength training versus stretching for improving range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare. 2021;9(4):427. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9040427 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9040427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8067745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ. Adaptations in the passive mechanical properties of skeletal muscle to altered patterns of use. J Appl Physiol. 2018;126(5):1483&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00700.2018 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00700.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30412028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay AD, Baxter BA, Hill MW, Blazevich AJ. Effects of eccentric resistance training on lower-limb passive joint range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55(4):710&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000003085 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000003085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmer JR, Wyles CC, Mara KC, Warner NS, Trousdale RT. Impact of perioperative pain control on knee range of motion and development of arthrofibrosis following primary total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2021;36(2):532&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arth.2020.08.037 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2020.08.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32933800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanks J, Myers B. Validity, reliability, and efficiency of a standard goniometer, medical inclinometer, and builder&#x2019;s inclinometer. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18(4):989&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.83944 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.83944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10399115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srijunto W, Namsawang J, Chaovalit S, Mickevicius M, Muanjai P. Correlations among flexibility, stiffness, strength and muscle ultrasound parameters in older males afflicted with hamstrings tightness. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2024;40:2011&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.10.033 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.10.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39593558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradines M, Ghedira M, Portero R, Masson I, Marciniak C, Hicklin D, et al. Ultrasound structural changes in triceps surae after a 1-year daily self-stretch program: a prospective randomized controlled trial in chronic hemiparesis. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2019;33(4):245&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968319829455 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968319829455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30900512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Wilke J. Do self-myofascial release devices release myofascia? Rolling mechanisms: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2019;49(8):1173&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01149-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01149-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31256353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadhi T, Barakat C, Evangelista AL, Pearson JR, Anand AS, Morrison TEA, et al. Loaded inter-set stretching for muscular adaptations in trained males: is the hype real? Int J Sports Med. 2022;43(2):168&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-1529-6281 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1529-6281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34375990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Alizadeh S, Anvar SH, Fischer J, Manieu J, Behm DG. Static stretch training versus foam rolling training effects on range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2024;54(9):2311&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-024-02041-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02041-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38760635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11393112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Tilp M, Nakamura M. A comparison of the effects of foam rolling and stretching on physical performance. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:720531. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.720531 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.720531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34658909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8514717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Nakamura M, Paternoster FK, Tilp M, Behm DG. A comparison of a single bout of stretching or foam rolling on range of motion in healthy adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2022;122(7):1545&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-022-04927-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-022-04927-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35298696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9197890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke J, M&#xfc;ller AL, Giesche F, Power G, Ahmedi H, Behm DG. Acute effects of foam rolling on range of motion in healthy adults: a systematic review with multilevel meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(2):387&#x2013;402. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01205-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01205-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Lohmann LH, Lichtenstein E, Jochum D, Siegel SD, et al. Foam rolling and stretching do not provide superior acute flexibility and stiffness improvements compared to any other warm-up intervention: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(4):509&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jshs.2024.01.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2024.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38244921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11184403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Olivares-Jabalera J, Andrade R. Time to move from mandatory stretching? We need to differentiate "can i?" from "do i have to?". Front Physiol. 2021;12:Article 714166. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.714166 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Lima CD, Hollander K, Konrad A, Zech A, et al. Physiology of stretch-mediated hypertrophy and strength increases: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2023;53(11):2055&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37556026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10587333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Behm DG, Wirth K, Keiner M, Schiemann S, et al. Effects of chronic static stretching on maximal strength and muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis with meta-regression. Sports Med. 2024;10(1):45. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-024-00706-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00706-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Konrad A. Critical evaluation and recalculation of current systematic reviews with meta-analysis on the effects of acute and chronic stretching on passive properties and passive peak torque. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-024-05564-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05564-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39098977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11568971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi K, Nakamura M, Konrad A, Mizuno T. Long-term static stretching can decrease muscle stiffness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(8):1294&#x2013;306. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14402 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37231582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade RJ, Freitas SR, Hug F, Le Sant G, Lacourpaille L, Gross R, et al. The potential role of sciatic nerve stiffness in the limitation of maximal ankle range of motion. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):14532. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32873-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-32873-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6162234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato M, Nihei Green F, Hotta K, Tsukamoto T, Kurita Y, Kubo A, et al. The efficacy of stretching exercises on arterial stiffness in middle-aged and older adults: a meta-analysis of randomized and non-randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17165643 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17165643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33238565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7700411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikebe H, Takiuchi S, Oi N, Takayanagi Y, Makino A, Itoh M, et al. Effects of trunk stretching using an exercise ball on central arterial stiffness and carotid arterial compliance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2022;122(5):1205&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-022-04912-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-022-04912-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35220498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larouche MC, Camir&#xe9; Bernier S, Racine R, Collin O, Desmons M, Mailloux C, et al. Stretch-induced hypoalgesia: a pilot study. Scand J Pain. 2020;20(4):837&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1515/sjpain-2020-0018 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/sjpain-2020-0018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLemore BH, McLemore SG, Rogers RR, Pederson JA, Williams TD, Marshall MR, et al. Nocebo effects on perceived muscle soreness and exercise performance following unaccustomed resistance exercise: a pilot study. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2020;5(2):40. https://doi.org/10.3390/jfmk5020040 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk5020040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7739351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YB, Gao F, Guo L, Mao ZX. Can placebo and nocebo affect post-exercise executive function? Scand J Psychol. 2023;64(4):430&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1111/sjop.12900 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sjop.12900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36659821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>