<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841071</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Greening Gastroenterology: Strategies to Reduce the Carbon Footprint in Clinical Practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103520</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103520</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103520</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103520</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Climate change is an escalating global health concern, and healthcare delivery contributes meaningfully to environmental impact, with gastroenterology among the more resource-intensive clinical fields. This narrative review explores the environmental footprint of gastroenterology - especially endoscopic practices - and presents actionable strategies to reduce its carbon emissions without compromising care quality. Endoscopic procedures, high in energy consumption and medical waste generation, contribute substantially to the specialty's carbon output. Additional contributors include pharmaceutical waste, inefficient waste management, and travel-related emissions from both patients and professionals. The review identifies several practical interventions, such as promoting combined procedures, reducing unnecessary biopsies, adopting reusable accessories, and implementing telemedicine and virtual conferencing to minimize travel. Sustainable disinfection technologies like plasma-activated gas and UVC light, alongside green pharmacy principles and antibiotic stewardship, are highlighted as promising innovations. Barriers to implementation - ranging from economic and regulatory constraints to clinician resistance - are critically examined, with recommendations to embed sustainability in clinical guidelines, staff training, and procurement practices. Real-world case studies underscore the feasibility and benefits of adopting sustainable gastroenterological practices across varied healthcare settings. Ultimately, the review calls for systemic transformation driven by standardized sustainability metrics, investment in green technologies, and equitable global collaboration. As climate change increasingly intersects with gastrointestinal health, greening gastroenterology is not only feasible but imperative for ensuring both environmental and patient well-being.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Yoon et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Heewon</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razi</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Islamic Azad University of Tehran Medical Sciences, Tehran, IRN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oigara</LastName><ForeName>Moses</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Tenwek Hospital, Nairobi, KEN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sujithkumar</LastName><ForeName>Supreeth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Bhopal, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katoch</LastName><ForeName>Abhilasha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology, Duke University School of Medicine, Durham, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alinkil</LastName><ForeName>Ashrit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Swansea Bay University Health Board, Swansea, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Gurinder</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Medical Sciences, Universidad Especializada de las Am&#xe9;ricas, Panama City, PAN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rai</LastName><ForeName>Manju</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biotechnology, Shri Venkateshwara University, Gajraula, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbon footprint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastroenterology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">green endoscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical waste management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sustainable healthcare</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>How much can optimization of hypofractionation help to reduce carbon equivalent emissions? A single-center modeling study. Vanmarcke D, Holubowska O, Poorthuis A, Mangelschots B, Daisne JF. Adv Radiat Oncol. 2025;10:101781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12142318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40486287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Environmentally sustainable gastroenterology practice: review of current state and future goals. Sonaiya S, Marino R, Agollari K, Sharma P, Desai M. Dig Endosc. 2024;36:406&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37723605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can gastric juice analysis with EndoFaster(&#xae;) reduce the environmental impact of upper endoscopy? Zullo A, Chiovelli F, Esposito E, Hassan C, Casini B. Healthcare (Basel) 2023;11:3186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10742638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbon emissions from patient travel for health care. Zurl H, Qian Z, Stelzl DR, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2025;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11959441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40163116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoping review for the SAGES EAES joint collaborative on sustainability in surgical practice. Huo B, Eussen MM, Marconi S, et al. Surg Endosc. 2024;38:5483&#x2013;5504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The environmental impact of gastrointestinal procedures: a prospective study of waste generation, energy consumption, and auditing in an endoscopy unit. Desai M, Campbell C, Perisetti A, et al. Gastroenterology. 2024;166:496&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38123023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary healthcare's carbon footprint and sustainable strategies to mitigate its contribution: a scoping review. Walsh SJ, O'Leary A, Bergin C, Lee S, Varley &#xc1;, Lynch M. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24:1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11662503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripple effect: safety, cost, and environmental concerns of using sterile water in endoscopy. Agrawal D, Crockett S, Palchaudhuri S, et al. Gastro Hep Adv. 2025;4:100625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12036045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40297529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interventions to reduce surgical waste burden: a systematic review. Vu C, Ibarra-Vega A, Yang CD, et al. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2024;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11338262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39171245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measuring medical waste from gastrointestinal endoscopies in South Korea to estimate their carbon footprint. Jung DH, Lee HJ, Jeon TJ, Cho YS, Kang BR, Youn NS, Cha JM. Gut Liver. 2025;19:43&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11736324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39748648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Design opportunities to reduce waste in operating rooms. Harding C, Van Loon J, Moons I, et al. Sustainability. 2021;13:2207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmaceuticals wastage and pharmaceuticals waste management in public health facilities of Dessie town, North East Ethiopia. Mohammed SA, Kahissay MH, Hailu AD. https://intheloop.mayoclinic.org/2022/12/13/handling-mayos-waste-with-pride-saving-millions-protecting-the-environment-in-the-process/ PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization: 2005. Management of solid health-care waste at primary health-care centres: a decision-making guide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice regarding the disposal of expired and unused medications among the Lebanese population. Hajj A, Domiati S, Haddad C, et al. J Pharm Policy Pract. 2022;15:107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9802024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36585685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disposal practices of unused and expired medicines among the general public and pharmacies: a mixed-method study in the Odisha state of eastern India. Kanyari SS, Senapati TR, Kar A. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10867696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38361720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health care waste management: a neglected and growing public health problem worldwide. Harhay MO, Halpern SD, Harhay JS, Olliaro PL. Trop Med Int Health. 2009;14:1414&#x2013;1417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safe medication disposal: need to sensitize undergraduate students. Aditya S. https://ijplsjournal.com/index.php/ijpls/article/view/698 Int J Pharm Life Sci. 2013;4:2475&#x2013;2480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker J. Minding the gap: research priorities to address pharmaceuticals in the environment. Health Care Without Harm, Health Care Research Collaborative. 2011. https://global.noharm.org/media/3877/download?inline=1  https://global.noharm.org/media/3877/download?inline=1 </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reducing the environmental impact of health care conferences: a study of emissions and practical solutions. Lichter KE, Sabbagh A, Demeulenaere S, et al. JCO Glob Oncol. 2024;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38359373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healthcare waste management practices and risk perceptions: findings from hospitals in the Algarve region, Portugal. Ferreira V, Teixeira MR. Waste Manag. 2010;30:2657&#x2013;2663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20713307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The environmental impact of small-bowel capsule endoscopy. Pioche M, Cunha Neves JA, Pohl H, et al. Endoscopy. 2024;56:737&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38657660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficiency and effectiveness of medical waste management performance, healthcare sector and its impact on environment in Jordan: an applied study. Al-Habash M, Al-Zu'bi A. https://nswai.org/docs/Efficiency%20and%20Effecteviness%20of%20Medical%20Waste%20Management%20Performance,.pdf World Appl Sci J. 2012;19:880&#x2013;893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reducing the environmental footprint of gastrointestinal endoscopy: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) and European Society of Gastroenterology and Endoscopy Nurses and Associates (ESGENA) Position Statement. Rodr&#xed;guez de Santiago E, Dinis-Ribeiro M, Pohl H, et al. Endoscopy. 2022;54:797&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35803275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interventions to achieve environmentally sustainable operating theatres: an umbrella systematic review using the behaviour change wheel. Almukhtar A, Batcup C, Bowman M, et al. Int J Surg. 2024;110:7245&#x2013;7267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11573083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39093843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart endoscopy is greener endoscopy: leveraging artificial intelligence and blockchain technologies to drive sustainability in digestive health care. Mascarenhas M, Ribeiro T, Afonso J, et al. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023;13:3625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10743290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green endoscopy: practical implementation. Donnelly L. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2022;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35812035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steps toward a greener endoscopy unit. de Jong D, Volkers A, de Ridder E, Neijenhuis M, Duijvestein M. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;21:2723&#x2013;2726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37330119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endoscopic Sustainability PrimAry Reporting Essentials (E-SPARE): European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) position statement. Cunha Neves JA, Baddeley R, Pohl H, et al. Endoscopy. 2025;57:674&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40112835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reprocessing and reuse of endoscopic accessories. Bhatia V, Bhardwaj V, Tevethia HV. J Dig Endosc. 2021;12:214&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single-use versus reusable endoscopes in gastroenterology: systematic review of full and partial economic evaluations. Zanganeh M, Jiang Y, Waugh N, Brown A, Chen YF, Arasaradnam RP, Andronis L. Endosc Int Open. 2025;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12372419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40860688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endoscopy and its alternatives in resource-limited countries in Africa. Asombang A, Bhat P. Tech Innov Gastrointest Endosc. 2024;26:283&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical waste reprocessing: injection molding using recycled blue wrapping paper from the operating room. van Straten B, van der Heiden DR, Robertson D, et al. J Clean Prod. 2021;322:129121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handling Mayo's waste with pride, saving millions, protecting the environment in the process. 2022. https://intheloop.mayoclinic.org/2022/12/13/handling-mayos-waste-with-pride-saving-millions-protecting-the-environment-in-the-process/ https://intheloop.mayoclinic.org/2022/12/13/handling-mayos-waste-with-pride-saving-millions-protecting-the-environment-in-the-process/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transitioning to office-based transperineal prostate biopsy&#x2014;a case study from a regional New Zealand hospital in economic and environmental sustainability. Martin C, Maoate K, Hooshyari A, Ordones FV, Vermeulen LP. Urology. 2025;203:53&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40174801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbon footprinting and environmental impact of gastrointestinal endoscopy procedures at a tertiary care institution: a prospective multi-dimensional assessment. Rughwani H, Kalapala R, Katrevula A, et al. Gut. 2025;74:926&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39904605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greener gastroenterology and hepatology: the British Society of Gastroenterology strategy for climate change and sustainability. Veitch AM. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2022;13:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35812022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targeted intervention to achieve waste reduction in gastrointestinal endoscopy. Cunha Neves JA, Roseira J, Queir&#xf3;s P, Sousa HT, Pellino G, Cunha MF. Gut. 2023;72:306&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35985798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>APAGE Position Statements on Green and Sustainability in Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Gastrointestinal Endoscopy.  [
Jan;
2026 
];Ang TL, Hang DV, Li JW, et al.  https://www.apagemit.org. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2025 40:821&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39888113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing the energy efficiency improvement potentials of HVAC systems considering economic and environmental aspects at hospitals. Teke A, Timur O. Renew Sustain Energy Rev. 2014;33:224&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmaceutical waste management: an overview. Kadam A, Patil S, Patil S, et al. Indian J Pharm Pract. 2016;9:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practices and challenges of infectious waste management: a qualitative descriptive study from tertiary care hospitals in Pakistan. Kumar R, Shaikh BT, Somrongthong R, Chapman RS. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4590381/ Pak J Med Sci. 2015;31:795&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4590381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26430405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmaceutical waste management in pharmacies in Serbia. Manojlovi&#x107; J, Jovanovi&#x107; V, Georgiev AM, et al. Indian J Pharm Educ Res. 2015;49:106&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of medical waste on indigenous communities in Balochistan Pakistan: sustainable solutions in reducing inequality and improving resilience in communities. Ullah S, Khan U, Jan Q, Saifuddin T. Ann Glob Health. 2025;91:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12047633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40321459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Views of health professionals on climate change and health: a multinational survey study. Kotcher J, Maibach E, Miller J, Campbell E, Alqodmani L, Maiero M, Wyns A. Lancet Planet Health. 2021;5:0&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green endoscopy: British Society of Gastroenterology (BSG), Joint Accreditation Group (JAG) and Centre for Sustainable Health (CSH) joint consensus on practical measures for environmental sustainability in endoscopy. Sebastian S, Dhar A, Baddeley R, et al. Gut. 2023;72:12&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sustainability in surgical practice: a collaborative call toward environmental sustainability in operating rooms. Johnson SM, Marconi S, Sanchez-Casalongue M, et al. Surg Endosc. 2024;38:4127&#x2013;4137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11289051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38951239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digital technologies and carbon neutrality goals: an in-depth investigation of drivers, barriers, and risk mitigation strategies. Bhatia M, Meenakshi N, Kaur P, et al. J Clean Prod. 2024;451:141946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative efficacy evaluation of disinfectants routinely used in hospital practice: India. Singh M, Sharma R, Gupta PK, Rana JK, Sharma M, Taneja N. Indian J Crit Care Med. 2012;16:123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3506067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23188950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison on the efficacy of disinfectants used in automated endoscope reprocessors: PHMB-DBAC versus orthophthalaldehyde. Kim SY, Lee HS, Hyun JJ, et al. Clin Endosc. 2011;44:109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3363059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22741121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review of digestive endoscopy-associated infections: bacterial pathogens, host susceptibility, and the impact of viral hepatitis. G&#xfc;n&#x219;ahin D, &#x218;andru V, Constantinescu G, et al. Microorganisms. 2025;13:2128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12472210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41011458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutala WA, Weber DJ. Mandell, Douglas, and Bennett's Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases. Vol. 2. Elsevier; 2015. Disinfection, sterilization, and control of hospital waste; pp. 3294&#x2013;3309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of low-temperature plasma-activated gas disinfection against biofilm on contaminated GI endoscope channels. Bhatt S, Mehta P, Chen C, Schneider CL, White LN, Chen HL, Kong MG. Gastrointest Endosc. 2019;89:105&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30120959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of ultraviolet light disinfection on reducing hospital-associated infections: a systematic review in healthcare environments. Maugeri A, Casini B, Esposito E, et al. J Hosp Infect. 2025;159:32&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39924116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameer MA, Foris LA, Mandiga P, et al. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Spontaneous Bacterial Peritonitis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28846337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of sterilization of reusable endoscopic biopsy forceps by autoclaving and ethylene oxide gas. Yoon JH, Yoon BC, Lee HL, et al. Dig Dis Sci. 2012;57:405&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adverse effects associated with long-term use of proton pump inhibitors. Maideen NM. Chonnam Med J. 2023;59:115&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10248387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37303818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anti-Helicobacter pylori, anti-inflammatory, and antioxidant activities of trunk bark of Alstonia boonei (Apocynaceae) Fagni Njoya ZL, Mbiantcha M, Djuichou Nguemnang SF, et al. Biomed Res Int. 2022;2022:9022135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9499789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36158881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integration of biological pre-treatment methods for increased energy recovery from paper and pulp biosludge. Chakraborty D, Shelvapulle S, Reddy KR, Kulkarni RV, Puttaiahgowda YM, Naveen S, Raghu AV. J Microbiol Methods. 2019;160:93&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30890400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recommendations emerging from carbon emissions estimations of the Society for Neuroscience annual meeting. Kay C, Kuper R, Becker EA. eNeuro. 2023;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37739787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of the COVID-19 pandemic on climate change summit negotiations from the climate governance perspective. Vo TP, Ngo HH, Guo W, et al. Sci Total Environ. 2023;878:162936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10023208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36934916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development and evaluation of an international teleproctoring program for bronchoscopic procedures. Conway FM, Tana A, Caneja C, et al. iScience. 2025;28:111653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11889662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40060899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An analysis of ways to decarbonize conference travel after COVID-19. Kl&#xf6;wer M, Hopkins D, Allen M, Higham J. Nature. 2020;583:356&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trend towards virtual and hybrid conferences may be an effective climate change mitigation strategy. Tao Y, Steckel D, Kleme&#x161; JJ, You F. Nat Commun. 2021;12:7324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence in gastrointestinal cancers: Diagnostic, prognostic, and surgical strategies. Nagaraju GP, Sandhya T, Srilatha M, Ganji SP, Saddala MS, El-Rayes BF. Cancer Lett. 2025;612:217461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12677147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39809357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revolutionizing Healthcare: How telemedicine is improving patient outcomes and expanding access to care. Ezeamii VC, Okobi OE, Wambai-Sani H, et al. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11298029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39099901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single-use accessories and endoscopes in the era of sustainability and climate change: a balancing act. Nabi Z, Tang RS, Sundaram S, Lakhtakia S, Reddy DN. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2024;39:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strategies to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from laparoscopic surgery. Thiel CL, Woods NC, Bilec MM. Am J Public Health. 2018;108:0&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29698098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleaning and disinfecting gastrointestinal endoscopy equipment. Lichtenstein D, Alfa MJ. Clinical Gastrointestinal Endoscopy. 2019:32&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low-cost disposable endoscope: pros and cons. Cioc&#xee;rlan M. Endosc Int Open. 2019;7:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6715437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31479502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of surgery on global climate: a carbon footprinting study of operating theatres in three health systems. MacNeill AJ, Lillywhite R, Brown PCJ. https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanplh/article/PIIS2542-519630162-6/fulltext Lancet Planet Health. 2017;1:381&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29851650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health care&#x2019;s climate footprint: the health sector contribution and opportunities for action. Karliner J, Slotterback S, Boyd R, et al. Eur J Public Health. 2020;30:165&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reducing pollution from the health care industry. Sherman JD, MacNeill A, Thiel C. JAMA. 2019;322:1043&#x2013;1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31373600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simulation of hospital waste supply chain in the context of Industry 4.0 - a systematic literature review. Ferreira A, Ramos AL, Ferreira JV, et al. Sustainability. 2024;16:6187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtually perfect? Telemedicine for Covid-19. Hollander JE, Carr BG. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1679&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32160451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The environmental footprint of health care: a global assessment. Lenzen M, Malik A, Li M, et al. Lancet Planet Health. 2020;4:271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delivering a net zero NHS. 2020. https://www.england.nhs.uk/greenernhs/a-net-zero-nhs/ https://www.england.nhs.uk/greenernhs/a-net-zero-nhs/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>