<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41559817</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2056-7529</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research involvement and engagement</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Involv Engagem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Notes about me, without me: Research about me, without me.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40900-025-00830-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In mental health services, documentation is dominated by providers who write clinical notes without the input of the individuals accessing the services. Although these notes are essential, they often exclude the voices and perspectives of those accessing services. We suggest that this one-sided approach can lead to feelings of alienation, loss of agency, and misrepresentation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN BODY" NlmCategory="METHODS">Our commentary explores co-writing, an approach to documentation where both the provider and the person accessing services jointly contribute to the notes. Co-writing can include various formats, from typed notes to drawings or dictated content, reflecting a more inclusive process. We present co-writing not just as a practical innovation but as an ethical shift aligned with ethics of care and concepts of care. We propose that by inviting individuals to co-author their narratives, co-writing offers opportunities to challenge traditional power imbalances in mental health services and improve the accuracy, emotional relevance, and inclusivity of documentation. We also suggest and examine the limitations and challenges of implementing co-writing, such as provider resistance, time constraints, and ethical considerations around consent and confidentiality. Strategies such as professional training, mentorship, and clear guidelines are suggested to support sustainable implementation. Although co-writing is promoted as a collaborative documentation practice, our analysis reveals that the research underpinning it rarely involves people with lived experience leading or co-creating the research. We present a commentary that critically points out that gap and calls for the co-writing of the evidence base itself to inform practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We suggest that co-writing clinical notes has the potential to transform mental health documentation from a provider-dominated task into a collaborative, empowering process. It offers a more ethical and accurate representation of individuals' experiences. We call for further research led by people with lived experience, and for the development of policies, training, and infrastructure that support the ethical integration of co-writing into mental health services.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahir-Knight</LastName><ForeName>Snita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, University of Otago-&#x14c;t&#x101;kou Whakaihu Waka, Wellington, Aotearoa, New Zealand. snita.ahir-knight@otago.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, University of Otago-&#x14c;t&#x101;kou Whakaihu Waka, Wellington, Aotearoa, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Res Involv Engagem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101708164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2056-7529</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>In mental health services, notes are usually written by providers without involving the person accessing the service. Although these notes are important, we suggest that this one-sided approach can leave people feeling misunderstood, disempowered, or invisible, and these are feelings that can negatively affect engagement in services. This commentary explores an alternative approach called co-writing, where providers and individuals work together to write one shared set of notes. This might involve typing, talking, drawing, or other creative ways of documenting experiences. Co-writing makes the process more inclusive, giving people a chance to tell their own story and be heard. We suggest that by enabling shared authorship, co-writing can help people feel more in control when accessing services. Although co-writing is promoted as a collaborative documentation practice, we reveal that the research underpinning it rarely involves people with lived experience leading or co-creating the research. We critically examine that gap and call for the co-writing of the evidence base itself to inform practice. We also look at challenges, like time pressures or concerns from providers, and suggest ways to make co-writing more practical in mental health services, such as training staff, using clear guidelines, and creating supportive environments. In conclusion, we suggest that co-writing has the potential to make documentation more empowering, accurate, and ethical, ultimately improving the quality of people&#x2019;s experiences within mental health services. However, more research, especially by people with lived experience, is needed to help guide its wider use.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical notes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-writing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Codocumentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Collaborative documentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent documentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethics of care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indigenous concepts of care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lived experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health documentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient involvement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41559817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12822283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-025-00830-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40900-025-00830-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Isenberg BM, Chu W, Boyd MR, Knudsen KS, Becker KD, Keenan-Miller D, Chorpita BF. A qualitative study of school mental health providers&#x2019; experiences with chart notes: perceived utility, burden, and areas for growth. Evid Based Pract Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2024;10:136&#x2013;53. 10.1080/23794925.2024.2426185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23794925.2024.2426185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter MD, Sabo K. Writing progress notes. In: Reiter MD, editor. A therapist&#x2019;s guide to writing in psychotherapy: Assessment, documentation, and intervention. New York: Routledge; 2023. pp. 18&#x2013;41. 10.4324/9781003294702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hagan M. Madness made me: A memoir. Auckland, NZ: Mary Egan Publishing; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam S, Gold E, Burstow B. From subjective opinion to medical fact: A critical discourse analysis of mental health nursing education. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2023;44(1):55&#x2013;63. 10.1080/01612840.2022.2113940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01612840.2022.2113940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35994049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albeck JH, Goldman C. Patient-therapist codocumentation: implications of jointly authored progress notes for psychotherapy practice, research, training, supervision, and risk management. Am J Psychother. 1991;XLV:317&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.psychotherapy.1991.45.3.317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1951785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faccio E, Pocobello R, Vitelli R, Stanghellini G. Grounding co-writing: an analysis of the theoretical basis of a new approach in mental health care. J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2023;30:123&#x2013;31. 10.1111/jpm.12835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpm.12835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10084039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter MD, Bibliowicz V, Sabo K, Yu XC, Delgado Y, Barrionuevo D, Rich B. Collaborative documentation: therapist experiences in jointly writing progress notes. J Syst Ther. 2022;41:1&#x2013;16. 10.1521/jsyt.2022.41.2.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/jsyt.2022.41.2.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander J, Rogers K, Simpson R, Rigby P. The value of client held records. Ment Health Nurs. 2002;22(6):12&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Person-centred recovery planning for mental health and well-being self-help tool. WHO QualityRights; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams C, Nassar EL, Nordlund J, Hu S, Rice DB, Cook V, Boruff J, Thombs BD. Engagement of people with lived experience in studies published in high-impact psychiatry journals: Meta-research review. Res Involv Engagem. 2024;10:115. 10.1186/s40900-024-00651-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-024-00651-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11539569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39508249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawke LD, Sheikhan NY, Roberts S, McKee S Research evidence and implementation gaps in the engagement of people with lived experience in mental health and substance use research: a scoping review. Res Involv Engagem. 2023;9(1):32. . 10.1186/s40900-023-00442-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-023-00442-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37170357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO framework for meaningful engagement of people living with noncommunicable diseases, and mental health and neurological conditions. WHO; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilligan C. In a different voice: psychological theory and women&#x2019;s development. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press; 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noddings N. Caring: A feminine approach to ethics and moral education. Berkeley, CA: University of California Press; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durie M. Mauri ora: the dynamics of M&#x101;ori health. Melbourne: Oxford University Press; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waitoki W, Levy M, editors. Te Manu Kai i Te matauranga: Indigenous psychology in Aotearoa/New Zealand. Wellington: New Zealand Psychological Society; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decker SE, Farook MW, Meshberg-Cohen S, Matsuura T, Manning M, Abel EA, Blakley L, Prelli F. Clinical Documentation of patient identities in the electronic health record: ethical principles to consider. Psychol Serv. 2024;21(3):589&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/ser0000816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37917474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulff SGS. Integrating the client&#x2019;s voice within case reports. J Syst Ther. 1998;17:3&#x2013;13. 10.1521/jsyt.1998.17.4.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/jsyt.1998.17.4.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacigalupe G. Writing in therapy: A participatory approach. J Fam Ther. 1996;18:361&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-6427.1996.tb00057.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiCarlo R, Garcia YE Electronic record keeping and psychotherapy alliance: the role of concurrent collaborative Documentation. In: Tettegah SY, Garcia YE, editors. Emotions, Technology, and Health. Academic; 2016. pp. 63&#x2013;82. 10.1016/B978-0-12-801737-1.00004-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan L, Lewicki T. Collaborative Documentation in mental health: applications to rehabilitation counseling. Rehabil Res Pol Educ. 2016;30:305&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/2168-6653.30.3.305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badding NC. Client involvement in case recording. Social Casework: J Contemp Social Work. 1989;70(9):539&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104438948907000903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott A, Doughty C. Confronted with paperwork: information and Documentation in peer support. J Ment Health. 2012;21:154&#x2013;64. 10.3109/09638237.2011.638002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638237.2011.638002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22251074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthew EB. Computer use in mental health treatment: Understanding collaborative Documentation and its effect on the therapeutic alliance. Psychotherapy. 2019;57:119&#x2013;28. 10.1037/pst0000254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pst0000254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31599638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo N, Matthews E, Baslock D, Stanhope V. Impact of collaborative Documentation on completeness and length of clinical notes in behavioral health settings. Psychiatr Serv. 2024;75:186&#x2013;90. 10.1176/appi.ps.2023011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.2023011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37528697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myklebust KK, Hoemsnes H, Kvello &#xd8;, Vatnar SKB Collaboration with clients to create journal notes: a mixed methods evaluation of a pilot intervention study in a municipality mental health services team. Couns Psychother Res. 2024;25. 10.1002/capr.12829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grantham D. Concurrent Documentation wins trifecta. Behav Health. 2010;30:32&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21114243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker P, Buchanan-Barker P. The tidal model of mental health recovery and reclamation: application in acute care settings. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2010;31(3):171&#x2013;80. 10.3109/01612840903276696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/01612840903276696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20144029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmos-Vega FM, Stalmeijer RE, Varpio L, Kahlke R. A practical guide to reflexivity in qualitative research: AMEE guide 149. Med. Teach. 2023;45(3):241&#x2013;51. 10.1080/0142159X.2022.2057287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2022.2057287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35389310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodgson JE. Reflexivity in qualitative research. J Hum Lact. 2019;35(2):220&#x2013;2. 10.1177/0890334419830990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0890334419830990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30849272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson MK, Govaart GH, Pownall M. Reflexivity in quantitative research: A rationale and beginner&#x2019;s guide. Soc Personal Psychol Compass. 2023;17(4):e12735. 10.1111/spc3.12735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/spc3.12735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>