<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41657781</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1728-869X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise science and fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Sci Fit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>"Phoenix Rising": A scoping review on the impacts of dragon boating exercise on well-being among breast cancer survivors and factors affecting their participation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>200453</StartPage><MedlinePgn>200453</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">200453</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jesf.2026.200453</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Breast cancer survivors (BCS) often experience declines in physical and psychosocial well-being post-treatment, making supportive interventions essential. Dragon boating(team-based paddling in a long boat) has emerged as a promising, popular exercise for BCS. However, no comprehensive reviews exist on its impacts or participation factors. This scoping review addressed these gaps by examining two research questions (RQ): RQ1) the impacts of dragon boating on BCS' well-being, and RQ2) facilitators and barriers influencing their participation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seven databases (PubMed, Embase, CINAHL, Web of Science, PsycInfo, Scopus, CNKI) were used to search for eligible studies from January 1996 to November 2025 involving BCS engaging in dragon boating. Screening from 245 records, 33 articles (18 quantitative, 14 qualitative, 1 mixed-methods) were identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among studies addressing RQ1 (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;27), 24 studies reported at least one benefit on well-being. Dragon boating improved BCS' physical functioning (e.g., upper limb strength, range of motion), psychosocial well-being(e.g.,mental health, posttraumatic growth), and health behaviors(healthier lifestyle), without increasing lymphedema risk. Benefits on biochemical indicators (e.g., anti-inflammatory markers/antioxidant capacity) were less conclusive. For RQ2 (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;10), common facilitators for joining dragon boating were social support, focus away from cancer, information sharing, and being physically active/competitive; common barriers included feeling not fit enough to participate, reminders of death/cancer recurrence, concerns about cancer identity disclosure, time commitment, and location constraints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Most studies demonstrated the benefits of dragon boating for BCS' physical and psychosocial well-being, but evidence did not support its superiority to other activities. To maximize impacts, addressing facilitators/barriers of participation will be important when designing and implementing dragon boating programs for BCS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Society of Chinese Scholars on Exercise Physiology and Fitness. Published by Elsevier (Singapore) Pte Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeung</LastName><ForeName>Nelson Chun Yiu</ForeName><Initials>NCY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tam</LastName><ForeName>Victor Chi Wing</ForeName><Initials>VCW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie Tsz Yung</ForeName><Initials>STY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Lihua</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ng</LastName><ForeName>Sze Nok</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jockey Club School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shy</LastName><ForeName>Deng Yau</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, National Taiwan Normal University, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sum</LastName><ForeName>Raymond Kim Wai</ForeName><Initials>RKW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Physical Education, Faculty of Education, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Singapore</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Sci Fit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101198241</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1728-869X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Barriers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dragon boating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Facilitators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Well-being</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Raymond Kim Wai Sum is a member of the Editoral Board of Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness. Raymond Sum was not involved in the journal's peer review process of, or decision related to, this manuscript. The other authors have no conflicts of interest relevant to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41657781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12874123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2026.200453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1728-869X(26)00014-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Cancer Fund. Breast Cancer Survivors: How Diet, Nutrition, Physical Activity and Breast Cancer Survivors.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann F.T., Reike A., Reimer V., et al. Effects of physical exercise on breast cancer-related secondary lymphedema: a systematic review. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2018;170:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell T.L., Yakiwchuk C.V., Griffin K.L., et al. Survivor dragon boating: a vehicle to reclaim and enhance life after treatment for breast cancer. Health Care Women Int. 2007;28:122&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J., Lee M.G. Effects of exercise interventions on breast cancer patients during adjuvant therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cancer Nurs. 2020;43:115&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong F., Ye W., Kuo C., et al. Exercise intervention improves clinical outcomes, but the "time of session" is crucial for better quality of life in breast cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancers. 2019;11:706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6562879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31121916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odynets T., Briskin Y., Todorova V. Effects of different exercise interventions on quality of life in breast cancer patients: a randomized controlled trial. Integr Cancer Ther. 2019;18:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6801883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31625419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie D.C. Abreast in a Boat-a race against breast cancer. Can Med Assoc J. 1998;159:376&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1229603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9732719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris S.R. "We're all in the same boat": a review of the benefits of dragon boat racing for women living with breast cancer. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012;2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3395246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22811743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero-Zapirain I., &#xc1;lvarez-Pardo S., Casta&#xf1;eda-Babarro A., et al. The effect of dragon boating on the quality of life for breast cancer survivors: a systematic review. Healthcare. 2024;12:1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11241423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38998825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunet J., Sabiston C.M., Meterissian S. Physical activity and breast cancer survivorship: evidence-based recommendations. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2012;6:224&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavallee J.F., Abdin S., Faulkner J., et al. Barriers and facilitators to participating in physical activity for adults with breast cancer receiving adjuvant treatment: a qualitative metasynthesis. Psychooncology. 2019;28:468&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D., Colquhoun H., O'Brien K.K. vol. 5. BioMed Central Ltd; 2010. pp. 1&#x2013;9. (Scoping Studies: Advancing the Methodology).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters M.D., Godfrey C.M., Khalil H., et al. Guidance for conducting systematic scoping reviews. JBI Evid Implement. 2015;13:141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26134548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani M., Hammady H., Fedorowicz Z., et al. Rayyan-a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2016;5:210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5139140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H., O'Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8:19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson C.A., Kennedy K., Jackson K.T. Trauma-informed approaches in the context of cancer care in Canada and the United States: a scoping review. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2023;24:2983&#x2013;2996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10594848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36086877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco A.C., Lillie E., Zarin W., et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Q.N., Gonzalez-Reyes A., Pluye P. Improving the usefulness of a tool for appraising the quality of qualitative, quantitative and mixed methods studies, the Mixed Methods Appraisal Tool (MMAT) J Eval Clin Pract. 2018;24:459&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman C., Evans R., Drever N., et al. Barriers and facilitators for female practitioners in orthopaedic training and practice: a scoping review. ANZ J Surg. 2025;95:647&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11982664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39754372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachholz P.A., De Oliveira D.C., Hinsliff-Smith K., et al. Mapping research conducted on long-term care facilities for older people in Brazil: a scoping review. Int J Environ Res Publ Health. 2021;18:1522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih T.L., Shy D.Y., Lin C.Y., et al. The efficacy of dragon boat training in improving the upper extremity function in breast cancer patients. Taipei City Medical Journal. 2017;14:161&#x2013;170. [In Chinese, English abstract]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane K., Jespersen D., McKenzie D.C. The effect of a whole body exercise programme and dragon boat training on arm volume and arm circumference in women treated for breast cancer. Eur J Cancer Care. 2005;14:353&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T., Casolo A., Bordignon V., et al. Keep calm and keep rowing: the psychophysical effects of dragon boat program in breast cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32:218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10924022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38456933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacorossi L., Gambalunga F., Molinaro S., et al. The effectiveness of the sport "dragon boat racing" in reducing the risk of lymphedema incidence: an observational study. Cancer Nurs. 2019;42:323&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denieffe S., Castineira C., Denny M. The impact of dragon boating for fatigue in cancer survivors. J Nurse Pract. 2021;17:1019&#x2013;1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchiorri G., Viero V., Triossi T., et al. New approach to evaluate late arm impairment and effects of dragon boat activity in breast cancer survivors. Medicine. 2017;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5682787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29095268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galanti G., Pedrizzetti G., Pedri S., et al. 2D longitudinal LV speckle tracking strain pattern in breast cancer survivors: sports activity vs exercise as prescription model. Intern Emerg Med. 2017;12:1149&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28875298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris S.R., Niesen-Vertommen S.L. Challenging the myth of exercise&#x2010;induced lymphedema following breast cancer: a series of case reports. J Surg Oncol. 2000;74:95&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10914817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeer B., Seller A., Schoenfisch B., et al. The impact of rehabilitation sport on breast cancer-related lymphoedema and quality of life. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023;307:1529&#x2013;1537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10110661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry D.C. The contribution of dragon boat racing to women's health and breast cancer survivorship. Qual Health Res. 2008;18:222&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18216341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabiston C.M., McDonough M.H., Crocker P.R. Psychosocial experiences of breast cancer survivors involved in a dragon boat program: exploring links to positive psychological growth. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2007;29:419&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17968046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unruh A.M., Elvin N. In the eye of the dragon: women's experience of breast cancer and the occupation of dragon boat racing. Can J Occup Ther. 2004;71:138&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15366630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough M.H., Sabiston C.M., Crocker P.R.E. An interpretative phenomenological examination of psychosocial changes among breast cancer survivors in their first season of dragon boating. J Appl Sport Psychol. 2008;20:425&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guinto-Adviento M.L., Zavala M.A.O. &#x201c;I am a complete woman&#x201d;: dragon boat and breast cancer survival. Rev Iberoam Psicol Ejerc Deporte. 2017;26:12&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montorsi M., Vezzoli A., Sposta F.M., et al. Systemic responses towards oxy-inflammation, hormones, and mood in breast cancer survivors: preliminary evidences from dragon boat endurance race. J Clin Med. 2025;14:2532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11989338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40217981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tresoldi I., Foti C., Masuelli L., et al. Effects of dragon boat training on cytokine production and oxidative stress in breast cancer patients: a pilot study. Open J Immunol. 2014;4:22&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasello B., Malfa G.A., Strazzanti A., et al. Effects of physical activity on systemic oxidative/DNA status in breast cancer survivors. Oncol Lett. 2017;13:441&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5245100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefani L., Galanti G., Di Tante V., et al. Dragon boat training exerts a positive effect on myocardial function in breast cancer survivors. Phys Sportsmed. 2015;43:307&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25882745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giganti M.G., Tresoldi I., Sorge R., et al. Physical exercise modulates the level of serum MMP-2 and MMP-9 in patients with breast cancer. Oncol Lett. 2016;12:2119&#x2013;2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27602150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry D.C. &#x201c;There is life after breast cancer&#x201d;: nine vignettes exploring dragon boat racing for breast cancer survivors. Leis Sci. 2007;29:53&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry D.C. Dragon boat racing for breast cancer survivors: leisure as a context for spiritual outcomes. Leisure. 2009;33:317&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell T., Nielsen E. Living life to the limits: dragon boaters and breast cancer. Can Womens Stu. 2002;21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray H.A., Verhoef M.J. Dragon boat racing and health-related quality of life of breast cancer survivors: a mixed-methods evaluation. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2013;13:205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23915045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fioretti C., Coppola S., Boscaino S., et al. The effectiveness of dragon boat racing on body image and traumatic symptoms of breast cancer patients. Health Psychol Res. 2024;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11196124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38915786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough M.H., Patterson M.C., Weisenbach B.B., et al. The difference is more than floating: factors affecting breast cancer survivors' decisions to join and maintain participation in dragon boat teams and support groups. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41:1788&#x2013;1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29521150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadd V., Sabiston C.M., McDonough M.H., et al. Sources of stress for breast cancer survivors involved in dragon boating: examining associations with treatment characteristics and self-esteem. J Womens Health. 2010;19:1345&#x2013;1353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20528480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisenbach B.B., McDonough M.H. Breast cancer survivors' decisions to join a dragon boating team. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2014;36:564&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25602139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough M.H., Sabiston C.M., Ullrich-French S. The development of social relationships, social support, and posttraumatic growth in a dragon boating team for breast cancer survivors. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2011;33:627&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21984639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya K.S., Blanchard C.M., Laing D.M. Exercise adherence in breast cancer survivors training for a dragon boat race competition: a preliminary investigation. Psychooncology. 2001;10:444&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culos-Reed S.N., Shields C., Brawley L.R. Breast cancer survivors involved in vigorous team physical activity: psychosocial correlates of maintenance participation. Psychooncology. 2005;14:594&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15549723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong A.J., Saxton H.R., Kauffeldt K.D., et al. &#x201c;We&#x2019;re all in the same boat together&#x201d;: exploring quality participation strategies in dragon boat teams for breast cancer survivors. Disabil Rehabil. 2021;43:3078&#x2013;3089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32126196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson N.L. Breast cancer-related lymphedema and resistance exercise: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:2656&#x2013;2665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26840439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton E., Kindermann G., Domegan C., et al. Blue care: a systematic review of blue space interventions for health and well-being. Health Promot Int. 2020;35:50&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30561661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wurz A., St-Aubin A., Brunet J. Breast cancer survivors' barriers and motives for participating in a group-based physical activity program offered in the community. Support Care Cancer. 2015;23:2407&#x2013;2416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25605568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunet J., Taran S., Burke S., et al. A qualitative exploration of barriers and motivators to physical activity participation in women treated for breast cancer. Disabil Rehabil. 2013;35:2038&#x2013;2045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23772995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alejandre J.C., Chastin S., Irvine K.N., et al. Contextual factors and programme theories associated with implementing blue prescription programmes: a systematic realist review. Health Soc Care Community. 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdin S., Lavallee J.F., Faulkner J., et al. A systematic review of the effectiveness of physical activity interventions in adults with breast cancer by physical activity type and mode of participation. Psychooncology. 2019;28:1381&#x2013;1393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31041830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd A., Moyer A. Group versus individual exercise interventions for women with breast cancer: a meta-analysis. Health Psychol Rev. 2009;4:22&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20607139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung N.C.Y., Lu Q., Mak W.W.S. Self-perceived burden mediates the relationship between self-stigma and quality of life among Chinese American breast cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2019;27:3337&#x2013;3345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>