<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41432635</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a Congested Match Schedule on Isometric Muscle Strength Performance in Elite Futsal Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e397</StartPage><EndPage>e403</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e397-e403</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005346</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gantois, P, Farinha, A, Fonseca, FdS, and Ribeiro, J. Effects of a congested match schedule on isometric muscle strength performance in elite futsal players. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): e397-e403, 2026-This study investigated the effects of a congested tournament schedule on isometric muscle strength performance in elite futsal players. Twelve elite-level outfield male futsal players (mean &#xb1; SD : age = 27.42 &#xb1; 5.60 years, body mass = 76.74 &#xb1; 8.91 kg, and height = 1.75 &#xb1; 0.04 m) from a top-tier Portuguese league team participated in this study. Postmatch neuromuscular fatigue was assessed by measuring the isometric strength of the hip adductors, abductors, and knee flexors on both dominant and nondominant sides. Baseline measurements (MD1) were taken before the first match, with follow-up tests conducted at 24 hours (MD2), 48 hours (rest day), and 72 hours (MD3) postbaseline. Adductor muscle strength in the dominant limb reduced significantly at MD2 ( p = 0.026; effect size [ES] = 0.20) and rest day ( p = 0.045; ES = 0.28) compared with MD1. Dominant-side hip abduction strength was significantly lower at MD2 ( p = 0.003; ES = 0.62), on the rest day ( p &lt; 0.005; ES = 0.56), and at MD3 ( p = 0.045; ES = 0.41) relative to baseline. No significant changes were found in knee flexor strength across time points ( p &gt; 0.05). In conclusion, these findings indicate that a congested schedule reduced hip adduction and abduction strength among elite futsal players, with prolonged decreases in hip abduction strength. By contrast, hip adduction strength displayed faster recovery after a rest day.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gantois</LastName><ForeName>Petrus</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Associate Graduate Program in Physical Education UPE/UFPB, Department of Physical Education, Jo&#xe3;o Pessoa, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Performance Optimization, GOD, Sporting Clube de Braga SAD, Braga, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farinha</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Performance Optimization, GOD, Sporting Clube de Braga SAD, Braga, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fonseca</LastName><ForeName>Fabiano de Souza</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal Rural University of Pernambuco (UFRPE), Department of Physical Education, Recife-PE, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Performance Optimization, GOD, Sporting Clube de Braga SAD, Braga, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development (CIDESD), University of Maia, Maia, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training load</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41432635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barreira J, Gantois P, Castro J, et al. Using bar velocity to assess post-match neuromuscular fatigue in young soccer players. Int J Sports Med 45: 589&#x2013;597, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 14: 377&#x2013;381, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstein CG, Dent JP, Parker P, et al. Etiology and recovery of neuromuscular fatigue following competitive soccer match-play. Front Physiol 8: 831, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume PA, Maxwell L. Delayed onset muscle soreness treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med 33: 145&#x2013;164, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale: Routledge, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow JF, Pearce AJ, Veale JP, VanderWesthuizen D, Coburn PT, Pizzari T. Hip adductor muscle strength is reduced preceding and during the onset of groin pain in elite junior Australian football players. J Sci Med Sport 13: 202&#x2013;204, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Pupo J, Detanico D, Santos SGD. The fatigue effect of a simulated futsal match protocol on isokinetic knee torque production. Sports Biomech 13: 332&#x2013;340, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hoyo M, Cohen DD, Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Influence of football match time&#x2013;motion parameters on recovery time course of muscle damage and jump ability. J Sports Sci 34: 1363&#x2013;1370, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A, Gregory J, Cohen D. The use of the functional H:Q ratio to assess fatigue in soccer. Int J Sports Med 31: 192&#x2013;197, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doeven S, Brink MS, Kosse SJ, Lemmink KAPM. Postmatch recovery of physical performance and biochemical markers in team ball sports: A systematic review. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 4: e000264, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogramaci SN, Watsford ML, Murphy AP. Changes in futsal activity profiles in a multiday tournament. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 55: 722&#x2013;729, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupr&#xe9; T, Potthast W. Are sprint accelerations related to groin injuries? A biomechanical analysis of adolescent soccer players. Sports Biomech 23: 3564&#x2013;3576, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engebretsen AH, Myklebust G, Holme I, Engebretsen L, Bahr R. Intrinsic risk factors for groin injuries among male soccer players: A prospective cohort study. Am J Sports Med 38: 2051&#x2013;2057, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filter A, Olivares-Jabalera J, Santalla A, et al. Curve sprinting in soccer: Kinematic and neuromuscular analysis. Int J Sports Med 41: 744&#x2013;750, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goossens L, Witvrouw E, Vanden Bossche L, De Clercq D. Lower eccentric hamstring strength and single leg hop for distance predict hamstring injury in PETE students. Eur J Sport Sci 15: 436&#x2013;442, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara A, Ono T, Kubota J, Okuwaki T, Fukubayashi T. Functional differences in the activity of the hamstring muscles with increasing running speed. J Sports Sci 28: 1085&#x2013;1092, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howle K, Waterson A, Duffield R. Recovery profiles following single and multiple matches per week in professional football. Eur J Sport Sci 19: 1303&#x2013;1311, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffries AC, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ, Wallace L, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM. Development of a revised conceptual framework of physical training for use in research and practice. Sports Med 52: 709&#x2013;724, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman DE, Raichlen DA, Pontzer H, Bramble DM, Cutright-Smith E. The human gluteus maximus and its role in running. J Exp Biol 209: 2143&#x2013;2155, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes M, Martins F, Brito J, et al. Epidemiology of injuries in elite male futsal players. Clin J Sport Med 33: 527&#x2013;532, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 367&#x2013;383, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally T, Edwards S, Halaki M, O'Dwyer N, Pizzari T, Blyton S. Quantifying demands on the hamstrings during high-speed running: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 33: 2423&#x2013;2443, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanez VF, Bueno MJDO, Caetano FG, Chierotti P, De Moraes SMF, Moura FA. Relationship between number of substitutions, running performance and passing during under-17 and adult official futsal matches. Int J Perform Anal Sport 20: 470&#x2013;482, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miley EN, Reeves AJ, Baker RT, Baker J, Hanna S. Reliability and validity of the Clinometer smartphone application for measuring knee flexion. Int J Athl Ther Train 28: 97&#x2013;103, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milioni F, Vieira LH, Barbieri RA, et al. Futsal match-related fatigue affects running performance and neuromuscular parameters but not finishing kick speed or accuracy. Front Physiol 7: 518, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Costa EC, Coutts AJ, Nakamura FY, Silva DAD, Aoki MS. Effects of a congested match schedule on isometric muscle strength performance of elite futsal players. Rev Bras Med Esporte 21: 40&#x2013;43, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin JB, Gimenez P, Edouard P, et al. Sprint acceleration mechanics: The major role of hamstrings in horizontal force production. Front Physiol 6: 404, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. Recovery in soccer: Part I-post-match fatigue and time course of recovery. Sports Med 42: 997&#x2013;1015, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. The influence of soccer playing actions on the recovery kinetics after a soccer match. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1517&#x2013;1523, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palucci Vieira LH, Kalva-filho CA, Santinelli FB, et al. Lateral preference and inter-limb asymmetry in completing technical tasks during official professional futsal matches: The role of playing position and opponent quality. Front Psychol 12: 725097, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandy MG, Lai AKM, Schache AG, Lin Y-C. How muscles maximize performance in accelerated sprinting. Scand J Med Sci Sports 31: 1882&#x2013;1896, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querido SM, Radaelli R, Brito J, Vaz JR, Freitas SR. Analysis of recovery methods' efficacy applied up to 72 hours postmatch in professional football: A systematic review with graded recommendations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 1326&#x2013;1342, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro JN, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Coutinho D, Brito J, Sampaio J, Travassos B. Activity profile and physical performance of match play in elite futsal players. Front Psychol 11: 1709, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro JN, Monteiro D, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Brito J, Sampaio J, Travassos B. Variation in physical performance of futsal players during congested fixtures. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 367&#x2013;373, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro JN, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Illa J, Couceiro M, Sampaio J, Travassos B. Exploring the effects of interchange rotations on high-intensity activities of elite futsal players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 18: 2044&#x2013;2050, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi V,G, Prill R, Jahnke S, Zaffagnini S, Becker R. The influence of gluteal muscle strength deficits on dynamic knee valgus: A scoping review. J Exp Orthop 9: 81&#x2013;93, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan J, DeBurca N, Mc Creesh K. Risk factors for groin/hip injuries in field-based sports: A systematic review. Br J Sports Med 48: 1089&#x2013;1096, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Rumpf MC, Hertzog M, et al. Acute and residual soccer match-related fatigue: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 539&#x2013;583, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyrou K, Freitas TT, Mar&#xed;n-Cascales E, Alcaraz PE. Physical and physiological match-play demands and player characteristics in futsal: A systematic review. Front Psychol 11: 569897, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyrou K, Freitas TT, Mar&#xed;n-Cascales E, Herrero-Carrasco R, Alcaraz PE. External match load and the influence of contextual factors in elite futsal. Biol Sport 39: 349&#x2013;354, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson R, Watson T. Is a professional soccer player's dominant lower limb at higher risk of injury than their nondominant lower limb? A systematic review. Phys Ther Rev 24: 314&#x2013;329, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Petersen J, Magnusson SP, H&#xf6;lmich P. Clinical assessment of hip strength using a hand-held dynamometer is reliable. Scand J Med Sci Sports 20: 493&#x2013;501, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead S, Till K, Weaving D, Jones B. The use of microtechnology to quantify the peak match demands of the football codes: A systematic review. Sports Med 48: 2549&#x2013;2575, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollin M, Pizzari T, Spagnolo K, Welvaert M, Thorborg K. The effects of football match congestion in an international tournament on hip adductor squeeze strength and pain in elite youth players. J Sports Sci 36: 1167&#x2013;1172, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yiannaki C, Barron DJ, Collins D, Carling C. Match performance in a reference futsal team during an international tournament &#x2013; Implications for talent development in soccer. Biol Sport 37: 147&#x2013;156, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>