<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41316105</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Challenges of healthcare quality in Kenya's tertiary hospitals: assessing the contribution and constraints of asset leasing financing mechanism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-025-13666-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Kenya&#x2019;s public tertiary healthcare is facing persistent quality of healthcare challenges characterized by acute shortage of healthcare workers, frequent industrial unrest, broken-down healthcare facilities, and erratic supply of essential commodities. To address these systemic challenges the government introduced the asset lease financing (ALF) mechanism aimed at strengthen tertiary hospitals through modern medical equipment and technologies. However, the effect of ALF on quality remains highly debated and controversial. This study examined the effect and constraints of ALF in improving quality of healthcare within Kenya&#x2019;s tertiary hospitals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A convergent parallel mixed-methods design was employed with quantitative data collected from 145 hospital managers, staff and patients. Descriptive statistics were used to summarize participants characteristics and indicators of study variables. Ordinary least square regression was then used to estimate the effect of ALF on quality of tertiary healthcare, controlling for existing traditional funding. Complementary qualitative insights were gathered from 26 policymakers, hospital managers, and health financing experts through semi-structured interviews and analyzed using thematic analysis to identify patterns in strengths and constraints. Integration of findings happened through triangulation to enhance interpretation and understanding.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Analysis showed that asset lease financing had a significant positive effect on quality of tertiary healthcare (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.587, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), explaining 26% of the variance. When traditional funding was controlled, ALF remained significant (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.495, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), with the model explaining 33% of the variance. Respondents attributed this to improved access to advanced diagnostic and therapeutic equipment, as well as expanded service capacity. However, descriptive summaries and qualitative perspectives revealed several constraints limiting ALF optimal effect in improving tertiary healthcare quality in Kenya. Stakeholders noted high recurrent costs, under-utilized assets, weak contract negotiation, and top-down procurement processes that limited hospital autonomy and contribution. Operational gaps, including inadequate training and delayed maintenance, further constrained ALF effect on quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">ALF has the potential to enhance quality of healthcare and technological capacity in Kenya&#x2019;s tertiary hospitals, but its effects are contingent on robust governance, effective contract design, and alignment with institutional capacity which seem lacking in the Kenyan context. Without these safeguards, current leasing arrangements risk becoming fiscally unsustainable with little quality enhancement. Policymakers should strengthen transparency, decentralize decision-making, and incorporate performance-based provisions into leasing contracts to maximize ALF effect in enhancing quality of care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12913-025-13666-w.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karino</LastName><ForeName>Ezekiel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strathmore University, P.O. Box 59857-00200, Karen Ole Sangale Rd, Off Langata Road, in Madaraka Estate, Nairobi, Kenya. ezmeteine@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ndegwa</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Co-operative University of Kenya, P.O. Box 24814-00502, Ushirika Road, Karen, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Were</LastName><ForeName>Vincent</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strathmore University, P.O. Box 59857-00200, Karen Ole Sangale Rd, Off Langata Road, in Madaraka Estate, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asset lease financing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Innovative financing mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tertiary healthcare</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study adhered to the declaration of Helsinki. The study was approved by Strathmore University Institutional Scientific, Ethics and Research Committee (SU-ISERC) under approval No. SU-ISERC2427/24 and later by granted permit by the National Commission for Science, Technology and Innovation (NACOSTI) under permit No. NACOSTI/P/24/41458. Written informed and free consent was obtained from the participants. Consent for publication: Not applicable. No personal data in the research. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41316105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12763892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-13666-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-025-13666-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kelm N. Scaling up health innovations in Africa: drawing lessons from the winners of the inaugural who Africa innovation challenge. In: Apha 2021 annual meeting and expo. American Public Health Association; 2021 October. https://apha.confex.com/apha/2021/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/493506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SM, Roland MO, Buetow SA. Defining quality of care. Soc Sci Med. 2000;51(11):1611&#x2013;25. 10.1016/S0277-9536(00)00057-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0277-9536(00)00057-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosadeghrad AM. A conceptual framework for quality of care. Mater Socio-Med. 2012;24(4):251&#x2013;61. 10.5455/msm.2012.24.251-261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/msm.2012.24.251-261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3732361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Everybody&#x2019;s business: strengthening health systems to improve health outcomes: WHO&#x2019;s framework for action. 2007. 10.30875/613a5f5b-en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titi-Ofei R, Osei-Afriyie D, Karamagi H. Monitoring quality of care in the WHO Africa region: a study design for measurement and tracking towards UHC attainment. Globalizat Health Action. 2021;14(1):1939493. 10.1080/16549716.2021.1939493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16549716.2021.1939493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8330734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34320908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, OECD, &amp; World Bank Group. Delivering quality health services: a global imperative for universal health coverage. World Health Organization; 2018. 10.1787/9789264300309-en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk ME, Gage AD, Arsenault C, Jordan K, Leslie HH, Roder-DeWan S, Pate M. High-quality health systems in the sustainable development goals era: time for a revolution. Lancet Global Health. 2018;6(11):e1196&#x2013;252. 10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30386-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30386-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleribe OO, Momoh J, Uzochukwu BSC, Mbofana F, Adebiyi A, Barbera T, Taylor-Robinson SD. Identifying key challenges facing healthcare systems in Africa and potential solutions. Int J Gen Med. 2019;12:395&#x2013;403. 10.2147/IJGM.S223882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S223882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6844097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31819592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D, David RA, Olaogun AAE, Auta A, Oni G, Akinyemi JO, Oni T. Health workforce and governance: the crisis in Nigeria. Hum Resour Health. 2017;15(1):32. 10.1186/s12960-017-0205-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-017-0205-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5427605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28494782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhane A, Assefa Y, Nigussie T, Gebreslassie M, Woldemichael K. The quality of health services in public facilities: the Ethiopian context. Ethiop J Health Dev. 2017;31(2):58&#x2013;64. 10.4314/ejhd.v31i2.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejhd.v31i2.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenya Law Reform Commission. Constitution of Kenya, 2010 (Article 43(1)(a)). Government of Kenya; 2010. https://www.klrc.go.ke/index.php/constitution-of-kenya/112-chapter-four-the-bill-of-rights/part-2-rights-and-fundamental-freedoms/209-43-economic-and-social-rights.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraa F, Degu A. Survival outcomes among pancreatic cancer patients at Kenyatta National hospital. J Gastrointest Cancer. 2022;53(4):958&#x2013;64. 10.1007/s12029-021-00723-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12029-021-00723-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34601708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said NS, Degu A. Assessment of survival outcomes among lung cancer patients at the national and referral hospital in Kenya. Cancer Med. 2023;12(8):9194&#x2013;201. 10.1002/cam4.5658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.5658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10166906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andel C, Davidow SL, Hollander M, Moreno DA. The economics of health care quality and medical errors. J Health Care Finance. 2012;39(1):39&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23155743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Kenya. Checklist for assessing quality of healthcare: Kenya quality model for health. Health MoH Publication; 2018. Retrieved from: https://qualityhealthcareawards.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/KQMH-Hospital-Checklist-for-assessing-Quality-of-Care.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Kenya. Health facility census report. 2023. https://www.health.go.ke/cs-nakhumicha-launches-vital-2023-kenya-health-facility-census-report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parliament of Kenya. Report on the status of national referral hospitals. Parliament of Kenya; 2019. https://parliament.go.ke/sites/default/files/2019-06/Report%20on%20The%20Status%20of%20National%20Referral%20Hospitals.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuya T, Maina T, Chuma J. Historical account of the national health insurance formulation in Kenya: experiences from the past decade. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:1&#x2013;11. 10.1186/s12913-015-0865-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-0865-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25884159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barasa E, Rogo K, Mwaura N, Chuma J. Kenya national hospital insurance fund reforms: implications and lessons for universal health coverage. Taylor and Francis ebooks. 2018. 10.1596/31150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1596/31150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30398396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David N, Wanjala P. A case for increasing public investments in health: raising public commitments to Kenya&#x2019;s health sector. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:Article 1120. 10.1186/s12889-020-08742-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagwanja N, Waithaka D, Nzinga J, Tsofa B, Boga M, Leli H, Barasa E. Shocks, stress and everyday health system resilience: experiences from the Kenyan coast. Health Policy Plann. 2020;35(5):522&#x2013;35. 10.1093/heapol/czaa002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czaa002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7225571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairu A, Orangi S, Mbuthia B, Barasa E. Examining health facility financing in Kenya in the context of devolution. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21:Article 1086. 10.1186/s12913-021-07123-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34645443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munge K, Briggs AH. The progressivity of health-care financing in Kenya. Health Policy Plann. 2014;29(7):912&#x2013;20. 10.1093/heapol/czt073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czt073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24107660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Kenya. The Kenya health public-private collaboration strategy 2020. 2020. https://guidelines.health.go.ke:8000/media/The_Kenya_Health_Public_Private_Collaboration_Strategy_2020.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Economic Affairs. The managed equipment service (MES) programme in Kenya: assessment report. Nairobi: IEA-Kenya; 2020. https://ieakenya.or.ke/publications/the-managed-equipment-service-mes-programme-in-kenya-assessment-report/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simeoni C, Kinoti W. Medical equipment leasing in Kenya: neocolonial global finance and misplaced health priorities (DAWN Discussion Paper No. 25). Development Alternatives with Women for a New Era (DAWN). 2020. https://docslib.org/doc/5792993/medical-equipment-leasing-in-kenya-neocolonial-global-finance-and-misplaced-health-priorities.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamova E, Zakirova O, Rodionova E. Leasing of hardware and software solutions in health care systems: potential benefits and perspectives. Proceedings of the New Silk Road: Business Cooperation and Prospective of Economic Development (NSRBCPED 2019). 2020. 10.2991/aebmr.k.200324.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Finance Corporation. Leasing in development: guidelines for emerging economies. 2nd ed. World Bank Group; 2009. https://documents1.worldbank.org/curated/en/998901468326962267/pdf/516730WP0Box341inDevelopment1Manual.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Group. Innovative finance for development solutions: initiatives of the world bank group. 2010. https://thedocs.worldbank.org/en/doc/deddcb43bddd1db90cb39a96c4909c2c-0090012021/original/INT-FY10-Annual-Report.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinrichs-Krapels S, Ditewig B, Boulding H, Chalkidou A. Purchasing high-cost medical devices and equipment in hospitals: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2022;12(9):e057516. 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-057516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-057516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36581959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp V, Kreder KJ. Medical equipment: leasing vs. buying. In: Sharp V, Kreder KJ, The complete business guide for a successful medical practice. Springer; 2015. p. 133&#x2013;48. 10.1007/978-3-319-11095-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley G. Innovative financing for development: a new model for development finance. United Nations Development Programme; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy D, Brikci N. Taskforce on innovative international financing for health systems: what next? Bull World Health Organ. 2010;88(6):478&#x2013;80. 10.2471/BLT.09.074419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2471/BLT.09.074419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20539870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SDG Partnership Platform, Kenya. (2020). Annual report. https://mptf.undp.org/sites/default/files/documents/35000/kenya_sdg_partnership_platform_2020_annual_report.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senate of the Republic of Kenya. Report of the investigation of the managed equipment services. Kenya Law; 2020 September 8. https://www.kelinkenya.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Final-Version-of-MES-Committee-Report-for-Tabling_08092020.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamzam AH, Abdul Wahab AK, Azizan MM, Satapathy SC, Lai KW, Hasikin K. A systematic review of medical equipment reliability assessment in improving the quality of healthcare services. Front Public Health. 2021;9:753951. 10.3389/fpubh.2021.753951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.753951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34646808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JD, Zald MN. Resource mobilization and social movements: a partial theory. Am J Sociol. 1977;82(6):1212&#x2013;41. 10.1086/226464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/226464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MC, Meckling WH. Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure. J Financ Econ. 1976;3(4):305&#x2013;60. 10.1016/0304-405X(76)90026-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-405X(76)90026-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donabedian A. The quality of care: how can it be assessed? JAMA. 1988;260(12):1743&#x2013;48. 10.1001/jama.260.12.1743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.260.12.1743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3045356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwuegbuzie AJ, Leech NL. Linking research questions to mixed methods data analysis procedures. Qual Rep. 2006;11(3):474&#x2013;98. 10.46743/2160-3715/2006.1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2006.1663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mugenda O, Mugenda A. Research methods: quantitative and qualitative approaches. 3rd rev. ed. African Centre for Technology Studies (ACTS) Press; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masaba BB, Moturi JK, Taiswa J, Mmusi-Phetoe RM. Devolution of healthcare system in Kenya: progress and challenges. Public Health. 2020;189:135&#x2013;40. 10.1016/j.puhe.2020.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2020.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33227596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Kenya. Clinical management and referral guidelines: Volume III: clinical management and referral of common conditions at levels 4&#x2013;6 hospitals (Clinical Management and Referral Guidelines, Vol. III, pp. 4&#x2013;6). Nairobi: Ministry of Medical Services and Ministry of Public Health and Sanitation; 2009. Retrieved from: http://guidelines.health.go.ke:8000/media/Clinical_Guidelines_Vol_III_Final.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyongesa MW, Onyango R, Ombaka J. Evaluation of health care quality in public and faith-based hospitals in Kiambu and Nairobi countries, in Kenya: a comparative study. J Emerging Trends Educ Res Policy Stud. 2015;6(2):150&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Republic of Kenya. The public private partnerships Act, No. 14 of 2021. Kenya Law; 2021. https://kenyalaw.org/kl/fileadmin/pdfdownloads/Acts/2021/ThePublicPrivatePartnershipsAct_No.14of2021.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bwire GM, Melese A, Miskin I. Learning from the Kenyan experiment: managed equipment services in healthcare. J Glob Health Innovations. 2025;14(2):Article e20256123. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC12066563/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Procurement and Asset Disposal Act, No. 33 of 2015 (Kenya). Revised edition 2022. Nairobi: Government of Kenya; 2015. Retrieved from: https://ppra.go.ke/download/the-public-procurement-and-asset-disposal-act-revised-edition-2022/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itenyi EN, Njeru J. Key takeaways for implementing managed equipment services in Kenya (Master&#x2019;s thesis, Kenyatta University). Kenyatta University Institutional Repository; 2024. https://ir-library.ku.ac.ke/items/4d48501e-acc5-489f-bd71-20187295ccdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njagi E, Iloka K, Wawira S, Thiga L, Muraguri N. Learning from the Kenyan experiment: key takeaways for implementing managed equipment services in developing countries. Front Health Serv. 2025;5:1361261. 10.3389/frhs.2025.1361261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frhs.2025.1361261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12066563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40356709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health (Kenya). (2025). https://health.go.ke/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Treasury of Kenya. (2025). https://www.treasury.go.ke/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Spinal Injury Referral Hospital. (2024). Facility profile / annual report. https://nsirh.or.ke/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathari National Teaching and Referral Hospital. Facility profile/annual report; 2024. Retrieved from: https://www.mntrh.go.ke/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moi Teaching and Referral Hospital. Annual report/facility profile; 2024. Retrieved from: https://www.mtrh.go.ke.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machini B, Achia TNO, Kipruto H, Amboko B, Chesang J. Factors associated with hospital length of stay in patients admitted with suspected malaria in Kenya: secondary analysis of a cross-sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2022;12(6):e059263. 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35725248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onditi JS. Factors affecting length of stay at accident and emergency department in Mater Misericordiae Hospital(Master&#x2019;s thesis, United States International University-Africa). USIU Digital Repository; 2022. https://erepo.usiu.ac.ke/bitstream/handle/11732/7311/Onditi,%20June%20S%20MBA%202022.pdf?sequence=1%26isAllowed=y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts RE. Qualitative interview questions: guidance for novice researchers. Qual Rep. 2020;25(9):3185&#x2013;90. 10.46743/2160-3715/2020.4640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2020.4640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. Naturalistic inquiry. Sage Publications; 1985. 10.1016/0147-1767(85)90062-8[5].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic analysis: a practical guide. Sage Publications; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graue C. Qualitative data analysis. Int J Sales Retailing Mark. 2015;4(9):5&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OANDA. Historical exchange rates. 2024 July. https://www.oanda.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsofa B, Molyneux S, Gilson L, Goodman C. How does decentralisation affect health sector planning and financial management? a case study of early effects of devolution in Kenya. Int J Equity Health, 2017;16:151. 10.1186/s12939-017-0649-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank. Public-private partnerships: reference guide version 2.0. World Bank Group; 2015. 10.1596/978-1-4648-0615-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon A, Cashin C. Assessing public expenditure on health from a fiscal space perspective (Policy Research Working Paper No. 5074). World Bank; 2010. 10.1596/1813-9450-5074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson K, Brikci N, Erlangga D, Alebachew A, De Allegri M, Balabanova D, Borghi J. The lancet global health commission on high-quality health systems in the SDG era: systemic challenges and opportunities for health systems strengthening. Lancet Global Health. 2017;5(9):e848&#x2013;49. 10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30273-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30273-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baris E, Mollahaliloglu S, Aydin S. Healthcare in Turkey: from laggard to leader. BMJ. 2012;344:e138. 10.1136/bmj.e138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.e138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21257656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meessen B, Hercot D, Noirhomme M, Ridde V, Tibouti A, Tashobya CK, Gilson L. Removing user fees in the health sector: a review of policy processes in six Sub-Saharan African countries. Health Policy Plann. 2011;26(suppl_2):ii16&#x2013;29. 10.1093/heapol/czr062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czr062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22027916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbindyo P, English M, Molyneux S. Institutional corruption in healthcare procurement in Kenya: perspectives from health sector stakeholders. Int J Health Policy Manag. 2021;10(5):245&#x2013;54. 10.34172/ijhpm.2020.76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/ijhpm.2020.76</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tullock G. Public choice. In: Durlauf SN, Blume LE, editors. The new Palgrave dictionary of economics. 2nd ed. Palgrave Macmillan; 2008. (Original work published 1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piatti-F&#xfc;nfkirchen M, Schneider P. From stumbling block to enabler: the role of public financial management in health service delivery in Tanzania and Zambia. Health Syst Reform. 2018;4(4):336&#x2013;45. 10.1080/23288604.2018.1513265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23288604.2018.1513265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30398392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>