<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41758989</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deep lateral extra-articular tenodesis (LET) is associated with improved tibial internal rotational stability and favourable patient-reported outcomes compared with superficial LET in high-grade pivot-shift male patients undergoing quadrupled hamstring autograft ACL reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70372</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Lateral extra-articular tenodesis (LET) has been shown to improve rotational stability and clinical outcomes and to reduce graft failure rates in selected high-risk patients. However, the comparative effects of deep (beneath-LCL) and superficial (over-LCL) LET techniques on clinical and biomechanical outcomes remain uncertain. This study aimed to compare the functional, kinematic, and strength outcomes of deep and superficial LET performed concomitantly with ACLR in patients with high-grade pivot-shift. It was hypothesised that superficial LET would result in clinical and biomechanical outcomes comparable to those of the deep LET technique.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, randomised, double-blind comparative study included 24 male patients with isolated ACL rupture and pivot-shift grades 2-3. Patients were divided equally into two treatment groups as ACLR with deep LET or superficial LET. All procedures used standardised quadrupled hamstring autografts. Clinical outcomes were assessed using the IKDC, Lysholm, and Tegner scores preoperatively and at 6 and 12 months. Biomechanical assessments included three-dimensional running gait analysis and isokinetic tibial rotation strength testing at 6 months postoperatively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All patients completed follow-up with no graft ruptures. Both groups showed significant improvement in IKDC and Lysholm scores at 6 and 12 months (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The deep LET group demonstrated greater improvement in IKDC (86.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.0 vs. 81.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.7, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.022) and Lysholm (90.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.9 vs. 85.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7.2, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.037) scores. Running gait analysis revealed reduced stance phase tibial rotation (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.035) and anterior translation (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) in the deep LET group, indicating superior dynamic control. Isokinetic torque recovery and Tegner activity levels (6.4 vs. 6.0, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.19) were comparable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Concomitant deep and superficial LET techniques effectively restored knee stability and improved clinical outcomes after ACL reconstruction. However, the deep LET technique was associated with improved tibial rotational stability and more favourable patient-reported outcomes in young, athletic male patients with high-grade pivot-shift.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 1, randomised controlled trials with adequate statistical power to detect differences (narrow confidence intervals) and follow up &gt;80%.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x15e;ahbat</LastName><ForeName>Yavuz</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9963-5334</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Erzurum Regional Training and Research Hospital, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Istinye University Bahcesehir Liv Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altay</LastName><ForeName>Nasuhi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5518-3938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Erzurum Regional Training and Research Hospital, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kocao&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Bar&#x131;&#x15f;</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2537-0660</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery &#x130;stanbul, Acibadem Altunizade Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Faculty of Medicine, Acibadem Mehmet Ali Aydinlar University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sever</LastName><ForeName>Ozan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2962-3968</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atat&#xfc;rk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Scientific Research Projects Coordination Unit of Atat&#xfc;rk University (Decision project number 13228, approved on October 25, 2023)</GrantID><Agency>Atat&#xfc;rk &#xdc;niversitesi</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lateral collateral ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">minimal clinically important difference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient&#x2010;reported outcome measures</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41758989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Akmese R, Ovali SA, Celebi MM, Malatyali B, Kocaoglu H. A surgical algorithm according to pivot&#x2010;shift grade in patients with ACL injury: a prospective clinical and radiological evaluation. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(8):23259671211025494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves BMO, Scoz RD, Burigo RL, Ferreira IC, Ramos APS, Mendes JJB, et al. Association between concentric and eccentric isokinetic torque and unilateral countermovement jump variables in professional soccer players. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2022;7(1):25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaeda M, Nakamae A, Hirata K, Kono Y, Uenishi H, Adachi N. Factors associated with dynamic knee valgus angle during single&#x2010;leg forward landing in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Asia Pac J Sports Med Arthrosc Rehabil Technol. 2020;22:56&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayeni OR, Chahal M, Tran MN, Sprague S. Pivot shift as an outcome measure for ACL reconstruction: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2012;20(4):767&#x2013;777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiba D, Gale T, Nishida K, Suntaxi F, Lesniak BP, Fu FH, et al. Lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis contributes little to change in vivo kinematics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(7):1803&#x2013;1812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Routledge; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devitt BM, Bouguennec N, Barfod KW, Porter T, Webster KE, Feller JA. Combined anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis does not result in an increased rate of osteoarthritis: a systematic review and best evidence synthesis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25(4):1149&#x2013;1160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirnberger J, K&#xf6;sters A, M&#xfc;ller E. Concentric and eccentric isokinetic knee extension: A reproducibility study using the IsoMed 2000&#x2010;dynamometer. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2012;20:31&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferretti A, Monaco E, Gaj E, Andreozzi V, Annibaldi A, Carrozzo A, et al. Risk factors for grade 3 pivot shift in knees with acute anterior cruciate ligament injuries: a comprehensive evaluation of the importance of osseous and soft tissue parameters from the SANTI Study Group. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(10):2408&#x2013;2417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgoulis AD, Ristanis S, Chouliaras V, Moraiti C, Stergiou N. Tibial rotation is not restored after ACL reconstruction with a hamstring graft. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2007;454:89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getgood A, Brown C, Lording T, Amis A, Claes S, Geeslin A, et al. The anterolateral complex of the knee: results from the International ALC Consensus Group Meeting. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(1):166&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getgood AMJ, Bryant DM, Litchfield R, Heard M, McCormack RG, Rezansoff A, et al. Lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis reduces failure of hamstring tendon autograft anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: 2&#x2010;year outcomes from the STABILITY study randomized clinical trial. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(2):285&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs CM, Hughes JD, Popchak AJ, Chiba D, Winkler PW, Lesniak BP, et al. Preoperative quantitative pivot shift does not correlate with in vivo kinematics following ACL reconstruction with or without lateral extraarticular tenodesis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(7):2802&#x2013;2809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giusto JD, Konstantinou E, Rabuck SJ, Lesniak BP, Hughes JD, Irrgang JJ, et al. When is anterolateral complex augmentation indicated? Perspectives from the 2024 Freddie Fu Panther Sports Medicine Symposium. J ISAKOS. 2025;11:100393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harput G, Ulusoy B, Yildiz TI, Demirci S, Eraslan L, Turhan E, et al. Cross&#x2010;education improves quadriceps strength recovery after ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heijboer RRO, Lubberts B, Guss D, Johnson AH, DiGiovanni CW. Incidence and risk factors associated with venous thromboembolism after orthopaedic below&#x2010;knee surgery. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2019;27(10):e482&#x2013;e490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollyer I, Sholtis C, Loughran G, Raji Y, Akhtar M, Smith PA, et al. Trends in lateral extra&#x2010;articular augmentation use and surgical technique with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction from 2016 to 2023, an ACL study group survey. J ISAKOS. 2024;9(6):100356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley ET, Fried JW, Kingery MT, Strauss EJ, Alaia MJ. Antero&#x2010;lateral ligament reconstruction improves knee stability alongside anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(3):764&#x2013;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inderhaug E, Stephen JM, Williams A, Amis AA. Biomechanical comparison of anterolateral procedures combined with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(2):347&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboudie P, Douiri A, Bouguennec N, Biset A, Graveleau N. Combined ACL and ALL reconstruction reduces the rate of reoperation for graft failure or secondary meniscal lesions in young athletes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(10):3488&#x2013;3498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopomo N, Zaffagnini S, Amis AA. Quantifying the pivot shift test: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21(4):767&#x2013;783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattes K, Manzer S, Kianmarz Y, Schaffert N. Reproducibility of isokinetic maximum strength in the closed chain of the lower extremities, hand and leg bilateral asymmetry. J Sport Human Perform. 2017;4:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Engler ID, Nazzal EM, Dalton JF, Lucidi GA, Hughes JD, et al. Current trends in the anterior cruciate ligament part II: evaluation, surgical technique, prevention, and rehabilitation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(1):34&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Nazzal EM, Lucidi GA, Serrano R, Hughes JD, Margheritini F, et al. Current trends in the anterior cruciate ligament part 1: biology and biomechanics. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(1):20&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettinari F, Carrozzo A, Saithna A, Ali AA, Alayane A, Barosso M, et al. Effect of lateral extra&#x2010;articular procedures combined with ACL reconstruction on the rate of graft rupture in patients aged older than 30 years: a matched&#x2010;pair analysis of 1102 patients from the SANTI Study Group. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(7):1765&#x2013;1772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson JTE. Eta squared and partial eta squared as measures of effect size in educational research. Educ Res Rev. 2011;6(2):135&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saithna A, Geeslin AG, Sonnery&#x2010;Cottet B. Lateral extra&#x2010;articular procedures with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: international consensus. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(9):3300&#x2013;3302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sever O, K&#x131;r R, Baykal C, Akyildiz Z, Nobari H. Overhead squat assessment reflects treadmill running kinematics. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean AJ, Lian J, Tisherman R, Meredith SJ, de Sa D, Lynch A, et al. Augmentation of anatomic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis does not significantly affect rotatory knee laxity: a time zero, in vivo kinematic analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(14):3495&#x2013;3502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slette EL, Mikula JD, Schon JM, Marchetti DC, Kheir MM, Turnbull TL, et al. Biomechanical results of lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis procedures of the knee: a systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2016;32(12):2592&#x2013;2611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery&#x2010;Cottet B. Current and future directions of anterior cruciate ligament surgery in sports: From the brain to the graft&#x2010;Think outside the notch. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(12):4115&#x2013;4117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery&#x2010;Cottet B, Barbosa NC, Vieira TD, Saithna A. Clinical outcomes of extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis/anterolateral reconstruction in the ACL injured knee. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(2):596&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery&#x2010;Cottet B, Carrozzo A, Saithna A, Monaco E, Vieira TD, Musahl V, et al. Indications for lateral extra&#x2010;articular procedures in the anterior cruciate ligament&#x2013;reconstructed knee: part I of an international consensus statement. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(9):3303&#x2013;3312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery&#x2010;Cottet B, Carrozzo A, Saithna A, Monaco E, Vieira TD, Musahl V, et al. Surgical treatment and complications of lateral extra&#x2010;articular procedures in the anterior cruciate ligament&#x2013;reconstructed knee: part II of an International Consensus Statement. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(9):3313&#x2013;3321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B, Vivekanantha P, Khalik HA, de SA D. Several factors predict the achievement of the patient acceptable symptom state and minimal clinically important difference for patient&#x2010;reported outcome measures following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(5):1617&#x2013;1632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SHS, Lau BPH, Khin LW, Lingaraj K. The importance of patient sex in the outcomes of anterior cruciate ligament reconstructions: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(1):242&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashman S, Kolowich P, Collon D, Anderson K, Anderst W. Dynamic function of the ACL&#x2010;reconstructed knee during running. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2007;454:66&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Melick N, Van Cingel REH, Brooijmans F, Neeter C, van Tienen T, Hullegie W, et al. Evidence&#x2010;based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1506&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA. Exploring the high reinjury rate in younger patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(11):2827&#x2013;2832.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>