<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41695996</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-142X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of nursing studies advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Nurs Stud Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Instruments to measure nurses' intention-to-stay in the profession: A systematic literature review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100496</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100496</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100496</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijnsa.2026.100496</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There is a large and increasing shortage of nursing staff. To alleviate this problem, healthcare systems should prioritize healthcare interventions that improve nurse retention over healthcare interventions that reduce it or leave it unchanged. One way to do so is to evaluate interventions on their anticipated impact on nurse intention-to-stay, which is an important precursor of retention. An overview of available instruments to quantify nurse intention-to-stay is lacking, resulting in researchers re-inventing the wheel. This review aims to fill this gap.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic literature search was performed in the databases Medline ALL via Ovid, Embase.com, Web of Science Core Collection, CINAHL Plus, PsycINFO, the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials via Wiley, and Google Scholar (200 highest-ranked references only). The search string consisted of terms and associated synonyms for 1) nursing staff, 2) personnel intent to stay/leave, and 3) surveys. Articles were included when there was a quantitative method mentioned for measuring the intention of nurses to stay or quit nursing and/or their job/position/organization. Information was extracted on the year of publication, study design, study population, number of participants, instrument used for measuring intention-to-stay, and whether the instrument was focused on leaving the job, organization, or profession. In addition, we checked whether the instrument was used to evaluate the (expected or realized) impact of an intervention and if an association was determined between intention-to-stay (measured through the instrument) and retention. The protocol was not registered.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">967 articles fulfilled our inclusion criteria, most of which were published in recent years. A total of 485 instruments were found. Nine regularly used instruments were identified, differing in their respective popularity over time, their size, the population for which they were developed and the strength of their link to actual retention. Notably, compared with the large body of literature on nurse intention-to-stay generally, the number of studies specifically measuring the impact of an intervention on nurse intention-to-stay is limited (n=20). Most of these intervention studies focused on changes in nurse training/mentorship or mental health support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION &amp; CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Many different instruments exist to measure nurses' intention-to-stay. To add to our identified instruments, a comparative study is needed to identify which instrument offers the strongest predictive value for nurse retention. The absence of studies specifically evaluating the impact of interventions on nurses' intention-to-stay creates a critical gap in understanding how health interventions influence retention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Dutch Research Council, 406.XS.04.151.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Zanden</LastName><ForeName>Myrthe</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Systems Science; Faculty of Technology, Policy and Management; Delft University of Technology; Delft, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine; Section Nursing Science; Erasmus MC; University Medical Center Rotterdam; Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hinrichs-Krapels</LastName><ForeName>Saba</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Systems Science; Faculty of Technology, Policy and Management; Delft University of Technology; Delft, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niehot</LastName><ForeName>Christa</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Library; Erasmus MC, University Medical Center Rotterdam; Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teeuw</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery Department; Dijklander Hospital; Hoorn, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madan</LastName><ForeName>Swasti</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent researcher.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Linden</LastName><ForeName>Naomi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Systems Science; Faculty of Technology, Policy and Management; Delft University of Technology; Delft, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Nurs Stud Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769252</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-142X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intention to leave</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intention to stay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nurses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Turnover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Workforce shortages</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Naomi van der Linden reports financial support was provided by Dutch Research Council. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41695996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12905783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnsa.2026.100496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-142X(26)00018-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ABUALRUB R., OMARI F., AL-ZARU I. Support, satisfaction and retention among Jordanian nurses in private and public hospitals. Int. nurs. rev. 2009;56:326&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19702806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL YAHYAEI A., HEWISON A., EFSTATHIOU N., CARRICK-SEN D. Nurses' intention to stay in the work environment in acute healthcare: a systematic review. J Res Nurs. 2022;27:374&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35832883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL ZAMEL L.G., ABDULLAH K.L., CHAN C.M., PIAW C.Y. Moderating Effect of Demographic Characteristics on the Relationship between Work Life Quality and Turnover Intention: A Cross-Sectional Study. Florence Nightingale J Nurs. 2021;29:203&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34263239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALI A.S.A., RAYAN A.H. Association Between Authentic Leadership in Nurse Managers and Performance and Intention to Leave Among Registered Nurses. J. Nurs. Res. 2023;31:e293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37769204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALLAN S.A.A., RAYAN A.H. Association Between Authentic Leadership in Nurse Managers and Performance and Intention to Leave Among Registered Nurses. J. Nurs. Res. 2023;31:e293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37769204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALMALKI M.J., FITZGERALD G., CLARK M. The relationship between quality of work life and turnover intention of primary health care nurses in Saudi Arabia. BMC health serv. res. 2012;12:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3507760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22970764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ARMMER F., BALL C. Perceptions of horizontal violence in staff nurses and intent to leave. Work. 2015;51:91&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25835724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AUSSERHOFER D., TAPPEINER W., WIESER H., SERDALY C., SIMON M., Z&#xda;&#xd1;IGA F., FAVEZ L. Administrative burden in Swiss nursing homes and its association with care workers&#x2019; outcomes&#x2014;a multicenter cross-sectional study. BMC geriatr. 2023;23:347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BAE S.H. Noneconomic and economic impacts of nurse turnover in hospitals: A systematic review. Int Nurs Rev. 2022;69:392&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9545246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35654041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BAEK G.L., LEE E. Impact of workplace bullying and resilience on new nurses' turnover intention in tertiary hospitals. Nurs. Health Sci. 2022;24:801&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36096475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BARLOW K.M., ZANGARO G.A. Meta-analysis of the reliability and validity of the Anticipated Turnover Scale across studies of registered nurses in the United States. J. Nurs. Manag. 2010;18:862&#x2013;873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20946222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BONIOL M., KUNJUMEN T., NAIR T.S., SIYAM A., CAMPBELL J., DIALLO K. The global health workforce stock and distribution in 2020 and 2030: a threat to equity and 'universal' health coverage? BMJ Glob Health. 2022:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9237893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BOTHMA C.F., ROODT G. The validation of the turnover intention scale. SA j. hum. resour. manag. 2013;11:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BRAMER W.M., DE JONGE G.B., RETHLEFSEN M.L., MAST F., KLEIJNEN J. A systematic approach to searching: an efficient and complete method to develop literature searches. J Med Libr Assoc. 2018;106:531&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6148622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30271302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BRAMER W.M., GIUSTINI D., DE JONGE G.B., HOLLAND L., BEKHUIS T. De-duplication of database search results for systematic reviews in EndNote. J Med Libr Assoc. 2016;104:240&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4915647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27366130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BUCHAN J., SCHAFFER F.A., CATTON H. International Centre on Nurse Migration; Philadelphia: 2018. Policy brief: Nurse Retention.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CAMMANN, C., FICHMAN, M., JENKINS, D. &amp; KLESH, J. 1983. The Michigan Organizational Assessment Questionnaire.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CAPACITEITSORGAAN 2022. Capaciteitsplan 2022-2025 Deelrapport 8, FZO-beroepen &amp; Ambulanceverpleegkundigen.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CASTLE N.G., ENGBERG J., ANDERSON R., MEN A. Job satisfaction of nurse aides in nursing homes: intent to leave and turnover. Gerontologist. 2007;47:193&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17440124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHEN J.-P., DAI Y.-M., QIN Y., LIANG S.-P., CHENG G., LIU Y., YANG C.-Z., HE H.-G., SHEN Q. Factors influencing turnover intention among male nurses in China: A large-scale descriptive correlational study. Int. Nurs. Rev. 2023;71:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHENG C.Y., LIOU S.R. Intention to leave of Asian nurses in US hospitals: does cultural orientation matter? J. clin. nurs. 2011;20:2033&#x2013;2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21401765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHENG C.-Y., TSAI H.-M., CHANG C.-H., LIOU S.-R. New Graduate Nurses&#x2019; Clinical Competence, Clinical Stress, and Intention to Leave: A Longitudinal Study in Taiwan. Sci. World J. 2014;2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24672363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHIEN W.T., YICK S.Y. An Investigation of Nurses' Job Satisfaction in a Private Hospital and Its Correlates. Open Nurs J. 2016;10:99&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4895062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHOI S., LEE J. Factors Influencing RNs' Intention to Stay in Nursing Homes: Multilevel Modeling Approach. J. Gerontol. Nurs. 2023;49:40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37379045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COWIN L. The effects of nurses' job satisfaction on retention: an Australian perspective. J Nurs Adm. 2002;32:283&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12021569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CRAMER M.E., HIGH R., CULROSS B., CONLEY D.M., NAYAR P., NGUYEN A.T., OJHA D. Retooling the RN workforce in long-term care: Nursing certification as a pathway to quality improvement. Geriatr. Nurs. 2014;35:182&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24534720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CROWE S., FUCHSIA HOWARD A., VANDERSPANK B. The mental health impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on Canadian critical care nurses. Intensive Crit. Care Nurs. 2022;71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DE SUL S.I.R., LUCAS P.R.M.B. Translation and validation of the anticipated turnover scale for the Portuguese cultural context. Nurs. Open. 2020;7:1475&#x2013;1481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DE VRIES N., BOONE A., GODDERIS L., BOUMAN J., SZEMIK S., MATRANGA D., DE WINTER P. The Race to Retain Healthcare Workers: A Systematic Review on Factors that Impact Retention of Nurses and Physicians in Hospitals. INQ.: J. Health Care Organ. Provis. Financ. 2023;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10014988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DUFFIELD C.M., ROCHE M.A., HOMER C., BUCHAN J., DIMITRELIS S. A comparative review of nurse turnover rates and costs across countries. J Adv Nurs. 2014;70:2703&#x2013;2712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25052582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DUNCAN V.N. Walden University; 2024. Compassion Satisfaction, Compassion Fatigue, Managerial Support, and Intent to Leave Among Mental Health Nurses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DURU D., HAMMOUD M. Identifying effective retention strategies for front-line nurses. Nurs. manag. (Harrow Lond. Engl.: 1994) 2021:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34490763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAVARO A., WONG C., OUDSHOORN A. Relationships among sex, empowerment, workplace bullying and job turnover intention of new graduate nurses. J. clin. nurs. 2021;30:1273&#x2013;1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33476435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FILIPOVA A.A. Relationships Among Ethical Climates, Perceived Organizational Support, and Intent-to-Leave for Licensed Nurses in Skilled Nursing Facilities. J. Appl. Gerontol. 2011;30:44&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FOSTER K., STEELE M., METCALFE J., TOOMEY N., ALEXANDER L. Well-being, turnover intention, and stigma attitudes of mental health transition-to-practice nurses: A cross-sectional study. Int. J. Ment. Health Nurs. 2024;33:409&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GAUDINE A., THORNE L. Nurses&#x2019; ethical conflict with hospitals: A longitudinal study of outcomes. Nurs. Ethics. 2012;19:727&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22619238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GHERMAN M.A., ARHIRI L., HOLMAN A.C., SOPONARU C. Protective factors against morally injurious memories from the COVID-19 pandemic on nurses&#x2019; occupational wellbeing: a cross-sectional experimental study. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2022;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36142089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GLAZER S., KRUSE B. The role of organizational commitment in occupational stress models. Int. J. stress manag. 2008;15:329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRIFFETH R., HOM P., GAERTNER S. A Meta-Analysis of Antecedents and Correlates of Employee Turnover: Update, Moderator Tests, and Research Implications for the Next Millennium. J. Manag. 2000;26:463&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HACKETT R.D., LAPIERRE L.M., HAUSDORF P.A. Understanding the Links between Work Commitment Constructs. J. Vocat. Behav. 2001;58:392&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HAN S.-S., HAN J.-W., AN Y.-S., LIM S.-H. Effects of role stress on nurses' turnover intentions: The mediating effects of organizational commitment and burnout. Jpn. J. Nurs. Sci. 2015;12:287&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25469956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HARIYATI R., NURDIANA N. Retention Strategy to Minimize Nurse Turnover: A Systematic Review. Int. J. Nurs. Health Serv. (IJNHS) 2019;1:99&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HART S.E. Hospital ethical climates and registered nurses' turnover intentions. J. Nurs. Scholarsh. 2005;37:173&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HARZING A. Publish or Perish. 2007. https://harzing.com/resources/publish-or-perish available from.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HINSHAW A.S., ATWOOD J.R. Anticipated Turnover: A Preventive Approach. West. J. Nurs. Res. 1982:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HINSHAW A.S., ATWOOD J.R. In: Annual Review of Nursing Research. WERLEY H.H., FITZPATRICK J.J., editors. Springer Berlin Heidelberg; Berlin, Heidelberg: 1984. Nursing Staff Turnover, Stress, and Satisfaction: Models, Measures, and Management.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6365122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HOLTER A. Capella University; 2022. Does Self-Efficacy, Grit, and Job Satisfaction Predict Turnover Intention Amongst New Registered Nurses?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HONG Y., QIU M., LIU L., HUANG F., WANG K., LIN R. Surface acting, emotional exhaustion, career calling and turnover intention among student nurses: A cross-sectional study. Nurse Educ. Pract. 2023;69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37060732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HU H., WANG C., LAN Y., WU X. Nurses&#x2019; turnover intention, hope and career identity: the mediating role of job satisfaction. BMC Nurs. 2022;21:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35144604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HUTER K., KRICK T., DOMHOFF D., SEIBERT K., WOLF-OSTERMANN K., ROTHGANG H. Effectiveness of Digital Technologies to Support Nursing Care: Results of a Scoping Review. J Multidiscip Heal. 2020;13:1905&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33328736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;SPIR DEMIR &#xd6;., Y&#x131;LD&#x131;R&#x131;M A., S&#xd6;NMEZ B., DUYGULU S. Relationship between structural empowerment and nurse and patient-reported outcomes: The mediating role of control over nursing practices. West. J. Nurs. Res. 2023;45:634&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37089109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KANG J., JEONG Y.J. Effects of a smartphone application for cognitive rehearsal intervention on workplace bullying and turnover intention among nurses. Int. J. Nurs. Pract. 2019;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KANG J., KIM J.-I., YUN S. Effects of a Cognitive Rehearsal Program on Interpersonal Relationships, Workplace Bullying, Symptom Experience, and Turnover Intention among Nurses: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Korean Acad Nurs. 2017;47:689&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KARIMI ROZVEH A., SAYADI L., HAJIBABAEE F., ALZUBAIDI S.S.I. Relationship between intention to leave with job satisfaction and burnout of nurses in Iraq: A cross-sectional correlational study. J Multidiscip Care. 2023;12:39&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KELLOWAY E.K., GOTTLIEB B.H., BARHAM L. The source, nature, and direction of work and family conflict: a longitudinal investigation. J Occup Health Psychol. 1999;4:337&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10526838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KIM Y., LEE E., LEE H. Association between workplace bullying and burnout, professional quality of life, and turnover intention among clinical nurses. PLoS one. 2019;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6924657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31860673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KIM Y.-B., LEE S.-H. The nursing work environment, supervisory support, nurse characteristics, and burnout as predictors of intent to stay among hospital nurses in the Republic of Korea: A path analysis. Healthcare. 2023:1653. MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37297792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KIM G.-M., LEE O.-K., SIM S.-H. Impacts of Ethical Dilemma, Job Stress, and Burnout on Turnover Intention of Long-term Care Hospital Nurses. J. Korean Acad. psychiatr. Ment. Health Nurs. 2024;33:210&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOX J., GROENEWOUD J., BAKKER E., BIERMA-ZEINSTRA S., RUNHAAR J., MIEDEMA H., ROELOFS P. Reasons why Dutch novice nurses leave nursing: A qualitative approach. Nurse educ. pract. 2020;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32781415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KRAUSZ M., SAGIE A., BIDERMANN Y. Actual and preferred work schedules and scheduling control as determinants of job-related attitudes. J. vocat. behav. 2000;56:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KUCUKKELEPCE G.S.SS, KARACA T. Job Satisfaction, Intent to Stay at Work, and Burnout Levels of Nurses Working in Coronavirus Disease 2019 Clinics: A Cross-Sectional Study. Mediterr. Nurs. Midwifery. 2022:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KUFFEL, Z. 2022. Healthcare provision under pressure from staff shortages.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KUTNEY-LEE A., BROOKS CARTHON M., SLOANE D.M., BOWLES K.H., MCHUGH M.D., AIKEN L.H. Electronic Health Record Usability: Associations With Nurse and Patient Outcomes in Hospitals. Med. Care. 2021:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8187272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEE H., KIM M.-S., YOON J.-A. Role of internal marketing, organizational commitment, and job stress in discerning the turnover intention of Korean nurses. Jpn. J. Nurs. Sci. 2011;8:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21615701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEE H., LIM Y., JUNG H.Y., SHIN Y.-W. Turnover intention of graduate nurses in South Korea. Jpn. J. Nurs. Sci. 2012;9:63&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22583941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEE L.C., YANG K.P., CHEN T.Y. A quasi-experimental study on a quality circle program in a Taiwanese hospital. Int J Qual Health Care. 2000;12:413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEINEWEBER C., CHUNGKHAM H.S., LINDQVIST R., WESTERLUND H., RUNESDOTTER S., SMEDS ALENIUS L., TISHELMAN C. Nurses' practice environment and satisfaction with schedule flexibility is related to intention to leave due to dissatisfaction: A multi-country, multilevel study. Int J Nurs Stud. 2016;58:47&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27087297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI C., CUI X., ZHAO Y., XIN Y., PAN W., ZHU Y. Missed Nursing Care as a Mediator in the Relationship between Career Calling and Turnover Intention. Int. Nurs. Rev. 2024;71:62&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37079658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI J.-H., CHEN T.-W., LEE H.-F., SHIH W.-M. The Effects of Emergency Room Violence toward Nurse&#x2032;s Intention to Leave&#x2014;Resilience as a Mediator. Healthcare. 2021;9:507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI N., ZHANG L., XIAO G., CHEN J., LU Q. The relationship between workplace violence, job satisfaction and turnover intention in emergency nurses. Int. Emerg. Nurs. 2019;45:50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30797732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI Z., CAO J., WU X., LI F., ZHU C. Intention to leave among newly graduated nurses: A descriptive, multicenter study. J. Adv. Nurs. 2020;76:3429&#x2013;3439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LIU Y., AUNGSUROCH Y. Factors influencing nurse-assessed quality nursing care: A cross-sectional study in hospitals. J. Adv. Nurs. 2018;74:935&#x2013;945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29148146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LIU S., GYABENG E., JOSHUA ATTEH SEWU G., NKRUMAH N.K., DARTEY B. Occupational health and safety and turnover intention in the Ghanaian power industry: The mediating effect of organizational commitment. BioMed Res. Int. 2019;2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6778914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31662974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LO W.-Y., LIN Y.-K., LEE H.-M., LIU T.-Y. The lens of Yin-Yang philosophy: the influence of paradoxical leadership and emotional intelligence on nurses&#x2019; organizational identification and turnover intention. Leadersh. Health Serv. 2023;36:434&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36853757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MA Y., CHEN F., XING D., MENG Q., ZHANG Y. Study on the associated factors of turnover intention among emergency nurses in China and the relationship between major factors. Int. Emerg. Nurs. 2022;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34864323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MALFAIT S., EECKLOO K., VAN BIESEN W., VAN HECKE A. The effectiveness of bedside handovers: A multilevel, longitudinal study of effects on nurses and patients. J. Adv. Nurs. 2019;75:1690&#x2013;1701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30666713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MCCLOSKEY J.C. Two requirements for job contentment: autonomy and social integration. Image J Nurs Sch. 1990;22:140&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2227978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MICHAELS C., SPECTOR P. Causes of Employee Turnover: A Test of the Mobley, Griffeth, Hand, and Meglino Model. J. Appl. Psychol. 1982;67:53&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MINKYUNG G., KIM Y.S., SOHYUNE S. Factors influencing turnover intention among operating room nurses in South Korea. J. Nurs. Res. 2022;30:e192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34897201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOBLEY W., HORNER S.O., HOLLINGSWORTH A.T. An evaluation of precursors of hospital employee turnover. J. appl. psychol. 1978;63(4):408&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">701211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOHAMMADNEJAD F., FREEMAN S., KLASSEN-ROSS T., HEMINGWAY D., BANNER D. Impacts of Technology Use on the Workload of Registered Nurses: A Scoping Review. J. Rehabil. Assist. Technol. Eng. 2023;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOKKINK L.B., DE VET H.C., PRINSEN C.A., PATRICK D.L., ALONSO J., BOUTER L.M., TERWEE C.B. COSMIN risk of bias checklist for systematic reviews of patient-reported outcome measures. Qual. life res. 2018;27:1171&#x2013;1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5891552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29260445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOON S.J., HAN S.S. A predictive model on turnover intention of nurses in Korea. J. Korean Acad. Nurs. 2011;41:633&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22143212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MRAYYAN M.T. Jordanian nurses' job satisfaction and intent to stay: comparing teaching and non-teaching hospitals. J. Prof. Nurs. 2007;23:125&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NAM S., KIM H., HONG S., WONG J.Y.H., FONG D.Y.T. The development of a shortened, Korean version of the Anticipated Turnover Scale for hospital nurses. Res. Nurs. Health. 2021;44:548&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NASERIAN E., POULADI S., BAGHERZADEH R., RAVANIPOUR M. Relationship between mental workload and musculoskeletal disorders with intention to leave service among nurses working at neonatal and pediatric departments: a cross-sectional study in Iran. BMC nurs. 2024;23:438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11202378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NEWHOUSE R.P., HOFFMAN J.J., SUFLITA J., HAIRSTON D.P. Evaluating an innovative program to improve new nurse graduate socialization into the acute healthcare setting. Nurs Adm Q. 2007;31:50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17198120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIKKHAH-FARKHANI Z., PIOTROWSKI A. Nurses&#x2019; turnover intention a comparative study between Iran and Poland. Med. Pr. 2020:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD/EUROPEAN COMMISSION . OECD Publishing; 2024. Health at a Glance: Europe 2024: State of Health in the EU Cycle.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PARK H. Unpublished doctoral dissertation. Yonsei University; 2002. Relationship between perceived nursing care role orgientation, job characteristics, and turnover among nurses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>POKU C.A., ABEBRESE A.K., DWUMFOUR C.K., OKRAKU A., ACQUAH D., BAM V. Draining the specialized nursing brains, the emigration paradigm of Ghana: A cross-sectional study. Nurs. Open. 2023;10:4022&#x2013;4032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36815597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RIVAZ M., TAVAKOLINIA M., MOMENNASAB M. Nursing professional practice environment and its relationship with nursing outcomes in intensive care units: a test of the structural equation model. Scand. J. Caring Sci. 2021;35:609&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SHAHPOURI S., NAMDARI K., ABEDI A. Mediating role of work engagement in the relationship between job resources and personal resources with turnover intention among female nurses. Appl. Nurs. Res. 2016;30:216&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27091281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SHOORIDEH F.A., ASHKTORAB T., YAGHMAEI F., ALAVI MAJD H. Relationship between ICU nurses&#x2019; moral distress with burnout and anticipated turnover. Nurs. Ethics. 2015;22:64&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24948793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SIMONS S. Workplace bullying experienced by Massachusetts registered nurses and the relationship to intention to leave the organization. Adv. nurs. sci. 2008;31:E48&#x2013;E59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18497581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SMAMA&#x2019;H Y., ESHAH N.F., AL-OWEIDAT I.A., RAYAN A., NASHWAN A.J. The impact of leadership styles of nurse managers on nurses&#x2019; motivation and turnover intention among Jordanian nurses. J. Healthc. Leadersh. 2023:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9884098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36718174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SONG J., KIM K., JANG Y. South Korean Nurse Residency Program for New Graduates: A Posttest Study. J. Contin. Educ. Nurs. 2024;55:393&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38696777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>STRUNK K.C., STRUNK K.K. The contribution of personality and workplace characteristics in predicting turnover intention among sexual assault nurse examiners: A path analytic study. J. forensic nurs. 2012;8:144&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22925130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SU X. Validation of the Chinese Version of the Turnover Intention Scale in Social Workers. J. Soc. Serv. Res. 2021;47:207&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SUNGUR C., &#xd6;ZER &#xd6;., SAYGILI M., U&#x11e;URLUO&#x11e;LU &#xd6;. Paternalistic Leadership, Organizational Cynicism, and Intention to Quit One&#x2019;s Job in Nursing. Hosp. Top. 2019;97:139&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TAMATA A.T., MOHAMMADNEZHAD M. A systematic review study on the factors affecting shortage of nursing workforce in the hospitals. Nurs Open. 2023;10:1247&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9912424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36303066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WAGNER C.M. Predicting nursing turnover with catastrophe theory. J. Adv. Nurs. 2010;66:2071&#x2013;2084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20636468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WANG X.-X., WANG L.-P., WANG Q.-Q., FANG Y.-Y., LV W.-J., HUANG H.-L., YANG T.-T., QIAN R.-L., ZHANG Y.-H. Related factors influencing Chinese psychiatric nurses' turnover: A cross-sectional study. J. Psychiatr. Ment. Health Nurs. 2022;29:698&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35716343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WEBSTER B., ARCHIBALD D. Self-rostering, work-life balance and job satisfaction in UK nursing: a literature review. Nurs Manag (Harrow) 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35880476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YANG Y.H., KIM J.K. Factors influencing turnover intention in clinical nurses: Compassion fatigue, coping, social support, and job satisfaction. J. Korean Acad. Nurs. Adm. 2016;22:562&#x2013;569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>YEH T.-F., CHANG Y.-C., FENG W.-H., SCLEROSIS M., YANG C.-C. Effect of workplace violence on turnover intention: the mediating roles of job control, psychological demands, and social support. INQ.: J. Health Care Organ. Provis. Financ. 2020;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZAHEER S., GINSBURG L., WONG H.J., THOMSON K., BAIN L., WULFFHART Z. Acute care nurses' perceptions of leadership, teamwork, turnover intention and patient safety - a mixed methods study. BMC Nurs. 2021;20:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8323271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34330272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHANG J., YANG X., ZHANG X., LIU Y., LIU M., FANG Y., LIU M., WU M. Mediating effects of social support and presenteeism on turnover intention and post-traumatic stress disorder among Chinese nurses in the post-pandemic era: a cross-sectional study. Front. Public Health. 2024;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10899410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38420027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>