<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41693614</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2151-4658</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis care &amp; research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Long-Term Lower Extremity Strength Training in Adults With Knee Osteoarthritis and Varus Alignment Reduce Knee Joint Loading During Gait?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/acr.80017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We examined whether 18 months of strength training in individuals with knee varus alignment and medial tibiofemoral osteoarthritis (OA) reduced knee joint loads during walking compared to an attention control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study was a secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial that compared the effects of strength training to a control group in adults with knee OA. For this analysis, control participants had knee varus malalignment (&#x2265;2&#xb0; varus; N&#xa0;=&#xa0;49); participants in the strength training group met the varus malalignment criterion and increased their hip abductor strength by &#x2265;20% from baseline to 18-month follow-up (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;39). Linear regressions were used to compare means between groups at 18 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The strength training group had greater increases in strength in the quadriceps (45%), hamstrings (68%), and hip abductors (42%) than the control group (16%, 11%, 4%, respectively; P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). There were no significant differences in the mean peak internal knee abduction moment or mean peak knee compressive force between groups at 18-month follow-up. The adjusted means at 18-month follow-up for the internal knee extension moment were significantly less (27%) in the strength training group (P<sub>adjusted</sub>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.03).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Among older adults with knee OA and varus alignment, long-term lower extremity strength training results in significant increases in strength but does not significantly alter most measures of knee joint loading during walking relative to an attention control group. The results cast doubt on whether clinically meaningful improvement in lower extremity muscle strength translates to clinically important attenuation in knee joint loading.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Arthritis Care &amp; Research published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American College of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Messier</LastName><ForeName>Stephen P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7033-8459</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vigliotti</LastName><ForeName>Matthew N</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rice</LastName><ForeName>Paige E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pietrosimone</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mihalko</LastName><ForeName>Shannon L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ip</LastName><ForeName>Edward H</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loeser</LastName><ForeName>Richard F</ForeName><Initials>RF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2832-6144</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Carolina School of Medicine, Chapel Hill.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hunter</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3197-752X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guermazi</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saldana</LastName><ForeName>Santiago</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennell</LastName><ForeName>Kim L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeVita</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>East Carolina University, Greenville, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>1 R01 AR059105-01</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>General Nutrition Centers</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG21332</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1 R01 AR059105-01</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG21332</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518086</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2151-464X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41693614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.80017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Theis KA, Murphy LB, Guglielmo D, et al. Prevalence of arthritis and arthritis&#x2010;attributable activity limitation &#x2013; United States, 2016&#x2010;2018. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2021;70(40):1401&#x2013;1407. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7040a2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neogi T. The epidemiology and impact of pain in osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2013;21(9):1145&#x2013;1153. doi:10.1016/j.joca.2013.03.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Jin F, Yao X, et al. Disease burden of osteoarthritis of the knee and hip due to a high body mass index in China and the USA: 1990&#x2010;2019 findings from the global burden of disease study 2019. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2022;23(1):63. doi:10.1186/s12891-022-05027-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramoff B, Caldera FE. Osteoarthritis. Med Clin North Am 2020;104(2):293&#x2013;311. doi:10.1016/j.mcna.2019.10.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes DG, Costa D, Cruz EB, et al. Association of physical activity with physical function and quality of life in people with hip and knee osteoarthritis: longitudinal analysis of a population&#x2010;based cohort. Arthritis Res Ther 2023;25:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primorac D, Molnar V, Rod E, et al. Knee osteoarthritis: a review of pathogenesis and state&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;art non&#x2010;operative therapeutic considerations. Genes (Basel) 2020;11(8):854. doi:10.3390/genes11080854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pre&#x2010;Competitive Consortium for Osteoarthritis; Osteoarthritis Research Society International. OA as a serious disease. Osteoarthritis Research Society International. December 1, 2016. Accessed August 31, 2022. https://oarsi.org/research-oarsi-success/oa-serious-disease</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BE, Girdwood MA, West TJ, et al. Muscle strength and osteoarthritis of the knee: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of longitudinal studies. Skeletal Radiol 2023;52(11):2085&#x2013;2097. doi:10.1007/s00256-022-04266-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinman RS, Hunt MA, Creaby MW, et al. Hip muscle weakness in individuals with medial knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2010;62(8):1190&#x2013;1193. doi:10.1002/acr.20199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnahdi AH, Zeni JA, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L. Muscle impairments in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Sports Health 2012;4(4):284&#x2013;292. doi:10.1177/1941738112445726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghava Neelapala YV, Bhagat M, Shah P. Hip muscle strengthening for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review of literature. J Geriatr Phys Ther 2020;43(2):89&#x2013;98. doi:10.1519/JPT.0000000000000214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza RB, Baum T, Wu S, et al. Effects of unloading on knee articular cartilage T1rho and T2 magnetic resonance imaging relaxation times: a case series. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2012;42(6):511&#x2013;520. doi:10.2519/jospt.2012.3975</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardinier ES, Di Stasi S, Manal K, et al. Knee contact force asymmetries in patients who failed return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport readiness criteria 6 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med 2014;42(12):2917&#x2013;2925. doi:10.1177/0363546514552184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Jordan JM. Epidemiology of osteoarthritis. Clin Geriatr Med 2010;26(3):355&#x2013;369. doi:10.1016/j.cger.2010.03.001 Erratum in: Clin Geriatr Med 2013;29:ix.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurwitz DE, Ryals AB, Case JP, et al. The knee adduction moment during gait in subjects with knee osteoarthritis is more closely correlated with static alignment than radiographic disease severity, toe out angle and pain. J Orthop Res 2002;20(1):101&#x2013;107. doi:10.1016/S0736-0266(01)00081-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Pater M, Beavers DP, et al. Influences of alignment and obesity on knee joint loading in osteoarthritic gait. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2014;22(7):912&#x2013;917. doi:10.1016/j.joca.2014.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanamas S, Hanna FS, Cicuttini FM, et al. Does knee malalignment increase the risk of development and progression of knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review. Arthritis Rheum 2009;61(4):459&#x2013;467. doi:10.1002/art.24336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birmingham TB, Kramer JF, Kirkley A, et al. Association among neuromuscular and anatomic measures for patients with knee osteoarthritis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2001;82(8):1115&#x2013;1118. doi:10.1053/apmr.2001.24306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer GM, van Tol AW, Bergink AP, et al. Association between valgus and varus alignment and the development and progression of radiographic osteoarthritis of the knee. Arthritis Rheum 2007;56(4):1204&#x2013;1211. doi:10.1002/art.22515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma L, Dunlop DD, Cahue S, et al. Quadriceps strength and osteoarthritis progression in malaligned and lax knees. Ann Intern Med 2003;138(8):613&#x2013;619. doi:10.7326/0003-4819-138-8-200304150-00006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang A, Hayes K, Dunlop D, et al. Hip abduction moment and protection against medial tibiofemoral osteoarthritis progression. Arthritis Rheum 2005;52(11):3515&#x2013;3519. doi:10.1002/art.21406</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorp LE, Wimmer MA, Foucher KC, et al. The biomechanical effects of focused muscle training on medial knee loads in OA of the knee: a pilot, proof of concept study. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 2010;10(2):166&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Hunt MA, Wrigley TV, et al. Hip strengthening reduces symptoms but not knee load in people with medial knee osteoarthritis and varus malalignment: a randomised controlled trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2010;18(5):621&#x2013;628. doi:10.1016/j.joca.2010.01.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sled EA, Khoja L, Deluzio KJ, et al. Effect of a home program of hip abductor exercises on knee joint loading, strength, function, and pain in people with knee osteoarthritis: a clinical trial. Phys Ther 2010;90(6):895&#x2013;904. doi:10.2522/ptj.20090294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVita P, Aaboe J, Bartholdy C, et al. Quadriceps&#x2010;strengthening exercise and quadriceps and knee biomechanics during walking in knee osteoarthritis: a two&#x2010;centre randomized controlled trial. Clin Biomech (Bristol) 2018;59:199&#x2013;206. doi:10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2018.09.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Mihalko SL, Beavers DP, et al. Strength Training for Arthritis Trial (START): design and rationale. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2013;14(1):208. doi:10.1186/1471-2474-14-208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma L, Lou C, Cahue S, et al. The mechanism of the effect of obesity in knee osteoarthritis: the mediating role of malalignment. Arthritis Rheum 2000;43(3):568&#x2013;575. doi:10.1002/1529-0131(200003)43:3&lt;568:AID-ANR13&gt;3.0.CO;2-E</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman RD, Gold GE. Atlas of individual radiographic features in osteoarthritis, revised. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2007;15 Suppl A:A1&#x2013;A56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, B&#xe9;dirian V, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;699. doi:10.1111/j.1532&#x2010;5415.2005.53221.x Erratum in: J Am Geriatr Soc 2019;67:1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellgren JH, Lawrence JS. Radiological assessment of osteo&#x2010;arthrosis. Ann Rheum Dis 1957;16(4):494&#x2013;502. doi:10.1136/ard.16.4.494</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell AL, Brand RA, Pedersen DR. Prediction of hip joint centre location from external landmarks. Hum Mov Sci 1989;8(1):3&#x2013;16. doi:10.1016/0167-9457(89)90020-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell AL, Pedersen DR, Brand RA. A comparison of the accuracy of several hip center location prediction methods. J Biomech 1990;23(6):617&#x2013;621. doi:10.1016/0021-9290(90)90054-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVita P, Hortobagyi T. Functional knee brace alters predicted knee muscle and joint forces in people with ACL reconstruction during walking. J Appl Biomech 2001;17(4):297&#x2013;311. doi:10.1123/jab.17.4.297</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Legault C, Loeser RF, et al. Does high weight loss in older adults with knee osteoarthritis affect bone&#x2010;on&#x2010;bone joint loads and muscle forces during walking? Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2011;19(3):272&#x2013;280. doi:10.1016/j.joca.2010.11.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumas R, Barr&#xe9; A, Moissenet F, et al. Can a reduction approach predict reliable joint contact and musculo&#x2010;tendon forces? J Biomech 2019;95:109329. doi:10.1016/j.jbiomech.2019.109329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy N, Buchanan WW, Goldsmith CH, et al. Validation study of WOMAC: a health status instrument for measuring clinically important patient relevant outcomes following total hip or knee arthroplasty in osteoarthritis. J Orthop Rheumatol 1988;1:95&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths G, Bellamy N, Kean WF, et al. A study of the time frame dependency of responses to the WOMAC osteoarthritis index. Inflammopharmacology 1993;2(1):85&#x2013;87. doi:10.1007/BF02663745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapstad H, Hanestad BR, Langeland N, et al. Cutpoints for mild, moderate and severe pain in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee ready for joint replacement surgery. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2008;9(1):55. doi:10.1186/1471-2474-9-55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siviero P, Limongi F, Gesmundo A, et al; EPOSA Research Group. Minimal clinically important decline in physical function over one year: EPOSA study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2019;20(1):227. doi:10.1186/s12891-019-2593-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor JM, Mills K, Buhagiar M, et al. Minimal important improvement thresholds for the six&#x2010;minute walk test in a knee arthroplasty cohort: triangulation of anchor&#x2010; and distribution&#x2010;based methods. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2016;17(1):390. doi:10.1186/s12891-016-1249-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry J, Burnfield J. Gait Analysis: Normal and Pathological Function. 2nd ed. Taylor &amp; Francis Group; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manal K, Gardinier E, Buchanan TS, et al. A more informed evaluation of medial compartment loading: the combined use of the knee adduction and flexor moments. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2015;23(7):1107&#x2013;1111. doi:10.1016/j.joca.2015.02.779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Mihalko SL, Beavers DP, et al. Effect of high&#x2010;intensity strength training on knee pain and knee joint compressive forces among adults with knee osteoarthritis: the START randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2021;325(7):646&#x2013;657. doi:10.1001/jama.2021.0411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Legault C, Mihalko S, et al. The Intensive Diet and Exercise for Arthritis (IDEA) trial: design and rationale. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2009;10:93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astephen JL, Deluzio KJ, Caldwell GE, et al. Biomechanical changes at the hip, knee, and ankle joints during gait are associated with knee osteoarthritis severity. J Orthop Res 2008;26(3):332&#x2013;341. doi:10.1002/jor.20496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz RJ, Harrison D, Wang H&#x2010;M, et al. Sagittal&#x2010;plane knee moment during gait and knee cartilage thickness. J Athl Train 2017;52(6):560&#x2013;566. doi:10.4085/1062-2050-52.4.05</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Mihalko SL, Legault C, et al. Effects of intensive diet and exercise on knee joint loads, inflammation, and clinical outcomes among overweight and obese adults with knee osteoarthritis: the IDEA randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2013;310(12):1263&#x2013;1273. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.277669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson DR, McWalter EJ, Johnston JD. The measurement of joint mechanics and their role in osteoarthritis genesis and progression. Rheum Dis Clin North Am 2008;34(3):605&#x2013;622. doi:10.1016/j.rdc.2008.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung EV, Marriott KA, Laing AC, et al. The relationship between muscle capacity utilization during gait and pain in people with symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. Gait Posture 2022;94:58&#x2013;66. doi:10.1016/j.gaitpost.2022.02.021</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>