<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41868476</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2398-502X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Wellcome open research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Wellcome Open Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing implementation strategies for improving infection prevention and control in acute healthcare facilities in Malawi: A formative study protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>223</StartPage><MedlinePgn>223</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">223</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.24040.3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Healthcare associated infections (HAIs) are infections that patients acquire while receiving treatment and are not present during admission. The prevalence of HAIs is typically higher (15%) in low-and middle-income countries than that in high-income countries (7%). HAIs present a significant burden on patients, families, and health systems as they contribute to longer hospital stays, increased healthcare costs, and antimicrobial resistance. HAIs can be prevented or reduced by implementing infection prevention and control (IPC) measures. However, IPC measures are often poorly implemented due to resource shortages, lack of training, and other systemic challenges. The goals of this formative study were twofold: 1. to carry out a situational analysis of IPC practices for HAI control in three hospitals in Southern Malawi, highlighting specific bottlenecks and enablers of IPC practices; and 2. to co-design tailored implementation strategies based on insights from situational analysis using participatory approaches with key IPC stakeholders to support more consistent and effective IPC implementation at the study sites.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study will be conducted in three health facilities in Malawi representing different healthcare levels: Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital, Zomba Central Hospital, and Chikwawa District Hospital. For situational analysis, six data collection tools will be used: a desk review of IPC policies and guidelines, the World Health Organization IPC Assessment Framework, participant and non-participant structured observations, interviews, and focus group discussions. The participatory component involves a three-day co-design workshop. Participants in both study components will include healthcare workers, support staff, policymakers, patients, and patient caregivers (guardians). Descriptive statistics will be used to analyse the quantitative data. A thematic framework analysis using NVivo 12 will be done on the qualitative data. The findings will be disseminated through workshops, academic publications, and stakeholder meetings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Multifaceted IPC implementation strategies tailored to the context of each hospital will be designed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Ng'ambi D et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ng'ambi</LastName><ForeName>Dorica</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-8766-8669</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Biology - BDRI, Malawi-Liverpool-Wellcome Trust Clinical Research Programme, Blantyre, Southern Region, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Sciences, Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, Liverpool, England, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tancred</LastName><ForeName>Tara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Sciences, Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, Liverpool, England, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feasey</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4041-1405</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Biology - BDRI, Malawi-Liverpool-Wellcome Trust Clinical Research Programme, Blantyre, Southern Region, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Sciences, Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, Liverpool, England, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The School of Medicine, University of St Andrews Faculty of Medicine, St Andrews, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hara</LastName><ForeName>Wilned Zoto</ForeName><Initials>WZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Improvement Unit, Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital, Blantyre, Southern Region, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Musopole</LastName><ForeName>Owen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Management Directorate, Government of Malawi Ministry of Health, Lilongwe, Central Region, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Byrne</LastName><ForeName>Thomasena</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Biology - BDRI, Malawi-Liverpool-Wellcome Trust Clinical Research Programme, Blantyre, Southern Region, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Sciences, Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, Liverpool, England, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Wellcome Open Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101696457</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2398-502X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Healthcare associated infections (HAIs) are infections that patients catch while being treated in health facilities. These infections are a significant health problem, especially in low-resource settings, such as Malawi. HAIs can lead to longer hospital stays, cost more money for patients and hospitals, and make it more difficult to treat illnesses and diseases because of drug resistance. Common types of hospital acquired infections include infections after surgery, infections from cannulas and catheters, and pneumonia acquired in hospitals. The World Health Organization (WHO) has established guidelines on infection prevention and control (IPC) to help hospitals prevent these infections. However, many hospitals in Malawi struggle to follow these guidelines because of challenges such as lack of staff, lack of training, and shortage of necessary supplies. This study focused on developing context-specific practical ways to improve IPC practices in hospitals in Malawi. This study will be conducted in three hospitals in Malawi. We aim to: 1. understand how IPC is currently being implemented in hospitals; 2. identify what makes it difficult or easy to follow IPC practices; and 3. involve everyone in creating a plan to improve the IPC. To do so, we will collect data from healthcare workers, policymakers, patients, caregivers, and guardians. We will interview some of these participants and conduct group discussions with others. We will also conduct observations of IPC practices. After learning from the collected data, we will work with some of these participants to develop practical ways to improve IPC practices in these hospitals. Findings from this research will be shared with hospital staff, the hospital community (patients, guardians, caregivers, and visitors), the government, and the public to promote better IPC practices across the country.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Ng'ambi D et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection prevention and control; healthcare associated infections; formative research; co-design; implementation strategies; WHO core components of IPC</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No competing interests were disclosed.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41868476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13000401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.24040.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Storr J, Twyman A, Zingg W, et al. :
Core components for effective Infection Prevention and Control programmes: new WHO evidence-based recommendations.

<i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control.</i>

2017;6(6): 6.
10.1186/s13756-016-0149-9


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-016-0149-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Allegranzi B, Nejad SB, Combescure C, et al. :
Burden of endemic health-care-associated infection in developing countries: systematic review and meta-analysis.

<i>Lancet.</i>

2011;377(9761):228&#x2013;41.
10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61458-4

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61458-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21146207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tomczyk S, Twyman A, de Kraker MEA, et al. :
The first WHO global survey on Infection Prevention and Control in health-care facilities.

<i>Lancet Infect Dis.</i>

2022;22(6):845&#x2013;56.
10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00809-4


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00809-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Allegranzi B, Kilpatrick C, Storr J, et al. :
Global Infection Prevention and Control priorities 2018&#x2013;22: a call for action.

<i>Lancet Glob Health.</i>

2017;5(12):e1178&#x2013;80.
10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30427-8


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30427-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7129117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29132606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bunduki GK, Masoamphambe E, Fox T, et al. :
Prevalence, risk factors, and antimicrobial resistance of endemic healthcare-associated infections in Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis.

<i>BMC Infect Dis.</i>

2024;24(1): 158.
10.1186/s12879-024-09038-0


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-024-09038-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10836007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38302895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tomczyk S, Storr J, Kilpatrick C, et al. :
Infection Prevention and Control (IPC) implementation in low-resource settings: a qualitative analysis.

<i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control.</i>

2021;10(1): 113.
10.1186/s13756-021-00962-3


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-021-00962-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34332622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization:
Core competencies for Infection Prevention and Control professionals.Geneva: World Health Organization,2020.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization:
Global guidelines for the prevention of surgical site infection.Geneva: World Health Organization2016;184.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ademuyiwa AO, Hardy P, Runigamugabo E, et al. :
Reducing Surgical Site Infections in Low-income and Middle-Income Countries (FALCON): a pragmatic, multicentre, stratified, randomised controlled trial.

<i>Lancet.</i>

2021;398(10312):1687&#x2013;99.
10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01548-8


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01548-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
By P, Black F, Hanchett M:
Preventing CAUTI: a patient-centered approach the infection prevention community must assure that ongoing CAUTI prevention programs are inclusive and effective.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Flores-Mireles A, Hreha TN, Hunstad DA:
Pathophysiology, treatment, and prevention of Catheter-Associated Urinary Tract Infection.

<i>Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil.</i>

2019;25(3):228&#x2013;40.
10.1310/sci2503-228


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1310/sci2503-228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6743745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce N: Improving compliance with Healthcare Associated Infection (HAI) practice guidelines to reduce the acquisition of HAIs. 2013;50. 10.7275/4356639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7275/4356639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Alqarni MS:
Catheter-Associated Urinary Tract Infection (CAUTI) in ICU patients.

<i>Middle East J Nurs.</i>

2021;15(1):25&#x2013;33.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wolfensberger A, Clack L, von Felten S, et al. :
Implementation and evaluation of a care bundle for prevention of non-ventilator-associated Hospital-Acquired Pneumonia (nvHAP) - A mixed-methods study protocol for a hybrid type 2 effectiveness-implementation trial.

<i>BMC Infect Dis.</i>

2020;20(1): 603.
10.1186/s12879-020-05271-5


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-020-05271-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32807090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Oranization:
Guidelines on core components of Infection Prevention and Control programmes at the national and acute health care facility level.2016;1&#x2013;91.
Reference Source
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27977095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utilization of family members to provide hospital care in Malawi: the role of hospital guardians.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Mangochi H, Tolhurst R, Simpson V, et al. :
A qualitative study exploring hand hygiene practices in a neonatal unit in Blantyre, Malawi: implications for controlling healthcare-associated infections [version 3; peer review: 2 approved].

<i>Wellcome Open Res.</i>

2022;7:146.
10.12688/wellcomeopenres.17793.1


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.17793.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37224320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Basu L, Frescas R, Kiwelu H:
Patient guardians as an instrument for person centered care.

<i>Global Health.</i>

 2014;10: 33.
10.1186/1744-8603-10-33


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-8603-10-33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Spoon D, Rietbergen T, Huis A, et al. :
Implementation strategies used to implement nursing guidelines in daily practice: a systematic review.

<i>Int J Nurs Stud.</i>

2020;111:
103748.
10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2020.103748

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2020.103748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Minimum requirements for Infection Prevention and Control programmes.
 2019.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization:
Global report on Infection Prevention and Control.Geneva: World Health Organization,2022;40&#x2013;41.
Reference Source
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Craig P, Dieppe P, Macintyre S, et al. :
Developing and evaluating complex interventions: the new Medical Research Council guidance.

<i>BMJ.</i>

2008;337(7676):
a1655.
10.1136/bmj.a1655


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.a1655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2769032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18824488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gadama Y, Kamtchum-Tatuene J, Benjamin L, et al. :
The significant gap between international standards and stroke management practices at Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital (Malawi): an audit report.

<i>Malawi Med J.</i>

2019;31(4):249&#x2013;55.
10.4314/mmj.v31i4.6


</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/mmj.v31i4.6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7036432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32128035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Barbour RS:
Making sense of focus groups.

<i>Med Educ.</i>

2005;39(7):742&#x2013;50.
10.1111/j.1365-2929.2005.02200.x

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2929.2005.02200.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hopkins PE:
Thinking critically and creatively about focus groups.

<i>Area.</i>

2007;39(4):528&#x2013;35.
10.1111/j.1475-4762.2007.00766.x
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-4762.2007.00766.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malawi Ministry of Health: National IPC-WASH-AMS guideline.2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ng'ambi D:
Data collection tools.

<i>Zenodo.</i>

 2025.
10.5281/zenodo.15202999
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.15202999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
:
The Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR) User Guide: a five-step guide for conducting implementation research using the framework.

<i>Implementation Science</i>
.2025;20(1) :
10.1186/s13012-025-01450-7
10.1186/s13012-025-01450-7

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-025-01450-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12357348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40819067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
:
Head Nurse Leadership: Facilitators and Barriers to Adherence to Infection Prevention and Control Programs&#x2014;A Qualitative Study Protocol.

<i>Nursing Reports</i>
.2024;14(3) :
10.3390/nursrep14030138
1849-1858
10.3390/nursrep14030138
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nursrep14030138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11348038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39189268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
:
The Nursing Organisational Context and the Surgical Site Infections: A Structural Equational Model.

<i>Nursing Open</i>
.2025;12(11) :
10.1002/nop2.70372
10.1002/nop2.70372
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.70372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12643819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41286584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>