<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41626406</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2976-8357</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Substance use : research and treatment</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Subst Use</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Building Community Capacity for Harm Reduction: An Adaptive Implementation Science Approach in Rural Appalachian Ohio.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29768357251413412</StartPage><MedlinePgn>29768357251413412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">29768357251413412</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/29768357251413412</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Rural communities face significant implementation challenges addressing the overdose epidemic, including limited treatment capacity, pervasive stigma toward people who use drugs, and social and political opposition to evidence-based interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Rather than implementing prescribed harm reduction services that may face community resistance, the Ohio Opioid Project adopted a capacity-building approach to address structural barriers and enhance community readiness for future harm reduction and treatment innovation across 3 rural Appalachian Ohio counties.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This applied implementation project used the Evidence-Making Intervention framework with process evaluation. Mixed-methods formative research included interviews with stakeholders (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;34) and people who use drugs (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;30), respondent-driven sampling surveys with people who use drugs (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;258), organizational network analysis, and surveillance data review. A 9-member Community Leadership Board - including health commissioners, treatment providers, and harm reduction program representatives - co-developed interventions targeting 3 structural barriers: substance use-related stigma, interagency fragmentation, and inadequate provider capacity. Community members served as leadership board representatives, implementation staff, intervention consultants, and data collectors, democratizing research involvement and building local public health capacity. Implementation followed an adaptive approach, allowing activities to evolve based on emerging needs, policy changes, and the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The service delivery plan included 20+&#x2009;activities across stigma reduction, interagency coordination, and provider capacity building. Key activities included peer recovery supporter training, law enforcement harm reduction seminars, faith-based stigma reduction forums, conflict resolution processes, establishment of drug court buprenorphine protocols, and HCV telehealth partnerships. Multiple activities were sustained by community partners beyond the research period, including resource clearinghouses, new regional partnerships, and organizational protocols integrating harm reduction into existing services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Capacity-building implementation science can address structural barriers to community-based harm reduction in resistant rural settings. By prioritizing community co-creation and adaptive implementation, this approach created foundational conditions for sustainable harm reduction innovation while respecting local contexts and readiness for change.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sibley</LastName><ForeName>Adams L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5073-8677</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Injury Prevention Research Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schalkoff</LastName><ForeName>Christine A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colston</LastName><ForeName>David C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piscalko</LastName><ForeName>Hannah M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Epidemiology, The Ohio State University College of Public Health, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spears</LastName><ForeName>Abby G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scioto Connect, Portsmouth, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>William C</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Go</LastName><ForeName>Vivian F</ForeName><Initials>VF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Subst Use</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918769579606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2976-8357</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capacity building</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community engagement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">harm reduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rural health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41626406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12852583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/29768357251413412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_29768357251413412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
National Institute on Drug Abuse. Drug overdose deaths: facts and figures. 2025. Accessed September 6, 2024. https://nida.nih.gov/research-topics/trends-statistics/overdose-death-rates</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigg KK, Monnat SM, Chavez MN. Opioid-related mortality in rural America: geographic heterogeneity and intervention strategies. Int J Drug Policy. 2018;57:119-129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29754032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody LN, Satterwhite E, Bickel WK. Substance use in rural Central Appalachia: current status and treatment considerations. J Rural Ment Health. 2017;41(2):123-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5648074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29057030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters DJ, Monnat SM, Hochstetler AL, Berg MT. The opioid hydra: understanding overdose mortality epidemics and syndemics across the rural-Urban Continuum. Rural Sociol. 2020;85(3):589-622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33814639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swann WL, Kim S, Kim SY, Schreiber TL. Urban-rural disparities in opioid use disorder prevention and response activities: a cross-sectional analysis. J Rural Health. 2021;37(1):16-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32639664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezell JM, Walters S, Friedman SR, et al. Stigmatize the use, not the user? Attitudes on opioid use, drug injection, treatment, and overdose prevention in rural communities. Soc Sci Med. 2021;268:113470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33253992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins RA, Whitney BM, Nance RM, et al. The rural opioid initiative consortium description: providing evidence to understand the fourth wave of the opioid crisis. Addict Sci Clin Pract. 2022;17(1):38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9321271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35883197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeller TA, Beachler T, Diaz L, et al. Attitudes toward syringe exchange programs in a rural Appalachian community. J Addict Dis. 2022;40(2):227-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34550054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner BJ. A theory of organizational readiness for change. Implement Sci. 2009;4(1):67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilenski SM, Greenberg MT, Feinberg ME. Community readiness as a multidimensional construct. J Community Psychol. 2007;35(3):347-365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2517859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engstrom M, Jason LA, Townsend SM, Pokorny SB, Curie CJ. Community readiness for prevention: applying stage theory to multi-community interventions. J Prev Interv Community. 2002;24(1):29-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson-Carpenter KD, Watson-Thompson J, Jones MD, Chaney L. Improving community readiness for change through coalition capacity building: evidence from a multisite intervention. J Community Psychol. 2017;45(4):486-499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28458405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson MG, Lavis JN, Travers R, Rourke SB. Community-based knowledge transfer and exchange: helping community-based organizations link research to action. Implement Sci. 2010;5(1):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20423486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes T, Lancaster K. Evidence-making interventions in health: a conceptual framing. Soc Sci Med. 2019;238:112488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31422173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsui JI, Whitney BM, Korthuis PT, et al. Methamphetamine use and utilization of medications for opioid use disorder among rural people who use drugs. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2023;250:110911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10599300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37549545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moullin JC, Dickson KS, Stadnick NA, Rabin B, Aarons GA. Systematic review of the exploration, preparation, implementation, Sustainment (EPIS) framework. Implement Sci. 2019;14(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6321673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30611302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard EL, Schalkoff CA, Piscalko HM, et al. &#x201c;You are not clean until you&#x2019;re not on anything&#x201d;: perceptions of medication-assisted treatment in rural Appalachia. Int J Drug Policy. 2020;85:102704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32173274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibley AL, Schalkoff CA, Richard EL, et al. &#x201c;I was raised in addiction&#x201d;: constructions of the self and the other in discourses of addiction and recovery. Qual Health Res. 2020;30(14):2278-2290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7649922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalkoff CA, Richard EL, Piscalko HM, et al. &#x201c;Now we are seeing the tides wash in&#x201d;: trauma and the opioid epidemic in rural Appalachian Ohio. Subst Use Misuse. 2021;56(5):650-659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33678117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins AB, Boyd J, Cooper HLF, McNeil R. The intersectional risk environment of people who use drugs. Soc Sci Med. 2019;234:112384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6719791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31254965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloud DH, Ibragimov U, Prood N, Young AM, Cooper HLF. Rural risk environments for hepatitis c among young adults in appalachian kentucky. Int J Drug Policy. 2019;72:47-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7335461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadanelli M, Cloud DH, Ibragimov U, et al. People, places, and stigma: a qualitative study exploring the overdose risk environment in rural Kentucky. Int J Drug Policy. 2020;85:102588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varda DM, Sprong S. Evaluating networks using PARTNER: a social network data tracking and learning tool. New Dir Eval. 2020;2020(165):67-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Akah H, Bush Stevens A, Santiago J. Addiction Evidence Project. Health Policy Institute of Ohio; 2021. Accessed November 22, 2024. https://www.healthpolicyohio.org/our-work/publications/addiction-evidence-project</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Institute on Drug Abuse. Risk behavior survey. 2016. Accessed December 5, 2025. https://datashare.nida.nih.gov/instrument/risk-behavior-survey</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan AT, Cacciola JC, Alterman AI, Rikoon SH, Carise D. The Addiction Severity Index at 25: origins, contributions and transitions. Am J Addict. 2006;15(2):113-124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havens JR, Lofwall MR, Frost SD, Oser CB, Leukefeld CG, Crosby RA. Individual and network factors associated with prevalent hepatitis C infection among rural Appalachian injection drug users. Am J Public Health. 2013;103(1):e44-e52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3518360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curriero FC, Wychgram C, Rebman AW, et al. The Lyme and Tickborne Disease Dashboard: a map-based resource to promote public health awareness and research collaboration. PLoS One. 2021;16(12):e0260122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8635336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34851988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raderstrong J, Boyea-Robinson T. The why and how of working with communities through collective impact. Community Dev. 2016;47(2):181-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kania J, Hanleybrown F, Splansky Juster J. Essential Mindset Shifts for Collective Impact. Standford Social Innovation Review; 2014. Accessed October 1, 2024. https://ssir.org/articles/entry/essential_mindset_shifts_for_collective_impact</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes T, Closson EF, Paparini S, Guise A, Strathdee S. Towards &#x201c;evidence-making intervention&#x201d; approaches in the social science of implementation science: the making of methadone in East Africa. Int J Drug Policy. 2016;30:17-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26905934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadish WR, Cook TD, Campbell DT. Experimental and Quasi-Experimental Designs for Generalized Causal Inference. 2nd ed. 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrends CN, Lu X, Corry GJ, et al. Harm reduction and health services provided by syringe services programs in 2019 and subsequent impact of COVID-19 on services in 2020. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2022;232:109323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8772135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins WD, Bolinski R, Bresett J, et al. COVID-19 During the opioid epidemic - exacerbation of stigma and vulnerabilities. J Rural Health. 2021;37(1):172-174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibley AL, Baker R, Levander XA, et al. &#x201c;I am not a junkie&#x201d;: social categorization and differentiation among people who use drugs. Int J Drug Policy. 2023;114:103999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10066877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36905779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook DL, Hetrick AT, Chettri SR, et al. The relationship between hepatitis C virus rates and office-based buprenorphine access in Ohio. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(6):ofab242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34159217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke E, Pyle M, Machin K, Varese F, Morrison AP. The effects of peer support on empowerment, self-efficacy, and internalized stigma: a narrative synthesis and meta-analysis. Stigma Health. 2019;4(3):337-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailie HA, Tickle A. Effects of employment as a peer support worker on personal recovery: a review of qualitative evidence. Ment Health Rev J. 2015;20(1):48-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froehlich W. Introduction to the Divided Community Project. Dispute Resolut J. 2018;73(3):9-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huskamp HA, Busch AB, Souza J, et al. How is telemedicine being used in opioid and other substance use disorder treatment? Health Aff. 2018;37(12):1940-1947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30633671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schranz AJ, Barrett J, Hurt CB, Malvestutto C, Miller WC. Challenges facing a rural opioid epidemic: treatment and prevention of HIV and hepatitis C. Curr HIV/AIDS Rep. 2018;15(3):245-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29796965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Substance Abuse &amp; Mental Health Services Administration. Waiver elimination (MAT Act). 2023. Accessed June 7, 2023. https://www.samhsa.gov/medications-substance-use-disorders/waiver-elimination-mat-act</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talal AH, Markatou M, Liu A, et al. Integrated hepatitis C-opioid use disorder care through facilitated telemedicine: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2024;331(16):1369-1378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38568601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaspohler P, Duffy J, Wandersman A, Stillman L, Maras MA. Unpacking prevention capacity: an intersection of research-to-practice models and community-centered models. Am J Community Psychol. 2008;41(3-4):182-196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18307028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birgel V, Decker L, R&#xf6;ding D, Walter U. Community capacity for prevention and health promotion: a scoping review on underlying domains and assessment methods. Syst Rev. 2023;12:147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37608344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster K, Rhodes T, Rosengarten M. Making evidence and policy in public health emergencies: lessons from COVID-19 for adaptive evidence-making and intervention. Evid Policy. 2020;16:477-490. doi: 10.1332/174426420X15913559981103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1332/174426420X15913559981103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitenstein SM, Gross D, Garvey CA, Hill C, Fogg L, Resnick B. Implementation fidelity in community-based interventions. Res Nurs Health. 2010;33(2):164-173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3409469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnstein SR. A ladder of citizen participation. J Am Inst Plann. 1969;35(4):216-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos WJ, Graham ID, Lalonde M, Demery Varin M, Squires JE. The effectiveness of champions in implementing innovations in health care: a systematic review. Implement Sci Commun. 2022;3(1):80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9308185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunce AE, Gru&#xdf; I, Davis JV, et al. Lessons learned about the effective operationalization of champions as an implementation strategy: results from a qualitative process evaluation of a pragmatic trial. Implement Sci. 2020;15(1):87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32998750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes-Maslow L, Osborne I, Jilcott Pitts SB. Best practices and innovative solutions to overcome barriers to delivering policy, systems and environmental changes in rural communities. Nutrition. 2018;10(8):1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dent E, Hoon E, Kitson A, et al. Translating a health service intervention into a rural setting: lessons learned. BMC Health Serv Res. 2016;16(1):62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4758176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SL, Blake K, Olson CR, Tessaro I. Community entry in conducting rural focus groups: process, legitimacy, and lessons learned. J Rural Health. 2002;18(1):118-124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12043750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy LJ, Hughes A, Hulen E, Figueroa A, Evans C, Begay RC. Hiring the experts: best practices for community-engaged research. Qual Res. 2016;16(5):592-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5100673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27833454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman SJ, Ye J, Leep CJ. Workforce turnover at local health departments: nature, characteristics, and implications. Am J Prev Med. 2014;47(5 3):S337-S343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25439254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Kerry J, McLean J, Hopkins T, et al. Characterizing asset-based studies in public health: development of a framework. Health Promot Int. 2023;38(2):daad015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10024477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36932994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S. Using theory-based evaluation to understand what works in asset-based community development. Community Dev J. 2023;58(2):206-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathie A, Cunningham G. From clients to citizens: asset-based community development as a strategy for community-driven development. Dev Pract. 2003;13(5):474-486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ennis G, West D. Exploring the potential of social network analysis in asset-based community development practice and research. Aust Soc Work. 2010;63(4):404-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musia&#x142; K, Juszczyszyn K. Properties of bridge nodes in social networks. In: Nguyen NT, Kowalczyk R, Chen SM, eds. Computational Collective Intelligence. Semantic Web, Social Networks and Multiagent Systems. Springer; 2009:357-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek SI, Bae SH. The effect of social network centrality on knowledge sharing. J Serv Sci Res. 2019;11(2):183-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samet JH, El-Bassel N, Winhusen TJ, et al. Community-based cluster-randomized trial to reduce opioid overdose deaths. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(11):989-1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11761538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38884347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>