<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41145337</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2426-0266</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of prevention of Alzheimer's disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Prev Alzheimers Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alzheimer Combination Therapies: Overview and Scenarios.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100328</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100328</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100328</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100328</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2274-5807(25)00271-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Progress in understanding the complexity of Alzheimer's disease informs the search for combination therapies that can successfully prevent or substantially slow the progression of the disease. Anti-amyloid monoclonal antibodies are the first approved disease targeted therapies; they slow disease progression by approximately 30 %. Building on these agents in add-on therapies is one avenue to designing combination treatments. Development of combination drugs consisting of two or more novel interventions is an alternate pathway for combination treatment development. Combination therapies can involve small molecule drugs, biological agents, devices, stem cells, gene therapies, lifestyle interventions, or cognitive training. Nonclinical assessment of drug combinations may involve animal models or new approach methodologies such as induced pluripotent stem cells or organoids. Phase 1 trials are required to characterize each member of a novel combination. Phase 2 trials may use a 2-by-2 factorial design comparing each drug to placebo and the drug combination. In Phase 3, comparison of the novel combination to standard of care may be sufficient or more complex designs may be required. Targets for combination therapies beyond amyloid-related processes include tau abnormalities, inflammation, neurodegeneration, and co-pathologies such as alpha-synuclein and TDP-43. The choice of combination therapies will depend on the strength of the information regarding the target, biomarkers to guide clinical trials, and a candidate agent with the appropriate mechanism of action. Computational strategies based on network analysis of disease and drugs, validation in non-clinical models, and use of real-world data may facilitate prioritization of candidates for combination treatments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cummings</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chambers-Grundy Center for Transformative Neuroscience, Department of Brain Health, Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine, University of Nevada Las Vegas (UNLV), Las Vegas, NV, USA. Electronic address: jcummings@cnsinnovations.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burstein</LastName><ForeName>Aaron H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alzheimer's Drug Discovery Foundation, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fillit</LastName><ForeName>Howard</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alzheimer's Drug Discovery Foundation, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM109025</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R35 AG071476</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Prev Alzheimers Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638820</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2274-5807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003131" MajorTopicYN="N">Combined Modality Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer's disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-pathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combination therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Monoclonal antibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synaptic plasticity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Acadia Pharmaceuticals Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Acumen Pharmaceuticals Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with ALZpath Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Annovis Bio Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Artery Therapeutics Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Axsome Therapeutics Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Biogen Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Biohaven Ltd that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Bristol-Myers Squibb Company that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Eisai Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Fosun Pharma USA Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Global Alzheimer&#x2019;s Platform Foundation that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Hummingbird Diagnostics GmbH that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with IGC Pharma that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Julius Clinical BV that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Kinoxis Therapeutics that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Lighthouse Pharma that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Eli Lilly and Company that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Lundbeck LLC that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Merck &amp; Co Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with MoCA Cognition that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Novo Nordisk Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with NSC Therapeutics GmbH that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with OptoCeutics that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co Ltd that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Praxis Bio Research that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with reMYND Nv that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Roche that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Scottish Brain Sciences that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Signant Health that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Jiangsu Simcere Pharmaceutical Co Ltd that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Sinaptica Therapeutics that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with T-Neuro Dx that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with TrueBinding Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Vaxxinity Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with CNS Innovations that includes: equity or stocks. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Mangrove Therapeutics that includes: equity or stocks. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Journal of Prevention of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease that includes: board membership. Jeffrey L Cummings reports a relationship with Journal of Prevention of Translational Neurodegeneration that includes: board membership. Jeffrey L Cummings has ownership of copy right for Neuropsychiatric Inventory. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with Therini Bio Inc that includes: board of directors membership. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with Alector Inc that includes: chairman, Independent Data Management Committee membership. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with ProMIS Neurosciences Inc that includes: clinical advisory board membership. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with LifeWorx that includes: consulting or advisory and board membership. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with TheKey that includes: consulting or advisory and board membership. Howard Fillit reports a relationship with ADmit Therapeutics SL that includes: board membership. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41145337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12627886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2274-5807(25)00271-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cummings J., Gold M., Mintun M., et al. Key considerations for combination therapy in Alzheimer's clinical trials: perspectives from an expert advisory board convened by the Alzheimer's drug discovery foundation. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2025;12(1) doi: 10.1016/j.tjpad.2024.100001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjpad.2024.100001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12183988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39800453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angioni D., Middleton L., Bateman R., et al. Challenges and opportunities for novel combination therapies in Alzheimer's disease: a report from the EU/US CTAD Task Force. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2025 doi: 10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12434272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40253240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack C.R., Jr., Andrews J.S., Beach T.G., et al. Revised criteria for diagnosis and staging of Alzheimer's disease: alzheimer's Association Workgroup. Alzheimers Dement. 2024;20(8):5143&#x2013;5169. doi: 10.1002/alz.13859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.13859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11350039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims J.R., Zimmer J.A., Evans C.D., et al. Donanemab in early symptomatic Alzheimer disease: the TRAILBLAZER-ALZ 2 randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2023;330(6):512&#x2013;527. doi: 10.1001/jama.2023.13239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.13239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37459141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dyck C.H., Swanson C.J., Aisen P., et al. Lecanemab in early Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med. 2023;388(1):9&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2212948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2212948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mummery C.J., B&#xf6;rjesson-Hanson A., Blackburn D.J., et al. Tau-targeting antisense oligonucleotide MAPT(Rx) in mild Alzheimer's disease: a phase 1b, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Nat Med. 2023;29(6):1437&#x2013;1447. doi: 10.1038/s41591-023-02326-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-023-02326-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10287562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson O., Blennow K., Zetterberg H., Dage J. Blood biomarkers for Alzheimer's disease in clinical practice and trials. Nat Aging. 2023;3(5):506&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1038/s43587-023-00403-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43587-023-00403-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10979350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37202517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascoal T.A., Aguzzoli C.S., Lussier F.Z., et al. Insights into the use of biomarkers in clinical trials in Alzheimer's disease. EBioMedicine. 2024;108 doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11663755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39366844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings J.L., Teunissen C.E., Fiske B.K., et al. Biomarker-guided decision making in clinical drug development for neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2025 doi: 10.1038/s41573-025-01165-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41573-025-01165-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40185982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings J.L., Osse A.M.L., Kinney J.W., Cammann D., Chen J. Alzheimer's disease: combination therapies and clinical trials for combination therapy development. CNS Drugs. 2024;38(8):613&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1007/s40263-024-01103-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-024-01103-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11258156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings J.L., Tong G., Ballard C. Treatment combinations for Alzheimer's disease: current and future pharmacotherapy options. J Alzheimers Dis. 2019;67(3):779&#x2013;794. doi: 10.3233/JAD-180766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-180766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6398562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration . U.S. department of health and human services, food and drug administration. Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER); Rockville, Maryland: 2013. Guidance for industry. Co-development of two or more new investigational drug for use in combination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir M.T., Uddin M.S., Mamun A.A., et al. Combination drug therapy for the management of Alzheimer's disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(9) doi: 10.3390/ijms21093272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21093272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta U., Kayed R. Amyloid beta, tau, and alpha-synuclein aggregates in the pathogenesis, prognosis, and therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases. Prog Neurobiol. 2022;214 doi: 10.1016/j.pneurobio.2022.102270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2022.102270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35447272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faridar A., Eid A.M., Thome A.D., et al. A phase 1 open-label pilot study of low-dose interleukine-2 immunotherapy in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Transl Neurodegener. 2023;12(1):54. doi: 10.1186/s40035-023-00387-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-023-00387-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10652426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37968718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisberg B., Doody R., Stoffler A., et al. Memantine in moderate-to-severe Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med. 2003;348(14):1333&#x2013;1341. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa013128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa013128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12672860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tariot P.N., Farlow M.R., Grossberg G.T., et al. Memantine treatment in patients with moderate to severe Alzheimer disease already receiving donepezil: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2004;291(3):317&#x2013;324. doi: 10.1001/jama.291.3.317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.291.3.317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong X., Jiang L., Qu M., Hassan S.S.U., Liu Z. Enhancing therapeutic efficacy of donepezil by combined therapy: a comprehensive review. Curr Pharm Des. 2021;27(3):332&#x2013;344. doi: 10.2174/1381612826666201023144836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612826666201023144836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33100197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deardorff W.J., Grossberg G.T. A fixed-dose combination of memantine extended-release and donepezil in the treatment of moderate-to-severe Alzheimer's disease. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2016;10:3267&#x2013;3279. doi: 10.2147/DDDT.S86463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DDDT.S86463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5055113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27757016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang K., Watt H., Golemme M., et al. Noradrenergic add-on therapy with extended-release guanfacine in Alzheimer's Disease (NorAD): study protocol for a randomised clinical trial and COVID-19 amendments. Trials. 2022;23(1):623. doi: 10.1186/s13063-022-06190-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-022-06190-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmer J.A., Ardayfio P., Wang H., et al. Amyloid-related imaging abnormalities with donanemab in early symptomatic Alzheimer Disease: secondary analysis of the TRAILBLAZER-ALZ and ALZ 2 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Neurol. 2025;82(5):461&#x2013;469. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2025.0065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2025.0065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11894547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40063015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honig L.S., Sabbagh M.N., van Dyck C.H., et al. Updated safety results from phase 3 lecanemab study in early Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2024;16(1):105. doi: 10.1186/s13195-024-01441-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-024-01441-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11084061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38730496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontecorvo M.J., Lu M., Burnham S.C., et al. Association of donanemab treatment with exploratory plasma biomarkers in early symptomatic Alzheimer disease: a secondary analysis of the TRAILBLAZER-ALZ randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2022;79(12):1250&#x2013;1259. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.3392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.3392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9577883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36251300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delrieu J., Bateman R.J., Touchon J., Sabbagh M., Cummings J. The future of AD clinical trials with the advent of anti-amyloid therapies: an CTAD Task Force Report. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2022;9(3):393&#x2013;399. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2022.48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2022.48</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35841240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boxer A.L., Sperling R., Aisen P., et al. The Alzheimer&#x2019;s Tau Platform (ATP): a phase 2, combination amyloid and tau therapy clinical trial for early AD. Alzheimer Dement. 2025;20 doi: 10.1002/alz.085111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.085111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartfai T., Lees G.V. Alzheimer drug trials: combination of safe and efficacious biologicals to break the amyloidosis-neuroinflammation vicious cycle. ASN Neuro. 2020;12 doi: 10.1177/1759091420918557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1759091420918557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7157973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32290675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erichsen J., Craft S. Targeting immunometabolic pathways for combination therapy in Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement (N Y) 2023;9(4) doi: 10.1002/trc2.12423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.12423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37786483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration: combination product definition combination product types. 2018. https://www.fda.gov/combination-products/about-combination-products/combination-product-definition-combination-product-types Accessed 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe M.S. gamma-Secretase: once and future drug target for Alzheimer's disease. Expert Opin Drug Discov. 2024;19(1):5&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1080/17460441.2023.2277350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17460441.2023.2277350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10872755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37915204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang C., Hernandez P., Liow K., et al. Buntanetap, a novel translational inhibitor of multiple neurotoxic proteins, proves to be safe and promising in both Alzheimer's and Parkinson's patients. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2023;10(1):25&#x2013;33. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2022.84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2022.84</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings J., Zhou Y., Lee G., et al. Alzheimer's disease drug development pipeline: 2025. Alzheimer Dement. 2025;11 doi: 10.1002/trc2.70098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.70098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12131090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40463637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo A.K., Dandapat J., Dash U.C., Kanhar S. Features and outcomes of drugs for combination therapy as multi-targets strategy to combat Alzheimer's disease. J Ethnopharmacol. 2018;215:42&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2017.12.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2017.12.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29248451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Guo K., Zhang P., et al. Exploring the mechanism of YangXue QingNao Wan based on network pharmacology in the treatment of Alzheimer's disease. Front genet. 2022;13:942203. doi: 10.3389/fgene.2022.942203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2022.942203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Chao L., Shen S., et al. Exploring the pharmacological mechanism of Bu-Wang San on Alzheimer's disease through multiple GEO datasets of the human hippocampus, network pharmacology, and metabolomics based on GCMS&#x2013; and UPLC-Q/TOF-MS. J Ethnopharmacol. 2025;350 doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2025.119994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2025.119994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40389089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C.L., Jiang Y., Li H.J. Quality consistency evaluation of traditional Chinese medicines: current status and future perspectives. Crit Rev Anal Chem. 2025;55(4):684&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1080/10408347.2024.2305267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408347.2024.2305267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38252135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Chen Y., Wang L., Liu Q., Yang S., Wang C. Advancing herbal medicine: enhancing product quality and safety through robust quality control practices. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14 doi: 10.3389/fphar.2023.1265178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1265178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10561302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37818188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pioro E.P., Brooks B.R., Cummings J., et al. Dextromethorphan plus ultra low-dose quinidine reduces pseudobulbar affect. Ann Neurol. 2010;68(5):693&#x2013;702. doi: 10.1002/ana.22093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.22093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20839238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings J.L., Lyketsos C.G., Peskind E.R., et al. Effect of dextromethorphan-quinidine on agitation in patients with Alzheimer disease dementia: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015;314(12):1242&#x2013;1254. doi: 10.1001/jama.2015.10214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.10214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26393847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iosifescu D.V., Jones A., O'Gorman C., et al. Efficacy and safety of AXS-05 (dextromethorphan-bupropion) in patients with major depressive disorder: a phase 3 randomized clinical trial (GEMINI) J Clin Psychiatry. 2022;83(4) doi: 10.4088/JCP.21m14345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.21m14345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35649167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration . U.S. department of health and human services, food and drug administration. Centers for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER); Rockville, Maryland: 2010. Guidance for industry: co-development of two or more unmarketed investigational drugs for use in combination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodick N.C., Offen W.W., Levey A.I., et al. Effects of xanomeline, a selective muscarinic receptor agonist, on cognitive function and behavioral symptoms in Alzheimer disease. Arch Neurol. 1997;54(4):465&#x2013;473. doi: 10.1001/archneur.1997.00550160091022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.1997.00550160091022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9109749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Dai Y., Hu C., et al. Cellular and molecular mechanisms of the blood-brain barrier dysfunction in neurodegenerative diseases. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2024;21(1):60. doi: 10.1186/s12987-024-00557-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12987-024-00557-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11264766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39030617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lochhead J.J., Yang J., Ronaldson P.T., Davis T.P. Structure, function, and regulation of the blood-brain barrier tight junction in central nervous system disorders. Front Physiol. 2020;11:914. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2020.00914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm H.P., Schumacher V., Schafer M., et al. Delivery of the Brainshuttle amyloid-beta antibody fusion trontinemab to non-human primate brain and projected efficacious dose regimens in humans. MAbs. 2023;15(1) doi: 10.1080/19420862.2023.2261509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19420862.2023.2261509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10572082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37823690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorick C.M., Breza V.R., Nowak K.M., et al. Applications of focused ultrasound-mediated blood-brain barrier opening. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2022;191 doi: 10.1016/j.addr.2022.114583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addr.2022.114583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9712235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezai A.R., D'Haese P.F., Finomore V., et al. Ultrasound blood-brain barrier opening and aducanumab in Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med. 2024;390(1):55&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2308719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2308719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38169490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngandu T., Lehtisalo J., Solomon A., et al. A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2015;385(9984):2255&#x2013;2263. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60461-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60461-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbera M., Lehtisalo J., Perera D., et al. A multimodal precision-prevention approach combining lifestyle intervention with metformin repurposing to prevent cognitive impairment and disability: the MET-FINGER randomised controlled trial protocol. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2024;16(1):23. doi: 10.1186/s13195-023-01355-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-023-01355-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10829308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38297399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Soria I., Iguacel I., Cuenca-Zaldivar J.N., et al. Cognitive stimulation and psychosocial results in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2023;115 doi: 10.1016/j.archger.2023.105114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2023.105114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37451002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Onofrio G., Sancarlo D., Addante F., et al. A pilot randomized controlled trial evaluating an integrated treatment of rivastigmine transdermal patch and cognitive stimulation in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2015;30(9):965&#x2013;975. doi: 10.1002/gps.4247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.4247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25504466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.Y., Qin J.Y., Ye J.Y., et al. The therapeutic effects of noninvasive brain stimulation combined with cognitive training in elders with Alzheimer's disease or amnesic mild cognitive impairment. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2024;11(1):222&#x2013;229. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2024.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2024.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Liu W., He J., et al. The cognitive effect of non-invasive brain stimulation combined with cognitive training in Alzheimer's disease and mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2024;16(1):140. doi: 10.1186/s13195-024-01505-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-024-01505-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11212379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonenko D., Thams F., Grittner U., et al. Randomized trial of cognitive training and brain stimulation in non-demented older adults. Alzheimers Dement (N Y) 2022;8(1) doi: 10.1002/trc2.12262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.12262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8864498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration . Guidance for industry, and fda staff. U.S. department of health and human services food and drug administration. center for devices and radiological health (CDRH) center for drug evaluation and research (CDER) Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research (CBER), and Office of Combination Products in the Office of the Commissioner; Rockville, Maryland: 2016. Human factors studies and related clinical study considerations in combination product design and development.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration. Road map to reducing animal testing in preclinical safety studies. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puzzo D., Gulisano W., Palmeri A., Arancio O. Rodent models for Alzheimer's disease drug discovery. Expert Opin Drug Discov. 2015;10(7):703&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1517/17460441.2015.1041913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17460441.2015.1041913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4592281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25927677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aytan N., Choi J.K., Carreras I., Kowall N.W., Jenkins B.G., Dedeoglu A. Combination therapy in a transgenic model of Alzheimer's disease. Exp Neurol. 2013;250:228&#x2013;238. doi: 10.1016/j.expneurol.2013.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2013.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori T., Koyama N., Tan J., Segawa T., Maeda M., Town T. Combination therapy with octyl gallate and ferulic acid improves cognition and neurodegeneration in a transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. J Biol Chem. 2017;292(27):11310&#x2013;11325. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M116.762658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M116.762658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5500797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration . U.S. department of health and human services, food and drug administration. Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER); Rockville, Maryland: 2006. Guidance for industry. Nonclinical safety evaluation of drug or biologic combinations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration . US department of health and human services, food and drug administration. Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER), Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research (CBER); Rockville, Maryland: 2023. Guidance for industry. Formal meetings between the FDA and sponsors or applicants of PDUFA products.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood B.R., Lourida I., Gong J., et al. Data-driven discovery of associations between prescribed drugs and dementia risk: a systematic review. Alzheimers Dement (N Y) 2025;11(1) doi: 10.1002/trc2.70037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.70037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11747987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39839078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Wang F., Zang C., et al. Comparing the effects of four common drug classes on the progression of mild cognitive impairment to dementia using electronic health records. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):8102. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-35258-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-35258-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10199021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37208478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales M.M., Garbarino V.R., Marques Zilli E., et al. Senolytic therapy to modulate the progression of Alzheimer's Disease (SToMP-AD): a pilot clinical trial. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2022;9(1):22&#x2013;29. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2021.62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2021.62</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8612719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35098970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales M.M., Garbarino V.R., Kautz T.F., et al. Senolytic therapy in mild Alzheimer's disease: a phase 1 feasibility trial. Nat Med. 2023;29(10):2481&#x2013;2488. doi: 10.1038/s41591-023-02543-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-023-02543-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10875739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37679434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahan B.C., Hall S.S., Beller E.M., et al. Reporting of factorial randomized trials: extension of the CONSORT 2010 statement. JAMA. 2023;330(21):2106&#x2013;2114. doi: 10.1001/jama.2023.19793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.19793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7617336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38051324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardlaw J.M., Woodhouse L.J., Mhlanga I.I., et al. Isosorbide mononitrate and cilostazol treatment in patients with symptomatic cerebral small vessel disease: the Lacunar Intervention Trial-2 (LACI-2) randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2023;80(7):682&#x2013;692. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2023.1526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2023.1526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10209826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37222252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnett T., Mozgunov P., Pallmann P., Villar S.S., Wheeler G.M., Jaki T. Adding flexibility to clinical trial designs: an example-based guide to the practical use of adaptive designs. BMC Med. 2020;18(1):352. doi: 10.1186/s12916-020-01808-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-020-01808-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayner C.R., Dron L., Park J.J.H., et al. Accelerating clinical evaluation of repurposed combination therapies for COVID-19. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;103(4):1364&#x2013;1366. doi: 10.4269/ajtmh.20-0995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.20-0995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32828137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman L.G., McKeehan N., Hara Y., et al. Value-generating exploratory trials in neurodegenerative dementias. Neurology. 2021;96(20):944&#x2013;954. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000011774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000011774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker T.B., Smith S.S., Bolt D.M., et al. Implementing clinical research using factorial designs: a primer. Behav Ther. 2017;48(4):567&#x2013;580. doi: 10.1016/j.beth.2016.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beth.2016.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5458623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28577591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty B., Collins L.M., Strecher V.J., Murphy S.A. Developing multicomponent interventions using fractional factorial designs. Stat Med. 2009;28(21):2687&#x2013;2708. doi: 10.1002/sim.3643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.3643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19575485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.J., Kong M., Ayers G.D., R L. Interaction index and different methods for determining drug interaction in combination therapy. J Biopharm Stat. 2007;17(3):461&#x2013;480. doi: 10.1080/10543400701199593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10543400701199593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satlin A., Wang J., Logovinsky V., et al. Design of a Bayesian adaptive phase 2 proof-of-concept trial for BAN2401, a putative disease-modifying monoclonal antibody for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement. 2016;2(1):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.trci.2016.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trci.2016.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29067290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer E.L., Mesenbrink P., Dunger-Baldauf C., et al. Decision rules for identifying combination therapies in open-entry, randomized controlled platform trials. Pharm Stat. 2022;21(3):671&#x2013;690. doi: 10.1002/pst.2194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pst.2194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9304586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35102685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Califf R.M. Biomarker definitions and their applications. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2018;243(3):213&#x2013;221. doi: 10.1177/1535370217750088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1535370217750088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5813875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group F-NBW . Silver Spring (MD) Bethesda (MD): Food and Drug Administration (US) National Institutes of Health (US); 2016. BEST (Biomarkers, endpoints, and other tools) resource.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai R., Li B., Bishnoi R. P-tau217 as a reliable blood-based marker of Alzheimer's disease. Biomedicines. 2024;12(8) doi: 10.3390/biomedicines12081836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines12081836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11351463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39200300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budd Haeberlein S., Aisen P.S., Barkhof F., et al. Two randomized phase 3 studies of aducanumab in early Alzheimer's disease. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2022;9(2):197&#x2013;210. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2022.30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2022.30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35542991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampel H., Elhage A., Cho M., Apostolova L.G., Nicoll J.A.R., Atri A. Amyloid-related imaging abnormalities (ARIA): radiological, biological and clinical characteristics. Brain. 2023;146(11):4414&#x2013;4424. doi: 10.1093/brain/awad188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awad188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10629981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37280110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antolini L., DiFrancesco J.C., Zedde M., et al. Spontaneous ARIA-like events in cerebral amyloid angiopathy-related inflammation: a multicenter prospective longitudinal cohort study. Neurology. 2021;97(18):e1809&#x2013;e1822. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000012778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000012778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feizpour A., Dore V., Doecke J.D., et al. Two-year prognostic utility of plasma p217+tau across the Alzheimer's continuum. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2023;10(4):828&#x2013;836. doi: 10.14283/jpad.2023.83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2023.83</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37874105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groot C., Smith R., Collij L.E., et al. Tau positron emission tomography for predicting dementia in individuals with mild cognitive impairment. JAMA Neurol. 2024;81(8):845&#x2013;856. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2024.1612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2024.1612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11165418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38857029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayato S., Takenaka O., Sreerama Reddy S.H., et al. Population pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic analyses of amyloid positron emission tomography and plasma biomarkers for lecanemab in subjects with early Alzheimer's disease. CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol. 2022;11(12):1578&#x2013;1591. doi: 10.1002/psp4.12862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/psp4.12862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9755918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36165093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leisgang Osse A.M., Kinney J.W., Cummings J.L. The Common Alzheimer's Disease Research Ontology (CADRO) for biomarker categorization. Alzheimers Dement (N Y) 2025;11(1) doi: 10.1002/trc2.70050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.70050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39935614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng F., Desai R.J., Handy D.E., et al. Network-based approach to prediction and population-based validation of in silico drug repurposing. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):2691. doi: 10.1038/s41467-018-05116-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-05116-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6043492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30002366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hasselt J.G.C., Iyengar R. Systems pharmacology: defining the interactions of drug combinations. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol. 2019;59:21&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1146/annurev-pharmtox-010818-021511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-pharmtox-010818-021511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30260737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J., Pieper A.A., Nussinov R., et al. Harnessing endophenotypes and network medicine for Alzheimer's drug repurposing. Med Res Rev. 2020;40(6):2386&#x2013;2426. doi: 10.1002/med.21709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/med.21709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32656864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang C., Zhang H., Xu J., et al. High-throughput target trial emulation for Alzheimer's disease drug repurposing with real-world data. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):8180. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-43929-1. (Describes the techniques involved in trial simulation to conduct virtual trials in medical record populations to determine the likely outcome of similarly peformed real world clinical trials.)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-43929-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38081829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C S. Not a slam dunk (or Free Lunch): the complex future of Alzheimer's combination therapy. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2025;12(6) doi: 10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjpad.2025.100211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12434263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40451697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>