<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41142507</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-2766</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Exploratory research in clinical and social pharmacy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Appropriateness of empiric antibiotic therapy for community-acquired pneumonia: A multicenter cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100669</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100669</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100669</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.rcsop.2025.100669</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) remains a major public health concern, with appropriate empiric antibiotic therapy critical to improving patient outcomes and combating antimicrobial resistance (AMR). Despite the availability of national guidelines, adherence among physicians in Lebanon was previously unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the appropriateness of empiric antibiotic prescribing for hospitalized CAP patients in Lebanon and identify factors associated with non-compliance with national guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional study was conducted in five Lebanese hospitals across various regions. Medical records of 380 adult CAP patients were reviewed. Empiric antibiotic regimens were evaluated for compliance with national CAP guidelines based on drug selection, dosage, route, and duration. Multivariate logistic regression was used to identify predictors of inappropriate prescribing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Only 38.9&#xa0;% of patients received fully guideline-concordant empiric therapy. Inappropriate prescribing was significantly associated with physician rank (residents: aOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;29.13, <i>p</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.001), geographic region (South Lebanon: aOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;7.78, <i>p</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.028), and antibiotic class (&#x3b2;-lactam plus respiratory fluoroquinolones: aOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;19.18, <i>p</i>&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). Clinical factors such as systemic inflammatory response syndrome and elevated serum creatinine were also linked to inappropriate use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Non-compliance with national CAP treatment guidelines is widespread in Lebanese hospitals and driven by physician experience, geographic disparities, and misalignment in antibiotic selection. Strengthening antimicrobial stewardship programs, regional training, and clinical decision support is essential to improve adherence and reduce AMR risk.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahme</LastName><ForeName>Deema</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Beirut Arab University, Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSPECT-LB (Institut National de Sant'e Publique, d'&#xc9;pid&#xe9;miologie Clinique et de Toxicologie-Liban), Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Doctoral School of Science and Technology, Lebanese University, Hadat, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chmaisse</LastName><ForeName>Hania Nakkash</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Beirut Arab University, Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salameh</LastName><ForeName>Pascale</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSPECT-LB (Institut National de Sant'e Publique, d'&#xc9;pid&#xe9;miologie Clinique et de Toxicologie-Liban), Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Doctoral School of Science and Technology, Lebanese University, Hadat, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gilbert and Rose-Marie Chagoury School of Medicine, Lebanese American University, Byblos, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918266300706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2667-2766</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotic prescribing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-acquired pneumonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Guideline adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lebanon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stewardship</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41142507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12547870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rcsop.2025.100669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-2766(25)00110-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tsoumani E., Carter J.A., Salomonsson S., Stephens J.M., Bencina G. Clinical, economic, and humanistic burden of community acquired pneumonia in Europe: a systematic literature review. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2023;22(1):876&#x2013;884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37823894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres A., Chalmers J.D., Dela Cruz C.S., et al. Challenges in severe community-acquired pneumonia: a point-of-view review. Intensive Care Med. 2019;45(2):159&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30706119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejada S., Romero A., Rello J. Community-acquired pneumonia in adults: what&#x2019;s new focusing on epidemiology, microorganisms and diagnosis? J Clin Pract Res. 2018;40(4):177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizri A., Ibrahim A., Dagher E., et al. Pneumococcal disease in high-risk adults in Lebanon: expert opinion. Vaccines (Basel) 2022;10(10):1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9607522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36298515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cilloniz C., Pericas J.M., Curioso W.H. Interventions to improve outcomes in community-acquired pneumonia. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2023;21(10):1071&#x2013;1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37691049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallazzi R., Ramirez J.A. Seminars in Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine. Thieme Medical Publishers, Inc; 2024. Definition, epidemiology, and pathogenesis of severe community-acquired pneumonia.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38330995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carella F., Aliberti S., Stainer A., Voza A., Blasi F. Long-term outcomes in severe community-acquired pneumonia. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;45(02):266&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnajjar M.S., Alnsour L., Saeed D., et al. The impact of adherence to community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) management guidelines on improving clinical outcomes in hospitalized patients. Pharm Pract. 2023;21(3):01&#x2013;07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idigo A.J., Wells J.M., Brown M.L., et al. Socio-demographic and comorbid risk factors for poor prognosis in patients hospitalized with community-acquired bacterial pneumonia in southeastern US. Heart Lung. 2024;65:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11641520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38382142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi T., Petty L., Vaughn V., et al. Risk factors and outcomes associated with inappropriate empiric broad-spectrum antibiotic use in hospitalized patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Antimicrob Stewardship Healthcare Epidemiol. 2023;3(S2) s31-s2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo C., Corrado M., Lim R., Thornton C.S. Guideline-concordant therapy for community-acquired pneumonia in the hospitalized population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2024;11(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11222985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38966853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micek S.T., Lang A., Fuller B.M., Hampton N.B., Kollef M.H. Clinical implications for patients treated inappropriately for community-acquired pneumonia in the emergency department. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14(1):61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24499035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie X.M., Li Y.S., Yang Z.W., et al. Initial empiric antibiotic therapy for community-acquired pneumonia in Chinese hospitals. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2018;24(6) 658.e1-.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamila R.S., Rochmanti M., Bachtiar A. Appropriate antibiotic use for community-acquired pneumonia in inpatient settings and its impact on 30-days readmission and mortality rate. Indian J Forens Med Toxicol. 2019;15(1):2765&#x2013;2772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong L.P., Alias H., Husin S.A., Ali Z.B., Sim B., Ponnampalavanar S.S.L.S. Factors influencing inappropriate use of antibiotics: findings from a nationwide survey of the general public in Malaysia. PloS One. 2021;16(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8528291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34669733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amati F., Bindo F., Stainer A., et al. Identify drug-resistant pathogens in patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Adv Respir Med. 2023;91(3):224&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10295768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37366804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb B.J., Sorensen J., Jephson A., Mecham I., Nathan. Broad-spectrum antibiotic use and poor outcomes in community-onset pneumonia: a cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2019;54(1) 1900057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickens C.I., Wunderink R.G. Principles and practice of antibiotic stewardship in the ICU. Chest. 2019;156(1):163&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divino V., Schranz J., Early M., Shah H., Jiang M., Dekoven M. The 1-year economic burden of community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) initially managed in the outpatient setting in the USA. J Comp Effect Res. 2020;9(2):127&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konomura K., Nagai H., Akazawa M. Economic burden of community-acquired pneumonia among elderly patients: a Japanese perspective. Pneumonia. 2017;9(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5715537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29226070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singanayagam A., Chalmers J.D. Severity assessment scores to guide empirical use of antibiotics in community acquired pneumonia. Lancet Respir Med. 2013;1(8):653&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24461668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghnieh R., Sakr Y., Kanj S.S., et al. The Lebanese Society for Infectious Diseases and Clinical Microbiology (LSIDCM) guidelines for adult community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) in Lebanon. J Med Libanais. 2014;62(1):40&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24684125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahbi F.A., Salmi I.A., Khamis F., et al. Physicians&#x2019; attitudes, knowledge, and practices regarding antibiotic prescriptions. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2023;32:58&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36584969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu H.T.L., Pham T.T.T., Duong Y.H., et al. Antibiotic prescribing practices of medical doctors in a resource-limited setting and the influence of individual perceptions and stewardship support: a survey in three tertiary hospitals in Vietnam. JAC-Antimicrob Resist. 2024;6(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11022071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38633223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs I., Shrayteh Z., Abdulkhalek R., Salameh P., Hallit S., Malaeb D. Professional practice evaluation of emergency department prescriptions for community-acquired infections in Lebanon. Int J Infect Dis. 2017;64:74&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderweele T.J. Principles of confounder selection. Eur J Epidemiol. 2019;34(3):211&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6447501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30840181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartuliares M.B., S&#xf8;gaard S.N., Rosenvinge F.S., Mogensen C.B., Hertz M.A., Skj&#xf8;t-Arkil H. Antibiotic guideline adherence at the emergency department: a descriptive study from a country with a restrictive antibiotic policy. Antibiotics. 2023;12(12):1680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10740443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38136712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattarello S., Ram&#xed;rez S., Almarales J.R., et al. Causes of non-adherence to therapeutic guidelines in severe community-acquired pneumonia. Rev Brasil Terap Intens. 2015;27(1):44&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4396896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25909312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costantini E., Allara E., Patrucco F., Faggiano F., Hamid F., Balbo P.E. Adherence to guidelines for hospitalized community-acquired pneumonia over time and its impact on health outcomes and mortality. Intern Emerg Med. 2016;11(7):929&#x2013;940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waagsb&#xf8; B., Tranung M., Dam&#xe5;s J.K., Heggelund L. Antimicrobial therapy of community-acquired pneumonia during stewardship efforts and a coronavirus pandemic: an observational study. BMC Pulm Med. 2022;22(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9569007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36242006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahoud N., Rizk R., Hleyhel M., et al. Trends in the consumption of antibiotics in the Lebanese community between 2004 and 2016. Int J Clin Pharmacol. 2021;43(4):1065&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahme D., Ayoub M., Shaito K., Saleh N., Assaf S., Lahoud N. First trend analysis of antifungals consumption in Lebanon using the World Health Organization collaborating center for drug statistics methodology. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9700908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36434539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh N., Awada S., Awwad R., et al. Evaluation of antibiotic prescription in the Lebanese community: a pilot study. Infect Ecol Epidemiol. 2015;5(1):27094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qumseya B., Goddard A., Qumseya A., Estores D., Draganov P.V., Forsmark C. Barriers to clinical practice guideline implementation among physicians: a physician survey. Int J Gener Med. 2021:7591&#x2013;7598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8572046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34754231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazzaka M. Pharmaceutical marketing strategies&#x2019; influence on physicians&#x2019; prescribing pattern in Lebanon: ethics, gifts, and samples. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019;19(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spasojevic N., Vasilj I., Hrabac B., Celik D. Rural - urban differences in health care quality assessment. Mater Soc Med. 2015;27(6):409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4753384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26937222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elseesy N.A.M., Al-Zahrani A.E., Kandil F.S., Mahsoon A., Elhady M.M. Compliance among registered nurses and doctors in critical care units: challenges affecting their adherence to standard precautions. Healthcare. 2023;11(22):2975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10671448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37998466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa Birarra M., Mekonnen G.B., Gelayee D.A., Assimamaw N.T., Kifle Z.D. Drug dose adjustment in patients with renal impairment attending a specialized referral hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. Metab Open. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36177456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahdal A.M., Elberry A.A. Evaluation of applying drug dose adjustment by physicians in patients with renal impairment. Saudi Pharm J. 2012;20(3):217&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3745053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23960796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguado Paredes A., Valera Rubio M., Mo&#xf1;ino-Dominguez L. British Medical Journal Publishing Group; 2022. 4CPS-245 Inappropriate antibiotic dosage adjustments in patients with renal impairment: A cross-sectional analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolson A., Aiyegbusi O., Baggott A. Improving antibiotic prescribing for UTIs in renal impairment. Access Microbiol. 2020;2(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy G., Perez M., Rodr&#xed;guez B., et al. Adherence with national guidelines in hospitalized patients with community-acquired pneumonia: results from the CAPO study in Venezuela. Arch Bronconeumol (English Edition) 2015;51(4):163&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24809678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viasus D., Vecino-Moreno M., De La Hoz J.M., Carratal&#xe0; J. Antibiotic stewardship in community-acquired pneumonia. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2017;15(4):351&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28002979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamana H., Matsui H., Tagami T., Hirashima J., Fushimi K., Yasunaga H. De-escalation versus continuation of empirical antimicrobial therapy in community-acquired pneumonia. J Infect. 2016;73(4):314&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27394401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifeh M., Moore N., Salameh P. Community usage pattern of antibiotics within Lebanese population: a prospective study. Am J Pharmacol Sci. 2017;5(2):49&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>