<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41535818</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In the light of isokinetic test and sEMG: how effective is core stabilization based exercise training in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127</StartPage><MedlinePgn>127</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">127</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-026-09489-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Core stabilization exercises are a crucial intervention in Adolescent Idiopathic Scoliosis (AIS), as they are widely accessible and specifically address trunk muscle weakness and neuromuscular deficits that are considered potential contributors to curve progression. The aim of this study was to demonstrate the effects of core stabilization based exercise training on muscle strength, neuromuscular control, quality of life, and Cobb angle improvement in patients with AIS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Thirty two patients with AIS were included in this prospective, randomized, and controlled study. Participants were randomly divided into two groups as training group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) and control group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;16). Two individuals were lost to follow-up, resulting in a final analytical sample of 30 participants, with 15 in the training group and 15 in the control group. Training group received core stabilization based exercise training. Control group received traditional exercises. These interventions were carried out in 16 sessions under the supervision of a physiotherapist 2 days a week to be applied daily for 8 weeks. Muscle strength (Biodex isokinetic dynamometer), neuromuscular control (sEMG), Cobb angle, quality of life (SRS-22 questionnaire), perception of cosmetic deformity (WRVAS), trunk rotation angle, and spinal flexibility were assessed at the beginning and end of the study. Between-group comparisons were performed using analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) with baseline values as covariates, and statistical significance was set at <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with the control group, the training group demonstrated significantly greater improvements in trunk muscle strength and neuromuscular control, with significant changes observed in the majority of parameters (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). A clinically meaningful reduction in Cobb angle was observed in the training group (mean decrease: 5.7&#xb0;, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Significant between-group improvements were also found in trunk rotation angle, spinal flexibility, quality of life, and perception of cosmetic deformity (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Based on comprehensive and objective assessments, and after adjusting for baseline differences, these findings indicate that core stabilization based exercise training may provide meaningful benefits for patients with AIS and support its consideration as a complementary component of conservative management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12891-026-09489-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xf6;kdemir</LastName><ForeName>Fuat</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Istanbul, 34050, Turkey. fuat.gokdemir@bezmialem.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Uskudar University, Istanbul, Turkey. fuat.gokdemir@bezmialem.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayd&#x131;n</LastName><ForeName>Resa</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m</LastName><ForeName>Sefa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Istanbul, 34050, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dursun</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#x15f;e Sena Manzak</ForeName><Initials>ASM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Istanbul, 34050, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ba&#x15f;kent</LastName><ForeName>Ak&#x131;n</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;apan</LastName><ForeName>Nalan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scoliosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Istanbul Faculty of Medicine Clinical Research Ethics Committee (E-29624016-050.99-206013) in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Written informed consent and permission for publication of their study data was obtained from all patients&#x2019; parents or legal guardians. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose. Written informed consent was obtained from the patients&#x2019; parents or legal guardians to confirm their voluntary participation. and permission for publication of the study data.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41535818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12892476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09489-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-026-09489-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goldstein LA, Waugh TR. Classification and terminology of scoliosis. Clin Orthop. 1973;93:10&#x2013;22. 10.1097/00003086-197306000-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003086-197306000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4722939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonstein JE. Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Lancet. 1994;344(8934):1407&#x2013;12. 10.1016/s0140-6736(94)90572-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(94)90572-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7968079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Wang SR, Qiu GX, Zhang JG, Zhuang QY. Research progress on the etiology and pathogenesis of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Chin Med J (Engl). 2020;133(4):483&#x2013;93. 10.1097/CM9.0000000000000652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CM9.0000000000000652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7046244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31972723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannink E, Toye F, Newman M, Barker KL. The experience of living with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a qualitative evidence synthesis using meta-ethnography. BMC Pediatr. 2023;23(1):373. 10.1186/s12887-023-04183-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-023-04183-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37481537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrijevi&#x107; V, Ra&#x161;kovi&#x107; B, Popovi&#x107; M, et al. Treatment of idiopathic scoliosis with conservative methods based on exercises: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1492241. 10.3389/fspor.2024.1492241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2024.1492241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11700739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39763485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss HR, Negrini S, Rigo M, et al. Indications for conservative management of scoliosis (guidelines). Scoliosis. 2006;1(1):5. 10.1186/1748-7161-1-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-7161-1-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16759357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao P, Li M, He Y, Wang J, Wang R. The effects of exercise on patients with moderate adolescent idiopathic scoliosis&#x202f;: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop Rev (Pavia). 2025;17:137661. 10.52965/001c.137661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52965/001c.137661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12139610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40476023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhang Z, Zhu Q. The effect of an exercise intervention on adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a network meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):655. 10.1186/s13018-023-04137-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-023-04137-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10476432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37667353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Peng H, Song Y, et al. Evaluating exercise therapies in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a systematic review with Bayesian network meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2025;13:e19175. 10.7717/peerj.19175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.19175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11967429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40183057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzak Dursun AS, Ozyilmaz S, Ucgun H, Elmadag NM. The effect of Pilates-based exercise applied with hybrid telerehabilitation method in children with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a randomized clinical trial. Eur J Pediatr. 2023(2). 10.1007/s00431-023-05340-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37993666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang Y, Liu M, Zhang Y, Wu Q, Wang Q. The efficacy of core stabilization exercise in mild and moderate adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2025;20(1):214. 10.1186/s13018-025-05612-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-025-05612-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11869405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40016756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Shen J, Liang J, et al. Effect of core-based exercise in people with scoliosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2021;35(5):669&#x2013;80. 10.1177/0269215520975105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215520975105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33356498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocaman H, Bek N, Kaya MH, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kturan B, Yeti&#x15f; M, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kturan &#xd6;. The effectiveness of two different exercise approaches in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a single-blind, randomized-controlled trial. PLoS One. 2021;16(4):e0249492. 10.1371/journal.pone.0249492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0249492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko KJ, Kang SJ. Effects of 12-week core stabilization exercise on the Cobb angle and lumbar muscle strength of adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis. J Exerc Rehabil. 2017;13(2):244&#x2013;9. 10.12965/jer.1734952.476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.1734952.476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru T, Yeldan &#x130;, Dereli EE, &#xd6;zdin&#xe7;ler AR, Dikici F, &#xc7;olak &#x130;. The efficacy of three-dimensional schroth exercises in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a randomised controlled clinical trial. Clin Rehabil. 2016;30(2):181&#x2013;90. 10.1177/0269215515575745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215515575745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25780260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini S, Donzelli S, Aulisa AG, Czaprowski D, Schreiber S, de Mauroy JC, et al. 2016 SOSORT guidelines: orthopaedic and rehabilitation treatment of idiopathic scoliosis during growth. Scoliosis Spinal Disord. 2018;13:3. 10.1186/s13013-017-0145-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13013-017-0145-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5795289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29435499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini S, Aulisa AG, Aulisa L, et al. 2011 SOSORT guidelines: orthopaedic and rehabilitation treatment of idiopathic scoliosis during growth. Scoliosis. 2012;7(1):3. 10.1186/1748-7161-7-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-7161-7-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22264320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczyk-Pawelec K, Piechura JR, Dziubek W, Ro&#x17c;ek K. Evaluation of isokinetic trunk muscle strength in adolescents with normal and abnormal postures. J Manipulative Physiol Ther. 2015;38(7):484&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.jmpt.2015.06.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmpt.2015.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26254851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estr&#xe1;zulas JA, de Jesus K, da Silva RA, Libardoni Dos Santos JO. Evaluation isometric and isokinetic of trunk flexor and extensor muscles with isokinetic dynamometer: a systematic review. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;45:93&#x2013;102. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dvir Z, editor. Isokinetics: muscle testing, interpretation and clinical applications. New York, Routledge: Taylor &amp; Francis; 2025. 10.4324/9781003380719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies G. Compendium of isokinetics in clinical usage and rehabilitation techniques. 4th ed. Onalaska, WI: S&amp;S; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabiner MD, Jeziorowski JJ, Divekar AD. Isokinetic measurements of trunk extension and flexion performance collected with the biodex clinical data station. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1990;11(12):590&#x2013;8. 10.2519/jospt.1990.11.12.590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.1990.11.12.590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74. 10.1016/s1050-6411(00)00027-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1050-6411(00)00027-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H, Zhang Q, Liu J, et al. Degenerative characteristics of multifidus at different vertebral levels of scoliosis in patients with degenerative lumbar scoliosis and relationship of these degenerative characteristics with surface electromyography activity. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23(1):1074. 10.1186/s12891-022-06038-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-022-06038-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SJ, Yue Q, Liu QJ, et al. Research on the correlation between balance function and core muscles in patients with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Neurospine. 2025;22(1):264&#x2013;75. 10.14245/ns.2448938.469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14245/ns.2448938.469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12010844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40211532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Dong H, Lei M, et al. The role of the paraspinal muscles in the development of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis based on surface electromyography and radiographic analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25(1):263. 10.1186/s12891-024-07329-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-024-07329-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38570738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng PTT, Claus A, Izatt MT, Pivonka P, Tucker K. Is spinal neuromuscular function asymmetrical in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis compared to those without scoliosis? A narrative review of surface EMG studies. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2022;63:102640. 10.1016/j.jelekin.2022.102640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2022.102640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35219074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greiner KA. Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: radiologic decision-making. Am Fam Physician. 2002;65(9):1817&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12018804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanay A, Cil A, Berk H, et al. Reliability and validity of adapted Turkish Version of Scoliosis Research Society-22 (SRS-22) questionnaire. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2005;30(21):2464&#x2013;8. 10.1097/01.brs.0000184366.71761.84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.brs.0000184366.71761.84</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16261127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amendt LE, Ause-Ellias KL, Eybers JL, Wadsworth CT, Nielsen DH, Weinstein SL. Validity and reliability testing of the scoliometer. Phys Ther. 1990;70(2):108&#x2013;17. 10.1093/ptj/70.2.108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/70.2.108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2296610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders JO, Polly DW Jr, Cats-Baril W, et al. Analysis of patient and parent assessment of deformity in idiopathic scoliosis using the Walter Reed Visual Assessment Scale. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2003;28(18):2158&#x2013;63. 10.1097/01.BRS.0000084629.97042.0B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.BRS.0000084629.97042.0B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14501929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson JT. Eta squared and partial eta squared as measures of effect size in educational research. Educ Res Rev. 2011;6(2):135&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.edurev.2010.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.edurev.2010.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, et al. G*power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;91. 10.3758/bf03193146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park YH, Park YS, Lee YT, et al. The effect of a core exercise program on Cobb angle and back muscle activity in male students with functional scoliosis: a prospective, randomized, parallel-group, comparative study. J Int Med Res. 2016;44(3):728&#x2013;34. 10.1177/0300060516639750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060516639750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5536699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;r G, Ayhan C, Yakut Y. The effectiveness of core stabilization exercise in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a randomized controlled trial. Prosthet Orthot Int. 2017;41(3):303&#x2013;10. 10.1177/0309364616664151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0309364616664151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27625122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung J, Veldhuizen AG, Halbertsma JP, et al. The relation between electromyography and growth velocity of the spine in the evaluation of curve progression in idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2004;29(9):1011&#x2013;6. 10.1097/00007632-200405010-00012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-200405010-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15105674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko JY, Suh JH, Kim H, Ryu JS. Proposal of a new exercise protocol for idiopathic scoliosis: a preliminary study. Medicine Baltimore. 2018;97(49):e13336. 10.1097/MD.0000000000013336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000013336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30544395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Shen X, Zhang L, Wang S, Wu Q. Effect of sling exercise combined with schroth therapy on adolescents with mild idiopathic scoliosis: A twelve-week randomized controlled trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2023 Oct;23. 10.3233/BMR-230102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38043003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibler WB, Press J, Sciascia A. The role of core stability in athletic function. Sports Med. 2006;36(3):189&#x2013;98. 10.2165/00007256-200636030-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636030-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willson JD, Dougherty CP, Ireland ML, Davis IM. Core stability and its relationship to lower extremity function and injury. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2005;13(5):316&#x2013;25. 10.5435/00124635-200509000-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/00124635-200509000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akuthota V, Nadler SF. Core strengthening. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85(3 Suppl 1):S86&#x2013;92. 10.1053/j.apmr.2003.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.apmr.2003.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau M, Pialasse JP, Mercier P, Blouin JS. Adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis show decreased intermuscular coherence in lumbar paraspinal muscles: a new pathophysiological perspective. Clin Neurophysiol. 2022;138:38&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.clinph.2022.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2022.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35364464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachmann KR, Yaszay B, Bartley CE, et al. A three-dimensional analysis of scoliosis progression in non-idiopathic scoliosis: is it similar to adolescent idiopathic scoliosis? Childs Nerv Syst. 2019;35(9):1585&#x2013;90. 10.1007/s00381-019-04239-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-019-04239-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31183529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagci G, Yakut Y. Core stabilization exercises versus scoliosis-specific exercises in moderate idiopathic scoliosis treatment. Prosthet Orthot Int. 2019;43(3):301&#x2013;8. 10.1177/0309364618820144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0309364618820144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30628526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng C, Lu H, Jiang S, et al. Comparison of the efficiency of spiral stabilization and core stabilization exercises in the treatment of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil Published Online November. 2025;13. 10.1097/PHM.0000000000002893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41248254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H, Li M, Wang N, et al. Effects of different physical therapy training protocols on patients with idiopathic scoliosis: short-term results. PLoS One. 2025;20(10):e0334713. 10.1371/journal.pone.0334713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0334713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12533888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41105645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru &#xc7;olak T, Durmu&#x15f; BB, Saat&#xe7;&#x131; EZ, &#xc7;a&#x11f;lar E, Ak&#xe7;ay B, Maeso SL. Systematic review of clinical outcome parameters of conservative treatment of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis patients. J Clin Med. 2025;14(4):1063. 10.3390/jcm14041063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14041063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11856454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40004591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheshire J, Gardner A, Berryman F, Pynsent P. Do the SRS-22 self-image and mental health domain scores reflect the degree of asymmetry of the back in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis? Scoliosis Spinal Disord. 2017;12:37. 10.1186/s13013-017-0144-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13013-017-0144-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotfryd AO, Franzin FJ, Poletto PR, de Abreu LC, Valenti VE, Rodrigues LMR. Pain assessment in patients with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis at different stages of disease evolution. MedicalExpress Published Online August. 2014;1. 10.5935/MedicalExpress.2014.04.02.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanazi MH, Parent EC, Dennett E. Effect of stabilization exercise on back pain, disability and quality of life in adults with scoliosis: a systematic review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54(5):647&#x2013;53. 10.23736/S1973-9087.17.05062-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.17.05062-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29144110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim S, Ozyilmaz S, Elmadag NM, Yabaci A. Effects of core stabilization exercises on pulmonary function, respiratory muscle strength, peripheral muscle strength, functional capacity, and perceived appearance in children with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;101(8):719&#x2013;25. 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceballos Laita L, Tejedor Cubillo C, Mingo G&#xf3;mez T, Jim&#xe9;nez Del Barrio S. Effects of corrective, therapeutic exercise techniques on adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. A systematic review. Arch Argent Pediatr. 2018;116(4):e582&#x2013;9. 10.5546/aap.2018.eng.e582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5546/aap.2018.eng.e582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30016036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C, Wong MS. Spinal flexibility assessment on the patients with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a literature review. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2018;43(4):E250-8. 10.1097/BRS.0000000000002276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BRS.0000000000002276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>