<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41304031</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Monotonic Behavior of Existing Bridge Piers Retrofitted by Expansive Concrete-Filled Steel Tubes: An Experimental and Numerical Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5186</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18225186</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>With the growing traffic volume in China, numerous existing highway bridges in seismic zones are constrained by outdated design standards that are inadequate against current seismic requirements. To address this issue, this study proposes a novel reinforcement technique using expansive concrete-filled steel tube (ECFST) for bridge piers. Through combined experimental and numerical investigations on ECFST columns, the effect of expansive agent (EA) content on steel tube strain was systematically examined. The monotonic quasi-static tests were conducted to evaluate the influence of steel tube thickness, concrete strength, reinforcement thickness, and EA content on the ultimate bearing capacity. The proposed method was implemented in a case study involving a reinforced concrete pier, with analysis focused on the "confinement-self-stress coupling mechanism" of ECFST. Results demonstrated good agreement between numerical simulations and experimental data. The optimal EA content was identified as 15%, achieving the most effective reinforcement. ECFST-reinforced piers exhibited significantly enhanced seismic performance, achieving up to 22.6% increase in peak bearing capacity compared to non-expansive concrete filling. While steel tube thickness considerably affected the reinforcement efficiency, concrete strength grade showed minimal impact. This research provides theoretical support and practical design guidelines for seismic retrofitting of similar bridge piers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Ganghui</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Mountain Bridge and Tunnel Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Engineering &amp; Technical College of Chengdu University of Technology, Leshan 614000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Guowen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8175-4327</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Mountain Bridge and Tunnel Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Hongyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3968-8052</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Engineering &amp; Technical College of Chengdu University of Technology, Leshan 614000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Shixiong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CSTB2023NSCQ-LZX0077</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Chongqing, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JDLHPYJD2020004</GrantID><Agency>Joint Training Base Construction Project for Graduate Students in Chongqing</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JDDSTD2022003</GrantID><Agency>Team Building Project for Graduate Tutors in Chongqing</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. SKLBT-2111</GrantID><Agency>the Innovation and Development Joint Project of State Key Laboratory of Mountain Bridge and Tunnel Engineering</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bridge piers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">expansive agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">expansive concrete-filled steel tube</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">experimental and numerical investigations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reinforcement technique</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41304031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12654221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18225186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18225186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jia H.Y., Xiao C.Z., Kang W., Wang C.Q., Zheng S.X. Review of research on vulnerability of transportation infrastructure to extreme climatic conditions. J. Southwest Jiaotong Univ. 2025;60:484&#x2013;502. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.0258-2724.20230650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.0258-2724.20230650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Wu H.X., Yang Y., Wen D.C. Investigation and mechanism analysis of bridge damage in the 2021 Maduo earthquake, Qinghai province. World Earthq. Eng. 2025;41 doi: 10.19994/j.cnki.WEE.2025.0038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19994/j.cnki.WEE.2025.0038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z.L., Wei B., Jiang L.Z., Li S.S. Research on damage quantification of high-speed railway bridge piers. China Civ. Eng. J. 2023;56:60&#x2013;68. doi: 10.15951/j.tmgcxb.21121285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15951/j.tmgcxb.21121285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>China Forum for UN Procurement . Technical Specification for Strengthening Engineering of Urban Bridges. China Standards Press; Beijing, China: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Yin S., Dai J., Liu M. Numerical investigation on the influences of different factors on the seismic performance of TRC-strengthened RC columns. J. Build. Eng. 2020;30:101245. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X. Ph.D. Thesis. Southwest Jiaotong University; Chengdu, China: 2015. Research on Compressive Performance and Bearing Capacity of RC Short Columns Strengthened with Circular Steel Jackets.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong Z.H., Deng J.D., Li Y., Liu A. Anti-seismic properties of damaged concrete bridge piers with hollow box-section strengthened with adhering steel plates I: Bi-directional quasi-static test. J. Southeast Univ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 2013;43:8. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1001-0505.2013.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1001-0505.2013.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Feng H., Su C., Li X., Zhou G., Wang Z. Seismic behavior of earthquake-damaged hollow RC piers repaired with CFRP grids and ECC. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;484:141865. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Guo M., Zhang W., Huang M. Seismic Behavior of Strengthened RC Columns under Combined Loadings. J. Bridg. Eng. 2022;27:05022005. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)BE.1943-5592.0001871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)BE.1943-5592.0001871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzaamia A., Ghrici M., Rebouh R., Pilakoutas K., Asteris P.G. Predicting the compressive strength of CFRP-confined concrete using deep learning. Eng. Struct. 2024;319:19. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayed Y.A., Ibrahim A.A., Tamrazyan A.G., Fahmy M.F. Machine-learning-based models versus design-oriented models for predicting the axial compressive load of FRP-confined rectangular RC columns. Eng. Struct. 2023;285:116030. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2023.116030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2023.116030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narlitepe F., Kian N., Demir U., Demir C., Ilki A. A novel hybrid thin jacketing method for seismic retrofitting of substandard reinforced concrete columns. Eng. Struct. 2025;342:120879. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.120879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.120879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R. Application of CFRP reinforced recycled concrete in structural research. Concrete. 2024;10:144&#x2013;147. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1002-3550.2024.10.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1002-3550.2024.10.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Ma W., Zhao D., Wang C., Lu Y. Axial compression behavior of steel fiber-reinforced ultra-high-strength concrete filled high-strength square steel tube stub columns. Pt AJ. Constr. Steel Res. 2026;236:109943. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2025.109943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2025.109943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng N., Liu X., Zhao H., Deng Y. Interfacial adhesion and optimization of ultra-high-performance concrete-filled steel tube columns containing welded rebar rings. Structures. 2025;75:108729. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2025.108729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2025.108729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D.-Y., Guo Y.-Q., Han L.-H., Hou C.-C. Experimental investigation on the interface of concrete-filled steel tubular (CFST) structures based on roughness and geometric deviation. Eng. Struct. 2025;336:120496. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.120496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.120496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas M.A., Ran X., Musleh A.A., Li P. Synergistic effect of expansive agent and steel fiber on interfacial performance and axial compression behavior of UHPC-filled steel tube columns. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;470:140543. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu X., Zhang Y., Rong X. Seismic behavior and bearing capacity prediction of assembled concrete-filled multicellular steel tube composite shear walls with different horizontal joints. J. Build. Eng. 2025;111:113462. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.113462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.113462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le H.A., Ho V.H., Nguyen P.-C., Le T.P., Lam M.N.-T. Axial compressive behavior of circular RC stub columns jacketed by UHPC and UHPFRC. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;21:e03761. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Fu Y., Ban S., Duan Z., Su J. Genetic evolutionary deep learning for fire resistance analysis in fibre-reinforced polymers strengthened reinforced concrete beams. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2025;169:109149. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.109149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.109149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y., Li K., Fan J., Zhu J., Jing D. Compressive and seismic performance of RC columns strengthened with steel strand meshes and ECC jacket: Analysis-oriented model and numerical investigation. J. Build. Eng. 2025;108:112844. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z., Elchalakani M., Yehia S., Ran H., Sadakkathulla M.A., Guo X. Engineered cementitious composite (ECC) strengthening of reinforced concrete structures: A state-of-the-art review. J. Build. Engineering. 2024;86:108941. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H.Z., Emons C.D. Fiber Reinforced Polymer (FRP) Composites for Strengthening Concrete Structures: Design, Construction and Applications. People&#x2019;s Communications Publishing House Co., Ltd.; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z.Y. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. South China University of Technology; Guangzhou, China: 2018. Experimental Research on Seismic Performance of Damaged RC Column with Different Reinforced Measures.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q., Lv X., Li X., Gao R., Ma Z.J. Effect of self-stressing on concrete-encased-steel filled circular CFRP tubes under axial compression. Structures. 2021;29:471&#x2013;483. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2020.10.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2020.10.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou C., Ma G., Hwang H.-J., Li S., Kang S.-M. Seismic retrofit of intact and damaged RC columns using prefabricated steel cage-reinforced UHPC jackets and NSM GFRP bars. Eng. Struct. 2024;17:15. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z., Pei X., Hou H., Han T., Liu L., Wang H., Han Y. Expansive Behavior in Circular Steel Tube Stub Columns of SCC Blended with CFB Bottom Ashes. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2019;31:04019279. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen P., Lu J.-X., Zheng H., Lu L., Wang F., He Y., Hu S. Expansive ultra-high performance concrete for concrete-filled steel tube applications. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;114:103813. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W., Fan Z., Shen P., Lu L., Zhou Z. Experimental and numerical study on the compressive behavior of micro-expansive ultra-high-performance concrete-filled steel tube columns. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;254:119150. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q., Li X., Lin Z., Wu Z. Compression behavior of expansive concrete-encased-steel filled square CFRP tubes. Compos. Struct. 2019;225:111106. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2019.111106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2019.111106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China . Specification for Mix Proportion Design of Ordinary Concrete (JGJ 55-2011) China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W., Yang R., Zhao H., Li H., Zuo W., Liu J. Shrinkage separation prediction of concrete-filled steel tube arch bridge: A coupling model concerning multiple factors. J. Build. Eng. 2024;95:110024. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y.-F., Geng Y., Ma H.-C., Zhang H. Creep behavior of composite steel tubular columns filled with weathered steel slag aggregate concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2025;114:114267. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.114267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.114267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Test Methods of Long-Term Performance and Durability of Ordinary Concrete. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Moon J., Du H., Xia X., Zhu D., Zhang P., Guo J. Early-age shrinkage and hydration of concrete incorporating a mutually reinforcing systems of super absorbent polymers and MgO expansive agent under low humidity conditions. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;417:135350. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D., Liu C., Wen C., Kang J., Li M., Jiang H. Restrained cracking failure behavior of concrete containing MgO compound expansive agent under adiabatic condition at early age. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;135:104825. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Zhang G., Chen H., Hu Y., Qi D., Chen H. Investigation on mechanical properties of expansive lightweight aggregate ultra-high-performance concrete-filled steel tube short columns: Axial compression and interfacial bonding performance. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2025;22:e04288. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Chen R. Application of magnesium oxide expansive agent in hydraulic concrete in China. Mag. Concr. Res. 2022;75:97&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1680/jmacr.21.00337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jmacr.21.00337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahir M.K., Marx S. Development of expansive concrete for chemical prestressing applications. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;19:e02611. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dassault Syst&#xe8;mes . ABAQUS Theory Manual (Version 6.16) Dassault Syst&#xe8;mes; Providence, RI, USA: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezoddin A., Azandariani M.G., Khatami S.M.H. Experimental and theoretical investigation on axial compressive bearing capacity of timber- and concrete-filled square steel tubes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;500:144136. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.144136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.144136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L.H. Principles of Concrete-Filled Steel Tubular Structures. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zhang K., Nong Y., Cai X., Tang J., Wang Y. Axial compression bearing capacity of concrete-filled circular aluminum tubular short columns: Calculation model and reliability analysis. Structures. 2025;80:109817. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo B., Wu M., Zhang X., Zhang P., Xiang P., Deng X., Huo J., Chen J., Xu S. Axial compressive bearing capacity of high-strength concrete-filled Q690 square steel tubular stub column. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;413:134859. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderone A.J., Lehman D.E., Moehle J.P. Behavior of Reinforced Concrete Bridge Columns Having Varying Aspect Ratios and Varying Lengths of Confinement. Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center; Berkeley, CA, USA: 2000. PEER 2000/08.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>