<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41870301</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Definition of Substantial Athletic Benefit and Satisfaction of a Neuromuscular and Strength Training Program for Ballet Dancers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005400</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Crampton, CT, Smith, ST, and Noyes, FR. Definition of substantial athletic benefit and satisfaction of a neuromuscular and strength training program for ballet dancers. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-The aim of this prospective cross-sectional study was to assess the psychometrics and performance outcomes on preprofessional ballet dancers undergoing a neuromuscular and strength training program. We hypothesized that ballet dancers would perceive substantial benefits of this training program and significantly improve performance outcomes. Twenty-eight dancers from a preprofessional ballet training program volunteered to participate in a 6-week neuromuscular and strength training program. The dancers completed a psychometric questionnaire and objective testing before and after the training program. The psychometric questionnaire evaluated individual substantial athletic benefits and satisfaction of the training program. Objective testing included the triple hop test and T-Drill hop test to assess the training program on improving horizontal distance hopped, time hopped, limb symmetry, and landing mechanics. The dancers reported high perceived substantial benefits in 79% (22 of 28) for teaching proper take-off and landing mechanics, and in 96% (27 of 28) for the program challenging and preparing them for dance activities. A high dancer satisfaction rating was reported in 93% (26 of 28 dancers) for the training program. A significant increase in distance hopped occurred in right and left lower limbs on the triple hop test (p &lt; 0.001). A significant decrease in time to complete the T-Drill hop test was reported on right and left lower limbs (p &lt; 0.001). The psychometric results of the high substantial athletic benefits, major overall satisfaction, and increased hop drill performance warrant the recommendation of this training program for ballet dancers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crampton</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cincinnati SportsMedicine Research and Education Foundation, Mercy Health, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie T</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noyes</LastName><ForeName>Frank R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ballet neuromuscular training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ballet strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dance medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychometric analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41870301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allen N, Nevill A, Brooks J, Koutedakis Y, Wyon M. Ballet injuries: Injury incidence and severity over 1 year. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 42: 781&#x2013;790, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen N, Nevill AM, Brooks JHM, Koutedakis Y, Wyon MA. The effect of a comprehensive injury audit program on injury incidence in ballet: A 3-year prospective study. Clin J Sport Med 23: 373&#x2013;378, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambegaonkar JP, Schock CS, Caswell SV, Cortes N, Hansen-Honeycutt J, Wyon MA. Lower extremity horizontal work but not vertical power predicts lower extremity injury in female collegiate dancers. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2018&#x2013;2024, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt A, Ekenman I, Westblad P, Lundberg A. Effects of fatigue and load variation on metatarsal deformation measured in vivo during barefoot walking. J Biomech 35: 621&#x2013;628, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber SD, Noyes FR, Mangine RE, McCloskey JW, Hartman W. Quantitative assessment of functional limitations in normal and anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knees. Clin Orthop Relat Res 255: 204&#x2013;214, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber-Westin SD, Hermeto AA, Noyes FR. A six-week neuromuscular training program for competitive junior tennis players. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2372&#x2013;2382, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barengo N, Meneses-Ech&#xe1;vez JF, Ramirez-Velez R, Cohen DD, Tovar G, Bautista J. The impact of the FIFA 11+ training program on injury prevention in football players: A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 11: 11986&#x2013;12000, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boden BP, Sheehan FT. Mechanism of non-contact ACL injury: OREF clinical research award 2021. J Orthop Res 40: 531&#x2013;540, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronner S, Brownstein B. Profile of dance injuries in a broadway show: A discussion of issues in dance medicine epidemiology. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 26: 87&#x2013;94, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldemeyer LE, Brown SM, Mulcahey MK. Neuromuscular training for the prevention of ankle sprains in female athletes: A systematic review. Phys Sportsmed 48: 363&#x2013;369, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson V, Sheehan F, Boden B. Video analysis of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries: A systematic review. JBJS Rev 4: e5, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cepeda NA, Polascik BA, Ling DI. A primer on clinically important outcome values: Going beyond relying on P values alone. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 102: 262&#x2013;268, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B, Mao D, Garrett WE, Yu B. Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in soccer: Loading mechanisms, risk factors, and prevention programs. J Sport Health Sci 3: 299&#x2013;306, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies WT, Myer GD, Read PJ. Is it time we better understood the tests we are using for return to sport decision making following ACL reconstruction? A critical review of the hop tests. Sports Med 50: 485&#x2013;495, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Truijen J, Bellemans J, Gokeler A. Test&#x2013;retest reliability and discriminative ability of forward, medial and rotational single-leg hop tests. Knee 26: 978&#x2013;987, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RW, Evans RI, Carvajal S. A survey of injuries among broadway performers: Types of injuries, treatments, and perceptions of performers. Med Probl Perf Art 11: 15&#x2013;19, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyhrie DP, Milgrom C, Hoshaw SJ, et al. Effect of fatiguing exercise on longitudinal bone strain as related to stress fracture in humans. Ann Biomed Eng 26: 660&#x2013;665, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrick JG, Requa RK. Ballet injuries: An analysis of epidemiology and financial outcome. Am J Sports Med 21: 586&#x2013;590, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gefen A. Biomechanical analysis of fatigue-related foot injury mechanisms in athletes and recruits during intensive marching. Med Biol Eng Comput 40: 302&#x2013;310, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glassman SD, Copay AG, Berven SH, Polly DW, Subach BR, Carreon LY. Defining substantial clinical benefit following lumbar spine arthrodesis. J Bone Joint Surg Am 90: 1839&#x2013;1847, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem HH, Snyder-Mackler LL, Moksnes HH, Engebretsen LL, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: The Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med 50: 804&#x2013;808, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grooms DR, Palmer T, Onate JA, Myer GD, Grindstaff T. Soccerspecific warm-up and lower extremity injury rates in collegiate Male soccer players. J Athl Train 48: 782&#x2013;789, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton RT, Shultz SJ, Schmitz RJ, Perrin DH. Triple-hop distance as a valid predictor of lower limb strength and power. J Athl Train 43: 144&#x2013;151, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JD, Brand JC, Cote MP, Faucett SC, Dhawan A. Research pearls: The significance of statistics and perils of pooling. Part 1: Clinical versus statistical significance. Arthroscopy 33: 1102&#x2013;1112, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Lindenfeld TN, Riccobene JV, Noyes FR. The effect of neuromuscular training on the incidence of knee injury in female athletes. A prospective study. Am J Sports Med 27: 699&#x2013;706, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori N, Newton R, Nosaka K, Stone MH. Weightlifting exercises enhance athletic performance that requires high-load speed strength. Strength Cond J 27: 50&#x2013;55, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johari MR, Kee YH, Kong PW. Validation of dance-specific balance test: Evidence from comparisons between dancers and nondancers. Mot Control 26: 558&#x2013;567, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karhade AV, Bono CM, Schwab JH, Tobert DG. Minimum clinically important difference: A metric that matters in the age of patient-reported outcomes. J Bone Joint Surg Am 103: 2331&#x2013;2337, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutedakis Y, Hukam H, Metsios G, et al. The effects of three months of aerobic and strength training on selected performance and fitness-related parameters in modern dance students. J Strength Cond Res 21: 808&#x2013;812, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutedakis Y, Sharp NCC. Thigh-muscles strength training, dance exercise, dynamometry, and anthropometry in professional ballerinas. J Strength Cond Res 18: 714&#x2013;718, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutedakis Y, Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Metsios G. The significance of muscular strength in dance. J Dance Med Sci 9: 29&#x2013;34, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laws H. Injury findings. In: Fit to Dance 2-Report of the Second National Inquiry into Dancers' Health and Injury in the UK. London, United Kingdom: Newgate Press, 2005. pp. 16&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liederbach M, Dilgen FE, Rose DJ. Incidence of anterior cruciate ligament injuries among elite ballet and modern dancers: A 5-year prospective study. Am J Sports Med 36: 1779&#x2013;1788, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logerstedt D, Grindem H, Lynch A, et al. Single-legged hop tests as predictors of self-reported knee function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: The Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Am J Sports Med 40: 2348&#x2013;2356, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long KL, Milidonis MK, Wildermuth VL, Kruse AN, Parham UT. The impact of dance-specific neuromuscular conditioning and injury prevention training on motor control, stability, balance, function and injury in professional ballet dancers: A mixed-methods quasi-experimental study. Int J Sports Physi Ther 16: 404&#x2013;417, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyman S, Lee Y, McLawhorn AS, Islam W, MacLean CH. What are the minimal and substantial improvements in the HOOS and KOOS and JR versions after total joint replacement? Clin Orthop Relat Res 476: 2432&#x2013;2441, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Jukic I, Milanovic D, Metikos D. Effects of sprint and plyometric training on muscle function and athletic performance. J Strength Cond Res 21: 543&#x2013;549, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall A, Carling C, Davison M, et al. Injury risk factors, screening tests and preventative strategies: A systematic review of the evidence that underpins the perceptions and practices of 44 football (soccer) teams from various premier leagues. Br J Sports Med 49: 583&#x2013;589, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mistiaen W, Roussel NA, Vissers D, Daenen L, Truijen S, Nijs J. Effects of aerobic endurance, muscle strength, and motor control exercise on physical fitness and musculoskeletal injury rate in preprofessional dancers: An uncontrolled trial. J Manipulative Physiol Ther 35: 381&#x2013;389, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munro AG, Herrington LC. Between-session reliability of four hop tests and the agility T-test. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1470&#x2013;1477, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrete R, Simms S, Gross J, et al. The test re-test reliability of a novel single leg hop test (T-Drill hop test). Int J Sports Phys Ther 16: 724&#x2013;731, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes FR, Barber SD, Mangine RE. Abnormal lower limb symmetry determined by 37 function hop tests after anterior cruciate ligament rupture. Am J Sports Med 19: 513&#x2013;518, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes FR, Barber-Westin SD. Neuromuscular retraining intervention programs: Do they reduce noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injury rates in adolescent female athletes? Arthroscopy 30: 245&#x2013;255, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes FR, Barber-Westin SD; Ohio Library and Information Network. ACL Injuries in the Female Athlete: Causes, Impacts, and Conditioning Programs (2nd ed.). Berlin, Germany: Springer, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Chang B, Fields K, et al. Defining the &#x201c;Substantial Clinical Benefit&#x201d; after arthroscopic treatment of femoroacetabular impingement. Am J Sports Med 45: 1297&#x2013;1303, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen A, Wong D, Dellal A, Paul D, Orhant E, Collie S. Effect of an injury prevention program on muscle injuries in elite professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res 27: 3275&#x2013;3285, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramkumar PN, Farber J, Arnouk J, Varner KE, Mcculloch PC. Injuries in a professional ballet dance company: A 10-year retrospective study. J Dance Med Sci 20: 30&#x2013;37, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid A, Birmingham TB, Stratford PW, Alcock GK, Giffin JR. Hop testing provides a reliable and valid outcome measure during rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther 87: 337&#x2013;349, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal M, McPherson AM, Docherty CL, Klossner J. Perceptions and utilization of strength training and conditioning in collegiate contemporary and ballet dancers: A qualitative approach. Med Prob Perf Artists 36: 78&#x2013;87, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross MD, Langford B, Whelan PJ. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of 4 single-leg horizontal hop tests. J Strength Cond Res 16: 617&#x2013;622, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel NA, Nijs J, Mottram S, Van Moorsel A, Truijen S, Stassijns G. Altered lumbopelvic movement control but not generalized joint hypermobility is associated with increased injury in dancers: A prospective study. Man Ther 14: 630&#x2013;635, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel NA, Vissers D, Kuppens K, et al. Effect of a physical conditioning versus health promotion intervention in dancers: A randomized controlled trial. Man Ther 19: 562&#x2013;568, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovere GD, Webb L, Gristina AG, Vogel JM. Musculoskeletal injuries in theatrical dance students. Am J Sports Med 11: 195&#x2013;198, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell JA. Preventing dance injuries: Current perspectives. Open Access J Sports Med 4: 199&#x2013;210, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers-Granelli H, Mandelbaum B, Adeniji O, et al. Efficacy of the FIFA 11+ injury prevention program in the collegiate Male soccer player. Am J Sports Med 43: 2628&#x2013;2637, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater D, Kvist J, Ardern CL. Biopsychosocial factors associated with return to preinjury sport after ACL injury treated without reconstruction: NACOX cohort study 12-month follow-up. Sports Health 15: 176&#x2013;184, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PJ, Gerrie BJ, Varner KE, McCulloch PC, Lintner DM, Harris JD. Incidence and prevalence of musculoskeletal injury in ballet. Orthop J Sports Med 3: 2325967115592621&#x2013;2325967115592629, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T, Myklebust G, Steffen K, et al. Comprehensive warm-up programme to prevent injuries in young female footballers: Cluster randomised controlled trial. BMJ 338: 95&#x2013;99, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sueyoshi T, Nakahata A, Emoto G, Yuasa T. Single-leg hop test performance and isokinetic knee strength after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in athletes. Orthop J Sports Med 5: 2325967117739811, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera AM, Barrera BD, Peterson LE, et al. An injury prevention program for professional ballet: A randomized controlled investigation. Orthop J Sports Med 8: 2325967120937643, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyon MA, Twitchett E, Angioi M, Clarke F, Metsios G, Koutedakis Y. Time motion and video analysis of classical ballet and contemporary dance performance. Int J Sports Med 32: 851&#x2013;855, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yau R, Golightly Y, Richardson D, Runfola C, Waller A, Marshall S. Potential predictors of injury among pre-professional ballet and contemporary dancers. J Dance Med Sci 21: 53&#x2013;63, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>