<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41669041</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2250-0685</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Bone Mineral Density and Its Correlation with Body Mass Index and Stress Fractures among Paramilitary Recruits.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>391</StartPage><EndPage>396</EndPage><MedlinePgn>391-396</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i02.6860</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Paramilitary recruits undergo repetitive high-intensity physical training, predisposing them to overuse musculoskeletal injuries such as stress fractures. Bone mineral density (BMD) and body mass index (BMI) are key determinants of bone strength, yet limited data exist from Indian paramilitary populations. This study aimed to evaluate BMD status and examine its association with BMI and stress fractures among active recruits.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A descriptive cross-sectional study was conducted among 200 paramilitary recruits (mean age 26.3 &#xb1; 3.88 years). BMD was measured at the calcaneus using a quantitative ultrasound densitometer (CM-300). BMI was calculated using standard anthropometric techniques. Stress fractures were diagnosed based on clinical evaluation, medical record review, and radiographic confirmation when indicated. Dietary pattern, rank, and lifestyle factors were recorded using a structured questionnaire. Associations were analyzed using chi-square tests and correlation statistics, with significance set at P &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean BMD T-score was -0.676 &#xb1; 0.572, with 24.5% of participants demonstrating osteopenia. Stress fractures were documented in 16% of recruits. Abnormal BMI (underweight 2.5%, overweight 13%) showed a significant association with osteopenia (P = 0.029). Low BMD was strongly associated with stress fractures, with 78.1% of fracture cases exhibiting osteopenia (P &lt; 0.01). Assistant commandants had a higher prevalence of low BMD compared with constables (35.5% vs. 17.7%, P = 0.005). Vegetarian recruits demonstrated significantly higher osteopenia and stress-fracture rates (P &lt; 0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Low BMD and abnormal BMI significantly increase susceptibility to stress fractures among paramilitary recruits. The high prevalence of osteopenia despite intensive physical activity highlights the need for routine BMD screening, BMI-focused conditioning, and structured nutritional interventions to enhance bone health and reduce training-related injuries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Indian Orthopaedic Research Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Upadhyay</LastName><ForeName>Avinash Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajpoot</LastName><ForeName>Manish Singh</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Nikhil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Vaibhav</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gohiya</LastName><ForeName>Ashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Swati</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Paul's Clinic, Kolkata, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101641392</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2250-0685</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body mass index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone mineral density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Paramilitary recruits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quantitative ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress fractures</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: Nil</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41669041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i02.6860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JOCR-16-2-391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cummings SR, Black DM. Bone mineral density and the prediction of fracture risk. J Bone Miner Res. 1985;5:629&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinking MF, Austin TM, Hayes AM. Low body mass index and the development of stress fractures in athletes. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2004;34:465&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrack RL, Gibbs AE, DeLuca SA. Effect of body mass index on the risk of stress fractures in athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34:1800&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB. Low energy availability and bone health in physically active individuals. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2007;6:229&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grier TL, Knapik JJ, Canada S, Canham-Chervak M, Jones BH. Risk factors associated with training-related injury in military recruits. Public Health. 2010;124:417&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20557912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nattiv A, Ackerman KE, Warren MP, De Souza MJ, Messina C, Williams NI, et al. Energy availability, body mass index, and stress fracture risk in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:1142&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannon M, Zwart SR, Smith SM. Calcium and vitamin D status in military populations. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2016;101:1338&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton PS, Emerson CP, Loucks AB. Bone health in military personnel:risk factors for stress fractures. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45((12)):2978&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lappe JM, Cullen DM, Haynatzki GR, Recker RR. Bone health and stress fractures in military personnel:A longitudinal study. Osteoporos Int. 2018;29:839&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown T, Patel DR, Roy B. Stress fractures in paramilitary recruits:A study of BMD and training load. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Brukner PD, Malcolm SA. Risk factors for stress fractures in physically active populations:Recent evidence and prevention strategies. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:2521&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosman F, Ruffing J, Zion M, Uhorchak J, Ralston S, Tendy S, et al. Determinants of stress fracture risk in US Military Academy cadets. Osteoporos Int. 2021;32:1201&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23624291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran DS, Israeli E, Evans RK, Yanovich R, Constantini N, Shabshin N, et al. Prediction model for stress fracture in young elite combat recruits. J Bone Miner Res. 2021;36:534&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva DS, Rocha LP, Nunes JD, Santos LG, Ferreira EF. Risk factors associated with stress fractures in military personnel:A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Gupta A, Singh S, Kumar P. Body mass index and physical training-related injuries in military personnel:Systematic review and meta-regression analysis. BMJ Mil Health. 2025;171:e2024002779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12703312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40037927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>