<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41418166</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1079-7114</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>135</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical review letters</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Rev Lett</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimal Phase-Insensitive Force Sensing with Non-Gaussian States.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>230802</StartPage><MedlinePgn>230802</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1103/7pyw-tgjd</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Quantum metrology enables sensitivity to approach the limits set by fundamental physical laws. Even a single continuous mode offers enhanced precision, with the improvement scaling with its occupation number. Due to their high information capacity, continuous modes allow for the engineering of quantum non-Gaussian states, which not only improve metrological performance but can also be tailored to specific experimental platforms and conditions. Recent advancements in control over continuous platforms operating in the quantum regime have renewed interest in sensing weak forces, also coupling to massive macroscopic objects. In this work, we investigate a force-sensing scheme where a physical process completely randomizes the direction of the induced phase-space displacement, and the unknown force strength is inferred through excitation-number-resolving measurements. We find that N-spaced states, where only every N^{th} Fock state occupation is nonzero, approach the achievable sensing bound. Additionally, non-Gaussian states are shown to be more resilient against decoherence than their Gaussian counterparts with the same occupation number. While Fock states typically offer the best protection against decoherence, we uncover a transition in the metrological landscape-revealed through a tailored decoherence-aware Fisher-information-based reward functional-where experimental constraints favor a family of number-squeezed Schr&#xf6;dinger cat states. Specifically, by implementing quantum optimal control in a minimal spin-boson system, we identify these states as maximizing force sensitivity under lossy dynamics and finite system controllability. Our results provide a pathway for enhancing force sensing in a variety of continuous quantum systems, ranging from massive systems like mechanical oscillators to massless systems such as quantum light and microwave resonators.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grochowski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr T</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palack&#xfd; University, Department of Optics, 17. listopadu 1192/12, 771 46 Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04qxnmv42</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filip</LastName><ForeName>Radim</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palack&#xfd; University, Department of Optics, 17. listopadu 1192/12, 771 46 Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04qxnmv42</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Rev Lett</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401141</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0031-9007</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41418166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/7pyw-tgjd</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>