<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41574581</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute responses of isometric handgrip exercise combined with blood flow restriction in the elderly.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2026.14110</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to investigate the influence of isometric handgrip exercise under different blood flow restriction times on acute responses related to safety and effectiveness in the elderly. Eleven physically active elderly people (70.1 &#xb1; 7.1 years) were subjected to three protocols (P1-1m), (P2-30s) and (P3-Control) of isometric handgrip contraction. Hemodynamic markers (SBP, DBP and HR), hematological markers (D-dimer, fibrinogen, APTT and ultrasensitive CRP) and surface electromyography (sEMG) of the flexor digitorum superficialis and extensor digitorum communis muscles were analyzed. The hemodynamic variables showed no significant difference P &lt; 0.05 between the moments before, immediately after, after 15 minutes, and after 30 minutes. The hematological variables showed no significant difference P &lt; 0.05 between the pre- and post-30 minute time points. The sEMG variables showed a significant difference of p&lt; 0.01 at the beginning, middle and end of each series and between the complete series for both muscles analyzed. In line with the aim of this study, we can accept the hypothesis that the P1-1m, P2-30s and P3-Control protocols are safe. However, we reject the hypothesis that the BFR protocols result in greater muscle activation compared to the protocol without BFR.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fernandes da Silva</LastName><ForeName>Thailson</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima de Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Leandro</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Assessment and Training Laboratory, Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campos Sousa Leite</LastName><ForeName>Johnatan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Studies Laboratory, Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza Martins</LastName><ForeName>Lucas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o Silva</LastName><ForeName>Robson</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ernesto Santos Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2397-5866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Handgrip</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thromboembolism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41574581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2026.14110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Martinsen EW, Medhus A, Sandvik L. Effects of aerobic exercise on depression: a controlled study. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed) 1985;291:109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. Seals DR, Hagberg JM, Hurley BF, et al JO. Endurance training in older men and women. I. Cardiovascular responses to exercise. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol 1984;57:1024-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>3. American College of Sports Medicine; Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2009;41:1510-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>4. Rodrigo-Mallorca D, Loaiza-Betancur AF, Monteagudo P, et al. Resistance training with blood flow restriction compared to traditional resistance training on strength and muscle mass in non-active older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18:11441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>5. Clarkson MJ, Conway L, Warmington SA. Blood flow restriction walking and physical function in older adults: A randomized control trial. J Sci Med Sport 2017;20:1041-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>6. Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 2016;19:669-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>7. Dionyssiotis Y, Masiero S, Maccarone MC, et al. Frailty: future prospectives in rehabilitation medicine. Eur J Transl Myol 2023;33:11347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>8. Maccarone MC, Masiero S, Papathanasiou J, et al. Frailty education: promoting geriatric competencies among physical medicine and rehabilitation residents. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2023;102:e137-e140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>9. Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol 2019;10:533. Erratum in: Front Physiol 2019;10:1332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>10. Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Wilson GJ, et al. Potential safety issues with blood flow restriction training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2011;21:510-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>11. Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Mar&#xed;n PJ, et al. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol 2012;112:1849-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. Hughes L, Rosenblatt B, Haddad F, et al. Comparing the effectiveness of blood flow restriction and traditional heavy load resistance training in the post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: a UK National Health Service randomised controlled trial. Sports Med 2019;49:1787-805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>13. Goessler K, Buys R, Cornelissen VA. Low-intensity isometric handgrip exercise has no transient effect on blood pressure in patients with coronary artery disease. J Am Soc Hypertens 2016;10:633-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>14. Bentley DC, Nguyen CHP, Thomas SG. High-intensity handgrip training lowers blood pressure and increases heart rate complexity among postmenopausal women: a pilot study. Blood Press Monit 2018;23:71-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Brook RD, Appel LJ, Rubenfire M, et al. Beyond medications and diet: alternative approaches to lowering blood pressure: a scientific statement from the american heart association. Hypertension 2013;61:1360-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>16. Marcel-Millet P, Gimenez P, Groslambert A, et al. The type of visual biofeedback influences maximal handgrip strength and activation strategies. Eur J Appl Physiol 2021;121:1607-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>17. Scott BR, Slattery KM, Sculley DV, Dascombe BJ. Hypoxia and resistance exercise: a comparison of localized and systemic methods. Sports Med 2014;44:1037-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>18. Wong V, Spitz RW, Song JS, et al. Blood flow restriction augments the cross-education effect of isometric handgrip training. Eur J Appl Physiol 2024;124:1575-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>19. Kawamura T. Assessing Ankle-Brachial Index (ABI) by using automated oscillometric devices. Arq Bras Cardiol 2008;90:294-8. English, Portuguese.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>20. Souza LR, Vicente JB, Melo GR, et al. Acute hypotension after moderate-intensity handgrip exercise in hypertensive elderly people. J Strength Conditioning Res 2018;32:2971&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>21. Lorenz DS, Bailey L, Wilk KE, Mangine RE, Head P, Grindstaff TL, Morrison S. Blood Flow Restriction Training. J Athl Train 2021;56:937-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>22. Pickering TG, Hall JE, Appel LJ, et al. Recommendations for blood pressure measurement in humans and experimental animals: Part 1: blood pressure measurement in humans: a statement for professionals from the Subcommittee of Professional and Public Education of the American Heart Association Council on High Blood Pressure Research. Hypertension 2005;45:142-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>23. Perotto AO. Anatomical guide for the electromyographer: the limbs and trunk. Charles C Thomas Publisher. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>24. Lin S, Sun P, Huang L, et al. Effects of the intensity, duration and muscle mass factors of isometric exercise on acute local muscle hemodynamic responses and systematic blood pressure regulation. Front Bioengin Biotechnol 2024;12:1444598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>25. Franceschi C, Garagnani P, Parini P, et al. Inflammaging: a new immune-metabolic viewpoint for age-related diseases. Nature Rev Endocrinol 2018;14:576&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>26. de Lima FR, Marin DP, Ferreira LT, et al. Effect of resistance training with total and partial blood flow restriction on biomarkers of oxidative stress and apoptosis in untrained men. Front Physiol 2021;12:720773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>27. Cifrek M, Medved V, Tonkovi&#x107; S, Ostoji&#x107; S. Surface EMG based muscle fatigue evaluation in biomechanics. Clin Biomech 2009;24:327&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>28. Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropractic Med 2016;15:155&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>29. Basmajian JV. Muscles alive. Their functions revealed by electromyography. Med J Australia 1962;2:878-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>30. Merletti R, Parker P. Electromyography: physiology, engineering, and non-invasive applications. Wiley-IEEE Press; 2004.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>