<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41872868</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of multicomponent exercise intervention on older adults with mild cognitive impairment based on HAPA-TPB theory (MIND-STEP): trial design and baseline data for a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09640-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Physical exercise has emerged as a promising non-pharmacological approach for improving cognitive and physical function in older adults with mild cognitive impairment (MCI). However, most existing interventions in nursing homes lack a strong theoretical foundation, standardized delivery, and evidence-based practice. This study aims to develop and evaluate a multicomponent exercise program grounded in the Health Action Process Approach-Theory of Planned Behavior theory (HAPA-TPB) to improve adherence and cognitive outcomes in older adults with MCI living in nursing homes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a randomized, single-blind, parallel-group controlled trial conducted in nursing homes in Huzhou, China. A total of 156 older adults with MCI were randomly assigned to either a 12-week, group-based multicomponent exercise intervention or a control group receiving usual care. The intervention, theoretically grounded in an integrated HAPA-TPB framework, integrates aerobic, resistance, and mind-body training with structured behavioral change strategies designed to enhance motivation, adherence, and sustained engagement, including peer interaction. The primary outcome is cognitive function assessed by the Montreal Cognitive Assessment-Basic (MoCA-B). Secondary outcomes include physical performance, sleep quality, intrinsic capacity, frailty, social support, and intervention feasibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 1351 participants completed preliminary eligibility screening, of whom 156 were eligible and randomized (78 per group). The mean (SD) age was 69.19&#xa0;years (SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;8.97), and 69.23% of participants were female. Baseline characteristics were comparable across groups in terms of demographic, socioeconomic, and health status indicators. Baseline cognitive function, assessed using the MoCA-B, showed no significant between-group difference (intervention: mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;17.29, SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.32; control: mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;16.74, SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.19; F&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.320, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.130), indicating comparability prior to the intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This MIND-STEP study will provide high-quality evidence on the effectiveness and implementation of a theory-based, multicomponent exercise intervention for older adults with MCI in nursing homes. Findings will inform future intervention design and policy development to promote cognitive and functional health in institutionalized older populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry ChiCTR2400088301. Registered on 15 August 2024.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Na</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Chenlu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global Health, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheng</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxiu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Sisi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jiali</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiuxia</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Rehabilitation Hospital, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yinke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Rehabilitation Hospital, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Haiqin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, the Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang Province, China. 1039770471@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global Health, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China. luoyanan@bjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Health and Development, Peking University, Beijing, China. luoyanan@bjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Vascular Homeostasis and Remodeling, Peking University, Beijing, China. luoyanan@bjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025HY1153</GrantID><Agency>Medical and Health Science Program of Zhejiang Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024YFC3607302</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25BJ03219</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Municipal Social Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The MIND-STEP study was approved by the Medical Ethics Committee of Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital (Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University). The trial is registered with the Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (ChiCTR2400088301). Trained research staff at Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital are responsible for obtaining written informed consent from all participants before enrollment (Supplementary Material 1). All participants are informed about the study objectives, procedures, potential risks and benefits, voluntary participation, and their right to withdraw at any time without consequences. No biological specimens are collected in this study. The protocol does not include ancillary studies involving additional use of participant data or biological samples beyond the predefined study objectives. Therefore, no additional consent provisions for ancillary studies are required. Research findings will be disseminated through publication in peer-reviewed journals and presentations to local stakeholders, as well as at provincial, national, and international conferences or forums. Competing interests: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41872868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09640-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09640-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gauthier S, Rosa-Neto P, Morais JA, C W. World Alzheimer Report 2021: Journey through the diagnosis of dementia. London, England: Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease International; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooldijk SS, Yaqub A, Wolters FJ, Licher S, Koudstaal PJ, Ikram MK, et al. Life expectancy with and without dementia in persons with mild cognitive impairment in the community. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2022;70(2):481&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia L, Du Y, Chu L, Zhang Z, Li F, Lyu D, et al. Prevalence, risk factors, and management of dementia and mild cognitive impairment in adults aged 60 years or older in China: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Public Health. 2020;5(12):e661-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding D, Zhao Q, Guo Q, Liang X, Luo J, Yu L, et al. Progression and predictors of mild cognitive impairment in Chinese elderly: a prospective follow-up in the Shanghai Aging Study. Alzheimers Dement Diagn Assess Dis Monit. 2016;4:28&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva JL, Agbangla NF, Le Page C, Ghernout W, Andrieu B. Effects of chronic physical exercise or multicomponent exercise programs on the mental health and cognition of older adults living in a nursing home: a systematic review of studies from the past 10 years. Front Psychol. 2022;13:888851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon J, Isoda H, Ueda T, Okura T. Cognitive and physical benefits of a game-like dual-task exercise among the oldest nursing home residents in Japan. Alzheimers Dement N Y. 2022;8(1):e12276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Bennett H, Miatke A, Dumuid D, Curtis R, Ferguson T, et al. Effectiveness of exercise for improving cognition, memory and executive function: a systematic umbrella review and meta-meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(12):866&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciria LF, Rom&#xe1;n-Caballero R, Vadillo MA, Holgado D, Luque-Casado A, Perakakis P, et al. An umbrella review of randomized control trials on the effects of physical exercise on cognition. Nat Hum Behav. 2023;7(6):928&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law CK, Lam FM, Chung RC, Pang MY. Physical exercise attenuates cognitive decline and reduces behavioural problems in people with mild cognitive impairment and dementia: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2020;66(1):9&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biazus-Sehn LF, Schuch FB, Firth J, Stigger FdS. Effects of physical exercise on cognitive function of older adults with mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2020;89:104048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen FT, Etnier JL, Chan KH, Chiu PK, Hung TM, Chang YK. Effects of exercise training interventions on executive function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(8):1451&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordes T, Bischoff LL, Schoene D, Schott N, Voelcker-Rehage C, Meixner C, et al. A multicomponent exercise intervention to improve physical functioning, cognition and psychosocial well-being in elderly nursing home residents: a study protocol of a randomized controlled trial in the PROCARE (prevention and occupational health in long-term care) project. BMC Geriatr. 2019;19(1):369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Liu C, Wan Q, Yu F. An integrative review of exercise interventions among community-dwelling adults with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Int J Older People Nurs. 2020;15(1):e12287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung AR, Kim D, Park EA. Cognitive intervention using information and communication technology for older adults with mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammisuli DM, Pietrabissa G, Castelnuovo G. Improving wellbeing of community-dwelling people with mild cognitive impairment: the SENIOR (SystEm of Nudge theory based ICT applications for OldeR citizens) project. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16(5):963&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadyab AH, LaCroix AZ, Feldman HH, van Dyck CH, Okonkwo OC, Tam SP, et al. Recruitment of a multi-site randomized controlled trial of aerobic exercise for older adults with amnestic mild cognitive impairment: the EXERT trial. Alzheimer&#x2019;s &amp; Dementia. 2021;17(11):1808&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngandu T, Lehtisalo J, Solomon A, Lev&#xe4;lahti E, Ahtiluoto S, Antikainen R, et al. A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2015;385(9984):2255&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivipelto M, Mangialasche F, Snyder HM, Allegri R, Andrieu S, Arai H, et al. World-wide FINGERS network: a global approach to risk reduction and prevention of dementia. Alzheimers Dement. 2020;16(7):1078&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan A-W, Tetzlaff JM, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Altman DG, Mann H, Berlin JA, et al. SPIRIT 2013 explanation and elaboration: guidance for protocols of clinical trials. BMJ (Clinical Research ed). 2013;346:e7586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AW, Boutron I, Hopewell S, Moher D, Schulz KF, Collins GS, et al. SPIRIT 2025 statement: updated guideline for protocols of randomized trials. Nat Med. 2025;31(6):1784&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Boutron I, Hopewell S, Moher D, Schulz KF, Collins GS, et al. SPIRIT 2025 explanation and elaboration: updated guideline for protocols of randomised trials. BMJ. 2025;389:e081660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann TC, Glasziou PP, Boutron I, Milne R, Perera R, Moher D, et al. Better reporting of interventions: template for intervention description and replication (TIDier) checklist and guide. BMJ. 2014;348:g1687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neils-Strunjas J, Crandall KJ, Ding X, Gabbard A, Rassi S, Otto S. Facilitators and barriers to attendance in a nursing home exercise program. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22(4):803&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Smith AL, Hanson CL, Neubeck L, Rowat A, McHale S. Physical activity interventions framed by the Health Action Process Approach for adults with long-term conditions: a scoping review. Int J Behav Med. 2024;31(6):987&#x2013;1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Bokyoung J, Kim Y. The relationship between exercise intention, behavioural plans, and exercise behaviour among Korean college students using the Health Action Process Approach (HAPA). Int J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1080/1612197x.2024.2323993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao X, Ji L, Jin Y, Si H, Bian Y, Wang W, et al. A theory-driven exercise intervention among community-dwelling (pre)frail older adults: protocol for a stepped-wedge cluster-randomized trial. J Adv Nurs. 2022;78(8):2634&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KL, Xu Y, Chu AQ, Ding D, Liang XN, Nasreddine ZS, et al. Validation of the Chinese version of Montreal Cognitive Assessment Basic for screening mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2016;64(12):e285-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julayanont P, Tangwongchai S, Hemrungrojn S, Tunvirachaisakul C, Phanthumchinda K, Hongsawat J, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment-Basic: a screening tool for mild cognitive impairment in illiterate and low-educated elderly adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2015;63(12):2550&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prince MJ, Acosta D, Guerra M, Huang Y, Jacob KS, Jimenez-Velazquez IZ, et al. Intrinsic capacity and its associations with incident dependence and mortality in 10/66 Dementia Research Group studies in Latin America, India, and China: a population-based cohort study. PLoS Med. 2021;18(9):e1003097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Smit E, Xue QL, Odden MC. Prevalence and correlates of frailty among community-dwelling Chinese older adults: the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2017;73(1):102&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Ding N, He J, Zhao R, Gu W, Ge X, et al. Associations between reversible and potentially reversible cognitive frailty and falls in community-dwelling older adults in China: a longitudinal study. BMC Geriatr. 2025;25(1):224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubben J, Blozik E, Gillmann G, Iliffe S, von Renteln Kruse W, Beck JC, et al. Performance of an abbreviated version of the Lubben Social Network Scale among three European community-dwelling older adult populations. Gerontologist. 2006;46(4):503&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galhardas L, Raimundo A, Marmeleira J. Feasibility, acceptability and effectiveness of a multimodal intervention program for nursing home residents: an exploratory case study. Geriatr Nurs. 2025;64:103413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang QH, Lyu X, Lin QR, Wang ZW, Tang L, Zhao Y, et al. Effects of a multicomponent intervention to slow mild cognitive impairment progression: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Nurs Stud. 2022;125:104110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautenschlager NT, Cox KL, Flicker L, Foster JK, van Bockxmeer FM, Xiao J, et al. Effect of physical activity on cognitive function in older adults at risk for Alzheimer disease: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2008;300(9):1027&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Xu X, Yang X, Wang SS, Zhou Y, Li Y. Effects of multicomponent exercise on cognitive function in persons with mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2024;158:104843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso M, Zou G, Speechley M, Almeida QJ, Liu-Ambrose T, Middleton LE, et al. Effects of exercise alone or combined with cognitive training and vitamin D supplementation to improve cognition in adults with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(7):e2324465.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>