<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41552674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1728-869X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise science and fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Sci Fit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise improves physical function in young women with functional ankle instability: a randomized controlled trial of 8-week structured high-intensity circuit training on balance, ankle function, and physical fitness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>200439</StartPage><MedlinePgn>200439</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">200439</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jesf.2025.200439</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Prolonged sedentary behavior in women is associated with weakened lower-body musculature and increased risk of falls and injury. Although high-intensity circuit training (HICT) has been reported to effectively improve aerobic and anaerobic fitness in previously inactive individuals, few studies have evaluated its effectiveness in young women with functional ankle instability (FAI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We aimed to evaluate the effect of an 8-week HICT program on balance, ankle stability, and physical fitness in sedentary young women with FAI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This randomized controlled trial included 96 sedentary young women with FAI (aged 18-30 years, Cumberland Ankle Instability Tool (CAIT)&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;25), who were randomly assigned to the HICT (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;54) or control (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;42) groups. The HICT group completed an 8-week program (3 sessions/week) with progressive intensity stages, whereas the control group maintained routine activity. A battery of outcomes was assessed before and after the intervention. The primary outcomes included objectively measured balance function and perceived ankle stability, whereas the secondary outcomes included body composition, body circumference, and physical fitness. Repeated-measures analysis of covariance was used to detect the time&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;group interaction effect, with adjustment for baseline values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A significant time&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;group interaction effect (<i>p</i>&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) was observed for balance function and ankle stability (<i>F</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;4.732-54.806, <i>&#x3b7;</i> <sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.048-0.496), body composition (i.e., reductions in hip and thigh circumference: <i>F</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.092-8.933, <i>&#x3b7;</i> <sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.061-0.213), and physical fitness (i.e., improvements in back and leg strength, flexibility, upper limb strength, and abdominal strength: <i>F</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;7.783-54.806, <i>&#x3b7;</i> <sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.082-0.386).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An 8-week HICT program appears to effectively improve balance and ankle stability in sedentary young women with FAI, providing preliminary evidence that HICT is a promising intervention for enhancing physical function and reducing the risk of falls and injuries in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Society of Chinese Scholars on Exercise Physiology and Fitness. Published by Elsevier (Singapore) Pte Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Qianwen</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, The Education University of Hong Kong, Tai Po, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Borui</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, The Education University of Hong Kong, Tai Po, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, The Education University of Hong Kong, Tai Po, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, The Education University of Hong Kong, Tai Po, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Fenghua</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, The Education University of Hong Kong, Tai Po, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Singapore</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Sci Fit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101198241</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1728-869X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankle stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-intensity circuit training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary individuals</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Fenghua SUN and Chen ZHENG are Associate Editors of Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness. Fenghua SUN and Cheng ZHENG were not involved in the journal&#x2019;s peer review process of, or decisions related to, this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41552674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12811444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2025.200439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1728-869X(25)00103-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Green A.N., McGrath R., Martinez V., Taylor K., Paul D.R., Vella C.A. Associations of objectively measured sedentary behavior, light activity, and markers of cardiometabolic health in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:907&#x2013;919. 10.1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24463602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubbard-Turner T., Turner M.J. Physical activity levels in college students with chronic ankle instability. J Athl Train. 2015;50(7):742&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4532186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25898110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog M.M., Kerr Z.Y., Marshall S.W., Wikstrom E.A. Epidemiology of ankle sprains and chronic ankle instability. J Athl Train. 2019;54(6):603&#x2013;610. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-447-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-447-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31135209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Mahrouqi M.M., Vicenzino B., MacDonald D.A., Smith M.D. Falls and falls-related injuries in individuals with chronic ankle symptoms: a cross-sectional study. J Foot Ankle Res. 2023;16(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10428594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37587537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Luo Z., Wu D., Fei J., Xie T., Su M. Effectiveness of exercise therapy on chronic ankle instability: a meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11972327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40188228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Zheng C., Hu M., et al. The effect of different high-intensity interval training protocols on cardiometabolic and inflammatory markers in sedentary young women: a randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2024:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38864405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras B. Human kinetics; 2013. Bodyweight Strength Training Anatomy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.-S., Yoon E.-S., Jung S.-Y., Yim K.-T., Kim D.-Y. Effect of high-intensity circuit training on obesity indices, physical fitness, and browning factors in inactive female college students. Exerc Rehabilit. 2021;17(3):207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8257432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran A.J., Percival M.E., Tricarico S., et al. Intermittent and continuous high&#x2010;intensity exercise training induce similar acute but different chronic muscle adaptations. Exp Physiol. 2014;99(5):782&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunus M., Raharjo S., Suwanto W., Pelana R., Giang N.T. The effect of high-intensity circuit training on physical fitness in healthy young males. Retos: nuevas tendencias en educaci&#xf3;n f&#xed;sica, deporte y recreaci&#xf3;n. 2024;(54):243&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivas J. California State University; Northridge: 2021. Effects of multi-joint and single-joint Exercises on Muscle Performance, Ligament Laxity and Static Balance in recreationally-trained Subjects.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miko&#x19a;ajec K., Maszczyk A., Chalimoniuk M., Langfort J., Go&#x19a;a&#x15b; A., Zajc A. The influence of strength exercises of the lower limbs on postural stability: a possible role of the autonomic nervous system. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2017;25(2):79&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipecki K., Rutowicz B. The impact of ten weeks of bodyweight training on the level of physical fitness and selected parameters of body composition in women aged 21-23 years. Polish J Sport Tour. 2015;22(2):64&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C.E., Chander H., Garner J.C., et al. Evaluating human balance following an exercise intervention in previously sedentary, overweight adults. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2017;2(2):19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J.H., Moon J.H., Kim H.J., Kong M.H., Oh Y.H. Sedentary lifestyle: overview of updated evidence of potential health risks. Korean J Fam Med. 2020;41(6):365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33242381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiller C.E., Refshauge K.M., Bundy A.C., Herbert R.D., Kilbreath S.L. The cumberland ankle instability tool: a report of validity and reliability testing. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87(9):1235&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16935061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho S.-Y., Chung Y.-C., Wu H.-J., Ho C.-C., Chen H.-T. Effect of high intensity circuit training on muscle mass, muscular strength, and blood parameters in sedentary workers. PeerJ. 2024;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10962336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38529312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F., Fang Y., Chan C.K.M., et al. Structured physical exercise interventions and children and adolescents with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Child Care Health Dev. 2024;50(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams N. The borg rating of perceived exertion (RPE) scale. Occup Med (Oxf) 2017;67(5):404&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio S.P., Ferrara M.S., Sopiarz K., Kelly M.S. Reliable change of the sensory organization test. Clin J Sport Med. 2008;18(2):148&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18332690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picot B., Terrier R., Forestier N., Fourchet F., McKeon P.O. The star excursion balance test: an update review and practical guidelines. Int J Athl Ther Train. 2021;26(6):285&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Ma H., Zhang W., et al. Effects of functional strength training combined with aerobic training on body composition, physical fitness, and movement quality in obese adolescents. Nutrients. 2024;16(10):1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11123798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38794672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borfe L., Brand C., Schneiders LdB., et al. Effects and responsiveness of a multicomponent intervention on body composition, physical fitness, and leptin in overweight/obese adolescents. Int J Environ Res Publ Health. 2021;18(14):7267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson M. Clackamas, Oregon. NeuroCom International Inc.; 2009. Balance manager systems: clinical interpretation guide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mylonas V., Grioriadis S., Chalitsios C., Stergiou N., Nikodelis T. Postural sway variability in young adults presents higher complexity during morning compared to evening hours while in older adults remains the same. Exp Brain Res. 2025;243(7):176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12170733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40522468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethards S., Everitt-Smith S., Roberts H., Scarborough G., Tate S., Bandy W.D. Intrarater test-retest reliability of an instrument used to measure back and leg strength. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 1995;5(1):31&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childs J.D., Teyhen D.S., Benedict T.M., et al. Effects of sit-up training versus core stabilization exercises on sit-up performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(11):2072&#x2013;2083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. 2016. A Power Primer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gribble P.A., Hertel J. Considerations for normalizing measures of the star excursion balance test. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci. 2003;7(2):89&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;rdenas J.S., Ch&#xe1;vez N.V., Ruiz M.R., Vega S.V., Antilef C.M., Silva N.B.F. The effectiveness of long-term physical rehabilitation to improve balance and locomotion in older people with Parkinson's disease: a systematic review. Scient J Sport Perform. 2023;2(3):326&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajjimaporn A., Khemtong C., Willems M.E. Body composition and physical fitness improve after 8 weeks of high-intensity circuit training using body weight in obese women. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2022;63(2) 10.23736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35620956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montealegre-Su&#xe1;rez D.P., Ramos-Gonz&#xe1;lez E.P., Romana-Cabrera L. Effects of high-intensity circuit training vs. interval training on body composition and oxygen consumption in college students. Hacia la Promoci&#xf3;n de la Salud. 2022;27(2):174&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klika B., Jordan C. High-intensity circuit training using body weight: maximum results with minimal investment. ACSM's Health &amp; Fit J. 2013;17(3):8&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>