<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41622262</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-intensity interval training improves the reactive strength index and motor ability of youth football players.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">137</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01560-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The aim of this randomized controlled trial was to determine the effects of a four-week running-based high-intensity interval training (HIIT) intervention on the reactive strength index (RSI) and motor abilities in youth football players. In this context, the contributions of the running-based HIIT protocol HIIT protocol, implemented in addition to regular football training, were evaluated on performance indicators such as speed, back strength, change of direction (COD), and countermovement jump (CMJ). This study aims to contribute to the development of scientifically grounded training programs to support performance improvement in youth football players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A quantitative research design was employed in this study, specifically a randomized pretest-posttest controlled experimental design. Twenty male youth football players, aged 11-13 years, who voluntarily participated in the study were randomly allocated to either the experimental group (EG; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) or the control group (CON; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10). The EG participated in a running-based HIIT program three times per week for four weeks by replacing a low-to-moderate-intensity technical-tactical segment of their regular football training, whereas the CON continued with only regular football training during this period without any additional training volume. The players underwent RSI, 10&#xa0;m, 20&#xa0;m, and 30&#xa0;m sprint tests, back strength tests, the Illinois Agility Test, and CMJ tests both before the training sessions and at the end of the four-week intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">According to the repeated-measures ANOVA results, pretest values did not differ significantly between the groups (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;.05). Over the 4-week period, significant improvements with large effect sizes were observed in RSI, sprint performance (10, 20, 30&#xa0;m), back strength, COD, and CMJ tests (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05; &#x3b7;p&#xb2; = 0.29-0.55). Significant group &#xd7; time interactions were also detected for all variables, again with large effect sizes (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05; &#x3b7;p&#xb2; = 0.20-0.30), indicating greater improvements in the EG compared to the CON. However, despite these favourable within-group changes, between-group post-test comparisons did not reach statistical significance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study revealed that a 4-week HIIT intervention applied to youth male football players had positive effects on the RSI and motor abilities, as evidenced by large within-group improvements and significant group &#xd7; time interactions, despite the absence of statistically significant between-group post-test differences. These findings suggest that HIIT protocols should be integrated into training programs as an effective strategy to improve explosive strength, COD, and overall functional performance in young athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This randomized controlled trial was retrospectively registered with ISRCTN (ISRCTN45188963) on 16 July 2025 due to administrative delays during ethics approval and registry processing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#x131;z&#x131;lca</LastName><ForeName>Serkan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Bitlis Eren University, Bitlis, Turkey. serkankizilca@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kahraman</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed Zahit</ForeName><Initials>MZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Bitlis Eren University, Bitlis, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okut</LastName><ForeName>Sedat</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Mu&#x15f; Alparslan University, Mu&#x15f;, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Ersin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Van Y&#xfc;z&#xfc;nc&#xfc; Y&#x131;l University, Van, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilici</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;mer Faruk</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Marmara University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;elik</LastName><ForeName>&#x130;smail</ForeName><Initials>&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Sciences, Mu&#x15f; Alparslan University, Mu&#x15f;, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x130;&#x15f;len</LastName><ForeName>Tayfun</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social Sciences, Mu&#x15f; Alparslan University, Mu&#x15f;, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alt&#x131;nta&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>Sebahattin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Winter Sports and Sports Sciences Institute, Atat&#xfc;rk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilici</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed Fatih</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Sciences, Mu&#x15f; Alparslan University, Mu&#x15f;, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training adaptation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki ( https://sites.jamanetwork.com/research-ethics/index.html ) and approved by the Noninterventional Clinical Research Ethics Committee of Bitlis Eren University (Meeting Date: 02.01.2025, Decision No: 13, Protocol No: 2024/9). Since all participants were under the age of 16, written informed consent was obtained from their parents or legal guardians prior to participation. In addition, assent was obtained from each child. This study was conducted using a randomized controlled trial design and was reported in accordance with the Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials (CONSORT) guidelines to ensure methodological transparency and comprehensive reporting. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41622262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13001278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01560-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01560-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gavrilova N, Mokhunko O. Features of determination of physical development and motor readiness of students in the process of football classes. Sci J Natl Pedagog Dragomanov Univ. 2023;1(159):18&#x2013;20. 10.31392/NPU-nc.series15.2023.1(159).04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31392/NPU-nc.series15.2023.1(159).04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AF, Alvurdu S, Akyildiz Z, Badicu G, Greco G, Clemente FM. Variations of the locomotor profile, sprinting, change-of-direction, and jumping performances in youth soccer players: interactions between playing positions and age-groups. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(2):998. 10.3390/ijerph19020998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19020998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35055819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills A, Butt J, Maynard I, Harwood C. Identifying factors perceived to influence the development of elite youth football academy players. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(16):1593&#x2013;604. 10.1080/02640414.2012.710753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.710753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22888797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento H, Anguera MT, Pereira A, Ara&#xfa;jo D. Talent identification and development in male football: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):907&#x2013;31. 10.1007/s40279-017-0851-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0851-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude O, Schnittker R, Schulte-Zurhausen R, M&#xfc;ller F, Meyer T. High-intensity interval training vs high-volume running training during pre-season conditioning in high-level youth football: a cross-over trial. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(13):1441&#x2013;50. 10.1080/02640414.2013.792953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2013.792953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23725006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibi&#x107; E, Mili&#x107; V, Radakovi&#x107; M, &#x106;eremid&#x17e;ic D, Andra&#x161;i&#x107; S, Korobeynikov G, Trajkovi&#x107; N. Effects of change of direction during high-intensity interval training on physical performance in young football players. Sci Rep. 2025;15:33865. 10.1038/s41598-025-07256-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-07256-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12485011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41028022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panasc&#xec; M, Castagna C, Rago V, Ferrando V, Ruggeri P, Faelli E. Effects of a 4-week off-season high-intensity training program on aerobic performance and sprint endurance ability in adolescent female football players: a pilot study. J Funct Morphology Kinesiol. 2025;10:396. 10.3390/jfmk10040396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk10040396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12550979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41133586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgerud J, Engen LC, Wisloff U, Hoff J. Aerobic endurance training improves soccer performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(11):1925&#x2013;31. 10.1097/00005768-200111000-00019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200111000-00019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iaia FM, Rampinini E, Bangsbo J. High-intensity training in football. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2009;4(3):291&#x2013;306. 10.1123/ijspp.4.3.291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.4.3.291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19953818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayhan RF, &#xc7;&#x131;k&#x131;kc&#x131; A, G&#xfc;lez O. The effect of reactive strength index on some parameters of young football players. Int J Sport Exerc Train Sci. 2021;7(1):31&#x2013;9. 10.18826/useeabd.835723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18826/useeabd.835723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvis P, Turner A, Read P, Bishop C. Reactive strength index and its associations with measures of physical and sports performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52(2):301&#x2013;30. 10.1007/s40279-021-01566-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01566-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34606061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL, Hughes MG, Williams CA. The influence of chronological age on periods of accelerated adaptation of stretch-shortening cycle performance in pre- and postpubescent boys. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(7):1889&#x2013;97. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e7faa8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e7faa8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, French D, Hayes PR. The effect of two plyometric training techniques on muscular power and agility in youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):332&#x2013;5. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318183a01a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318183a01a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19002073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijatovic D, Krivokapic D, Versic S, Dimitric G, Zenic N. Change of direction speed and reactive agility in prediction of injury in football: prospective analysis over one half-season. Healthc (Basel). 2022;10(3):440. 10.3390/healthcare10030440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10030440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35326918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaouachi A, Manzi V, Wong del P, Chaalali A, Laurencelle L, Chamari K, Castagna C. Intermittent endurance and repeated sprint ability in soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2663&#x2013;9. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e347f4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e347f4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellal A, Varliette C, Owen A, Chirico EN, Pialoux V. Small-sided games versus interval training in amateur soccer players: effects on the aerobic capacity and the ability to perform intermittent exercises with changes of direction. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(10):2712&#x2013;20. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824294c4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824294c4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rumpf MC, Cronin JB, Pinder SD, Oliver JL, Hughes MG. Effect of different training methods on running sprint times in male youth. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2012;24(2):170&#x2013;86. 10.1123/pes.24.2.170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.24.2.170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radnor JM, Oliver JL, Waugh CM, Myer GD, Moore IS, Lloyd RS. The influence of growth and maturation on stretch&#x2013;shortening cycle function in youth. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):57&#x2013;71. 10.1007/s40279-017-0785-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0785-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28900862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle: part I, cardiopulmonary emphasis. Sports Med. 2013;43(5):313&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s40279-013-0029-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0029-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Faigenbaum AD, Stone MH, et al. Position statement on youth resistance training: the 2014 international consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(7):498&#x2013;505. 10.1136/bjsports-2013-092952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammami M, Gaamouri N, Shephard RJ, Chelly MS. Effects of contrast strength vs plyometric training on lower-limb explosive performance, ability to change direction and neuromuscular adaptation in soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2094&#x2013;103. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomakos P, Tsekos P, Tselios Z, Spyrou K, Katsikas C, Tsoukos A, Bogdanis GC. Effects of two in-season short high-intensity interval training formats on aerobic and neuromuscular performance in young soccer players. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(4):812&#x2013;21. 10.52082/jssm.2024.812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomakos P, Spyrou K, Katsikas C, Geladas ND, Bogdanis GC. Effects of concurrent high-intensity and strength training on muscle power and aerobic performance in young soccer players during the pre-season. Sports (Basel). 2023;11(3):59. 10.3390/sports11030059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports11030059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36976945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Aravena A, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla P, S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;n EB, Cancino-L&#xf3;pez J, Gallardo-Fuentes F, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a JM. Effects of high-intensity interval training with specific techniques on jumping ability and change of direction speed in karate athletes: an inter-individual analysis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:769267. 10.3389/fphys.2021.769267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.769267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Blagrove RC, Drury B, Fernandes JF, Paxton K, Chaabene H, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of small-sided games vs conventional endurance training on endurance performance in male youth soccer players: a meta-analytical comparison. Sports Med. 2019;49(5):731&#x2013;42. 10.1007/s40279-019-01086-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01086-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30868441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodas G, Ventura JL, Cadefau JA, Cuss&#xf3; R, Parra J. A short training programme for the rapid improvement of both aerobic and anaerobic metabolism. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(6):2166&#x2013;72. 10.1007/s004210000223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10985604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL. The youth physical development model: A new approach to long-term athletic development. Strength Cond J. 2012;34(3):61&#x2013;72. 10.1519/SSC.0b013e31825760ea.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e31825760ea</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrete C, Requena B, Suarez-Arrones L, de Villarreal ES. Effect of strength and high-intensity training on jumping, sprinting, and intermittent endurance performance in prepubertal soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(2):413&#x2013;22. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31829b2222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31829b2222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24473467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, De Mar&#xe9;es M, Koehler K, Linville J, Holmberg HC, Mester J. Effects of 5 weeks of high-intensity interval training vs volume training in 14-year-old soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(5):1271&#x2013;8. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d67c38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d67c38</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21490513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Alvarez C, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Sanchez-Sanchez J, Yanci J, Castillo D, Izquierdo M. Optimal reactive strength index: is it an accurate variable to optimize plyometric training effects on measures of physical fitness in young soccer players? J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):885&#x2013;93. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29389692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michailidis Y, Ganotakis C, Motsanos N, Metaxas T. The effects of an HIIT program on young soccer players&#x2019; physical performance. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2023;18(4):1155&#x2013;63. 10.1177/17479541221102530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541221102530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karvonen MJ, Kentala E, Mustala O. The effects of training on heart rate: a longitudinal study. Ann Med Exp Biol Fenn. 1957;35:307&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13470504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Monahan KD, Seals DR. Age-predicted maximal heart rate revisited. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001;37(1):153&#x2013;6. 10.1016/S0735-1097(00)01054-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(00)01054-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11153730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratford C, Dos&#x2019;Santos T, McMahon JJ. Comparing drop jumps with 10/5 repeated jumps to measure reactive strength index. Prof Strength Cond. 2020;57:23&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markwick WJ, Bird SP, Tufano JJ, Seitz LB, Haff GG. The intraday reliability of the reactive strength index calculated from a drop jump in professional men&#x2019;s basketball. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(4):482&#x2013;8. 10.1123/ijspp.2014-0265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2014-0265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25394213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie K, Carson BP, Lyons M, Kenny IC. The relationship between maximal strength and reactive strength. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):548&#x2013;53. 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southey B, Connick MJ, Spits D, Austin D, Beckman E. Determining interday and intraday reliability of the 10/5 repeated jump test in elite Australian footballers. Int J Strength Cond. 2023;3(1). 10.47206/ijsc.v3i1.181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan EP, Ebben WP, Jensen RL. Reliability of the reactive strength index and time to stabilization during depth jumps. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(5):1677&#x2013;82. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318182034b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318182034b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Silva AF, Clemente FM, Siahkouhian M, Garc&#xed;a-Gordillo M&#xc1;, Adsuar JC, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J. Analysis of fitness status variations of under-16 soccer players over a season and their relationships with maturational status and training load. Front Physiol. 2021;11:597697. 10.3389/fphys.2020.597697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.597697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aky&#xfc;z M, &#xd6;zmaden M, Do&#x11f;ru Y, Karademir E, Ayd&#x131;n Y, Hayta &#xdc;. Gen&#xe7; basketbolcularda Statik ve Dinamik germe Egzersizlerinin baz&#x131; Fiziksel parametrelere Etkisi. J Hum Sci. 2017;14(2):1492&#x2013;500. 10.14687/jhs.v14i2.4560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14687/jhs.v14i2.4560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor A, Karaka&#x15f; F, Mor H, Yurtseven R, Y&#x131;lmaz AK, Acar K. Gen&#xe7; futbolcularda diren&#xe7; band&#x131; Egzersizlerinin baz&#x131; performans parametrelerine Etkisi. Spormetre Beden Egitim Spor Bilim Derg. 2022;20(1):128&#x2013;42. 10.33689/spormetre.1095371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33689/spormetre.1095371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan T. Farkl&#x131; &#x131;s&#x131;nma Protokollerinin Eklem Hareket geni&#x15f;li&#x11f;i, s&#x131;&#xe7;rama ve sprint performans&#x131;na Etkisi. OPUS Int J Soc Res. 2019;13(20):621&#x2013;35. 10.26466/opus.574260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26466/opus.574260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Jones PA, Suchomel TJ, Lake J, Comfort P. Influence of the reactive strength index modified on force- and power-time curves. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(2):220&#x2013;7. 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28605214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nay&#x131;ro&#x11f;lu S, Y&#x131;lmaz AK, Silva AF, Silva R, Nobari H, Clemente FM. Effects of small-sided games and running-based high-intensity interval training on body composition and physical fitness in under-19 female soccer players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2022;14(1):119. 10.1186/s13102-022-00516-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-022-00516-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9238068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akg&#xfc;l M&#x15e;, Koz M, G&#xfc;rses VV, K&#xfc;rk&#xe7;&#xfc; R. Y&#xfc;ksek &#x15f;iddetli interval Antrenman. Spormetre Beden Egitim Spor Bilim Derg. 2017;15(2):39&#x2013;46. 10.1501/Sporm_0000000306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1501/Sporm_0000000306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, C&#xe1;mara-P&#xe9;rez JC, Soto-Hermoso VM, Latorre-Rom&#xe1;n P&#xc1;. A high intensity interval training (HIIT)-based running plan improves athletic performance by improving muscle power. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(1):146&#x2013;53. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27172268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;kkurt K, K&#x131;vrak AO. The effect of high intensity interval training during eight weeks on speed, agility, and acceleration in U19 soccer players. Pak J Med Health Sci. 2021;15(8):2390&#x2013;5. 10.53350/pjmhs211582390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53350/pjmhs211582390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong PL, Chaouachi A, Chamari K, Dellal A, Wisloff U. Effect of preseason concurrent muscular strength and high-intensity interval training in professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(3):653&#x2013;60. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181aa36a2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181aa36a2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19816215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stankovi&#x107; M, Trajkovi&#x107; N, Ma&#x10d;ak D, &#x110;or&#x111;evi&#x107; D, Lazi&#x107; A, Milanovi&#x107; Z. Effects of linear and change of direction high-intensity interval training on physical performance of elite female soccer players. Biol Sport. 2024;41(4):31&#x2013;9. 10.5114/biolsport.2024.134761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.134761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11475003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Nassis GP, Rebelo A. Strength training in soccer with a specific focus on highly trained players. Sports Med Open. 2015;1(1):17. 10.1186/s40798-015-0006-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-015-0006-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26284158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schache AG, Dorn TW, Blanch PD, Brown N, Pandy MG. Mechanics of the human hamstring muscles during sprinting. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(4):647&#x2013;58. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318236a3d2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318236a3d2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21912301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorn TW, Schache AG, Pandy MG. Muscular strategy shift in human running: dependence of running speed on hip and ankle muscle performance. J Exp Biol. 2012;215(11):1944&#x2013;56. 10.1242/jeb.064527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.064527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22573774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short S, Short G, Lehman G, Friesen J, Johnson B. A critical review of trunk and hip exercise prescription: applying evidence for a modern approach. Int J Sports Phys Therapy. 2025;20(3):448&#x2013;75. 10.26603/001c.129972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.129972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11872577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40041532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsartsapakis I, Zafeiroudi A, Trigonis I, Lyrtzis C, Astrapellos K. Development and implementation of a core training protocol: effects on muscle activation, hypertrophy, balance, and quality of life in recreationally active adults. Methods Protocols. 2025;8:77. 10.3390/mps8040077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mps8040077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12286126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40700315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin JB, Samozino P. Interpreting power&#x2013;force&#x2013;velocity profiles for individualized and specific training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(2):267&#x2013;72. 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Samozino P, Martinez-Ruiz E, Brughelli M, Schmikli S, Morin JB, Mendez-Villanueva A. Progression of mechanical properties during on-field sprint running after returning to sport from a hamstring muscle injury in soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(8):690&#x2013;5. 10.1055/s-0033-1363192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1363192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24424959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to endurance and strength training. Cold Spring Harbor Perspect Med. 2018;8(6):a029769. 10.1101/cshperspect.a029769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a029769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chmura P, Chmura J, Chodor W, Dro&#x17c;d&#x17c;owski A, Rokita A, Konefa&#x142; M. The effects of high-intensity interval training at the anaerobic and psychomotor fatigue thresholds on physiological parameters in young soccer players: a prospective study. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1221121. 10.3389/fphys.2023.1221121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1221121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10513167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37745255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AJ, Singh LS, Mola DW. Effect of interval training on selected motor abilities of youth football players. Slobozhanskyi her Sci Sport. 2025;29(2):167&#x2013;75. 10.15391/snsv.2025-2.07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15391/snsv.2025-2.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Keihaniyan A, EatemadyBoroujeni A, Oftade A, Takhsha S, Asadi A, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of heart rate vs speed-based high-intensity interval training on aerobic and anaerobic capacity of female soccer players. Sports (Basel). 2017;5(3):57. 10.3390/sports5030057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports5030057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota T, Afonso J, S&#xe1; M, Clemente FM. An agility training continuum for team sports: from cones and ladders to small-sided games. Strength Cond J. 2022;44(1):46&#x2013;56. 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaouachi A, Chtara M, Hammami R, Chtara H, Turki O, Castagna C. Multidirectional sprints and small-sided games training effect on agility and change of direction abilities in youth soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(11):3121&#x2013;7. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25148467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajrin F, Kusnanik NW. Effects of high intensity interval training on increasing explosive power, speed, and agility. J Phys Conf Ser. 2018;947:012045. 10.1088/1742-6596/947/1/012045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/947/1/012045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munandar RA, Setijono H, Kusnanik NW. The effect of Tabata training and high-intensity interval training on agility improvement. Int J Soc Sci Humanit Res. 2022;4(2):281&#x2013;3. 10.47191/ijsshr/v5-i1-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47191/ijsshr/v5-i1-37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabdwal MC, Pal S, Poonia R. Effect of periodized interval training in combination with explosive strength and speed in game-like situation on agility and high-intensity aerobic capacity of youth soccer players. Phys Educ Theory Methodol. 2023;23(4):716&#x2013;21. 10.17309/tmfv.2023.5.09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17309/tmfv.2023.5.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambright KR, Bunn JA, Figueroa Y, Mu&#xf1;oz M. Resistance training versus interval training in female youth soccer players. Women Sport Phys Act J. 2024;32(1):1. 10.1123/wspaj.2024-0076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/wspaj.2024-0076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleksy &#x141;, Mika A, Kuchciak M, Stolarczyk A, Adamska O, Szczud&#x142;o M, Kielnar R, Wola&#x144;ski P, Deszczy&#x144;ski JM, Reichert P. Relationship between countermovement jump and sprint performance in professional football players. J Clin Med. 2024;13(15):4581. 10.3390/jcm1315458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm1315458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11312931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39124847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen X, Song F, Yang L, Xu Q. Small-sided soccer games promote greater adaptations on vertical jump and change-of-direction deficit and similar adaptations in aerobic capacity than high-intensity interval training in females. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(2):445. 10.52082/jssm.2024.445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11149063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38841638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>