<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41432641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Soy Pretzel Consumption on Blood Biomarkers and Muscle Soreness After Intense Resistance Exercise in Healthy, Trained Males: A Preliminary Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>422</StartPage><EndPage>430</EndPage><MedlinePgn>422-430</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005348</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>McClure, J, Sommer, A, Kraemer, WJ, and Vodovotz, Y. Effects of soy pretzel consumption on blood biomarkers and muscle soreness after intense resistance exercise in healthy, trained males: a preliminary study. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 422-430, 2026-Intense resistance exercise can cause exercise-induced muscle damage (EIMD), resulting in inflammation and muscle soreness. Soy protein and its isoflavones have been hypothesized to reduce inflammation, enhance antioxidant capacity, and support recovery. This preliminary study examined the effects of a soy soft pretzel (SSP) on soreness and biomarkers of EIMD. Ten trained male athletes aged 19-29 years completed a double-blind, randomized, crossover trial with either SSP or a wheat pretzel (control). Muscle soreness was measured using a visual analog scale, and blood samples were analyzed for markers of inflammation and muscle damage. Urinary isoflavones were measured to confirm compliance. Serum testosterone was notably lower after SSP (14.54 &#xb1; 5.07 nmol&#xb7;L -1 ) than wheat (16.35 &#xb1; 5.76 nmol&#xb7;L -1 ; p = 0.0072; d = -0.60). Although interleukin-6 levels declined more quickly starting at 6 hours in the SSP group ( d &#x2248; -0.50), this difference was not statistically significant. Urinary daidzein, genistein, and glycitein levels were all significantly higher ( p &lt; 0.001, 0.011, and 0.011; d &gt; 1.0), indicating absorption of soy isoflavones. Soreness ratings showed no significant difference between treatments, likely because of high individual variability ( d &lt; 0.20). These results suggest that while soy pretzel intake affects hormonal and isoflavone responses, its impact on soreness and inflammatory markers remains uncertain and requires further study with larger, adequately powered samples. Practically, soy-based recovery snacks could be a convenient, athlete-friendly option that is generally well tolerated; however, coaches and sports nutritionists should interpret these findings as preliminary until more definitive evidence becomes available.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClure</LastName><ForeName>Jenna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Functional Food, Research and Entrepreneurship, Department of Food Science and Technology, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sommer</LastName><ForeName>Abigail</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Functional Food, Research and Entrepreneurship, Department of Food Science and Technology, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kraemer</LastName><ForeName>William J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vodovotz</LastName><ForeName>Yael</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Functional Food, Research and Entrepreneurship, Department of Food Science and Technology, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>OSC 19-D-38</GrantID><Agency>Ohio Soybean Council</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007529">Isoflavones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D030262">Soybean Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007529" MajorTopicYN="N">Isoflavones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000652" MajorTopicYN="N">urine</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045730" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soy Foods</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030262" MajorTopicYN="N">Soybean Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41432641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription (7th ed.). Lippincott, Williams &amp; Wilkins: Philadelphia, PA, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azadbakht L, Kimiagar M, Mehrabi Y, et al. Soy consumption, markers of inflammation, and endothelial function: A cross-over study in postmenopausal women with the metabolic syndrome. Diabetes Care 30: 967&#x2013;973, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bieber S, Jefferson J. Chapter 12-Rhabdomyolysis. In: Nephrology Secrets (4th ed.), 2019. pp. 89&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongiovanni T, Yin MOL, Heaney L. The athlete and gut microbiome: Short-chain fatty acids as potential ergogenic aids for exercise and training. Int J Sports Med 42: 1143&#x2013;1158, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown MA, Stevenson EJ, Howatson G. Whey protein hydrolysate supplementation accelerates recovery from exercise-induced muscle damage in females. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 43: 324&#x2013;330, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley JD, Thomson RL, Coates AM, et al. Supplementation with a whey protein hydrolysate enhances recovery of muscle force-generating capacity following eccentric exercise. J Sci Med Sport 13: 178&#x2013;181, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buell JL, Franks R, Ransone J, et al. National Athletic Trainers&#x2019; Association position statement: Evaluation of dietary supplements for performance nutrition. J Athl Train 48: 124&#x2013;136, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira &#xc9;, Marinho DA, Neiva HP, Louren&#xe7;o O. Inflammatory effects of high and moderate intensity exercise&#x2014;A systematic review. Front Physiol 10: 1550, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crouse JR III, Morgan T, Terry JG, et al. A randomized trial comparing the effect of casein with that of soy protein containing varying amounts of isoflavones on plasma concentrations of lipids and lipoproteins. Arch Int Med 159: 2070&#x2013;2076, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos Ferreira D, Toscano LT, Cabral T, et al. Effect of carbohydrates versus carbohydrates plus proteins and antioxidants on oxidative stress and muscle damage induced by single bout resistance exercise. Sport Sci Health 14: 387&#x2013;392, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Droke EA, Hager KA, Lerner MR, et al. Soy isoflavones avert chronic inflammation-induced bone loss and vascular disease. J Inflamm 4: 17&#x2013;12, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdman J. AHA science advisory: Soy protein and cardiovascular disease: A statement for healthcare professionals from the Nutrition Committee of the AHA. Circulation 102: 2555&#x2013;2559, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Pedersen BK. Muscle-derived interleukin-6: Mechanisms for activation and possible biological roles. FASEB J 16: 1335&#x2013;1347, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedewa MV, Hathaway ED, Ward-Ritacco CL. Effect of exercise training on C reactive protein: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised and non-randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med 51: 670&#x2013;676, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennigar SR, McClung JP, Pasiakos SM. Nutritional interventions and the IL-6 response to exercise. FASEB J 31: 3719&#x2013;3728, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper L, Ryder JJ, Kurzer MS, et al. Effects of soy protein and isoflavones on circulating hormone concentrations in pre- and post-menopausal women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod Update 15: 423&#x2013;440, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper DR, Kraemer WJ, Focht BC, et al. Endocrinological roles for testosterone in resistance exercise responses and adaptations. Sports Med 47: 1709&#x2013;1720, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ives SJ, Bloom S, Matias A, et al. Effects of a combined protein and antioxidant supplement on recovery of muscle function and soreness following eccentric exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 14: 21, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kami&#x144;ski M, Skonieczna-&#x17b;ydecka K, Nowak JK, Stachowska E. Global and local diet popularity rankings, their secular trends, and seasonal variation in google trends data. Nutrition 79&#x2013;80: 110759, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Jagim A, Hagele A, J&#xe4;ger R. Plant proteins and exercise: What role can plant proteins have in promoting adaptations to exercise? Nutrients 13: 1962, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Lee J. A review of nutritional intervention on delayed onset muscle soreness. Part I. J Exerc Rehabil 10: 349&#x2013;356, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Wagenmakes A, Manders R, et al. Combined ingestion of protein and free leucine with carbohydrate increases postexercise muscle protein synthesis in vivo in male subjects. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 288: 6&#x2013;653, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC. Recovery responses of testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol 122: 549&#x2013;558, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattimer JM, Haub MD. Effects of dietary fiber and its components on metabolic health. Nutrients 2: 1266&#x2013;1289, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP, Pasiakos S. The role of exercising muscle length in the protective adaptation to a single bout of eccentric exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 93: 286&#x2013;293, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-Canoves P, Scheele C, Pedersen BK, Serrano AL. Interleukin-6 myokine signaling in skeletal muscle: A double edged sword? FEBS J 280: 4131&#x2013;4148, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Gillitt ND, Sha W, Esposito D, Ramamoorthy S. Metabolic recovery from heavy exertion following banana compared to sugar beverage or water only ingestion: A randomized, crossover trial. PLoS One 13: e0194843, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M, Sacco P. Delayed-onset muscle soreness does not reflect the magnitude of eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports 12: 337&#x2013;346, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien MT, O'Sullivan O, Claesson MJ, Cotter PD. The athlete gut microbiome and its relevance to health and performance: A review. Sports Med 52: 119&#x2013;128, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake JM, Neubauer O, Della Gatta PA, Nosaka K. Muscle damage and inflammation during recovery from exercise. J Appl Physiol 122: 559&#x2013;570, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire: PAR-Q &amp; You. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenburg JB, Bar PR, De Boer RW. Relations between muscle soreness and biochemical and functional outcomes of eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol 74: 2976&#x2013;2983, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Does exercise-induced muscle damage play A role in skeletal muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res 26: 1441&#x2013;1453, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenoy S, Dhawan M, Singh SJ. Four weeks of supplementation with isolated soy protein attenuates exercise-induced muscle damage and enhances muscle recovery in well trained athletes: A randomized trial. Asian J Sports Med 7: e33528, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slavin J. Nutritional benefits of soy protein and soy fiber. J Am Diet Assoc 91: 816&#x2013;819, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solak BB, Akin N. Health benefits of whey protein: A review. J Food Sci Eng 2: 129&#x2013;137, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer A, Vodovotz Y. Soy enhanced soft pretzels designed for exercise recovery. J Funct Foods 94: 105109, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer AA. Effect of Soy Addition to Soft Pretzels on Product Quality, Acceptability, and Satiety in Active and Less Active Populations: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorichter S, Mair J, Koller A, et al. Skeletal troponin I as a marker of exercise-induced muscle damage. J Appl Physiol 83: 1076&#x2013;1082, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stipanuk MH. Biochemical, Physiological, &amp; Molecular Aspects of Human Nutrition (2nd ed), 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR, Gordon NF, Liguori G. ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription (Vol. 10). Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tourville T, Connolly D, Reed B. Effects of sensory-level high-volt pulsed electrical current on delayed-onset muscle soreness. J Sports Sci 24: 941&#x2013;949, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Z, Cholewa JM, Dardevet D, et al. Effects of oat protein supplementation on skeletal muscle damage, inflammation and performance recovery following downhill running in untrained collegiate men. Food Funct 9: 4720&#x2013;4729, 2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Bi X, Yu B, Chen D. Isoflavones: Anti-inflammatory benefit and possible caveats. Nutrients 8: 361, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Veliky CV, Birru RL, et al. Potential protective effects of equol (Soy isoflavone metabolite) on coronary heart diseases&#x2014;From molecular mechanisms to studies in humans. Nutrients 13: 3739, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuniga KE, Clinton SK, Erdman JW Jr. The interactions of dietary tomato powder and soy germ on prostate carcinogenesis in the TRAMP model. Cancer Prev Res 6: 548&#x2013;557, 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>