<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41326630</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics of continental shale reservoirs in the Xuanhua Basin of Yanshan area and their influence on gas-bearing properties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>842</StartPage><MedlinePgn>842</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">842</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-30550-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The continental shale of the Jurassic Xiahuayuan Formation in the Xuanhua Basin of the Yanshan area displays widespread occurrence and notable thickness, indicating good potential for industrial-scale shale gas production. However, there are still many uncertainties regarding the characteristics of shale reservoirs, their gas-bearing properties, and the main controlling factors. To characterize the Xiahuayuan Formation shale, this study employed total organic carbon (TOC) analysis, X-ray diffraction (XRD), low-temperature N<sub>2</sub> adsorption (LTN<sub>2</sub>A), and in-situ gas content measurement to systematically investigate organic matter (OM) composition, reservoir properties, and gas occurrence characteristics. Moreover, the principal influencing factors of the gas-bearing characteristics were discussed. The results indicate that the Xiahuayuan Formation shale exhibits relatively high TOC content and is in the mature to high-mature stage. The OM type is mainly Type &#x2162; kerogen, providing a favorable foundation for the formation and storage of shale gas. The in-situ desorption gas content is predominantly composed of free gas. Both the adsorbed and free gas contents gradually increase as burial depth increases. Shale gas content is influenced by multiple geological factors. Among them, the TOC is conducive to hydrocarbon generation in shale. It promotes the development of OM pores, increases pore volume (PV) and specific surface area (SSA), and thus shows a positive correlation with various gas contents. As R<sub>o</sub> increases, both the hydrocarbon adsorption capacity and the ability to store free gas are enhanced. In addition, quartz has a remarkable resistance to compaction and can effectively protect the pore structure. When its content is relatively high, it tends to have a slight positive relationship with various gas contents. Conversely, carbonate minerals, by filling the original pores and microfractures, show a negative association with various gas contents. In contrast, clay minerals contribute to the formation of numerous secondary pores and show a positive correlation with various gas contents. The pore structure of shale primarily consists of mesopores and micropores. An increase in micropore volume leads to a reduction in the average pore size (APS), promoting an increase in SSA and PV, and further enhancing the adsorption capacity and storage space of shale. This research are intended to offer a robust geological foundation for future exploration and development efforts related to continental shale gas resources.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Civil Engineering, Suzhou University, Suzhou, 234000, China. jiangwei3q@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Coalbed Methane Development and Mining Area Environmental Remediation of Suzhou, School of Resources and Civil Engineering, Suzhou University, Suzhou, 234000, China. jiangwei3q@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Jiasheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Civil Engineering, Suzhou University, Suzhou, 234000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Wenheng</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Civil Engineering, Suzhou University, Suzhou, 234000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Civil Engineering, Suzhou University, Suzhou, 234000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Hengyuan Coal and Electricity Group Company Limited, Renlou Coal Mine, Huaibei, 235123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024PT04</GrantID><Agency>scientific research platform project of Suzhou University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024AH051809</GrantID><Agency>University Natural Science Research Project of Anhui Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023xhx074, 2025xhx055</GrantID><Agency>Wei Jiang, horizontal research project of Suzhou University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202510379056</GrantID><Agency>College Students' innovation and entrepreneurship training program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Continental shale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gas-bearing properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Main controlling factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xiahuayuan formation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xuanhua basin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41326630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12779971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-30550-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-30550-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zou, C. et al. Development progress, potential and prospect of shale gas in China. <i>Nat. Gas. Ind.</i><b>41</b>, 1&#x2013;14. 10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2021.01.001 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2021.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X. et al. Geological characteristics, resource potential, and development direction of shale gas in China. <i>Petrol. Explor. Dev.</i><b>52</b>, 17&#x2013;32. 10.1016/S1876-3804(25)60002-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(25)60002-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, C. et al. Advances, challenges, and countermeasures in shale gas exploration of underexplored plays, sequences and new types in China. <i>Oil Gas Geol.</i><b>45</b>, 309&#x2013;326. 10.11743/ogg20240201 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11743/ogg20240201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Comparison of exploration and development history, geological characteristics and exploitation conditions of shale gas in China and the United States and its enlightenment. <i>Acta Pet. Sin.</i><b>43</b>, 1687. 10.7623/syxb202212002 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7623/syxb202212002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz, B. &amp; Lin, F. Lacustrine basin unconventional resource plays: Key differences. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>56</b>, 255&#x2013;265. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2014.02.013 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2014.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, T. et al. Factors controlling differential enrichment of organic matter in saline lacustrine rift basin: A case study of third member Shahejie Fm in Dongpu depression. <i>Acta Sedimentol. Sin.</i><b>39</b>, 140&#x2013;152. 10.14027/j.issn.1000-0550.2020.125 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14027/j.issn.1000-0550.2020.125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Sedimentary depositional environment and organic matter enrichment mechanism of lacustrine black shales: A case study of the Chang 7 member in the Ordos Basin. <i>Acta Sedimentol. Sin.</i><b>41</b>, 1810&#x2013;1829. 10.14027/j.issn.1000-0550.2023.118 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14027/j.issn.1000-0550.2023.118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X., L&#xfc;, X., Shen, Y., Guo, S. &amp; Guan, Y. A modified supercritical Dubinin-Radushkevich model for the accurate estimation of high pressure methane adsorption on shales. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>193</b>, 1&#x2013;15. 10.1016/j.coal.2018.04.008 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2018.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrose, R. J., Hartman, R. C., Diaz-Campos, M., Akkutlu, I. Y. &amp; Sondergeld, C. H. Shale gas-in-place calculations part I: new pore-scale considerations. <i>Spe J.</i><b>17</b>, 219&#x2013;229. 10.2118/131772-PA (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/131772-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q., Ewing, R. P. &amp; Rowe, H. D. Low nanopore connectivity limits gas production in Barnett formation.. <i>J. Geophys. Res. Sol. Ea.</i><b>120</b>, 8073&#x2013;8087. 10.1002/2015JB012103 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2015JB012103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, H., Li, T., Zhang, T. &amp; Xiao, X. Characterization of methane adsorption on overmature Lower Silurian-Upper Ordovician shales in Sichuan Basin, southwest China: Experimental results and geological implications. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>156</b>, 36&#x2013;49. 10.1016/j.coal.2016.01.013 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2016.01.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, Y., Xiao, X., Zhou, Q., Liu, W. &amp; Zhao, Y. Influence of water on the methane adsorption capacity of organic-rich shales and its controlling factors: A review. <i>Energies</i><b>16</b>, 3305. 10.3390/en16083305 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16083305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q. et al. Occurrence features and gas content analysis of marine and continental shales: A comparative study of Longmaxi Formation and Yanchang Formation. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>56</b>, 504&#x2013;522. 10.1016/j.jngse.2018.06.019 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2018.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi, H. et al. Adsorptioncharacteristic and influence factors of Longmaxi shale in southeastern Chongqing. <i>Nat. Gas. Geosci.</i><b>25</b>(2), 302&#x2013;310 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparik, M. et al. Geological controls on the methane storage capacity in organic-rich shales. <i>Int. J. Coal. Geol.</i><b>123</b>, 34&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.coal.2013.06.010 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2013.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Su, S. &amp; Zhang, G. Early Mesozoic basin development in North China: Indications of cratonic deformation. <i>J. Asian Earth Sci.</i><b>62</b>, 221&#x2013;236. 10.1016/j.jseaes.2012.09.011 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2012.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorin, Y. A. et al. The east Siberia transect. <i>Int. Geol. Rev.</i><b>37</b>, 154&#x2013;175. 10.1080/00206819509465398 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00206819509465398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Gurnis, M., Ma, P. &amp; Zhang, B. Reconstruction of northeast Asian deformation integrated with western Pacific plate subduction since 200 Ma. <i>Earth-Sci. Rev.</i><b>175</b>, 114&#x2013;142. 10.1016/j.earscirev.2017.10.012 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2017.10.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, J. et al. Molecular and carbon isotopic variation during canister degassing of terrestrial shale: A case study from Xiahuayuan formation in the Xuanhua Basin, North China. <i>Minerals.</i><b>11</b>(8), 843. 10.3390/min11080843 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min11080843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Q., Dong, T., He, S. &amp; Zhai, G. Methane adsorption capacity of marine-continental transitional facies shales: The case study of the Upper Permian Longtan Formation, northern Guizhou Province, Southwest China. <i>J. Petrol. Sci. Eng.</i><b>183</b>, 106406. 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106406 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y. et al. The organic geochemistry, pore structure and methane adsorption/storage capacity of lacustrine shales from the Cretaceous Madongshan Formation, Liupanshan Basin, China. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>96</b>, 104287. 10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104287 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gai, H. et al. Characteristics of molecular nitrogen generation from overmature black shales in South China: Preliminary implications from pyrolysis experiments. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>120</b>, 104527. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2020.104527 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2020.104527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Liu, Z., Chen, F.-R., Zhang, K. &amp; Tang, L. Behavior and controlling factors of methane adsorption in Jurassic continental shale, northeastern Sichuan Basin. <i>Energy Geosci.</i><b>4</b>, 83&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.engeos.2022.08.007 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engeos.2022.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, D. et al. Progress on sedimentology of transitional facies shales and new discoveries of shale gas. <i>Acta Sedimentol. Sin.</i><b>39</b>, 29&#x2013;45 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Ellis, G. S., Ruppel, S. C., Milliken, K. &amp; Yang, R. Effect of organic-matter type and thermal maturity on methane adsorption in shale-gas systems. <i>Org. Geochem.</i><b>47</b>, 120&#x2013;131. 10.1016/j.orggeochem.2012.03.012 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orggeochem.2012.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, D. et al. Basic characteristics and accumulation rules of shale gas in coal measures. <i>Coal Geol. Explor.</i><b>42</b>, 6. 10.3969/j.issn.1001-1986.2014.04.006 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1001-1986.2014.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, G. et al. Critical factors controlling adsorption capacity of shale gas in Wufeng-Longmaxi formation, Sichuan Basin: evidences from both experiments and molecular simulations. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>88</b>, 103774. 10.1016/j.jngse.2018.06.019 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2018.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, D. et al. Comparison of marine and continental shale gas reservoirs and their gas-bearing properties in China: The examples of the Longmaxi and Shahezi shales. <i>Energy Fuels</i><b>35</b>, 4029&#x2013;4043. 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c04245 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c04245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Pore structure evolution and geological controls in lacustrine shale systems with implications for marine shale reservoir characterization. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 17702. 10.1038/s41598-025-02415-y (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02415-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12095546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40399384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. Pore structure and heterogeneity of shale gas reservoirs and its effect on gas storage capacity in the Qiongzhusi formation. <i>Geosci. Front.</i><b>12</b>, 101244. 10.1016/j.gsf.2021.101244 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2021.101244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapp, L. J. et al. The influence of rigid matrix minerals on organic porosity and pore size in shale reservoirs: Upper Devonian Duvernay Formation, Alberta, Canada. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>227</b>, 103525. 10.1016/j.coal.2020.103525 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2020.103525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Cheng, H., Hu, Q., Liu, L. &amp; Hao, L. Diagenesis and pore evolution for various lithofacies of the Wufeng-Longmaxi shale, southern Sichuan Basin China. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>133</b>, 105251. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2021.105251 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2021.105251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Pore development of the Lower Longmaxi shale in the southeastern Sichuan Basin and its adjacent areas: Insights from lithofacies identification and organic matter. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>122</b>, 104662. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2020.104662 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2020.104662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, A. et al. Variations of pore structure in organic-rich shales with different lithofacies from the Jiangdong block, fuling shale gas field, SW China: Insights into gas storage and pore evolution. <i>Energy Fuels</i><b>34</b>, 12457&#x2013;12475. 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c02529 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c02529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks, R. G., Reed, R. M., Ruppel, S. C. &amp; Hammes, U. Spectrum of pore types and networks in mudrocks and a descriptive classification for matrix-related mudrock pores. <i>AAPG Bull.</i><b>96</b>, 1071&#x2013;1098. 10.1306/08171111061 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1306/08171111061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, E. et al. Exploration potential of different lithofacies of deep marine shale gas systems: Insight into organic matter accumulation and pore formation mechanisms. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>102</b>, 104563. 10.1016/j.jngse.2022.104563 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2022.104563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Er, C. et al. Characteristics and occurrence mechanism of organicrich shale in the Triassic Yanchang Formation, Ordos Basin, China. <i>Nat. Gas Geosci.</i><b>27</b>, 1202&#x2013;1214. 10.11764/j.issn.1672-1926.2016.07.1202 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11764/j.issn.1672-1926.2016.07.1202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, P. H. Pore-throat sizes in sandstones, tight sandstones, and shales. <i>AAPG Bull.</i><b>93</b>, 329&#x2013;340. 10.1306/10240808059 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1306/10240808059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, E. D. et al. Accumulation condition and shale gas potential of the marine-terrestrial transitional facies: a case study of Jinshacan 1 well of Longtan Formation in northern Guizhou. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>49</b>, 1166&#x2013;1181. 10.13247/j.cnki.jcumt.001184 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13247/j.cnki.jcumt.001184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J., Zhang, A., Li, J., Shang, D. &amp; Zhou, X. Study on microscale pore structure and bedding fracture characteristics of shale oil reservoir. <i>Energy</i><b>278</b>, 127829. 10.1016/j.energy.2023.127829 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sing, K. S. W. Reporting physisorption data for gas/solid systems with special reference to the determination of surface area and porosity (Recommendations 1984). <i>Pure Appl. Chem.</i><b>57</b>, 603&#x2013;619. 10.1351/pac198557040603 (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1351/pac198557040603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Liu, S., Yan, X., Tang, X. &amp; Liu, Y. Evaluation of gas content in shale. <i>Oil Gas Geol</i><b>42</b>, 28&#x2013;40 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, L. T., Loucks, R. G., Zhang, T., Ruppel, S. C. &amp; Shao, D. Pore and pore network evolution of Upper Cretaceous Boquillas (Eagle Ford&#x2013;equivalent) mudrocks: Results from gold tube pyrolysis experiments. <i>AAPG Bull.</i><b>100</b>, 1693&#x2013;1722. 10.1306/04151615092 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1306/04151615092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y. &amp; Guo, S. Characterization of whole-aperture pore structure and its effect on methane adsorption capacity for transitional shales. <i>Energy Fuels</i><b>32</b>, 3176&#x2013;3188. 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.7b03807 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.7b03807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, F. et al. Lithofacies and reservoir characteristics of the lower cretaceous continental shahezi shale in the changling fault depression of Songliao Basin, NE China. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>98</b>, 401&#x2013;421. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2018.08.035 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2018.08.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, W. et al. Analyses of the characteristics and main controlling factors for the micro/nanopores in Niutitang shale from China&#x2019;s southeastern Chongqing and northern Guizhou regions. <i>Earth Sci. Front.</i><b>26</b>, 220 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, T. et al. Pore formation and evolution of organic-rich shale during the entire hydrocarbon generation process: Examination of artificially and naturally matured samples. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>93</b>, 104020. 10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104020 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenger, B. et al. Formation, preservation and connectivity control of organic pores in shale. <i>Petrol. Explor. Dev.</i><b>48</b>, 798&#x2013;812. 10.1016/S1876-3804(21)60067-8 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(21)60067-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, H., Jia, W., Peng, P., Zeng, J. &amp; He, R. Evolution of organic matter and nanometer-scale pores in an artificially matured shale undergoing two distinct types of pyrolysis: A study of the Yanchang Shale with Type II kerogen. <i>Org. Geochem.</i><b>105</b>, 56&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.orggeochem.2017.01.004 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orggeochem.2017.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klewiah, I., Berawala, D. S., Walker, H. C. A., Andersen, P. &#xd8;. &amp; Nadeau, P. H. Review of experimental sorption studies of CO<sub>2</sub> and CH<sub>4</sub> in shales. <i>J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng.</i><b>73</b>, 103045. 10.1016/j.jngse.2019.103045 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2019.103045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, H., Zhou, W., Zhang, R., Liu, S. &amp; Zhou, Q. Characterizations of pore, mineral and petrographic properties of marine shale using multiple techniques and their implications on gas storage capability for Sichuan Longmaxi gas shale field in China. <i>Fuel</i><b>241</b>, 360&#x2013;371. 10.1016/j.fuel.2018.12.035 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2018.12.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, Y. et al. Effect of pore structure on methane sorption potential of shales. <i>Petrol. Explor. Dev.</i><b>41</b>, 272&#x2013;281. 10.1016/S1876-3804(14)60033-1 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(14)60033-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Mineral types and organic matters of the Ordovician-Silurian Wufeng and Longmaxi Shale in the Sichuan Basin, China: Implications for pore systems, diagenetic pathways, and reservoir quality in fine-grained sedimentary rocks. <i>Mar. Petrol. Geol.</i><b>86</b>, 655&#x2013;674. 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2017.06.031 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2017.06.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C., Nie, H., Zeng, C., Cheng, L. &amp; Shao, X. Shale reservoir space characteristics and the effect on gas content in Lower Palaeozoic Erathem of the eastern Sichuan Basin. <i>Acta Geol. Sin.</i><b>88</b>, 1311&#x2013;1320 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L., Tang, S. &amp; Xi, Z. Total organic carbon enrichment and its impact on pore characteristics: a case study from the Niutitang Formation shales in northern Guizhou. <i>Energies</i><b>12</b>, 1480. 10.3390/en12081480 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en12081480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Z. et al. The whole-aperture pore structure characteristics and its effect on gas content of the Longmaxi Formation shale in the southeastern Sichuan Basin. <i>Earth Sci. Front.</i><b>23</b>, 126&#x2013;134 (2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>