<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41613017</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-9367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sports and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sports Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of blood flow restriction training in early postoperative rehabilitation after ACL reconstruction: a randomised controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1689257</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1689257</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1689257</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fspor.2025.1689257</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries represent the most prevalent type of knee injury, with surgical reconstruction being the prevailing treatment modality. However, postoperative pain and muscle weakness are common occurrences. Blood flow restriction (BFR) training has demonstrated potential in enhancing muscle adaptation and reducing pain; nevertheless, its efficacy in the early postoperative period following ACL reconstruction remains to be determined. The present study investigates whether the incorporation of BFR into low-load strength training confers additional clinical benefits in comparison to low-load exercise alone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 30 patients (24 male, 6 female) with a mean age of 32.3 (&#xb1; 12.4) years were included in the study. All patients had undergone primary ACL reconstruction with a semitendinosus graft and standardized fixation techniques. They were randomised to receive either low-load strength training with (LL-BFR) or without BFR (LL). The interventions consisted of four sets of leg press exercises (30 repetitions for the first set, 15 for subsequent sets) performed twice a week for four weeks, starting four weeks postoperatively, as an adjunct to standard rehabilitation protocols. The primary outcome measure was pain perception, which was assessed by pressure pain thresholds (PPT) and a visual analogue scale (VAS) for knee pain at rest and during a functional stair-climbing test. We further included strength and functional measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Mixed linear models were employed for the statistical analysis. No statistically significant differences between groups were observed for the primary or secondary outcome measures. Only, significant time effects were found for both groups for subjective pain (rest <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, stairs <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003); maximum strength (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002); active (ext. <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.035, flex. <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and passive range of motion (ROM) (ext. <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.029, flex. <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) on the affected side and International Knee Documentation Committee (IDKC) scores (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The present study shows that a combination of BFR and low-load strength training does not provide additional clinical benefits to low-load training alone in the early postoperative phase, following ACL reconstruction in our study group. Further research is required to explore the potential efficacy of BFR in specific patient subpopulations, with different training loads or at later stages of rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Barzyk, Fiedler, Schlag, Heitner, Bender and Paul.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barzyk</LastName><ForeName>Philipp</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiedler</LastName><ForeName>Carolin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlag</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heitner</LastName><ForeName>Albrecht</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bender</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Jochen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rennbahnklinik, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sports Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-9367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BFR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-load training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41613017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12847322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2025.1689257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li X, Xiao F, Ren H, Peng Y, Feng F, Dong Q. The effects of blood flow restriction training on early muscle strength and mid-term knee function following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg. (2025) 20:273. 10.1186/s13018-025-05673-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-025-05673-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11905650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40075371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renstr&#xf6;m PA. Eight clinical conundrums relating to anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury in sport: recent evidence and a personal reflection. Br J Sports Med. (2013) 47:367&#x2013;72. 10.1136/bjsports-2012-091623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22942168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todor A. Advances in anterior cruciate ligament injury, reconstruction and rehabilitation. Medicina (Mex). (2024) 60:136. 10.3390/medicina60010136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina60010136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10821448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38256396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochman M, Kasprzak M, Kielar A. ACL Reconstruction: which additional physiotherapy interventions improve early-stage rehabilitation? A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2022) 19:15893. 10.3390/ijerph192315893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192315893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9739138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36497965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh IJ, Chang CB, Seo ES, Kim SJ, Seong SC, Kim TK. Pain management by periarticular multimodal drug injection after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized, controlled study. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg Off Publ Arthrosc Assoc N Am Int Arthrosc Assoc. (2012) 28:649&#x2013;57. 10.1016/j.arthro.2011.10.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2011.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22281194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly AC, Chou R, Dettori JR, Turner JA, Friedly JL, Rundell SD, et al. 
Noninvasive nonpharmacological treatment for chronic pain: a systematic review update, AHRQ comparative effectiveness reviews. <i>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (US), Rockville (MD)</i>. (2020) 209:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanasios S, Lignos I, Kouvaras K, Moutzouri M, Gioftsos G. Low-Intensity blood flow restriction exercises modulate pain sensitivity in healthy adults: a systematic review. Healthcare. (2023) 11:726. 10.3390/healthcare11050726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11050726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10000465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36900731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaegter HB, Jones MD. Exercise-induced hypoalgesia after acute and regular exercise: experimental and clinical manifestations and possible mechanisms in individuals with and without pain. Pain Rep. (2020) 5:e823. 10.1097/PR9.0000000000000823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000000823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. (2019) 49:95&#x2013;108. 10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Grant I, Patterson SD. Aerobic exercise with blood flow restriction causes local and systemic hypoalgesia and increases circulating opioid and endocannabinoid levels. J Appl Physiol. (2021) 131:1460&#x2013;8. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00543.2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00543.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34498944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Patterson SD. The effect of blood flow restriction exercise on exercise-induced hypoalgesia and endogenous opioid and endocannabinoid mechanisms of pain modulation. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md 1985. (2020) 128:914&#x2013;24. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00768.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00768.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, Vechin FC, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Damas F, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Auckl NZ. (2018) 48:361&#x2013;78. 10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29043659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. (2015) 45:187&#x2013;200. 10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice D, Nijs J, Kosek E, Wideman T, Hasenbring MI, Koltyn K, et al. Exercise-Induced hypoalgesia in pain-free and chronic pain populations: state of the art and future directions. J Pain. (2019) 20:1249&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.jpain.2019.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpain.2019.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30904519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Exercise with blood flow restriction: an updated evidence-based approach for enhanced muscular development. Sports Med Auckl NZ. (2015) 45:313&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s40279-014-0288-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0288-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25430600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T, Bemben MG. Blood flow restriction pressure recommendations: the hormesis hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. (2014) 82:623&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.mehy.2014.02.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2014.02.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24636784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S. What phenomena do occur in blood flow-restricted muscle? Int J KAATSU Train Res. (2005) 1:37&#x2013;44. 10.3806/ijktr.1.37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.1.37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinau H-U, Biemer E, Encke A. Major Limb Replantation and Postischemia Syndrome: Investigation of Acute Ischemia-Induced Myopathy and Reperfusion Injury, Softcover Reprint of the Original 1st ed. 1988 Edition. ed. Heidelberg: Springer Berlin; (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. The effects of low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on leg muscle strength in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. (2010) 108:147&#x2013;55. 10.1007/s00421-009-1204-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1204-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Chacon-Mikahil MPT, Cavaglieri CR, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Vechin FC, et al. Effect of concurrent training with blood flow restriction in the elderly. Int J Sports Med. (2015) 36:395&#x2013;9. 10.1055/s-0034-1390496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1390496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Cross-Transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2008) 40:258. 10.1249/mss.0b013e31815c6d7e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e31815c6d7e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Kanaley JA, Ploutz-Snyder LL. Neuromuscular function following muscular unloading and blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. (2014) 114:1357&#x2013;65. 10.1007/s00421-014-2864-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-014-2864-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa J, Neto GR, Santos HH, Ara&#xfa;jo JP, Silva HG, Cirilo-Sousa MS. Effects of strength training with blood flow restriction on torque, muscle activation and local muscular endurance in healthy subjects. Biol Sport. (2017) 34:83&#x2013;90. 10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Mauch M, Paul J, Ritzmann R. Evidenz-basierte effekte von blood flow restriction training in der rehabilitation von kniearthrose und kreuzbandrupturen: ein systematisches review. Sports Orthop Traumatol, Thema: Aktuelle Themen aus der Sporttraumatologie/Current Topics from Sports Traumatology. (2020) 36:131&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.orthtr.2020.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orthtr.2020.04.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Rosenblatt B, Haddad F, Gissane C, McCarthy D, Clarke T, et al. Comparing the effectiveness of blood flow restriction and traditional heavy load resistance training in the post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: a UK national health service randomised controlled trial. Sports Med. (2019) 49:1787&#x2013;805. 10.1007/s40279-019-01137-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01137-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31301034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz RB, Gualano B, Rodrigues R, Kurimori CO, Fuller R, Lima FR, et al. Benefits of resistance training with blood flow restriction in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2018) 50:897&#x2013;905. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta H, Kurosawa H, Ikeda H, Iwase Y, Satou N, Nakamura S. Low-load resistance muscular training with moderate restriction of blood flow after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Acta Orthop Scand. (2003) 74:62&#x2013;8. 10.1080/00016470310013680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00016470310013680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12635796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal N, Williams GN, Davis MC, Wallace RB, Mikesky AE. Efficacy of blood flow-restricted, low-load resistance training in women with risk factors for symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. PM R. (2015) 7:376&#x2013;84. 10.1016/j.pmrj.2014.09.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2014.09.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4385750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25289840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira de Melo RF, Komatsu WR, de Freitas MS, Vieira de Melo ME, Cohen M. Comparison of quadriceps and hamstring muscle strength after exercises with and without blood flow restriction following anterior cruciate ligament surgery: a randomized controlled trial. J Rehabil Med. (2022) 54:jrm00337. 10.2340/jrm.v54.2550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/jrm.v54.2550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9639477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36190389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryk FF, dos Reis AC, Fingerhut D, Araujo T, Schutzer M, Cury R, et al. Exercises with partial vascular occlusion in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. (2016) 24:1580&#x2013;6. 10.1007/s00167-016-4064-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-016-4064-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26971109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran MT, Bedi A, Mendias CL, Wojtys EM, Kujawa MV, Palmieri-Smith RM. Blood flow restriction training applied with high-intensity exercise does not improve quadriceps muscle function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. (2020) 48:825&#x2013;37. 10.1177/0363546520904008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520904008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32167837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper SA, Roberts LM, Layne AS, Jaeger BC, Gardner AK, Sibille KT, et al. Blood-Flow restriction resistance exercise for older adults with knee osteoarthritis: a pilot randomized clinical trial. J Clin Med. (2019) 8:265. 10.3390/jcm8020265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm8020265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6406824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30795545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal N, Davis MD, Mikesky AE. Efficacy of blood flow-restricted low-load resistance training for quadriceps strengthening in men at risk of symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. Geriatr Orthop Surg Rehabil. (2015) 6:160&#x2013;7. 10.1177/2151458515583088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2151458515583088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4536503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26328230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack RA, Lambert BS, Hedt CA, Delgado D, Goble H, McCulloch PC. Blood flow restriction therapy preserves lower extremity bone and muscle mass after ACL reconstruction. Sports Health. (2023) 15:361&#x2013;71. 10.1177/19417381221101006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381221101006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35762124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Ishii N. Applications of vascular occlusion diminish disuse atrophy of knee extensor muscles. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2000) 32:2035. 10.1097/00005768-200012000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200012000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen E, R&#xf8;stad V, Larmo A. Intermittent blood flow restriction does not reduce atrophy following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sport Health Sci. (2016) 5:115&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.jshs.2014.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2014.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Patterson SD, Haddad F, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, McCarthy D, et al. Examination of the comfort and pain experienced with blood flow restriction training during post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: a UK national health service trial. Phys Ther Sport Off J Assoc Chart Physiother Sports Med. (2019) 39:90&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.06.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.06.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Haddad F, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Comparison of the acute perceptual and blood pressure response to heavy load and light load blood flow restriction resistance exercise in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients and non-injured populations. Phys Ther Sport. (2018) 33:54&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.07.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung W-S, Kim S-H, Nam S-S, Kim J-W, Moon H-W. Effects of rehabilitation exercise with blood flow restriction after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Appl Sci. (2022) 12:12058. 10.3390/app122312058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app122312058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil AA, Fayaz NA, Fawzy E, Mohamed NA, Waly AH, Mohammed MM. Influence of blood flow restriction training on knee pain after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a double blinded randamized controlled trial. J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol. (2023) 30:30&#x2013;8. 10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Damas FR, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Berton RPB, et al. Comparisons between low-intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training on quadriceps muscle mass and strength in elderly. J Strength Cond Res. (2015) 29:1071. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchanan HM, Midgley J-A. Evaluation of pain threshold using a simple pressure algometer. Clin Rheumatol. (1987) 6:510&#x2013;7. 10.1007/BF02330587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02330587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3449302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinser AM, Sands WA, Stone MH. Reliability and validity of a pressure algometer. J Strength Cond Res. (2009) 23:312. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31818f051c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31818f051c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu EK, Ozdincler AR. Reliability and responsiveness of algometry for measuring pressure pain threshold in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Phys Ther Sci. (2015) 27:1961&#x2013;5. 10.1589/jpts.27.1961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.27.1961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stausholm MB, Bjordal JM, Moe-Nilssen R, Naterstad IF. Pain pressure threshold algometry in knee osteoarthritis: intra- and inter-rater reliability. Physiother Theory Pract. (2023) 39:615&#x2013;22. 10.1080/09593985.2021.2023929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593985.2021.2023929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35019810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins LD, Taylor MK, Park D, Ghodadra N, Marchant M, Pietrobon R, et al. Reliability and validity of the international knee documentation committee (IKDC). Subjective Knee Form Joint Bone Spine. (2007) 74:594&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jbspin.2007.01.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2007.01.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17888709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams MA, Conway TL. Eta squared. In: Michalos AC, editor. Encyclopedia of Quality of Life and Well-Being Research. Dordrecht: Springer Netherlands; (2014). p. 1965&#x2013;6. 10.1007/978-94-007-0753-5_918</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-94-007-0753-5_918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V, Whiteley R, Epameinontidis K. Blood flow restriction induces hypoalgesia in recreationally active adult male anterior knee pain patients allowing therapeutic exercise loading. Phys Ther Sport. (2018) 32:235&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.05.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.05.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V, Whiteley R, Giakas G. Low load resistance training with blood flow restriction decreases anterior knee pain more than resistance training alone. A pilot randomised controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. (2018) 34:121&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30268966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau WY, Muthalib M, Nosaka K. Visual analog scale and pressure pain threshold for delayed onset muscle soreness assessment. J Musculoskelet Pain. (2013) 21:320&#x2013;6. 10.3109/10582452.2013.848967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10582452.2013.848967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanches ML, Juliano Y, Novo NF, Guimar&#xe3;es AS, Rodrigues Conti PC, Alonso LG. Correlation between pressure pain threshold and pain intensity in patients with temporomandibular disorders who are compliant or non-compliant with conservative treatment. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. (2015) 120:459&#x2013;68. 10.1016/j.oooo.2015.05.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oooo.2015.05.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26188733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobes &#xc1;lvarez C, Issa-Khozouz Santamar&#xed;a P, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mat&#xed;as R, Pecos-Mart&#xed;n D, Achalandabaso-Ochoa A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero S, et al. Comparison of blood flow restriction training versus non-occlusive training in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction or knee osteoarthritis. A Systematic Review J Clin Med. (2020) 10:68. 10.3390/jcm10010068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10010068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc BB, Truyens A, Heymans MJLF, Jansen EJP, Schotanus MGM. Effect of low-load blood flow restriction training after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Int J Sports Phys Ther. (2022) 17:334&#x2013;46. 10.26603/001c.33151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.33151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8975583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Q, Zhang Y, Qin J, Wu F. Effects of low-load blood flow restriction training on muscle volume after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. (2024) 12:23259671241301731. 10.1177/23259671241301731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671241301731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11645764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39678440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeitlin C, Shepherd M, Lack SD, Neal BS. Blood flow restriction training compared to conventional training in people with knee pain: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. (2025) 74:65&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2025.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2025.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40435680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz A, Bielitzki R, Behrendt T, Centner C, Behrens T, Held S, et al. Positions&#xad;papier zum blood-flow-restriction training. Bundesinstitut f&#xfc;r Sportwissenschaft (BISp). (2023) 1:50&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Bell ZW, et al. Blood flow restriction does not augment low force contractions taken to or near task failure. Eur J Sport Sci. (2020) 20:650&#x2013;9. 10.1080/17461391.2019.1664640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1664640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31486720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino G, Ugrinowitsch C, Aihara AY, Fernandes AR, Parcell AC, Ricard M, et al. Effects of strength training and vascular occlusion. Int J Sports Med. (2008) 29:664&#x2013;7. 10.1055/s-2007-989405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-989405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18213536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylwander C, Larsson I, Haglund E, Bergman S, Andersson MLE. Pressure pain thresholds in individuals with knee pain: a cross-sectional study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. (2021) 22:516. 10.1186/s12891-021-04408-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-021-04408-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8180166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Wetzstein CJ, McLafferty CL, Zuckerman PA, Landers KA, Bamman MM. High-resistance versus variable-resistance training in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2001) 33:1759&#x2013;64. 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein LF, Tricoli V, Barroso R, Rodacki A, Russo LF, Aihara L, et al. Effects of strength and power training on neuromuscular variables in older adults. J Aging Phys Act. (2012) 20:171&#x2013;85. 10.1123/japa.20.2.171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.20.2.171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22472578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Fukuda T, Uchida Y, Iida H, Meguro M, et al. Muscle size and arterial stiffness after blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2014) 24:799&#x2013;806. 10.1111/sms.12087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23730848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopewell S, Chan AW, Collins GS, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Moher D, Schulz KF, et al. CONSORT 2025 statement: updated guideline for reporting randomised trials. BMJ.. (2025) 388:e081123. 10.1136/bmj-2024-081123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2024-081123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11995449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40228833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>