<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41369593</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Force Plate-Derived Isometric Midthigh Pull Data in Girls Youth and Adult Soccer Players: A Comparison Between Age Groups.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e358</StartPage><EndPage>e365</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e358-e365</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005337</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Fahey, JT, Comfort, P, and Ripley, NJ. Force plate derived isometric mid-thigh pull data in girls youth and adult soccer players: a comparison between age groups. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): e358-e365, 2026-Expression of maximal and rapid force (i.e., force at 250 ms) is important for sporting success. Despite growing participation rates, injury risk in women soccer remains high. Furthermore, relative strength does not seem to change across age groups with no current data on rapid force production. This study was designed to report net and relative net isometric midthigh pull (IMTP) peak and rapid force for girls youth soccer players. Ninety-four youth soccer players, categorized into Foundation Development Phase (FDP; U11-U12, n = 21, 10.9 &#xb1; 0.6 years, 42.8 &#xb1; 7.6 kg, 1.49 &#xb1; 0.08 m), Youth Development Phase (YDP; U13-U15, n = 35, 13.6 &#xb1; 1.0 years, 54.8 &#xb1; 7.9 kg, 1.60 &#xb1; 0.06 m), and Professional Development Phase (PDP; n = 38, U16-U21, 16.2 &#xb1; 1.1 years, 63.4 &#xb1; 6.8 kg, 1.67 &#xb1; 0.06 m) performed the IMTP. Moderate-to-large differences were observed between FDP vs. YDP and PDP for net peak force, relative net peak force, and relative net force at 250 ms, with no differences between YDP and PDP players, respectively. Small-to-moderate increases in relative net peak force were observed between FDP vs. YDP and PDP. The results of this study highlight that maximal and rapid relative strength plateaus with increasing age. This could be problematic for players aiming to transition to senior and international standards of women's football and warrants further investigation. Practitioners should design strength and conditioning programs to enhance maximal and rapid relative strength to physically prepare youth players for the increased match-demands associated with increasing age and competition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fahey</LastName><ForeName>Jack T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Psychology and Sport, School of Health and Society, University of Salford, Salford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Football Medicine and Science, Manchester United Football Club, Carrington Training Complex, Manchester, United Kingdom ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comfort</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Psychology and Sport, School of Health and Society, University of Salford, Salford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength and Power Research Group, School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ripley</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Psychology and Sport, School of Health and Society, University of Salford, Salford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Football Medicine and Science, Manchester United Football Club, Carrington Training Complex, Manchester, United Kingdom ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013848" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thigh</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">female football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">force assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower-limb strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peak force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rapid force</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Anderson J, Magnussen P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Neural adaptation to resistance training: Changes in evoked V-wave and H-reflex responses. J Appl Physiol 92: 2309&#x2013;2318, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alt T, Knicker AJ, Severin J, Horn D, Nodler YT, Str&#xfc;der HK. Peak power assessment of isokinetic knee flexor and extensor tests&#x2014;Pitfalls of a dynamometer-based assessment. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci 24: 123&#x2013;128, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LL, Aagaard P. Influence of maximal muscle strength and intrinsic muscle contractile properties on contractile rate of force development. Eur J Appl Physiol 96: 46&#x2013;52, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LL, Andersen JL, Zebis MK, Aagaard P. Early and late rate of force development: Differential adaptive responses to resistance training? Scand J Med Sci Sports 20: e162&#x2013;e169, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong N, van Mechelen W. Interpreting exercise performance data in relation to body size. Paediatric Exercise Science and Medicine. Oxford, United Kingdom: Oxford University Press, 2008. pp. 3&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckham GK, Mizuguchi S, Carter C, et al. Relationships of isometric mid-thigh pull variables to weightlifting performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 53: 573&#x2013;581, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridges AJ, Holler KA. How many is enough? Determining optimal sample sizes for normative studies in pediatric neuropsychology. Child Neuropsychol 13: 528&#x2013;538, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brydges CR. Effect size guidelines, sample size calculations, and statistical power in gerontology. Innov Aging 3: igz036, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Dos'Santos T, Beckham GK, Stone MH, Guppy SN, Haff GG. Standardization and methodological considerations for the isometric midthigh pull. Strength Cond J 41: 57&#x2013;79, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Jones PA, McMahon JJ, Newton R. Effect of knee and trunk angle on kinetic variables during the isometric midthigh pull: Test-retest reliability. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 58&#x2013;63, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Jones PA, Thomas C, Dos&#x2019;Santos T, McMahon JJ, Suchomel TJ. Changes in early and maximal isometric force production in response to moderate- and high load strength and power training. J Strength Cond Res 36: 593&#x2013;599, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, McMahon JJ, Lake JP, Ripley NJ, Triplett NT, Haff GG. Relative strength explains the differences in multi-joint rapid force production between sexes. PLoS One 19: e0296877, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Stewart A, Bloom L, Clarkson B. Relationships between strength, sprint, and jump performance in well-trained youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 173&#x2013;177, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1582&#x2013;1598, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Witt JK, English KL, Crowell JB, et al. Isometric midthigh pull reliability and relationship to deadlift one repetition maximum. J Strength Cond Res 32: 528&#x2013;533, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Casolo A, Negro F, et al. The increase in muscle force after 4 weeks of strength training is mediated by adaptations in motor unit recruitment and rate coding. J Physiol 597: 1873&#x2013;1887, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Morris R, Murray E, Robinson C, Turner L, Jones B. The influence of age and maturity status on the maximum and explosive strength characteristics of elite youth female soccer players. Sci Med Footb 1: 209&#x2013;215, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Nicholson G, Begg C, Jones B, Bissas A. Importance of physical qualities for speed and change of direction ability in elite female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1669&#x2013;1677, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Sawczuk T, Scantlebury S, Till K, Jones B. Seasonal changes in the physical performance of elite youth female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2636&#x2013;2643, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Scantlebury S, Murray E, Turner L, Robsinon C, Jones B. Physical characteristics of elite youth female soccer players characterized by maturity status. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2321&#x2013;2328, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Till K, Redgrave J, et al. Influence of age on the anthropometric and performance characteristics of high-level youth female soccer players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 13: 779&#x2013;786, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahey J, Comfort P, Ripley NJ. Lower limb muscle strength matters: Effect of relative isometric strength on countermovement and rebound jump performance in elite youth female soccer players. Muscles 4: 23, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahey JT, Comfort P, Jones P, Ripley NJ. Effect of 6-week single leg countermovement jump training on force time metrics in elite female youth footballers. J Sports Sci: 43: 1196&#x2013;1206, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FIFA. Women's Football Member Association Survey Report. Neuchatel, Switzerland: CIES, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles G, Lutton G, Martin J. Scoping review of the isometric mid-thigh pull performance relationship to dynamic sport performance assessments. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 7: 114, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy SN, Brady CJ, Comfort P, Haff GG. The isometric mid-thigh pull: a review and methodology&#x2014;Part 1. Prof Strength Cond 51: 13&#x2013;19, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy SN, Brady CJ, Comfort P, Haff GG. The isometric mid-thigh pull: a review and methodology&#x2014;Part 2. Prof Strength Cond 51: 21&#x2013;29, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy SN, Brady CJ, Kotani Y, et al. A comparison of manual and automatic force onset identification methodologies and their effect on force-time characteristics in the isometric midthigh pull. Sports Biomech 23: 1663&#x2013;1680, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy SN, Kotani Y, Brady CJ, Connolly S, Comfort P, Haff GG. The reliability and magnitude of time-dependent force-time characteristics during the isometric midthigh pull are affected by both testing protocol and analysis choices. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1191&#x2013;1199, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Carlock JM, Hartman MJ, et al. Force-time curve characteristics of dynamic and isometric muscle actions of elite women Olympic weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res 19: 741&#x2013;748, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, et al. Force-time dependent characteristics of dynamics and isometric muscle actions. J Strength Cond Res 11: 269&#x2013;272, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagglund M, Walden M, Ekstrand J. Previous injury as a risk factor for injury in elite football: A prospective study over two consecutive seasons. Br J Sports Med 40: 767&#x2013;772, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkness-Armstrong A, Till K, Datson N, Myhill N, Emmonds S. A systematic review of match-play characteristics in women's soccer. PLoS One 17: e0268334, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Measures of reliability in sports medicine and science. Sports Med 30: 1&#x2013;15, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. A new view statistics. J Behav Brain Sci 5: 10, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PA, Thomas C, Dos'Santos T, McMahon JJ, Graham-Smith P. The role of eccentric strength in 180&#x25e6; turns in female soccer players. Sports (Basel) 5: 42, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY. Statistical notes for clinical researchers: Assessing normal distribution (2) using skewness and kurtosis. Restor Dent Endod 38: 52&#x2013;54, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larruskain J, Lekue JA, Diaz N, Odriozola A, Gil SM. A comparison of injuries in elite male and female football players: A five-season prospective study. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 237&#x2013;245, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Valenciano A, Raya-Gonzalez J, Garcia-Gomez JA, et al. Injury profile in women's football: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 51: 423&#x2013;442, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Valenciano A, Raya-Gonzalez J, Garcia-Gomez JA, et al. Response to comment on: &#x201c;injury profile in women's football: A systematic review and meta-analysis&#x201d;. Sports Med 51: 2667&#x2013;2670, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone S, Hughes B, Doran DA, Collins K, Gabbett TJ. Can the workload-injury relationship be moderated by improved strength, speed and repeated-sprint qualities? J Sci Med Sport 22: 29&#x2013;34, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Ripley NJ, Comfort P. Force plate-derived countermovement jump normative data and benchmarks for professional rugby league players. Sensors (Basel) 22, 8669, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuilliam SJ, Clark DR, Erskine RM, Brownlee TE. Free-weight resistance training in youth athletes: A narrative review. Sports Med 50: 1567&#x2013;1580, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuilliam SJ, Clark DR, Erskine RM, Brownlee TE. Mind the gap! A survey comparing current strength training methods used in men's versus women's first team and academy soccer. Sci Med Footb 6: 597&#x2013;604, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Stone JD, Galster SM, Hagen JA. Analyzing force-time curves: Comparison of commercially available automated software and custom MATLAB analyses. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2387&#x2013;2402, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moeskops S, Oliver JL, Read P, et al. Within- and between-session reliability of the isometric midthigh pull in young female athletes. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1892&#x2013;1901, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris R, Jones B, Myers T, et al. Isometric midthigh pull characteristics in elite youth male soccer players: Comparisons by age and maturity offset. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2947&#x2013;2955, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassis GP, Massey A, Jacobsen P, et al. Elite football of 2030 will not be the same as that of 2020: Preparing players, coaches, and support staff for the evolution. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 962&#x2013;964, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimphius S. Exercise and sport science failing by design in understanding female athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 1157&#x2013;1158, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimphius S, McBride JM, Rice PE, Goodman-Capps CL, Capps CR. Comparison of quadriceps and hamstring muscle activity during an isometric squat between strength-matched men and women. J Sports Sci Med 18: 101&#x2013;108, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, McBride JM, Cormie P, McCaulley GO. Relationship between countermovement jump performance and multijoint isometric and dynamic tests of strength. J Strength Cond Res 22: 699&#x2013;707, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okholm Kryger K, Wang A, Mehta R, et al. Can we evidence-base injury prevention and management in women's football? A scoping review. Res Sports Med 31: 687&#x2013;702, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okholm Kryger K, Wang A, Mehta R, Impellizzeri FM, Massey A, McCall A. Research on women's football: A scoping review. Sci Med Footb 6: 549&#x2013;558, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randell RK, Clifford T, Drust B, et al. Physiological characteristics of female soccer players and health and performance considerations: A narrative review. Sports Med 51: 1377&#x2013;1399, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson S, Bartlett JD, Gastin PB. Red, amber, or green? Athlete monitoring in team sport: The need for decision-support systems. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: S273&#x2013;S279, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles-Palazon FJ, Lopez-Valenciano A, De Ste Croix M, et al. Epidemiology of injuries in male and female youth football players: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci 11: 681&#x2013;695, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryman Augustsson S, Ageberg E. Weaker lower extremity muscle strength predicts traumatic knee injury in youth female but not male athletes. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 3: e000222, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott D, Haigh J, Lovell R. Physical characteristics and match performances in women's international versus domestic-level football players: A 2-year, league-wide study. Sci Med Footb 4: 211&#x2013;215, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano MA, Paredes V, Comfort P, et al. &#x201c;You are not wrong about getting strong:&#x201d; an insight into the impact of age group and level of competition on strength in Spanish football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 1&#x2013;8, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas C, Jones PA, Dos'Santos T. Countermovement jump force-time curve analysis between strength-matched male and female soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19, 3352, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trecroci A, Milanovic Z, Frontini M, Iaia FM, Alberti G. Physical performance comparison between under 15 elite and sub-elite soccer players. J Hum Kinet 61: 209&#x2013;216, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald&#xe9;n M, Knudsen M, Lundblad M, Ekstrand J. The female player: Special considerations . In: Return to Play in Football. Musahl V, Karlsson J, Krutsch W, Mandelbaum B, Espregueira-Mendes J, d'Hooghe P, eds. Heidelberg, Germany: Springer Berlin, 2018. pp. 929&#x2013;940.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>