<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888949</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of resistance training on myostatin in older adults with frailty and/or sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01655-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Myostatin (MSTN) is regarded as a key factor influencing skeletal muscle strength and function, and elevated circulating levels of MSTN may be closely associated with age-related sarcopenia and frailty. Given the limitations of pharmacological interventions, exercise intervention may emerge as a potential non-pharmacological strategy to regulate MSTN concentration. Therefore, this study aims to systematically evaluate the effect of resistance training (RT) on serum MSTN levels in elderly individuals with sarcopenia/frailty using meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In accordance with the PRISMA guidelines, a systematic search was conducted in Chinese and English databases, including PubMed, Web of Science, the Cochrane Library, and China National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI), for relevant studies from database inception to November 2025. Two researchers independently performed literature screening, literature searching, data extraction, and assessed the risk of bias of included studies using the original Cochrane risk of bias tool (The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials). Only studies investigating the chronic effects of RT (intervention duration&#x2265;8 weeks) were included.Subsequently, to account for the statistical dependency arising from multiple effect sizes reported within single studies, a multilevel meta-analysis was conducted. Analyses were performed using R software (version 4.4.1) with the&#xa0;metafor&#xa0;package (version 4.8.0). The standardized mean difference (SMD) and its 95% confidence interval (95%CI) were calculated for serum MSTN levels. Subgroup analysis was performed based on participants' physical state (sarcopenia vs. frailty).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 9 studies (contributing 11 intervention arms, with a total sample size of n= 330) were included. The multilevel meta-analysis showed that RT reduced serum MSTN concentrations in frail/sarcopenic elderly individuals (SMD = -0.23 (95%CI: -0.44 to -0.01), p &lt; 0.001), with negligible heterogeneity (I&#xb2; = 0%). Subgroup analysis revealed a significant effect of RT in elderly individuals with sarcopenia (SMD = -0.35, 95%CI: -0.65 to -0.06,&#xa0;p&#xa0;&lt; 0.05), but not in those with frailty (SMD = -0.08, 95%CI: -0.40 to 0.23,&#xa0;p&#xa0;= 0.599). The difference between subgroups was statistically significant (p &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Very low-certainty evidence from this meta-analysis suggests that RT may be associated with a reduction in serum MSTN concentrations in frail or sarcopenic older adults, with a more consistent effect observed in those with sarcopenia. These findings highlight the potential of RT as a non-pharmacological strategy, but further high-quality trials are needed to confirm its efficacy and establish optimal training parameters.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Polytechnic University, Wuhu, Anhui, China. 2231312134@stu.ahpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mingming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hefei Preschool Education College, Hefei, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Caiwei</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wannan Medical College, Wuhu, Anhui, China. 714739499@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Yinuo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Polytechnic University, Wuhu, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yeshou</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Polytechnic University, Wuhu, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changzhou University, Changzhou, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shouzhi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wannan Medical College, Wuhu, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly population</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myostatin (MSTN)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01655-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01655-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: Report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Age Ageing. 2010;39(4):412&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso-Bouz&#xf3;n C, Carcaillon L, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a FJ, Amor-Andr&#xe9;s MS, El Assar M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Ma&#xf1;as L. Association between endothelial dysfunction and frailty: the Toledo Study for Healthy Aging. Age (Dordr) Feb. 2014;36(1):495&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzilay JI, Blaum C, Moore T, et al. Insulin resistance and inflammation as precursors of frailty: the Cardiovascular Health Study. Arch Intern Med Apr. 2007;9(7):635&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Zhang F. Associations between sarcopenia (defined by low muscle mass), inflammatory markers, and all-cause mortality in older adults: mediation analyses in a large U.S. NHANES community sample, 1999&#x2013;2006. Front Med (Lausanne). 2025;12:1515839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pansarasa O, Mimmi MC, Davin A, Giannini M, Guaita A, Cereda C. Inflammation and cell-to-cell communication, two related aspects in frailty. Immun Ageing Oct. 2022;26(1):49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen OO, Savikangas TM, Tirkkonen AK, Al&#xe9;n MJ, Hautala AJ, Sipil&#xe4; S. Effects of 12-month physical and cognitive training on sarcopenia determinants in older adults: a subgroup analysis of a randomised clinical trial. Aging Clin Exp Res Feb. 2025;6(1):36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Hao Q, Hai S, Wang H, Cao L, Dong B. Sarcopenia as a predictor of all-cause mortality among community-dwelling older people: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Maturitas Sep. 2017;103:16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimokihara S, Yokoyama K, Ihira H, et al. Linear Association between Frailty as Assessed by the Kihon Checklist and Quality of Life in Community-Dwelling Older Adults: A Cross-Sectional Population-Based Study. Ann Geriatr Med Res Mar. 2025;29(1):66&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Zhang Y, Xv M, Sun L, Wang M. Association between oral health status and frailty in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1514623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Li WY, Ho M, Chau PH. The Prevalence of Sarcopenia in Chinese Older Adults: Meta-Analysis and Meta-Regression. Nutrients Apr. 2021;24(5):1441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Langley B, Berry C, et al. Myostatin, a negative regulator of muscle growth, functions by inhibiting myoblast proliferation. J Biol Chem. 2000;275(51):40235&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewasi G, Nagda P, Bahl G, Jain V, Gupta SK. Myostatin-driven muscle hypertrophy: a double-edged sword in muscle physiology. J Rare Dis Aug. 2025;14(1):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, McPherron AC. Regulation of myostatin activity and muscle growth. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S Jul. 2001;31(16):9306&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apgar JR, Mader M, Agostinelli R, et al. Beyond CDR-grafting: Structure-guided humanization of framework and CDR regions of an anti-myostatin antibody. MAbs Oct. 2016;8(7):1302&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Hellberg M, Hellmark T, H&#xf6;glund P, Clyne N. Muscle mass and plasma myostatin after exercise training: a substudy of Renal Exercise (RENEXC)-a randomized controlled trial. Nephrol Dial Transpl Jan. 2021;1(1):95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittemore LA, Song K, Li X, et al. Inhibition of myostatin in adult mice increases skeletal muscle mass and strength. Biochem Biophys Res Commun Jan. 2003;24(4):965&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Abdelmajeed M, Aboelwafa R, Genena DMM, Emara R, MYOSTATIN AS A, POTENTIAL DIAGNOSTIC BIOMARKER IN ELDERLY PATIENTS WITH SARCOPENIA. NILES J Geriatric Gerontol. 2024;7(2):321&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White TA, LeBrasseur NK. Myostatin and sarcopenia: opportunities and challenges - a mini-review. Gerontology. 2014;60(4):289&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilski J, Pierzchalski P, Szczepanik M, Bonior J, Zoladz JA. Multifactorial Mechanism of Sarcopenia and Sarcopenic Obesity. Role of Physical Exercise, Microbiota and Myokines. Cells Jan. 2022;4(1):160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Pedersen BK. Muscle-derived interleukin-6: mechanisms for activation and possible biological roles. Faseb j Sep. 2002;16(11):1335&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassar R, Vernus B, Carnac G, et al. Myostatin gene inactivation increases post-mortem calpain-dependent muscle proteolysis in mice. Meat Sci Mar. 2022;185:108726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirahata A, Nakanishi N, Ono Y, Inoue S, Kotani J. Utility of Plasma Myostatin as a Predictive Biomarker for Post Intensive Care Syndrome in Patients With Sepsis. Acute Med Surg Jan-Dec. 2025;12(1):e70098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Andre M, Johnson M, Bansal PN, et al. A mouse anti-myostatin antibody increases muscle mass and improves muscle strength and contractility in the mdx mouse model of Duchenne muscular dystrophy and its humanized equivalent, domagrozumab (PF-06252616), increases muscle volume in cynomolgus monkeys. Skelet Muscle Nov. 2017;9(1):25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker C, Lord SR, Studenski SA, et al. Myostatin antibody (LY2495655) in older weak fallers: a proof-of-concept, randomised, phase 2 trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol Dec. 2015;3(12):948&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhouse L, Gandhi R, Warden SJ, et al. A Phase 2 Randomized Study Investigating the Efficacy and Safety of Myostatin Antibody LY2495655 versus Placebo in Patients Undergoing Elective Total Hip Arthroplasty. J Frailty Aging. 2016;5(1):62&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak JY, Kwon KS. Pharmacological Interventions for Treatment of Sarcopenia: Current Status of Drug Development for Sarcopenia. Ann Geriatr Med Res Sep. 2019;23(3):98&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascher H, Tannerstedt J, Brink-Elfegoun T, Ekblom B, Gustafsson T, Blomstrand E. Repeated resistance exercise training induces different changes in mRNA expression of MAFbx and MuRF-1 in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab Jan. 2008;294(1):E43&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Load-mediated downregulation of myostatin mRNA is not sufficient to promote myofiber hypertrophy in humans: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985) Nov. 2007;103(5):1488&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Aria B, Symonds ME, Rosenkranz SK. The effects of resistance training on myostatin and follistatin in adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiol Behav Oct. 2023;1:269:114272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Suzuki T, Kim M, et al. Effects of exercise and milk fat globule membrane (MFGM) supplementation on body composition, physical function, and hematological parameters in community-dwelling frail Japanese women: a randomized double blind, placebo-controlled, follow-up trial. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(2):e0116256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amasene M, Cadenas-Sanchez C, Echeverria I, et al. Effects of Resistance Training Intervention along with Leucine-Enriched Whey Protein Supplementation on Sarcopenia and Frailty in Post-Hospitalized Older Adults: Preliminary Findings of a Randomized Controlled Trial. J Clin Med Dec. 2021;24(1):97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions. Explanation elaboration BMJ. 2009;339:b2700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(1):16&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, et al. Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia: 2019 Consensus Update on Sarcopenia Diagnosis and Treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc Mar. 2020;21(3):300&#x2013;e3072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang EYZ, Cheung J, Liu JYW, Kwan RYC, Lam SC. Groningen Frailty Indicator-Chinese (GFI-C) for pre-frailty and frailty assessment among older people living in communities: psychometric properties and diagnostic accuracy. BMC Geriatr Oct. 2022;7(1):788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong L, Duque G, McMahon LP. Sarcopenia and Frailty: Challenges in Mainstream Nephrology Practice. Kidney Int Rep Oct. 2021;6(10):2554&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelaiditi E, Cesari M, Canevelli M, et al. Cognitive frailty: rational and definition from an (I.A.N.A./I.A.G.G.) international consensus group. J Nutr Health Aging Sep. 2013;17(9):726&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Bossuyt PM, Leeflang MM, Takwoingi Y, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Diagnostic Test Accuracy. 1st edition. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmandi Z, Daryanoosh F, Ahmadi Hekmatikar AH, Awang Daud DM. Highlighting the effect of reduced training volume on maintaining hormonal adaptations obtained from periodized resistance training in sarcopenic older women. Expert Rev Endocrinol Metab Mar. 2024;19(2):187&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Bae J, Lee J. Complex Exercise Improves Anti-Inflammatory and Anabolic Effects in Osteoarthritis-Induced Sarcopenia in Elderly Women. Healthc (Basel) Jun. 2021;10(6):711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang M, Gu Y, Wang Z, He X, Chen N. Effects of 12-week whole-body vibration training versus resistance training in older people with sarcopenia. Sci Rep Feb. 2025;27(1):6981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negaresh R, Ranjbar R, Baker JS, et al. Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy, Insulin-like Growth Factor 1, Myostatin and Follistatin in Healthy and Sarcopenic Elderly Men: The Effect of Whole-body Resistance Training. Int J Prev Med. 2019;10:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Cao G, Tang Y, Liu X, Zhou Y, Chen M. 36-Week personalized resistance training improves muscle function and circulating myokines in older women with possible sarcopenic obesity: a randomized clinical trial. BMC Geriatr Sep. 2025;24(1):702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei S, Eslami R, Tartibian B. The effects of TRX suspension training on sarcopenic biomarkers and functional abilities in elderlies with sarcopenia: a controlled clinical trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil Feb. 2024;26(1):58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Song Y, Zhu J, Ding P, Chen N. Effectiveness of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction vs. conventional high-intensity resistance training in older people diagnosed with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep Nov. 2024;18(1):28427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun R, Wan J, Tang J, et al. Effectiveness of resistance training on body composition, muscle strength, and biomarker in sarcopenic older adults: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arch Gerontol Geriatr Jan. 2025;128:105595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langley B, Thomas M, Bishop A, Sharma M, Gilmour S, Kambadur R. Myostatin inhibits myoblast differentiation by down-regulating MyoD expression. J Biol Chem Dec. 2002;20(51):49831&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez J, Vernus B, Chelh I, et al. Myostatin and the skeletal muscle atrophy and hypertrophy signaling pathways. Cell Mol Life Sci Nov. 2014;71(22):4361&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAURO A. Satellite cell of skeletal muscle fibers. J Biophys Biochem Cytol. 1961;9(2):493&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennebry A, Berry C, Siriett V, et al. Myostatin regulates fiber-type composition of skeletal muscle by regulating MEF2 and MyoD gene expression. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol Mar. 2009;296(3):C525&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Xia X, Wang Q, et al. Myostatin Mutation Enhances Bovine Myogenic Differentiation through PI3K/AKT/mTOR Signalling via Removing DNA Methylation of RACK1. Cells. Dec. 2022;23(1):59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji Y, Li M, Chang M, et al. Inflammation: Roles in Skeletal Muscle Atrophy. Antioxidants (Basel). Aug. 2022;29(9):1686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendias CL, Bakhurin KI, Faulkner JA. Tendons of myostatin-deficient mice are small, brittle, and hypocellular. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2008;105(1):388&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetzlich B, Nyakundi BB, Yang J. Therapeutic applications and challenges in myostatin inhibition for enhanced skeletal muscle mass and functions. Mol Cell Biochem. 2025;480(3):1535&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hittel DS, Axelson M, Sarna N, Shearer J, Huffman KM, Kraus WE. Myostatin decreases with aerobic exercise and associates with insulin resistance. Med Sci Sports Exerc Nov. 2010;42(11):2023&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan AS, Li G, Blumenthal JB, Ortmeyer HK. Aerobic exercise&#x2009;+&#x2009;weight loss decreases skeletal muscle myostatin expression and improves insulin sensitivity in older adults. Obes (Silver Spring) Jul. 2013;21(7):1350&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Impact of resistance loading on myostatin expression and cell cycle regulation in young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab Jun. 2005;288(6):E1110&#x2013;1119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Martel GF, Ferrell RE, Metter EJ, Hurley BF, Rogers MA. Myostatin gene expression is reduced in humans with heavy-resistance strength training: a brief communication. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) Jun. 2003;228(6):706&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc Mar. 2012;44(3):406&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos AR, Neves MT Jr., Gualano B, et al. Blood flow restricted resistance training attenuates myostatin gene expression in a patient with inclusion body myositis. Biol Sport Jun. 2014;31(2):121&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamouille S, Derynck R. Cell size and invasion in TGF-beta-induced epithelial to mesenchymal transition is regulated by activation of the mTOR pathway. J Cell Biol Jul. 2007;30(3):437&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welle SL. Myostatin and muscle fiber size. Focus on Smad2 and 3 transcription factors control muscle mass in adulthood and Myostatin reduces Akt/TORC1/p70S6K signaling, inhibiting myoblast differentiation and myotube size. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol Jun. 2009;296(6):C1245&#x2013;1247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, McCarthy JJ, Hornberger TA, et al. Mechanisms of mechanical overload-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: current understanding and future directions. Physiol Rev Oct. 2023;1(4):2679&#x2013;757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki MS, Soares AG, Miyabara EH, Baptista IL, Moriscot AS. Expression of genes related to myostatin signaling during rat skeletal muscle longitudinal growth. Muscle Nerve Dec. 2009;40(6):992&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Liu C, Jiang N, et al. Myostatin: a potential therapeutic target for metabolic syndrome. Front Endocrinol. 2023;14:1181913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendler L, Z&#xe1;dor E, Ver Heyen M, Dux L, Wuytack F. Myostatin levels in regenerating rat muscles and in myogenic cell cultures. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 2000;21(6):551&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radzka J, &#x141;api&#x144;ska Z, Szwedowicz U, Gajewska-Naryniecka A, Gizak A, Kulbacka J. Alternations of NF-&#x3ba;B Signaling by Natural Compounds in Muscle-Derived Cancers. Int J Mol Sci Jul. 2023;25(15):11900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Jia F, Wang M, Yang S. Analysis of the mechanism of skeletal muscle atrophy from the pathway of decreased protein synthesis [J]. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1533394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol Jan. 2009;15(1):211&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand A, Nambirajan A, Kumar V, et al. Alterations in Autophagy and Mammalian Target of Rapamycin (mTOR) Pathways Mediate Sarcopenia in Patients with Cirrhosis. J Clin Exp Hepatol Mar-Apr. 2022;12(2):510&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bideshki MV, Behzadi M, Jamali M, Jamilian P, Zarezadeh M, Gargari BP. Ergogenic Benefits of &#x3b2;-Hydroxy-&#x3b2;-Methyl Butyrate (HMB) Supplementation on Body Composition and Muscle Strength: An Umbrella Review of Meta-Analyses. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2025;16(1):e13671.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>