<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41924119</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0915-5287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of physical therapy science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Phys Ther Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gait analysis and evaluation of knee buckling risk following total knee arthroplasty.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>157</StartPage><EndPage>162</EndPage><MedlinePgn>157-162</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1589/jpts.38.157</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>[Purpose] Total knee arthroplasty (TKA) can alleviate pain and improve daily functioning in patients with knee osteoarthritis. However, postoperative decreases in knee extensor strength and limitations in joint range of motion (ROM) may increase the risk of knee buckling. This study aimed to investigate gait characteristics and mechanical conditions potentially associated with knee buckling in patients following TKA. [Participants and Methods] This study was conducted on patients following TKA. Based on the inclusion criteria, this study included 21 patients (25 knees; postoperative day 22.0 &#xb1; 10.5) with data for knee joint position sense, knee-extension strength, tibial acceleration, knee flexion angle, and electromyography (EMG) of vastus medialis, vastus lateralis (VL), rectus femoris, tibialis anterior, and lateral head of the gastrocnemius during gait. EMG signals were normalized using the maximal voluntary contraction method. Participants walked six steps at a self-selected speed and the second gait cycle on the operated side was analyzed. [Results] Knee joint position sense and knee flexion angle at initial contact (IC) showed a moderate positive correlation. Moderate negative correlations were observed between postoperative days and VL activity and between maximum vertical direction tibial acceleration and VL activity. [Conclusion] Decreased position sense may affect knee joint control at IC, potentially manifesting as an increased knee flexion angle and suggesting the involvement of mechanical conditions associated with knee buckling. Furthermore, VL muscle activity during gait decreased with increasing postoperative days, and greater VL muscle activity was associated with gait patterns characterized by reduced vertical tibial acceleration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2026&#xa9;by the Society of Physical Therapy Science. Published by IPEC Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimizu</LastName><ForeName>Ryosuke</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JCHO Gunma Central Hospital: 1-7-13 Koun-chou, Maebashi-shi, Gunma 371-0025, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health Sciences, Gunma University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimura</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JCHO Gunma Central Hospital: 1-7-13 Koun-chou, Maebashi-shi, Gunma 371-0025, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Ena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health Sciences, Gunma University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaji</LastName><ForeName>Takehiko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health Sciences, Gunma University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>J Phys Ther Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105359</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0915-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee buckling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tibial acceleration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare relevant to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41924119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13038373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.38.157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2025-143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani M, Yaali R, Sadeghi H, et al. : The effect of foot posture on static balance, ankle and knee proprioception in 18-to-25-year-old female student: a cross-sectional study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord, 2023, 24: 547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10318675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37403076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stensdotter AK, Bjerke J, Djupsj&#xf6;backa M: Postural sway in single-limb and bilateral quiet standing after unilateral total knee arthroplasty. Gait Posture, 2015, 41: 769&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25755019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Haga N: Textbook of orthopedic surgery, 4th ed. Tokyo: Nankodo, 2017, pp 158&#x2013;159, 243&#x2013;244 (in Japanese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabadghav R, Potdar A, Patil V, et al. : Additional effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on knee extension lag, pain and knee range of motion in immediate postsurgical phase (0&#x2013;2 weeks) in primary total knee arthroplasty patient. Ann Transl Med, 2019, 7: S253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6829005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31728377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moxley Scarborough D, Krebs DE, Harris BA: Quadriceps muscle strength and dynamic stability in elderly persons. Gait Posture, 1999, 10: 10&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10469937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loyd BJ, Jennings JM, Falvey JR, et al. : Magnitude of deformity correction may influence recovery of quadriceps strength after total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty, 2017, 32: 2730&#x2013;2737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5572744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28559195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zobel I, Erfani T, Bennell KL, et al. : Relationship of buckling and knee injury to pain exacerbation in knee osteoarthritis: a web-based case-crossover study. Interact J Med Res, 2016, 5: e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4938888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27342008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thacher RR, Hickernell TR, Grosso MJ, et al. : Decreased risk of knee buckling with adductor canal block versus femoral nerve block in total knee arthroplasty: a retrospective cohort study. Arthroplast Today, 2017, 3: 281&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29204497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita Y, Mera H, Watanabe T, et al. : Significantly earlier ambulation and reduced risk of near-falls with continuous infusion nerve blocks: a retrospective pilot study of adductor canal block compared to femoral nerve block in total knee arthroplasty. BMC Musculoskelet Disord, 2022, 23: 768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9373377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35953812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Japanese Association of Rehabilitation Medicine (JARM): Standards for Joint
Range of Motion Representation and Measurement Methods (in Japanese). https://www.jarm.or.jp/member/kadou03.html (Accessed Apr.
1, 2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira DC, Barboza SD, da Costa FD, et al. : Can pain influence the proprioception and the motor behavior in subjects with mild and moderate knee osteoarthritis? BMC Musculoskelet Disord, 2014, 15: 321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4190294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olin ED, Gutierrez GM: EMG and tibial shock upon the first attempt at barefoot running. Hum Mov Sci, 2013, 32: 343&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23643493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kito N, Shimazawa S, Yuge C, et al. : Noninvasive acceleration measurements to characterize knee osteoarthritis in gait. Phys Ther Jpn, 2004, 31: 86&#x2013;94 (in Japanese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafson JA, Gorman S, Fitzgerald GK, et al. : Alterations in walking knee joint stiffness in individuals with knee osteoarthritis and self-reported knee instability. Gait Posture, 2016, 43: 210&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5572142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrokhi S, O&#x2019;Connell M, Gil AB, et al. : Altered gait characteristics in individuals with knee osteoarthritis and self-reported knee instability. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther, 2015, 45: 351&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6196716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25808531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudo S: Clinical anatomy for understanding the &#x201c;why?&#x201d; of musculoskeletal disorders. Tokyo: Igaku-Shoin, 2012, pp 145&#x2013;146, 165&#x2013;166 (in Japanese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue YY, Shi JN, Zhang K, et al. : The effects of total knee arthroplasty on knee proprioception of patients with knee osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res, 2022, 17: 258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9077928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>