<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41186987</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Contributions of Muscle Architecture and Tissue Properties to Knee Extensor Force Production.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005243</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hirono, T, Murota, N, Tanaka, H, Yagi, M, Wang, Z, Mukai, H, Itsuda, H, and Ichihashi, N. Contributions of muscle architecture and tissue properties to knee extensor force production. J Strength Cond Res 39(12): e1371-e1379, 2025-Muscular characteristics, such as muscle size, fascicle length and angle, connective tissue within the muscle, and stiffness, are related to muscle force. This study aimed to investigate the contributions of these factors for isometric contraction strength in the quadriceps muscles using multivariate analyses. Maximal voluntary isometric strength of the quadriceps at 3 different knee angles (40, 70, and 100&#xb0;) in 48 adults (24 men, 23.5 &#xb1; 3.0 years) was evaluated. The cross-sectional area (CSA), fascicle length, pennation angle, echo intensity, and shear elastic modulus of the quadriceps were evaluated using ultrasonography. Simple regression analyses revealed that CSA, echo intensity, shear elastic modulus, and fascicle length were significantly related to peak torque and rate of torque development (RTD). The peak torque during isometric contraction was significantly explained by CSA as an independent variable at all knee angles (&#x3b2; = 0.445-0.732), but not by other variables (adjusted R2 = 0.457-0.678). The RTD as a dependent variable was explained by CSA at all angles (&#x3b2; = 0.491-0.702), and by fascicle length at 100&#xb0; of knee flexion (&#x3b2; = 0.206), but not by other variables (adjusted R2 = 0.371-0.665). These results suggested that maximal isometric contraction strength was determined mainly by muscle CSA, not by other variables.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirono</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4337-6249</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murota</LastName><ForeName>Norihiko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Hiroki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Unit, Kyoto University Hospital, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yagi</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation, Kansai Medical University, Osaka, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zimin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Fellow of Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mukai</LastName><ForeName>Hiyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Itsuda</LastName><ForeName>Hikari</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Fellow of Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ichihashi</LastName><ForeName>Noriaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation, Kansai Medical University, Osaka, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>24K20528</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">echo intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elastography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fascicle length</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isometric contraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle morphology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of torque development</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41186987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alfuraih AM, Tan AL, O'Connor P, Emery P, Wakefield RJ. The effect of ageing on shear wave elastography muscle stiffness in adults. Aging Clin Exp Res 31: 1755&#x2013;1763, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso J, McHugh MP, Mullaney MJ, Tyler TF. Effect of hamstring flexibility on isometric knee flexion angle-torque relationship. Scand J Med Sci Sports 19: 252&#x2013;256, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R. Association of the rate of torque development and joint angle with passive muscle stiffness. Eur J Appl Physiol 124: 2665&#x2013;2673, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R, Nosaka K, Inami T, et al. Difference in fascicle behaviors between superficial and deep quadriceps muscles during isometric contractions. Muscle Nerve 53: 797&#x2013;802, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R, Saito A, Umemura Y, Akima H. Local architecture of the vastus intermedius is a better predictor of knee extension force than that of the other quadriceps femoris muscle heads. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 376&#x2013;382, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R, Suzuki Y. Positive relationship between passive muscle stiffness and rapid force production. Hum Mov Sci 66: 285&#x2013;291, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R, Taniguchi K, Saito A, Fujimiya M, Katayose M, Akima H. Validity of fascicle length estimation in the vastus lateralis and vastus intermedius using ultrasonography. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 24: 214&#x2013;220, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ. Effects of physical training and detraining, immobilisation, growth and aging on human fascicle geometry. Sports Med 36: 1003&#x2013;1017, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985) 103: 1565&#x2013;1575, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Coleman DR, Horne S, Cannavan D. Anatomical predictors of maximum isometric and concentric knee extensor moment. Eur J Appl Physiol 105: 869&#x2013;878, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Zhou S. Intra- and intermuscular variation in human quadriceps femoris architecture assessed in vivo. J Anat 209: 289&#x2013;310, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chleboun GS, Howell JN, Conatser RR, Giesey JJ. Relationship between muscle swelling and stiffness after eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 529&#x2013;535, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM. Sarcopenia =/= dynapenia. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 63: 829&#x2013;834, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossich VRA, Laett CT, Gavilao UF, Blazevich AJ, Oliveira CG. Faster intrinsic rate of torque development in elbow flexors than knee extensors: Effect of muscle architecture? J Electromyogr Kinesiol 59: 102570, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudicio A, Martinez-Valdes E, Cogliati M, Orizio C, Negro F. The force-generation capacity of the tibialis anterior muscle at different muscle-tendon lengths depends on its motor unit contractile properties. Eur J Appl Physiol 122: 317&#x2013;330, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Negro F, Holobar A, et al. You are as fast as your motor neurons: Speed of recruitment and maximal discharge of motor neurons determine the maximal rate of force development in humans. J Physiol 597: 2445&#x2013;2456, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Buckthorpe MW, Hannah R. Human capacity for explosive force production: Neural and contractile determinants. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: 894&#x2013;906, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukumoto Y, Ikezoe T, Yamada Y, et al. Skeletal muscle quality assessed from echo intensity is associated with muscle strength of middle-aged and elderly persons. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1519&#x2013;1525, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukumoto Y, Taniguchi M, Hirono T, et al. Influence of ultrasound focus depth on the association between echo intensity and intramuscular adipose tissue. Muscle Nerve 66: 568&#x2013;575, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukunaga T, Roy RR, Shellock FG, et al. Physiological cross-sectional area of human leg muscles based on magnetic resonance imaging. J Orthop Res 10: 928&#x2013;934, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AM, Huxley AF, Julian FJ. The variation in isometric tension with sarcomere length in vertebrate muscle fibres. J Physiol 184: 170&#x2013;192, 1966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greig CA, Botella J, Young A. The quadriceps strength of healthy elderly people remeasured after eight years. Muscle Nerve 16: 6&#x2013;10, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hager R, Poulard T, Nordez A, Dorel S, Guilhem G. Influence of joint angle on muscle fascicle dynamics and rate of torque development during isometric explosive contractions. J Appl Physiol (1985) 129: 569&#x2013;579, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes EMK, Neubauer NA, Cornett KMD, O'Connor BP, Jones GR, Jakobi JM. Age and sex-related decline of muscle strength across the adult lifespan: A scoping review of aggregated data. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 45: 1185&#x2013;1196, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirono T, Okudaira M, Takeda R, et al. Association between physical fitness tests and neuromuscular properties. Eur J Appl Physiol 124: 1703&#x2013;1717, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Abe T, Fukunaga T. Muscle-fiber pennation angles are greater in hypertrophied than in normal muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985) 74: 2740&#x2013;2744, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Baltzopoulos V. In vivo determination of the patella tendon and hamstrings moment arms in adult males using videofluoroscopy during submaximal knee extension and flexion. Clin Biomech 14: 118&#x2013;124, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Guo JY, Cohen JH, Parker KJ. Relationship between shear elastic modulus and passive muscle force: An ex-vivo study. J Biomech 46: 2053&#x2013;2059, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber RL, Friden J. Functional and clinical significance of skeletal muscle architecture. Muscle Nerve 23: 1647&#x2013;1666, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maden-Wilkinson TM, Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Folland JP. Muscle architecture and morphology as determinants of explosive strength. Eur J Appl Physiol 121: 1099&#x2013;1110, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: Physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1091&#x2013;1116, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moltubakk MM, Eriksrud O, Paulsen G, Seynnes OR, Bojsen-Moller J. Hamstrings functional properties in athletes with high musculo-skeletal flexibility. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 659&#x2013;665, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monte A, Franchi MV. Regional muscle features and their association with knee extensors force production at a single joint angle. Eur J Appl Physiol 123: 2239&#x2013;2248, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota JA, Giuliani HK, Gerstner GR, Ryan ED. The rate of velocity development associates with muscle echo intensity, but not muscle cross-sectional area in older men. Aging Clin Exp Res 30: 861&#x2013;865, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisell R. Mechanics of the knee. Acta Orthop Scand 56: 1&#x2013;42, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordez A, Gennisson JL, Casari P, Catheline S, Cornu C. Characterization of muscle belly elastic properties during passive stretching using transient elastography. J Biomech 41: 2305&#x2013;2311, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Hopkins WG, Cronin JB, Storey AG, Nelson AR. The effects of regional quadriceps architecture on angle-specific rapid force expression. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 48: 829&#x2013;840, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Hopkins WG, Nelson AR, Storey AG, Cronin JB. The effect of regional quadriceps anatomical parameters on angle-specific isometric torque expression. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 46: 368&#x2013;378, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer TB, Thompson BJ. Influence of age on passive stiffness and size, quality, and strength characteristics. Muscle Nerve 55: 305&#x2013;315, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peduzzi P, Concato J, Feinstein AR, Holford TR. Importance of events per independent variable in proportional hazards regression analysis. II. Accuracy and precision of regression estimates. J Clin Epidemiol 48: 1503&#x2013;1510, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillen S, Tak RO, Zwarts MJ, et al. Skeletal muscle ultrasound: Correlation between fibrous tissue and echo intensity. Ultrasound Med Biol 35: 443&#x2013;446, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power GA, Crooks S, Fletcher JR, Macintosh BR, Herzog W. Age-related reductions in the number of serial sarcomeres contribute to shorter fascicle lengths but not elevated passive tension. J Exp Biol 224: 242172, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser EM, Draskovits T, Praschak M, Quittan M, Graf A. Association between ultrasound measurements of muscle thickness, pennation angle, echogenicity and skeletal muscle strength in the elderly. Age (Dordr) 35: 2377&#x2013;2388, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werkhausen A, Gloersen O, Nordez A, Paulsen G, Bojsen-Moller J, Seynnes OR. Linking muscle architecture and function in vivo: Conceptual or methodological limitations? PeerJ 11: e15194, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi M, Taniguchi M, Tateuchi H, et al. Relationship between individual forces of each quadriceps head during low-load knee extension and cartilage thickness and knee pain in women with knee osteoarthritis. Clin Biomech 91: 105546, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>