<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41591380</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of the Effects of Barefoot and Shod Training on Foot Structure, Muscle Strength, and Sensory Function.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005354</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Koyama, K and Hosono, S. Comparison of the effects of barefoot and shod training on foot structure, muscle strength, and sensory function. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-The aim of this study was to compare the effects of 8 weeks multicomponent lower-limb training under barefoot versus shod conditions on foot muscle strength, structure, and sensory function. Healthy adults were assigned to either a barefoot training (BARE; n = 11), shod training (SHOD; n = 11), or control (CON; n = 15) groups. BARE and SHOD completed 2 weekly training including agility, balance, and strength exercises. Measurements were taken at baseline and weeks 2, 4, 6, and 8. Outcome measures included toe flexor strength, foot arch height, and foot sensory threshold. Relative toe flexor strength increased at weeks 4, 6, and 8 in both BARE and SHOD compared with baseline and was higher than in CON. For standing relative toe flexor strength, BARE showed greater values at weeks 6 and 8 than at weeks 2, and the value at week 6 was greater than at week 4, whereas in SHOD, only values at week 8 were greater than values at week 2. In contrast, arch-related variables and foot sensory threshold showed no significant changes during most of the training period in either group, and between-group differences were generally not significant. In CON, no significant changes were observed in nearly all outcome measures from baseline to week 8. Throughout the training period, no significant differences were found between BARE and SHOD in nearly all outcome measures. Overall, compared with shod training, 8 weeks of barefoot multicomponent exercises led to continued improvement in standing toe flexor strength without changing foot structure and sensory function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyama</LastName><ForeName>Keiji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Toin University of Yokohama, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosono</LastName><ForeName>Shuhei</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot sensory threshold</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">footwear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medial longitudinal arch</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multicomponent lower-limb training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">toe flexor strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41591380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aibast H, Okutoyi P, Sigei T, et al. Foot structure and function in habitually barefoot and shod adolescents in Kenya. Curr Sports Med Rep 16: 448&#x2013;458, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angin S, Crofts G, Mickle KJ, Nester CJ. Ultrasound evaluation of foot muscles and plantar fascia in pes planus. Gait Posture 40: 48&#x2013;52, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beierle R, Burton P, Smith H, Smith M, Ives SJ. The effect of barefoot running on EMG activity in the gastrocnemius and tibialis anterior in active college-aged females. Int J Exerc Sci 12: 1110&#x2013;1120, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell-Krotoski JA, Buford WL Jr. The force/time relationship of clinically used sensory testing instruments. J Hand Ther 10: 297&#x2013;309, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell-Krotoski JA, Fess EE, Figarola JH, Hiltz D. Threshold detection and semmes-weinstein monofilaments. J Hand Ther 8: 155&#x2013;162, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell-Krotoski J, Weinstein S, Weinstein C. Testing sensibility, including touch-pressure, two-point discrimination, point localization, and vibration. J Hand Ther 6: 114&#x2013;123, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binnie MJ, Dawson B, Pinnington H, Landers G, Peeling P. Sand training: A review of current research and practical applications. J Sports Sci 32: 8&#x2013;15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang R, Kent-Braun JA, Hamill J. Use of MRI for volume estimation of tibialis posterior and plantar intrinsic foot muscles in healthy and chronic plantar fasciitis limbs. Clin Biomech 27: 500&#x2013;505, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrum RG, Conners RT, Coons JM. The effect of running barefoot and in barefoot-style footwear on running economy at two self-determined speeds. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 59: 1292&#x2013;1297, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFreitas JM, Beck TW, Stock MS, Dillon MA, Kasishke PR II. An examination of the time course of training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 2785&#x2013;2790, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick R, McCloskey DI. Proprioceptive, visual and vestibular thresholds for the perception of sway during standing in humans. J Physiol 478 (Pt 1): 173&#x2013;186, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong Yan A, Quinlan S, Cheung RTH. Minimalist school shoes improve intrinsic foot muscle size, strength, and arch integrity among primary school students. J Sports Sci 42: 1157&#x2013;1163, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmour JC, Burns Y. The measurement of the medial longitudinal arch in children. Foot Ankle Int 22: 493&#x2013;498, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldmann JP, Sanno M, Willwacher S, Heinrich K, Br&#xfc;ggemann GP. The potential of toe flexor muscles to enhance performance. J Sports Sci 31: 424&#x2013;433, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennig EM, Sterzing T. Sensitivity mapping of the human foot: Thresholds at 30 skin locations. Foot Ankle Int 30: 986&#x2013;991, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holowka NB, Wallace IJ, Lieberman DE. Foot strength and stiffness are related to footwear use in a comparison of minimally- vs. conventionally-shod populations. Sci Rep 8: 3679, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichikawa S, Kumai T, Okunuki T, et al. Comparison of foot posture and foot muscle morphology between lifesaver athletes and healthy adults. Res Sports Med 31: 506&#x2013;516, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inglis JT, Kennedy PM, Wells C, Chua R. The role of cutaneous receptors in the foot. Adv Exp Med Biol 508: 111&#x2013;117, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavounoudias A, Roll R, Roll JP. The plantar sole is a 'dynamometric map' for human balance control. Neuroreport 9: 3247&#x2013;3252, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly LA, Cresswell AG, Racinais S, Whiteley R, Lichtwark G. Intrinsic foot muscles have the capacity to control deformation of the longitudinal arch. J R Soc Interface 11: 20131188, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy PM, Inglis JT. Distribution and behaviour of glabrous cutaneous receptors in the human foot sole. J Physiol 538: 995&#x2013;1002, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama K. Effects of a 12-week barefoot exercise training on foot muscle functions and arch height. Gazz Med Ital Arch Sci Med 181: 191&#x2013;198, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama K, Hirokawa M, Yoshitaka Y, Yamauchi J. Toe flexor muscle strength and morphological characteristics of the foot in judo athletes. Int J Sports Med 40: 263&#x2013;268, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama K, Yamauchi J. Altered postural sway following fatiguing foot muscle exercises. PLoS One 12: e0189184, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama K, Yamauchi J. Increased toe flexor strength does not relate to altered postural sway during static upright standing after 12 weeks of multicomponent exercise training. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 520&#x2013;529, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama K, Yamauchi J. Mechanical drivers of intrinsic foot muscle for maximum toe flexor strength in upright standing across different body size. Foot 61: 102128, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurihara T, Yamauchi J, Otsuka M, Tottori N, Hashimoto T, Isaka T. Maximum toe flexor muscle strength and quantitative analysis of human plantar intrinsic and extrinsic muscles by a magnetic resonance imaging technique. J Foot Ankle Res 7: 26, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latey PJ, Burns J, Hiller C, Nightingale EJ. Relationship between intrinsic foot muscle weakness and pain: A systematic review. J Foot Ankle Res 7: A51&#x2013;A52, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenstein E, Morat M, Roth R, Donath L, Faude O. Agility-based exercise training compared to traditional strength and balance training in older adults: A pilot randomized trial. PeerJ 8: e8781, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maemichi T, Ichikawa S, Kumai T. Effect of training in a sandy environment on foot morphology and function. J Bodyw Mov Ther 40: 1657&#x2013;1663, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald KA, Stearne SM, Alderson JA, North I, Pires NJ, Rubenson J. The role of arch compression and metatarsophalangeal joint dynamics in modulating plantar fascia strain in running. PLoS One 11: e0152602, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeon PO, Fourchet F. Freeing the foot: Integrating the foot core system into rehabilitation for lower extremity injuries. Clin Sports Med 34: 347&#x2013;361, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller EE, Whitcome KK, Lieberman DE, Norton HL, Dyer RE. The effect of minimal shoes on arch structure and intrinsic foot muscle strength. J Sport Health Sci 3: 74&#x2013;85, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita N, Yamauchi J, Kurihara T, et al. Toe flexor strength and foot arch height in children. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 350&#x2013;356, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med 58: 115&#x2013;130, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuka M, Yamauchi J, Kurihara T, Morita N, Isaka T. Toe flexor strength and lower-limb physical performance in adolescent. Gazz Med Ital 174: 307&#x2013;313, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinnington HC, Lloyd DG, Besier TF, Dawson B. Kinematic and electromyography analysis of submaximal differences running on a firm surface compared with soft, dry sand. Eur J Appl Physiol 94: 242&#x2013;253, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, Zhang S, Cui K, Zhang X, Fu W. Effects of a 12-week gait retraining program combined with foot core exercise on morphology, muscle strength, and kinematics of the arch: A randomized controlled trial. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 10: 1022910, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strzalkowski NDJ, Peters RM, Inglis JT, Bent LR. Cutaneous afferent innervation of the human foot sole: What can we learn from single-unit recordings? J Neurophysiol 120: 1233&#x2013;1246, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung KD, Franz JR, Kram R. A test of the metabolic cost of cushioning hypothesis during unshod and shod running. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 324&#x2013;329, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger CL, Wooden MJ. Effect of foot intrinsic muscle strength training on jump performance. J Strength Cond Res 14: 373&#x2013;378, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegener C, Hunt AE, Vanwanseele B, Burns J, Smith RM. Effect of children's shoes on gait: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Foot Ankle Res 4: 3, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi J, Koyama K. Force-generating capacity of the toe flexor muscles and dynamic function of the foot arch in upright standing. J Anat 234: 515&#x2013;522, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi J, Koyama K. Importance of toe flexor strength in vertical jump performance. J Biomech 104: 109719, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi J, Koyama K. The mechanical role of the metatarsophalangeal joint in human jumping. PLoS One 17: e0268634, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Deng L, Yang Y, Xiao S, Li L, Fu W. Effects of 12-week transition training with minimalist shoes on achilles tendon loading in habitual rearfoot strike runners. J Biomech 128: 110807, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zifchock RA, Davis I, Hillstrom H, Song J. The effect of gender, age, and lateral dominance on arch height and arch stiffness. Foot Ankle Int 27: 367&#x2013;372, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>