<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41923660</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-650X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food &amp; function</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Funct</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SELFormer-guided discovery of xanthohumol and cirsilineol as multi-target natural therapeutics for type 2 diabetes: computational prediction and experimental validation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5fo03765d</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) requires multi-target therapeutic approaches addressing both insulin resistance and insulin secretion deficits. Although natural compounds are promising multi-target candidates, systematic identification of their polypharmacological profiles remains challenging. The objective of this study was to establish a computational framework for identifying natural compounds with multi-target therapeutic potential against T2DM through integrated structure-activity analysis and experimental validation. We developed an SELFormer deep learning model to predict natural compound activities against six T2DM-related proteins including glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor (GLP1R), kinesin family member-11 (KIF11) for insulin secretion and insulin receptor (INSR), peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma (PPARG), fibroblast growth factor receptor-1 (FGFR1) and insulin-like growth factor-1 receptor (IGF1R) for insulin resistance. Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection (UMAP) for dimension reduction clustering characterized chemical space distributions and molecular docking validated multi-target binding. Selected compounds were experimentally validated using 3T3-L1 adipocytes and mouse insulinoma (MIN6) pancreatic &#x3b2;-cells. The SELFormer model achieved <i>R</i><sup>2</sup> = 0.937 and RMSE = 0.331 on the training dataset and <i>R</i><sup>2</sup> = 0.918 and RMSE = 0.353 on the testing dataset, with minimal overfitting (&#x394;<i>R</i><sup>2</sup> = 0.019). Among approximately two million screened compounds, 35 natural compounds demonstrated high predicted activity (pIC<sub>50</sub> &gt; 7), clustering into eight distinct chemical families. Multi-target network analysis and molecular docking identified curcumin, xanthohumol, hesperetin, (-)-epicatechin, and cirsilineol as lead candidates with favorable binding energies ranging from -7 to -10 kcal mol<sup>-1</sup> across the six targets. Food source analysis identified strawberries, grapes, and tea as rich dietary sources of these bioactive compounds. In 3T3-L1 adipocytes, all five compounds significantly enhanced insulin-stimulated glucose uptake at 10 &#x3bc;M, achieving efficacy comparable to that of metformin. In MIN6 cells, xanthohumol and cirsilineol increased glucose-stimulated insulin secretion to levels comparable to exendin-4, while curcumin, hesperetin, and (-)-epicatechin produced modest but significant increases. In conclusion, this integrated computational and experimental framework identified food-derived natural compounds with validated dual-pathway therapeutic activity against T2DM, providing a systematic and reproducible methodology for multi-target drug discovery in complex metabolic disorders.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Junyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5931-1477</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Advanced Clinical Medicine, Peking University, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioconvergence, Hoseo University, Asan, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Meiling</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Shanxi Institute of Science and Technology, Jincheng, 048000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sunmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6092-8340</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioconvergence, Hoseo University, Asan, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food and Nutrition, Obesity/Diabetes Research Center, Hoseo University, Asan, Korea. smpark@hoseo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Food Funct</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549033</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-6496</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41923660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5fo03765d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>