<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41136506</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simulation analysis of traffic flow stability for intelligent connected vehicles at mountain tunnel entrances considering nonlinear coupling effects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37310</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37310</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-21318-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The sudden changes in light and slope at the entrance of mountain tunnels can easily lead to unstable traffic flow, especially in mixed traffic flow containing ICV. The existing control methods are difficult to simultaneously address three challenges: dynamically changing lighting and slope environments, vehicle data privacy protection requirements, and insufficient adaptability to different tunnel scenarios. This study developed the MF3DQN-TF control framework to address these issues by integrating environmental perception and vehicle control. The framework first establishes a correlation model between light gradient and slope resistance, converting environmental risks into quantifiable control signals; Secondly, design an intelligent weight allocation mechanism to automatically increase the decision-making priority of environmental factors in strong light areas; Finally, a distributed training architecture is adopted to achieve knowledge sharing in multi tunnel scenarios while protecting vehicle data privacy. The verification results show that in typical tunnel testing scenarios, this framework significantly improves performance compared to traditional methods: the amplitude of speed fluctuations is reduced by about 40% compared to conventional control methods, the risk of rear end collisions is reduced to one-third of that of traditional reinforcement learning schemes, and the communication transmission volume is only half of that of typical federated learning methods. The verification results show that in typical tunnel testing scenarios, this framework reduces speed standard deviation by 41.4% (vs. PID control), cuts high-risk TTC&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;2&#xa0;s events by 62.5% (vs. centralized DQN), and nearly halves communication volume (46.2% reduction vs. FedProx). These improvements stem from the collaborative processing mechanism of the framework for environmental risks and vehicle status, providing a new technological path for safety control in complex tunnel environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Mengmeng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Hefei University of Technology, Hefei, 230009, China. ypssb0@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Intelligent Transportation, Anhui Sanlian University, Hefei, 230009, China. ypssb0@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Provincial Key Laboratory of Transportation Information and Safety, Anhui Sanlian University, Hefei, 230009, China. ypssb0@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>JTX202302</GrantID><Agency>The Open Project of Anhui Province Key Laboratory of Transportation Information and Safety in Ordinary Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022AH030161</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Province Excellent Youth Program for Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KJZD2023001</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Sanlian University Campus level Research Fund Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>zjt23001</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Sanlian University Collaborative Innovation Center Special Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic collaborative control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Federated reinforcement learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mountain tunnel traffic flow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nonlinear coupling effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robust optimization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests:: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41136506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12552686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21318-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-21318-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. A time-varying harmonic impedance estimation method based on improved BP neural network with attention mechanism. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>2</b>(49), 111905&#x2013;111905 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2025.111905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Peng, S. &amp; Zhou, Y. Spatial&#x2013;temporal graph transformer network for traffic network flow prediction using parallel training based on cloud computing. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>18</b>(11), 113422&#x2013;113422 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Y., Wu, D. &amp; Han, Z. Flow decomposition based spatial&#x2013;temporal filtering self-attention networks for traffic flow forecasting. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>158</b>, 111243&#x2013;111243 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2025.111243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H. et al. A lattice model of mixed traffic flow based on critical safety potential field and driver vigilance feedback: Numerical simulation of critical safety potential field fluctuations characterizing the effects of vehicle mass and volume differences. <i>Chaos, Solitons and Fractals: Interdiscip. J. Nonlinear Sci. Nonequilibrium Complex Phenom.</i><b>199</b>(P1), 116689&#x2013;116689 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2025.116689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, X., Raadsen, P. M. &amp; Bliemer, C. M. A systematic review of node models for macroscopic network loading of traffic flows. <i>Transp. Res. Part B</i><b>19</b>(23), 103273&#x2013;103273 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trb.2025.103273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, T., Chen, J. &amp; Chung, E. Integrating micro and macro traffic control for mixed autonomy traffic. <i>Commun. Trans. Res.</i><b>5</b>(10), 188&#x2013;189 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, C. et al. Application of attention mechanism-based LSTM neural network in stratigraphy identification. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>27</b>(10), 5267&#x2013;5269 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Duan, H. &amp; Yu, F. Spatio-temporal grey model based on tensor Tucker decomposition for traffic flow prediction. <i>Appl. Math. Model.</i><b>14</b>(21), 116231&#x2013;116231 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apm.2025.116231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, H. et al. Incorporating graph theory and time series analysis for fine-grained traffic flow prediction in port areas. <i>Ocean Eng.</i><b>335</b>, 121693&#x2013;121693 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2025.121693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Hu Y, Zhao Z, et al. Traffic Flow Prediction Based on Time-Domain Graph Convolution and GRU [J]. International Journal of Intelligent Transportation Systems Research, (prepublish): 1&#x2013;15. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann, H. H. et al. The influence of spatial configuration on e-scooter traffic flows. <i>Transp. Res. Part A</i><b>19</b>(8), 104529&#x2013;104529 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, K. et al. Enhancing Mixed Traffic Stability with TD3-Driven Bilateral Control in Autonomous Vehicle Chains [J]. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b>(11), 4790&#x2013;4790 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17114790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y. et al. The impact of selfish driving behavior of autonomous vehicles on mixed traffic flow. <i>Physica A</i><b>6</b>(71), 130691&#x2013;130691 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physa.2025.130691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Diffusion-Attention Traffic Generation: Traffic Generation Based on the Fusion of a Diffusion Model and a Self-Attention Mechanism. <i>Electronics</i><b>14</b>(10), 1977&#x2013;1977 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14101977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M., Chen, Y. &amp; Hao, R. Connected and Automated Vehicle Trajectory Control in Stochastic Heterogeneous Traffic Flow with Human-Driven Vehicles Under Communication Delay and Disturbances. <i>Actuators</i><b>14</b>(5), 246&#x2013;246 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/act14050246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, D., Siwach, V. &amp; Redhu, P. The interplay of passing, driver attention, and cyber attack-induced information delays on traffic stability. <i>Chaos, Solitons and Fractals: Interdiscip. J. Nonlinear Sci. Nonequilibrium Complex Phenom.</i><b>31</b>(6), 116366&#x2013;116366 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2025.116366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhao M, Liu X, et al., Vehicle-cloud cooperative hierarchical optimization control for mixed traffic in the bottleneck area of the tunnel entrance [J]. International Journal of Modern Physics C, (prepublish):127&#x2013;131. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, D. et al. Analyzing the impact of adjacent lane dynamics on traffic stability under passing and driver attention in a two-lane scenario. <i>Int. J. Non-Linear Mech.</i><b>17</b>(2), 105040&#x2013;105040 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnonlinmec.2025.105040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen, L. B. et al. Study on traffic flows with connected vehicles and human-driven vehicles. <i>Appl. Math. Comput.</i><b>4</b>(9), 129182&#x2013;129182 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. A traffic flow forecasting method based on hybrid spatial&#x2013;temporal gated convolution. <i>Int. J. Mach. Learn. Cybern.</i><b>16</b>(3), 1&#x2013;13 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, L., Zheng, F. &amp; Liu, X. Uncertainty, Efficiency, and Stability of Mixed Traffic Flow: Stochastic Model-Based Analyses. <i>Transp. Res. Rec.</i><b>2678</b>(8), 336&#x2013;357 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03611981231215338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J. Study of the effect of traffic and static loads on the stability and deformation of shallow urban utility tunnels. <i>Multiscale Multidiscip. Model. Exp. Design</i><b>7</b>(6), 5317&#x2013;5331 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41939-024-00495-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, L., Du, Z. &amp; Wu, K. Evaluation of Traffic Signs Information Volume at Highway Tunnel Entrance Zone Based on Driver&#x2019;s Visual Characteristics. <i>Transp. Res. Rec.</i><b>2678</b>(6), 804&#x2013;823 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03611981231200228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Gao, P. &amp; Wei, C. Practical Exponential Stability of Uncertain Nonlinear Delayed Urban Traffic Systems. <i>Eng. Lett.</i><b>32</b>(5), 46&#x2013;49 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Z. et al. Linear internal stability for mixed traffic flow of CAVs with different automation levels. <i>Physica A</i><b>6</b>(42), 129759&#x2013;129763 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physa.2024.129759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong, T., Li, Y. &amp; Qin, Y. Enhancing stability of traffic flow mixed with connected automated vehicles via enabling partial regular vehicles with vehicle-to-vehicle communication function. <i>Physica A</i><b>6</b>(41), 1297500&#x2013;1297504 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, J. et al. Dynamic traffic safety risk assessment in road tunnel entrance zone based on drivers&#x2019; psychophysiological perception states: Methodology and case-study insights. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Sp. Technol. Inc. Trenchless Technol. Res.</i><b>14</b>(7), 105677&#x2013;105678 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Z. et al. A microscopic traffic flow model for explaining nonlinear traffic phenomena: Modeling, stability analysis and validation. <i>Mod. Phys. Lett. B</i><b>38</b>(29), 78&#x2013;82 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0217984924502701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneguzzer, C. Stability of Traffic Equilibria in a Day-to-Day Dynamic Model of Route Choice and Adaptive Signal Control. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>(5), 56&#x2013;61 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14051891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai, W. H., Xu, L., Zhang, T. &amp; Liu, D. W. Bifurcation Analysis of the Macroscopic Traffic Flow Model Based on Driver&#x2019;s Anticipation and Traffic Jerk Effect. <i>Fluid Dyn.</i><b>58</b>(8), 1395&#x2013;1419 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S0015462823601249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Modeling and analysis of mixed traffic flow capacity and stability considering human-driven vehicle drivers&#x2019; trust attitude towards intelligent connected vehicles. <i>Physica A</i><b>63</b>(5), 129486&#x2013;129489 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physa.2023.129486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, L., Du, Z. &amp; Ma, A. Evaluation of traffic signs information volume at highway tunnel entrance zone based on the visual sample entropy of novice and experienced drivers. <i>Traffic Inj. Prev.</i><b>25</b>(3), 11&#x2013;11 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15389588.2023.2300645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, Y., Zhong, L. &amp; Zhong, X. Study of stability and object tracking of traffic video image for smart cities. <i>Pers. Ubiquit. Comput.</i><b>28</b>(2), 431&#x2013;442 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00779-024-01786-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, J., Liu, Y. &amp; Li, Z. A speed optimization model for connected and autonomous vehicles at expressway tunnel entrance under mixed traffic environment. <i>PLoS ONE</i><b>19</b>(12), e0314044 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0314044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11627392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39652614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrtagic, S. et al. AI-Enabled Assessment of Roadway Integrity: Forecasting Bitumen Deformation and Road Stability Throughout the Lifecycle Under Traffic Impact. <i>Int. J. Transp. Dev. Integr.</i><b>7</b>(4), 471&#x2013;475 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18280/ijtdi.070406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lihua, L. et al. Stabilizing traffic flow by autonomous vehicles: Stability analysis and implementation considerations. <i>Transp. Res. Part C</i><b>158</b>(2), 104449&#x2013;104453 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijie, Y., Xuedong, H. &amp; Wei, W. Stability and capacity for heterogeneous traffic flow mixed with vehicles in multiple controls [J]. <i>Transp. B: Transp. Dyn.</i><b>11</b>(1), 649&#x2013;682 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanyan, Q., Qinzhong, L. &amp; Hua, W. Stability analysis and connected vehicles management for mixed traffic flow with platoons of connected automated vehicles. <i>Transp. Res. Part C</i><b>157</b>, 104370 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trc.2023.104370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, J. Research on Traffic Safety at Tunnel Entrance and Exit. <i>J. Arch. Res. Dev.</i><b>7</b>(1), 69&#x2013;72 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhihong, Y. et al. Fundamental diagram and stability of mixed traffic flow considering platoon size and intensity of connected automated vehicles. <i>Physica A</i><b>604</b>(6), 749&#x2013;753 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>