<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41795034</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhanced forecasting of friction and cohesion of augmented unsaturated soil with nanostructured quarry fines (NQF) addition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8899</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43458-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shear strength parameters such as friction angle and cohesion are fundamental to solving geotechnical engineering problems related to slope stability, foundation design, and earthwork construction. This study presents the prediction of friction angle (Fi) and cohesion (Nc) of an unsaturated lateritic soil using three intelligent learning techniques: Support Vector Machine (SVM), Radial Basis Function (RBF), and Multilayer Perceptron (MLP), with Linear Multivariate Regression (LMR) adopted as a baseline model to evaluate agreement between input and output variables. The motivation for employing machine learning approaches stems from the limitations of complex laboratory testing and the need for reliable predictive tools that can support design and field applications. The investigated soil, classified as A-7-6 and poorly graded, exhibited coefficients of uniformity and curvature of 2.05 and 0.84, respectively. It was characterized by high plasticity and significant clay content, with a clay fraction of 23.02%, clay activity of 2, friction angle of 15&#xb0;, maximum dry density of 1.84&#xa0;g/cm3 at an optimum moisture content of 16.2%, and was tested under cyclic direct shear conditions. Multiple datasets were generated from varying treatment conditions and soil descriptors, forming the basis for model development. Eleven input parameters were used to predict Fi and Nc, and model performance was evaluated using Variance Accounted For (VAF), Root Mean Square Error (RMSE), Mean Absolute Error (MAE), and coefficient of determination (R2). The results indicate that RBF and MLP outperformed SVM and LMR in both training and testing phases for predicting cohesion and friction angle, demonstrating superior generalization capability. Sensitivity analysis using the Cosine Domain Method revealed that unsaturated unit weight had the greatest influence on friction angle prediction, while clay content was the most influential parameter for cohesion. Among all models, MLP achieved the highest accuracy and overall predictive performance. Based on this optimal model, a Graphical User Interface was developed to enable users to input soil parameters and obtain rapid predictions, providing a practical tool for researchers and practitioners in geotechnical engineering.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamchoom</LastName><ForeName>Viroon</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Excellent Center for Green and Sustainable Infrastructure, Department of Civil Engineering, School of Engineering, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang (KMITL), Bangkok, 10520, Thailand. viroon.ka@kmitl.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van</LastName><ForeName>Duc Bui</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Kampala International University, Western Campus, Kampala, Uganda. buivand738@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Shahab</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alimoradijazi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammadreza</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, K. N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amini-Khoshalan</LastName><ForeName>Hasel</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Kurdistan, Kurdistan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaghorbanali</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, University of Southern Queensland, Springfield, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shokri</LastName><ForeName>Behshad Jodeiri</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Senior Researcher, University of Southern Queensland, Springfield, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arunachalam</LastName><ForeName>Krishna Prakash</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Ciencias de la Construcci&#xf3;n, Facultad de Ciencias de la Construcci&#xf3;n Ordenamiento Territorial, Universidad Tecnol&#xf3;gica Metropolitana, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanostructured Quarry Fines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shear Failures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unsaturated Soil, Graphical User Interface</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41795034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12987958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43458-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43458-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shen, J. &amp; Jimenez, R. Predicting the shear strength parameters of sandstone using genetic programming. <i>Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ.</i><b>77</b>, 1647&#x2013;1662 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-017-1023-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoodzadeh, A. et al. Machine learning techniques to predict rock strength parameters. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>55</b>, 1721&#x2013;1741 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-021-02747-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandelwal, M. et al. Implementing an ANN model optimized by genetic algorithm for estimating cohesion of limestone samples. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>34</b>, 307&#x2013;317 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-017-0541-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiba, M., Ibrahim, A. F., Elkatatny, S. &amp; Ali, A. Prediction of cohesion and friction angle from well-logging data using decision tree and random forest. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>, 26 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-021-09154-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kainthola, A. et al. Prediction of strength parameters of Himalayan rocks: A statistical and ANFIS approach. <i>Geotech. Geol. Eng.</i>10.1007/s10706-015-9899-z (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-015-9899-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonmez, H., Gokceoglu, C., Nefeslioglu, H. A. &amp; Kayabasi, A. Estimation of rock modulus: For intact rocks with an artificial neural network and for rock masses with a new empirical equation. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>43</b>, 224&#x2013;235 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2005.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorlu, K., Gokceoglu, C., Ocakoglu, F., Nefeslioglu, H. A. &amp; Acikalin, S. Prediction of uniaxial compressive strength of sandstones using petrography-based models. <i>Eng. Geol.</i><b>96</b>, 141&#x2013;158 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2007.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik, A., Sezer, E. A., Cabalar, A. F. &amp; Gokceoglu, C. Modeling of the uniaxial compressive strength of some clay-bearing rocks using neural network. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i>10.1016/j.asoc.2010.10.008 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2010.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabalar, A. F., Cevik, A. &amp; Gokceoglu, C. Some applications of Adaptive Neuro-Fuzzy Inference System (ANFIS) in geotechnical engineering. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i>10.1016/j.compgeo.2011.09.008 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2011.09.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C., Ebid, A. M., Nwobia, L. &amp; Dao-Phuc, L. Prediction and performance analysis of compression index of multiple-binder-treated soil by genetic programming approach. <i>Nanotechnol. Environ. Eng.</i>10.1007/s41204-021-00123-2 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41204-021-00123-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K., Igboayaka, C., Orji, F., Ugwuanyi, H. &amp; Van, D. B. Triaxial and density behaviour of quarry dust based geopolymer cement treated expansive soil with crushed waste glasses for pavement foundation purposes. <i>Int. J. Pavement Res. Technol.</i><b>12</b>, 78&#x2013;87. 10.1007/s42947-019-0010-7 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42947-019-0010-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Swelling potential of clayey soil modified with rice husk ash activated by calcination for pavement underlay by plasticity index method (PIM). <i>Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i>10.1155/2021/6688519 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6688519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Application of 3-algorithm ANN programming to predict the strength performance of hydrated-lime activated rice husk ash treated soil, Springer. 1 3. (1939). 10.1007/s41939-021-00093-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. &amp; Shakeri, J. Intelligent prediction of coefficients of curvature and uniformity of hybrid cement modified unsaturated soil with NQF inclusion. <i>Clean. Eng. Technol.</i>10.1016/j.clet.2021.100152 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clet.2021.100152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Application of ANFIS hybrids to predict coefficients of curvature and uniformity of treated unsaturated lateritic soil for sustainable earthworks. <i>Clean. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.clema.2021.100005 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clema.2021.100005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeri, J., Shokri, B. J. &amp; Dehghani, H. Prediction of blast-induced ground vibration using gene expression programming (GEP), artificial neural networks (ANNS), and linear multivariate regression (LMR). <i>Arch. Min. Sci.</i><b>65</b>, 317&#x2013;335. 10.24425/ams.2020.133195 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24425/ams.2020.133195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeri, J., Bascompta, M., Alimoradijazi, M. &amp; Dehghani, H. Application of artificial intelligence techniques for predicting the flyrock, Sungun Mine, Iran. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>16</b>(8), 488 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-023-11561-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jodeiri Shokri, B., Dehghani, H. &amp; Shamsi, R. Predicting silver price by applying a coupled multiple linear regression (MLR) and imperialist competitive algorithm (ICA). <i>Metaheuristic Comput. Appl.</i><b>1</b>, 101&#x2013;114. 10.12989/mca.2020.1.1.101 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12989/mca.2020.1.1.101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili, M. et al. Multiple regression, ANN and ANFIS models for prediction of backbreak in the open pit blasting. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>30</b>, 549&#x2013;558. 10.1007/s00366-012-0298-2 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-012-0298-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Mousavi, A. &amp; Monjezi, M. Prediction of blast-induced dust emissions in surface mines using integration of dimensional analysis and multivariate regression analysis. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>, 163. 10.1007/s12517-021-09376-2 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-021-09376-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monjezi, M., Dehghani, H., Shakeri, J. &amp; Mehrdanesh, A. Optimization of prediction of flyrock using linear multivariate regression (LMR) and gene expression programming (GEP)&#x2014;Topal Novin mine, Iran. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i>10.1007/S12517-021-07772-2 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S12517-021-07772-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moomivand, H., Khoshalan, H. A., Shakeri, J. &amp; Vandyousefi, H. Development of new comprehensive relations to assess rock fragmentation by blasting for different open-pit mines using GEP algorithm and MLR procedure. <i>Int. J. Min. Geo-Engineering.</i><b>56</b>, 401&#x2013;411. 10.22059/IJMGE.2022.339174.594951 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22059/IJMGE.2022.339174.594951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>vapnik 1998 statistical learning theory - Google Scholar, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smola, A. J. &amp; Scholkopf, B. A tutorial on support vector regression. (1998). NeuroCOLT2. Univ. London, London, UK, Tech. Rep. NC2-TR-1998-030. - Google Search, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amini, H., Gholami, R., Monjezi, M., Torabi, S. R. &amp; Zadhesh, J. Evaluation of flyrock phenomenon due to blasting operation by support vector machine. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i>10.1007/s00521-011-0631-5 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-011-0631-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Support vector machine (SVM) prediction of coefficients of curvature and uniformity of hybrid cement modified unsaturated soil with NQF inclusion. <i>Clean. Eng. Technol.</i>10.1016/j.clet.2021.100290 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clet.2021.100290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibike, Y. B., Velickov, S., Solomatine, D. &amp; Abbott, M. B. Model induction with support vector machines: Introduction and applications. <i>J. Comput. Civ. Eng.</i><b>15</b>, 208&#x2013;216. 10.1061/(asce)0887-3801(2001)15:3(208) (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0887-3801(2001)15:3(208)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samui, P. &amp; Sitharam, T. G. Least-square support vector machine applied to settlement of shallow foundations on cohesionless soils. <i>Int. J. Numer. Anal. Methods Geomech.</i><b>32</b>, 2033&#x2013;2043. 10.1002/nag.731 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nag.731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J., Hosseini, S., Chen, Q. &amp; Armaghani, D. J. Super learner ensemble model: A novel approach for predicting monthly copper price in future. <i>Resour. Policy</i><b>85</b>, 103903 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resourpol.2023.103903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoj, K. &amp; Monjezi, M. Prediction of flyrock in open pit blasting operation using machine learning method. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i>10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.05.005 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandelwal, M. &amp; Kankar, P. K. Prediction of blast-induced air overpressure using support vector machine. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>4</b>, 427&#x2013;433. 10.1007/s12517-009-0092-7 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-009-0092-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. et al. Evolving support vector regression using grey wolf optimization; forecasting the geomechanical properties of rock. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>38</b>, 1819&#x2013;1833. 10.1007/s00366-020-01131-7 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-020-01131-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanipanah, M., Monjezi, M., Shahnazar, A., Jahed Armaghani, D. &amp; Farazmand, A. Feasibility of indirect determination of blast induced ground vibration based on support vector machine. <i>Meas. J. Int. Meas. Confed</i>. 10.1016/j.measurement.2015.07.019 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2015.07.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, Z. &amp; Li, H. Recognition and prediction of ground vibration signal based on machine learning algorithm. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>32</b>, 1937&#x2013;1947. 10.1007/s00521-019-04496-z (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-019-04496-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Monjezi, M., Bakhtavar, E. &amp; Mousavi, A. Prediction of dust emission due to open pit mine blasting using a hybrid artificial neural network. <i>Nat. Resour. Res.</i>10.1007/s11053-021-09930-5 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11053-021-09930-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. S., Ong, Z. C., Ismail, Z. &amp; Khoo, S. Y. A comparative study of vibrational response based impact force localization and quantification using radial basis function network and multilayer perceptron. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>85</b>, 87&#x2013;98. 10.1016/j.eswa.2017.05.027 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2017.05.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broomhead, D. &amp; Lowe D. S. and Multivariable Functional Interpolation and Adaptive Networks, Complex Syst. 2 321&#x2013;355. (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeri, J., Asadizadeh, M. &amp; Babanouri, N. The prediction of dynamic energy behavior of a Brazilian disk containing nonpersistent joints subjected to drop hammer test utilizing heuristic approaches. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>34</b>, 9777&#x2013;9792 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-022-06964-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhtavar, E., Hosseini, S., Hewage, K. &amp; Sadiq, R. Green blasting policy: Simultaneous forecast of vertical and horizontal distribution of dust emissions using artificial causality-weighted neural network. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>283</b>, 124562. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124562 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeri, J., Khoshalan, H. A., Dehghani, H., Bascompta, M. &amp; Onyelowe, K. Developing new models for flyrock distance assessment in open-pit mines. <i>J. Min. Environ.</i><b>13</b>, 377&#x2013;391. 10.22044/jme.2022.11805.2170 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22044/jme.2022.11805.2170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Poormirzaee, R., Gilani, S. O. &amp; Jiskani, I. M. A reliability-based rock engineering system for clean blasting: risk analysis and dust emissions forecasting. <i>Clean. Technol. Environ. Policy</i> 1&#x2013;18. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson, P. K. (1990). Artificial neural system&#x2014;foundat&#x2026; Google Scholar, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Atterberg limits of modified compacted clayey soil for sustainable green subgrade structure. <i>J. Kejuruteraan</i><b>33</b>, 651&#x2013;659. 10.17576/jkukm-2021-33(3)-23 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17576/jkukm-2021-33(3)-23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C618 (1978). Specification for fly ash and raw&#x2026; Google Scholar, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BS 1377&#x2013;2, 3. Methods of Testing Soils for Civil Engineering Purposes, British Standard Institute, London. - Google Search, (n.d.). (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unidos, E. <i>American Standard for Testing and Materials</i> 63 (ASTM, 2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BS 1924. 1990. Methods of Tests for Stabilized Soil&#x2026; Google Scholar, (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Poormirzaee, R. &amp; Hajihassani, M. An uncertainty hybrid model for risk assessment and prediction of blast-induced rock mass fragmentation. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>160</b>, 105250 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2022.105250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Pourmirzaee, R., Armaghani, D. J. &amp; Sabri Sabri, M. M. Prediction of ground vibration due to mine blasting in a surface lead&#x2013;zinc mine using machine learning ensemble techniques. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 6591 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-33796-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10121721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37085660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Mousavi, A., Monjezi, M. &amp; Khandelwal, M. Mine-to-crusher policy: Planning of mine blasting patterns for environmentally friendly and optimum fragmentation using Monte Carlo simulation-based multi-objective grey wolf optimization approach. <i>Resour. Policy</i><b>79</b>, 103087 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resourpol.2022.103087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Hosseini, S., Armaghani, D. J. &amp; Mohamad, E. T. Data-driven optimized artificial neural network technique for prediction of flyrock induced by boulder blasting. <i>Mathematics</i><b>11</b>, 2358 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11102358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platt, J. C. <i>Sequential Minimal Optimization: A Fast Algorithm for Training Support Vector Machines Graph Embedding View project ClearType View project Sequential Minimal Optimization</i> (A Fast Algorithm for Training Support Vector Machines, 1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandelwal, M. Blast-induced ground vibration prediction using support vector machine. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>27</b>, 193&#x2013;200. 10.1007/s00366-010-0190-x (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-010-0190-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagan, M. T. &amp; Menhaj, M. B. Training feedforward networks with the Marquardt algorithm. <i>IEEE Trans. Neural Netw.</i><b>5</b>, 989&#x2013;993. 10.1109/72.329697 (1994).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/72.329697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18267874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armaghani, D. J., Hasanipanah, M. &amp; Mohamad, E. T. A combination of the ICA-ANN model to predict air-overpressure resulting from blasting. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>32</b>, 155&#x2013;171 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-015-0408-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahani, N. M. et al. Predicting angle of internal friction and cohesion of rocks based on machine learning algorithms. <i>Mathematics</i>10.3390/math10203875 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10203875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faradonbeh, R. S. et al. Harnessing machine learning for seismic event discrimination in deep underground mining: a case study from Western Australia. In Deep Mining 2024: Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Deep and High Stress Mining (pp. 831&#x2013;852). (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeri, J. et al. Intelligent approaches for predicting the intact rock mechanical parameters and crack stress thresholds. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>57</b>(10), 8499&#x2013;8528 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-03959-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. &amp; Zhang, Q. A hierarchical analysis for rock engineering using artificial neural networks. <i>Rock. Mech. Rock. Eng.</i><b>30</b>, 207&#x2013;222 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01045717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. et al. Optimal compressive strength of RHA ultra-high-performance lightweight concrete (UHPLC) and its environmental performance using life cycle assessment. <i>Civ. Eng. J.</i><b>8</b>, 2391&#x2013;2410. 10.28991/CEJ-2022-08-11-03 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.28991/CEJ-2022-08-11-03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C., Shakeri, J., Amini-Khoshalan, H., Usungedo, T. F. &amp; Alimoradi-Jazi, M. Computational modeling of desiccation properties (CW, LS, and VS) of waste-based activated ash-treated Black Cotton Soil for sustainable subgrade using Artificial Neural Network, Gray-Wolf, and Moth-Flame optimization techniques. <i>Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i>10.1155/2022/4602064 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/4602064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>