<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41704967</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevention of Lower Limb Muscle Atrophy With Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation in a Patient With Tachycardia-Induced Cardiomyopathy Secondary to Thyroid Storm: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101732</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101732</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101732</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101732</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathy (TIC) is reversible; however, the acute phase is often accompanied by hemodynamic instability, which makes conventional exercise therapy difficult to implement. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) has been suggested as a potential alternative strategy to prevent muscle atrophy. Herein, we report a case in which NMES was used in a patient during the acute phase of TIC, secondary to thyroid storm, highlighting its safety and potential effectiveness. A male in his 40s was diagnosed with TIC associated with thyroid storm. On admission, the patient presented with atrial fibrillation, severe cardiac dysfunction with a left ventricular ejection fraction of 19%, and markedly elevated thyroid hormone levels. Due to unstable hemodynamics, conventional exercise therapy was deferred, and NMES was initiated on day nine of hospitalization, and it was continued until day 12. It was performed once daily for 20 minutes. Muscle ultrasonography revealed that quadriceps muscle thickness had decreased by approximately 5% during hospitalization. Importantly, no hemodynamic deterioration or adverse events were observed. From day 13, aerobic exercises using a cycle ergometer and resistance training were initiated. The patient achieved a six-minute walk distance of 545 m and was discharged on day 28. NMES was safely implemented without adverse events, even during periods of hemodynamic instability in a patient with TIC. In situations where conventional exercise therapy is limited due to hemodynamic instability, NMES may represent a feasible intervention option. The findings of this single case are hypothesis-generating and warrant further investigation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Sato et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Shinya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shimane University Hospital, Izumo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imaoka</LastName><ForeName>Kei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shimane University Hospital, Izumo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakao</LastName><ForeName>Shuri</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shimane University Hospital, Izumo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egusa</LastName><ForeName>Norimasa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shimane University Hospital, Izumo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maniwa</LastName><ForeName>Sokichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Shimane University Faculty of Medicine, Izumo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac rehabilitation (cr)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid storm</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41704967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12908502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arrhythmia-induced cardiomyopathy: JACC State-of-the-Art Review. Huizar JF, Ellenbogen KA, Tan AY, Kaszala K. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:2328&#x2013;2344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31072578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathy: a review of animal models and clinical studies. Shinbane JS, Wood MA, Jensen DN, Ellenbogen KA, Fitzpatrick AP, Scheinman MM. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997;29:709&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9091514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LV and myocyte structure and function after early recovery from tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathy. Spinale FG, Holzgrefe HH, Mukherjee R, Arthur SR, Child MJ, Powell JR, Koster WH. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:0&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7864211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JCS/JACR 2021 guideline on rehabilitation in patients with cardiovascular disease. Makita S, Yasu T, Akashi YJ, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36503954/ Circ J. 2022;87:155&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36503954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromuscular electrical stimulation is feasible in patients with acute heart failure. Kondo T, Yamada S, Tanimura D, et al. ESC Heart Fail. 2019;6:975&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6816057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31461577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety of neuromuscular electrical stimulation among critically ill patients: systematic review. Sachetti A, Carpes MF, Dias AS, Sbruzzi G. Rev Bras Ter Intensiva. 2018;30:219&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6031422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29995088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2016 guidelines for the management of thyroid storm from the Japan Thyroid Association and Japan Endocrine Society (First edition) Satoh T, Isozaki O, Suzuki A, et al. Endocr J. 2016;63:1025&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of acute phase intensive electrical muscle stimulation in frail elderly patients with acute heart failure (ACTIVE-EMS): rationale and protocol for a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Tanaka S, Kamiya K, Matsue Y, et al. Clin Cardiol. 2017;40:1189&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6490620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29247531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromuscular electrical stimulation may attenuate muscle proteolysis after cardiovascular surgery: a preliminary study. Iwatsu K, Iida Y, Kono Y, Yamazaki T, Usui A, Yamada S. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2017;153:373&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27793340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound-measured quadriceps muscle thickness and mortality in older patients with heart failure. Saito H, Fujimoto Y, Matsue Y, et al. Can J Cardiol. 2024;40:2555&#x2013;2564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39270750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The accuracy of volume estimates using ultrasound muscle thickness measurements in different muscle groups. Miyatani M, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;91:264&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14569399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedside ultrasound is a practical and reliable measurement tool for assessing quadriceps muscle layer thickness. Tillquist M, Kutsogiannis DJ, Wischmeyer PE, et al. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2014;38:886&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4502435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23980134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of electrical muscle stimulation on the reduction of muscle volume loss in acute heart failure patients. Matsuo K, Yoneki K, Tatsuki H, et al. Int Heart J. 2022;63:1141&#x2013;1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36450554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Electrical muscle stimulation preserves the muscle mass of critically ill patients: a randomized study. Gerovasili V, Stefanidis K, Vitzilaios K, et al. Crit Care. 2009;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2784391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19814793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In-hospital electrical muscle stimulation for patients early after heart failure decompensation: results from a prospective randomised controlled pilot trial. Poltavskaya M, Sviridenko V, Giverts I, et al. Open Heart. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35817498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glucocorticoid-induced skeletal muscle atrophy. Schakman O, Kalista S, Barb&#xe9; C, Loumaye A, Thissen JP. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2013;45:2163&#x2013;2172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23806868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steroid myopathy in cancer patients. Batchelor TT, Taylor LP, Thaler HT, Posner JB, DeAngelis LM. Neurology. 1997;48:1234&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9153449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromuscular electrical stimulation reduces skeletal muscle protein degradation and stimulates insulin-like growth factors in an age- and current-dependent manner: a randomized, controlled clinical trial in major abdominal surgical patients. Strasser EM, St&#xe4;ttner S, Karner J, et al. Ann Surg. 2009;249:738&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyroid hormones and skeletal muscle&#x2014;new insights and potential implications. Salvatore D, Simonides WS, Dentice M, Zavacki AM, Larsen PR. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2014;10:206&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4037849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24322650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on physiologic and functional measurements in patients with heart failure: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Gomes Neto M, Oliveira FA, Reis HF, de Sousa Rodrigues E Jr, Bittencourt HS, Oliveira Carvalho V. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2016;36:157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26784735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>