<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731268</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Complex Training Versus Ballistic Training on Physical Fitness Abilities of Athletes and Healthy Individuals: A Systematic Review with Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02395-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The literature is equivocal on whether complex training (i.e., combining traditional resistance and ballistic exercises within a single session) is superior to ballistic training in improving physical fitness qualities. This systematic review with meta-analysis aims to compare the effects of complex and ballistic training on physical fitness outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search using the PRISMA 2020 guidelines was conducted in electronic databases (i.e., PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science). From the included studies, data were extracted for linear sprint, vertical jump (i.e., countermovement jump, squat jump), change of direction speed, and maximal strength. The risk of bias of the included studies was assessed using RoB-2 and ROBINS-I tools for randomized and nonrandomized studies, respectively. The meta-analyses were computed using a DerSimonian and Laird random effects model, reporting Hedges' g effect size (ES) with 95% confidence and prediction intervals. Statistical significance was set at p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05. In addition, the certainty of evidence was assessed using the GRADE approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 20 studies were initially eligible. However, one study was excluded owing to critical concerns at risk of bias assessment stage. Thereafter, 19 studies involving 537 participants ranging from "tier 0" (i.e., sedentary) to "tier 3" (i.e., highly trained) level were included. Randomized studies presented low (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;2), some (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;10), and high concerns (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;5) regarding the risk of bias, while nonrandomized studies presented moderate concerns (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;2). Compared with ballistic training, significantly greater improvements were reported after complex training for one-repetition maximum (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.12, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.010), squat jump (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.37, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004), 10&#xa0;m (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.67, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.033), and 40&#xa0;m (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.72, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005) linear sprint. Furthermore, a significant moderating effect of training duration was observed for complex training, favoring longer (&gt;&#x2009;7.5&#xa0;weeks) interventions. The certainty of the evidence was low for the squat jump and very low for all other outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest complex training to be superior in improving one-repetition maximum squat, squat jump, 10&#xa0;m, and 40&#xa0;m linear sprint compared with ballistic training alone. However, 5&#xa0;m, 20&#xa0;m, change of direction speed, countermovement jump, and jump power were similarly improved after both training methods. In addition, a longer intervention duration (&gt;&#x2009;7.5&#xa0;weeks) may optimize complex training effects. However, the certainty of the evidence was low for the squat jump and very low for all other outcomes. To increase confidence in the certainty of the current evidence, and therefore to provide robust recommendations favoring (or not) the use of complex training (and its prescription factors) over ballistic training to improve participants' physical fitness, more robust studies would be required (e.g., larger samples).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROTOCOL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The protocol was published in the Open Science Framework (OSF) platform on 13/04/2024 (DOI: https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/STUZ7 ; Archive link: https://archive.org/details/osf-registrations-stuz7-v1 ).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapa</LastName><ForeName>Rohit K</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1258-9065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis School of Sports Sciences, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, 412115, India. rohit.thapa@ssss.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagchi</LastName><ForeName>Amritashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Somaiya Sports Academy, Somaiya Vidyavihar University, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uysal</LastName><ForeName>H&#xfc;seyin &#x15e;ahin</ForeName><Initials>H&#x15e;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Burdur Mehmet Akif Ersoy University, Burdur, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talukdar</LastName><ForeName>Kaushik</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Sport and Exercise Science, Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afonso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramirez-Campillo</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Universidad Andres Bello, 7591538, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Sciences and Human Performance Laboratories, Instituto de Alta Investigaci&#xf3;n, Universidad de Tarapac&#xe1;, Arica, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Consent for Publication:: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material:: All data generated or analyzed during this study are included in the article as tables, figures, and/or Electronic Supplementary Material. Any other data requirement can be directed to the corresponding author upon reasonable request. Competing Interests: Rohit K. Thapa, Amritashish Bagchi, H&#xfc;seyin &#x15e;ahin Uysal, Kaushik Talukdar, Jose Afonso, and Rodrigo Ramirez-Campillo declare that they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this review. Authors&#x2019; Contributions: RKT and RRC conceived the idea and design for the article. RKT, AB, and RRC conducted the literature review and/or performed the data acquisition. RKT and RRC conducted the formal analysis and/or interpretation of the data. RKT, AB, HSU, KT, JA, and RRC drafted and/or critically revised the work. All authors have read and approved the manuscript and have agreed both to be personally accountable for the author's own contributions and to ensure that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work, even those in which the author were not personally involved, are appropriately investigated, resolved, and the resolution documented in the literature.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02395-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02395-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhong Y, Weldon A, Bishop C, Li Y. Practices of strength and conditioning coaches across Chinese high-performance sports. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2023;18(5):1442&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541231176491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos CS, Pinto JR, Scoz RD, Alves BM, Oliveira PR, Soares WJ, et al. What is the traditional method of resistance training: a systematic review. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2022;62(9):1191&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33721981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12112-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Golas A, Stastny P, Nawrocka M, Krzysztofik M, Zajac A. Does tempo of resistance exercise impact training volume? J Hum Kinet. 2018;62:241&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6006544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, McGuigan MR, Freitas TT, Bishop C, Zabaloy S, Mercer VP, et al. Half-squat and jump squat exercises performed across a range of loads: differences in mechanical outputs and strength deficits. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(5):1052&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Training for muscular power. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2000;11(2):341&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10810765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1047-9651(18)30133-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormier P, Freitas TT, Loturco I, Turner A, Virgile A, Haff GG, et al. Within session exercise sequencing during programming for complex training: historical perspectives, terminology, and training considerations. Sports Med. 2022;52(10):2371&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01715-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;thi JM, Howald H, Claassen H, R&#xf6;sler K, Vock P, Hoppeler H. Structural changes in skeletal muscle tissue with heavy-resistance exercise. Int J Sports Med. 1986;7(3):123&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2942497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight CA, Kamen G. Adaptations in muscular activation of the knee extensor muscles with strength training in young and older adults. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2001;11(6):405&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1050-6411(01)00023-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(8):1582&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181d2013a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaras N, Spengos K, Methenitis S, Papadopoulos C, Karampatsos G, Georgiadis G, et al. Effects of strength vs. ballistic-power training on throwing performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2013;12(1):130&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moir GL, Munford SN, Moroski LL, Davis SE. The effects of ballistic and nonballistic bench press on mechanical variables. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(12):3333&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28225524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney SJ, Turner AN, Fletcher IM. Ballistic exercise as a pre-activation stimulus: a review of the literature and practical applications. Sports Med. 2014;44(10):1347&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24943044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0214-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Haugen T, Freitas TT, Bishop C, Moura TBMA, Mercer VP, et al. Strength and conditioning practices of Brazilian olympic sprint and jump coaches. J Hum Kinet. 2023;86(1):175&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37181261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10170547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/jhk/159646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa RK, Lum D, Moran J, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of complex training on sprint, jump, and change of direction ability of soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Psychol. 2021;11:627869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7862112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.627869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa RK, Narvariya P, Weldon A, Talukdar K, Ramirez-Campillo R. Can complex contrast training interventions improve aerobic endurance, maximal strength, and repeated sprint ability in soccer players? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Monten J Sports Sci Med. 2022;11(2):45&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26773/mjssm.220906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormier P, Freitas TT, Rubio-Arias J, Alcaraz PE. Complex and contrast training: does strength and power training sequence affect performance-based adaptations in team sports? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1461&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32084104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas TT, Martinez-Rodriguez A, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Alcaraz PE. Short-term adaptations following complex training in team-sports: a meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(6):e0180223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28662108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5491153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0180223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer P, Uebellacker F, Mitter B, Aigner AJ, Hasenoehrl T, Ristl R, et al. Combining higher-load and lower-load resistance training exercises: a systematic review and meta-analysis of findings from complex training studies. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(7):838&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30683485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagaduan J, Schoenfeld BJ, Pojskic H. Systematic review and meta-analysis on the effect of contrast training on vertical jump performance. Strength Cond J. 2019;41(3):63&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagaduan J, Pojskic H. A meta-analysis on the effect of complex training on vertical jump performance. J Hum Kinet. 2020;71:255&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32148589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7052715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2019-0087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Asadi A, Roohi S. Enhancing muscular performance in women: compound versus complex, traditional resistance and plyometric training alone. J Musculoskelet Res. 2014;17(2):1450007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218957714500079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito J, Vasconcellos F, Oliveira J, Krustrup P, Rebelo A. Short-term performance effects of three different low-volume strength-training programmes in college male soccer players. J Hum Kinet. 2014;40:121&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4096099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammami M, Gaamouri N, Shephard RJ, Chelly MS. Effects of contrast strength vs. plyometric training on lower-limb explosive performance, ability to change direction and neuromuscular adaptation in soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2094&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de S&#xe1;ez Villarreal E, Requena B, Izquierdo M, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Enhancing sprint and strength performance: combined versus maximal power, traditional heavy-resistance and plyometric training. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16(2):146&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.05.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berriel GP, Cardoso AS, Costa RR, Rosa RG, Oliveira HB, Kruel LFM, et al. Does complex training enhance vertical jump performance and muscle power in elite male volleyball players? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(4):586&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi A, Hammami R, Moran J, Borji R, Sahli S, Rebai H. Effect of a 16-week combined strength and plyometric training program followed by a detraining period on athletic performance in pubertal volleyball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2117&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29401199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobar-&#xc1;lvarez JA, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Da Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o FA, Fuentes-Garc&#xed;a JP. Effect of supplementary physical training on vertical jump height in professional ballet dancers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(8):1257&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abt G, Boreham C, Davison G, Jackson R, Nevill A, Wallace E, et al. Power, precision, and sample size estimation in sport and exercise science research. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(17):1933&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1776002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murad MH, Asi N, Alsawas M, Alahdab F. New evidence pyramid. Evid Based Med. 2016;21(4):125&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27339128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4975798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebmed-2016-110401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald CJ, Lamont HS, Garner JC. A comparison of the effects of 6 weeks of traditional resistance training, plyometric training, and complex training on measures of strength and anthropometrics. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(2):422&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220df79</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ, Haekkinen K. Effects of ballistic training on preseason preparation of elite volleyball players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(2):323&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199902000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Deeks J. Chapter 7: selecting studies and collecting data, pp 168&#x2013;182. In Higgins JPT, Green S (editors) Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 510 [updated March 2011] The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011 Available from wwwcochrane-handbookorg. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X, Wang W, Liu J, Tong T. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from the sample size, median, range and/or interquartile range. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4383202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-14-135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DK, In J, Lee S. Standard deviation and standard error of the mean. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2015;68(3):220&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26045923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4452664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4097/kjae.2015.68.3.220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of WebPlotDigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif. 2017;41(2):323&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27760807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0145445516673998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, Savovi&#x107; J, Berkman ND, Viswanathan M, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i4919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall IJ, Kuiper J, Wallace BC. RobotReviewer: evaluation of a system for automatically assessing bias in clinical trials. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2015;23(1):193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26104742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4713900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocv044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentine JC, Pigott TD, Rothstein HR. How many studies do you need? A primer on statistical power for meta-analysis. J Ed Behavioral Stat. 2010;35(2):215&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/1076998609346961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG. Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions: The Cochrane Collaboration; 2008, pp. 243&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontopantelis E, Springate DA, Reeves D. A re-analysis of the Cochrane Library data: the dangers of unobserved heterogeneity in meta-analyses. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(7):e69930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3724681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0069930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W, Cheung MW. Outlier and influence diagnostics for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1(2):112&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadlec D, Sainani KL, Nimphius S. With great power comes great responsibility: common errors in meta-analyses and meta-regressions in strength &amp; conditioning research. Sports Med. 2023;53(2):313&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36208412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01766-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.1186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Assessing risk of bias due to missing results in a synthesis. In: Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Second edition. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019, pp 365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JPA, Terrin N, Jones DR, Lau J, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d4002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315:629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Clemente FM, B&#xfc;ttner FC, Andrade R. The perils of misinterpreting and misusing &#x201c;Publication Bias&#x201d; in meta-analyses: sn education review on funnel plot-based methods. Sports Med. 2024;54(2):257&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37684502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01927-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L, Lin L. The trim-and-fill method for publication bias: practical guidelines and recommendations based on a large database of meta-analyses. Medicine. 2019;98(23):e15987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31169736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6571372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000015987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Thapa RK, Afonso J, Perez-Castilla A, Bishop C, Byrne PJ, et al. Effects of plyometric jump training on the reactive strength index in healthy individuals across the lifespan: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(5):1029&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36906633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10115703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01825-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Akl EA, Kunz R, Vist G, Brozek J, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):383&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Alonso-Coello P, Guyatt GH, Yepes-Nu&#xf1;ez JJ, Akl EA, Hazlewood G, et al. GRADE guidelines: 19. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences&#x2014;risk of bias and indirectness. J Clin Epidemiol. 2019;111:94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29452223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.01.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Coello PA, Guyatt GH, Yepes-Nu&#xf1;ez JJ, Akl EA, Hazlewood G, et al. GRADE guidelines: 20. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences - inconsistency, imprecision, and other domains. J Clin Epidemiol. 2019;111:83&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Brozek J, Alonso-Coello P, Rind D, et al. Corrigendum to GRADE guidelines 6. Rating the quality of evidence-imprecision. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:1283&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21839614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2011.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arabatzi F, Kellis E, Sa&#xe8;z-Saez De Villarreal E. Vertical jump biomechanics after plyometric, weight lifting, and combined (weight lifting + plyometric) training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(9):2440&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20706157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e274ab</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyttle AD, Wilson GJ, Ostrowski KJ. Enhancing performance: maximal power versus combined weights and plyometrics training. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10(3):173&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Saez Villarreal E, Izquierdo M, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Enhancing jump performance after combined vs. maximal power, heavy-resistance, and plyometric training alone. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3274&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22082794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182163085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd DJ, Alvar BA. Analysis of acute explosive training modalities to improve lower-body power in baseball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1177&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Jamurtas AZ, Leontsini D, Taxildaris K, Aggelousis N, Kostopoulos N, et al. Evaluation of plyometric exercise training, weight training, and their combination on vertical jumping performance and leg strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(4):470&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan N, Nuhmani S, Kachanathu SJ, Muaidi QI. Efficacy of complex training on angular velocity of shoulder in collegiate basketball players. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2018;31(5):859&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-170907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Radnor JM, Croix MBDS, Cronin JB, Oliver JL. Changes in sprint and jump performances after traditional, plyometric, and combined resistance training in male youth pre-and post-peak height velocity. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(5):1239&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radnor JM, Lloyd RS, Oliver JL. Individual response to different forms of resistance training in school-aged boys. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(3):787&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27379963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Sixto A, Harrison AJ, Flor&#xed;a P. Effects of plyometric vs. combined plyometric training on vertical jump biomechanics in female basketball players. J Hum Kinet. 2021;77(1):25&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8008314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2021-0009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelzke M, Stutzig N, Thorhauer HA, Granacher U. Promoting lower extremity strength in elite volleyball players: effects of two combined training methods. J Sci Med Sport. 2012;15(5):457&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22484082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali K, Gupta S, Hussain ME, Alzhrani M, Manzar MD, Khan M, et al. Effect of plyometric versus complex training on core strength, lower limb, and upper limb power in male cricketers: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38008712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10680285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00771-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukri&#x107; A, Karaleji&#x107; M, Jakovljevi&#x107; S, Petrovi&#x107; B, Mandi&#x107; R. Impact of different training methods to the maximum vertical jump height in junior basketball players. Fiz Kult. 2012;66(1):25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5937/fizkul1201025K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Hern&#xe1;n MA, McAleenan A, Reeves BC, Higgins JPT. Assessing risk of bias in a non-randomized study. In: Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Sanchez J, Rodriguez-Fernandez A, Granacher U, Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R. Plyometric jump training effects on maximal strength in soccer players: a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized-controlled studies. Sports Med Open. 2024;10(1):52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38727944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11087442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00720-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxfeldt M, Overgaard K, Hvid LG, Dalgas U. Effects of plyometric training on jumping, sprint performance, and lower body muscle strength in healthy adults: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analyses. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29(10):1453&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de S&#xe1;ez Villarreal E, Requena B, Newton RU. Does plyometric training improve strength performance? A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(5):513&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2009.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SJ, Oliver JL, Pedley JS, Haff GG, Lloyd RS. Comparison of weightlifting, traditional resistance training and plyometrics on strength, power and speed: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52(7):1533&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35025093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9213388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01627-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa RK, Uysal H, Clemente FM, Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of complex training compared to resistance training alone on physical fitness of healthy individuals: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(14):1367&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39163393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2391657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Hornsby WG, Suarez DG, Duca M, Pierce KC. Training specificity for athletes: emphasis on strength-power training: a narrative review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2022;7(4):102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9680266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk7040102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones EJ, Bishop PA, Woods AK, Green JM. Cross-sectional area and muscular strength: a brief review. Sports Med. 2008;38(12):987&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200838120-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrio ED, Thapa RK, Villanueva-Flores F, Garcia-Atutxa I, Santiba&#xf1;ez-Gutierrez A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Landa J, et al. Plyometric jump training exercise optimization for maximizing human performance: a systematic scoping review and identification of gaps in the existing literature. Sports. 2023;11(8):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37624130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10457889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports11080150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubac D, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B. Skeletal muscle contraction time and tone decrease after 8 weeks of plyometric training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(6):1610&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Mikulic P. Neuro-musculoskeletal and performance adaptations to lower-extremity plyometric training. Sports Med. 2010;40(10):859&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20836583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11318370-000000000-00000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93(4):1318&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00283.2002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waugh CM, Korff T, Fath F, Blazevich AJ. Effects of resistance training on tendon mechanical properties and rapid force production in prepubertal children. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117(3):257&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4122689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00325.2014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Liew B, Ramirez-Campillo R, Granacher U, Negra Y, Chaabene H. The effects of plyometric jump training on lower-limb stiffness in healthy individuals: a meta-analytical comparison. J Sport Health Sci. 2023;12(2):236&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2021.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruyn EC, Watsford M, Murphy A. The relationship between lower-body stiffness and dynamic performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2014;39(10):1144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25007238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Sanchez-Sanchez J, Romero-Moraleda B, Yanci J, Garcia-Hermoso A, Manuel Clemente F. Effects of plyometric jump training in female soccer player&#x2019;s vertical jump height: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(13):1475&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32255389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1745503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Moran J, de Villarreal ES, Lloyd RS. Effects of plyometric jump training on jump and sprint performance in young male soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(12):2125&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01337-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>