<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41736098</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The long-term effects of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion, strength, balance, and jump performance in athletes with limited ankle dorsiflexion: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">113</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01609-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The long-term effects of tissue flossing (TF) on mobility, strength, balance, and muscle power remain unclear, particularly regarding its potential to produce performance enhancements. Here, we aimed to investigate the effects of TF on ankle range of motion (ROM), strength, balance, and jump performance in team- and racket-sport athletes with limited ankle dorsiflexion (DF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Forty male athletes (DF-ROM&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;10&#xb0;) were randomized into a TF group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;20) or a control group performing static stretching (SS, <i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;20). The TF intervention employed a standard figure-of-eight bandaging technique with 50&#x2013;70% overlap, consisting of active movements with elastic band compression, three times a week for six weeks, followed by a six-week detraining period. The SS group performed 3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;30&#xa0;s stretches for the gastrocnemius and soleus muscles. Outcomes included DF and plantarflexion (PF) ROM, isokinetic strength at 30&#xb0;/s and 120&#xb0;/s, Y-balance test (YBT), and Sargent jump test (SJT), measured at baseline, post-intervention, and post-detraining.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">TF produced larger gains than SS in DF-ROM (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.52) and PF-ROM (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.90), with partial retention after detraining (DF: <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.26; PF: <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.22). Strength improved mainly in DF (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.36&#x2013;0.78) and in PF at slower speeds (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;017-0.29), with partial retention (DF at 30 and 120&#xb0;/s: <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004&#x2013;0.04, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04&#x2013;0.13; PF at 30&#xb0;/s: <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.06). YBT scores increased in the posteromedial (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.84) and posterolateral (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, <i>d</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.84) directions, but not anteriorly (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). No significant effects were observed for SJT (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">A six-week TF program effectively improved ankle ROM, strength, and dynamic balance in athletes with restricted DF, with many benefits persisting after detraining. Compared with static stretching, tissue flossing was more effective for long-term ankle function but did not enhance vertical jump performance. These results suggest that tissue flossing is a practical and efficient strategy for team- and racket-sport athletes seeking to restore and maintain ankle mobility and stability during training and rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This trial was registered at the Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (Identifier: IRCT20230612058457N7) on June 14, 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-026-01609-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daneshmandi</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Injury and Corrective Exercise, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Guilan, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alimoradi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Injuries and Corrective Exercises, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Shahid Bahonar University of Kerman, Kerman, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HERC - Health, Exercise &amp; Research Center, Mina Rashid, Dubai Maritime City, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghosi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Technical and Vocational University (TVU), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monfaredian</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Biomechanics, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Shahid Bahonar University of Kerman, Kerman, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barati</LastName><ForeName>Amirhossein</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Health, Faculty of Physical Education, University of Shahid Behshti, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Granacher</LastName><ForeName>Urs</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7095-813X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Exercise and Human Movement Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany. urs.granacher@sport.uni-freiburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankle joint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Floss band</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Range of motion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of Guilan University, Iran (IR.GUILAN.REC.1404.017). Informed consent was obtained from all participants involved in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41736098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12967009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01609-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01609-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rad NF, Alimoradi M, Antohe B, Uysal H&#x15e;, Korkmaz S, Relph N, et al. Modelling of ankle joint range of motion and landing quality scores in female soccer players with quantile regression approach. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(6):e0325180. 10.1371/journal.pone.0325180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0325180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12140249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40472041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Overmayer RG. The effects of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion and jump performance. Phys Ther Sport. 2017;25:20&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2016.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2016.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong C-M, Blackburn JT, Norcross MF, McGrath M, Padua DA. Ankle-dorsiflexion range of motion and landing biomechanics. J Athl Train. 2011;46(1):5&#x2013;10. 10.4085/1062-6050-46.1.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-46.1.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21214345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RL, Davenport TE, Paulseth S, Wukich DK, Godges JJ, Altman RD, et al. Ankle stability and movement coordination impairments: ankle ligament sprains: clinical practice guidelines linked to the international classification of functioning, disability and health from the orthopaedic section of the American Physical Therapy Association. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2013;43(9):A1&#x2013;40. 10.2519/jospt.2013.0305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2013.0305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24313720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabi T, Saki F, Ramezani F, Tahayori B. Comprehensive corrective exercise program improves ankle function in female athletes with limited weight-bearing ankle dorsiflexion: A randomized controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(10):e0312152. 10.1371/journal.pone.0312152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0312152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11527180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39480882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez V, Soler A, Ansa A, L&#xf3;pez-Samanes &#xc1;, Madruga-Parera M, Beato M, et al. Acute and chronic effects of competition on ankle dorsiflexion ROM in professional football players. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20(1):51&#x2013;60. 10.1080/17461391.2019.1611930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1611930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31072261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Chen N, Wang J, Zhang Z, Jiang C, Chen Z, et al. The prevalence and characteristics of chronic ankle instability in elite athletes of different sports: A cross-sectional study. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7478. 10.3390/jcm11247478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm11247478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9783869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young R, Nix S, Wholohan A, Bradhurst R, Reed L. Interventions for increasing ankle joint dorsiflexion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Foot Ankle Res. 2013;6(1):46. 10.1186/1757-1146-6-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1757-1146-6-46</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24225348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada M, Pietrosimone BG, Gribble PA. Therapeutic interventions for increasing ankle dorsiflexion after ankle sprain: a systematic review. J Athl Train. 2013;48(5):696&#x2013;709. 10.4085/1062-6050-48.4.11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-48.4.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3784372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23914912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo B, Hall T, Berwart M, Biernaux E, Detrembleur C. The immediate effects of two manual therapy techniques on ankle musculoarticular stiffness and dorsiflexion range of motion in people with chronic ankle rigidity: A randomized clinical trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehab. 2018;31(3):515&#x2013;24. 10.3233/bmr-170963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/bmr-170963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianhong G, Soon CC, Seng TJ, Zaremohzzabieh Z, Samsudin S. The effect of tissue flossing technique on sports and injury prevention and rehabilitation: a systematic review of recent research. Int J Hum Mov Sports Sci. 2021;9(6):1157&#x2013;73. 10.13189/saj.2021.090611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13189/saj.2021.090611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starrett K, Cordoza G. Becoming a supple leopard: the ultimate guide to resolving pain, preventing injury, and optimizing athletic performance. 2nd ed. Las Vegas: Victory Belt Publishing. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Mo&#x10d;nik R, Nakamura M. Effects of tissue flossing on the healthy and impaired musculoskeletal system: A scoping review. Front Physiol. 2021;12:666129. 10.3389/fphys.2021.666129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.666129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8176205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34093228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi R, Giorgi F. Stretching the limits: A systematic review of tissue flossing&#x2019;s impact on exercise performance. Sports Orthop Traumatol. 2024;40(4):338&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.orthtr.2024.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orthtr.2024.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skopal LK, Drinkwater EJ, Behm DG. Application of mobility training methods in sporting populations: a systematic review of performance adaptations. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(1):46&#x2013;60. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2321006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2321006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38433623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands W, McNeal J. Mobility and flexibility training for young athletes. Strength and Conditioning for Young Athletes. Routledge; 2019. pp. 265&#x2013;78. 10.4324/9781351115346-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuli&#x15b; S, Pietraszewski P, Callegari B. Characteristics of post-exercise lower limb muscle tremor among speed skaters. Sensors. 2025;25(14):4301. 10.3390/s25144301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25144301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12298239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40732429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuli&#x15b; S, K&#x142;obuchowski W, Skorulski M, Ornowski K, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A, Maszczyk A, et al. Beyond mechanical load: metabolic factors and advanced rehabilitation in sports tendinopathy: A comprehensive systematic review. J Clin Med. 2025;14(21):7480. 10.3390/jcm14217480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14217480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12610271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41226877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AK, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;17(2):317&#x2013;31. 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon B-H, Kim J-W. Effects of floss bands on ankle joint range of motion and balance ability. Phys Ther Korea. 2022;29(4):274&#x2013;81. 10.12674/ptk.2022.29.4.274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12674/ptk.2022.29.4.274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy-Williams N, Driller MW, Halson SL, Fell JW, Shing C. Evaluating the Kikuhime pressure monitor for use with sports compression clothing. Sports Eng. 2014;17(1):55&#x2013;60. 10.1007/s12283-013-0125-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12283-013-0125-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimoradi M, Sahebozamani M, Hosseini E, Konrad A, Noorian S. The effect on flexibility and a variety of performance tests of the addition of 4 weeks of soleus stretching to a regular dynamic stretching routine in amateur female soccer players. Sports. 2023;11(7):138. 10.3390/sports11070138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports11070138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10383580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37505625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshmandi H, Alghosi M, Alimoradi M, Monfaredian O, Barati A, Granacher U. Acute effects of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion in athletes with limited ankle dorsiflexion: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17:375. 10.1186/s13102-025-01484-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01484-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12750873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41423614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoel LS, Xixirry MG, Soeira TP, Saad MC, Riberto M. Identification of ankle injury risk factors in professional soccer players through a preseason functional assessment. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(6):2325967120928434. 10.1177/2325967120928434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967120928434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iranmanesh M, Shafiei Nikou S, Saadatian A, Alimoradi M, Khalaji H, Monfaredian O, et al. The training and detraining effects of 8-week dynamic stretching of hip flexors on hip range of motion, pain, and physical performance in male professional football players with low back pain. A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2025;43(16):1572&#x2013;86. 10.1080/02640414.2025.2513163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2025.2513163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40465522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini E, Alimoradi M, Iranmanesh M, Saki F, Konrad A. The effects of 8 weeks of dynamic hamstring stretching or nordic hamstring exercises on balance, range of motion, agility, and muscle performance among male soccer players with hamstring shortness: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17(1):187. 10.1186/s13102-025-01216-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01216-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12239349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40635029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles PG, Vasconcellos FV, de Salles GF, Fonseca RT, Dantas EH. Validity and reproducibility of the sargent jump test in the assessment of explosive strength in soccer players. J Hum kinet. 2012;33:115&#x2013;21. 10.2478/v10078-012-0050-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10078-012-0050-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosier E. The long-term effects of tissue flossing on ankle dorsiflexion range of motion in athletes with chronic ankle instability [Master of Science thesis]. Illinois State University. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behaviors science.(2nd). New Jersey: Laurence Erlbaum Associates, Hillsdale.; 1988. pp. 20&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneda H, Takahira N, Tsuda K, Tozaki K, Sakai K, Kudo S, et al. The effects of tissue flossing and static stretching on gastrocnemius exertion and flexibility. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2020;28(2):205&#x2013;13. 10.3233/IES-192235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-192235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C-B, Lee J-K, Park S, Park J-W. Effects of flossing band technique, static and dyndmic stretching on hamstring on knee range of motion, muscle activity, and proprioception. J Korean Phys Ther. 2023;35(6):206&#x2013;12. 10.18857/jkpt.2023.35.6.206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18857/jkpt.2023.35.6.206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schleip R, M&#xfc;ller DG. Training principles for fascial connective tissues: scientific foundation and suggested practical applications. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2013;17(1):103&#x2013;15. 10.1016/j.jbmt.2012.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2012.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Thung JS, Chee CS, Tee CCL, Kamalden TFT, Samsudin S, et al. The potential mechanisms of tissue flossing with Flossband application around the joints or soft tissues: A theoretical framework. Apunts Sports Med. 2024;59(224):100453. 10.1016/j.apunsm.2024.100453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apunsm.2024.100453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalc M, Mikl S, &#x17d;&#xf6;k&#x161; F, Vogrin M, St&#xf6;ggl T. Effects of different tissue flossing applications on range of motion, maximum voluntary contraction, and h-reflex in young martial arts fighters. Front Physiol. 2021;12:752641. 10.3389/fphys.2021.752641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.752641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34721076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Bernsteiner D, Budini F, Reiner MM, Glash&#xfc;ttner C, Berger C, et al. Tissue flossing of the thigh increases isometric strength acutely but has no effects on flexibility or jump height. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(12):1648&#x2013;58. 10.1080/17461391.2020.1853818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2020.1853818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogrin M, Kalc M, Li&#x10d;en T. Acute effects of tissue flossing around the upper thigh on neuromuscular performance: a study using different degrees of wrapping pressure. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;30(4):601&#x2013;8. 10.1123/jsr.2020-0105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2020-0105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33238242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneda H, Takahira N, Tsuda K, Tozaki K, Kudo S, Takahashi Y, et al. Effects of tissue flossing and dynamic stretching on hamstring muscles function. J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19(4):681&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baida SR, Gore SJ, Franklyn-Miller AD, Moran KA. Does the amount of lower extremity movement variability differ between injured and uninjured populations? A systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(4):1320&#x2013;38. 10.1111/sms.13036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29239047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi K, Seidi F, Mousavi SH, Alghosi M, Morad NH. Comparison of postural sway in individuals with and without dynamic knee valgus. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):75. 10.1186/s13102-023-00686-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00686-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10316634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37400853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Yu G, Zhang X, Wang Y-z, Chen Y-p. Relationship between ankle pain, range of motion, strength and balance in individuals with functional ankle instability: a cross-sectional study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023;24(1):955. 10.1186/s12891-023-07079-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-023-07079-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10704625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38066472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrison JC, Bothwell JM, Wolf G, Aryal S, Thigpen CA. Y balance test&#x2122; anterior reach symmetry at three months is related to single leg functional performance at time of return to sports following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10(5):602&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4595913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26491610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nozu S, Johnson KA, Tanaka T, Inoue M, Nishio H, Takazawa Y. The accuracy of ankle eccentric torque control explains dynamic postural control during the Y-Balance Test. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18(5):1113&#x2013;22. 10.26603/001c.87760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.87760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10547066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37795317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata K, Wilson S. Trunk posture and spinal stability. Clin Biomech. 2001;16(8):650&#x2013;9. 10.1016/s0268-0033(01)00064-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0268-0033(01)00064-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11535346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedaghati P, Alghosi M, Hosseini F, Ghafouri M, Fallahi Farrash F, Parvaneh Sarand A. Correlation between sagittal plane curvature of the upright human spine and postural stability in adults. Phys Treatments-Specific Phys Therapy J. 2024;14(4):303&#x2013;10. 10.32598/ptj.14.4.584.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32598/ptj.14.4.584.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Wang Q, Zhao Z, Song Q, Zhao P, Wang D. Acute effects of tissue flossing on boxers with chronic knee pain. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2025;12:1508054. 10.3389/fbioe.2024.1508054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2024.1508054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11772274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39877264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheatham SW, Baker R. Tissue flossing: A commentary on clinical practice recommendations. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(4):477&#x2013;89. 10.26603/001c.94598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.94598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10987303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedaghati P, Alghosi M, Hosseini F. The effect of fatigue on postural control in individuals with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review. BMC Neurol. 2023;23(1):409. 10.1186/s12883-023-03464-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-023-03464-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10655337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang N-J, Hung W-C, Lee C-L, Chang W-D, Wu B-H. Effects of a single session of floss band intervention on flexibility of thigh, knee joint proprioception, muscle force output, and dynamic balance in young adults. Appl Sci. 2021;11(24):12052. 10.3390/app112412052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app112412052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanyshyn J, Nigg D. Contribution of the lower extremity joints to mechanical energy in running vertical jumps and running long jumps. J Sports Sci. 1998;16(2):177&#x2013;86. 10.1080/026404198366885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404198366885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9531006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>