<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41799374</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2359-7232</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discoveries (Craiova, Romania)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discoveries (Craiova)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advances in the prevention and prenatal treatment of spina bifida.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e222</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e222</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e222</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15190/d.2026.1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Spina bifida is a neural tube defect (NTD) that arises when the neural tube fails to close properly during early development. This review focuses on myelomeningocele (MMC), the most common severe form of spina bifida, which often leads to motor and sensory impairments, including lower limb weakness or paralysis, as well as renal, urological, orthopedic, developmental, and psychosocial challenges. We explore the etiology, pathogenesis, prevention, diagnosis, and management of spina bifida, with a special emphasis on in-utero surgical repair. Over the past several decades, researchers and clinicians have made remarkable strides across all stages of care from prevention to postnatal outcomes. Widespread use of folic acid supplementation has significantly reduced the number of new cases. Advances in prenatal imaging and diagnostics now allow for earlier and more accurate detection, enabling timely intervention. In-utero surgical techniques continue to evolve, with innovative hybrid approaches that combine the strengths of open and minimally invasive methods. The momentum in this field shows no sign of slowing. Promising developments in stem cell therapy, biomaterials, robotic-assisted surgery, 3D printing, and enhanced imaging are redefining&#xa0;treatment goals in spina bifida. With each advance, clinicians gain better tools to improve outcomes for both mother and child, minimizing risks and maximizing long-term health and quality of life for both patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Sluzala ZB et al., Applied Systems and Discoveries Journals.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sluzala</LastName><ForeName>Zachary B</ForeName><Initials>ZB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charlotte Lozier Institute, Arlington, VA 22206, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furth</LastName><ForeName>Katrina E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charlotte Lozier Institute, Arlington, VA 22206, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Catholic University of America, Psychology Department, Washington, DC 20064, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Romania</Country><MedlineTA>Discoveries (Craiova)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101665061</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2359-7232</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spina bifida</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomaterials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fetal surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fetal therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myelomeningocele</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural tube defects.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prenatal surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stem cells</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interests: The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41799374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12967227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15190/d.2026.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global Birth Prevalence of Spina Bifida by Folic Acid Fortification Status: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Atta Callie A M, Fiest Kirsten M, Frolkis Alexandra D, Jette Nathalie, Pringsheim Tamara, St Germaine-Smith Christine, Rajapakse Thilinie, Kaplan Gilaad G, Metcalfe Amy. American journal of public health. 2016;106(1):e24&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4695937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National population-based estimates for major birth defects, 2016-2020. Stallings Erin B, Isenburg Jennifer L, Rutkowski Rachel E, Kirby Russell S, Nembhard Wendy N, Sandidge Theresa, Villavicencio Stephan, Nguyen Hoang H, McMahon Daria M, Nestoridi Eirini, Pabst Laura J. Birth defects research. 2024;116(1):e2301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38277408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized trial of prenatal versus postnatal repair of myelomeningocele. Adzick N Scott, Thom Elizabeth A, Spong Catherine Y, Brock John W, Burrows Pamela K, Johnson Mark P, Howell Lori J, Farrell Jody A, Dabrowiak Mary E, Sutton Leslie N, Gupta Nalin, Tulipan Noel B, D'Alton Mary E, Farmer Diana L. The New England journal of medicine. 2011;364(11):993&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3770179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal surgery for myelomeningocele: After the Management of Myelomeningocele Study (MOMS). Moldenhauer Julie S, Adzick N Scott. Seminars in fetal &amp; neonatal medicine. 2017;22(6):360&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh Ranbir, Munakomi Sunil. Embryology, Neural Tube. StatPearls Publishing; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torchia, Persaud . The Developing Human: Clinically Oriented Embryology. 12th edition. Elsevier; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critical appraisal on neural tube defects and their complexities. Shaikh Fouziya, Sanadhya Mallica, Kaleem Safa, Verma Tiya, Jayaraj Richard L, Ahmad Faizan. Pediatrics and neonatology. 2025;66(6):515&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40274469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spina Bifida Prevention: A Narrative Review of Folic Acid Supplements for Childbearing Age Women. Ledet Iii Lloyd F, Plaisance Connor J, Daniel Charles P, Wagner Maxwell J, Alvarez Ivan, Burroughs Caroline R, Rieger Ross, Siddaiah Harish, Ahmadzadeh Shahab, Shekoohi Sahar, Kaye Alan D, Varrassi Giustino. Cureus. 2024;16(1):e53008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10894015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38406082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of Neural Tube Defects: Gene-Environment Interactions, Preventative Approaches and Future Perspectives. Isakovi&#x107; Jasmina, &#x160;imuni&#x107; Iva, Jage&#x10d;i&#x107; Denis, Hribljan Valentina, Mitre&#x10d;i&#x107; Dinko. Biomedicines. 2022;10(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9138472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35625701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Closing the Gap: Prenatal Repair and the Reimagined Future of Spina Bifida. Aydin Emrah, Peiro Jose Luis, Habli Monuira. Clinical obstetrics and gynecology. 2025;68(3):383&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40697157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsonovich, Alruwaili, Das . Myelomeningocele. StatPearls Publishing; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spina bifida. Copp Andrew J, Adzick N Scott, Chitty Lyn S, Fletcher Jack M, Holmbeck Grayson N, Shaw Gary M. Nature reviews. Disease primers. 2015;1:15007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4898641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Overview of Spina Bifida. Parvin Afroza, Hasan Md Mahmudul. Open Journal of Orthopedics. 2023;13(10):443-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>20-year survival of children born with congenital anomalies: a population-based study. Tennant Peter W G, Pearce Mark S, Bythell Mary, Rankin Judith. Lancet (London, England) 2010;375(9715):649&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20092884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robotic Fetal Surgery: The Next Frontier? Boswell Timothy C., Ahn Edward S., Ruano Rodrigo, Gargollo Patricio C. Minimally Invasive and Robotic-Assisted Surgery in Pediatric Urology. 2020:359-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partitioning of One-Carbon Units in Folate and Methionine Metabolism Is Essential for Neural Tube Closure. Leung Kit-Yi, Pai Yun Jin, Chen Qiuying, Santos Chloe, Calvani Enrica, Sudiwala Sonia, Savery Dawn, Ralser Markus, Gross Steven S, Copp Andrew J, Greene Nicholas D E. Cell reports. 2017;21(7):1795&#x2013;1808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5699646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Why is folate effective in preventing neural tube closure defects? Sato Kohji. Medical hypotheses. 2020;134:109429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31634773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Double-blind randomised controlled trial of folate treatment before conception to prevent recurrence of neural-tube defects. Laurence K M, James N, Miller M H, Tennant G B, Campbell H. British medical journal (Clinical research ed.) 1981;282(6275):1509&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1505459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6786536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Further experience of vitamin supplementation for prevention of neural tube defect recurrences. Smithells R W, Nevin N C, Seller M J, Sheppard S, Harris R, Read A P, Fielding D W, Walker S, Schorah C J, Wild J. Lancet (London, England) 1983;1(8332):1027&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6133069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of neural tube defects: results of the Medical Research Council Vitamin Study. MRC Vitamin Study Research Group. Lancet (London, England) 1991;338(8760):131&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1677062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects and safety of periconceptional oral folate supplementation for preventing birth defects. De-Regil Luz Maria, Pe&#xf1;a-Rosas Juan Pablo, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Gaxiola Ana C, Rayco-Solon Pura. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2015;2015(12):CD007950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of 4.0 mg versus 0.4 mg Folic Acid Supplementation on the Reproductive Outcomes: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Bortolus Renata, Filippini Francesca, Cipriani Sonia, Trevisanuto Daniele, Cavallin Francesco, Zanconato Giovanni, Somigliana Edgardo, Cesari Elena, Mastroiacovo Pierpaolo, Parazzini Fabio. Nutrients. 2021;13(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8704306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34959975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folate and folic acid in the periconceptional period: recommendations from official health organizations in thirty-six countries worldwide and WHO. Gomes Sandra, Lopes Carla, Pinto Elisabete. Public health nutrition. 2016;19(1):176&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25877429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Updated estimates of neural tube defects prevented by mandatory folic Acid fortification - United States, 1995-2011. Williams Jennifer, Mai Cara T, Mulinare Joe, Isenburg Jennifer, Flood Timothy J, Ethen Mary, Frohnert Barbara, Kirby Russell S. MMWR. Morbidity and mortality weekly report. 2015;64(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4584791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25590678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decline in the prevalence of neural tube defects following folic acid fortification and its cost-benefit in South Africa. Sayed Abdul-Rauf, Bourne David, Pattinson Robert, Nixon Jo, Henderson Bertram. Birth defects research. Part A, Clinical and molecular teratology. 2008;82(4):211&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18338391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevented cases of neural tube defects and cost savings after folic acid fortification of flour in Brazil. Rodrigues Viviane Belini, Silva Everton Nunes da, Dos Santos Andr&#xe9; Marques, Santos Leonor Maria Pacheco. PloS one. 2023;18(2):e0281077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9946232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36812183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reduction in neural-tube defects after folic acid fortification in Canada. De Wals Philippe, Tairou Fassiatou, Van Allen Margot I, Uh Soo-Hong, Lowry R Brian, Sibbald Barbara, Evans Jane A, Van den Hof Michiel C, Zimmer Pamela, Crowley Marian, Fernandez Bridget, Lee Nora S, Niyonsenga Theophile. The New England journal of medicine. 2007;357(2):135&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17625125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folic acid flour fortification: impact on the frequencies of 52 congenital anomaly types in three South American countries. L&#xf3;pez-Camelo Jorge S, Castilla Eduardo E, Orioli I&#xea;da M. American journal of medical genetics. Part A. 2010;152A(10):2444&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20814949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Global Burden of Neural Tube Defects and Disparities in Neurosurgical Care. Yacob Alex, Carr Christopher J, Foote Jake, Scullen Tyler, Werner Cassidy, Mathkour Mansour, Bui Cuong J, Dumont Aaron S. World neurosurgery. 2021;149:e803&#x2013;e820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33540098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Nature-Inspired Search Space Reduction Technique for Spine Identification on Ultrasound Samples of Spina Bifida Cases. Cengizler &#xc7;a&#x11f;lar, &#xdc;n M Kerem, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kkurt Selim. Scientific reports. 2020;10(1):9280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel evolutionary method for spine detection in ultrasound samples of spina bifida cases. Cengizler Caglar, Kerem &#xdc;n M, Buyukkurt Selim. Computer methods and programs in biomedicine. 2021;198:105787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical workflow of sonographers performing fetal anomaly ultrasound scans: deep-learning-based analysis. Drukker L, Sharma H, Karim J N, Droste R, Noble J A, Papageorghiou A T. Ultrasound in obstetrics &amp; gynecology : the official journal of the International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology. 2022;60(6):759&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10107110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determination of anatomic level of myelomeningocele by prenatal ultrasound. Barnes Katherine S, Singh Sumit, Barkley Ariana, Lepard Jacob, Hopson Betsy, Cawyer Chase R, Blount Jeffrey P, Rocque Brandon G. Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2022;38(5):985&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>First-Trimester Cranial Ultrasound Markers of Open Spina Bifida. Zhu Xia, Zhao Sheng, Yang Xiaohong, Feng Qian, Zhang Xiaoyan, Yang Fan, Chen Xinlin. Journal of ultrasound in medicine : official journal of the American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine. 2021;40(6):1155&#x2013;1162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32951226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open Spina Bifida: The Role of Ultrasound Markers in the First Trimester and Morphopathology Correlation. Ungureanu Delia Roxana, Com&#x103;nescu Maria Cristina, Istrate-Ofi&#x163;eru Anca-Maria, Zoril&#x103; George-Lucian, Dr&#x103;gu&#x219;in Roxana Cristina, Iliescu Dominic Gabriel. Current health sciences journal. 2023;49(3):445&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10832886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38314210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>First-trimester ultrasound of the cerebral lateral ventricles in fetuses with open spina bifida: a retrospective cohort study. Volpe Nicola, Bovino Alessandra, Di Pasquo Elvira, Corno Enrico, Taverna Michela, Valentini Beatrice, Dall'Asta Andrea, Brawura-Biskupsi-Samaha Robert, Ghi Tullio. American journal of obstetrics &amp; gynecology MFM. 2024;6(9):101445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measurement of the Area and Circumference of the Leg: Preliminary Results of a New Method for Estimating Leg Muscle Trophism in Fetuses With Open Lumbosacral Spina Bifida. Milani H&#xe9;rbene Jos&#xe9; Figuinha, de S&#xe1; Barreto Enoch Quinder&#xe9;, Araujo J&#xfa;nior Edward, Cavalheiro S&#xe9;rgio, Barbosa Maur&#xed;cio Mendes, Moron Antonio Fernandes. Journal of ultrasound in medicine : official journal of the American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine. 2022;41(2):377&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerebellar herniation demonstrated by the occipitum-dens line: Ultrasonography assessment of normal fetuses, fetuses with myelomeningocele, and fetuses that underwent antenatal myelomeningocele surgery. Barreto Enoch Quinder&#xe9; de S&#xe1;, Cavalheiro S&#xe9;rgio, Milani Herbene Jos&#xe9; Figuinha, Barbosa Maur&#xed;cio Mendes, Araujo J&#xfa;nior Edward, Nardozza Luciano Marcondes Machado, Moron Antonio Fernandes. Prenatal diagnosis. 2018;38(4):280&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29427561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Research progress on ultrasound and molecular markers for prenatal diagnosis of neural tube defects. Yin Jiao, Wang Yan, Wang Sihong, Li Gang, Gu Hui, Chen Lizhu. Heliyon. 2024;10(16):e36060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11378877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal Diagnosis and Outcomes of Cervical Meningocele and Myelomeningocele. Chao An-Shine, Jhang Lan-Sin, Hsieh Peter Ching-Chang. Journal of medical ultrasound. 2024;32(1):21&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11040477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38665341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic accuracy of prenatal ultrasound in identifying the level of the lesion in fetuses with open spina bifida: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Di Mascio Daniele, Greco Francesca, Rizzo Giuseppe, Khalil Asma, Buca Danilo, Sorrentino Felice, Vasciaveo Lorenzo, Greco Pantaleo, Nappi Luigi, D'Antonio Francesco. Acta obstetricia et gynecologica Scandinavica. 2021;100(2):210&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imaging Fetal Spine Malformations in the Context of In Utero Surgery. Nagaraj Usha D, Bierbrauer Karin S, Stevenson Charles B. Magnetic resonance imaging clinics of North America. 2024;32(3):431&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38944432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal and postnatal MRI findings in open spinal dysraphism following intrauterine repair via open versus fetoscopic surgical techniques. Nagaraj Usha D, Bierbrauer Karin S, Stevenson Charles B, Peiro Jose L, Lim Foong Yen, Habli Mounira A, Kline-Fath Beth M. Prenatal diagnosis. 2020;40(1):49&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31351017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of the accuracy of fetal magnetic resonance imaging and ultrasonography for the diagnosis of fetal congenital malformations of the spine and spinal cord. Tang Xing, Bai Guoyan, Wang Hong, Guo Fan, Yin Hong. Prenatal diagnosis. 2022;42(10):1295&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35808906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal imaging of the normal and abnormal spinal cord: recommendations from the Fetal Task Force of the European Society of Paediatric Radiology (ESPR) and the European Society of Neuroradiology (ESNR) Pediatric Neuroradiology Committee. Garel Juliette, Rossi Andrea, Blondiaux El&#xe9;onore, Cassart Marie, Hoffmann Chen, Garel Catherine. Pediatric Radiology. 2023;54(4):548-561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37803194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on prenatal diagnosis and fetal surgery for myelomeningocele. Meller C&#xe9;sar, Covini Delfina, Aiello Horacio, Izbizky Gustavo, Portillo Medina Santiago, Ota&#xf1;o Lucas. Archivos argentinos de pediatria. 2021;119(3):e215&#x2013;e228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What can fetal neurosonography reveal about the future of an unborn child? Walter Uwe. Ultraschall in der Medizin (Stuttgart, Germany : 1980) 2025;46(5):418&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41052507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novel Techniques in Antenatal Imaging of Spinal Dysraphisms. Royal Charis, Chertin Leon, Alfawzan Mohammed, Killian Mary Elaine. Current urology reports. 2025;26(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11885386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40047946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New Techniques for the Study of Neural Tube Defects. Lei Yunping, Finnell Richard H. Advanced Techniques in Biology &amp;amp; Medicine. 2015;04(01)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4826067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27066597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whole exome sequencing identifies novel predisposing genes in neural tube defects. Lemay Philippe, De Marco Patrizia, Traverso Monica, Merello Elisa, Dionne-Laporte Alexandre, Spiegelman Dan, Henrion &#xc9;douard, Diallo Ousmane, Audibert Fran&#xe7;ois, Michaud Jacques L, Cama Armando, Rouleau Guy A, Kibar Zoha, Capra Valeria. Molecular genetics &amp; genomic medicine. 2019;7(1):e00467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30415495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rare deleterious variants in GRHL3 are associated with human spina bifida. Lemay Philippe, De Marco Patrizia, Emond Alexandre, Spiegelman Dan, Dionne-Laporte Alexandre, Laurent Sandra, Merello Elisa, Accogli Andrea, Rouleau Guy A, Capra Valeria, Kibar Zoha. Human mutation. 2017;38(6):716&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28276201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loss-of-function de novo mutations play an important role in severe human neural tube defects. Lemay Philippe, Guyot Marie-Claude, Tremblay &#xc9;lizabeth, Dionne-Laporte Alexandre, Spiegelman Dan, Henrion &#xc9;douard, Diallo Ousmane, De Marco Patrizia, Merello Elisa, Massicotte Christine, D&#xe9;silets Val&#xe9;rie, Michaud Jacques L, Rouleau Guy A, Capra Valeria, Kibar Zoha. Journal of medical genetics. 2015;52(7):493&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25805808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identification of new candidate genes for spina bifida through exome sequencing. Azzar&#xe0; Alessia, Rendeli Claudia, Crivello Anna Maria, Brugnoletti Fulvia, Rumore Roberto, Ausili Emanuele, Sangiorgi Eugenio, Gurrieri Fiorella. Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2021;37(8):2589&#x2013;2596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33855610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutations in planar cell polarity gene SCRIB are associated with spina bifida. Lei Yunping, Zhu Huiping, Duhon Cody, Yang Wei, Ross M Elizabeth, Shaw Gary M, Finnell Richard H. PloS one. 2013;8(7):e69262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3724847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Variants identified in PTK7 associated with neural tube defects. Lei Yunping, Kim Sung-Eun, Chen Zhongzhong, Cao Xuanye, Zhu Huiping, Yang Wei, Shaw Gary M, Zheng Yufang, Zhang Ting, Wang Hong-Yan, Finnell Richard H. Molecular genetics &amp; genomic medicine. 2019;7(4):e00584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6465732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutations in the planar cell polarity genes CELSR1 and SCRIB are associated with the severe neural tube defect craniorachischisis. Robinson Alexis, Escuin Sarah, Doudney Kit, Vekemans Michel, Stevenson Roger E, Greene Nicholas D E, Copp Andrew J, Stanier Philip. Human mutation. 2012;33(2):440&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22095531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targeted panel sequencing establishes the implication of planar cell polarity pathway and involves new candidate genes in neural tube defect disorders. Beaumont Marie, Akloul Linda, Carr&#xe9; Wilfrid, Qu&#xe9;lin Chlo&#xe9;, Journel Hubert, Pasquier Laurent, Fradin M&#xe9;lanie, Odent Sylvie, Hamdi-Roz&#xe9; Houda, Watrin Erwan, Dup&#xe9; Val&#xe9;rie, Dubourg Christ&#xe8;le, David V&#xe9;ronique. Human genetics. 2019;138(4):363&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30838450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intrauterine Treatment of Spina Bifida: Primate Model. Michejda Maria. European Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 1984;39(04):259-261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6388186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The paralysis associated with myelomeningocele: clinical and experimental data implicating a preventable spinal cord injury. Heffez D S, Aryanpur J, Hutchins G M, Freeman J M. Neurosurgery. 1990;26(6):987&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2362676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intrauterine repair of experimental surgically created dysraphism. Heffez D S, Aryanpur J, Rotellini N A, Hutchins G M, Freeman J M. Neurosurgery. 1993;32(6):1005&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8327074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero surgery rescues neurological function at birth in sheep with spina bifida. Meuli M, Meuli-Simmen C, Hutchins G M, Yingling C D, Hoffman K M, Harrison M R, Adzick N S. Nature medicine. 1995;1(4):342&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7585064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero repair of experimental myelomeningocele saves neurological function at birth. Meuli M, Meuli-Simmen C, Yingling C D, Hutchins G M, Timmel G B, Harrison M R, Adzick N S. Journal of pediatric surgery. 1996;31(3):397&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8708911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The spinal cord lesion in human fetuses with myelomeningocele: implications for fetal surgery. Meuli M, Meuli-Simmen C, Hutchins G M, Seller M J, Harrison M R, Adzick N S. Journal of pediatric surgery. 1997;32(3):448&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latissimus dorsi flap procedures to cover myelomeningocele in utero: a feasibility study in human fetuses. Meuli-Simmen C, Meuli M, Adzick N S, Harrison M R. Journal of pediatric surgery. 1997;32(8):1154&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9269961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endoscopic coverage of fetal open myelomeningocele in utero. Bruner J P, Tulipan N E, Richards W O. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 1997;176(1 Pt 1):256&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Successful fetal surgery for spina bifida. Adzick N S, Sutton L N, Crombleholme T M, Flake A W. Lancet (London, England) 1998;352(9141):1675&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9853442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal surgery for myelomeningocele and the incidence of shunt-dependent hydrocephalus. Bruner J P, Tulipan N, Paschall R L, Boehm F H, Walsh W F, Silva S R, Hernanz-Schulman M, Lowe L H, Reed G W. JAMA. 1999;282(19):1819&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Improvement in hindbrain herniation demonstrated by serial fetal magnetic resonance imaging following fetal surgery for myelomeningocele. Sutton L N, Adzick N S, Bilaniuk L T, Johnson M P, Crombleholme T M, Flake A W. JAMA. 1999;282(19):1826&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reduced hindbrain herniation after intrauterine myelomeningocele repair: A report of four cases. Tulipan N, Hernanz-Schulman M, Bruner J P. Pediatric neurosurgery. 1998;29(5):274&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9917546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero repair of myelomeningocele. Farmer Diana l. Archives of Surgery. 2003;138(8):872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12912746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal Repair and Physical Functioning Among Children With Myelomeningocele: A Secondary Analysis of a Randomized Clinical Trial. Houtrow Amy J, MacPherson Cora, Jackson-Coty Janet, Rivera Monica, Flynn Laura, Burrows Pamela K, Adzick N Scott, Fletcher Jack, Gupta Nalin, Howell Lori J, Brock John W, Lee Hanmin, Walker William O, Thom Elizabeth A. JAMA pediatrics. 2021;175(4):e205674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Randomized Trial of Prenatal versus Postnatal Repair of Myelomeningocele. Adzick N. Scott, Thom Elizabeth A., Spong Catherine Y., Brock John W., Burrows Pamela K., Johnson Mark P., Howell Lori J., Farrell Jody A., Dabrowiak Mary E., Sutton Leslie N., Gupta Nalin, Tulipan Noel B., D'Alton Mary E., Farmer Diana L. New England Journal of Medicine. 2011;364(11):993-1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3770179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal surgery for myelomeningocele and the need for cerebrospinal fluid shunt placement. Tulipan Noel, Wellons John C, Thom Elizabeth A, Gupta Nalin, Sutton Leslie N, Burrows Pamela K, Farmer Diana, Walsh William, Johnson Mark P, Rand Larry, Tolivaisa Susan, D'alton Mary E, Adzick N Scott. Journal of neurosurgery. Pediatrics. 2015;16(6):613&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26369371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal Repair of Myelomeningocele and School-age Functional Outcomes. Houtrow Amy J, Thom Elizabeth A, Fletcher Jack M, Burrows Pamela K, Adzick N Scott, Thomas Nina H, Brock John W, Cooper Timothy, Lee Hanmin, Bilaniuk Larissa, Glenn Orit A, Pruthi Sumit, MacPherson Cora, Farmer Diana L, Johnson Mark P, Howell Lori J, Gupta Nalin, Walker William O. Pediatrics. 2020;145(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31980545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Management of Myelomeningocele Study: full cohort 30-month pediatric outcomes. Farmer Diana L, Thom Elizabeth A, Brock John W, Burrows Pamela K, Johnson Mark P, Howell Lori J, Farrell Jody A, Gupta Nalin, Adzick N Scott. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2018;218(2):256.e1&#x2013;256.e13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29246577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact on family and parental stress of prenatal vs postnatal repair of myelomeningocele. Antiel Ryan M, Adzick N Scott, Thom Elizabeth A, Burrows Pamela K, Farmer Diana L, Brock John W, Howell Lori J, Farrell Jody A, Houtrow Amy J. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2016;215(4):522.e1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27263997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orthopaedic outcomes of prenatal versus postnatal repair of myelomeningocele. Swarup Ishaan, Talwar Divya, Howell Lori J, Adzick N Scott, Horn Bernard David. Journal of pediatric orthopedics. Part B. 2022;31(1):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endoscopic surgery for the antenatal treatment of myelomeningocele: the CECAM trial. Pedreira Denise A L, Zanon Nelci, Nishikuni Koshiro, Moreira de S&#xe1; Renato A, Acacio Greg&#xf3;rio L, Chmait Ramen H, Kontopoulos Eftichia V, Quintero Rub&#xe9;n A. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2016;214(1):111.e1&#x2013;111.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26386383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic Meningomyelocele Repair Study (fMMC) National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrials.gov. 2025. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT02230072 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT02230072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laparotomy-assisted, two-port fetoscopic myelomeningocele repair: infant to preschool outcomes. Sanz-Cortes Magdalena, Whitehead William E, Johnson Rebecca M, Aldave Guillermo, Castillo Heidi, Desai Nilesh K, Donepudi Roopali, Joyeux Luc, King Alice, Kralik Stephen F, Lepard Jacob, Mann David G, McClugage Samuel G, Nassr Ahmed A, Naus Claire, Nguyen Gabrielle, Castillo Jonathan, Ravindra Vijay M, Sutton Caitlin D, Weiner Howard L, Belfort Michael A. Journal of neurosurgery. Pediatrics. 2025;35(1):10&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39486058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic Open Neural Tube Defect Repair: Development and Refinement of a Two-Port, Carbon Dioxide Insufflation Technique. Belfort Michael A, Whitehead William E, Shamshirsaz Alireza A, Bateni Zhoobin H, Olutoye Oluyinka O, Olutoye Olutoyin A, Mann David G, Espinoza Jimmy, Williams Erin, Lee Timothy C, Keswani Sundeep G, Ayres Nancy, Cassady Christopher I, Mehollin-Ray Amy R, Sanz Cortes Magdalena, Carreras Elena, Peiro Jose L, Ruano Rodrigo, Cass Darrell L. Obstetrics and gynecology. 2017;129(4):734&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28277363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic NEOX Cord 1K&#xae; Spina Bifida Repair. National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrials.gov. 2025. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04243889 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04243889</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellular Therapy for In Utero Repair of Myelomeningocele - The CuRe Trial (CuRe) National Library of Medicine. ClinicalTrials.gov. 2026. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04652908 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04652908</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UC Davis Health Children&#x2019;s Hospital. The CuRe Trial. UC Davis Health Children&#x2019;s Hospital. https://health.ucdavis.edu/children/cure-trial/ https://health.ucdavis.edu/children/cure-trial/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal versus postnatal repair procedures for spina bifida for improving infant and maternal outcomes. Grivell Rosalie M, Andersen Chad, Dodd Jodie M. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2014;2014(10):CD008825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25348498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detailed Analysis of Hydrocephalus and Hindbrain Herniation After Prenatal and Postnatal Myelomeningocele Closure: Report From a Single Institution. Flanders Tracy M, Heuer Gregory G, Madsen Peter J, Buch Vivek P, Mackell Catherine M, Alexander Erin E, Moldenhauer Julie S, Zarnow Deborah M, Flake Alan W, Adzick N Scott. Neurosurgery. 2020;86(5):637&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of Prenatal Repair for Fetal Myelomeningocele on Gastrointestinal Function. Munoz Jessian L, Kelling Emma, Johnson Rebecca M, Buskmiller Cara, Whitehead William E, Joyeux Luc, Donepudi Roopali V, Nassr Ahmed A, Belfort Michael A, Castillo Jonathan, Castillo Heidi, Cortes Magdalena Sanz. The Journal of pediatrics. 2025;282:114573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40185309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal myelomeningocele repair: the post-MOMS experience at the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia. Moldenhauer Julie S, Soni Shelly, Rintoul Natalie E, Spinner Susan S, Khalek Nahla, Martinez-Poyer Juan, Flake Alan W, Hedrick Holly L, Peranteau William H, Rendon Norma, Koh Jamie, Howell Lori J, Heuer Gregory G, Sutton Leslie N, Johnson Mark P, Adzick N Scott. Fetal diagnosis and therapy. 2015;37(3):235&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25138132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middle Cerebral Artery Doppler before and after Fetal Spina Bifida Repair: An Indirect Sign of Hindbrain Compression and Decompression? Vonzun Ladina, Ruegg Ladina, Zepf Julia, Str&#xfc;bing Nele, Grehten Patrice, Meuli Martin, Mazzone Luca, Moehrlen Ueli, Ochsenbein-Koelble Nicole. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2024:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38880089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal myelomeningocele surgery: preschool functional status using the Functional Independence Measure for children (WeeFIM). Danzer Enrico, Gerdes Marsha, Bebbington Michael W, Koh Jamie, Adzick Scott N, Johnson Mark P. Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2011;27(7):1083&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21327591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term neurofunctional outcome, executive functioning, and behavioral adaptive skills following fetal myelomeningocele surgery. Danzer Enrico, Thomas Nina H, Thomas Allison, Friedman Karen B, Gerdes Marsha, Koh Jamie, Adzick N Scott, Johnson Mark P. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2016;214(2):269.e1&#x2013;269.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26440692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preschool neurodevelopmental outcome of children following fetal myelomeningocele closure. Danzer Enrico, Gerdes Marsha, Bebbington Michael W, Zarnow Deborah M, Adzick N Scott, Johnson Mark P. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2010;202(5):450.e1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20347433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maternal-fetal surgery for myelomeningocele: neurodevelopmental outcomes at 2 years of age. Johnson Mark Paul, Gerdes Marsha, Rintoul Natalie, Pasquariello Patrick, Melchionni Jeanne, Sutton Leslie N, Adzick N Scott. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2006;194(4):1145&#x2013;50; discussion 1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16580316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subsequent pregnancy outcomes after open maternal-fetal surgery for myelomeningocele. Goodnight William H, Bahtiyar Ozan, Bennett Kelly A, Emery Stephen P, Lillegard J B, Fisher Allan, Goldstein Ruth, Jatres Jillian, Lim Foong-Yen, McCullough Laurence, Moehrlen Ueli, Moldenhauer Julie S, Moon-Grady Anita J, Ruano Rodrigo, Skupski Daniel W, Thom Elizabeth, Treadwell Marjorie C, Tsao KuoJen, Wagner Amy J, Waqar Lindsay N, Zaretsky Michael. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2019;220(5):494.e1&#x2013;494.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6511319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30885769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Management of Myelomeningocele Study: obstetrical outcomes and risk factors for obstetrical complications following prenatal surgery. Johnson Mark P, Bennett Kelly A, Rand Larry, Burrows Pamela K, Thom Elizabeth A, Howell Lori J, Farrell Jody A, Dabrowiak Mary E, Brock John W, Farmer Diana L, Adzick N Scott. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2016;215(6):778.e1&#x2013;778.e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5896767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27496687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reproductive outcomes after pregnancy complicated by maternal-fetal surgery. Wilson R Douglas, Johnson Mark P, Flake Alan W, Crombleholme Timothy M, Hedrick Holly L, Wilson Jordan, Adzick N Scott. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2004;191(4):1430&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reproductive outcomes in subsequent pregnancies after a pregnancy complicated by open maternal-fetal surgery (1996-2007). Wilson R Douglas, Lemerand Kerrie, Johnson Mark P, Flake Alan W, Bebbington Michael, Hedrick Holly L, Adzick N Scott. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2010;203(3):209.e1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20537307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of Prenatal Repair of Myelomeningocele on Urological Outcomes at School Age. Brock John W, Thomas John C, Baskin Laurence S, Zderic Stephen A, Thom Elizabeth A, Burrows Pamela K, Lee Hanmin, Houtrow Amy J, MacPherson Cora, Adzick N Scott. The Journal of urology. 2019;202(4):812&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Comparative Analysis of Bladder Pattern of Patients who Underwent In Utero Versus Postnatal Myelomeningocele Repair. Parizi Jo&#xe3;o Luiz Gomes, Leal da Cruz Marcela, Andrade Maria Cristina, Garrone Gilmar, Ottoni S&#xe9;rgio Leite, Cavalheiro S&#xe9;rgio, Moron Antonio, Macedo Antonio. The Journal of urology. 2020;203(1):194&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31479395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advances in Fetal Repair of Spina Bifida Integrating Prenatal Surgery, Stem Cells, and Biomaterials. Evangelista Aleksandra, Ruccolo Luigi, Friuli Valeria, Benazzo Marco, Conti Bice, Pisani Silvia. Biomedicines. 2026;14(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12838692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41595670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open Fetal Surgical Outcomes for Myelomeningocele Closure Stratified by Maternal Body Mass Index in a Large Single-Center Cohort. Moldenhauer Julie S, Soni Shelly, Jatres Jillian, Gebb Juliana, Khalek Nahla, Paidas Teefey Christina, Johnson Mark P, Flake Alan W, Hedrick Holly L, Peranteau William H, Heuer Gregory G, Adzick N Scott. Fetal diagnosis and therapy. 2020;47(12):889&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal myelomeningocele repair: a narrative review of the history, current controversies and future directions. Yamashiro Kaeli J, Farmer Diana L. Translational pediatrics. 2021;10(5):1497&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8192992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34189108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Should we modify eligibility criteria for fetal surgery for open spinal dysraphism? Jouannic Jean-Marie, Dugas Ana&#xef;s, Maurice Paul, Dhombres Ferdinand, Garel Catherine, Blondiaux &#xc9;l&#xe9;onore, Denis Timoth&#xe9;e de Saint, Guilbaud Lucie. European journal of obstetrics, gynecology, and reproductive biology. 2026;318:114912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Improved Postoperative Metrics with Modified Myofascial Closure in Fetal Myelomeningocele Repair. Flanders Tracy M, Madsen Peter J, Pisapia Jared M, Hudgins Eric D, Mackell Catherine M, Alexander Erin E, Moldenhauer Julie S, Zarnow Deborah M, Flake Alan W, Adzick N Scott, Heuer Gregory G. Operative neurosurgery (Hagerstown, Md.) 2020;18(2):158&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31222267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The potential impact of intraoperative neurophysiological monitoring on neurological function outcomes after postnatal spina bifida repair. Krause Matthias, Leibnitz Florian, Kn&#xfc;pfer Matthias Manfred, Merkenschlager Andreas, Griessenauer Christoph J, Gburek-Augustat Janina. Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2025;41(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11850449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39992435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Intrauterine Treatment of Open Spinal Dysraphism. Keil Corinna, Sass Benjamin, Schulze Maximilian, K&#xf6;hler Siegmund, Axt-Fliedner Roland, Bedei Ivonne. Deutsches Arzteblatt international. 2025;122(2):33&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12416013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39654393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gestational age at birth varies by surgical technique in prenatal open spina bifida repair: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zargarzadeh Nikan, Sambatur Enaja, Abiad May, Rojhani Ehsan, Javinani Ali, Northam Weston, Chmait Ramen H, Krispin Eyal, Aagaard Kjersti, Shamshirsaz Alireza A. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2025;232(6):524&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39983885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous/mini-laparotomy fetoscopic repair of open spina bifida: a novel surgical technique. Chmait Ramen H, Monson Martha A, Pham Huyen Q, Chu Jason K, Van Speybroeck Alexander, Chon Andrew H, Kontopoulos Eftichia V, Quintero Ruben A. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2022;227(3):375&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal surgical intervention for myelomeningocele: lessons learned, outcomes, and future implications. Danzer Enrico, Joyeux Luc, Flake Alan W, Deprest Jan. Developmental medicine and child neurology. 2020;62(4):417&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In-utero repair of open neural tube defects, lesion closure techniques and the choice of patch. Stevenson Charles B, Fletcher Stephen, Larrew Thomas, Chu Jason K. Best practice &amp; research. Clinical obstetrics &amp; gynaecology. 2025;103:102677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41240491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic single-layer repair of open spina bifida using a cellulose patch: preliminary clinical experience. Pedreira Denise A L, Zanon Nelci, de S&#xe1; Renato A M, Acacio Greg&#xf3;rio L, Ogeda Edilson, Belem Teresa M L O U, Chmait Ramen H, Kontopoulos Eftichia, Quintero Ruben A. The journal of maternal-fetal &amp; neonatal medicine : the official journal of the European Association of Perinatal Medicine, the Federation of Asia and Oceania Perinatal Societies, the International Society of Perinatal Obstetricians. 2014;27(16):1613&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>"This is how we do it" Maternal and fetal anesthetic management for fetoscopic myelomeningocele repairs: the Texas Children's Fetal Center protocol. Naus Claire A, Mann David G, Andropoulos Dean B, Belfort Michael A, Sanz-Cortes Magdalena, Whitehead William E, Sutton Caitlin D. International journal of obstetric anesthesia. 2025;61:104316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39721283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Experience of 300 cases of prenatal fetoscopic open spina bifida repair: report of the International Fetoscopic Neural Tube Defect Repair Consortium. Sanz Cortes Magdalena, Chmait Ramen H, Lapa Denise A, Belfort Michael A, Carreras Elena, Miller Jena L, Brawura Biskupski Samaha Robert, Sepulveda Gonzalez Gerardo, Gielchinsky Yuval, Yamamoto Masami, Persico Nicola, Santorum Marta, Ota&#xf1;o Lucas, Nicolaou Ermos, Yinon Yoav, Faig-Leite Fernanda, Brandt Reynaldo, Whitehead William, Maiz Nerea, Baschat Ahmet, Kosinski Przemyslaw, Nieto-Sanjuanero Adriana, Chu Jason, Kershenovich Amir, Nicolaides Kypros H. American journal of obstetrics and gynecology. 2021;225(6):678.e1&#x2013;678.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34089698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proceedings of the First Annual Meeting of the International Fetoscopic Myelomeningocele Repair Consortium. Sanz Cortes M, Lapa D A, Acacio G L, Belfort M, Carreras E, Maiz N, Peiro J L, Lim F Y, Miller J, Baschat A, Sepulveda G, Davila I, Gielchinsky Y, Benifla M, Stirnemann J, Ville Y, Yamamoto M, Figueroa H, Simpson L, Nicolaides K H. Ultrasound in obstetrics &amp; gynecology : the official journal of the International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology. 2019;53(6):855&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31169957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benefits and complications of fetal and postnatal surgery for open spina bifida: systematic review and proportional meta&#x2010;analysis. Kunpalin Y., Karadjole V. S., Medeiros E. S. B., Dom&#xed;nguez&#x2010;Moreno M., Sichitiu J., Abbasi N., Ryan G., Shinar S., Snelgrove J. W., Kulkarni A. V., Van Mieghem T. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2025;66(2):135-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12317308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40492626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal Surgery for Myelomeningocele: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Outcomes in Fetoscopic versus Open Repair. Kabagambe Sandra K., Jensen Guy W., Chen Yue Julia, Vanover Melissa A., Farmer Diana L. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2017;43(3):161-174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28910784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal in-utero management of myelomeningocele: a mini-review on history, challenges, management gap, and recommendations. Fareed Areeba, Farhat Solay, Kerhani Abed AlRazzak, Choudhary Anood, Raza Syeda Sadia Masood. Annals of Medicine &amp;amp; Surgery. 2024;86(6):3196-3198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11152817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38846903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myelomeningocele Surgery over the 10 Years Following the MOMS Trial: A Systematic Review of Outcomes in Prenatal versus Postnatal Surgical Repair. Paslaru Francesca Gabriela, Panaitescu Anca Maria, Iancu George, Veduta Alina, Gica Nicolae, Paslaru Alexandru Catalin, Gheorghiu Anamaria, Peltecu Gheorghe, Gorgan Radu Mircea. Medicina. 2021;57(7):707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8307221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34356988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous fetoscopic closure of large open spina bifida using a bilaminar skin substitute. Lapa (Pedreira) D. A., Acacio G. L., Gon&#xe7;alves R. T., S&#xe1; R. A. M., Brandt R. A., Chmait R. H., Kontopoulos E. V., Quintero R. A. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2018;52(4):458-466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29314321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic repair of open spina bifida between 26 0/7 and 27 6/7 gestational weeks and postnatal cerebrospinal fluid diversion. Chmait Ramen H., Chu Jason K., Van Speybroeck Alexander L., Llanes Ms. Arlyn S., Korst Lisa M., Nguyen HaiThuy N., Kontopoulos Eftichia V., Quintero Rub&#xe9;n A. The Journal of Maternal-Fetal &amp;amp; Neonatal Medicine. 2025;38(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40081964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurodevelopmental Outcomes after Fetoscopic Myelomeningocele Repair. Corroenne Romain, Rangwani Sabrina, Whitehead William E., Johnson Rebecca M., Nassr Ahmed A., Buskmiller Cara, Munoz Jessian L., Castillo Jonathan, Castillo Heidi, Donepudi Roopali V., Belfort Michael A., Sanz Cortes Magdalena. The Journal of Pediatrics. 2025;279:114472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39828055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of Labor and Delivery After Fetoscopic Repair of an Open Neural Tube Defect. Kohn Jaden R., Rao Vibha, Sellner Allison A., Sharhan Dina, Espinoza Jimmy, Shamshirsaz Alireza A., Whitehead William E., Belfort Michael A., Sanz Cortes Magdalena. Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2018;131(6):1062-1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and Effectiveness of Fetal Myelomeningocele Repair: Case Series Analysis Using an Exteriorized Uterus and a Fetoscopic Approach. Miranda M&#xe1;rcio Lopes, Ximenes Renato, Andrade Kleber Cursino, Baldo Carlos, Villarreal Mauro, Caetano Marcos Roberto, Lajos Giuliane, Dal Fabbro Mateus, Bustorff-Silva Joaquim Murray, Aydin Emrah, Peiro Jose L. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2025;52(5):521-531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40435982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does fetoscopic or open repair for spina bifida affect fetal and postnatal growth? Sanz Cortes M., Davila I., Torres P., Yepez M., Lee W., Guimaraes C. V., Sangi&#x2010;Haghpeykar H., Whitehead W. E., Castillo J., Nassr A. A., Espinoza J., Shamshirsaz A. A., Belfort M. A. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2019;53(3):314-323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30672627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambulation after &lt;i&gt;in&#x2010;utero&lt;/i&gt; fetoscopic or open neural tube defect repair: predictors for ambulation at&#x2009;30&#x2009;months. Sanz Cortes M., Corroenne R., Pyarali M., Johnson R. M., Whitehead W. E., Espinoza J., Donepudi R., Castillo J., Castillo H., Mehollin&#x2010;Ray A. R., Shamshirsaz A. A., Nassr A. A., Belfort M. A. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2024;64(2):203-213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38243917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes Following Fetoscopic Repair of Myelomeningocele: A Prospective Single&#x2010;Center Experience. Duron Vincent, Miller Russell, Feldstein Neil, Schmoke Nicholas, Wu Yeu Sanz, Shirel Tyler, Ring Laurence, Landau Ruth, Azizi Hana, Ingrassia Rosalie, Breslin Noelle, Simpson Lynn. Prenatal Diagnosis. 2025;45(5):658-667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40133605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee Opinion No. 720: Maternal&#x2013;Fetal Surgery for Myelomeningocele. Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2017;130(3):e164-e167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28832491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic two&#x2010;layer closure of open neural tube defects. Gin&#xe9; C., Ar&#xe9;valo S., Ma&#xed;z N., Rod&#xf3; C., Manrique S., Poca A., Molino J. A., Carreras E., L&#xf3;pez M. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2018;52(4):452-457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29876992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achieving water-tight open spina bifida closure through a novel three-port three-layer fetoscopic repair. Bowman Robin, Alhajjat Amir, Muller Rya, Scoville Jonathan, Shaaban Aimen. American Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology MFM. 2025;7(7):101697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40368003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic Myelomeningocele (MMC) Repair: Evolution of the Technique and a Call for Standardization. Cruz Stephanie M., Hameedi Sophia, Sbragia Lourenco, Ogunleye Oluseyi, Diefenbach Karen, Isaacs Albert M., Etchegaray Adolfo, Olutoye Oluyinka O. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2025;14(5):1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11900223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40094785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOMS3: Follow-up in the Teen and Young Adult Years to the Management of Myelomeningocele Study. Children's Hospital of Philadelphia. 2023. https://www.chop.edu/news/moms3-follow- management-myelomeningocele-study https://www.chop.edu/news/moms3-follow- management-myelomeningocele-study</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neural Tube Defects: Review of Experimental Evidence on Stem Cell Therapy and Newer Treatment Options. Dhaulakhandi Dhara B., Rohilla Seema, Rattan Kamal Nain. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2010;28(2):72-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tissue Engineering Strategies for Fetal Myelomeningocele Repair in Animal Models. Watanabe Miho, Kim Aimee G., Flake Alan W. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2014;37(3):197-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25060746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomaterials in fetal surgery. Winkler Sally M., Harrison Michael R., Messersmith Phillip B. Biomaterials Science. 2019;7(8):3092-3109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8232972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31099350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neural stem cell delivery to the spinal cord in an ovine model of fetal surgery for spina bifida. Fauza Dario O., Jennings Russell W., Teng Yang D., Snyder Evan Y. Surgery. 2008;144(3):367-373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18707035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manufacture and preparation of human placenta-derived mesenchymal stromal cells for local tissue delivery. Lankford Lee, Chen Y. Julia, Saenz Zoe, Kumar Priyadarsini, Long Connor, Farmer Diana, Wang Aijun. Cytotherapy. 2017;19(6):680-688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Placental Mesenchymal Stromal Cells: Preclinical Safety Evaluation for Fetal Myelomeningocele Repair. Jackson Jordan E., Pivetti Christopher, Stokes Sarah C., Theodorou Christina M., Kumar Priyadarsini, Paxton Zachary J., Hyllen Alicia, Reynaga Lizette, Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Surgical Research. 2021;267:660-668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of clinical-grade human placental mesenchymal stromal cells in fetal ovine myelomeningocele repair. Theodorou Christina M., Stokes Sarah C., Jackson Jordan E., Pivetti Christopher D., Kumar Priyadarsini, Yamashiro Kaeli J., Paxton Zachary J., Reynaga Lizette, Hyllen Alicia A., Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2022;57(4):753-758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term safety evaluation of placental mesenchymal stromal cells for in utero repair of myelomeningocele in a novel ovine model. Stokes Sarah C, Theodorou Christina M, Jackson Jordan E, Pivetti Christopher, Kumar Priyadarsini, Yamashiro Kaeli J, Paxton Zachary J, Reynaga Lizette, Hyllen Alicia, Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2022;57(1):18-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9415987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Placental Mesenchymal Stromal Cells Rescue Ambulation in Ovine Myelomeningocele. Wang Aijun, Brown Erin G., Lankford Lee, Keller Benjamin A., Pivetti Christopher D., Sitkin Nicole A., Beattie Michael S., Bresnahan Jacqueline C., Farmer Diana L. Stem Cells Translational Medicine. 2015;4(6):659-669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25911465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High density placental mesenchymal stromal cells provide neuronal preservation and improve motor function following in utero treatment of ovine myelomeningocele. Vanover Melissa, Pivetti Christopher, Lankford Lee, Kumar Priyadarsini, Galganski Laura, Kabagambe Sandra, Keller Benjamin, Becker James, Chen Y. Julia, Chung Karen, Lee Chelsey, Paxton Zachary, Deal Bailey, Goodman Laura, Anderson Jamie, Jensen Guy, Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2019;54(1):75-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6339576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30529115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Placental mesenchymal stromal cells seeded on clinical grade extracellular matrix improve ambulation in ovine myelomeningocele. Kabagambe Sandra, Keller Benjamin, Becker James, Goodman Laura, Pivetti Christopher, Lankford Lee, Chung Karen, Lee Chelsey, Chen Y. Julia, Kumar Priyadarsini, Vanover Melissa, Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2018;53(1):178-182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29122293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero treatment of myelomeningocele with placental mesenchymal stromal cells &#x2014; Selection of an optimal cell line in preparation for clinical trials. Galganski Laura A, Kumar Priyadarsini, Vanover Melissa A, Pivetti Christopher D, Anderson Jamie E, Lankford Lee, Paxton Zachary J, Chung Karen, Lee Chelsey, Hegazi Mennatalla S, Yamashiro Kaeli J, Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2020;55(9):1941-1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7170747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CuRe Trial Animation. ProLifedoc Inc. https://discoveriesjournals.org/art/Suppl/Supplemental%20Video1-CuReTrial.mp4 https://discoveriesjournals.org/art/Suppl/Supplemental%20Video1-CuReTrial.mp4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transamniotic Stem Cell Therapy. Lazow Stefanie P., Fauza Dario O. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology. 2019:61-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31302870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transamniotic stem cell therapy (TRASCET) in a rabbit model of spina bifida. Shieh Hester F, Tracy Sarah A, Hong Charles R, Chalphin Alexander V, Ahmed Azra, Rohrer Lucas, Zurakowski David, Fauza Dario O. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2019;54(2):293-296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partial or complete coverage of experimental spina bifida by simple intra-amniotic injection of concentrated amniotic mesenchymal stem cells. Dionigi Beatrice, Ahmed Azra, Brazzo Joseph, Connors John Patrick, Zurakowski David, Fauza Dario O. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2015;50(1):69-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25598096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trans-amniotic stem cell therapy (TRASCET) minimizes Chiari-II malformation in experimental spina bifida. Dionigi Beatrice, Brazzo Joseph A., Ahmed Azra, Feng Christina, Wu Yaotang, Zurakowski David, Fauza Dario O. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2015;50(6):1037-1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25929798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison between placental and amniotic mesenchymal stem cells for transamniotic stem cell therapy (TRASCET) in experimental spina bifida. Feng Christina, D. Graham Christopher, Connors John Patrick, Brazzo Joseph, Zurakowski David, Fauza Dario O. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2016;51(6):1010-1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27013425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application potential of bone marrow mesenchymal stem cell (BMSCs) based tissue-engineering for spinal cord defect repair in rat fetuses with spina bifida aperta. Li Xiaoshuai, Yuan Zhengwei, Wei Xiaowei, Li Hui, Zhao Guifeng, Miao Jiaoning, Wu Di, Liu Bo, Cao Songying, An Dong, Ma Wei, Zhang Henan, Wang Weilin, Wang Qiushi, Gu Hui. Journal of Materials Science: Materials in Medicine. 2016;27(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26894267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sensory neuron differentiation potential of in utero mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in rat fetuses with spina bifida aperta. Ma Wei, Wei Xiaowei, Gu Hui, Li Hui, Guan Kaoping, Liu Dan, Chen Lizhu, Cao Songying, An Dong, Zhang Henan, Huang Tianchu, Miao Jianing, Zhao Guifeng, Wu Di, Liu Bo, Wang Weilin, Yuan Zhengwei. Birth Defects Research Part A: Clinical and Molecular Teratology. 2015;103(9):772-779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26172505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neural crest stem cells integrate into the injured spinal cord in the fetal lamb model of myelomeningocele. Saadai Payam, Wang Aijun, Nout Yvette S., Downing Timothy L., Lofberg Katrine, Beattie Michael S., Bresnahan Jacqueline C., Li Song, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2013;48(1):158-163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23331809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bioengineering of Fetal Skin: Differentiation of Amniotic Fluid Stem Cells into Keratinocytes. Basler Michelle, Pontiggia Luca, Biedermann Thomas, Reichmann Ernst, Meuli Martin, Mazzone Luca. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2019;47(3):198-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31509837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bioengineering and in utero transplantation of fetal skin in the sheep model: A crucial step towards clinical application in human fetal spina bifida repair. Mazzone Luca, Moehrlen Ueli, Ochsenbein&#x2010;K&#xf6;lble Nicole, Pontiggia Luca, Biedermann Thomas, Reichmann Ernst, Meuli Martin. Journal of Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine. 2019;14(1):58-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Tissue Engineering Approach for Prenatal Closure of Myelomeningocele with Gelatin Sponges Incorporating Basic Fibroblast Growth Factor. Watanabe Miho, Jo Jun-ichiro, Radu Antonetta, Kaneko Michio, Tabata Yasuhiko, Flake Alan W. Tissue Engineering Part A. 2010;16(5):1645-1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19954327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Tissue Engineering Approach for Prenatal Closure of Myelomeningocele: Comparison of Gelatin Sponge and Microsphere Scaffolds and Bioactive Protein Coatings. Watanabe Miho, Li Hiaying, Roybal Jessica, Santore Matthew, Radu Antonetta, Jo Jun-Ichiro, Kaneko Michio, Tabata Yasuhiko, Flake Alan. Tissue Engineering Part A. 2011;17(7-8):1099-1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complete tissue coverage achieved by scaffold-based tissue engineering in the fetal sheep model of Myelomeningocele. Watanabe Miho, Li Haiying, Kim Aimee G., Weilerstein Aaron, Radu Anteneta, Davey Marcus, Loukogeorgakis Stavros, S&#xe1;nchez Melissa D., Sumita Kazutaka, Morimoto Naoki, Yamamoto Masaya, Tabata Yasuhiko, Flake Alan W. Biomaterials. 2016;76:133-143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26520044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alginate microparticles loaded with basic fibroblast growth factor induce tissue coverage in a rat model of myelomeningocele. Farrelly James S, Bianchi Anthony H, Ricciardi Adele S, Buzzelli Gina L, Ahle Samantha L, Freedman-Weiss Mollie R, Luks Valerie L, Saltzman W Mark, Stitelman David H. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2019;54(1):80-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero Repair of an Experimental Neural Tube Defect in a Chronic Sheep Model Using Biomatrices. Eggink A.J., Roelofs L.A.J., Feitz W.F.J., Wijnen R.M.H., Mullaart R.A., Grotenhuis J.A., van Kuppevelt T.H., Lammens M.M.Y., Crevels A.J., Hanssen A., van den Berg P.P. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2005;20(5):335-340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16113549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Histological Evaluation of Acute Covering of an Experimental Neural Tube Defect with Biomatrices in Fetal Sheep. Eggink A.J., Roelofs L.A.J., Lammens M.M.Y., Feitz W.F.J., Wijnen R.M.H., Mullaart R.A., van Moerkerk H.T.B., van Kuppevelt T.H., Crevels A.J., Hanssen A., Lotgering F.K., van den Berg P.P. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2006;21(2):210-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16491005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delayed Intrauterine Repair of an Experimental Spina Bifida with a Collagen Biomatrix. Eggink A.J., Roelofs L.A.J., Feitz W.F.J., Wijnen R.M.H., Lammens M.M.Y., Mullaart R.A., van Moerkerk H.T.B., van Kuppevelt T.H., Crevels A.J., Verrijp K., Lotgering F.K., van den Berg P.P. Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2007;44(1):29-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18097188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic coverage of experimental myelomeningocele in sheep using a patch with surgical sealant. Fontecha Cesar G., Peiro Jose L., Sevilla Juan J., Aguirre Marius, Soldado Francisco, Fresno Laura, Fonseca Carla, Chacaltana Asiul, Martinez Vicente. European Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology and Reproductive Biology. 2011;156(2):171-176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inert patch with bioadhesive for gentle foetal surgery of myelomeningocele in a sheep model. Fontecha Cesar G., Peiro Jose L., Aguirre Marius, Soldado Francisco, A&#xf1;or Sonia, Fresno Laura, Martinez-Iba&#xf1;ez Vicente. European Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology and Reproductive Biology. 2009;146(2):174-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19615808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single-Access Fetal Endoscopy (SAFE) for myelomeningocele in sheep model I: amniotic carbon dioxide gas approach. Peiro Jose L., Fontecha Cesar G., Ruano Rodrigo, Esteves Marielle, Fonseca Carla, Marotta Mario, Haeri Sina, Belfort Michael A. Surgical Endoscopy. 2013;27(10):3835-3840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23670742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero repair of myelomeningocele with autologous amniotic membrane in the fetal lamb model. Brown Erin G., Saadai Payam, Pivetti Christopher D., Beattie Michael S., Bresnahan Jacqueline C., Wang Aijun, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2014;49(1):133-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24439597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal repair of myelomeningocele with aligned nanofibrous scaffolds&#x2014;a pilot study in sheep. Saadai Payam, Nout Yvette S., Encinas Jose, Wang Aijun, Downing Timothy L., Beattie Michael S., Bresnahan Jacqueline C., Li Song, Farmer Diana L. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2011;46(12):2279-2283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biosynthetic cellulose induces the formation of a neoduramater following pre-natal correction of meningomyelocele in fetal sheep. Oliveira Rita de C&#xe1;ssia Sanchez e, Valente Paulo Roberto, Abou-Jamra Rog&#xe9;rio C., Ara&#xfa;jo Andrezza, Saldiva Paulo Hil&#xe1;rio, Pedreira Denise Ara&#xfa;jo Lapa. Acta Cirurgica Brasileira. 2007;22(3):174-181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17546289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison between two surgical techniques for prenatal correction of meningomyelocele in sheep. Herrera Silvia Rejane Fontoura, Leme Ricardo Jos&#xe9; de Almeida, Valente Paulo Roberto, Caldini Elia Garcia, Saldiva Paulo Hil&#xe1;rio Nascimento, Pedreira Denise Araujo Lapa. Einstein (Sao Paulo, Brazil) 2012;10(4):455&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23386086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Local host response of commercially available dural patches for fetal repair of spina bifida aperta in rabbit model. Kunpalin Yada, Vergote Simen, Joyeux Luc, Telli Onur, David Anna L., Belfort Michael, De Coppi Paolo, Deprest Jan. Prenatal Diagnosis. 2023;43(3):370-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36650109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bio-engineering of fetal cartilage for in utero spina bifida repair. Dasargyri Athanasia, Reichmann Ernst, Moehrlen Ueli. Pediatric Surgery International. 2019;36(1):25-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31576465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collagen-Heparin-FGF2-VEGF Scaffolds Induce a Regenerative Gene Expression Profile in a Fetal Sheep Wound Model. Gansevoort Merel, Oostendorp Corien, Bouwman Linde F., Tiemessen Dorien M., Geutjes Paul J., Feitz Wout F. J., van Kuppevelt Toin H., Daamen Willeke F. Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine. 2024;21(8):1173-1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11589036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39215940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryopreserved human umbilical cord versus biocellulose film for prenatal spina bifida repair in a physiologic rat model. Snowise Saul, Mann Lovepreet, Morales Yisel, Moise Kenneth J., Johnson Anthony, Fletcher Stephen, Grill Raymond J., Tseng Scheffer C.G., Papanna Ramesha. Prenatal Diagnosis. 2017;37(5):473-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28295455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allografts for Skin Closure during In Utero Spina Bifida Repair in a Sheep Model. Mann Lovepreet K., Won Jong Hak, Patel Rajan, Bergh Eric P., Garnett Jeannine, Bhattacharjee Meenakshi B., Narayana Ponnada A., Jain Ranu, Fletcher Stephen A., Lai Dejian, Papanna Ramesha. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2021;10(21):4928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryopreserved human umbilical cord patch for in&#x2010;utero spina bifida repair. Papanna R., Moise K. J., Mann L. K., Fletcher S., Schniederjan R., Bhattacharjee M. B., Stewart R. J., Kaur S., Prabhu S. P., Tseng S. C. G. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2016;47(2):168-176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26489897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurological Outcomes after Human Umbilical Cord Patch for In Utero Spina Bifida Repair in a Sheep Model. Papanna Ramesha, Mann Lovepreet, Snowise Saul, Morales Yisel, Prabhu Sanjay, Tseng Scheffer, Grill Raymond, Fletcher Stephen, Moise Kenneth. American Journal of Perinatology Reports. 2016;06(03):e309-e317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5017885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27621952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allogenic Umbilical Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells Improve Motor Function in Prenatal Surgical Repair of Myelomeningocele: An Ovine Model Study. Athiel Y, Jouannic J-M, Mauffr&#xe9;, Dehan C, Adam C, Blot S, Lallemant P, De Saint Denis T, Larghero J, Nasone J, Guilbaud L. Obstetric Anesthesia Digest. 2025;45(1):37-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero treatment of myelomeningocele with allogenic umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in an ovine model. Guilbaud Lucie, Dugas Ana&#xef;s, Weber Mathilde, Deflers Carole, Lallemant Pauline, Lilin Thomas, Adam Clovis, Cras Audrey, Mebarki Miryam, Z&#xe9;rah Michel, Faivre Lionel, Larghero J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me, Jouannic Jean-Marie. Current Research in Translational Medicine. 2022;70(1):103314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryopreserved Human Umbilical Cord for In Utero Myeloschisis Repair. Papanna Ramesha, Fletcher Stephen, Moise Kenneth J., Mann Lovepreet K., Tseng Scheffer C. G. Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2016;128(2):325-330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27400004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In utero Plastic Surgery in Zurich: Successful Use of Distally Pedicled Random Pattern Transposition Flaps for Definitive Skin Closure during Open Fetal Spina Bifida Repair. Meuli Martin, Meuli-Simmen Claudia, Mazzone Luca, Tharakan Sasha J., Zimmermann Roland, Ochsenbein Nicole, Moehrlen Ueli. Fetal Diagnosis and Therapy. 2017;44(3):173-178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29258087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febotics &#x2013; a marriage of fetal surgery and robotics. Berris M, Shoham M. Computer Aided Surgery. 2006;11(4):175-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robot-Assisted Endoscopic Intrauterine Myelomeningocele Repair: A Feasibility Study. Aaronson Oran S., Tulipan Noel B., Cywes Robert, Sundell H&#xe5;kan W., Davis Georges H., Bruner Joseph P., Richards William O. Pediatric Neurosurgery. 2002;36(2):85-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robot-enhanced fetoscopic surgery. Knight Colin G., Lorincz Attila, Johnson Anthony, Gidell Kelly, Rabah Rajah, Klein Michael D., Langenburg Scott E. Journal of Pediatric Surgery. 2004;39(10):1463-1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15486888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous fetoscopic patch coverage of experimental lumbosacral full-thickness skin lesions in sheep. Kohl T., Hartlage M. G., Kiehitz D., Westphal M., Buller T., Achenbach S., Aryee S., Gembruch U., Brentrup A. Surgical Endoscopy. 2003;17(8):1218-1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12739111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnetically Assisted Robotic Fetal Surgery for the Treatment of Spina Bifida. Gervasoni Simone, Lussi Jonas, Viviani Silvia, Boehler Quentin, Ochsenbein Nicole, Moehrlen Ueli, Nelson Bradley J. IEEE Transactions on Medical Robotics and Bionics. 2022;4(1):85-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetoscopic Robotic Open Spina Bifida Treatment (&lt;scp&gt;FROST&lt;/scp&gt;): A Preclinical Feasibility and Learning Curve Study. Kunpalin Yada, Kik Charlotte C., Lebouthillier Francis, Abbasi Nimrah, Ryan Greg, Spoor Jochem, Looi Thomas, Kulkarni Abhaya V., Van Mieghem Tim. BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynaecology. 2025;132(9):1259-1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12232515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40177988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Three-dimensional printing in congenital heart disease: Considerations on training and clinical implementation from a teaching session. Biglino Giovanni, Milano Elena G, Capelli Claudio, Wray Jo, Shearn Andrew IU, Caputo Massimo, Bucciarelli-Ducci Chiara, Taylor Andrew M, Schievano Silvia. The International Journal of Artificial Organs. 2019;42(10):595-599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31104546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Use of 3D Printing in Fetal Surgery for Surgical Planning: A Scoping Review. Fils Aaron J., Kasmirski Julia, Okpaise Oluwateniayo, Reynolds John M., Tonni Gabriele, Werner Heron, Ruano Rodrigo. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2024;13(17):4999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11396012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound&#x2010;based three&#x2010;dimensional printed medical model for multispecialty team surgical rehearsal prior to fetoscopic myelomeningocele repair. Miller J. L., Ahn E. S., Garcia J. R., Miller G. T., Satin A. J., Baschat A. A. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2018;51(6):836-837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28850758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global variability in fetal spina bifida surgery: a survey of neurosurgical strategies. Kik Charlotte C., Kunpalin Yada, Kulkarni Abhaya V., DeKoninck Philip L. J., Spoor Jochem K. H., Van Mieghem Tim. Journal of Neurosurgery: Pediatrics. 2025;36(1):3-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40250050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evolving Practices in Prenatal Open Spinal Dysraphism: A Global Survey of Selection Criteria, Surgical Techniques, and Diagnostic Trends. Keil Corinna, Wiora Noemi, Krispin Eyal, Windhorst Anita, Axt&#x2010;Fliedner Roland, Bedei Ivonne. Prenatal Diagnosis. 2025;46(1):75-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12819936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41298113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after fetal spina bifida surgery: global practice. Nulens K., Kunpalin Y., Nijs K., Carvalho J. C. A., Pollard L., Abbasi N., Ryan G., Mieghem T. Van. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2024;64(5):669-677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38764196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Policy and Practice for Intrauterine Fetal Resuscitation During Fetal Surgery for Open Spina Bifida Repair. Gallagher Katie, Crombag Neeltje, Prashar Kavita, Deprest Jan, Ourselin Sebastien, David Anna L., Marlow Neil. JAMA Network Open. 2023;6(4):e239855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10130943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37097634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maternal&#x2013;fetal surgery for myelomeningocele longitudinal follow-up model: Mitigation of care fragmentation through care coordination and outcomes reporting. Castillo Jonathan, Locastro Mary M, Corroenne Romain, Malhotra Anjali, Van Speybroeck Alexander, Lai Grace, Belfort Michael A, Sanz Cortes Magdalena, Castillo Heidi. Journal of Pediatric Rehabilitation Medicine. 2025;18(2):146-154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous fetoscopic patch closure of human spina bifida aperta: advances in fetal surgical techniques may obviate the need for early postnatal neurosurgical intervention. Kohl Thomas, Tchatcheva Kristina, Merz Waltraut, Wartenberg Hans C., Heep Axel, M&#xfc;ller Andreas, Franz Axel, Stressig R&#xfc;diger, Willinek Winfried, Gembruch Ulrich. Surgical Endoscopy. 2008;23(4):890-895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18818968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous minimal&#x2010;access fetoscopic surgery for spina bifida aperta. Part &lt;scp&gt;II&lt;/scp&gt;: maternal management and outcome. Degenhardt J., Sch&#xfc;rg R., Winarno A., Oehmke F., Khaleeva A., Kawecki A., Enzensberger C., Tinneberg H.&#x2010;R., Faas D., Ehrhardt H., Axt&#x2010;Fliedner R., Kohl T. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2014;44(5):525-531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24753062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percutaneous minimally invasive fetoscopic surgery for spina bifida aperta. Part I: surgical technique and perioperative outcome. Kohl T. Ultrasound in Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology. 2014;44(5):515-524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24891102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The first experience with 16 open microsurgical fetal surgeries for myelomeningocele in Germany. El Damaty Ahmed, Els&#xe4;sser Michael, Pfeifer Ulrich, Kotzaeridou Urania, Gille Christian, Spratte Julia, Zivanovic Oliver, Sohn Christoph, Krieg Sandro M., B&#xe4;chli Heidrun, Unterberg Andreas. European Journal of Paediatric Neurology. 2025;55:79-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40154034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Systematic classification of maternal and fetal intervention&#x2010;related complications following open fetal myelomeningocele repair&#xa0;&#x2013;&#xa0;results from a large prospective cohort. Vonzun L, Kahr MK, Noll F, Mazzone L, Moehrlen U, Meuli M, H&#xfc;sler M, Kr&#xe4;henmann F, Zimmermann R, Ochsenbein&#x2010;K&#xf6;lble N. BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynaecology. 2020;128(7):1184-1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33152167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The clinical experience of fetoscopic repair of myelomeningocele in Taiwan: The dilemma in prenatal decision-making and first successful case. Feng Ming, Chen Pei-Chen, Lin Guan-Ru, Lin Tzu-Yi, Hsieh T'sang-T'ang, Shaw Steven W. Taiwanese Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology. 2024;63(6):904-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39482001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetal Surgery for Open Spina Bifida in Canada: Initial Results. Pruthi Vagisha, Abbasi Nimrah, Ryan Greg, Drake James, Kulkarni Abhaya V., Kwan-Wong Terence, Phillips John, Thakur Varsha, Church Paige, Diambomba Yenge, Kelly Edmond, Vermeersch Leslie, Pollard Lindsay, Carvalho Jose C.A., Van Mieghem Tim. Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology Canada. 2021;43(6):733-739.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33227419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contemporary Outcomes of a National Fetal Spina Bifida Surgery Service. Kik Charlotte C., Kunpalin Yada, Kulkarni Abhaya V., Varghese Abby, Abbasi Nimrah, Ryan Greg, Dekoninck Philip L. J., Church Paige T., Malhotra Armaan, Raghuram Kamini, Kelly Edmond, Van Mieghem Tim. Prenatal Diagnosis. 2024;44(13):1635-1640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11628204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39425664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xe9;sultats pr&#xe9;liminaires de l&#x2019;&#xe9;tude PRIUM : programme de r&#xe9;paration in utero des my&#xe9;lom&#xe9;ningoc&#xe8;les. Friszer S, Dhombres F, Di Rocco F, Rigouzzo A, Garel C, Guilbaud L J Gynecol Obstet Biol Reprod(Paris) 2016;(45):738&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26566108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open fetal surgery for myelomeningocele repair in France. Guilbaud Lucie, Maurice Paul, Lallemant Pauline, De Saint-Denis Timoth&#xe9;e, Maisonneuve Emeline, Dhombres Ferdinand, Friszer St&#xe9;phanie, Di Rocco Federico, Garel Catherine, Moutard Marie-Laure, Lachtar Mohamed-Ali, Rigouzzo Agn&#xe8;s, Forin V&#xe9;ronique, Z&#xe9;rah Michel, Jouannic Jean-Marie. Journal of Gynecology Obstetrics and Human Reproduction. 2021;50(9):102155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadassah International. Hadassah Medical Center&#xD;
Performs Israel&#x2019;s First Spina Bifida Fetal Surgery to&#xD;
Lessen Crippling Spinal Damage. Hadassah International. https://hadassahinternational.org/hadassah-medical- center-performs-israels-first-spina-bifida-fetal- surgery-lessen-crippling-spinal-damage https://hadassahinternational.org/hadassah-medical- center-performs-israels-first-spina-bifida-fetal- surgery-lessen-crippling-spinal-damage</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenatal Spina Bifida Repair: A Survey of Current Practice in the United States. Garg Stuti P., Shah Krish V., Lentskevich Marina, Yau Alice, Gosain Arun K. Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery - Global Open. 2024;12(12):e6377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39703379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethical challenges in conducting maternal-fetal surgery trials. A systematic review. Cavolo Alice, Gastmans Chris, Crombag Neeltje. Pediatric Research. 2024;98(2):479-490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12454111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39639107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethical challenges in invasive maternal-fetal intervention. Austin Mary T., Cole Thomas R., McCullough Laurence B., Chervenak Frank A. Seminars in Pediatric Surgery. 2019;28(4):150819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31451174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Fetus as a Patient Surgical Considerations. HARRISON MICHAEL R., ADZICK N. SCOTT. Annals of Surgery. 1991;213(4):279-291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1358346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2009009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Unborn Patient: Prenatal Diagnosis and Treatment. Copel Joshua A. JAMA: The Journal of the American Medical Association. 1991;265(17):2261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison MR, Evans ML, Adzick NS, Holzgreve W . The Unborn Patient: The Art and Science of Fetal Therapy. 3rd ed. W.B. Saunders Company; 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>