<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41269473</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Divergent Responses to Training Load in Professional Australian Football: Are Insights Obtained from Generic and Running-based Assessments Complementary or Redundant?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>139</StartPage><MedlinePgn>139</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">139</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00946-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Generic neuromuscular assessments are widely used to monitor training responses in team sports. Emerging running-based measures have been proposed to offer greater sensitivity to residual neuromuscular training effects by aligning more closely with the exercise dose, yet their practical utility remains ambiguous. Concurrent evaluation is thus necessary to identify athlete monitoring assessments that best capture meaningful responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We examined within-athlete relationships among common training response measures and their associations with prior weekly external training load in professional Australian Football athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Repeated-measures, observational.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-three male athletes were regularly assessed over two pre-seasons following 48-hours of no training. Outcome measures were derived from maximal performances in adductor strength and countermovement jump (CMJ) assessments, the final minute of a continuous-fixed submaximal fitness test (CF-SMFT: 3-minutes, 12&#xa0;km&#x22c5;h<sup>-1</sup>), and the plateau-phase of a high-intensity intermittent-fixed run (HI-IR<sub>plateau</sub>: 50&#xa0;m, ~&#x2009;25&#xa0;km&#x22c5;h<sup>-1</sup>). External loads were derived from Global Navigation Satellite Systems. Repeated-measures correlations assessed relationships between the response measures, while linear mixed-effects models evaluated measurement variability. Generalised Additive Models examined associations between prior weekly external training loads and the response measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Adductor strength and CMJ measures showed low within-athlete variability (coefficient of variation, CV&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.3-6.6%) and limited associations with weekly external loads. Conversely, 2 standard deviation (SD) increases in weekly total distance were associated with reductions in CF-SMFT HR<sub>ex</sub> of -&#x2009;1.3%-points (95% Confidence Intervals, CI: -&#x2009;0.9, -&#x2009;1.8), and as large as -&#x2009;3.2%-points. Similarly, 2 SD increases in very-high speed running (&gt;&#x2009;25&#xa0;km.h<sup>-1</sup>) were associated with declines in HI-IR<sub>plateau</sub> velocity of -&#x2009;0.4&#xa0;km&#xb7;h<sup>-1</sup> (95% CI: -&#x2009;0.1, -&#x2009;0.8), and as much as -&#x2009;1.2&#xa0;km&#xb7;h<sup>-1</sup>. Both effects exceeded thresholds of practical significance, as indicated by the typical error of measurement. Accelerometer-vector measures presented inconsistent associations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Weekly external load changes were reflected in CF-SMFT HR<sub>ex</sub> and HI-IR<sub>plateau</sub> velocity, supporting their practical utility for athlete monitoring; whereas measures derived from generic neuromuscular tests (adductor strength, and CMJ) showed limited responsiveness. Associations between external loads and accelerometer-derived measures presented significant uncertainty, which currently limits confident recommendations on the utility of these emerging techniques.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arguedas-Soley</LastName><ForeName>Adriano</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1356-1283</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, Australia. adrianoarguedas23@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Performance Department, Greater Western Sydney (GWS) Giants Football Club, Sydney, NSW, Australia. adrianoarguedas23@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shushan</LastName><ForeName>Tzlil</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0544-1986</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Performance Department, Greater Western Sydney (GWS) Giants Football Club, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poulos</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Performance Department, Greater Western Sydney (GWS) Giants Football Club, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lovell</LastName><ForeName>Ric</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5859-0267</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norris</LastName><ForeName>Dean</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7744-6233</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Performance Department, Greater Western Sydney (GWS) Giants Football Club, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adductor strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Countermovement jump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Embedded testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular state</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Response measure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Submaximal fitness test</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: The study received approval from the Human Research Ethics Committee at Western Sydney University (HREC number: H15643). All athletes were aware that the scientific investigation and analysis may occur under their contractual agreements, with no experimental manipulation. Informed consent for analysis of anonymised data was therefore not deemed necessary [75]. Nonetheless, all data collection and handling conformed to recommendations of the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for Publication: The authors confirm that they have obtained the necessary consent for the publication of any data and findings within the present manuscript. An official letter from the reference club is attached to this submission titled &#x201c;Data Approval Letter - Divergent Responses to Training&#x201d; as a supplementary file. Competing Interests: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal interests that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41269473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12638591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00946-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00946-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scott TJ, McLaren SJ, Lovell R, Scott MTU, Barrett S. The reliability, validity and sensitivity of an individualised sub-maximal fitness test in elite rugby league athletes. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(8):840&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2021.2021047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35001859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan S, Kempton T, Impellizzeri FM, Coutts AJ. Training monitoring in professional Australian football: theoretical basis and recommendations for coaches and scientists. Sci Med Footb. 2020;4(1):52&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2019.1641212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B, Woods JJ. Changes in muscle contractile properties and neural control during human muscular fatigue. Muscle Nerve: Official J Am Association Electrodiagn Med. 1984;7(9):691&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880070902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6100456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanrenterghem J, Nedergaard NJ, Robinson MA, Drust B. Training load monitoring in team sports: a novel framework separating physiological and Biomechanical load-adaptation pathways. Sports Med. 2017;47(11):2135&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0714-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):270&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Shrier I, McLaren SJ, Coutts AJ, McCall A, Slattery K et al. Understanding training load as exposure and dose. Sports Med. 2023:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West S, Shrier I, Impellizzeri FM, Clubb J, Ward P, Bullock G. Training-Load management ambiguities and weak logic: creating potential consequences in sport training and performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;1(aop):1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39255956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri F, Shrier I, McLaren S, Coutts A, McCall A, Slattery K et al. Understanding training load as exposure and dose.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor K-L, Cronin J, Gill ND, Chapman DW, Sheppard J. Sources of variability in iso-inertial jump assessments. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(4):546&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.5.4.546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooney MG, Cormack S, O&#x2019;Brien BJ, Morgan WM, McGuigan M. Impact of neuromuscular fatigue on match exercise intensity and performance in elite Australian football. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2013;27(1):166&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182514683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22395264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP. Neuromuscular, biochemicndocrine and physiological responses of elite rugby league players to competitive match-play. 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, Loturco I, Harry J, Virgile A, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance Profiling, neuromuscular fatigue Monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Conditioning J. 2022;10:15&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe GAB, Phibbs PJ, Till K, Jones BL, Read DB, Weakley JJ, et al. Changes in adductor strength after competition in academy rugby union players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2016;30(2):344&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Norris D, McLaren SJ, Buchheit M, Scott TJ, Barrett S, et al. A worldwide survey on the practices and perceptions of submaximal fitness tests in team sports. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;18(7):765&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37207997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreira J, Gantois P, Castro J, Mesquita X, Peixoto R, Cid MF, et al. Using bar velocity to assess post-match neuromuscular fatigue in young soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2024;45(08):589&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2150-0960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37549884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaghan DE, Guy JH, Kean CO, Scanlan AT, Kertesz AHM, Elsworthy N. Back squat velocity to assess neuromuscular status of rugby league players following a match. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(1):36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris D, Joyce D, Siegler J, Cohen D, Lovell R. Considerations in interpreting neuromuscular state in elite level Australian rules football players. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(7):702&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33715988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson NE, Boyd AJ, Murray AM. Countermovement jump is not affected during final competition Preparation periods in elite rugby sevens players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2016;30(3):777&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Lacome M, Cholley Y, Simpson BM. Neuromuscular responses to conditioned soccer sessions assessed via GPS-embedded accelerometers: insights into tactical periodization. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(5):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Strudwick AJ, Buchheit M, Atkinson G, Drust B, Gregson W. The influence of changes in acute training load on daily sensitivity of morning-measured fatigue variables in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(s2):S2&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Stuart DG. Neurobiology of muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 1992;72(5):1631&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1992.72.5.1631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1601767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns SP, Knicker AJ, Thompson MW, Sj&#xf8;gaard G. Evaluation of models used to study neuromuscular fatigue. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2005;33(1):9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15640715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB, Hunkin SL, Fahrner B, Robertson S. Deceleration, acceleration, and impacts are strong contributors to muscle damage in professional Australian football. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2019;33(12):3374&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Cart&#xf3;n-Llorente A, Ja&#xe9;n-Carrillo D, Delgado-Floody P, Carrasco-Alarc&#xf3;n V, Mart&#xed;nez C, et al. Does fatigue alter step characteristics and stiffness during running? Gait Posture. 2020;76:259&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2019.12.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31881479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Micallef J-P, Millet GP. Changes in spring-mass model characteristics during repeated running sprints. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:125&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1638-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20824280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darch L, Chalmers S, Wiltshire J, Causby R, Arnold J. Running-induced fatigue and impact loading in runners: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(13):1512&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2022.2089803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35723671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabita G, Slawinski J, Girard O, Bignet F, Hausswirth C. Spring-mass behavior during exhaustive run at constant velocity in elite triathletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:685&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181fb3793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Samozino P, Millet GY. Changes in running kinematics, kinetics, and spring-mass behavior over a 24-h run. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(5):829&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181fec518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Pyne DB, Telford RD, Hawley JA. Factors affecting running economy in trained distance runners. Sports Med. 2004;34(7):465&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434070-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15233599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett J, Akyildiz Z, Leduc C, van den Hoek D, Manuel Clemente F, Ardig&#xf2; LP. Peak running speed can be used to monitor neuromuscular fatigue from a standardized running test in team sport athletes. Res Sports Med. 2021:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Brocherie F, Morin J-B, Millet GP. Mechanical alterations during interval-training treadmill runs in high-level male team-sport players. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(1):87&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27256789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Dalleau G, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Jeannin T, Belli A. A simple method for measuring stiffness during running. J Appl Biomech. 2005;21(2):167&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jab.21.2.167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16082017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: do all roads lead to rome? Front Physiol. 2014;5:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2014.00073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24578692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider C, Wiewelhove T, McLaren SJ, R&#xf6;leke L, K&#xe4;sbauer H, Hecksteden A, et al. Monitoring training and recovery responses with heart rate measures during standardized warm-up in elite badminton players. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(12):e0244412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0244412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7751974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Gray A, Morin J-B. Assessing Stride variables and vertical stiffness with GPS-embedded accelerometers: preliminary insights for the monitoring of neuromuscular fatigue on the field. J Sports Sci Med. 2015;14(4):698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4657410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26664264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leduc C, Tee J, Lacome M, Weakley J, Cheradame J, Ramirez C, et al. Convergent validity, reliability, and sensitivity of a running test to monitor neuromuscular fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15(8):1067&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett J, Graham SR, Eston RG, Burgess DJ, Garrett LJ, Jakeman J, et al. A novel method of assessment for monitoring neuromuscular fatigue in Australian rules football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(5):598&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Byrne F, Wycherley TP, Bishop C, Schwerdt S, Porter J, Buckley JD. Accelerometer detected lateral sway during a submaximal running test correlates with endurance exercise performance in elite Australian male cricket players. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(5):519&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, McLaren SJ, Buchheit M, Scott TJ, Barrett S, Lovell R. Submaximal fitness tests in team sports: a theoretical framework for evaluating physiological state. Sports Med. 2022;52(11):2605&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01712-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9584880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35817993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsley BJ, Tofari PJ, Halson SL, Kemp JG, Chalkley D, Cole MH et al. Validity and reliability of thoracic-mounted inertial measurement units to derive gait characteristics during running. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2022:10&#x2013;1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37884006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie D, Hopkins WG, Buchheit M, Cordy J, Bartlett JD. Quantification of training and competition load across a season in an elite Australian football club. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(4):474&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varley MC, Fairweather IH, Aughey RJ. Validity and reliability of GPS for measuring instantaneous velocity during acceleration, deceleration, and constant motion. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(2):121&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.627941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22122431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone JJ, Lovell R, Varley MC, Coutts AJ. Unpacking the black box: applications and considerations for using GPS devices in sport. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(s2):S2&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27736244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormann CF, Elith J, Bacher S, Buchmann C, Carl G, Carr&#xe9; G, et al. Collinearity: a review of methods to deal with it and a simulation study evaluating their performance. Ecography. 2013;36(1):27&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0587.2012.07348.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S, Trewartha G, Cross MJ, Kemp SPT, Stokes KA. Monitoring what matters: a systematic process for selecting training-load measures. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(s2):S2&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27834553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffries AC, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ, Wallace L, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM. Development of a revised conceptual framework of physical training for use in research and practice. Sports Med. 2021:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan S, Kempton T, Pacecca E, Coutts AJ. Measurement properties of an adductor strength-assessment system in professional Australian footballers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):256&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29952674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole R, Sporer B, Stellingwerff T, Sleivert G. Alternative countermovement-jump analysis to quantify acute neuromuscular fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(1):84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2013-0413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Lovell R, Buchheit M, Scott TJ, Barrett S, Norris D, et al. Submaximal fitness test in team sports: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis of exercise heart rate measurement properties. Sports Medicine-Open. 2023;9(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00564-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10039193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36964427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Lovell R, McLaren SJ, Buchheit M, Iacono AD, Arguedas-Soley A et al. Assessing criterion and longitudinal validity of submaximal heart rate indices as measures of cardiorespiratory fitness: a preliminary study in football. J Sci Med Sport. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38702215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd LJ, Ball K, Aughey RJ. The reliability of minimaxx accelerometers for measuring physical activity in Australian football. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2011;6(3):311&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.6.3.311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21911857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Lovell R, McLaren SJ, Barrett S, Buchheit M, Scott TJ, et al. A methodological comparison of protocols and analytical techniques to assess the outcome measures of submaximal fitness tests. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;1(aop):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38086364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira AS, Pirscoveanu CI. Implications of sample size and acquired number of steps to investigate running biomechanics. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):3083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-82876-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33542463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick JF, Akenhead R, Russell M, Hicks KM, Hayes PR. Sensitivity and reproducibility of a fatigue response in elite youth football players. Sci Med Footb. 2019;3(3):214&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2019.1571685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers TM, Massard TI, Clothier PJ, Lovell R. Measuring vertical stiffness in sport with accelerometers: exercise caution! J Strength Conditioning Res. 2018;32(7):1919&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29120988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson LC, Clermont CA, Watari R, Exley T, Ferber R. Automated accelerometer-based gait event detection during multiple running conditions. Sensors. 2019;19(7):1483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s19071483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30934672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Calculating correlation coefficients with repeated observations: part 2&#x2014;Correlation between subjects. BMJ. 1995;310(6980):633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.310.6980.633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2549010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7703752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W, Marshall S, Batterham A, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med + Sci Sports + Exerc. 2009;41(1):3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood SN. Fast stable restricted maximum likelihood and marginal likelihood Estimation of semiparametric generalized linear models. J Royal Stat Soc Ser B: Stat Methodol. 2011;73(1):3&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-9868.2010.00749.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood SN. Generalized additive models: an introduction with R: chapman and hall/CRC; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra G, Wood SN. Practical variable selection for generalized additive models. Comput Stat Data Anal. 2011;55(7):2372&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csda.2011.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood SN. On p-values for smooth components of an extended generalized additive model. Biometrika. 2013;100(1):221&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/biomet/ass048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra G, Wood SN. Coverage properties of confidence intervals for generalized additive model components. Scand J Stat. 2012;39(1):53&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-9469.2011.00760.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer JL, Graham JW. Missing data: our view of the state of the Art. Psychol Methods. 2002;7(2):147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1082-989X.7.2.147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12090408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collings TJ, Lima YL, Dutaillis B, Bourne MN. Concurrent validity and test&#x2013;retest reliability of VALD ForceDecks&#x2019; strength, balance, and movement assessment tests. J Sci Med Sport. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38777737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili A, Stewart AM, Hopkins WG, Elias GP, Lazarus BH, Rowell AE, et al. Normal variability of weekly musculoskeletal screening scores and the influence of training load across an Australian football league season. Front Physiol. 2018;9:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5835227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naughton M, Scott T, McLean S, Solomon C, Walsh J, Weaving D. The influence of external loads on post-match neuromuscular fatigue in international rugby union: A partial least squares correlational analysis. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(15):1421&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2394745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39258624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonie TA, Brade CJ, Finucane ME, Jacques A, Grisbrook TL. Hip adduction and abduction strength and adduction-to-abduction ratio changes across an Australian football league season. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(1):2&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31445951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor SJ, Busa MA, Yaggie JA, Bollt EM. High resolution MEMS accelerometers to estimate VO2 and compare running mechanics between highly trained inter-collegiate and untrained runners. PLoS ONE. 2009;4(10):e7355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0007355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19806216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Allen SJ, Black MI, Handsaker JC, Forrester SE. Running technique is an important component of running economy and performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(7):1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5473370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28263283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalleau G, Belli A, Viale F, Lacour JR, Bourdin M. A simple method for field measurements of leg stiffness in hopping. Int J Sports Med. 2004;25(03):170&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2003-45252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15088239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Meur Y, Hausswirth C, Natta F, Couturier A, Bignet F, Vidal PP. A multidisciplinary approach to overreaching detection in endurance trained athletes. J Appl Physiol. 2013;114(3):411&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01254.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23195630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole RJ, Stellingwerff T, Sporer BC. Effect of acute fatigue and training adaptation on countermovement jump performance in elite snowboard cross athletes. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2015;29(1):37&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25029001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter EM, Maughan RJ. Requirements for ethics approvals. 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19847681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>