<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41324447</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Return to performance criteria in soccer after musculoskeletal injury: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>724</StartPage><EndPage>751</EndPage><MedlinePgn>724-751</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70180</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Return to performance (RTPe), the final stage of the return to sport (RTS) continuum remains poorly defined in current soccer-related musculoskeletal (MSK) research, with limited identification and application of physical and/or psychological performance-based indicators. This scoping review aimed to systematically identify and synthesise currently used RTPe criteria, with a specific focus on facilitating return to competitive soccer at the same or higher level than pre-injury and identify gaps in relation to sport-specific demands. A scoping review was conducted in accordance with the PRISMA-ScR guidelines, using comprehensive Boolean search strategies across PubMed, CINAHL, and Web of Science databases. A total of twenty-nine peer reviewed studies met the inclusion criteria. Reported RTPe criteria encompassed the following domains: clinical examination, strength assessment, functional testing, performance-based testing, time elapsed since injury, and patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). Most studies concentrated on the second stage of the three-stage RTS continuum, that is, 'Return to Sports', with limited integration of on-field, sport specific, or ecologically valid performance assessments. In addition, studies frequently neglect recommendations advocating a multidimensional and standardised test battery. Moreover, psychological readiness and performance-level demands-critical components of RTPe in elite soccer-were seldom addressed or often lacked standardised definitions. Female athletes were underrepresented despite higher injury incidence (6.77 vs. 5.70/1000&#x2009;h in males). Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries were overrepresented, whereas more frequently occurring injuries like posterior thigh and groin injuries received less attention. More than half of the studies focused on elite athletes, limiting generalisability to recreational level. These findings underscore the urgent need for more robust, operationalized, and sport-specific RTPe criteria to support clinical decision-making and optimise outcomes following musculoskeletal injury in soccer. Existing criteria do not reliably capture readiness to pre-injury performance levels, addressing performance metrics, sport specific demands, and sex-specific considerations. Level of Evidence: N/A.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eppinga</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7537-7000</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Human Movement Sciences, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MCZ Fysiotherapie en Sportbegeleiding, Groningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Welling</LastName><ForeName>Wouter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Training Medicine and Training Physiology, TGTF, Royal Netherlands Army, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dekker</LastName><ForeName>Rienk</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zwerver</LastName><ForeName>Hans</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Human Movement Sciences, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Valley, Department of Sports Medicine, Hospital Gelderse Vallei, Ede, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068958" MajorTopicYN="Y">Return to Sport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009141" MajorTopicYN="Y">Musculoskeletal System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071066" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Reported Outcome Measures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decision making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soccer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41324447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12850624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allen T, Wilson S, Cohen DD, Taberner M. Drill design using the &#x2018;control&#x2010;chaos continuum&#x2019;: blending science and art during return to sport following knee injury in elite football. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;50:22&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33862346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann S, Neumann R, H&#xe4;rtel S, Kurz G, Stein T, Woll A. Agility testing in amateur soccer: a pilot study of selected physical and perceptual&#x2010;cognitive contributions. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0253819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8224952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelozzi M, Madama M, Corsica C, Calvisi V, Properzi G, McCaw ST, et al. Rate of force development as an adjunctive outcome measure for return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport decisions after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42:772&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, Witvrouw E, Clarsen B, Cools A, et al. 2016 Consensus statement on return to sport from the First World Congress in Sports Physical Therapy, Bern. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:853&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O'Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8:19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnason A, Sigurdsson SB, Gudmundsson A, Holme I, Engebretsen L, Bahr R. Risk factors for injuries in football. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:5&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14754854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista I, Johansen D, Figueiredo P, Rebelo A, Pettersen SA. Positional differences in peak&#x2010; and accumulated&#x2010; training load relative to match load in elite football. Sports. 2019;8:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7023441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31877942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista I, Johansen D, Seabra A, Pettersen SA. Position specific player load during match&#x2010;play in a professional football club. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0198115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisciotti GN, Volpi P, Alberti G, Aprato A, Artina M, Auci A, et al. Italian consensus statement (2020) on return to play after lower limb muscle injury in football (soccer). BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2019;5:e000505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6797382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31673400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanch P, Gabbett TJ. Has the athlete trained enough to return to play safely? The acute:chronic workload ratio permits clinicians to quantify a player's risk of subsequent injury. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:471&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy RH, Stepan JG, Silvers HJ, Mandelbaum BR. Defending puts the anterior cruciate ligament at risk during soccer: a gender&#x2010;based analysis. Sports Health. 2015;7:244&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4482300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Optimising the late&#x2010;stage rehabilitation and return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2019;49:1043&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F, Della Villa S, Roi GS. On&#x2010;field rehabilitation part 2: a 5&#x2010;stage program for the soccer player focused on linear movements, multidirectional movements, soccer&#x2010;specific skills, soccer&#x2010;specific movements, and modified practice. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49:570&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Tamisari A, Villa FD. A ten task&#x2010;based progression in rehabilitation after acl reconstruction: from post&#x2010;surgery to return to play &#x2013; a clinical commentary. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15:611&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7735691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33354394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgi CR, Peters S, Ardern CL, Magill JR, Gomez CD, Sylvain J, et al. Which criteria are used to clear patients to return to sport after primary ACL reconstruction? A scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1154&#x2013;1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona G, Moreno&#x2010;Simonet L, Cosio PL, Astrella A, Fern&#xe1;ndez D, Cadefau JA, et al. Hamstrings on focus: are 72 hours sufficient for recovery after a football (soccer) match? A multidisciplinary approach based on hamstring injury risk factors and histology. J Sports Sci. 2024;42:1130&#x2013;1146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39087576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa RV, Verhagen E, Resende RA, Ocarino JM. Performance in field&#x2010;tests and dynamic knee valgus in soccer players psychologically ready and not ready to return to sports after ACL reconstruction. Knee. 2023;42:297&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37119602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Paolo S, Nijmeijer E, Bragonzoni L, Dingshoff E, Gokeler A, Benjaminse A. Comparing lab and field agility kinematics in young talented female football players: implications for ACL injury prevention. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23:859&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35400311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doege J, Ayres JM, Mackay MJ, Tarakemeh A, Brown SM, Vopat BG, et al. Defining return to sport: a systematic review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9:23259671211009589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34377709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draovitch P, Patel S, Marrone W, Grundstein MJ, Grant R, Virgile A, et al. The return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport clearance continuum is a novel approach toward return to sport and performance for the professional athlete. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:e93&#x2013;e101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop G, Ardern CL, Andersen TE, Lewin C, Dupont G, Ashworth B, et al. return&#x2010;to&#x2010;play practices following hamstring injury: a worldwide survey of 131 Premier League Football Teams. Sports Med. 2020;50:829&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estevez Rodriguez JL, Rivilla Garcia J, Jimenez&#x2010;Rubio S. Return to performance of a soccer player with an adductor longus injury: A case report. Medicina (Kaunas) 2024;60:1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11727924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39768878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanchini M, Impellizzeri FM, Silbernagel KG, Combi F, Benazzo F, Bizzini M. Return to competition after an Achilles tendon rupture using both on and off the field load monitoring as guidance: a case report of a top&#x2010;level soccer player. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;29:70&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28647204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanchini M, Steendahl IB, Impellizzeri FM, Pruna R, Dupont G, Coutts AJ, et al. Exercise&#x2010;based strategies to prevent muscle injury in elite footballers: a systematic review and best evidence synthesis. Sports Med. 2020;50:1653&#x2013;1666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32185630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa D, Arce G, Espregueira&#x2010;Mendes J, Maestu R, Mosquera M, Williams A, et al. Return to sport soccer after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: ISAKOS consensus. J ISAKOS. 2022;7:150&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35998884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forelli F, Le Coroller N, Gaspar M, Memain G, Kakavas G, Miraglia N, et al. Ecological and specific evidence&#x2010;based safe return to play after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in soccer players: a new international paradigm. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18:526&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T, Sancho I, Dingenen B, Willy RW. When progressing training loads, what are the considerations for healthy and injured athletes? Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:947&#x2013;948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Dingenen B, Hewett TE. Rehabilitation and return to sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: where are we in 2022? Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:e77&#x2013;e82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golberg E, Sommerfeldt M, Pinkoski A, Dennett L, Beaupre L. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport decision&#x2010;making: a scoping review. Sports Health. 2023;16:115&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10732109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36707977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez&#x2010;Piqueras P, Gonzalez&#x2010;Rubio J, Sainz de Baranda P, Najera A. Use of functional performance tests in sports: Evaluation proposal for football players in the rehabilitation phase. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;64:148&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31453505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Peacock R. Effectiveness and efficiency of search methods in systematic reviews of complex evidence: audit of primary sources. BMJ. 2005;331:1064&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1283190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16230312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M, Ekstrand J. Injury recurrence is lower at the highest professional football level than at national and amateur levels: does sports medicine and sports physiotherapy deliver? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:751&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27015858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Walden M, Ekstrand J. Lower reinjury rate with a coach&#x2010;controlled rehabilitation program in amateur male soccer: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:1433&#x2013;1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17369558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horan D, B&#xfc;ttner F, Blake C, H&#xe4;gglund M, Kelly S, Delahunt E. Injury incidence rates in women's football: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of prospective injury surveillance studies. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:471&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kekelekis A, Kounali Z, Kofotolis N, Clemente FM, Kellis E. Epidemiology of injuries in amateur male soccer players: a prospective one&#x2010;year study. Healthcare. 2023;11:352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36766927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani Haft Lang M, Mofateh R, Orakifar N, Goharpey S. Differences in neurocognitive functions between healthy controls and anterior cruciate ligament&#x2010;reconstructed male athletes who passed or failed return to sport criteria: a preliminary study. J Sport Rehabil. 2023;32:645&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurz E, Bloch H, Buchholz I, Maier D, Praetorius A, Seyler S, et al. Assessment of return to play after an acute shoulder injury: protocol for an explorative prospective observational German multicentre study. BMJ Open. 2023;13:e067073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9900062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Valenciano A, Ruiz&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez I, Garcia&#x2010;G&#xf3;mez A, Vera&#x2010;Garcia FJ, De Ste Croix M, Myer GD, et al. Epidemiology of injuries in professional football: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:711&#x2013;718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9929604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31171515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestroni L, Turner A, Papadopoulos K, Sideris V, Read P. Total score of athleticism: profiling strength and power characteristics in professional soccer players after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction to assess readiness to return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:3121&#x2013;3130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10543956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37681510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauvais&#x2010;Jarvis F, Bairey Merz N, Barnes PJ, Brinton RD, Carrero JJ, DeMeo DL, et al. Sex and gender: modifiers of health, disease, and medicine. Lancet. 2020;396:565&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32828189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer SW, Queen RM, Taylor D, Moorman CT, Toth AP, Garrett WE, et al. Functional testing differences in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients released versus not released to return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:1648&#x2013;1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25868636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Martinez&#x2010;Ruiz E, Edouard P, Morin J&#x2010;B, Martinez&#x2010;Martinez F, Idoate F, et al. A multifactorial, criteria&#x2010;based progressive algorithm for hamstring injury treatment. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:1482&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28277402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell A, Waite O, Holding C, Greig M. The development of a return to performance pathway involving a professional soccer player returning from a multi&#x2010;structural knee injury: a case report. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18:450&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Bangsbo J. Match performance of high&#x2010;standard soccer players with special reference to development of fatigue. J Sports Sci. 2003;21:519&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12848386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Peters MDJ, Stern C, Tufanaru C, McArthur A, Aromataris E. Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30453902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norouzi S, Esfandiarpour F, Mehdizadeh S, Yousefzadeh NK, Parnianpour M. Lower extremity kinematic analysis in male athletes with unilateral anterior cruciate reconstruction in a jump&#x2010;landing task and its association with return to sport criteria. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20:492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31656192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleksy &#x141;, Mika A, Kielnar R, Szczud&#x142;o M, Racheniuk H, Adamska O, et al. Composite Score of Readiness (CSR) as a data reduction technique for monitoring the RTS process in footballers following ACL reconstruction. Symmetry. 2023;15:298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleksy &#x141;, Mika A, Sulowska&#x2010;Daszyk I, Szymczyk D, Kuchciak M, Stolarczyk A, et al. Standard RTS criteria effectiveness verification using FMS, Y&#x2010;balance and TJA in footballers following ACL reconstruction and mild lower limb injuries. Sci Rep. 2021;11:1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33452381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otley T, Myers H, Lau BC, Taylor DC. Return to sport after shoulder stabilization procedures: a criteria&#x2010;based testing continuum to guide rehabilitation and inform return&#x2010;to&#x2010;play decision making. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:e237&#x2013;e246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualini I, Rossi LA, Brandariz R, Tanoira I, Fuentes N, Denard PJ, et al. Effect of playing position on return to sport, functional outcomes, and recurrence after arthroscopic bankart repair in soccer players. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671221138106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9709182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36466593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Godfrey CM, Khalil H, McInerney P, Parker D, Soares CB. Guidance for conducting systematic scoping reviews. Int J Evid&#x2010;Based Healthcare. 2015;13:141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26134548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picinini F, Della Villa F, Tallent J, Patterson SD, Galassi L, Parigino M, et al. High return to competition rate after on&#x2010;field rehabilitation in competitive male soccer players after ACL reconstruction: GPS tracking in 100 consecutive cases. Orthop J Sports Med. 2025;13:23259671251320093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11881939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40052178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piskin D, Benjaminse A, Dimitrakis P, Gokeler A. Neurocognitive and neurophysiological functions related to ACL injury: a framework for neurocognitive approaches in rehabilitation and return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sports tests. Sports Health. 2022;14:549&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34236003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Enes Kayaalp M, Ramadanov N, Karlsson J, Hirschmann MT. Enhancing research methods: The role of systematic and scoping reviews in orthopaedics, sports medicine and rehabilitation. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11:e70069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11534858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39502322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampinini E, Coutts A, Castagna C, Sassi R, Impellizzeri F. Variation in top level soccer match performance. Int J Sports Med. 2007;28:1018&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17497575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds J, Connor M, Jamil M, Beato M. Quantifying and comparing the match demands of U18, U23, and 1ST team English professional soccer players. Front Physiol. 2021;12:706451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34276425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles&#x2010;Palaz&#xf3;n FJ, L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Valenciano A, De Ste Croix M, Oliver JL, Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;G&#xf3;mez A, Sainz de Baranda P, et al. Epidemiology of injuries in male and female youth football players: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11:681&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9729930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34700052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MD, Vicenzino B, Bahr R, Bandholm T, Cooke R, Mendon&#xe7;a LDM, et al. Return to sport decisions after an acute lateral ankle sprain injury: introducing the PAASS framework&#x2010;an international multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:1270&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stares J, Dawson B, Peeling P, Drew M, Heasman J, Rogalski B, et al. How much is enough in rehabilitation? High running workloads following lower limb muscle injury delay return to play but protect against subsequent injury. J Sci Med Sport. 2018;21:1019&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolen T, Chamari K, Castagna C, Wisl U. Physiology of soccer: an update. Sports Med. 2005;35:501&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15974635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taberner M, Allen T, O'keefe J, Cohen DD. Contextual considerations using the &#x2018;control&#x2010;chaos continuum&#x2019; for return to sport in elite football &#x2010; Part 1: Load planning. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;53:67&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34839202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JB, Ford KR, Queen RM, Owen EC, Gisselman AS. Incorporating internal and external training load measurements in clinical decision making after ACL reconstruction: a clinical commentary. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16:565&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JB, Owen E, Ford KR. Incorporating workload measures into rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A case report. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15:823&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33110702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson A, Einarsson E, Hansen C, Bleakley C, Whiteley R. Marked asymmetry in vertical force (but not contact times) during running in ACL reconstructed athletes &lt;9 months post&#x2010;surgery despite meeting functional criteria for return to sport. J Sci Med Sport. 2018;21:890&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tol JL, Hamilton B, Eirale C, Muxart P, Jacobsen P, Whiteley R. At return to play following hamstring injury the majority of professional football players have residual isokinetic deficits. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1364&#x2013;1369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O'Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA&#x2010;ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valente HG, Oliveira RR, Baroni BM. How are hamstring strain injuries managed in elite men's football clubs? A survey with 62 Brazilian physical therapists. Phys Ther Sport. 2023;61:73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36940549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Beijsterveldt AM, Steffen K, Stubbe JH, Frederiks JE, van de Port IGL, Backx FJG. Soccer injuries and recovery in Dutch male amateur soccer players: results of a prospective cohort study. Clin J Sport Med. 2014;24:337&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24346734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, Backx F, Goedhart EA, Huisstede BM. Return to play after hamstring injuries in football (soccer): a worldwide Delphi procedure regarding definition, medical criteria and decision&#x2010;making. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1583&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28360143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dyk N, Wangensteen A, Vermeulen R, Whiteley R, Bahr R, Tol JL, et al. Similar isokinetic strength preinjury and at return to sport after hamstring injury. Med Sci Sports Exer. 2019;51:1091&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Rijn L, Nijhuis&#x2010;van der Sanden MWG, Hoogeboom TJ, van Cingel REH. Fatigue affects quality of movement more in ACL&#x2010;reconstructed soccer players than in healthy soccer players. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27:549&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30259146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vereijken A, Aerts I, Van Trijffel E, Tassignon B, Verschueren J, Meeusen R. Pre&#x2010; and postmatch hop test outcomes in soccer players returning to performance after lower extremity injury. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2022;62:953&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34137573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergani L, Cuniberti M, Zanovello M, Maffei D, Farooq A, Eirale C. Return to play in long&#x2010;standing adductor&#x2010;related groin pain: a Delphi study among experts. Sports Med Open. 2022;8:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8766680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35043267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W. Return to sports after an ACL reconstruction in 2024 &#x2010; A glass half full? A narrative review. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;67:141&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38749349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Benjaminse A, Lemmink K, Gokeler A. Passing return to sports tests after ACL reconstruction is associated with greater likelihood for return to sport but fail to identify second injury risk. Knee. 2020;27:949&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Frik L. On&#x2010;field tests for patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a scoping review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671211055481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8727834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambaldi M, Beasley I, Rushton A. Return to play criteria after hamstring muscle injury in professional football: a Delphi consensus study. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1221&#x2013;1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28246078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Brink M, aus der F&#xfc;nten K, Tr&#xf6;&#xdf; T, Willeit P, Meyer T, et al. The time course of injury risk after return&#x2010;to&#x2010;play in professional football (soccer). Sports Med. 2024;55:193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39276305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>