<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41259603</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1998-4030</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>128</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2025 Sep-Oct 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Noise &amp; health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Noise Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Wind Instrument Training and Sound-Based Interventions for Sleep Quality and Obstructive Sleep Apnoea: A Narrative Synthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>545</StartPage><EndPage>554</EndPage><MedlinePgn>545-554</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/nah.nah_111_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Tolerability issues with continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) therapy for obstructive sleep apnoea (OSA) have spurred interest in nonpharmacological alternatives like sound-based interventions (wind instrument training, singing and music therapy) for improving upper airway function and sleep quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search of PubMed, Embase, Scopus, Web of Science and Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (through March 2024) identified studies evaluating the effects of wind instrument training, vocal interventions (singing or speech therapy) or music therapy on OSA-related outcomes and sleep quality. Eight studies, specifically, four randomised controlled trials, one before-after quasi-experimental study and three cross-sectional observational studies, were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Wind instrument training, particularly that with high-resistance instruments, showed moderate effectiveness in reducing OSA severity and improving sleep outcomes, although no significant improvements in pulmonary function were reported. Music-based interventions (e.g., passive bedtime listening) had mixed effects on sleep quality. Some evidence indicated that structured vocal exercises (singing or speech therapy) can reduce snoring and enhance outcomes when combined with CPAP, but results varied across studies. Overall, sound-based interventions demonstrated potential benefits for OSA, although heterogeneity amongst studies was high.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This review highlights sound-based interventions as a unique and promising nonpharmacological treatment for OSA. In contrast to CPAP, which has a mechanical approach, these strategies aim to improve airway patency via upper airway muscle training and may serve as alternatives or adjuncts for patients intolerant of CPAP. Although moderate evidence supports their ability to improve sleep quality and OSA symptoms, outcomes remain inconsistent. The noninvasive, low-cost nature of sound-based interventions underscores substantial clinical potential. Large multicentre trials with long follow-ups and direct comparisons with CPAP are warranted to validate efficacy and clarify underlying mechanisms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Music, Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>KaiLi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>League Committee Office, Shanghai Industrial Technology School, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Noise Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9815620</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1463-1741</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009147" MajorTopicYN="Y">Music Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063346" MajorTopicYN="Y">Singing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045422" MajorTopicYN="N">Continuous Positive Airway Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013070" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">music therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obstructive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep apnoea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wind instruments</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest regarding the publication of this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41259603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12677268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/nah.nah_111_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00140329-202509000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdullatif J, Certal V, Zaghi S, Song SA, Chang ET, Gillespie MB, et al. Maxillary expansion and maxillomandibular expansion for adult OSA: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Craniomaxillofac Surg. 2016;44:574&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26948172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho M, Certal V, Capasso R. Comprehensive review of surgeries for obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol. 2013;79:780&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9442369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24474491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riaz M, Certal V, Nigam G, Abdullatif J, Zaghi S, Kushida CA, et al. Nasal expiratory positive airway pressure devices (Provent) for OSA: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Disord. 2015;2015:734798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4699057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26798519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Certal V, Nishino N, Camacho M, Capasso R. Reviewing the systematic reviews in OSA surgery. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2013;149:817&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24154748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuck BA, Dreher A, Heiser C, Herzog M, K&#xfc;hnel T, Maurer JT, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of snoring in adults&#x2014;S2k guideline of the German Society of Otorhinolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery. Sleep Breath. 2015;19:135&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24729153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewy J. Music therapy as a potential intervention for sleep improvement. Nat Sci Sleep. 2020;12:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32021519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrovsky DV, Ramesh P, McPhillips MV, Hodgson NA. Effects of music interventions on sleep in older adults: a systematic review. Geriatr Nurs. 2021;42:869&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-R&#xed;o F, Alonso-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Armada E, Mediano O, Lores V, Rojo B, et al. CPAP effect on recurrent episodes in patients with sleep apnea and myocardial infarction. Int J Cardiol. 2013;168:1328&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho M, Guilleminault C, Wei JM, Song SA, Noller MW, Reckley LK, et al. Oropharyngeal and tongue exercises (myofunctional therapy) for snoring: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2018;275:849&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Suarez A, Lo Cascio C, Zahn A, Heitz M, Braendli O. Didgeridoo playing as alternative treatment for obstructive sleep apnoea syndrome: randomized controlled trial. BMJ. 2006;332:266&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1360393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16377643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian RK, Saikumar P, Joshua SD, Devaki PR, Marthandam LJ. Estimation of lung functions and risk of developing obstructive sleep apnoea in wind instrument players. Indian J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2018;70:565&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DL, Zahuranec DB, Majersik JJ, Wren PA, Gruis KL, Zupancic M, et al. Risk of sleep apnea in orchestra members. Sleep Med. 2009;10:657&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward CP, York KM, McCoy JG. Risk of obstructive sleep apnea lower in double reed wind musicians. J Clin Sleep Med. 2012;8:251&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22701381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaferia G, Badke L, Santos-Silva R, Bommarito S, Tufik S, Bittencourt L. Effect of speech therapy as adjunct treatment to continuous positive airway pressure on the quality of life of patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Sleep Med. 2013;14:628&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23702236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojay A, Ernst E. Can singing exercises reduce snoring? A pilot study. Complement Ther Med. 2000;8:151&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11068344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majeed NM, Lua VYQ, Chong JS, Lee ASY. Does bedtime music listening improve subjective sleep quality and next-morning well-being in young adults? A randomized crossover trial. Psychol Music. 2021;49:1714&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmat L, Tak&#xe1;cs J, B&#xf3;dizs R. Music improves sleep quality in students. J Adv Nurs. 2008;62:327&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18426457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Weijden FN, Kuitert RB, Berkhout FRU, van der Weijden GA. Influence of tooth position on wind instrumentalists&#x2019; performance and embouchure comfort: a systematic review. J Orofac Orthop. 2018;79:205&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5954010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wali SO, Abaalkhail BA. Prevalence and predictors of habitual snoring in a sample of Saudi middle-aged adults. Saudi Med J. 2015;36:920&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4549587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26219441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuiman M, James A, Divitini M, Bartholomew H. Longitudinal study of risk factors for habitual snoring in a general adult population: the Busselton Health Study. Chest. 2006;130:1779&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17166996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinzer R, Vat S, Marques-Vidal P, Marti-Soler H, Andries D, Tobback N, et al. Prevalence of sleep-disordered breathing in the general population: the HypnoLaus study. Lancet Respir Med. 2015;3:310&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25682233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnardottir ES, Bjornsdottir E, Olafsdottir KA, Benediktsdottir B, Gislason T. Obstructive sleep apnoea in the general population: highly prevalent but minimal symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2016;47:194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26541533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crinion SJ, Ryan S, McNicholas WT. Obstructive sleep apnoea as a cause of nocturnal non-dipping blood pressure: recent evidence regarding clinical importance and underlying mechanisms. Eur Respir J. 2017;49:1601818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28077479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petro A, Dzierzewski JM, Martin JL, Alessi C, Jouldjian S, Josephson K, et al. A survey to assess patients&#x2019; interest in the didgeridoo as an alternative therapy for obstructive sleep apnea. Sleep. 2017;40:A213.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>