<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41268274</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A predictive model for anlotinib-osimertinib efficacy in advanced non-small cell lung cancer with acquired resistance: circulating tumor DNA and angiogenesis markers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8439</StartPage><EndPage>8453</EndPage><MedlinePgn>8439-8453</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/HTAG4562</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To develop a predictive model for the efficacy of anlotinib combined with osimertinib in treating advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) with acquired resistance, based on circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) clearance and angiogenesis markers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed data from 378 patients with acquired resistance advanced NSCLC treated at Shanghai University Mengchao Cancer Hospital between November 2020 and October 2022. Patients were divided into a monotherapy group (n=181, receiving osimertinib alone) and a combination therapy group (n=197, receiving anlotinib plus osimertinib). The combination therapy group was further stratified into two subgroups based on progression-free survival (PFS): better efficacy (PFS &#x2265;16 months) and poorer efficacy (PFS &lt;16 months). Venous blood samples were collected before and after two treatment cycles for ctDNA detection using next-generation sequencing (NGS) and measurement of angiogenesis markers using electrochemiluminescence immunoassays. Multivariate logistic regression was employed to identify independent predictors, and a nomogram predictive model was constructed and validated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The combination therapy group demonstrated significantly longer PFS and overall survival compared to the monotherapy group. After two treatment cycles, the combination therapy group showed a significant reduction in ctDNA levels, variant allele frequency (VAF), and a higher clearance rate of the T790M mutation. Additionally, angiogenesis markers were significantly lower in the combination therapy group post-treatment (all P&lt;0.05). Multivariate logistic regression identified significant predictors of poor therapeutic effect. The nomogram model exhibited excellent predictive performance, with an AUC of 0.912 in the training set and 0.959 in the test set.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The developed nomogram reliably predicts the efficacy of anlotinib combined with osimertinib in treating acquired resistance NSCLC, offering valuable guidance for personalized treatment decisions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Shanghai University Mengchao Cancer Hospital Shanghai 201800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Urology II, Hunan Cancer Hospital Changsha 410013, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Xiangtan Central Hospital Xiangtan 411100, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Kunlun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Fourth People's Hospital of Changde Changde 415100, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Weisi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Changsha County People's Hospital, Hunan Provincial People's Hospital Xingsha Compus Changsha 410100, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anlotinib</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">circulating tumor DNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osimertinib</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41268274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12628259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/HTAG4562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pandya P, Al-Qasrawi DS, Klinge S, Justilien V. Extracellular vesicles in non-small cell lung cancer stemness and clinical applications. Front Immunol. 2024;15:1369356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11099288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38765006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Li M, Huang W, Zhang J, Wei S, Yang Y, Wang Z, Ye S, Gong H, Zhang Y, Li J, Song H, Wang L, Chen X, Lin H, Ding G, Li H, Zheng A, Ma X, Chen S, Liu L, Zhang K, Fu C, Liu W, Wang J, Zhang X, Liu T, Han D, Zhao Q, Wu P, Yuan Q, Tian L, Zhang P, Wu X, Chen F, Zhang Z, Li B. Thoracic radiotherapy improves the survival in patients with EGFR-mutated oligo-organ metastatic non-small cell lung cancer treated with epidermal growth factor receptor-tyrosine kinase inhibitors: a multicenter, randomized, controlled, phase III trial. J Clin Oncol. 2025;43:412&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39374473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park W, Wei S, Xie CL, Han JH, Kim BS, Kim B, Jin JS, Yang ES, Cho MK, Ryu D, Yang HX, Bae SJ, Ha KT. Targeting pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase 1 overcomes EGFR C797S mutation-driven osimertinib resistance in non-small cell lung cancer. Exp Mol Med. 2024;56:1137&#x2013;1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11148081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst RS, Wu YL, John T, Grohe C, Majem M, Wang J, Kato T, Goldman JW, Laktionov K, Kim SW, Yu CJ, Vu HV, Lu S, Lee KY, Mukhametshina G, Akewanlop C, de Marinis F, Bonanno L, Domine M, Shepherd FA, Urban D, Huang X, Bolanos A, Stachowiak M, Tsuboi M. Adjuvant osimertinib for resected EGFR-mutated stage IB-IIIA non-small-cell lung cancer: updated results from the phase III randomized ADAURA trial. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41:1830&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10082285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36720083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaquier JB, Ortiz-Cuaran S, Ricciuti B, Mezquita L, Cardona AF, Recondo G. Tackling osimertinib resistance in EGFR-mutant non-small cell lung cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2023;29:3579&#x2013;3591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37093192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H, Shao C, Luo Z, Wang T, Tong L, Liu H, Yao X, Lei J, Zhao J, Gao Y, Jiang T, Yan X. Perioperative sintilimab and neoadjuvant anlotinib plus chemotherapy for resectable non-small-cell lung cancer: a multicentre, open-label, single-arm, phase 2 trial (TD-NeoFOUR trial) Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2024;9:296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11514280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39465257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HQ, Zhang YX, Chen G, Yu QT, Zhang H, Wu GW, Wu D, Lin YC, Zhu JF, Chen JH, Hu XH, Lan B, Zhou ZQ, Lin HF, Wang ZB, Lei XL, Pan SM, Chen LM, Zhang J, Kong TD, Yao JC, Zheng X, Li F, Zhang L, Fang WF. Gefitinib (an EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor) plus anlotinib (an multikinase inhibitor) for untreated, EGFR-mutated, advanced non-small cell lung cancer (FL-ALTER): a multicenter phase III trial. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2024;9:215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11319491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39134529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy MJ. Circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) as a biomarker for lung cancer: early detection, monitoring and therapy prediction. Tumour Biol. 2024;46:S283&#x2013;S295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37270828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostou V, Ho C, Nicholas G, Juergens RA, Sacher A, Fung AS, Wheatley-Price P, Laurie SA, Levy B, Brahmer JR, Balan A, Niknafs N, Avrutin E, Zhu L, Sausen M, Bradbury PA, O&#x2019;Donnell-Tormey J, Gaudreau PO, Ding K, Dancey J. ctDNA response after pembrolizumab in non-small cell lung cancer: phase 2 adaptive trial results. Nat Med. 2023;29:2559&#x2013;2569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37814061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbosh C, Frankell AM, Harrison T, Kisistok J, Garnett A, Johnson L, Veeriah S, Moreau M, Chesh A, Chaunzwa TL, Weiss J, Schroeder MR, Ward S, Grigoriadis K, Shahpurwalla A, Litchfield K, Puttick C, Biswas D, Karasaki T, Black JRM, Mart&#xed;nez-Ruiz C, Bakir MA, Pich O, Watkins TBK, Lim EL, Huebner A, Moore DA, Godin-Heymann N, L&#x2019;Hernault A, Bye H, Odell A, Kalavakur P, Gomes F, Patel AJ, Manzano E, Hiley CT, Carey N, Riley J, Cook DE, Hodgson D, Stetson D, Barrett JC, Kortlever RM, Evan GI, Hackshaw A, Daber RD, Shaw JA, Aerts H, Licon A, Stahl J, Jamal-Hanjani M, Birkbak NJ, McGranahan N, Swanton C. Tracking early lung cancer metastatic dissemination in TRACERx using ctDNA. Nature. 2023;616:553&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7614605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long C, Li K, Liu Z, Zhang N, Xing X, Xu L, Gai F, Che N. Real-world analysis of the prognostic value of EGFR mutation detection in plasma ctDNA from patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer Med. 2023;12:7982&#x2013;7991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36621813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang I, Kim JW, Ylaya K, Chung EJ, Kitano H, Perry C, Hanaoka J, Fukuoka J, Chung JY, Hewitt SM. Tumor-associated macrophage, angiogenesis and lymphangiogenesis markers predict prognosis of non-small cell lung cancer patients. J Transl Med. 2020;18:443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33228719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettinger DS, Akerley W, Borghaei H, Chang AC, Cheney RT, Chirieac LR, D&#x2019;Amico TA, Demmy TL, Govindan R, Grannis FW Jr, Grant SC, Horn L, Jahan TM, Komaki R, Kong FM, Kris MG, Krug LM, Lackner RP, Lennes IT, Loo BW Jr, Martins R, Otterson GA, Patel JD, Pinder-Schenck MC, Pisters KM, Reckamp K, Riely GJ, Rohren E, Shapiro TA, Swanson SJ, Tauer K, Wood DE, Yang SC, Gregory K, Hughes M. Non-small cell lung cancer, version 2.2013. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2013;11:645&#x2013;653. quiz 653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23744864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman D, Pao W, Riely GJ, Engelman JA, Kris MG, J&#xe4;nne PA, Lynch T, Johnson BE, Miller VA. Clinical definition of acquired resistance to epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitors in non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28:357&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3870288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19949011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oken MM, Creech RH, Tormey DC, Horton J, Davis TE, McFadden ET, Carbone PP. Toxicity and response criteria of the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group. Am J Clin Oncol. 1982;5:649&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7165009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, Schwartz LH, Sargent D, Ford R, Dancey J, Arbuck S, Gwyther S, Mooney M, Rubinstein L, Shankar L, Dodd L, Kaplan R, Lacombe D, Verweij J. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1) Eur J Cancer. 2009;45:228&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19097774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peduzzi P, Concato J, Kemper E, Holford TR, Feinstein AR. A simulation study of the number of events per variable in logistic regression analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 1996;49:1373&#x2013;1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8970487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC, Steyerberg EW. Events per variable (EPV) and the relative performance of different strategies for estimating the out-of-sample validity of logistic regression models. Stat Methods Med Res. 2017;26:796&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25411322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Zhao J, Chen T, Hu X, Wang L, Shi Y, Liu Y. Efficacy and safety of osimertinib plus anlotinib in advanced non-small-cell lung cancer patients after drug resistance. Thorac Cancer. 2023;14:873&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10067354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36843208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv L, Hua X, Liu J, Zhan S, Zhang Q, Liang X, Feng J, Song Y. Anlotinib reverses osimertinib resistance via inhibiting epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition and angiogenesis in non-small cell lung cancer. J Biomed Res. 2024:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12481689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39375945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han R, Guo H, Shi J, Zhao S, Jia Y, Liu X, Liu Y, Cheng L, Zhao C, Li X, Zhou C. Osimertinib in combination with anti-angiogenesis therapy presents a promising option for osimertinib-resistant non-small cell lung cancer. BMC Med. 2024;22:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11040894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38658988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liu H, Hu N, Wang Y, Yang Z, Zhang J, Han B. Survival benefit of anlotinib in T790M-positive non-small-cell lung cancer patients with acquired osimertinib resistance: a multicenter retrospective study and exploratory in vitro study. Cancer Med. 2023;12:15922&#x2013;15932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37387596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei T, Xu T, Zhang N, Zou X, Kong Z, Wei C, Wang Z. Anlotinib combined with osimertinib reverses acquired osimertinib resistance in NSCLC by targeting the c-MET/MYC/AXL axis. Pharmacol Res. 2023;188:106668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36681369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Li Z, Wang L, Liang Y, Huang C, Chen P, Huang D, Song X, Ding C, Wang C, Jiang R. Osimertinib plus anlotinib for advanced NSCLC with acquired EGFR T790M mutation: results from a multicenter phase II study with ctDNA analysis. BMC Med. 2025;23:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12001677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40234867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishigaki A, Kida N, Tsubokura H, Yoshimura M, Shimoi K, Yoshida A, Okada H. Effects of cigarette smoke extract on angiogenesis and aromatase activity in KGN cells. Sci Rep. 2025;15:13967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12015283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40263391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliri AW, Tommasi S, Besaratinia A. Relationships among smoking, oxidative stress, inflammation, macromolecular damage, and cancer. Mutat Res Rev Mutat Res. 2021;787:108365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa R, Moglad E, Goyal A, Bhat AA, Almalki WH, Kazmi I, Alzarea SI, Ali H, Oliver BG, MacLoughlin R, Dureja H, Singh SK, Dua K, Gupta G. Deciphering NF-kappaB pathways in smoking-related lung carcinogenesis. EXCLI J. 2024;23:991&#x2013;1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11382301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39253534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang J, Wang J, Zhao X, Zhang T, Yang Y, Pang J, Ou Q, Wu L, Xu X, Xu K, Zhao J, Bai N, Yang P, Wang S, Wang L, Bi N. Unrevealing the therapeutic benefits of radiotherapy and consolidation immunotherapy using ctDNA-defined tumor clonality in unresectable locally advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer Lett. 2024;582:216569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Zhao B, Yin Y, Jiang Y, Feng X, Wang L, Zhai L, Liu G, Shi D, Qin J. ctDNA SNORD3F hypermethylation is a prognostic indicator in EGFR-TKI-treated advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer Manag Res. 2024;16:1405&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11476527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39411686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Wu R, Liu X, Xie B, Xie C, Li S, Wu Z, Zhang Z, Tang Z, Gu L. Clinical application of ctDNA in early diagnosis, treatment and prognosis of patients with non-small cell lung cancer. Future Oncol. 2024;20:2213&#x2013;2224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11514542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39073412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite da Silva LF, Saldanha EF, de Menezes JSA, Halamy Pereira L, de Bragan&#xe7;a Dos Santos JAR, Buonopane IR, de Souza EM, de Menezes CUG, Lopes G. Plasma ctDNA kinetics as a predictor of systemic therapy response for advanced non-small cell lung cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oncologist. 2025;30:oyae344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11853598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39998904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Li R, Wen H, Zhou Q, Xu C. Circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA)-based minimal residual disease in non-small cell lung cancer. Chin Med J Pulm Crit Care Med. 2023;1:207&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11332816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39171282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang JM, Cheng ZW, Zhang L, Tan TF, Zhang T, Shi HB, Hou KF, Xia Q. Proteomic insights into the molecular mechanism of anlotinib inhibition in TP53-mutated non-small cell lung cancer. J Proteomics. 2025;316:105433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40113013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan W, Zhao J, Chen W, Shang H, Peng J, Lin J. Anlotinib overcomes multiple drug resistant colorectal cancer cells via inactivating PI3K/AKT pathway. Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2021;21:1987&#x2013;1995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Z, Liao W, Wei W, Zhong G, He C, Zhang H, Liu Q, Xu X, Liang J, Liu Z. Anlotinib as a promising inhibitor on tumor growth of oral squamous cell carcinoma through cell apoptosis and mitotic catastrophe. Cancer Cell Int. 2021;21:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33422069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Liu X, Liu W, Zhou X, Zhang Z, Hu Y, Liu P, Li X, Liu H, Li S. Aumolertinib combined with anlotinib inhibits proliferation of non-small cell lung cancer cells by down-regulating the PI3K/AKT pathway. Nan Fang Yi Ke Da Xue Xue Bao. 2024;44:1965&#x2013;1975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11526449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39523097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhen H, Tian J, Li G, Zhao P, Zhang Y, Che J, Cao B. Raltitrexed enhanced antitumor effect of anlotinib in human esophageal squamous carcinoma cells on proliferation, invasiveness, and apoptosis. BMC Cancer. 2023;23:207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36870981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Jiang J. Advances in predictive biomarkers for anti-angiogenic therapy in non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer Control. 2024;31:10732748241270589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11363049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39192835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>