<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41366698</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing university athletes' physical activity and decision-making through educational interventions grounded in the theory of planned behavior.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1346</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1346</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1346</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-025-03700-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The decision-making processes and physical activities of university athletes are crucial for both individual well-being and athletic performance. The Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB) provides a comprehensive framework for examining the cognitive factors that influence athletes' participation in physical activity. However, existing applications of TPB have primarily focused on general student populations, leaving a gap in our understanding of how this theory operates within the high-stakes, performance-driven environment of university athletics. This study aims not only to examine how TPB constructs (attitude, subjective norms, and perceived behavioral control) relate to university athletes' decision-making and physical activity behaviors but also to evaluate the effectiveness of a theory-based intervention designed to enhance these factors. Ultimately, the goal is to inform the development of evidence-based strategies for improving both health outcomes and decision-making competencies among student-athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An experimental pretest/posttest control-experimental research method was employed. Data were collected through structured questionnaires designed to assess attitudes, subjective norms, and perceived behavioral control - different aspects of the decision-making process - as well as the physical activities of the participating university athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA ANALYSIS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The data collected from the pretests and posttests were analyzed through descriptive statistics (Mean and SD) and inferential statistics (MANCOVA) to compare the mean scores of the control and experimental groups on all study variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results showed that following an educational intervention, the experimental group demonstrated significantly improved scores in attitudes, subjective norms, perceived behavioral control, decision-making process, and physical activity measures, suggesting the effectiveness of the intervention. In contrast, the control group unexpectedly exhibited higher social resistance scores, potentially indicating unintended effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights the effectiveness of educational interventions in enhancing key determinants of planned behavior and promoting physical activity among university athletes. By establishing a direct link between TPB-based training and measurable improvements in decision-making and behavioral outcomes, the study provides actionable insights for coaches, educators, and sports psychologists seeking to foster more autonomous, health-conscious, and strategically capable athlete populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Physical Education, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, 450001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ruilin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Physical Education, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, 450001, China. xrl@zzu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loh</LastName><ForeName>Yean Chun</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Minden, Penang, 11800, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Minden, Penang, 11800, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Decision Making</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011582" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological Theory</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092963" MajorTopicYN="N">Theory of Planned Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decision making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Planned behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">University athletes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This research study was conducted according to the guidelines of the Declaration of Helsinki and the study's protocols were reviewed and granted by the Ethical Committee of Universiti Sains Malaysia. The informed consent was waived by the Ethical committee due to anonymized data were obtained. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41366698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12690960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-025-03700-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-025-03700-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Shephard RJ, Stephens TE, editors. Physical activity, fitness, and health: International proceedings and consensus statement; Proceedings of the International Consensus Symposium on Physical Activity, Fitness, and Health; Toronto, ON, Canada. 2 May 1992;Champaign, IL, USA: Human Kinetics Publishers; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Centers for disease control and Prevention. National center for health Statistics. healthy people 2010: Understanding and improving health. Washington, DC, USA: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fish C, Nies MA. Health promotion needs of students in a college environment. Public Health Nurs. 1996;13:104&#x2013;11. 10.1111/j.1525-1446. 1996.tb00227. x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8936243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi Z. The research on the extracurricular physical exercise current situation and countermeasures of college students in Hubei Province. Wuhan, China: Huazhong University of Science and Technology; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinger MK, Brittain DR, Hutchinson SR. Associations between physical activity and health-related factors in a National sample of college students. J Am Coll Health. 2014;62:67&#x2013;74. 10.1080/07448481.2013.849710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2013.849710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24313698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mack DE, Wilson PM, Lightheart V, Oster K, Gunnell KE, Campus Healthy. Physical activity trends and the role of information provision. J Phys Act Health. 2010;2009(6):435&#x2013;43. 10.1123/jpah.6.4.435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jpah.6.4.435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19842457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon-Larsen P, Nelson MC, Popkin BM. Longitudinal physical activity and sedentary behavior trends: adolescence to adulthood. Am J Prev Med. 2004;27:277&#x2013;83. 10.1016/j.amepre.2004.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2004.07.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparling PB, Snow TK. Physical activity patterns in recent college alumni. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2002;73:200&#x2013;5. 10.1080/02701367.2002.10609009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2002.10609009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12092895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage CJ. Can the theory of planned behavior predict the maintenance of physical activity? Health Psychol. 2005;24:235. 10.1037/0278-6133.24.3.235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0278-6133.24.3.235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15898858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grol RP, Bosch MC, Hulscher ME, Eccles MP, Wensing M. Planning and studying improvement in patient care: the use of theoretical perspectives. Milbank Q. 2007;85:93&#x2013;138. 10.1111/j.1468-0009.2007.00478.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0009.2007.00478.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2690312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17319808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glanz K, Rimer BK, Viswanath K, editors. Health behavior and health education: Theory, Research, and practice. Hoboken, NJ, USA: Wiley; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen, I. From intentions to actions: A theory of planned behavior. In Action control: From cognition to behavior. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. 1985;pp. 11-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo L, Montagnani E, Pietrantuono D, Fratini T, Di Giminiani R, Palermi S, Ceccarini F, Migliaccio GM, Lupu E, Padulo J. Self-Myofascial release of the foot plantar surface: the effects of a single exercise session on the posterior muscular chain flexibility after one hour. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(2):974. 10.3390/ijerph20020974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20020974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36673731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hraste M, De Giorgio A, Mandi&#x107; Jelaska P, Padulo J, Grani&#x107; I. When mathematics Meets physical activity in the school-aged child: the effect of an integrated motor and cognitive approach to learning geometry. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(8):e0196024. 10.1371/journal.pone.0196024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0196024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6082508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotarska K, Nowak MA, Timoszyk-Tomczak C. Coping with stress among physically active and inactive students at different educational stages during the pandemic. Acta Kinesiologica. 2024;18(1):9&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake H, Chaplin WJ, Gupta A. The effectiveness of digital interventions for self-management of chronic pain in employment settings: a systematic review. Br Med Bull. 2024;151(1):36&#x2013;48. 10.1093/bmb/ldae007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bmb/ldae007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38972661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Bragazzi NL, De Giorgio A, Grgantov Z, Prato S, Ardig&#xf2; LP. The effect of physical activity on cognitive performance in an Italian elementary school: insights from a pilot study using structural equation modeling. Front Physiol. 2019;10:202. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6412095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30890960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Padulo J, Russo L, Racil G, Ltifi MA, Picerno P, Iuliano E, Migliaccio GM. 4&#x2013;6 repetition maximum (RM) and 1-RM prediction in Free-Weight bench press and Smith machine squat based on body mass in male athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(8):1366&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38888595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racil G, Aouichaoui C, Hawani A, Signorelli P, Chamari K, Migliaccio GM, Trabelsi Y, Padulo J. The impact of interval training on adiponectin to leptin ratios and on blood pressures in severely obese adolescent girls: A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2024:1&#x2013;9.&#xa0;10.1080/02640414.2024.2369447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38904424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzisarantis NDL, Hagger MS, Smith B. Influences of perceived autonomy support on physical activity within the theory of planned behavior. Eur J Soc Psychol. 2007;37:934&#x2013;54. 10.1002/ejsp.407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejsp.407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen SM, Chen S, Carter C. Fundamental human needs: making social cognition relevant. Psychol Inq. 2000;11:269&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jubari I, Arif H, Li&#xf1;&#xe1;n F. Entrepreneurial intention among university students in malaysia: integrating self-determination theory and the theory of planned behavior. Int Entrep Manag J. 2019;15:1323&#x2013;42. 10.1007/s11365-018-0529-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11365-018-0529-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger MS, Chatzisarantis NDL, Harris J. From psychological need satisfaction to intentional behavior: testing a motivational sequence in two behavioral contexts. Personal Soc Psychol Bull. 2006;32:131&#x2013;48. 10.1177/0146167205279905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0146167205279905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger MS, Chatzisarantis NDL. Integrating the theory of planned behaviour and self-determination theory in health behaviour: A meta-analysis. Br J Health Psychol -. 2009;14:275&#x2013;302. 10.1348/135910708X373959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1348/135910708X373959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18926008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standage M, Duda JL, Ntoumanis N. A model of contextual motivation in physical education: using constructs from self-determination and achievement goal theories to predict physical activity intentions. J Educ Psychol. 2003;95:97. 10.1037/0022-0663.95.1.97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.95.1.97</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PM, Rodgers WM. The relationship between perceived autonomy support, exercise regulations and behavioral intentions in women. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2004;5:229&#x2013;42. 10.1016/S1469-0292(03)00003-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1469-0292(03)00003-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger MS, Chatzisarantis NLD, Biddle SJH. A meta-analytic review of the theories of reasoned action and planned behavior in physical activity: predictive validity and the contribution of additional variables. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2002;24(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausenblas HA, Carron AV, Mack DE. Application of the theories of reasoned action. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 1997;19:36&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsep.19.1.36</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I, Fishbein M. Understanding attitudes and predicting social behaviour. Behaviour Englewood Cliffs. Prentice-Hall; 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darker CD, French DP, Eves FF, Sniehotta FF. An intervention to promote walking amongst the general population based on an &#x2018;extended&#x2019; theory of planned behaviour: a waiting list randomized controlled trial. Psychol Health. 2010;25(1):71&#x2013;88. 10.1080/08870440902893716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870440902893716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20391208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saber FSH, Gh S. The survey of theory of planned behavior constructs regarding Girl student&#x2019;s physical activity in Naeinpayame Noor university in 2012. Health Syst Res. 2013;9(9):1014&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yekaninejad MS, Akaberi A, Pakpour A. Factors associated with physical activity in adolescents in qazvin: an application of the theory of planned behavior. J North Khorasan Univ Med Sci. 2012;4(3):449&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solhi M, Zinatmotlagh F, Karimzade SK, Taghdisi MH, Jalilian F. Designing and implementing educational program to promote physical activity among students: an application of the theory of planned behavior. Horizon Med Sci. 2012;18(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi Tabatabaei SV, Taghdisi MH, Nakhaei N, Balali F. Effect of educational intervention based on the theory of planned behaviour on the physical activities of kerman health center&#x2019;s staff (2008). Horizon Med Sci. 2012;18(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endsley MR. Toward a theory of situation awareness in dynamic systems. Hum Factors. 1995;37(1):32&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1518/001872095779049543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AM, Ward P. Perceptual expertise in sport: some considerations when applying the expert performance approach. Hum Mov Sci. 2007;26(2):283&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson JW, King EC. Situational influences on musicians&#x2019; performance anxiety: A qualitative study. Psychol Music. 2004;32(4):432&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feltz DL, Lirgg CD. Self-efficacy beliefs of athletes, teams, and coaches. In: Singer RN, Hausenblas HA, Janelle CM, editors. Handbook of sport psychology. 2nd ed. Wiley; 2001. pp. 340&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahneman D, Tversky A. Prospect theory: an analysis of decision under risk. Econometrica. 1979;47(2):263&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1914185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo D, Hristovski R, Seifert L, Carvalho J, Davids K. Ecological cognition: expert decision-making behaviour in sport. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2019;12:1&#x2013;25. 10.1080/1750984X.2017.1349826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750984X.2017.1349826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AF, Conte D, Clemente FM. Decision-making in youth team-sports players: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:3803. 10.37766/inplasy2020.4.0207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37766/inplasy2020.4.0207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belling PK, Suss J, Ward P. The effect of time constraint on anticipation, decision making, and option generation in complex and dynamic environments. Cogn Technol Work. 2015;17:355&#x2013;66. 10.1007/s10111-015-0334-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10111-015-0334-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musculus L, Raab M, Belling P, Lobinger B. Linking self-efficacy and decisionmaking processes in developing soccer players. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2018;39:72&#x2013;80. 10.1016/j.psychsport.2018.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2018.07.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinrade NP, Jackson RC, Ashford KJ. Reinvestment, task complexity and decision making under pressure in basketball. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2015;20:11&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.psychsport.2015.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2015.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kal&#xe9;n A, Bisagno E, Musculus L, Raab M, P&#xe9;rez-Ferreir&#xf3;s Williams A A. M., et al. The role of domain-specific and domain-general cognitive functions and skills in sports performance: a meta-analysis. Psychol Bull. 2021;147:1290&#x2013;308. 10.1037/bul0000355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce L, Farrow D, Raynor A, Mann D. But I can&#x2019;t pass that far! The influence of motor skill on decision making. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2012;13:152&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.psychsport.2011.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2011.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandhu D, Mohan MM, Nittala NAP, Jadhav P, Bhadauria A, Saxena KK. Theories of motivation: A comprehensive analysis of human behavior drivers. Acta Psychol. 2024;244:104177. 10.1016/j.actpsy.2024.104177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actpsy.2024.104177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38354564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrow D, Abernethy B, Jackson RC. Probing expert anticipation with the Temporal occlusion paradigm: experimental investigations of some methodological issues. Motor Control. 2005;9:330&#x2013;49. 10.1123/mcj.9.3.330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/mcj.9.3.330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aglioti SM, Cesari P, Romani M, Urgesi C. Action anticipation and motor resonance in elite basketball players. Nat Neurosci. 2008;11:1109&#x2013;16. 10.1038/nn.2182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.2182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19160510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huesmann K, Loffing F, B&#xfc;sch D, Schorer J, Hagemann N. Varying degrees of perception-action coupling and anticipation in handball goalkeeping. J Motor Behav. 2021;10:1&#x2013;10. 10.1080/00222895.2021.1984868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00222895.2021.1984868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34663190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdollahi A. Optimization and Bayesian Inference in Model-based Decision Making. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moeini B, Barati M, Heidarimoghadam R, Tapak L, Parsamajd S. Determinants of regular physical activities in Iranian older adults based on the extended social cognitive theory. Ageing International; 2023. pp. 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes RE, Courneya KS. Investigating multiple components of attitude, subjective norm, and perceived control: an examination of the theory of planned behavior in the exercise domain. Br J Soc Psychol. 2003;42(1):129&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1348/014466603763276162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12713760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie E, Owen N, Sallis JF. Inactive Australian college students&#x2019; preferred activities, sources of assistance, and motivators. Am J Health Promotion. 1999;13(4):197&#x2013;9. van der.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4278/0890-1171-13.4.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10351847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Bij AK, Laurant MG, Wensing M. Effectiveness of physical activity interventions for older adults: a review. Am J Prev Med. 2002;22(2):120&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0749-3797(01)00413-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11818183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Human agency in social cognitive theory. Am Psychol. 1989;44(9):1175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.44.9.1175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2782727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Deci EL. Intrinsic and extrinsic motivations: classic definitions and new directions. Contemp Educ Psychol. 2000;25(1):54&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/ceps.1999.1020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10620381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Eerde W, Thierry H. Vroom&#x2019;s expectancy models and work-related criteria: A meta-analysis. J Appl Psychol. 1996;81(5):575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.81.5.575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dien DSF. A Chinese perspective on kohlberg&#x2019;s theory of moral development. Dev Rev. 1982;2(4):331&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0273-2297(82)90017-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ordanini A, Rubera G, DeFillippi R. The many moods of inter-organizational imitation: A critical review. Int J Manage Reviews. 2008;10(4):375&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-2370.2008.00233.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould-Williams J, Davies F. Using social exchange theory to predict the effects of HRM practice on employee outcomes: an analysis of public sector workers. Public Manage Rev. 2005;7(1):1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1471903042000339392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root CM, Masuyama K, Green DS, Enell LE, N&#xe4;ssel DR, Lee CH, Wang JW. A presynaptic gain control mechanism fine-tunes olfactory behavior. Neuron. 2008;59(2):311&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2008.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2539065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18667158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>