<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41665612</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>External Load of Professional Female Soccer Players in the Competitive Microcycle: Influence of Playing Position and Contextual Variables.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e323</StartPage><EndPage>e331</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e323-e331</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005387</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>S&#xe1;nchez-Abselam, O, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez, FT, Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez, A, and Onetti-Onetti, W. External load of professional female soccer players in the competitive microcycle: Influence of playing position and contextual variables. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): e324-e332, 2026-Women's soccer has experienced substantial growth in recent years, accompanied by increased scientific interest in performance-related variables. This study aimed to analyze the external load across competitive microcycles in a professional women's soccer team and to examine the influence of playing position and contextual factors (match location, outcome, and opponent quality) on physical demands. Eighteen professional players (age: 24.5 &#xb1; 5.6 years; body mass: 58.8 &#xb1; 14.8 kg; height: 165 &#xb1; 5.7 cm) from a Spanish second-division team were monitored across 13 microcycles using 10 Hz Global Positioning System devices. Players were categorized into 5 positions: central defenders, external defenders, midfielders, wingers, and forwards. Significant differences were observed across microcycle days ( p &lt; 0.001), with match day (MD) presenting the highest external load values, and MD-1 the lowest. Playing position significantly affected explosive distance, high-speed running, and high metabolic load distance ( p &lt; 0.001), with forwards showing the highest values and central defenders the lowest. In addition, greater physical demands were recorded when competing against lower-ranked opponents. These findings provide relevant insights for physical performance staff, highlighting the importance of adjusting training loads based on both positional profiles and contextual factors to optimize performance and recovery strategies in elite women's soccer.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Abselam</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Didactics of Languages, Arts and Sport, University of Malaga, Malaga, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education, Sport, Innovation and Health Research Group (FE22), IBIMA Tech, Health and Innovation Technology Area, Institute of Biomedical Research in Malaga (IBIMA, Bionand Platform), Malaga, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Tom&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>FT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports, University of Granada, Granada, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez</LastName><ForeName>Alfonso</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Didactics of Languages, Arts and Sport, University of Malaga, Malaga, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education, Sport, Innovation and Health Research Group (FE22), IBIMA Tech, Health and Innovation Technology Area, Institute of Biomedical Research in Malaga (IBIMA, Bionand Platform), Malaga, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onetti-Onetti</LastName><ForeName>Wanesa</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vice--Rectorate for Research, Universidad Internacional de La Rioja, Logro&#xf1;o, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FPU 23/00586</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Universidades</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CSD2024-99777</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Cultura y Deporte</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GPS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">load monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of opposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41665612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alahmad TA, Kearney P, Cahalan R. Injury in elite women's soccer: A systematic review. Phys Sportsmed 48: 259&#x2013;265, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman DG. Practical Statistics for Medical Research. London: Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann S, Forcher L, Ruf L, et al. Match-related physical performance in professional soccer: Position or player specific? PLoS One 16: e0256695, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aquino R, Munhoz Martins GH, Palucci Vieira LH, Menezes RP. Influence of match location, quality of opponents, and match status on movement patterns in Brazilian professional football players. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2155&#x2013;2161, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arenas-Pareja M, L&#xf3;pez-Sierra P, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez S, Garc&#xed;a-Rubio J. Influence of menstrual cycle on internal and external load in professional women basketball players. Healthcare 11: 822, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asgari M, Alizadeh MH, Shahrbanian S, Nolte K, Jaitner T. Effects of the FIFA 11+ and a modified warmup programme on injury prevention and performance improvement among youth male football players. PLoS One 17: e0275545, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz R, Jones MT, Jagim AR, et al. In-season match demands of men&#x2019;s collegiate soccer: A comparison by half, position, match outcome, match location, and competition phase. Int J Strength Cond 3: 1&#x2013;10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, et al. Monitoring athlete training loads: Consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: S2161&#x2013;S2170, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casamichana D, Barba E, Gantois P, Nakamura F, Erkizia B, Castellano J. Match-play running demands in a female soccer professional club: From academy to professional team. Int J Sports Sci Coach 19: 2045&#x2013;2055, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choice EE, Tufano JJ, Jagger KL, Cochrane-Snyman KC. Match-play external load and internal load in NCAA Division II women's soccer. J Strength Cond Res 37: 633&#x2013;639, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Crowcroft S, Kempton T. Developing athlete monitoring systems: Theoretical basis and practical applications. In: Recovery and Well-being in Sport and Exercise (Vol 17-31). Abington: Routledge, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curzi D, Amatori S, Silvestri F, et al. Professional football training and recovery: A longitudinal study on the effects of weekly conditioning session and workload variables. PLoS One 19: e0310036, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Cohen DD, Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Influence of football match time&#x2013;motion parameters on recovery time course of muscle damage and jump ability. J Sports Sci 34: 1363&#x2013;1370, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Seradilla E, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Marroyo JA, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Villa Vicente JG. Inter- and intra-microcycle external load analysis in female professional soccer players: A playing position approach. PLoS One 17: e0264908, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;ez A, Lozano D, Arjol-Serrano JL, et al. Influence of contextual factors on physical demands and technical-tactical actions regarding playing position in professional soccer players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 13: 157, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes R, Ceylan H&#x130;, Clemente FM, et al. In-season microcycle quantification of professional women soccer players&#x2014;external, internal and wellness measures. Healthcare (Basel) 10: 695, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessi MS, Zarrouk N, Di Salvo V, Filetti C, Barker AR, Moalla W. Effects of tapering on physical match activities in professional soccer players. J Sports Sci 34: 2189&#x2013;2194, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FIFA. Women&#x2019;s Football: Member Associations Survey Report 2023. F&#xe9;d&#xe9;ration Internationale de Football Association 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Use of relative speed zones increases the high-speed running performed in team sport match play. J Strength Cond Res 29: 3353&#x2013;3359, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Unanue J, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Gim&#xe9;nez JV, et al. Influence of contextual variables and the pressure to keep category on physical match performance in soccer players. PLoS One 13: e0204256, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves LG, Nobari H, Rites AA, Nakamura FY, Garcia GR, Aquino R. Influence of contextual factors on match running performance of starters and non-starters in elite youth male soccer players. Sci Prog 107: 368504241239187, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guridi Lopategui I, Castellano Paulis J, Echeazarra Escudero I. Physical demands and internal response in football sessions according to tactical periodization. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 858&#x2013;864, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt A, Norton K, Lyons K. Movement profiles of elite women soccer players during international matches and the effect of opposition's team ranking. J Sports Sci 32: 1874&#x2013;1880, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppe MW, Baumgart C, Polglaze T, Freiwald J. Validity and reliability of GPS and LPS for measuring distances covered and sprint mechanical properties in team sports. PLoS One 13: e0192708, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 270&#x2013;273, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings D, Cormack S, Coutts AJ, Boyd LJ, Aughey RJ. Variability of GPS units for measuring distance in team sport movements. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 565&#x2013;569, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiely J. Periodization paradigms in the 21st century: Evidence-led or tradition-driven? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 7: 242&#x2013;250, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen CB. Uncovering the influence of contextual factors on short peak periods in Women's football. The Arctic University of Norway, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 4: 863, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone J, Di Michele R, Morgans R, Burgess D, Morton JP, Drust B. Seasonal training-load quantification in elite English premier league soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 489&#x2013;497, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Garc&#xed;a A, G&#xf3;mez D&#xed;az A, Bradley PS, Morera F, Casamichana D. Quantification of a professional football team's external load using a microcycle structure. J Strength Cond Res 32: 3511&#x2013;3518, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modric T, Versic S, Sekulic D. Playing position specifics of associations between running performance during the training and match in male soccer players. Acta Gymnica 50: 51&#x2013;60, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaizola A, Errekagorri I, Lopez-de-Ipina K, Mar&#xed;a Calvo P, Castellano J. Comparison of the external load in training sessions and official matches in female football: A case report. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 15820, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Brito JP, Martins A, et al. In-season internal and external training load quantification of an elite European soccer team. PLoS One 14: e0209393, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Ceylan H&#x130;, Fernandes R, et al. Do contextual factors influence running and accelerometry GPS based variables in professional women soccer players? A case study about the effect of match location and result. Proc Inst Mech Eng P J Sports Eng Technol 239: 61&#x2013;69, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osgnach C, Poser S, Bernardini R, Rinaldo R, Di Prampero PE. Energy cost and metabolic power in elite soccer: A new match analysis approach. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 170&#x2013;178, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otte FW, Millar SK, Klatt S. How does the modern football goalkeeper train?&#x2013;An exploration of expert goalkeeper coaches' skill training approaches. J Sports Sci 38: 1465&#x2013;1473, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Dunlop G, Rouissi M, Haddad M, Mendes B, Chamari K. Analysis of positional training loads (ratings of perceived exertion) during various-sided games in European professional soccer players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 11: 374&#x2013;381, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Djaoui L, Newton M, Malone S, Mendes B. A contemporary multi-modal mechanical approach to training monitoring in elite professional soccer. Sci Med Footb 1: 216&#x2013;221, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passos Ramos G, Datson N, Mahseredjian F, et al. Activity profile of training and matches in Brazilian Olympic female soccer team. Sci Med Footb 3: 231&#x2013;237, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reche-Soto P, Cardona-Nieto D, Diaz-Suarez A, et al. Player load and metabolic power dynamics as load quantifiers in soccer. J Hum Kinet 69: 259&#x2013;269, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez Porras LD, Solano-Mora L, Rivas-Borb&#xf3;n M, et al. Profile of physical demands in female soccer players during competitions: A systematic review. Strength Cond J 46: 567&#x2013;586, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Moraleda B, Nedergaard NJ, Morencos E, Casamichana D, Ramirez-Campillo R, Vanrenterghem J. External and internal loads during the competitive season in professional female soccer players according to their playing position: Differences between training and competition. Res Sports Med 29: 449&#x2013;461, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Abselam O, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez FT, Figueiredo A, Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Onetti-Onetti W. Effect of the role, playing position and the body characteristics on physical performance in female soccer players. Heliyon 10: e29240, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandm&#xe6;l S, Dalen T. Comparison of GPS and IMU systems for total distance, velocity, acceleration and deceleration measurements during small-sided games in soccer. Cogent Soc Sci 9: 2209365, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens TGA, de Ruiter CJ, Twisk JWR, Savelsbergh GJP, Beek PJ. Quantification of in-season training load relative to match load in professional Dutch Eredivisie football players. Sci Med Footb 1: 117&#x2013;125, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss A, Sparks M, Pienaar C. Use of GPS analysis to quantify the internal and external match demands of semi-elite level female soccer players during a tournament. J Sports Sci Med 18: 73&#x2013;81, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Forte P, Ferraz R, et al. Monitoring accumulated training and match load in football: A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18: 3906, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trewin J, Meylan C, Varley MC, Cronin J, Ling D. Effect of match factors on the running performance of elite female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2002&#x2013;2009, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanrenterghem J, Nedergaard NJ, Robinson MA, Drust B. Training load monitoring in team sports: A novel framework separating physiological and biomechanical load-adaptation pathways. Sports Med 47: 2135&#x2013;2142, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vescovi JD, Falenchuk O. Contextual factors on physical demands in professional women's soccer: Female Athletes in Motion study. Eur J Sport Sci 19: 141&#x2013;146, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villaseca&#x2010;Vicu&#xf1;a R, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras J, Merino-Mu&#xf1;oz P, Morales-Acu&#xf1;a F, Gir&#xe1;ldez J, Zabaloy S. Influence of the quality of the opponent on physical, technical, and tactical performance of elite female soccer players in international competitions. Sport Sci Health 20: 863&#x2013;872, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker GJ, Hawkins R. Structuring a program in elite professional soccer. Strength Cond J 40: 72&#x2013;82, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winther AK, Baptista I, Pedersen S, et al. An analysis of training load in highly trained female football players. PLoS One 19: e0299851, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Morel B, Trama R, Hautier CA. Influence of fatigue on the rapid hamstring/quadriceps force capacity in soccer players. Front Physiol 12: 627674, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>