<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41827078</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-799X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic surgery and research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Surg Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cross-education effects of healthy-side lower-limb strength training on neuromuscular function recovery following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13018-026-06776-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Based on cross-education theory, this study aimed to investigate whether Healthy-Side Lower-Limb Strength Training could promote neuromuscular function recovery of the injured limb in patients following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) through central nervous system-mediated contralateral adaptive mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A single-masked, randomized controlled trial was conducted with 40 patients at 5-6 weeks post-ACLR, who were randomly allocated to intervention and control groups (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;20). The control group received conventional rehabilitation, while the intervention group received conventional rehabilitation plus Healthy-Side Lower-Limb Strength Training for 6 weeks. The Lysholm knee function score was used to assess knee joint function at baseline and post-intervention. A wireless surface electromyography system was used to measure root mean square (RMS) values of bilateral rectus femoris, semitendinosus, tibialis anterior, and lateral gastrocnemius muscles during maximal voluntary contraction and level walking. The activation ratios of the flexor and extensor muscle groups were calculated to evaluate muscle synergy patterns. The effects of Healthy-side strength training on bilateral lower limb muscle activation patterns and knee joint function were assessed through within-group pre- and post-intervention comparisons and between-group analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Following the 6-week intervention, Lysholm knee function scores improved significantly in both groups, with the intervention group demonstrating a significantly greater magnitude of improvement than the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). At baseline, the RMS values of all recorded muscles on the affected side were significantly lower than those on the unaffected side during both MVC and level walking in both groups (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). Following the intervention, the intervention group demonstrated significant reductions in affected-to-unaffected limb asymmetry across all four muscle groups during both MVC and level walking (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), whereas the control group exhibited significant asymmetry reductions in only a limited number of muscle groups during MVC alone (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). In the intervention group, the RMS values of the bilateral rectus femoris, semitendinosus, tibialis anterior, and lateral gastrocnemius increased significantly during both MVC and level walking relative to baseline (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). In contrast, the control group demonstrated significant improvements in only a limited subset of muscle groups. Between-group post-intervention comparisons revealed that the intervention group achieved significantly higher activation levels in the unaffected-side rectus femoris, bilateral semitendinosus, and unaffected-side tibialis anterior than the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Both groups exhibited a declining trend in flexor-extensor co-contraction ratios; however, neither between-group nor within-group differences reached statistical significance (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Healthy-Side Lower-Limb Strength Training effectively promoted knee joint function recovery and enhanced bilateral lower limb muscle activation in patients following ACLR through cross-education mechanisms. These findings validate the clinical utility of cross-education theory and support Healthy-side strength training as an innovative rehabilitation strategy for early post-ACLR recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry ChiCTR2400087325. Registered on 25/07/2024.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Training, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>ZiHao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Special Education and Rehabilitation, Binzhou Medical University, Yantai City, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>XiangZhan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Special Education and Rehabilitation, Binzhou Medical University, Yantai City, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>BaoHua</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Sports, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China. liubaohua8259@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>YueHan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Qingdao, China. Aa19861802747@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KFKT-2023-026</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development Project of the Chinese Association of Rehabilitation Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23ZYJ0228</GrantID><Agency>2023 Higher Education Science Research Plan Project of the China Association of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>50012304488</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Foundation of Binzhou Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Surg Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265112</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-799X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy-side strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroplasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface electromyography</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the Affiliated Hospital of Binzhou Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Consent for publication: Written informed consent for publication was obtained from all participants. The participant in Figs.&#xa0;1, 2, 3 and 4 specifically consented to publication of this de-identified image, which does not display facial features or any personally identifiable information. Consent for publication: Participants give their consent for publication of their image if require. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41827078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-026-06776-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13018-026-06776-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N, King JB. Anterior cruciate ligament injury[J]. Br J Sports Med. 1998;32(3):266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn L, Rembeck E, Rauch A. [Anterior cruciate ligament injury in adults: Diagnostics and treatment][J]. Orthopade. 2020;49(11):1013&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Zhang H, Li J, et al. The effects of foot orthoses on radiological parameters and pain in children with flexible flat feet: a systematic review and meta-analysis[J]. Front Pediatr. 2024;12:1388248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramjug S, Ghosh S, Walley G, et al. Isolated anterior cruciate ligament deficiency, knee scores and function[J]. Acta Orthop Belg. 2008;74(5):643&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J, Maffulli N, Maganaris CN, et al. Reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament with a patella-tendon-bone graft may lead to a permanent loss of bone mineral content due to decreased patellar tendon stiffness[J]. Med Hypotheses. 2005;64(6):1166&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migliorini F, Lucenti L, Mok YR et al. Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Using Lateral Extra-Articular Procedures: A Systematic Review[J]. Med (Kaunas), 2025,61(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piedade SR, Leite Arruda BP, de Vasconcelos RA, et al. Rehabilitation following surgical reconstruction for anterior cruciate ligament insufficiency: What has changed since the 1960s?-State of the art[J]. J ISAKOS. 2023;8(3):153&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N. The Early Versus Late Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Debate: History Teaches Us That We Cannot Use Reason and Evidence to Fight and Win Against Conviction[J]. Arthroscopy. 2018;34(9):2524&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde A, Mane P, Shetty C et al. Peroneus Longus Tendon Autograft for Primary Arthroscopic Reconstruction of the Anterior Cruciate Ligament[J]. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J, 2023,13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordano L, Maffulli N, Carimati G, et al. Increased Time to Surgery After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Tear in Female Patients Results in Greater Risk of Medial Meniscus Tear: A Study of 489 Female Patients[J]. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(3):613&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N, Osti L. ACL stability, function, and arthritis: what have we been missing?[J]. Orthopedics. 2013;36(2):90&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papalia R, Franceschi F, Tecame A, et al. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and return to sport activity: postural control as the key to success[J]. Int Orthop. 2015;39(3):527&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebreen M, Maffulli N, Migliorini F, et al. Known-group validity of passive knee joint position sense: a comparison between individuals with unilateral anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and healthy controls[J]. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pipino G, Tomasi E, Mardones R, et al. Rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: dry land vs aquatic rehabilitation[J]. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2023;13(3):421&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemos T, Albarello JCS, Silva SC, et al. Quadriceps force fluctuation during maximal isometric contraction is altered in ACL injury and is associated with lower limb functional performance: a cross-sectional study with athletes[J]. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2024;14(3):499&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N, Oliva F. Coper Classification Early After ACL Rupture Changes With Progressive Neuromuscular and Strength Training and Is Associated With 2-Year Success: Letter to the Editor[J]. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(11):NP64&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley LK. Deficits in Quadriceps Strength and Patient-Oriented Outcomes at Return to Activity After ACL Reconstruction: A Review of the Current Literature[J]. Sports Health. 2015;7(3):231&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arhos EK, Capin JJ, Buchanan TS, et al. Quadriceps Strength Symmetry Does Not Modify Gait Mechanics After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction, Rehabilitation, and Return-to-Sport Training[J]. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(2):417&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakavas G, Malliaropoulos N, Bikos G, et al. Periodization in Anterior Cruciate Ligament Rehabilitation: A Novel Framework[J]. Med Princ Pract. 2021;30(2):101&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albarello JCS, Laett CT, de Palma AMS, et al. Associated ACL reconstruction and meniscal repair do not affect the evolution of isokinetic parameters in professional athletes: a prospective study with a one-year follow-up[J]. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2024;14(3):450&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AK, Palmieri-Smith RM, Lepley LK. Contribution of Neuromuscular Factors to Quadriceps Asymmetry After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction[J]. J Athl Train. 2018;53(4):347&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escamilla RF, Macleod TD, Wilk KE, et al. Anterior cruciate ligament strain and tensile forces for weight-bearing and non-weight-bearing exercises: a guide to exercise selection[J]. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(3):208&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Cingel REH, Brooijmans F, et al. Evidence-based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus[J]. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1506&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakavas G, Malliaropoulos N, Pruna R, et al. Neuroplasticity and Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury[J]. Indian J Orthop. 2020;54(3):275&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C, Liu Z, Wang Y, et al. Posterior Cruciate Ligament Retention versus Posterior Stabilization for Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Meta-Analysis[J]. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(1):e0147865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Liu C, Sun Z, et al. Postural control characteristics as reflected by center of pressure measurements in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients at varying post-operative stages: a cross-sectional comparative study[J]. J Orthop Surg Res. 2026;21(1):76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Yao H, Fan T et al. Twelve Weeks of a Staged Balance and Strength Training Program Improves Muscle Strength, Proprioception, and Clinical Function in Patients with Isolated Posterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries[J]. Int J Environ Res Public Health, 2021,18(23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culiver AM, Grooms DR, Caccese JB, et al. fMRI Activation in Sensorimotor Regions at 6 Weeks After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction[J]. Am J Sports Med. 2025;53(4):791&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarzycki R, Morton SM, Charalambous CC, et al. Corticospinal and intracortical excitability differ between athletes early after ACLR and matched controls[J]. J Orthop Res. 2018;36(11):2941&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez KM, Palmieri-Smith RM, Krishnan C. How does anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction affect the functioning of the brain and spinal cord? A systematic review with meta-analysis[J]. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10(2):172&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheurer SA, Sherman DA, Glaviano NR, et al. Corticomotor function is associated with quadriceps rate of torque development in individuals with ACL surgery[J]. Exp Brain Res. 2020;238(2):283&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone BG, Lepley AS, Ericksen HM, et al. Neural Excitability Alterations After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction[J]. J Athl Train. 2015;50(6):665&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Gribble PA, Thomas AC, et al. Quadriceps neural alterations in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed patients: A 6-month longitudinal investigation[J]. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(6):828&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrushko JW, Carr JC, Farthing JP, et al. Potential role of cross-education in early-stage rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction[J]. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(23):1474&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Zehr EP. Restoring symmetry: clinical applications of cross-education[J]. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42(2):70&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harput G, Ulusoy B, Yildiz TI, et al. Cross-education improves quadriceps strength recovery after ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial[J]. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Krentz JR, Magnus CRA, et al. Changes in functional magnetic resonance imaging cortical activation with cross education to an immobilized limb[J]. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(8):1394&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Carroll TJ, et al. Contralateral Effects of Unilateral Strength and Skill Training: Modified Delphi Consensus to Establish Key Aspects of Cross-Education[J]. Sports Med. 2021;51(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fimland MS, Helgerud J, Solstad GM, et al. Neural adaptations underlying cross-education after unilateral strength training[J]. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(6):723&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minshull C, Gallacher P, Roberts S, et al. Contralateral strength training attenuates muscle performance loss following anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction: a randomised-controlled trial[J]. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(12):3551&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik D, Co&#x15f;kunsu D, Kili&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu O. Translation and cultural adaptation of the Turkish Lysholm knee scale: ease of use, validity, and reliability[J]. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013;471(8):2602&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs KK, Steadman JR, Hay CJ, et al. Lysholm score and Tegner activity level in individuals with normal knees[J]. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(5):898&#x2013;901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Liu L, Chang X, et al. Cross-cultural translation of the Lysholm knee score in Chinese and its validation in patients with anterior cruciate ligament injury[J]. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2016;17(1):436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myklebust G, Holm I, Maehlum S, et al. Clinical, functional, and radiologic outcome in team handball players 6 to 11 years after anterior cruciate ligament injury: a follow-up study[J]. Am J Sports Med. 2003;31(6):981&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, et al. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures[J]. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti PH, Jarbas Da Silva J, Jon Schoenfeld B et al. (2016) Muscle Activation Differs between Three Different Knee Joint-Angle Positions during a Maximal Isometric Back Squat Exercise[J]. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp),2016: 3846123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skvortsov D, Altukhova A, Kaurkin S et al. Long-Term Outcomes of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Based on Gait Analysis[J]. Diagnostics (Basel), 2024,14(17).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H, Cao Z, Wang S, et al. Surface electromyography characteristics of patients with anterior cruciate ligament injury in different rehabilitation phases[J]. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1116452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Hinder MR, Gandevia SC, et al. The ipsilateral motor cortex contributes to cross-limb transfer of performance gains after ballistic motor practice[J]. J Physiol. 2010;588(Pt 1):201&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Fu Y, Shu J, et al. Application of cross-migration theory in limb rehabilitation of stroke patients with hemiplegia[J]. World J Clin Cases. 2023;11(19):4531&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fari&#xf1;as J, Mayo X, Giraldez-Garc&#xed;a MA, et al. Set Configuration in Strength Training Programs Modulates the Cross Education Phenomenon[J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(9):2414&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazer AK, Pearce AJ, Howatson G, et al. Determining the potential sites of neural adaptation to cross-education: implications for the cross-education of muscle strength[J]. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(9):1751&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Rothwell J, et al. Neurophysiological adaptations in the untrained side in conjunction with cross-education of muscle strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis[J]. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2018;124(6):1502&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce AJ, Hendy A, Bowen WA, et al. Corticospinal adaptations and strength maintenance in the immobilized arm following 3 weeks unilateral strength training[J]. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23(6):740&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Dragone D, Dvir Z, et al. Cross-education of muscular strength following unilateral resistance training: a meta-analysis[J]. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(11):2335&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus CRA, Barss TS, Lanovaz JL, et al. Effects of cross-education on the muscle after a period of unilateral limb immobilization using a shoulder sling and swathe[J]. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2010;109(6):1887&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuyul-V&#xe1;squez I, &#xc1;lvarez E, Riquelme A, et al. Effectiveness of Unilateral Training of the Uninjured Limb on Muscle Strength and Knee Function of Patients With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Cross-Education[J]. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31(5):605&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecce E, Conti A, Del Vecchio A, et al. Cross-education: motor unit adaptations mediate the strength increase in non-trained muscles following 8 weeks of unilateral resistance training[J]. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1512309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Bisschop M, Benjaminse A, et al. Quadriceps function following ACL reconstruction and rehabilitation: implications for optimisation of current practices[J]. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22(5):1163&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Failla MJ, Arundale AJH, Logerstedt DS, et al. Controversies in knee rehabilitation: anterior cruciate ligament injury[J]. Clin Sports Med. 2015;34(2):301&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice DA, McNair PJ. Quadriceps arthrogenic muscle inhibition: neural mechanisms and treatment perspectives[J]. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2010;40(3):250&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norte G, Rush J, Sherman D. Arthrogenic Muscle Inhibition: Best Evidence, Mechanisms, and Theory for Treating the Unseen in Clinical Rehabilitation[J]. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31(6):717&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson AL, Schilaty ND, Anderson S, et al. Arthrogenic muscle inhibition after anterior cruciate ligament injury: Injured and uninjured limb recovery over time[J]. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1143376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papandreou MG, Billis EV, Antonogiannakis EM, et al. Effect of cross exercise on quadriceps acceleration reaction time and subjective scores (Lysholm questionnaire) following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction[J]. J Orthop Surg Res. 2009;4:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimijashni M, Sarvestani FK, Yoosefinejad AK. The Effect of Contralateral Knee Neuromuscular Exercises on Static and Dynamic Balance, Knee Function, and Pain in Athletes Who Underwent Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Single-Blind Randomized Controlled Trial[J]. J Sport Rehabil. 2023;32(5):524&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisner-Janowicz I, Chen B, Sangari S, et al. Corticospinal excitability across lower limb muscles in humans[J]. J Neurophysiol. 2023;130(3):788&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amundsen Huffmaster SL, Van Acker GMR, Luchies CW, et al. Muscle synergies obtained from comprehensive mapping of the primary motor cortex forelimb representation using high-frequency, long-duration ICMS[J]. J Neurophysiol. 2017;118(1):455&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert GHM, Carson RG. Neural mechanisms mediating cross education: With additional considerations for the ageing brain[J]. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2022;132:260&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>