<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41740127</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Optical Illusion With a Sensorimotor Training on Somatosensory and Motor Function in Healthy Subjects: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e232</StartPage><EndPage>e239</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e232-e239</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005323</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Grande-Alonso, M, Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez, F, P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez, A, Cividanes-Garc&#xed;a, N, Mart&#xed;n-Tejedor, C, Soriano, M, Vidal-Quevedo, C, Forner-&#xc1;lvarez, C, and La Touche, R. Effects of optical illusion with a sensorimotor training on somatosensory and motor function in healthy subjects: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): e233-e240, 2026-The main objective was to assess the effects of an intervention with optical illusion glasses along with sensorimotor training based on cross-learning on somatosensory and motor variables in healthy subjects. This study was a randomized single-blind controlled trial. A total of 38 healthy subjects were randomly distributed into 2 groups: optical illusion group (OIG) and nonoptical illusion group (N-OIG). All subjects underwent 8 intervention sessions based on sensorimotor training on the dominant side. The OIG conducted the training using Prism Glasses branded graphs which acted as a mirror therapy. A pre, middle, and postassessment of tactile sensitivity, manual dexterity, and pain sensitivity was conducted. The OIG showed greater changes in tactile sensitivity of the dominant epicondyle than sensorimotor training alone. In manual dexterity, both groups produced significant improvements at the end of the intervention. Finally, only the OIG resulted in significant local hypoalgesia at the end of the intervention. It seems that using optical illusion glasses, together with a sensorimotor training program, has a greater impact than a sensorimotor training program alone on tactile sensitivity, very complex manual dexterity tasks, and on the improvement of pain sensitivity at least locally. The findings of this article suggest that integrating OI glasses into training regimens may enhance outcomes for athletes or individuals undergoing rehabilitation. Further studies should be conducted with the aim of having a transfer to a clinical population with pain or sensorimotor impairment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grande-Alonso</LastName><ForeName>M&#xf3;nica</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Alcal&#xe1;. Faculty of Medicine, Department of Surgery, Medical and Social Sciences, Alcal&#xe1; de Henares, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez</LastName><ForeName>Ferran</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, University of Valencia, c/ Gasc&#xf3; Oliag n&#xba;5 46010, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Musculoskeletal Disorders Unit, La Salle Functional Rehabilitation Institute, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cividanes-Garc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>Nerea</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Salle Higher Centre for University Studies (CSEU), Autonomous University of Madrid, 28023 Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;n-Tejedor</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Salle Higher Centre for University Studies (CSEU), Autonomous University of Madrid, 28023 Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soriano</LastName><ForeName>Marine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Salle Higher Centre for University Studies (CSEU), Autonomous University of Madrid, 28023 Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vidal-Quevedo</LastName><ForeName>Celia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Service, Jim&#xe9;nez Diaz Foundation Health Research Institute (IIS-FJD, UAM), Madrid, 28040, Spain; Rey Juan Carlos University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forner-&#xc1;lvarez</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-1575-1589</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physiotherapy, University of Valencia, c/ Gasc&#xf3; Oliag n&#xba;5 46010, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>La Touche</LastName><ForeName>Roy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Salle Higher Centre for University Studies (CSEU), Autonomous University of Madrid, 28023 Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Motion in Brains Research Group, Institute of Neuroscience and Sciences of the Movement (INCIMOV), La Salle Higher Centre for University Studies (CSEU), Autonomous University of Madrid, 28023 Madrid, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">manual dexterity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mirror therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optical illusion glasses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain sensitivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tactile sensitivity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41740127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202603000-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arya KN, Pandian S, Vikas, Puri V. Mirror illusion for sensori-motor training in stroke: A randomized controlled trial. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis 27: 3236&#x2013;3246, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beg RA, Shaphe MA, Qasheesh M, et al. Intermanual transfer effects on performance gain following dominant hand training in community-dwelling healthy adults: A preliminary study. J Multidiscip Healthc 14: 1007&#x2013;1016, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell-Krotoski JA, Fess EE, Figarola JH, Hiltz D. Threshold detection and semmes-weinstein monofilaments. J Hand Ther 8: 155&#x2013;162, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boesch E, Bellan V, Moseley GL, Stanton TR. The effect of bodily illusions on clinical pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PAIN 157: 516&#x2013;529, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutron I, Altman DG, Moher D, Schulz KF, Ravaud P, CONSORT NPT Group. CONSORT statement for randomized trials of nonpharmacologic treatments: A 2017 update and a CONSORT extension for nonpharmacologic trial abstracts. Ann Int Med 167: 40&#x2013;47, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardini F, Longo MR, Driver J, Haggard P. Rapid enhancement of touch from non-informative vision of the hand. Neuropsychologia 50: 1954&#x2013;1960, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavina-Pratesi C, Connolly JD, Monaco S, et al. Human neuroimaging reveals the subcomponents of grasping, reaching and pointing actions. Cortex 98: 128&#x2013;148, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Wang P, Bai Y, Wang Y. Effects of mirror training on motor performance in healthy individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 5: e000590, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YH, Siow T, Wang J, Lin S, Chao Y. Greater cortical activation and motor recovery following mirror therapy immediately after peripheral nerve repair of the forearm. Neuroscience 481: 123&#x2013;133, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesterton LS, Sim J, Wright CC, Foster NE. Interrater reliability of algometry in measuring pressure pain thresholds in healthy humans, using multiple raters. Clin J Pain 23: 760&#x2013;766, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirer-Sastre R, Beltr&#xe1;n-Garrido JV, Corbi F. Contralateral effects after unilateral strength training: A meta-analysis comparing training loads. J Sports Sci Med 16: 180&#x2013;186, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Eta-squared and partial eta-squared in fixed factor anova designs. Educ Psychol Meas 33: 107&#x2013;112, 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. (2nd ed.). Hillsdale NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1988. p. 567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer C, No&#xe9; E, Llorens R. Mirror therapy in chronic stroke survivors with severely impaired upper limb function: A randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 52: 271&#x2013;278, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Hortobagyi T, M&#xe1;rquez G. Does ipsilateral corticospinal excitability play a decisive role in the cross-education effect caused by unilateral resistance training? A systematic review. Neurologia 36: 285&#x2013;297, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Almeida Oliveira R, Cintia Dos Santos Vieira P, Rodrigues Martinho Fernandes LF, et al. Mental practice and mirror therapy associated with conventional physical therapy training on the hemiparetic upper limb in poststroke rehabilitation: A preliminary study. Top Stroke Rehabil 21: 484&#x2013;494, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deconinck FJA, Smorenburg ARP, Benham A, et al. Reflections on mirror therapy: A systematic review of the effect of mirror visual feedback on the brain. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 29: 349&#x2013;361, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Pellegrino G, Fadiga L, Fogassi L, Gallese V, Rizzolatti G. Understanding motor events: A neurophysiological study. Exp Brain Res 91: 176&#x2013;180, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickins DSE, Sale MV, Kamke MR. Intermanual transfer and bilateral cortical plasticity is maintained in older adults after skilled motor training with simple and complex tasks. Front Aging Neurosci 7: 73, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dohle C, P&#xfc;llen J, Nakaten A, et al. Mirror therapy promotes recovery from severe hemiparesis: A randomized controlled trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 23: 209&#x2013;217, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eads J, Lorimer Moseley G, Hillier S. Non-informative vision enhances tactile acuity: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuropsychologia 75: 179&#x2013;185, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods 39: 175&#x2013;191, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazer AK, Pearce AJ, Howatson G, et al. Determining the potential sites of neural adaptation to cross-education: Implications for the cross-education of muscle strength. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1751&#x2013;1772, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garry MI, Loftus A, Summers JJ. Mirror, mirror on the wall: Viewing a mirror reflection of unilateral hand movements facilitates ipsilateral M1 excitability. Exp Brain Res 163: 118&#x2013;122, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green LA, Gabriel DA. The cross education of strength and skill following unilateral strength training in the upper and lower limbs. J Neurophysiol 120: 468&#x2013;479, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung D, Park JW, Kim YH, You JSH. Neuroplastic and motor behavioral changes after intermanual transfer training of non-dominant hand: A prospective fMRI study. NeuroRehabilitation 44: 25&#x2013;35, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leo F, Nataletti S, Brayda L. Non-informative vision improves spatial tactile discrimination on the shoulder but does not influence detection sensitivity. Exp Brain Res 238: 2865&#x2013;2875, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung M, Rantalainen T, Teo WP, Kidgell D. The ipsilateral corticospinal responses to cross-education are dependent upon the motor-training intervention. Exp Brain Res 236: 1331&#x2013;1346, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Carroll TJ, et al. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength and skill training: Modified Delphi consensus to establish key aspects of cross&#x2014;Education. Sports Med 51: 11&#x2013;20, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manuweera T, Yarossi M, Adamovich S, Tunik E. Parietal activation associated with target-directed right hand movement is lateralized by mirror feedback to the ipsilateral hemisphere. Front Hum Neurosci 12: 531, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason J, Frazer AK, Horvath DM, et al. Ipsilateral corticomotor responses are confined to the homologous muscle following cross-education of muscular strength. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 43: 11&#x2013;22, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matesanz-Garc&#xed;a L, C&#xe1;ceres-Pajuelo JE, Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez F, et al. Effects of neural mobilizations through movement representation techniques for the improvement of neural mechanosensitivity of the median nerve region: A randomized controlled trial. Somatosens Mot Res 38: 267&#x2013;276, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Rebolledo G, Gatica-Rojas V, Torres-Cueco R, Albornoz-Verdugo M, Guzm&#xe1;n-Mu&#xf1;oz E. Update on the effects of graded motor imagery and mirror therapy on complex regional pain syndrome type 1: A systematic review. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil 30: 441&#x2013;449, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milde C, Rance M, Kirsch P, et al. Do mirror glasses have the same effect on brain activity as a mirror box? Evidence from a functional magnetic resonance imaging study with healthy subjects. PLoS One 10: e0127694, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto W, Kawahara Y, Mori S, Setsu K, Hattori F. Augmented visual feedback for complex motor skill acquisition: A demonstration with healthy young adults. Percept Mot Skills 130: 2685&#x2013;2699, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moseley GL. Graded motor imagery is effective for long-standing complex regional pain syndrome: A randomised controlled trial. Pain 108: 192&#x2013;198, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostajeran M, Alizadeh S, Rostami HR, Ghaffari A, Adibi I. Feasibility and efficacy of an early sensory&#x2014;Motor rehabilitation program on hand function in patients with stroke: A pilot, single-subject experimental design. Neurol Sci 45: 2737&#x2013;2746, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojima I, Mima T, Koganemaru S, et al. Human motor plasticity induced by mirror visual feedback. J Neurosci 32: 1293&#x2013;1300, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojima I, Koganemaru S, Kawamata T, Fukuyama H, Mima T. Action observation with kinesthetic illusion can produce human motor plasticity. Eur J Neurosci 41: 1614&#x2013;1623, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevopoulos E, Simeonidis T, Tsolakis C, Koulouvaris P, Papandreou M. The adjunctive benefits of mirror cross education on kinetic chain exercise approach in volleyball athletes with scapular dyskinesis. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 62: 98&#x2013;109, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlow SE, Kinsbourne M. Asymmetrical transfer of training between hands: Implications for interhemispheric communication in normal brain. Brain Cogn 11: 98&#x2013;113, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzolatti G, Fogassi L. The mirror mechanism: Recent findings and perspectives. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 369: 20130420, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzolatti G, Fadiga L, Gallese V, Fogassi L. Premotor cortex and the recognition of motor actions. Brain Res Cogn Brain Res 3: 131&#x2013;141, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzolatti G, Fadiga L, Fogassi L, Gallese V. The space around us. Science 277: 190&#x2013;191, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romkema S, Bongers RM, Van Der Sluis CK. Influence of mirror therapy and motor imagery on intermanual transfer effects in upper-limb prosthesis training of healthy participants: A randomized pre-posttest study. PLoS One 13: e0204839, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidel S, Kasprian G, Furtner J, et al. Mirror therapy in lower limb amputees&#x2014;A look beyond primary motor cortex reorganization. R&#xf6;fo 183: 1051&#x2013;1057, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyyah M, Topuz S. The effect of mirror therapy on joint movement, pain and functionality in acute upper limb burns. Burns 49: 1432&#x2013;1438, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takala EP. Pressure pain threshold on upper trapezius and levator scapulae muscles. Repeatability and relation to subjective symptoms in a working population. Scand J Rehabil Med 22: 63&#x2013;68, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thieme H, Mehrholz J, Pohl M, Behrens J, Dohle C. Mirror therapy for improving motor function after stroke. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012: CD008449, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiffin J, Asher EJ. The purdue pegboard: Norms and studies of reliability and validity. J Appl Psychol 32: 234&#x2013;247, 1948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tominaga W, Matsubayashi J, Deguchi Y, et al. A mirror reflection of a hand modulates stimulus-induced 20-Hz activity. Neuroimage 46: 500&#x2013;504, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tominaga W, Matsubayashi J, Furuya M, et al. Asymmetric activation of the primary motor cortex during observation of a mirror reflection of a hand. PLoS One 6: e28226&#x2013;e28227, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turville ML, Cahill LS, Matyas TA, Blennerhassett JM, Carey LM. The effectiveness of somatosensory retraining for improving sensory function in the arm following stroke: A systematic review. Clin Rehabil 33: 834&#x2013;846, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varalta V, Munari D, Fonte C, et al. Rehabilitation of somatic sensation and related deficit of motor control by mirror box therapy: A case report. Neurocase 28: 42&#x2013;47, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie HM, Zhang KX, Wang S, et al. Effectiveness of mirror therapy for phantom limb pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 103: 988&#x2013;997, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yal&#xe7;&#x131;n G, M&#xfc;lko&#x11f;lu C, G&#xfc;lmez S, Gen&#xe7; H. The effect of mirror therapy in the rehabilitation of flexor tendon injuries after primary surgical repair. Hand Surg Rehabil 43: 101612, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarossi M, Manuweera T, Adamovich SV, Tunik E. The effects of mirror feedback during target directed movements on ipsilateral corticospinal excitability. Front Hum Neurosci 11: 242, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang J, Ding L, Shu B, Chen D, Jia J. Associated mirror therapy enhances motor recovery of the upper extremity and daily function after stroke: A randomized control study. Neural Plast 2021: 7266263, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>