<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41740621</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-656X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in obstetrics &amp; gynecology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Midlife weight gain: challenges and solutions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>94</StartPage><EndPage>102</EndPage><MedlinePgn>94-102</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/GCO.0000000000001093</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Understanding the interplay between aging, hormonal changes, and lifestyle factors is crucial for effective obesity management in midlife and menopausal women. This review is timely given rising rates of obesity and associated comorbidities, the rapid evolution of pharmacologic interventions for obesity, and the growing recognition of the impact of midlife weight gain on women's long-term health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Weight gain in midlife women is primarily driven by age-related metabolic changes, with menopause contributing to unfavorable shifts in body composition and central adiposity. Obesity in menopause is associated with heightened risks of cardiometabolic disease, mood disorders, sleep disturbances, and impaired quality of life. Newer antiobesity medications have substantial efficacy in weight reduction and cardiometabolic risk improvement. Lifestyle interventions - resistance training and Mediterranean diet - remain foundational. Screening for comorbidities and attention to mental health are essential components of care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Management of midlife weight gain in women requires a multifaceted approach, integrating lifestyle modification, pharmacotherapy, and, when appropriate, surgical intervention. Clinicians should prioritize early identification of at-risk individuals, provide anticipatory guidance, and personalize interventions. Ongoing research is needed for evidence-based protocols for weight maintenance after initial loss, along with guidance on maintaining lean muscle mass while on incretin therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Sharon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Primary Care and Population Health.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>Karen E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynecology, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9007264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-872X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucagon-like receptor agonists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">midlife women</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight gain</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41740621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GCO.0000000000001093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001703-202604000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Apovian C, Aronne L, Barenbaum S. Clinical management of obesity. 3rd ed. The Obesity Society; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternfeld B, Wang H, Quesenberry CP Jr, et al. Physical activity and changes in weight and waist circumference in midlife women: findings from the Study of Women&#x2019;s Health Across the Nation. Am J Epidemiol 2004; 160:912&#x2013;922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field AE, Willett WC, Lissner L, Colditz GA. Dietary fat and weight gain among women in the Nurses&#x2019; Health Study. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2007; 15:967&#x2013;976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikairajah A, Walsh E, Tabatabaei-Jafari H, Cherbuin N. Fat mass changes during menopause: a meta-analysis. Obes Rev 2019; 221:393&#x2013;409.e50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado MD, Saadedine M, Kapoor E, et al. Weight gain in midlife women. Curr Obes Rep. 2024; 13:352&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moccia P, Belda-Montesinos R, Monllor-Tormos A, et al. Body weight and fat mass across the menopausal transition: hormonal modulators. Gynecol Endocrinol 2022; 38:99&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khawaja T, Nied M, Wilgor A, Neeland IJ. Impact of visceral and hepatic fat on cardiometabolic health. Curr Cardiol Rep 2024; 26:1297&#x2013;1307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khoudary SR, Aggarwal B, Beckie TM, et al.; American Heart Association Prevention Science Committee of the Council on Epidemiology and Prevention; and Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing. Menopause transition and cardiovascular disease risk: implications for timing of early prevention: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 2020; 142:e506&#x2013;e532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao V, Clark A, Aggarwal B. Obesity and severity of menopausal symptoms: a contemporary review. Curr Diab Rep 2023; 23:361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson CJ, Thurston RC, El Khoudary SR, et al. Association of vasomotor symptoms with weight gain, body composition, and metabolic syndrome in the Study of Women&#x2019;s Health Across the Nation. Menopause 2023; 30:45&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JM, Jiang J, Chang J, et al. Impact of lifetime obesity on urinary incontinence in the Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative. J Urol 2022; 207:1096&#x2013;1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbagallo F, Cucinella L, Tiranini L, et al. Obesity and sexual health: focus on postmenopausal women. Climacteric 2024; 27:122&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey WT, Mechanick JI, Brett EM, et al.; Reviewers of the AACE/ACE Obesity Clinical Practice Guidelines. American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists and American College of Endocrinology Comprehensive Clinical Practice Guidelines for Medical Care of Patients with Obesity. Endocr Pract 2016; 22 Suppl 3:1&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirer AG, Young T, Palta M, et al. Sleep-disordered breathing and the menopausal transition among participants in the sleep in Midlife Women Study. Menopause 2017; 24:157&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubbs AS, Khader W, Fernandez F, Grandner MA. The common denominators of sleep, obesity, and psychopathology. Curr Opin Psychol 2020; 34:84&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean RC, Morrison DS, Shearer R, et al. Attrition and weight loss outcomes for patients with complex obesity, anxiety and depression attending a weight management programme with targeted psychological treatment. Clin Obes 2016; 6:133&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SC, Kato TA, Lee JH, Yu SH. Exploring the bidirectional relationship between depression and obesity. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 2025; 54:193&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohebbi R, Shojaa M, Kohl M, et al. Exercise training and bone mineral density in postmenopausal women: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis of intervention studies with emphasis on potential moderators. Osteoporos Int 2023; 34:1145&#x2013;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy KL, Troiano RP, Ballard RM, et al. The physical activity guidelines for Americans. JAMA 2018; 320:2020&#x2013;2028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines, Obesity Expert Panel, 2013. Expert Panel Report: Guidelines (2013) for the management of overweight and obesity in adults. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2014; 22 Suppl 2:S41&#x2013;410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva TR, Oppermann K, Reis FM, et al. Nutrition in menopausal women: a narrative review. Nutrients 2021; 13:2149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrea L, Pugliese G, Laudisio D, et al. Mediterranean diet as medical prescription in menopausal women with obesity: a practical guide for nutritionists. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 2021; 61:1201&#x2013;1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugliese G Dr, Barrea L Dr, Laudisio D Dr, et al. Mediterranean diet as tool to manage obesity in menopause: a narrative review. Nutrition 2020; 79-80:110991&#x2013;110980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy HJ, Clifton PM, Astrup A, et al. The role of protein in weight loss and maintenance. Am J Clin Nutr 2015; 101:1320S&#x2013;1329S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannidhi D, Abeles R, Andrew W, et al. Lifestyle medicine for obesity in the era of highly effective anti-obesity treatment. Nutrients 2025; 17:2382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakken K, Eggen AE, Lund E. Side-effects of hormone replacement therapy and influence on pattern of use among women aged 45-64 years. The Norwegian Women and Cancer (NOWAC) study 1997. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand 2004; 83:850&#x2013;856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Bassford T, Green SB, et al. Postmenopausal hormone therapy and body composition &#x2013; a substudy of theestrogen plus progestin trial of the Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative. Am J Clin Nutr 2005; 82:651&#x2013;656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadakis GE, Hans D, Gonzalez Rodriguez E, et al. Menopausal hormone therapy is associated with reduced total and visceral adiposity: the OsteoLaus Cohort. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2018; 103:1948&#x2013;1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salpeter SR, Walsh JME, Ormiston TM, et al. Meta-analysis: effect of hormone-replacement therapy on components of themetabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women. Diabetes Obes Metab 2006; 8:538&#x2013;554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho L, Kaunitz AM, Faubion SS, et al.; ACC CVD in Women Committee. Rethinking menopausal hormone therapy: for whom, what, when, and how long? Circulation 2023; 147:597&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidlinger S, Winterberger K, Pape J, et al. Impact of estrogens on resting energy expenditure: a systematic review. Obes Rev 2023; 24:e13605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoff AM, Brown-Frandsen K, Colhoun HM, et al.; SELECT Trial Investigators. Semaglutide and cardiovascular outcomes in obesity without diabetes. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:2221&#x2013;2232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastreboff AM, Aronne LJ, Ahmad NN, et al.; SURMOUNT-1 Investigators. Tirzepatide once weekly for the treatment of obesity. N Engl J Med 2022; 387:205&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinpour A, Sood A, Kamalpour J, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and major adverse cardiovascular events in patients with and without diabetes: a meta-analysis of randomized-controlled trials. Clin Cardiol 2024; 47:e24314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingvay I, Sumithran P, le Roux CW, Cohen RV. There is no magic bullet for obesity. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2023; 11:541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudzune KA, Kushner RF. Medications for obesity: a review. JAMA 2024; 332:571&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilding JPH, Batterham RL, Davies M, et al.; STEP 1 Study Group. Weight regain and cardiometabolic effects after withdrawal of semaglutide: the STEP 1 trial extension. Diabetes Obes Metab 2022; 24:1553&#x2013;1564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadde KM, Allison DB, Ryan DH, et al. Effects of low-dose, controlled-release, phentermine plus topiramate combination on weight and associated comorbidities in overweight and obese adults (CONQUER): a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2011; 377:1341&#x2013;1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey WT, Ryan DH, Look M, et al. Two-year sustained weight loss and metabolic benefits with controlled-release phentermine/topiramate in obese and overweight adults (SEQUEL): a randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 extension study. Am J Clin Nutr 2012; 95:297&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi-Sunyer X, Astrup A, Fujioka K, et al.; SCALE Obesity and Prediabetes NN8022-1839 Study Group. A randomized, controlled trial of 3.0&#x2009;mg of liraglutide in weight management. N Engl J Med 2015; 373:11&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra A, Bednarik J, Chakladar S, et al. Tirzepatide for the treatment of obstructive sleep apnea: Rationale, design, and sample baseline characteristics of the SURMOUNT &#x2013; OSA phase 3 trial. Contemp Clin Trials 2024; 141:107516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomba R, Hartman ML, Lawitz EJ, et al.; SYNERGY-NASH Investigators. Tirzepatide for metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis with liver fibrosis. N Engl J Med 2024; 391:299&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torgerson JS, Hauptman J, Boldrin MN, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L. XENical in the prevention of diabetes in obese subjects (XENDOS) study: a randomized study of orlistat as an adjunct to lifestyle changes for the prevention of type 2 diabetes in obese patients. Diabetes Care 2004; 27:155&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Abildstr&#xf8;m SZ, Borlaug BA, et al.; STEP-HFpEF Trial Committees and Investigators. Semaglutide in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:1069&#x2013;1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal H, Bays H, Czernichow S, et al.; STEP 9 Study Group. Once-weekly semaglutide in persons with obesity and knee osteoarthritis. N Engl J Med 2024; 391:1573&#x2013;1583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossing P, Baeres FMM, Bakris G, et al. The rationale, design and baseline data of FLOW, a kidney outcomes trial with once-weekly semaglutide in people with type 2 diabetes and chronic kidney disease. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2023; 38:2041&#x2013;2051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melson E, Ashraf U, Papamargaritis D, Davies MJ. What is the pipeline for future medications for obesity? Int J Obes (Lond) 2025; 49:433&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastreboff AM, Kaplan LM, Fr&#xed;as JP, et al.; Retatrutide Phase 2 Obesity Trial Investigators. Triple-hormone-receptor agonist retatrutide for obesity &#x2013; a phase 2 trial. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:514&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams TD, Davidson LE, Litwin SE, et al. Weight and metabolic outcomes 12 years after gastric bypass. N Engl J Med 2017; 377:1143&#x2013;1155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arterburn DE, Johnson E, Coleman KJ, et al. Weight outcomes of sleeve gastrectomy and gastric bypass compared to nonsurgical treatment. Ann Surg 2021; 274:e1269&#x2013;e1276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicker D, Sagy YW, Ramot N, et al. Bariatric metabolic surgery vs glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and mortality. JAMA Netw Open 2024; 7:e2415392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. 8. Obesity and weight management for the prevention and treatment of type 2 diabetes: standards of care in diabetes-2025. Diabetes Care 2025; 48 Suppl 1:S167&#x2013;S180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland IJ, Linge J, Birkenfeld AL. Changes in lean body mass with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapies and mitigation strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26 Suppl 4:16&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardeli AV, Komatsu TR, Mori MA, et al. Resistance training prevents muscle loss induced by caloric restriction in obese elderly individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 2018; 10:423.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>