<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41149374</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2310-2861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gels (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gels</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Size Effects of Modified Nano-Silica on the Physical Properties of Resorcinol-Poly(acrylamide-co-2-acrylamido-2-methylpropanesulfonic acid) Gels in Harsh Reservoir Conditions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">769</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/gels11100769</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nano-silica is widely used to enhance gel properties, but its size, concentrations, and aggregation behaviors all matter. The influencing rules of these factors remain unclear especially in harsh reservoir conditions. This study presented a comprehensive investigation into the gelation, rheological, and plugging properties of phenolic polymer gels reinforced by modified nano-silica (GSNP) of different sizes and concentrations in harsh reservoir conditions. Specifically, the nano-silica was modified with a highly soluble silane, and gel properties were evaluated through rheological, differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), and sandpack flooding tests. The results showed that the incorporation of GSNP prolonged the gelation time, enhanced gel strength, and improved stability, allowing the gelation solution to enter deeper into the formation while maintaining long-time effectiveness. The optimal gel system was obtained with 0.4 wt.% GSNP-30, under which condition the storage modulus increased by approximately 14 times, and the content of non-freezable bound water more than doubled. This system exhibited plugging efficiency exceeding 80% in formations with permeabilities ranging from 1000 to 6000 millidarcy and enhanced the oil recovery factor by over 25%. The reinforcement mechanisms were attributed to the adsorption of GSNP onto polymer chains and its role in filling the gel matrix, which enhanced polymer hydrophilicity, suppressed polymer aggregation/curling, prevented ion penetration, and promoted the formation of a more uniform gel network. Careful optimization of nanoparticle size and concentration was essential to avoid the detrimental effects due to nanoparticle overfilling and aggregation. The novelty of this study lies in the practicable formulation of thermal and salt-tolerant gel systems with facile modified nano-silica of varying sizes and the systematic study of size and concentration effects. These findings offer practical guidance for tailoring nanoparticle parameters to cater for high-temperature and high-salinity reservoir conditions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Xun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7798-4453</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Drilling and Production Engineering for Oil and Gas, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yuxuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiating</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shunan Gas Mine, Southwest Oil and Gas Field Branch, China National Petroleum Corporation, Luzhou 646000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Yudan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Sheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Drilling and Production Engineering for Oil and Gas, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western Research Institute, Yangtze University, Karamay 834000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7798-2749</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Drilling and Production Engineering for Oil and Gas, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lifeng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Yangtze University, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Drilling and Production Engineering for Oil and Gas, Wuhan 430100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.52104019</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Science Foundation of China (NSFC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No.2024TSYCTD0018</GrantID><Agency>the "Tianshan Talents" Training Program - Science and Technology Innovation Team Project of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Gels</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101696925</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2310-2861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gel strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">harsh reservoir conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-time stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">modified nano-silica</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overfilling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Jiating Chen was employed by the Shunan Gas Mine, Southwest Oil and Gas Field Branch. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41149374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12563236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels11100769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">gels11100769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Babagbemi A.S., Mofunlewi S., Sote O.K., Onobrakpor O. Polymeric Gel Treatment for Water Shutoff&#x2014;A Case Study; Proceedings of the SPE Nigeria Annual International Conference and Exhibition; Lagos, Nigeria. 31 July&#x2013;2 August 2023; p. D031S021R005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang C., Guo J., Fei D., Xue P., Li J. A Novel Polymer Gel System with Low Density Property for Preferential Flow Control to Enhanced Oil Recovery. Phys. Fluids. 2025;37:043125. doi: 10.1063/5.0268039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0268039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabi M.S., Moradi R., Andrade L.O. Chemically Crosslinked Polyvinyl Alcohol for Water Shut-Off and Conformance Control Treatments During Oil Production: The Effect of Silica Nanoparticles. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2023;140:e53382. doi: 10.1002/app.53382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.53382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Xue M., Bai Y., Antonio P., Lv W., Hou B. Self-Healing Movable Gel for Enhanced Heavy Oil Recovery in Harsh Fractured Reservoirs. Phys. Fluids. 2025;37:083116. doi: 10.1063/5.0282037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0282037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q.-H., Ge J.-J., Ding L., Zhang G.-C. Unlocking the Potentials of Gel Conformance for Water Shutoff in Fractured Reservoirs: Favorable Attributes of the Double Network Gel for Enhancing Oil Recovery. Pet. Sci. 2023;20:1005&#x2013;1017. doi: 10.1016/j.petsci.2022.10.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petsci.2022.10.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi J., Liu Y., Chen J., Bo L., Qu G., Jiang N., He W. Preparation and Performance Evaluation of a Temperature and Salt Resistant Hydrophobic Associative Weak Polymer Gel System. Molecules. 2023;28:3125. doi: 10.3390/molecules28073125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28073125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37049888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z., Hu J., Liu P., Sun Y. Synthesis and Performance Evaluation of Alginate-Coated Temperature-Sensitive Polymer Gel Microspheres. Gels Basel Switz. 2023;9:480. doi: 10.3390/gels9060480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels9060480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10297886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37367150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong C., Wei F., Li W., Liu P., Wu Y., Dai M., Chen J. Mechanism of Polyacrylamide Hydrogel Instability on High-Temperature Conditions. ACS Omega. 2018;3:10716&#x2013;10724. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b01205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b01205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6645078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31459189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seright R., Brattekas B. Water Shutoff and Conformance Improvement: An Introduction. Pet. Sci. 2021;18:450&#x2013;478. doi: 10.1007/s12182-021-00546-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-021-00546-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China University of Petroleum; Qingdao, China: 2022. Study on Gel Water Plug Agent with Amino Resin as Crosslinking Agent.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Zhang X., Lv K., Liu J., Xiu Z., Wang Z., Huang X., Bai Y., Wang J., Jin J. Synthesis of Hydrophobic Associative Polymers to Improve the Rheological and Filtration Performance of Drilling Fluids under High Temperature and High Salinity Conditions. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2022;209:109808. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2021.109808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2021.109808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Lai X., Di Y., Wu Z., Li H., Wang L., Wen X. Preparation of Heat-Resistant and Salt-Resistant Hydrophobically Associating Polymer by Inverse Emulsion Polymerization and Its Rheological Properties. Polym. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2024;41:34&#x2013;43. doi: 10.16865/j.cnki.1000-7555.2024.0235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16865/j.cnki.1000-7555.2024.0235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almoshin A.M., Alsharaeh E., Fathima A., Bataweel M. A Novel Polymer Nanocomposite Graphene Based Gel for High Temperature Water Shutoff Applications; Proceedings of the SPE Kingdom of Saudi Arabia Annual Technical Symposium and Exhibition; Dammam, Saudi Arabia. 23&#x2013;26 April 2018; p. SPE-192358-MS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J., Wang Q., Liu P., Xiong G., Chen P., Chen X., Liu J. Nanocomposite Gels for Water Shut-Off and Temporary Plugging in the Petroleum Industry: A Review. Pet. Sci. Technol. 2023;41:2204&#x2013;2239. doi: 10.1080/10916466.2022.2108839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10916466.2022.2108839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira K.A.B., Oliveira P.F., Chaves I., Pedroni L.G., Oliveira L.A., Mansur C.R.E. Rheological Properties of Nanocomposite Hydrogels Containing Aluminum and Zinc Oxides with Potential Application for Conformance Control. Colloid Polym. Sci. 2022;300:609&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1007/s00396-022-04978-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00396-022-04978-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casalini A., Lima R. Water Shut&#x2014;Off Treatments in Oilfield by Micro and Nano Technology: A Good Way to get More Oil and Less Water; Proceedings of the Abu Dhabi International Petroleum Exhibition &amp; Conference; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates. 13&#x2013;16 November 2017; p. D011S017R005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Zhang Z., Zeng H., Huang F., Lu X., Sheng W. Preparation and Performance of High-Temperature-Resistant, Degradable Inorganic Gel for Steam Applications. SPE J. 2024;29:4266&#x2013;4281. doi: 10.2118/219775-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/219775-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida A.I.A.D.R., Carvalho L.D.O., Lopes R.C.F.G., Sena L.E.B., Do Amparo S.Z.S., De Oliveira C.P.M., Calado H.D.R., Silva G.G., De Vasconcelos C.K.B., Viana M.M. Enhanced Polyacrylamide Polymer Hydrogels Using Nanomaterials for Water Shutoff: Morphology, Thermal and Rheological Investigations at High Temperatures and Salinity. J. Mol. Liq. 2024;405:125041. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B., Li H., Wang Y., Zhang G., Zhang Q. Nanocomposite Hydrogels with High Strength Cross-Linked by Titania. RSC Adv. 2013;3:7233. doi: 10.1039/c3ra41350k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c3ra41350k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Fu M., Hu J. Preparation and Performance Evaluation of Temperature-Resistant and Salt-Resistant Gels. Gels. 2024;10:337. doi: 10.3390/gels10050337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10050337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38786254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi B., Zhang G., Zhang L., Wang C., Li Z., Chen F. Study on a Strong Polymer Gel by the Addition of Micron Graphite Oxide Powder and Its Plugging of Fracture. Gels. 2024;10:304. doi: 10.3390/gels10050304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10050304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38786221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilavya A., Rathwa P., Paine S., Makwana M., Bera A. Gelation Studies of Nanographene Oxide-Augmented Nanocomposite Polymer Gel Systems for Water Shutoff Technique in Oil Reservoirs. J. Mol. Liq. 2025;421:126928. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu Y. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China University of Petroleum; Qingdao, China: 2023. Preparation and Stability Mechanism of Temperature and Salt Resistant Modified-Graphite Hybrid Polymer Gel.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Zhao X., Ke Y. Effects of Silica Nanoparticle on the Solution Properties of Hydrophobically Associating Polymer Based on Acrylamide and &#x3b2;-Cyclodextrin. J. Mol. Liq. 2019;296:111885. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2019.111885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2019.111885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldo L.J., Giraldo M.A., Llanos S., Maya G., Zabala R.D., Nassar N.N., Franco C.A., Alvarado V., Cort&#xe9;s F.B. The Effects of SiO2 Nanoparticles on the Thermal Stability and Rheological Behavior of Hydrolyzed Polyacrylamide Based Polymeric Solutions. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2017;159:841&#x2013;852. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2017.10.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2017.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamlooh M., Hamza A., Hussein I.A., Nasser M.S., Magzoub M., Salehi S. Investigation of the Rheological Properties of Nanosilica-Reinforced Polyacrylamide/Polyethyleneimine Gels for Wellbore Strengthening at High Reservoir Temperatures. Energy Fuels. 2019;33:6829&#x2013;6836. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.9b00974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.9b00974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi Dijvejin Z., Ghaffarkhah A., Sadeghnejad S., Vafaie Sefti M. Effect of Silica Nanoparticle Size on the Mechanical Strength and Wellbore Plugging Performance of SPAM/Chromium (III) Acetate Nanocomposite Gels. Polym. J. 2019;51:693&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1038/s41428-019-0178-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41428-019-0178-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telin A., Safarov F., Yakubov R., Gusarova E., Pavlik A., Lenchenkova L., Dokichev V. Thermal Degradation Study of Hydrogel Nanocomposites Based on Polyacrylamide and Nanosilica Used for Conformance Control and Water Shutoff. Gels. 2024;10:846. doi: 10.3390/gels10120846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10120846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11675931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39727603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Dai C., Wang K., Zou C., Gao M., Fang Y., Zhao M., Wu Y., You Q. Study on a Novel Cross-Linked Polymer Gel Strengthened with Silica Nanoparticles. Energy Fuels. 2017;31:9152&#x2013;9161. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.7b01432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.7b01432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir Z., Mohd Saaid I., Mohamed Jan B. An Optimization Study of Polyacrylamide-Polyethylenimine-Based Polymer Gel for High Temperature Reservoir Conformance Control. Int. J. Polym. Sci. 2018;2018:2510132. doi: 10.1155/2018/2510132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/2510132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir Z., Saaid I.M., Mohd Junaidi M.U., Wan Bakar W.Z. Weakened PAM/PEI Polymer Gel for Oilfield Water Control: Remedy with Silica Nanoparticles. Gels. 2022;8:265. doi: 10.3390/gels8050265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels8050265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9141833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35621563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordoba A., Rivera-Mu&#xf1;oz E.M., Vel&#xe1;zquez-Castillo R., Esquivel K. PDMS/TiO2 and PDMS/SiO2 Nanocomposites: Mechanical Properties&#x2019; Evaluation for Improved Insulating Coatings. Nanomaterials. 2023;13:1699. doi: 10.3390/nano13101699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano13101699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10223323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37242114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare Y. The Roles of Nanoparticles Accumulation and Interphase Properties in Properties of Polymer Particulate Nanocomposites by a Multi-Step Methodology. Compos. Part Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2016;91:127&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2016.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2016.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleki-Khalan S., Hosseini-Nasab S.M. Study on Mechanisms of Novel Nano-Composite Polymer Gels with Silica and Alpha-Alumina Nanoparticles for Water Shut-Off in Hydrocarbon Reservoirs. Results Eng. 2025;26:105274. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2025.105274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2025.105274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu P., Shang Z., Yao M., Li X. Mechanistic Insight into Improving Strength and Stability of Hydrogels via Nano-Silica. J. Mol. Liq. 2022;357:119094. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv D., Li J., Bo Q., Xie Z., Dai C., Zhao G. A Novel Profile Control Agent in High-Temperature and High-Salinity Reservoirs: Dispersed Particle Gel Prepared from Modified Nanographite-Strengthened Bulk Gel. Energy Fuels. 2023;37:19487&#x2013;19498. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Ge J., Guo H., Lyu Q., Xu Y., Wu Q. Strengthening Phenolic Gel by Nano-SiO2 Under High Temperature and High Salinity Conditions. Polym. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2022;38:19&#x2013;28. doi: 10.16865/j.cnki.1000-7555.2022.0287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16865/j.cnki.1000-7555.2022.0287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal M., Prasanth Kumar R., Ojha K. Impact Assessment of Polymer, Cross-Linker, and Nanoparticles on Gelation Kinetics and Properties of Silica Nanocomposite Hydrogel for Water Shut-Off Treatment in Harsh Reservoir Conditions. J. Mol. Liq. 2024;411:125746. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareie C., Bahramian A.R., Sefti M.V., Salehi M.B. Network-Gel Strength Relationship and Performance Improvement of Polyacrylamide Hydrogel Using Nano-Silica; with Regards to Application in Oil Wells Conditions. J. Mol. Liq. 2019;278:512&#x2013;520. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2019.01.089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2019.01.089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F., Bai Y., Gu X., Kang S., Yang Y., Wang K. A Novel Fracturing Fluid Based on Functionally Modified Nano-Silica-Enhanced Hydroxypropyl Guar Gel. Gels. 2024;10:369. doi: 10.3390/gels10060369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10060369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11203310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38920916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Z., Li J., Lyu D., Zhang W., Zhen E., Qu B., Li Z., Zhao G. Water Control and Oil Increasing Effect of Organic-inorganic Nano-hybrid Gel in Deep Fractured Reservoirs. Oilfield Chem. 2025;42:98&#x2013;107. doi: 10.19346/j.cnki.1000-4092.2025.01.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19346/j.cnki.1000-4092.2025.01.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MalekiKhalan S., HosseiniNasab S.M. Enhancing Water Shut-Off in Oil Reservoirs Using Silica Nanoparticle-Reinforced Polymer Gels: A Lab Study. Iran. J. Chem. Eng. 2025;22:65&#x2013;85. doi: 10.22034/ijche.2025.494665.1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22034/ijche.2025.494665.1554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao W., Zhang G., Jiang P., Pei H. Investigation of Polymer Gel Reinforced by Oxygen Scavengers and Nano-SiO2 for Flue Gas Flooding Reservoir. Gels. 2023;9:268. doi: 10.3390/gels9040268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels9040268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10138175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37102880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman A.A., El-hoshoudy A.N., Attia A.M. Assessment of Xanthan Gum and Xanthan-G-Silica Derivatives as Chemical Flooding Agents and Rock Wettability Modifiers. Oil Gas Sci. Technol.&#x2014;Rev. D&#x2019;IFP Energ. Nouv. 2020;75:12. doi: 10.2516/ogst/2020004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2516/ogst/2020004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang T., Hou J., Qu M., Zhao M., Raj I. High-Viscosity &#x3b1;-Starch Nanogel Particles to Enhance Oil Recovery. RSC Adv. 2020;10:8275&#x2013;8285. doi: 10.1039/C9RA06938K.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9RA06938K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9049917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35497851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Ge J., Li L., Zhang G., Li Z., Wang W., Liu M. New Insights and Experimental Investigation of High-Temperature Gel Reinforced by Nano-SiO2. Gels. 2022;8:362. doi: 10.3390/gels8060362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels8060362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9223159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35735706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bila A., Tors&#xe6;ter O. Experimental Investigation of Polymer-Coated Silica Nanoparticles for EOR under Harsh Reservoir Conditions of High Temperature and Salinity. Nanomaterials. 2021;11:765. doi: 10.3390/nano11030765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano11030765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Ge J., Zhang G., Wang M., Chen D., Jiang P., Pei H., Chen W., Li J. Preparation and Temperature Resistance Mechanism of Nanoparticle-Enhanced Polymer Gel. Colloid Polym. Sci. 2024;302:1097&#x2013;1108. doi: 10.1007/s00396-024-05253-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00396-024-05253-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijani M., Khamehchi E., Shabani M. Comprehensive Experimental Investigation of the Effective Parameters on Stability of Silica Nanoparticles During Low Salinity Water Flooding with Minimum Scale Deposition into Sandstone Reservoirs. Sci. Rep. 2022;12:16472. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-20595-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-20595-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9526713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36183020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Ng Y.H., Lau H.C., Tors&#xe6;ter O., Stubbs L.P. Experimental Investigation of Stability of Silica Nanoparticles at Reservoir Conditions for Enhanced Oil-Recovery Applications. Nanomaterials. 2020;10:1522. doi: 10.3390/nano10081522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano10081522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh S., Neubauer E., Borovina A., Hincapie R.E., Clemens T., Ness D. Wettability Changes Due to Nanomaterials and Alkali&#x2014;A Proposed Formulation for EOR. Nanomaterials. 2021;11:2351. doi: 10.3390/nano11092351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano11092351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8469516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worthen A.J., Tran V., Cornell K.A., Truskett T.M., Johnston K.P. Steric Stabilization of Nanoparticles with Grafted Low Molecular Weight Ligands in Highly Concentrated Brines Including Divalent Ions. Soft Matter. 2016;12:2025&#x2013;2039. doi: 10.1039/C5SM02787J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5SM02787J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sydansk R.D. A Newly Developed Chromium(Lll) Gel Technology. SPE Reserv. Eng. 1990;5:346&#x2013;352. doi: 10.2118/19308-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/19308-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Xue F., Cheng R. States of Water in Partially Swollen Poly(Vinyl Alcohol) Hydrogels. Polymer. 2005;46:12026&#x2013;12031. doi: 10.1016/j.polymer.2005.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymer.2005.09.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Ge J. Experimental Investigation of the Entanglement Network and Nonlinear Viscoelastic Behavior of a Nano-SiO2 Strengthened Polymer Gel. J. Mol. Liq. 2021;339:117288. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong X., Li C., Li Y., Pu H., Zhou Y., Zhao J.X. Enhanced Oil Recovery in High Salinity and Elevated Temperature Conditions with a Zwitterionic Surfactant and Silica Nanoparticles Acting in Synergy. Energy Fuels. 2020;34:2893&#x2013;2902. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.9b04067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.9b04067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong X., Chen J., Xu F., Chen X. Experimental Investigation of Zwitterionic Surfactant-Based Silica Nanofluid Spontaneous Imbibition at High Salinity and Elevated Temperature Conditions. J. Mol. Liq. 2022;364:119995. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith C., Daigle H. Manipulation of Pickering Emulsion Rheology Using Hydrophilically Modified Silica Nanoparticles in Brine. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2018;509:132&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2017.08.100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2017.08.100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28898733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid Mohammadi M., Sahraei E., Bayati B. Gelation Studies of High Molecular Weight Polymeric Nanoparticles for Application in Fractured Oil Reservoirs with Harsh Conditions. Energy Sources Part A Recovery Util. Environ. Eff. 2024;46:11058&#x2013;11072. doi: 10.1080/15567036.2020.1788672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15567036.2020.1788672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliabadian E., Kamkar M., Chen Z., Sundararaj U. Prevention of Network Destruction of Partially Hydrolyzed Polyacrylamide (HPAM): Effects of Salt, Temperature, and Fumed Silica Nanoparticles. Phys. Fluids. 2019;31:013104. doi: 10.1063/1.5080100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.5080100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sydansk R.D. Acrylamide-Polymer/Chromium(III)-Carboxylate Gels for Near Wellbore Matrix Treatments. SPE Adv. Technol. Ser. 1993;1:146&#x2013;152. doi: 10.2118/20214-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/20214-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>