<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41318312</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-1861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of science and medicine in sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Med Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Shoulder HD Pilot Trial: A qualitative study of patient and therapist experience, acceptability, tolerance and perception of a high and low load-volume intervention for rotator cuff tendinopathy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1440-2440(25)00482-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jsams.2025.10.014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore the experiences of people, specifically the acceptability and tolerances of a high and low load-volume (intensity * X sets X repetitions) exercise programme for rotator cuff tendinopathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A nested qualitative study with individual in-depth semi-structured interviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twelve participants (6 high load-volume, 6 low load-volume) were recruited at the conclusion of a pilot and feasibility trial comparing high and low load-volume exercise for rotator cuff tendinopathy. Analysis followed an inductive thematic approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Three themes were identified: (1) Intensity: influenced by belief that the treatment will or won't work; (2) adherence: progress reinforced by a positive experience; and (3) education: reassurance and clear instruction regarding pain. Participants expressed initial doubt regarding the rationale behind both the high load-volume intervention and low load-volume intervention (i.e. either too easy or too hard). However, both groups surprised themselves with the improvement they made. Acceptability and tolerance of exercise intensity, either low or high, is are largely influenced by past exercise experience, expectations, attitudes and beliefs regarding the effectiveness of the exercise programme. Findings highlight the acceptability of both approaches for most people with rotator cuff tendinopathy, after some participants were initially apprehensive. Participants expressed the value of practical, informative, condition specific knowledge; the importance of tangible progress with their exercise programme; and appreciation for a low level of burden in adhering to their exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Individualisation of exercise intensity is important, yet needs to consider individual preference, response to the load stimulus and the patients baseline physical capacity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naunton</LastName><ForeName>Josh</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Musculoskeletal Research Unit (MMRU), Department of Physiotherapy, School of Primary and Allied Health Care, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Science, Peninsula Campus, Monash University, Australia; Physiotherapy, Department of Rural Allied Health, La Trobe University Rural Health School, Australia; Physiotherapy &amp; Exercise Physiology, Allied Health and Continuing Care, Bendigo Health, Australia. Electronic address: J.Naunton@Latrobe.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrett</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Innovation, Bendigo Health, Australia; Holsworth Research Initiative, La Trobe University, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kidgell</LastName><ForeName>Dawson</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Exercise Neuroplasticity Unit, Department of Physiotherapy, School of Primary and Allied Health Care, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Science, Peninsula Campus, Monash University, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennell</LastName><ForeName>Kim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health, Exercise and Sports Medicine, Department of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Medicine, Dentistry and Health Sciences, , The University of Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haines</LastName><ForeName>Terry</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation, Ageing and Independent Living Research Centre, School of Primary and Allied Health Care, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Science, Peninsula Campus, Monash University, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malliaras</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Musculoskeletal Research Unit (MMRU), Department of Physiotherapy, School of Primary and Allied Health Care, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Science, Peninsula Campus, Monash University, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Sci Med Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9812598</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1878-1861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High load-volume</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rotator cuff tendinopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder pain</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interest statement None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41318312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2025.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1440-2440(25)00482-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>