<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41184351</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on the configuration strategy of active support long-and short-term energy storage devices based on ESD-considered short circuit ratio.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38298</StartPage><MedlinePgn>38298</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">38298</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-22289-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Although the evaluation of system strength under high penetration of renewable energy sources (RESs) has been widely studied, traditional short-circuit ratio (SCR) indicators mainly focus on the interactions among RESs and are concentrated on steady-state research, neglecting the dynamic regulation effect of energy storage devices (ESDs) on system stability. In addition, most of the existing optimization methods aim to improve economic efficiency and lack system stability analysis based on SCR quantification. Therefore, this paper proposes an ESD-considered short-circuit ratio (ECSCR) that incorporates the contribution of ESDs to the short-circuit capacity of nodes. A bi-layer optimization strategy for the active support long-and short-term energy storage device is developed. The upper-layer optimizes the installation locations of ESDs by maximizing the minimum ECSCR (MinECSCR) on the RES buses, while the lower-layer uses the Newton-Raphson algorithm to dynamically adjust the power distribution of ESD to balance stability and economy. Specifically, when the ECSCR is less than the critical short-circuit ratio (CSCR), the fast-response flywheel energy storage (FES) and battery energy storage (BES) prioritize the restoration of stability; when the ECSCR is greater than the CSCR, the lower-cost thermal energy storage (TES) serves as the main power generation unit to minimize operating costs. The verification of the improved IEEE 9-bus, 39-bus system, and 14-bus system shows that compared with traditional SCR indicators, the proposed ECSCR can significantly enhance the nodal strength and reduce operating costs while ensuring system stability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hai</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northeastern University, Shenyang, 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northeastern University, Shenyang, 110819, China. wangrui@ise.neu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Qiuye</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northeastern University, Shenyang, 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhengmao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aalto University, 00076, Espoo, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, 639798, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESD-considered Short-Circuit Ratio (ECSCR)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Storage Devices (ESDs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bi-layer optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">grid strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41184351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12583808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-22289-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-22289-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lin, B. &amp; Liu, Z. Assessment of flexible coal power and battery energy storage system in supporting renewable energy. <i>Energy</i><b>313</b>, 133805. 10.1016/j.energy.2024.133805 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.133805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, D. et al. Assessing impact of renewable energy integration on system strength using site-dependent short circuit ratio. <i>IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy</i><b>9</b>, 1072&#x2013;1080. 10.1109/TSTE.2017.2764871 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2017.2764871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, L. et al. Multiple renewable short-circuit ratio for assessing weak system strength with inverter-based resources. <i>CSEE J. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>10</b>, 2271&#x2013;2282. 10.17775/CSEEJPES.2023.10060 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17775/CSEEJPES.2023.10060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayvaz, A. &amp; Istemihan Genc, V. Information-gap decision theory based transient stability constrained optimal power flow considering the uncertainties of wind energy resources. <i>IET Renew. Power Gener.</i><b>14</b>, 1946&#x2013;1955. 10.1049/iet-rpg.2019.1367 (2020) https://ietresearch.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1049/iet-rpg.2019.1367..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-rpg.2019.1367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, F., Xin, H., Wu, D., Liu, Y. &amp; Chen, X. Assessing small-signal grid strength of 100% inverter-based power systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Deliv.</i><b>39</b>, 2784&#x2013;2796. 10.1109/TPWRD.2024.3432582 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2024.3432582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee, D. IEEE guide for planning dc links terminating at ac locations having low short-circuit capacities (IEEE, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., Zhao, F., Wu, H. &amp; Wang, X. Comparison analysis of short circuit ratio variants on the indication of power system voltage stability. In <i>2024 IEEE 15th International Symposium on Power Electronics for Distributed Generation Systems (PEDG)</i>, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/PEDG61800.2024.10667372 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, L., Sun, H., Xu, S., Zhao, B. &amp; Zhang, J. A critical system strength evaluation of a power system with high penetration of renewable energy generations. <i>CSEE J. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>8</b>, 710&#x2013;720. 10.17775/CSEEJPES.2021.03020 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17775/CSEEJPES.2021.03020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Evaluating system strength for large-scale wind plant integration. In <i>2014 IEEE PES General Meeting| Conference &amp; Exposition</i>, 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmall, J. et al. Voltage stability of large-scale wind plants integrated in weak networks: An ercot case study. In <i>2015 IEEE Power &amp; Energy Society General Meeting</i>, 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, W., Xin, H., Wu, D. &amp; Huang, L. Small signal stability analysis of multi-infeed power electronic systems based on grid strength assessment. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Syst.</i><b>34</b>, 1393&#x2013;1403. 10.1109/TPWRS.2018.2875305 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2018.2875305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, H., Teng, Y., Cheng, S., Sun, P. &amp; Chen, Z. Distributed multi-energy storage cooperative optimization control method for power grid voltage stability enhancement. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>216</b>, 109012. 10.1016/j.epsr.2022.109012 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2022.109012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Amine, H., Mouaz, A. K., Messaoud, H., Othmane, A. &amp; Saad, M. Contribution to strengthening bus voltage stability and power exchange balance of a decentralized dc-multi-microgrids: Performance assessment of classical, optimal, and nonlinear controllers for hybridized energy storage systems control. <i>Sustain. Cities Soc.</i><b>96</b>, 104647. 10.1016/j.scs.2023.104647 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2023.104647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D., Sun, Q. &amp; Hu, J. Bi-level optimal allocation of virtual power plants considering grid strength using integrated short-circuit ratio. <i>CSEE J. Power Energy Syst.</i>10.17775/CSEEJPES.2022.08040 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17775/CSEEJPES.2022.08040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari, M., Tolbert, L. M. &amp; Piesciorovsky, E. C. Grid forming inverter with increased short-circuit contribution to address inverter-based microgrid protection challenges. <i>IEEE Open J. Ind. Electron. Soc.</i><b>5</b>, 481&#x2013;500. 10.1109/OJIES.2024.3406915 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/OJIES.2024.3406915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Optimal operation with dynamic partitioning strategy for centralized shared energy storage station with integration of large-scale renewable energy. <i>J. Mod. Power Syst. Clean Energy</i><b>12</b>, 359&#x2013;370 (2024) (<b>10.35833/MPCE.2023.000345</b>).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35833/MPCE.2023.000345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W., Zhang, J., Zeng, P. &amp; Liu, W. Energy storage configuration and day-ahead pricing strategy for electricity retailers considering demand response profit. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>136</b>, 107633 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2021.107633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, X., Wu, T., Yao, W. &amp; Yang, Y. Selection method for new energy output guaranteed rates considering optimal energy storage configuration. <i>CSEE J. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>10</b>, 539&#x2013;547. 10.17775/CSEEJPES.2020.03330 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17775/CSEEJPES.2020.03330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Discussion on optimization method of new power system planning considering short circuit ratio. In <i>2021 IEEE 5th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i>, 809&#x2013;813. 10.1109/EI252483.2021.9713530 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes, R., Achilles, S. &amp; MacDowell, J. Report to nerc erstf for composite short circuit ratio (cscr) estimation guideline. <i>GE Energy Consulting</i> (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayvaz, A. &amp; Ayvaz, B. G&#xfc;&#xe7; sistemlerinde meydana gelen kisa devre ar&#x131;zalar&#x131;na karsi akim sinirlayici yapisinin en uygun yerle&#x15f;im yerinin belirlenmesi. <i>Sakarya Univ. J. Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 613&#x2013;621 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, J., Ran, L., Wang, Z. &amp; Zhang, M. Optimal energy scheduling of virtual power plant integrating electric vehicles and energy storage systems under uncertainty. <i>Energy</i><b>309</b>, 132988. 10.1016/j.energy.2024.132988 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.132988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Strategic two-stage diagonal quadratic approximation method for economic dispatch with energy storage. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng.</i><b>22</b>, 4216&#x2013;4230. 10.1109/TASE.2024.3408893 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2024.3408893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, A. B. et al. Renewable integration and energy storage management and conversion in grid systems: A comprehensive review. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 2583&#x2013;2602. 10.1016/j.egyr.2025.02.008 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2025.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. et al. Progress in electrical energy storage system: A critical review. <i>Prog. Nat. Sci.</i><b>19</b>, 291&#x2013;312. 10.1016/j.pnsc.2008.07.014 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnsc.2008.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede, A. A., Kalogiannis, T., Mierlo, J. &amp; Berecibar, M. A comprehensive review of stationary energy storage devices for large scale renewable energy sources grid integration. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>159</b>, 112213. 10.1016/j.rser.2022.112213 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2022.112213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, P., Zeng, P., Tang, Z., Zhou, X. &amp; Zhu, Y. A distributionally collaborated planning of energy storage, transmission and distribution systems considering long- and short-term energy storage characteristics. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>120</b>, 116396. 10.1016/j.est.2025.116396 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.116396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J. et al. Active operation strategy of hybrid energy storage in regional integrated energy systems based on long short-term memory network. In <i>2023 2nd International Conference on Smart Grids and Energy Systems (SGES)</i>, 381&#x2013;388. 10.1109/SGES59720.2023.10366907 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T., Yang, Z. &amp; Duan, Y. Short- and long-duration cooperative energy storage system: Optimizing sizing and comparing rule-based strategies. <i>Energy</i><b>281</b>, 128273. 10.1016/j.energy.2023.128273 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.128273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao, Y. et al. Case study on flywheel energy storage systems: Lptn-based transient thermal analysis. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>120</b>, 116319. 10.1016/j.est.2025.116319 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.116319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, H. et al. Smart optimization in battery energy storage systems: An overview. <i>Energy AI</i><b>17</b>, 100378. 10.1016/j.egyai.2024.100378 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2024.100378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, K., Wu, C., Gan, H., Liu, C. &amp; Zhao, J. Latent heat thermal energy storage: Theory and practice in performance enhancement based on heat pipes. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>97</b>, 112844. 10.1016/j.est.2024.112844 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.112844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayvaz, A. A new and effective directional overcurrent relay coordination approach for iidg-based distribution networks using different setting groups for peak and off-peak demand periods. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>237</b>, 111017. 10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111017 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, S. &amp; Mahapatra, G. Numerical solution of fuzzy non-linear equations under generalized trapezoidal fuzziness by Newton&#x2013;Raphson method. <i>Frankl. Open</i><b>9</b>, 100168. 10.1016/j.fraope.2024.100168 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fraope.2024.100168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costilla-Enriquez, N., Weng, Y. &amp; Zhang, B. Combining Newton&#x2013;Raphson and stochastic gradient descent for power flow analysis. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Syst.</i><b>36</b>, 514&#x2013;517. 10.1109/TPWRS.2020.3029449 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2020.3029449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheykhsarraf, A., Abedini, M. &amp; Davarpanah, M. A novel method for optimal placement and tuning of the power system stabilizer in the multi-machine system. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>221</b>, 109451. 10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109451 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreotti, A., Caiazzo, B., Fridman, E., Petrillo, A. &amp; Santini, S. Distributed dynamic event-triggered control for voltage recovery in islanded microgrids by using artificial delays. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybern.</i><b>54</b>, 3890&#x2013;3903. 10.1109/TCYB.2024.3364820 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2024.3364820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38416631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>