<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41347122</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2688-5115</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedics and sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multimodal Approaches for Pain Management and Improving Functional Outcomes Following Amputation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>449</StartPage><EndPage>463</EndPage><MedlinePgn>449-463</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.26502/josm.511500227</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the United States, limb amputation affects around 2.3 million people, with projected numbers rising due to the higher levels of diabetes and peripheral vascular disease. Amputee patients not only encounter mobility loss but also residual limb pain, psychological stress, and disparities in access to healthcare. This article presents a critical review of the current literature on functional outcomes and pain management for patients who underwent limb amputation. In terms of pharmacological therapies, gabapentinoids and antidepressants provide minimal relief for post amputation pain, whereas surgical techniques including targeted muscle reinnervation and regenerative peripheral nerve interfaces have resulted in much larger improvements in decreasing neuroma-related and phantom limb pain. The non-pharmacological therapies, including mirror therapy, graded motor imagery, and virtual reality are some of the most effective interventions for reduction of phantom limb pain. Functional improvement can be optimized through microprocessor-controlled prosthetics, osseointegration, and early rehabilitation with an emphasis on resistance training, mobility, and psychological support. Newer techniques including neuromodulation and artificial intelligence-enhanced prosthetic control also play a part in rehabilitation; however, evidence is limited due to their novel introduction to the rehabilitation space. Overall, a multidisciplinary and individualized multimodal approach to rehabilitation remains the gold standard to improve pain control, quality of life, and functional restoration.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parvizi</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kandikattu</LastName><ForeName>Sugeeth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahafi</LastName><ForeName>Ramtin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allahverdian</LastName><ForeName>Artin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Blake</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fraix</LastName><ForeName>Marcel P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Devendra K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research, College of Osteopathic Medicine of the Pacific, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, California 91766, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R25 AI179582</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918470780006676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2688-5115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amputation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heterotopic ossification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microprocessor-controlled prosthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mirror therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromodulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phantom limb pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prosthetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regenerative peripheral nerve interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Residual limb pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Targeted muscle reinnervation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: All authors have read the manuscript and declare no conflict of interest. No writing assistance was utilized in the production of this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41347122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2113752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12674603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26502/josm.511500227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rivera JA, Churovich K, Anderson AB, et al. Estimating recent US limb loss prevalence and updating future projections. Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl 6 (2024): 100376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparling T, Iyer L, Pasquina P, et al. Cortical reorganization after limb loss: bridging the gap between basic science and clinical recovery. J Neurosci 44 (2024): e1051232024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes JA, Eid MA, Creager MA, et al. Epidemiology and risk of amputation in patients with diabetes mellitus and peripheral artery disease. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 40 (2020): 1808&#x2013;1817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32580632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong DG, Tan T, Boulton AJM, et al. Diabetic foot ulcers: a review. JAMA 330 (2023): 62&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10723802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher KA, Mills JL, Armstrong DG, et al. Current status and principles for the treatment and prevention of diabetic foot ulcers in the cardiovascular patient population: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 149 (2024): e232&#x2013;e253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11067094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38095068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison MA, Armstrong DG, Goodney PP, et al. Health disparities in peripheral artery disease: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 148 (2023): 286&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11520198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37317860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassavin D, Mota L, Ostertag-Hill CA, et al. Amputation rates and associated social determinants of health in the most populous US counties. JAMA Surg 159 (2024): 69&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37910120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association. Management of peripheral artery disease. Circulation (2023). Available at: https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association. Global perspectives on vascular health. Circulation (2021). Available at: https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/full/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster JB, Crunkhorn A, Sall J, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the rehabilitation of lower limb amputation: an update from the Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 98 (2019): 820&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31419214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent ML, Hsia HJ, Van de Ven TJ, Buchheit TE. Perioperative pain management strategies for amputation: a topical review. Pain Med 18 (2017): 504&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27402960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal NTB, de Ara&#xfa;jo NM, Silva SO, et al. Pain management in the postoperative period of amputation surgeries: a scoping review. J Clin Nurs 32 (2023): 7718&#x2013;7729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37605033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyns A, Dusar FR, Arienti C, et al. Overview of Cochrane systematic reviews for rehabilitation interventions in persons with amputation: a mapping synthesis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 61 (2025): 351&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12105599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40202277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limakatso K, Bedwell GJ, Madden VJ, Parker R. The prevalence and risk factors for phantom limb pain in people with amputations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 15 (2020): e0240431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spezia MC, Dy CJ, Brogan DM. Phantom limb pain management. J Hand Surg 50 (2025): 208&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flor H Phantom-limb pain: characteristics, causes, and treatment. Lancet Neurol 1 (2002): 182&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12849487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stankevicius A, Wallwork SB, Summers SJ, et al. Prevalence and incidence of phantom limb pain, phantom limb sensations and telescoping in amputees: a systematic rapid review. Eur J Pain 25 (2021): 23&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diers M, Krumm B, Fuchs X, et al. The prevalence and characteristics of phantom limb pain and non-painful phantom phenomena in a nationwide survey of 3,374 unilateral limb amputees. J Pain 23 (2022): 411&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34583023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaso A, Adahan HM, Gjika A, et al. Peripheral nervous system origin of phantom limb pain. Pain 155 (2014): 1384&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata G, Di Iorio R, Ilari S, et al. Phantom limb syndrome: from pathogenesis to treatment. A narrative review. Neurol Sci 45 (2024): 4741&#x2013;4755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38853232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuffler DP. Origins of phantom limb pain. Mol Neurobiol 55 (2018): 60&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28921474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins KL, Russell HG, Schumacher PJ, et al. A review of current theories and treatments for phantom limb pain. J Clin Invest 128 (2018): 2168&#x2013;2176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29856366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makin TR, Flor H. Brain (re)organisation following amputation: implications for phantom limb pain. Neuroimage 218 (2020): 116943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andoh J, Milde C, Tsao JW, Flor H. Cortical plasticity as a basis of phantom limb pain: fact or fiction? Neuroscience 387 (2018): 85&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giummarra MJ, Moseley GL. Phantom limb pain and bodily awareness: current concepts and future directions. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol 24 (2011): 524&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21772144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Andoh J, Lyu Y, et al. Peripheral input and phantom limb pain: a somatosensory event-related potential study. Eur J Pain 24 (2020): 1314&#x2013;1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone AB, Hollmann MW, Terwindt LE, Lirk P. Chronic post amputation pain: pathophysiology and prevention options for a heterogenous phenomenon. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol 36 (2023): 572&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37552016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doshi TL, Dolomisiewicz E, Caterina MJ, et al. Postamputation pain: a multidisciplinary review of epidemiology, mechanisms, prevention, and treatment. Reg Anesth Pain Med 50 (2025): 175&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39909547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke C, Lindsay DR, Pyati S, Buchheit T. Residual limb pain is not a diagnosis: a proposed algorithm to classify postamputation pain. Clin J Pain 29 (2013): 551&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23328317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>List EB, Krijgh DD, Martin E, Coert JH. Prevalence of residual limb pain and symptomatic neuromas after lower extremity amputation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain 162 (2021): 1906&#x2013;1913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Lai S, Li J, et al. Early postoperative rapid rehabilitation yields more favorable short-term outcomes in patients undergoing patellar realignment surgery for recurrent patellar dislocation: a prospective randomized controlled study. Am J Sports Med 52 (2024): 2205&#x2013;2214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38884318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buch NS, Qerama E, Brix Finnerup N, Nikolajsen L. Neuromas and postamputation pain. Pain 161 (2020): 147&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31568042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stover G, Prahlow N. Residual limb pain: an evidence-based review. NeuroRehabilitation 47 (2020): 315&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nger M, Pinto CB, Pacheco-Barrios K, et al. Protective and risk factors for phantom limb pain and residual limb pain severity. Pain Pract 20 (2020): 578&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7363546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32176435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang BL, Mondshine J, Fleury CM, et al. Incidence and nerve distribution of symptomatic neuromas and phantom limb pain after below-knee amputation. Plast Reconstr Surg 149 (2022): 976&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35188944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EY, Sammarco MC, Spinner RJ, Shin AY. Current concepts of the management of painful traumatic peripheral nerve neuromas. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 33 (2025): 178&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39813122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang CD, Hoftiezer YAJ, Raasveld FV, et al. Biology and pathophysiology of symptomatic neuromas. Pain 165 (2024): 550&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37851396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Sun X, Wang C, et al. Mechanisms and treatment of painful neuromas. Rev Neurosci 29 (2018): 557&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lans J, Groot OQ, Hazewinkel MHJ, et al. Factors related to neuropathic pain following lower extremity amputation. Plast Reconstr Surg 150 (2022): 446&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10375758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35687412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray AL, Morgenroth DC, Czerniecki JM. Residual limb claudication in a traumatic transtibial amputee. PM R 5 (2013): 152&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subedi N, Heire P, Parmer V, et al. Multimodality imaging review of the post-amputation stump pain. Br J Radiol 89 (2016): 20160572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg NM, Bull AMJ. Application of a mechanobiological algorithm to investigate mechanical mediation of heterotopic bone in trans-femoral amputees. Sci Rep 8 (2018): 14196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6155077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson GJ, Lee MY, Mehta MK. Heterotopic ossification in the residual lower limb in an adult nontraumatic amputee patient. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 89 (2010): 245&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19966560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter BK, Burns TC, Lacap AP, et al. Heterotopic ossification in the residual limbs of traumatic and combat-related amputees. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 14 (2006): S191&#x2013;S197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao G, Zhang S, Wang Y, et al. Pathogenesis of acquired heterotopic ossification: risk factors, cellular mechanisms, and therapeutic implications. Bone 168 (2023): 116655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raasveld FV, Liu WC, Renthal WR, et al. Heterotopic ossification is associated with painful neuromas in transtibial amputees undergoing surgical treatment of symptomatic neuromas. Plast Reconstr Surg 155 (2025): 185&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38507565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facchin A, Lemaire S, Toner LG, et al. When bone forms where it shouldn&#x2019;t: heterotopic ossification in muscle injury and disease. Int J Mol Sci 26 (2025): 7516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12347653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40806642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno L, Ibrahimi M, Gruppioni E, et al. Sockets for limb prostheses: a review of existing technologies and open challenges. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng 65 (2018): 1996&#x2013;2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29993506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xf6;ring K, Trost C, Hofer C, et al. How common are chronic residual limb pain, phantom pain, and back pain more than 20 years after lower limb amputation for malignant tumors? Clin Orthop Relat Res 479 (2021): 2036&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33739309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamessian A, Van de Ven T, Buchheit T, et al. Differential expression of systemic inflammatory mediators in amputees with chronic residual limb pain. Pain 158 (2017): 68&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5161626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27682210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pino G, Piombino V, Carassiti M, et al. Neurophysiological models of phantom limb pain: what can be learnt. Minerva Anestesiol 87 (2021): 481&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culp CJ, Abdi S. Current understanding of phantom pain and its treatment. Pain Physician 25 (2022): E941&#x2013;E957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therrien AS, Howard C, Buxbaum LJ. Aberrant activity in an intact residual muscle is associated with phantom limb pain in above-knee amputees. J Neurophysiol 125 (2021): 2135&#x2013;2143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33949884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolajsen L, Hansen CL, Nielsen J, et al. The effect of ketamine on phantom pain: a central neuropathic disorder maintained by peripheral input. Pain 67 (1996): 69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8895233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden RN, McCabe CS, Goebel A, et al. Complex Regional Pain Syndrome: Practical Diagnostic and Treatment Guidelines, 5th Edition. Pain Med 23 Suppl 1 (2022): S1&#x2013;S53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibu&#x142;a-Tar&#x142;owska E, Wiszniewska A, Turyk M, et al. Ketamine-From an Anesthetic to a Psychiatric Drug: Mechanisms of Action, Clinical Applications and Potential Risks. Molecules 30 (2025): 2824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12251107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40649336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson T, Whiter F, Gallop K, et al. NMDA receptor antagonists and pain relief: A meta-analysis of experimental trials. Neurology 92 (2019): e1652&#x2013;e1662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30842296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro MC, Cashin AG, Visser EJ, et al. Ketamine and other NMDA receptor antagonists for chronic pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 8 (2025): CD015373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu E, Cohen SP. Postamputation pain: epidemiology, mechanisms, and treatment. J Pain Res 6 (2013): 121&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23426608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahuja V, Thapa D, Ghai B. Strategies for prevention of lower limb post-amputation pain: A clinical narrative review. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol 34 (2018): 439&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30774224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne R Limitations of NSAIDs for pain management: toxicity or lack of efficacy? J Pain 1 Suppl 3 (2000): 14&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huse E, Larbig W, Flor H, et al. The effect of opioids on phantom limb pain and cortical reorganization. Pain 90 (2001): 47&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11166969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur A, Kapural L, Chiacchierini RP, et al. Post-Amputation Pain: Combined Analyses of Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating Opioids and Gabapentinoids versus Placebo. J Pain Res 17 (2024): 3449&#x2013;3453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11514656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39469333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone M, Critchley P, Buggy DJ. Gabapentin in postamputation phantom limb pain: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, cross-over study. Reg Anesth Pain Med 27 (2002): 481&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12373695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S, Zhou MM, Xia R, et al. Gabapentin for phantom limb pain after amputation in pediatric oncology: a systematic review protocol. Syst Rev 10 (2021): 26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7807458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33441185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subedi B, Grossberg GT. Phantom limb pain: mechanisms and treatment approaches. Pain Res Treat 2011. (2011): 864605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagoshi Y, Watanabe A, Inoue S, et al. Usefulness of milnacipran in treating phantom limb pain. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat 8 (2012): 549&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3506153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23185119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall N, Eldabe S. Phantom limb pain: a review of pharmacological management. Br J Pain 12 (2018): 202&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6194972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheesborough JE, Smith LH, Kuiken TA, et al. Targeted muscle reinnervation and advanced prosthetic arms. Semin Plast Surg 29 (2015): 62&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4317279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25685105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorklund KA, Alexander J, Tulchin-Francis K, et al. Targeted Muscle Reinnervation for Limb Amputation to Avoid Neuroma and Phantom Limb Pain in Patients Treated at a Pediatric Hospital. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 11 (2023): e4944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach GA, Dean RA, Kumar NG, et al. Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interface Surgery: Anatomic and Technical Guide. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 11 (2023): e5127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10351954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37465283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Yu P, Chen Z, et al. Regenerative peripheral nerve interface reduces the incidence of neuroma in the lower limbs after amputation: a retrospective study based on ultrasound. J Orthop Surg Res 18 (2023): 619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10463429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37620955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sehirlioglu A, Ozturk C, Yazicioglu K, et al. Painful neuroma requiring surgical excision after lower limb amputation caused by landmine explosions. Int Orthop 33 (2009): 533&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2899049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17940765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslow JI, LeMone A, Scarola GT, et al. Digital Nerve Management and Neuroma Prevention in Hand Amputations. Hand (N Y) 18 (2023): 838&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senger JB, Hardy P, Thorkelsson A, et al. A Direct Comparison of Targeted Muscle Reinnervation and Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interfaces to Prevent Neuroma Pain. Neurosurgery 93 (2023): 1180&#x2013;1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37265342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley J, van Gr&#xf6;ningen R, Green C. Spinal cord stimulation for intractable pain following limb amputation. Neuromodulation 16 (2013): 530&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23009132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbett M, South E, Harden M, et al. Brain and spinal stimulation therapies for phantom limb pain: a systematic review. Health Technol Assess 22 (2018): 1&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan N, Zhou B, Park E. Dorsal Root Ganglion Stimulation for the Management of Phantom Limb Pain: A Scoping Review. Pain Physician 25 (2022): E1174&#x2013;E1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36375184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Kim YY. Mirror therapy for phantom limb pain. Korean J Pain 25 (2012): 272&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3468806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23091690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falbo KJ, Phelan H, Hackman D, et al. Graded motor imagery and its phases for individuals with phantom limb pain following amputation: A scoping review. Clin Rehabil 38 (2024): 287&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10860367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37849299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu&#xe9;mann M, Oli&#xe9; E, Raquin L, et al. Effect of mirror therapy in the treatment of phantom limb pain in amputees: A systematic review of randomized placebo-controlled trials does not find any evidence of efficacy. Eur J Pain 27 (2023): 3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10086832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36094758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambron E, Miller A, Kuchenbecker KJ, et al. Immersive Low-Cost Virtual Reality Treatment for Phantom Limb Pain: Evidence from Two Cases. Front Neurol 9 (2018): 67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5825921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29515513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim NA, Abd Razak NA, Shanmuganathan T, et al. On the use of virtual reality for individuals with upper limb loss: a systematic scoping review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 58 (2022): 612&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9987328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35044131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevelyan EG, Turner WA, Robinson N. Acupuncture for the treatment of phantom limb pain in lower limb amputees: study protocol for a randomized controlled feasibility trial. Trials 16 (2015): 158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4405855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25873101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MI, Mulvey MR, Bagnall AM, et al. Transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) for phantom pain and stump pain following amputation in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 8 (2015): CD007264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne CE, Engelke MK, Schreier A, et al. Effects of tactile desensitization on postoperative pain after amputation surgery. J Perianesth Nurs 33 (2018): 689&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30236577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limakatso K, Parker R. Treatment recommendations for phantom limb pain in people with amputations: An expert consensus Delphi study. PM R 13 (2021): 1216&#x2013;1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8597012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura VL, Faurot KR, Gaylord SA, et al. Mind-body interventions for treatment of phantom limb pain in persons with amputation. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 91 (2012): 701&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6457458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22286895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oakley DA, Whitman LG, Halligan PW. Hypnotic imagery as a treatment for phantom limb pain: two case reports and a review. Clin Rehabil 16 (2002): 368&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12061470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan WB, Anderson G, Kovoor M, et al. Phantom limb syndrome: Assessment of psychiatric and medical comorbidities associated with phantom pain in 44,028 below knee amputees. Injury 53 (2022): 3697&#x2013;3701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36163201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jong R, Shysh AJ. Development of a multimodal analgesia protocol for perioperative acute pain management for lower limb amputation. Pain Res Manag 2018. (2018): 5237040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams ACC, Fisher E, Hearn L, et al. Psychological therapies for the management of chronic pain (excluding headache) in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 8 (2020): CD007407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosser BA, Fisher E, Janjua S, et al. Psychological therapies delivered remotely for the management of chronic pain (excluding headache) in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 8 (2023): CD013863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccleston C, Morley SJ, Williams AC. Psychological approaches to chronic pain management: evidence and challenges. Br J Anaesth 111 (2013): 59&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23794646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte MS, Bradbury AW, Kolh P, et al. Global vascular guidelines on the management of chronic limb-threatening ischemia. J Vasc Surg 69 (2019): 3S&#x2013;125S.e40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8365864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thibaut A, Beaudart C, Maertens DE, et al. Impact of microprocessor prosthetic knee on mobility and quality of life in patients with lower limb amputation: a systematic review of the literature. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 58 (2022): 452&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9987462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35148043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keszler MS, Heckman JT, Kaufman GE, et al. Advances in prosthetics and rehabilitation of individuals with limb loss. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 30 (2019): 423&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrini FM, Valle G, Bumbasirevic M, et al. Enhancing functional abilities and cognitive integration of the lower limb prosthesis. Sci Transl Med 11 (2019): eaav8939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herr HM, Clites TR, Srinivasan S, et al. Reinventing extremity amputation in the era of functional limb restoration. Ann Surg 273 (2021): 269&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhang H, Li Y, et al. Comparative effects of interventions on phantom limb pain: A network meta-analysis. World Neurosurg 167 (2022): e888&#x2013;e899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaheer A, Khan S, Malik R, et al. Effects of phantom exercises on pain, mobility, and quality of life among lower limb amputees: A randomized controlled trial. BMC Neurol 21 (2021): 424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier LV, Williams J, Rizzo JR, et al. Applying behavior change techniques to support client outcomes in outpatient neurorehabilitation: A clinicians guide. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 103 (2022): 1685&#x2013;1693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger H, Marincek C. Return to work after lower limb amputation. Disabil Rehabil 23 (2001): 508&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Sommer C, Rehm S, et al. Cortical binding potential of opioid receptors in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome and reduced systemic interleukin-4 levels: A pilot study. Front Neurosci 14 (2020): 512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raspopovic S, Valle G, Ortiz-Catalan M. Personalized prosthetics with sensory feedback for functional restoration. Nat Mater 20 (2021): 991&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33686277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicora G, Rossi D, Bianchi A, et al. Systematic review of AI/ML applications in multi-domain robotic rehabilitation: Trends, gaps, and future directions. J Neuroeng Rehabil 22 (2025): 116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12103758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40414904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostler C Meaningful outcome measurement following lower limb prosthetic rehabilitation. PhD Thesis. University of Southampton, School of Health Science, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>