<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41306561</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1053-5888</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IEEE signal processing magazine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IEEE Signal Process Mag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Domain-Randomized Deep Learning for Neuroimage Analysis: Selecting Training Strategies, Navigating Challenges, and Maximizing Benefits.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>78</StartPage><EndPage>90</EndPage><MedlinePgn>78-90</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/MSP.2025.3590806</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Deep learning has revolutionized neuroimage analysis by delivering unprecedented speed and accuracy. However, the narrow scope of many training datasets constrains model robustness and generalizability. This challenge is particularly acute in magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), where image appearance varies widely across pulse sequences and scanner hardware. A recent domain-randomization strategy addresses the generalization problem by training deep neural networks on synthetic images with randomized intensities and anatomical content. By generating diverse data from anatomical segmentation maps, the approach enables models to accurately process image types unseen during training, without retraining or fine-tuning. It has demonstrated effectiveness across modalities including MRI, computed tomography, positron emission tomography, and optical coherence tomography, as well as beyond neuroimaging in ultrasound, electron and fluorescence microscopy, and X-ray microtomography. This tutorial paper reviews the principles, implementation, and potential of the synthesis-driven training paradigm. It highlights key benefits, such as improved generalization and resistance to overfitting, while discussing trade-offs such as increased computational demands. Finally, the article explores practical considerations for adopting the technique, aiming to accelerate the development of generalizable tools that make deep learning more accessible to domain experts without extensive computational resources or machine learning knowledge.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffmann</LastName><ForeName>Malte</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Athinoula A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging and the Departments of Radiology at Harvard Medical School and Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 EB033773</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD109436</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 CA255479</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P41 EB030006</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD099846</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG064027</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U24 NS135561</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R00 HD101553</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>IEEE Signal Process Mag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101212681</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-5888</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">domain generalization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">domain randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical image analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroimaging</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41306561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2098107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12646568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MSP.2025.3590806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fischl Bruce, &#x201c;FreeSurfer,&#x201d; NeuroImage, vol. 62, no. 2, pp. 774&#x2013;781, 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3685476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone Ian B, Cash David, Ridgway Gerard R, MacManus David G, Ourselin Sebastien, Fox Nick C, and Schott Jonathan M, &#x201c;MIRIAD&#x2014;public release of a multiple time point Alzheimer&#x2019;s MR imaging dataset,&#x201d; NeuroImage, vol. 70, pp. 33&#x2013;36, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3809512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23274184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althnian Alhanoof, AlSaeed Duaa, Al-Baity Heyam, Samha Amani, Dris Alanoud Bin, Alzakari Najla, Elwafa Afnan Abou, et al. , &#x201c;Impact of dataset size on classification performance: an empirical evaluation in the medical domain,&#x201d; Applied Sciences, vol. 11, no. 2, pp. 796, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Kaiyang, Liu Ziwei, Qiao Yu, Xiang Tao, et al. , &#x201c;Domain generalization: a survey,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 45, no. 4, pp. 4396&#x2013;4415, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath Karthik, Hoopes Andrew, Alexander Daniel C, et al. , &#x201c;Synthetic data in generalizable, learning-based neuroimaging,&#x201d; Imaging Neuroscience, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells William M, Grimson W Eric L, Kikinis Ron, and Jolesz Ferenc A, &#x201c;Adaptive segmentation of MRI data,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 15, no. 4, pp. 429&#x2013;442, 1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18215925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Leemput Koen, Maes Frederik, Vandermeulen Dirk, et al. , &#x201c;A unifying framework for partial volume segmentation of brain MR images,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 22, no. 1, pp. 105&#x2013;119, 2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ckert Daniel, Sonoda Luke I, Hayes Carmel, Hill Derek LG, Leach Martin O, and Hawkes David J, &#x201c;Nonrigid registration using free-form deformations: application to breast MR images,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 18, no. 8, pp. 712&#x2013;721, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10534053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csurka Gabriela, &#x201c;Domain adaptation for visual applications: a comprehensive survey,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:1702.05374, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Mei and Deng Weihong, &#x201c;Deep visual domain adaptation: A survey,&#x201d; Neurocomputing, vol. 312, pp. 135&#x2013;153, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson W Evan, Li Cheng, and Rabinovic Ariel, &#x201c;Adjusting batch effects in microarray expression data using empirical bayes methods,&#x201d; Biostatistics, vol. 8, no. 1, pp. 118&#x2013;127, 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gretton Arthur, Smola Alex, Huang Jiayuan, Schmittfull Marcel, et al. , &#x201c;Covariate shift by kernel mean matching,&#x201d; Dataset shift in machine learning, vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 5, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Baochen, Feng Jiashi, and Saenko Kate, &#x201c;Correlation alignment for unsupervised domain adaptation,&#x201d; Domain adaptation in computer vision applications, pp. 153&#x2013;171, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Zhaoqing, Yu Weijie, Yi Xiaokai, Khan Asifullah, Yuan Feng, et al. , &#x201c;Recent progress on generative adversarial networks (GANs): a survey,&#x201d; IEEE Access, vol. 7, pp. 36322&#x2013;36333, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzeng Eric, Hoffman Judy, Saenko Kate, and Darrell Trevor, &#x201c;Adversarial discriminative domain adaptation,&#x201d; in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2017, pp. 7167&#x2013;7176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorten Connor and Khoshgoftaar Taghi M, &#x201c;A survey on image data augmentation for deep learning,&#x201d; Journal of Big Data, vol. 6, no. 1, pp. 1&#x2013;48, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Franzes Gustav, Niehues Jan Moritz, Khader Firas, Arasteh Soroosh Tayebi, Haarburger Christoph, Kuhl Christiane, Wang Tianci, Han Tianyu, Nolte Teresa, Nebelung Sven, et al. , &#x201c;A multimodal comparison of latent denoising diffusion probabilistic models and generative adversarial networks for medical image synthesis,&#x201d; Scientific Reports, vol. 13, no. 1, pp. 12098, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10372018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37495660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias Juan Eugenio, &#x201c;A ready-to-use machine learning tool for symmetric multi-modality registration of brain MRI,&#x201d; Scientific Reports, vol. 13, no. 1, pp. 6657, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann Malte, Hoopes Andrew, Greve Douglas N, Fischl Bruce, and Dalca Adrian V, &#x201c;Anatomy-aware and acquisition-agnostic joint registration with SynthMorph,&#x201d; Imaging Neuroscience, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Jingru, Dalca Adrian V, Fischl Bruce, Moreno Rodrigo, and Hoffmann Malte, &#x201c;Learning accurate rigid registration for longitudinal brain MRI from synthetic data,&#x201d; in IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging. IEEE, 2025, pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billot Benjamin, Greve Douglas N, Puonti Oula, Thielscher Axel, Van Leemput Koen, Fischl Bruce, Dalca Adrian V, et al. , &#x201c;SynthSeg: Segmentation of brain MRI scans of any contrast and resolution without retraining,&#x201d; Medical Image Analysis, vol. 86, pp. 102789, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10154424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrickson Timothy J, Reiners Paul, Moore Lucille A, Lundquist Jacob T, Fayzullobekova Begim, Perrone Anders J, Lee Erik G, Moser Julia, Day Trevor KM, et al. , &#x201c;BIBSNet: A deep learning baby image brain segmentation network for MRI scans,&#x201d; bioRxiv, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalevskyi Vladyslav, Sanchez Thomas, Roulet Margaux, Verdera Jordina Aviles, Hutter Jana, Kebiri Hamza, and Cuadra Meritxell Bach, &#x201c;Improving cross-domain brain tissue segmentation in fetal MRI with synthetic data,&#x201d; in Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention. Springer, 2024, pp. 437&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laso Pablo, Cerri Stefano, Sorby-Adams Annabel, et al. , &#x201c;Quantifying white matter hyperintensity and brain volumes in heterogeneous clinical and low-field portable MRI,&#x201d; in IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging. IEEE, 2024, pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chollet Etienne, Balbastre Ya&#xeb;l, Mauri Chiara, et al. , &#x201c;Neurovascular segmentation in sOCT with deep learning and synthetic training data,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.01419, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoopes Andrew, Mora Jocelyn S, Dalca Adrian V, et al. , &#x201c;SynthStrip: skull-stripping for any brain image,&#x201d; NeuroImage, vol. 260, pp. 119474, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley William, Ngo Nathan, Dalca Adrian V., Fischl Bruce, Z&#xf6;llei Lilla, and Hoffmann Malte, &#x201c;Boosting skull-stripping performance for pediatric brain images,&#x201d; in IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging. IEEE, 2024, pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann Malte, Billot Benjamin, Greve Douglas N, Iglesias Juan Eugenio, Fischl Bruce, and Dalca Adrian V, &#x201c;SynthMorph: learning contrast-invariant registration without acquired images,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 41, no. 3, pp. 543&#x2013;558, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey Neel, Abulnaga Mazdak, Billot, et al. , &#x201c;AnyStar: domain randomized universal star-convex 3D instance segmentation,&#x201d; in IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision, 2024, pp. 7593&#x2013;7603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann Malte, Hoopes Andrew, Fischl Bruce, and Dalca Adrian V, &#x201c;Anatomy-specific acquisition-agnostic affine registration learned from fictitious images,&#x201d; in Medical Imaging 2023: Image Processing. SPIE, 2023, vol. 12464, p. 1246402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey Neel, Billot Benjamin, Wong Hallee E., Wang Clinton, Ren Mengwei, Grant Ellen, et al. , &#x201c;Learning general-purpose biomedical volume representations using randomized synthesis,&#x201d; in International Conference on Learning Representations, 2025, pp. 1&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias Juan Eugenio, Billot Benjamin, Balbastre Ya&#xeb;l, Tabari Azadeh, Conklin John, Gonz&#xe1;lez R Gilberto, Alexander Daniel C, Golland Polina, Edlow Brian L, Fischl Bruce, et al. , &#x201c;Joint super-resolution and synthesis of 1 mm isotropic MP-RAGE volumes from clinical MRI exams with scans of different orientation, resolution and contrast,&#x201d; NeuroImage, vol. 237, pp. 118206, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlin Ken, &#x201c;An image synthesizer,&#x201d; ACM Siggraph Computer Graphics, vol. 19, no. 3, pp. 287&#x2013;296, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arsigny Vincent, Commowick Olivier, Pennec Xavier, and Ayache Nicholas, &#x201c;A log-euclidean framework for statistics on diffeomorphisms,&#x201d; in Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention. Springer, 2006, pp. 924&#x2013;931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sled John G, Zijdenbos Alex P, and Evans Alan C, &#x201c;A nonparametric method for automatic correction of intensity nonuniformity in MRI data,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 87&#x2013;97, 1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9617910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abukmeil Mohanad, Ferrari Stefano, Genovese Angelo, Piuri Vincenzo, and Scotti Fabio, &#x201c;A survey of unsupervised generative models for exploratory data analysis and representation learning,&#x201d; Acm Computing Surveys, vol. 54, no. 5, pp. 1&#x2013;40, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Zhijian, Wen Junhao, Erus Guray, et al. , &#x201c;Identifying five dominant dimensions of neurodegeneration in brain aging through deep learning: correlations with clinical and genetic measures,&#x201d; in Alzheimer&#x2019;s Association International Conference. ALZ, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakrishnan Guha, Zhao Amy, Sabuncu Mert R, Guttag John, and Dalca Adrian V, &#x201c;Voxelmorph: a learning framework for deformable medical image registration,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 38, no. 8, pp. 1788&#x2013;1800, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doan Mike and Plis Sergey, &#x201c;Scaling synthetic brain data generation,&#x201d; IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Xiaoling, Puonti Oula, Iglesias Juan Eugenio, Fischl Bruce, and Balbastre Yael, &#x201c;Learn2Synth: learning optimal data synthesis using hypergradients,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2411.16719, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>