<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41803198</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI-driven fault detection and classification in photovoltaic systems using deep learning techniques.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8727</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40246-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The growing needs of the world regarding electricity and the exhaustion of fossil fuel resources have aggravated the need to use renewable energy, especially the photovoltaic (PV) systems. Nevertheless, internal defects and external environmental conditions are often known to affect the operational efficiency and reliability of PV modules. This paper presents PVDefectNet, a deep learning-based fault detector and classifier of the PV systems. The proposed solution applies a resnet architecture with data augmentation techniques to enhance its resistance to operating in different operating environments. PVDefectNet is a process based on five stages that include data preparation and preprocessing, model architecture design, training, evaluation and visualization, and performance analysis. The experimental findings indicate that the proposed framework has a high classification performance with an average accuracy of 98, precision of 97.1, recall of 96.5 and F1-score of 96.8 that is better than some of the current methods. Moreover, the visualizations provided by Grad-CAM prove that the model is concentrated on physically significant defect areas, which increases interpretability and reliability. These results suggest that PVDefectNet is a good and clear solution in intelligent monitoring and maintenance of PV systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talaat</LastName><ForeName>Fatma M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Artificial Intelligence, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafrelsheikh, 33516, Egypt. fatma.nada@ai.kfs.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salem</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Artificial Intelligence, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafrelsheikh, 33516, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaban</LastName><ForeName>Warda M</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Communication and Electronics Engineering Department, Nile Higher Institute for Engineering and Technology, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI in solar power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fault detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photovoltaic systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics statement: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals performed by any of the authors. All methods were performed in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41803198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12979695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40246-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40246-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gielen, D. et al. Global energy transformation: a roadmap to 2050. https://www.h2knowledgecentre.com/content/researchpaper1605 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. IEA, https://www.iea.org/, [<b>last access 16 July 2024</b>].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain Nengroo, S. et al. An optimized methodology for a hybrid Photo-Voltaic and energy storage system connected to a Low-Voltage grid. <i>Electronics</i><b>8</b>, 176. 10.3390/electronics8020176 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics8020176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran, S., Uthra, R. A. &amp; Preetharoselyn, J. Deep Learning-Based model for defect detection and localization on photovoltaic panels. <i>Comput. Syst. Sci. Eng.</i><b>44</b> (3). 10.32604/csse.2023.028898 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, S. et al. A breakthrough in Penta-Hybrid nanofluid flow modeling for heat transfer enhancement in a spatially dependent magnetic field: machine learning approach. <i>Int. J. Thermophys.</i><b>46</b>, 2. 10.1007/s10765-024-03467-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10765-024-03467-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, B. et al. Machine learning applications in health monitoring of renewable energy systems. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>189</b>, 114039 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, M. &amp; Khanam, R. In-Depth review of YOLOv1 to YOLOv10 variants for enhanced photovoltaic defect detection. <i>Solar</i><b>4</b>, 351&#x2013;386. 10.3390/solar4030016 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/solar4030016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dada, M. &amp; Popoola, P. Recent advances in solar photovoltaic materials and systems for energy storage applications: a review. <i>Beni-Suef Univ. J. Basic. Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 66. 10.1186/s43088-023-00405-5 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43088-023-00405-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, N. C. &amp; Ismail, H. Voting-Based ensemble learning algorithm for fault detection in photovoltaic systems under different weather conditions. <i>Mathematics</i><b>10</b>, 285. 10.3390/math10020285 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10020285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero, H. et al. Applications of Artificial Intelligence to Photovoltaic Systems: A Review. Applied Sciences, Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute (MDPI). <b>12</b>(19), 10.3390/app121910056 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roumpakias, E. &amp; Stamatelos, T. H. Monitoring and fault detection in photovoltaic systems in central Greece using artificial neural networks. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 12016. 10.3390/app122312016 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app122312016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ar&#xe9;valo, P., Cano, A., Benavides, D. &amp; Jurado, F. Fault analysis in clustered microgrids utilizing SVM-CNN and differential protection. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>164</b>, 112031. 10.1016/j.asoc.2024.112031 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2024.112031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seghiour, A., Abbas, H. A., Chouder, A. &amp; Rabhi, A. Deep learning method based on autoencoder neural network applied to faults detection and diagnosis of photovoltaic system. <i>Simul. Model. Pract. Theory</i>. <b>123</b>, 102704. 10.1016/j.simpat.2022.102704 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.simpat.2022.102704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, W., Yang, Q., Dai, Z. &amp; Yan, W. Module defect detection and diagnosis for intelligent maintenance of solar photovoltaic plants: Techniques, systems and perspectives. <i>Energy</i>, <b>297</b> 131222.10.1016/j.energy.2024.131222 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>halivendula, S. R. &amp; Tarigonda, H. Recent advances in organic phase change materials for thermal energy storage: A review on sustainable development applications. <i>Int. J. Thermophys.</i><b>46</b>, 88. 10.1007/s10765-025-03559-9 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10765-025-03559-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, F. et al. A novel framework on intelligent detection for module defects of PV plant combining the visible and infrared images. <i>Sol. Energy</i>. <b>236</b>, 406&#x2013;416. 10.1016/j.solener.2022.03.018 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2022.03.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X., Song, C., Zhang, H., Sun, X. &amp; Zhao, J. HRNet-based automatic identification of photovoltaic module defects using electroluminescence images. <i>Energy</i><b>267</b>, 126605. 10.1016/j.energy.2022.126605 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.126605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Et-taleby, A., Chaibi, Y., Boussetta, M., Allouhi, A. &amp; Benslimane, M. A novel fault detection technique for PV systems based on the K-means algorithm, coded wireless orthogonal frequency division multiplexing and thermal image processing techniques. <i>Sol. Energy</i>. <b>237</b>, 365&#x2013;376. 10.1016/j.solener.2022.04.017 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2022.04.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazen, M. A., Seoud, R. A. A. &amp; Shaker, Y. O. Deep learning for automatic defect detection in PV modules using electroluminescence Images, in IEEE access, <b>11</b>, pp. 57783&#x2013;57795, (2023). 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3284043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail, A. et al. Fault detection and computation of power in PV cells under faulty conditions using deep-learning. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>9</b>, 4325&#x2013;4336. 10.1016/j.egyr.2023.03.094 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2023.03.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duranay, Z. B. Fault detection in solar energy systems: A deep learning approach. <i>Electronics</i><b>12</b>, 4397. 10.3390/electronics12214397 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics12214397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaybhaye, S. et al. Classification and early detection of solar panel faults with deep neural network using aerial and electroluminescence images. <i>J. Fail. Anal. Preven</i>. <b>24</b>, 1746&#x2013;1758. 10.1007/s11668-024-01959-x (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11668-024-01959-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaban, W. M. Detection and classification of photovoltaic module defects based on artificial intelligence. <i>Neural Comput. Applic</i>. <b>36</b>, 16769&#x2013;16796. 10.1007/s00521-024-10000-z (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-024-10000-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GitHub. https://github.com/zae-bayern/elpv-dataset , (<b>Last accessed on 20 June 2024</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz, C. et al. A Benchmark for Visual Identification of Defective Solar Cells in Electroluminescence Imagery. In <i>Proceedings of the European PV Solar Energy Conference and Exhibition (EU PVSEC)</i>, Brussels, Belgium, PP. 24&#x2013;28. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voutsinas, S., Karolidis, D., Voyiatzis, I. &amp; Samarakou, M. Development of a machine-learning-based method for early fault detection in photovoltaic systems. <i>J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>70</b>, 1&#x2013;17. 10.1186/s44147-023-00200-0 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44147-023-00200-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaban, W. M., Kabeel, A. E., Attia, M. E. H. &amp; Talaat, F. M. Optimizing photovoltaic thermal solar systems efficiency through advanced artificial intelligence driven thermal management techniques. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>247</b>, 123029. 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123029 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.123029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, W. &amp; Wai, R. J. A novel fault identification method for photovoltaic array via convolutional neural network and residual gated recurrent Unit, in IEEE access, <b>8</b>, pp. 159493&#x2013;159510, (2020). 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3020296</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, M. S., Gharghory, S. M. &amp; Kamal, H. A. A hybrid model of CNN and LSTM autoencoder-based short-term PV power generation forecasting. <i>Electr. Eng.</i><b>106</b> (4), 4239&#x2013;4255. 10.1007/s00202-023-02220-8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00202-023-02220-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel Samee, N. et al. Metaheuristic optimization through deep learning classification of COVID-19 in chest X-ray images. <i>Computers Mater. Continua</i>. <b>73</b> (2), 4193&#x2013;4210. 10.32604/cmc.2022.031147 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/cmc.2022.031147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodadadi, N. et al. Data-driven PSO-CatBoost machine learning model to predict the compressive strength of CFRP-confined circular concrete specimens. <i>Thin-Walled Struct.</i><b>198</b>, 111763. 10.1016/j.tws.2024.111763 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tws.2024.111763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kenawy, E. S. M. et al. Optimized ensemble algorithm for predicting metamaterial antenna parameters. <i>Computers Mater. Continua</i>. <b>71</b> (3), 4989&#x2013;5003. 10.32604/cmc.2022.023884 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/cmc.2022.023884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkenawy, E. S. M. et al. Greylag Goose optimization and multilayer perceptron for enhancing lung cancer classification. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 23784. 10.1038/s41598-024-72013-x (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-72013-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39390014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouali, Y. et al. Optimization of proton exchange membrane fuel cell design parameters using tianji&#x2019;s horse racing optimization. <i>Sci. Rep.</i>10.1038/s41598-026-35200-6 (2026).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35200-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12876966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41519869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>