<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41885792</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute and Long-Term Effects of Spinning-Based High-Intensity Interval Training on Inducible Nitric Oxide Synthase: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005464</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Uysal, A and Soslu, R. Acute and long-term effects of spinning-based high-intensity interval training on inducible nitric oxide synthase: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-This study investigated the acute and long-term effects of a 6-week high-intensity interval training (HIIT) spinning program on oxidative stress and inflammatory biomarkers, including inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS), in physically active male university students. Subjects were randomly assigned to an experimental group (n = 10), which completed the supervised HIIT intervention, and a control group (n = 10), which maintained their habitual physical activity. Acute physiological stress was elicited using the 30-15 Intermittent Fitness Test (30-15 IFT), and venous blood samples were collected immediately before and after the 30-15 IFT, both before and after the intervention. Analyses included total antioxidant capacity, total oxidant capacity, oxidative stress index, paraoxonase 1, arylesterase, and iNOS. The acute exercise (30-15 IFT) performed did not lead to significant changes in biochemical parameters in either group. Long-term spinning-based HIIT resulted in significant increases in resting pretest values in the experimental group, with total antioxidant capacity significantly increased (p &lt; 0.001), suggesting enhanced endogenous antioxidant defense. This was accompanied by a significant increase in total oxidant capacity (p &lt; 0.007) and oxidative stress index (p &lt; 0.032), indicating elevated oxidative load and systemic redox imbalance. A marked increase in paraoxonase 1 activity (p &lt; 0.001) further reflected adaptive upregulation of antioxidant enzyme systems. However, no significant changes were detected in arylesterase activity or iNOS levels. In conclusion, the findings indicate that spinning-based HIIT elicits selective biochemical responses, particularly enhancing antioxidant status, while inflammatory and enzymatic responses may require higher exercise volume or prolonged exposure to manifest.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uysal</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9234-1176</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey University, Karaman, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soslu</LastName><ForeName>Recep</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3751-063</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular response to training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nitric oxide pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">redox balance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41885792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Afzalpour ME, Gharakhanlou R, Gaeini AA, Mohebbi H, Hedayati M, Khazaei M. The effects of aerobic exercises on the serum oxidized ldl and total antioxidant capacity in non-active men. Glob Heart 3: 77&#x2013;82, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anitha TS, Srikanth K, Suganya S, Muthukumar S, A comparative clinical study on the generation of nitrosative stress in cataractous lenses of smokers and non-smoker tobacco patients. Eur J Ophthalmol 29: 178&#x2013;182, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berzosa C, Cebrian I, Fuentes-Broto L, et al. Acute exercise increases plasma total antioxidant status and antioxidant enzyme activities in untrained men. J Biomed Biotechnol 2011: 540458, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boa BC, Souza MD, Leite RD, et al. Chronic aerobic exercise associated to dietary modification improve endothelial function and eNOS expression in high fat fed hamsters. PLoS One 9: e102554, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Stavrinou P, Fatouros IG, et al. Short-term high-intensity interval exercise training attenuates oxidative stress responses and improves antioxidant status in healthy humans. Food Chem Toxicol 61: 171&#x2013;177, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga VA, Couto GK, Lazzarin MC, Rossoni LV, Medeiros A. Aerobic exercise training prevents the onset of endothelial dysfunction via increased nitric oxide bioavailability and reduced reactive oxygen species in an experimental model of menopause. PLoS One 10: e0125388, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Dikmen U, Vassallo C. The 30-15 &#x131;ntermittent fitness test&#x2014;two decades of learnings. Sport Perform Sci Rep 1: 1&#x2013;13, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casella-Filho A, Chagas ACP, Maranh&#xe3;o RC, et al. Effect of exercise training on plasma levels and functional properties of high-density lipoprotein cholesterol in the metabolic syndrome. Am J Cardiol 107: 1168&#x2013;1172, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Massimo C, Scarpelli P, Penco M, Tozzi-Ciancarelli MG. Possible involvement of plasma antioxidant defences in training-associated decrease of platelet responsiveness in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 406&#x2013;412, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Abed K, Rebai H, Bloomer RJ, et al. Antioxidant status and oxidative stress at rest and in response to acute exercise in judokas and sedentary men. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2400&#x2013;2409, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etgen GJ, Fryburg DA, Gibbs EM. Nitric oxide stimulates skeletal muscle glucose transport through a calcium/contraction&#x2013;and phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase&#x2013;independent pathway. Diabetes 46: 1915&#x2013;1919, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;rstermann U, Sessa WC. Nitric oxide synthases: Regulation and function. Eur Heart J 33: 829&#x2013;837, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharakhanlou R, Afzalpour ME, Gaeini AA, Rahnama N. Effects of aerobic exercises on the serum paraoxonase 1/arylesterase activity and lipid profile in non-active healthy men. Int J Sports Sci Eng 1: 105&#x2013;112, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gielen S, Adams V, Linke A, et al. Exercise training in chronic heart failure: Correlation between reduced local inflammation and improved oxidative capacity in the skeletal muscle. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil 12: 393&#x2013;400, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golbidi S, Laher I. Exercise and the aging endothelium. J Diabetes Res 2013: 789607, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhammer E, Ben-Sira D, Zaid G, et al. Paraoxonase activity following exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation program. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev 27: 151&#x2013;154, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamurcu Z, Saritas N, Baskol G, Akpinar N. Effect of wrestling exercise on oxidative dna damage, nitric oxide level and paraoxonase activity in adolescent boys. Pediatr Exerc Sci 22: 60&#x2013;68, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris MB, Mitchell BM, Sood SG, Webb RC, Venema RC. Increased nitric oxide synthase activity and hsp90 association in skeletal muscle following chronic exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 104: 795&#x2013;802, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes N, Fogarty M, Sadofsky L, Jones HS. Physiologically-obtainable polyphenol exposures modulate reactive oxygen and nitrogen species signaling in the C2C12 model of skeletal muscle ageing. Eur J Pharmacol 941: 175511, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ipekoglu G, Baynaz K, Mor A, Acar K, Arslano&#x11f;lu C, Arslano&#x11f;lu E. Examining lactate changes during high &#x131;ntensity spinning training. Univers J Educ Res 6: 1260&#x2013;1263, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Chaloupka EC, Mastrangelo MA, Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, O'Connor E. Metabolic and perceptual responses during spinning cycle exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 853&#x2013;859, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojda G, Hambrecht R. Molecular mechanisms of vascular adaptations to exercise. Physical activity as an effective antioxidant therapy? Cardiovasc Res 67: 187&#x2013;197, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurowski M, Seys S, Bonini M, et al. Physical exercise, immune response, and susceptibility to infections-current knowledge and growing research areas. Allergy 77: 2653&#x2013;2664, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin KA, Macneil RG, Dirain M, Sandesara B, Manini TM, Buford TW. Blood flow restriction enhances post-resistance exercise angiogenic gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 2077&#x2013;2083, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llanos P, Palomero J. Reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RONS) and cytokines myokines involved in glucose uptake and insulin resistance in skeletal muscle. Cells 11: 4008, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Wiltshire HD, Baker JS, Wang Q. Effects of high &#x131;ntensity exercise on oxidative stress and antioxidant status in untrained humans: A systematic review. Biology 10: 1272, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdirejei TA, Razi M, Barari A, et al. A comparative study of the effects of endurance and resistance exercise training on PON1 and lipid profile levels in obese men. Sport Sci Health 11: 263&#x2013;270, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x142;kowska P, Sawczuk M. Cytokines as biomarkers for evaluating physical exercise in trained and non-trained individuals: A narrative review. Int J Mol Sci 24: 11156, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed MK, Zuckerbraun BS. Nitric Oxide in Human Physiology. Carbon Monoxide in Drug Discovery. Hoboken: Wiley, 2022. pp. 136&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourad M, Aly O, Mourad A. Nitric oxide: Synthesis, pathophysiology and application on oncology and cardiovascular diseases. Octahedron Drug Res 10: 34&#x2013;49, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins AL, van Rosendal SP, Briskey DR, Fassett RG, Wilson GR, Coombes JS. Variability in oxidative stress biomarkers following a maximal exercise test. Biomarkers 18: 446&#x2013;454, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niess AM, Sommer M, Schlotz E, Northoff H, Dickhuth HH, Fehrenbach E. Expression of the inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) in human leukocytes: Responses to running exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 1220&#x2013;1225, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes-Silva A, Freitas-Lima LC, The association between physical exercise and reactive oxygen species (ROS) production. J Sports Med Doping Stud 5: 1&#x2013;7, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohri P, Bhardwaj R, Kaur R, et al. Nitric Oxide in Plant Biology. Amsterdam, the Netherlands: Elsevier, 169&#x2013;196, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oral O. Nitric oxide and its role in exercise physiology. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 61: 1208&#x2013;1211, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostapiuk-Karolczuk J, Zembron-Lacny A, Naczk M, et al. Cytokines and cellular inflammatory sequence in non-athletes after prolonged exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 52: 563&#x2013;568, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otocka-Kmiecik A, Lewandowski M, Stolarek R, Szkudlarek U, Nowak D, Orlowska-Majdak M. Effect of single bout of maximal excercise on plasma antioxidant status and paraoxonase activity in young sportsmen. Redox Rep 15: 275&#x2013;281, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pautz A, Art J, Hahn S, Nowag S, Voss C, Kleinert H. Regulation of the expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase. Nitric Oxide 23: 75&#x2013;93, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigamonti E, Touvier T, Clementi E, Manfredi AA, Brunelli S, Rovere-Querini P. Requirement of inducible nitric oxide synthase for skeletal muscle regeneration after acute damage. J Immunol 190: 1767&#x2013;1777, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouder JN, Morey RD, Speckman PL, Province JM. Default bayes factors for ANOVA designs. J Math Psychol 56: 356&#x2013;374, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruta B, Otocka-Kmiecik A, Nowak D, Kujawa J. Antiatherosclerotic effect of exercise on the antioxidant properties of paraoxonase&#x2014;a preliminary examination. Polish Ann Med 19: 84&#x2013;88, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D; CONSORT Group. CONSORT 2010 statement: Updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomized trials. Ann Intern Med 152: 726&#x2013;732, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi S, Dikshit M. Modulation of polymorphonuclear leukocytes function by nitric oxide. Thromb Res 100: 223&#x2013;247, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi S, Singh MP, Dikshit M. Nitric oxide-mediated augmentation of polymorphonuclear free radical generation after hypoxia-reoxygenation. Blood 93: 333&#x2013;340, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JF, Correa IC, Diniz TF, et al. Obesity, &#x131;nflammation, and exercise training: Relative contribution of iNOS and eNOS in the modulation of vascular function in the mouse aorta. Front Physiol 7: 386, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W, Kwak HB, Kim JH, Lawler JM. Exercise training modulates the nitric oxide synthase profile in skeletal muscle from old rats. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 64: 540&#x2013;549, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soslu R, &#xd6;zer &#xd6;, Uysal A, Pamuk &#xd6;. Deaf and non-deaf basketball and volleyball players' multi-faceted difference on repeated counter movement jump performances: Height, force and acceleration. Front Sports Act Living 4: 941629, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soylu Karapinar O, Pinar N, &#xd6;zcan O, &#xd6;zg&#xfc;r T, Dolap&#xe7;&#x131;o&#x11f;lu K. Protective effect of alpha-lipoic acid in methotrexate-induced ovarian oxidative injury and decreased ovarian reserve in rats. Gynecol Endocrinol 33: 653&#x2013;659, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stankovi&#x107; M, Gu&#x161;i&#x107; M, Nikoli&#x107; S, et al. 30&#x2013;15 intermittent fitness test: A systematic review of studies, examining the VO2max estimation and training programming. Appl Sci 11: 11792, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tom&#xe1;s M, Elosua R, Sent&#xed; M, et al. Paraoxonase1-192 polymorphism modulates the effects of regular and acute exercise on paraoxonase1 activity. J Lipid Res 43: 713&#x2013;720, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsakiris S, Karikas GA, Parthimos T, Tsakiris T, Bakogiannis C, Schulpis KH. Alpha-tocophrol supplementation prevents the exercise-induced reduction of serum paraoxonase 1/arylesterase activities in healthy individuals. Eur J Clin Nutr 63: 215&#x2013;221, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker PS, Briskey DR, Scanlan AT, Coombes JS, Dalbo VJ. High intensity interval training favourably affects antioxidant and inflammation mRNA expression in early-stage chronic kidney disease. Free Radic Biol Med 89: 466&#x2013;472, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagenmakers EJ, Marsman M, Jamil T, et al. Bayesian inference for psychology. Part I: Theoretical advantages and practical ramifications. Psychon Bull Rev 25: 35&#x2013;57, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo J. Exercise and function of nitric oxide. J Tour Sports Res 1: 55&#x2013;64, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulfahmidah Z, Safei I. The role of reactive oxygen species in muscle: Benefcial/harmful. Green Med J 4: 84&#x2013;92, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>