<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41493989</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-3375</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLOS global public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLOS Glob Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers and facilitators to antibiotic stewardship in Nigeria's private healthcare sector: A qualitative interview study with national health and regulatory interest holders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0005731</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0005731</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0005731</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005731</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) poses a growing global health concern, particularly in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) such as Nigeria, where stewardship efforts have largely overlooked the private healthcare sector. Given that most Nigerians seek care from private providers, understanding the barriers and opportunities for implementing antibiotic stewardship programs in this setting is critical. We conducted a qualitative study consisting of semi-structured interviews with 14 interest holders from national health and regulatory organizations in Nigeria. Participants were purposively selected for their expertise and leadership roles related to antibiotic use and regulation in Nigeria, ensuring representation from professional associations, federal agencies, and technical bodies. Interviews were conducted virtually between August and December 2024, transcribed verbatim, and thematically analyzed using Braun and Clarke's six-step framework. Codes were grouped into four thematic domains reflecting the roles of key actors (private sector, practitioners, government and health systems, and patients), and mapped to the Social-Ecological Model (SEM) to reflect individual, organizational, and policy-level influences. Participants identified multiple barriers to stewardship implementation in the private sector, including inconsistent prescribing practices, limited access to diagnostics, weak regulatory enforcement, and knowledge gaps among practitioners and patients. System-level constraints such as workforce shortages and fragmented AMR surveillance infrastructure were also cited. However, participants did highlight several facilitators, including licensing-linked training requirements, institutional partnerships, and openness within the private sector to adopt stewardship initiatives. Recommended strategies included standardized training programs, development of prescribing guidelines and protocols, performance-based incentives, and community-based public awareness campaigns. This study underscores the urgent need for targeted, context-sensitive stewardship strategies tailored to Nigeria's private healthcare sector. Engagement with interest holders revealed both systemic challenges and actionable opportunities to strengthen antibiotic stewardship and support broader AMR control efforts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Mahdi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahdi</LastName><ForeName>Aaya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ngassa Detchaptche</LastName><ForeName>Sarah Pascale</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klinton</LastName><ForeName>Joel Shyam</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, School of Public Health Sciences, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eriobu</LastName><ForeName>Nnakelu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Centre of Excellence (IRCE), Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uche</LastName><ForeName>Blessing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-4133-4965</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Centre of Excellence (IRCE), Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maredia</LastName><ForeName>Nawal</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5928-3717</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oga-Omenka</LastName><ForeName>Charity</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, School of Public Health Sciences, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Centre of Excellence (IRCE), Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sulis</LastName><ForeName>Giorgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6641-0094</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Centre of Excellence (IRCE), Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodological and Implementation Research Program, Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLOS Glob Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918283779606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-3375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>I have read the journal&#x2019;s policy and the authors of this manuscript have the following competing interests: GS serves as Academic Editor for PLOS Global Public Health. All other authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41493989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12774337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PGPH-D-25-02175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global action plan on antimicrobial resistance. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2015. https://www.amcra.be/swfiles/files/WHO%20actieplan_90.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26242647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antimicrobial Resistance Collaborators. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in 2019: a systematic analysis. Lancet. 2022;399(10325):629&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis K, Limato R, Monga M, Egid B, Paul S, Okioma S, et al. Antimicrobial resistance, equity and justice in low- and middle-income countries: an intersectional critical interpretive synthesis. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):9078. doi: 10.1038/s41467-025-64137-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-64137-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12518637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41083441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otaigbe II, Elikwu CJ. Drivers of inappropriate antibiotic use in low- and middle-income countries. JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2023;5(3):dlad062. doi: 10.1093/jacamr/dlad062</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jacamr/dlad062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10230568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37265987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesola RO, Opuni E, Idris I, Okesanya OJ, Igwe O, Abdulazeez MD, et al. Navigating Nigeria&#x2019;s Health Landscape: Population Growth and Its Health Implications. Environ Health Insights. 2024;18:11786302241250211. doi: 10.1177/11786302241250211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11786302241250211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38698838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christian B-IN, Christian NG, Keshinro MI, Olutade-Babatunde O. How to build bridges for Universal Health Coverage in Nigeria by linking formal and informal health providers. BMJ Glob Health. 2023;8(11):e014165. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-014165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2023-014165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10680001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38007226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Ministry of Health N. Second National Strategic Health Development Plan 2018&#x2013;2022. Abuja, Nigeria: Federal Ministry of Health Nigeria. 2018. https://ngfrepository.org.ng:8443/jspui/handle/123456789/3283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajisegiri WS, Abimbola S, Tesema AG, Odusanya OO, Ojji DB, Peiris D, et al. Aligning policymaking in decentralized health systems: Evaluation of strategies to prevent and control non-communicable diseases in Nigeria. PLOS Glob Public Health. 2021;1(11):e0000050. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0000050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0000050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10022121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukwu EE, Oshun PO, Osuolale KA, Chuka-Ebene VO, Salako A, Idigbe IE, et al. Antimicrobial stewardship programmes in healthcare facilities in Lagos State, Nigeria: a needs assessment. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2021;25:162&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1016/j.jgar.2021.02.034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgar.2021.02.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukwu EE, Oladele DA, Enwuru CA, Gogwan PL, Abuh D, Audu RA, et al. Antimicrobial resistance awareness and antibiotic prescribing behavior among healthcare workers in Nigeria: a national survey. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):22. doi: 10.1186/s12879-020-05689-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-020-05689-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7792030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadse SN, Ugemuge S, Singh C. Impact of Antimicrobial Stewardship on Reducing Antimicrobial Resistance. Cureus. 2023;15(12):e49935. doi: 10.7759/cureus.49935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38179391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Programming Initiative on Antimicrobial Resistance (JPIAMR). Global coordination of antimicrobial resistance research. Stockholm, Sweden: JPIAMR. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Commonwealth Partnerships for Antimicrobial Stewardship Scheme. https://www.globalhealthpartnerships.org/our-work/grants/cwpams/. Accessed 2025 April 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashiru-Oredope D, Langford BJ, Bonaconsa C, Nampoothiri V, Charani E, Goff DA. Global collaborations in antimicrobial stewardship: All hands on deck. Antimicrob Steward Healthc Epidemiol. 2023;3(1):e66. doi: 10.1017/ash.2023.122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ash.2023.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10127241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry G, Hayfield N, Clarke V, Braun V. Thematic analysis. In: Willig C, Rogers WS, editors. The SAGE Handbook of Qualitative Research in Psychology. 2nd ed. London: SAGE Publications. 2017. p. 17&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeroy KR, Bibeau D, Steckler A, Glanz K. An ecological perspective on health promotion programs. Health Educ Q. 1988;15(4):351&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1177/109019818801500401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/109019818801500401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3068205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management Sciences for Health. Strengthening Antimicrobial Stewardship in Nigeria: Building Institutional Capacity in AMS at Nigerian Health Facilities. Nigeria: USAID MTaPS Program. 2022. https://www.mtapsprogram.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/MTaPS-Nigeria-Technical-Brief-AMS-December-2022.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar I, Dalglish SL, Angell B, Sanuade O, Abimbola S, Adamu AL, et al. The Lancet Nigeria Commission: investing in health and the future of the nation. Lancet. 2022;399(10330):1155&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02488-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02488-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35303470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otaigbe II. Achieving universal health coverage in low- and middle-income countries through digital antimicrobial stewardship. Front Digit Health. 2023;5:1298861. doi: 10.3389/fdgth.2023.1298861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1298861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38162693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achi CR, Ayobami O, Mark G, Egwuenu A, Ogbolu D, Kabir J. Operationalising One Health in Nigeria: Reflections From a High-Level Expert Panel Discussion Commemorating the 2020 World Antibiotics Awareness Week. Front Public Health. 2021;9:673504. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2021.673504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.673504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8203202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34136458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokharel S, Raut S, Adhikari B. Tackling antimicrobial resistance in low-income and middle-income countries. BMJ Glob Health. 2019;4(6):e002104. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2019-002104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2019-002104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6861125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31799007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veepanattu P, Singh S, Mendelson M, Nampoothiri V, Edathadatil F, Surendran S, et al. Building resilient and responsive research collaborations to tackle antimicrobial resistance-Lessons learnt from India, South Africa, and UK. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;100:278&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.08.057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.08.057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Charani E, Devi S, Sharma A, Edathadathil F, Kumar A, et al. A road-map for addressing antimicrobial resistance in low- and middle-income countries: lessons learnt from the public private participation and co-designed antimicrobial stewardship programme in the State of Kerala, India. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2021;10(1):32. doi: 10.1186/s13756-020-00873-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-020-00873-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7878026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davwar P, Bitrus N, Nyam D, Ioramo K, Zawaya K, Agboghoroma O. Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practice of Doctors in Nigeria Regarding Antimicrobial Resistance. Niger Med J. 2023;64(4):492&#x2013;502. doi: 10.60787/NMJ-64-4-296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.60787/NMJ-64-4-296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11214715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38952878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamere N, Garwe ST, Akinwotu OO, Tuck C, Krockow EM, Yadav S, et al. Scoping Review of National Antimicrobial Stewardship Activities in Eight African Countries and Adaptable Recommendations. Antibiotics (Basel). 2022;11(9):1149. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics11091149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics11091149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36139929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas C, Batura N, Wulandari LPL, Khan M, Wiseman V. Improving antibiotic use through behaviour change: a systematic review of interventions evaluated in low- and middle-income countries. Health Policy Plan. 2021;36(5):594&#x2013;605. doi: 10.1093/heapol/czab021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czab021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33822953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MS, Bory S, Rego S, Suy S, Durrance-Bagale A, Sultana Z, et al. Is enhancing the professionalism of healthcare providers critical to tackling antimicrobial resistance in low- and middle-income countries?. Hum Resour Health. 2020;18(1):10. doi: 10.1186/s12960-020-0452-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-020-0452-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7014603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Ahmed R, Adam RZ, Coetzee R. Antimicrobial resistance, antibiotic prescribing practices and antimicrobial stewardship in South Africa: a scoping review. JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2025;7(1):dlaf014. doi: 10.1093/jacamr/dlaf014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jacamr/dlaf014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11791682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39906361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakubu K, Shanthosh J, Adebayo KO, Peiris D, Joshi R. Scope of health worker migration governance and its impact on emigration intentions among skilled health workers in Nigeria. PLOS Glob Public Health. 2023;3(1):e0000717. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0000717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0000717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maki G, Smith I, Paulin S, Kaljee L, Kasambara W, Mlotha J, et al. Feasibility Study of the World Health Organization Health Care Facility-Based Antimicrobial Stewardship Toolkit for Low- and Middle-Income Countries. Antibiotics (Basel). 2020;9(9):556. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics9090556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics9090556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32872440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otaigbe II. Policy entrepreneurs are integral in efforts to curb antimicrobial resistance in low and middle income countries. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1292660. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1292660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1292660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10963478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38532974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iheanacho CO, Eze UIH. Antimicrobial resistance in Nigeria: challenges and charting the way forward. Eur J Hosp Pharm. 2022;29(2):119. doi: 10.1136/ejhpharm-2021-002762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ejhpharm-2021-002762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35190457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okolie OJ, Ismail SU, Igwe U, Adukwu EC. Assessing barriers and opportunities for the improvement of laboratory performance and robust surveillance of antimicrobial resistance in Nigeria- a quantitative study. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2025;14(1):29. doi: 10.1186/s13756-025-01530-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-025-01530-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11993948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine; Health and Medicine Division; Board on Population Health and Public Health Practice; Committee on the Long-Term Health and Economic Effects of Antimicrobial Resistance in the United States. Combating Antimicrobial Resistance and Protecting the Miracle of Modern Medicine. Palmer GH, Buckley GJ. Washington (DC): National Academies Press (US). 2021. doi: 10.17226/26350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17226/26350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34694763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seale AC, Hutchison C, Fernandes S, Stoesser N, Kelly H, Lowe B, et al. Supporting surveillance capacity for antimicrobial resistance: Laboratory capacity strengthening for drug resistant infections in low and middle income countries. Wellcome Open Res. 2017;2:91. doi: 10.12688/wellcomeopenres.12523.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.12523.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5686477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29181453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronat J-B, Natale A, Kesteman T, Andremont A, Elamin W, Hardy L, et al. AMR in low-resource settings: M&#xe9;decins Sans Fronti&#xe8;res bridges surveillance gaps by developing a turnkey solution, the Mini-Lab. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27(10):1414&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2021.04.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2021.04.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulumbe BH, Abdulrahim A, Ibrahim MN. Rising antibiotic costs as a potential driver of antimicrobial resistance in Nigeria. Discov Public Health. 2025;22(1). doi: 10.1186/s12982-025-00398-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12982-025-00398-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukwu EE, Oladele DA, Awoderu OB, Afocha EE, Lawal RG, Abdus-Salam I, et al. A national survey of public awareness of antimicrobial resistance in Nigeria. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2020;9(1):72. doi: 10.1186/s13756-020-00739-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-020-00739-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Eze UA. Awareness and Knowledge of Antimicrobial Resistance, Antimicrobial Stewardship and Barriers to Implementing Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing among Medical Laboratory Scientists in Nigeria: A Cross-Sectional Study. Antibiotics (Basel). 2023;12(5):815. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics12050815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics12050815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10215829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37237717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>