<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896764</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Frequency, genetic mechanisms and factors associated with fluoroquinolone (pre-XDR) and aminoglycoside resistance among multidrug-resistant tuberculosis cases in Northwestern Nigeria.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-13191-z</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamuda</LastName><ForeName>Kasimu</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kano Independent Research Centre Trust, Kano, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aliyu</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Sani</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Life Sciences, Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suleman</LastName><ForeName>Mikailu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Abba Kasim</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Abubakar Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garba</LastName><ForeName>Bala Yazeed</ForeName><Initials>BY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aminu</LastName><ForeName>Dalhatu Abdullahi</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Public Health and Infectious Diseases, Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dan-Inna</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Zaharadeen</ForeName><Initials>MZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Federal Medical Centre, Gusau, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathew</LastName><ForeName>Gaius</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Services, Federal Ministry of Health, Abuja, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salihu</LastName><ForeName>Hamisu Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kano Independent Research Centre Trust, Kano, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussaini</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim Muhammed</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Life Sciences, Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdullahi</LastName><ForeName>Idris Nasir</ForeName><Initials>IN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, College of Medical Sciences, Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Nigeria. inabdullahi@abu.edu.ng.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rrs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-resistant TB</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nigeria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tuberculosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pre-XDR-TB</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: This study was approved by the ethical research committee of the National Tuberculosis and Leprosy Training Centre (NTBLTC and the Research Ethics Committee of Kaduna State Ministry of Health, Nigeria (approved number: NHREC/17/03/2018). Human ethics: This study was performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent to participate: Written informed consent was obtained from all the participants and from the legal guardians of the participants who were illiterate. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-13191-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-13191-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suleac M, Rezende A, Naranjo S, Djassi M. A Case of Extensive Tuberculosis With Bacterial Infection Treated in a Peripheral Hospital. Cureus. 2024;16(3):e57067. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.57067. PMID: 38681350; PMCID: PMC11052601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugwu KO, Agbo MC, Ezeonu IM. Prevalence of tuberculosis, drug-resistant tuberculosis and hiv/tb co-infection in Enugu Nigera. Afr J Infect Dis. 2021;15(2):24&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.21010/ajid.v15i2.5. PMID: 33889799; PMCID: PMC8052972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global tuberculosis report 2025: TB disease burden. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2025. Available from: https://www.who.int/teams/global-programme-on-tuberculosis-and-lung-health/tb-reports/global-tuberculosis-report-2025/tb-disease-burden.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monde N, Munyeme M, Chongwe G, Wensman JJ, Zulu M, Siziya S, Tembo R, Siame KK, Shambaba O, Malama S. First and Second-Line Anti-Tuberculosis Drug-Resistance Patterns in Pulmonary Tuberculosis Patients in Zambia. Antibiot (Basel). 2023;12(1):166. https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics12010166. PMID: 36671366; PMCID: PMC9855139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Forsman LD, Xu C, Zhang H, Zhu Y, Shao G, Wang S, Cao J, Xiong H, Niward K, Sch&#xf6;n T, Bruchfeld J, Zhu L, Alffenaar JW, Hu Y. Second-line antituberculosis drug exposure thresholds predictive of adverse events in multidrug-resistant tuberculosis treatment. Int J Infect Dis. 2024;140:62&#x2013;69. Epub 2024 Jan 3. PMID: 38176643. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2024.01.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO consolidated guidelines on tuberculosis. Module 4: treatment - drug-resistant tuberculosis treatment, 2022 update. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240063129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad R, Gupta N, Banka A. Multidrug-resistant tuberculosis/rifampicin-resistant tuberculosis: Principles of management. Lung India. 2018 Jan-Feb;35(1):78&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.4103/lungindia.lungindia_98_17. PMID: 29319042; PMCID: PMC5760876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakala DY, Tamuzi JM, Shumba CS, Nyasulu PS. Burden and determinants of MDR-TB among prisoners in sub-Saharan Africa: Systematic review and meta-analysis protocol. J Public Health Afr. 2025;16(4):1364. https://doi.org/10.4102/jphia.v16i4.1364. PMID: 40936809; PMCID: PMC12421582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x117;velaitien&#x117; K, Davidavi&#x10d;ien&#x117; VE, Danila E. Tuberculosis treatment failure: what are the risk factors? A comprehensive literature review. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2025;20(1):1030. https://doi.org/10.5826/mrm.2025.1030. PMID: 40622307; PMCID: PMC12320958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viney K, Linh NN, Gegia M, Zignol M, Glaziou P, Ismail N. New definitions of pre-extensively and extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis update from the World Health Organization. Eur Respir J. 2021;57(4):2100361&#x2013;2100361. https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.congress-2021.OA1599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan R, Prabuseenivasan S, Hannah S, Vaishanavee V, Senthildevi V, Kannadhasan T, Suchithra R, Rajendran P, Chinnaiyan P, Jayabal L, Frederick A, Shanmugam S. Genotype MTBDRsl version 2 and phenotypic drug resistance detection of Mycobacterium tuberculosis for fluoroquinolones and aminoglycosides. Int J Mycobacteriol. 2023 Jul-Sep;12(3):299&#x2013;304. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijmy.ijmy_120_23. PMID: 37721236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehru VJ, Jose Vandakunnel M, Brammacharry U, Ramachandra V, Pradhabane G, Mani BR, Vn AD, Muthaiah M. Risk assessment and transmission of fluoroquinolone resistance in drug-resistant pulmonary tuberculosis: a retrospective genomic epidemiology study. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):19719. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70535-y. PMID: 39181942; PMCID: PMC11344791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Yang J, Wang H, Sha W, Yu F. Key resistance-associated mutations in multidrug-resistant tuberculosis: a genomic study from Shanghai, China, with a focus on aminoglycosides. BMC Microbiol. 2025;25(1):702. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12866-025-04446-x. PMID: 41168684; PMCID: PMC12574157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardee Y, Dreyer AW, Koornhof HJ, Omar SV, da Silva P, Bhyat Z, Ismail NA. Evaluation of the GenoType MTBDRsl Version 2.0 assay for second-line drug resistance detection of Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolates in South Africa. J Clin Microbiol. 2017;55(3):791&#x2013;800. Epub 2016 Dec 14. PMID: 27974543; PMCID: PMC5328447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamuda K, Aliyu MS, Suleman M, Ibrahim AK, Maifada AI, Song AM, Garba BY, Aminu DA, Dan-Inna MZ, Jiya-Chitumu EN, Abdullahi IN. Epidemiology and molecular characterization of multidrug-resistant Mycobacterium tuberculosis among patients with pulmonary symptoms in Kaduna State, Nigeria. Acta Trop. 2025;269:107748. Epub 2025 Jul 17. PMID: 40683583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hain Lifescience GmbH. Genotype MTBDRplus 2.0 Product Insert Hain Lifescience GmbH. Nehren, Germany https://www.hain-lifescience.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyedum CC, Alobu I, Ukwaja KN. Prevalence of drug-resistant tuberculosis in Nigeria: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(7):e0180996. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0180996. PMID: 28704459; PMCID: PMC5509256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel O, Osman E, Oladimeji O, Dairu OG. Pre-extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis amomg multidrug-resistant tuberculosis patients in Nigeria. Global Adv Res J Microbiol. 2013;2:22&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu NO, Ulasi AE, Okoronkwo CU, Unegbu VN. Pre-extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis among pulmonary multidrug-resistant tuberculosis patients in Eastern Nigeria. Lung India. 2023 Nov-Dec;40(6):492&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.4103/lungindia.lungindia_337_23. PMID: 37961955; PMCID: PMC10723212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madukaji L, Okohu I, Usman S, Oyedum U, Enagi A, Usman A, Adedeji AS, Owolagba F, Ofuche E, Samuels JO, Jolayemi T, Okonkwo P. Early detection of Pre-XDR TB with line probe assay in a high TB burden country. Afr Health Sci. 2021;21(3):968&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.4314/ahs.v21i3.2. PMID: 35222556; PMCID: PMC8843309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diriba G, Alemu A, Yenew B, Tola HH, Gamtesa DF, Mollalign H, Eshetu K, Moga S, Abdella S, Tollera G, Kebede A, Dangisso MH. Epidemiology of extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis among patients with multidrug-resistant tuberculosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;132:50&#x2013;63. Epub 2023 Apr 16. PMID: 37072053; PMCID: PMC10302157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinulingga HE, Sinaga BY, Siagian P, Ashar T. Profile and risk factors of pre-XDR-TB and XDR-TB patients in a national reference hospital for Sumatra region of Indonesia. Narra J. 2023;3(3):e407. https://doi.org/10.52225/narra.v3i3.407. Epub 2023 Nov 13. PMID: 38455612; PMCID: PMC10919437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Lotia-Farrukh I, Khan PY, Adnan S, Sodho JS, Bano S, Siddiqui MR, Ghafoor A, Isani AK, Salahuddin N, Khan U. High prevalence of multidrug-resistant TB among household contacts in a high burden setting. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2023;27(8):646&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.5588/ijtld.23.0123. PMID: 37491755; PMCID: PMC10365561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iweama CN, Agbaje OS, Umoke PCI, Igbokwe CC, Ozoemena EL, Omaka-Amari NL, Idache BM. Nonadherence to tuberculosis treatment and associated factors among patients using directly observed treatment short-course in north-west Nigeria: A cross-sectional study. SAGE Open Med. 2021;9:2050312121989497. PMID: 33614034; PMCID: PMC7871291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad Dayyab F, Iliyasu G, Garba Ahmad B, Aliyu Umar I, Musa Shuaib N, Bajehson M, Muhammad Daiyab I, Akpala O, Remilekun O, Garba Habib A, For Kano TB Concilium Experts. Emerging threat of drug-resistant tuberculosis and trends in the era of COVID-19: A descriptive study from northwestern Nigeria. J Clin Tuberc Other Mycobact Dis. 2022;28:100319. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jctube.2022.100319. PMID: 35599722; PMCID: PMC9110314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvajal E, Escand&#xf3;n S, Adewole PD, Castro-Rodr&#xed;guez B, Rodr&#xed;guez-Pazmi&#xf1;o &#xc1;S, Orlando SA, Narvaez A, Alabi OS, Garcia-Bereguiain MA. Population structure and antibiotic resistance profiles of Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolates from Ibadan, Nigeria (2019&#x2013;2020): a pilot study to improve affordable molecular diagnostic tools. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1657825. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2025.1657825. PMID: 41089875; PMCID: PMC12515896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avalos E, Catanzaro D, Catanzaro A, Ganiats T, Brodine S, Alcaraz J, Rodwell T. Frequency and geographic distribution of gyrA and gyrB mutations associated with fluoroquinolone resistance in clinical Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolates: a systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(3):e0120470. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0120470. PMID: 25816236; PMCID: PMC4376704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reta MA, Maningi NE, Fourie PB. Patterns and profiles of drug resistance-conferring mutations in Mycobacterium tuberculosis genotypes isolated from tuberculosis-suspected attendees of spiritual holy water sites in Northwest Ethiopia. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1356826. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2024.1356826. PMID: 38566794; PMCID: PMC10985251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerriegel S, Oberhauser B, George AG, Dafae F, Richter E, R&#xfc;sch-Gerdes S, Niemann S. Sequence analysis for detection of first-line drug resistance in Mycobacterium tuberculosis strains from a high-incidence setting. BMC Microbiol. 2012;12:90. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2180-12-90. PMID: 22646308; PMCID: PMC3404943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bablishvili N, Tukvadze N, Shashkina E, Mathema B, Gandhi NR, Blumberg HM, Kempker RR. Impact of gyrB and eis Mutations in Improving Detection of Second-Line-Drug Resistance among Mycobacterium tuberculosis Isolates from Georgia. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2017;61(9):e01921&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.01921-16. PMID: 28630205; PMCID: PMC5571295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Hoffner S, Wu L, Zhao Q, Jiang W, Xu B. Prevalence and genetic characterization of second-line drug-resistant and extensively drug-resistant Mycobacterium tuberculosis in Rural China. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2013;57(8):3857&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.00102-13. Epub 2013 Jun 3. PMID: 23733477; PMCID: PMC3719720.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>