<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41556032</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Orthopedic Rehabilitation Following Complex Repair of the Flexor and Extensor Tendons, Artery, and Nerve: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e99643</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e99643</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e99643</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.99643</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Simultaneous injury of both the flexor and extensor tendons of the hand is a rare condition that can lead to significant functional impairment and is often accompanied by arterial and nerve damage. This study aims to share the clinical outcomes of the rehabilitation process following a complex hand injury. Surgical repair was performed on a patient with injuries to the flexor and extensor tendons, as well as the radial artery and median nerve, followed by an intensive and structured rehabilitation program. The rehabilitation protocol was initiated with early passive movements and later progressed to include controlled active exercises, sensory training, and muscle strengthening. Functional outcomes were evaluated over a short-term follow-up period of 12 weeks using objective clinical measures, including range of motion and grip strength. Although validated functional outcome scales such as the Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder, and Hand or Patient-Rated Wrist Evaluation were not applied, meaningful improvements in functional hand use were observed. This case highlights that in situations where tendon, nerve, and arterial injuries occur concurrently, early and controlled rehabilitation plays a critical role in functional recovery alongside surgical treatment. However, long-term follow-up is required to fully evaluate nerve regeneration and sustained functional outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Novruzova et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Novruzova</LastName><ForeName>Aydan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Kocaeli University, Kocaeli, TUR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complex hand injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early and controlled rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mid-position splint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthopedic rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tendon repair</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41556032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12812336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.99643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wolfe SW, Hotchkiss RN, Pederson WC, Kozin SH. Green&#x2019;s Operative Hand Surgery. 7th ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2016. Green&#x2019;s Operative Hand Surgery. 7th Ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexor tendon injuries. Tang JB. Clin Plast Surg. 2019;46:295&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term results of extensor tendon repair. Newport ML, Blair WF, Steyers CM Jr. J Hand Surg Am. 1990;15:961&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2269792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Median and ulnar nerve injuries: a meta-analysis of predictors of motor and sensory recovery after modern microsurgical nerve repair. Ruijs AC, Jaquet JB, Kalmijn S, Giele H, Hovius SE. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2005;116:484&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16079678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The evidence-base for the management of flexor tendon injuries of the hand: review. Ishak A, Rajangam A, Khajuria A. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2019;48:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6806617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexor tendon healing and restoration of the gliding surface. An ultrastructural study in dogs. Gelberman RH, Vande Berg JS, Lundborg GN, Akeson WH. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1983;65:70&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6848538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation following surgery for flexor tendon injuries of the hand. Peters SE, Jha B, Ross M. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;1:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33434949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation of flexor and extensor tendon injuries in the hand: current updates. Howell JW, Peck F. Injury. 2013;44:397&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23347765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zone-II flexor tendon repair: a randomized prospective trial of active place-and-hold therapy compared with passive motion therapy. Trumble TE, Vedder NB, Seiler JG 3rd, Hanel DP, Diao E, Pettrone S. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2010;92:1381&#x2013;1389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20516313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexor tendon injuries: I. Foundations of treatment. Strickland JW. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 1995;3:44&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10790652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>