<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41223884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2234-2591</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ewha medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ewha Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lifestyle prescriptions for diabetes management in primary care: a narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e55</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e55</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e55</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12771/emj.2025.00808</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetes mellitus is a complex chronic disease with a rapidly increasing global prevalence. For this condition, non-pharmacological lifestyle modification is as important as pharmacological treatment. This review aims to comprehensively examine lifestyle prescriptions for diabetes across multiple domains to integrate current insights and understanding. In medical nutrition therapy, which is central to diabetes treatment and management, excessive carbohydrate intake should be restricted, while individualized consumption of high-quality carbohydrates, protein, and unsaturated fatty acids is recommended. Intake of added sugars and sodium should also be limited. Physical activity should similarly be tailored to the individual, with a combination of aerobic exercise and resistance training recommended. Careful consideration of hypoglycemia risk and diabetes complications is essential. Additional strategies include limitations on uninterrupted sedentary time to less than 30 minutes, maintenance of a healthy body weight, smoking cessation, alcohol abstinence, sleep health improvements, and attention to psychosocial care. In primary care settings, patient-specific assessment, multidisciplinary lifestyle prescriptions, and education to support behavior modification are expected to play a pivotal role in the treatment and management of diabetes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Hye Jun</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Chung-Ang University Medical Center, Chung-Ang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jung-Ha</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Chung-Ang University Medical Center, Chung-Ang University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Ewha Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101606065</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2234-3180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lifestyle prescription</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical nutrition therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary health care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflict of interest</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41223884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12611436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12771/emj.2025.00808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">emj.2025.00808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>International Diabetes Federation (IDF) IDF diabetes atlas 2021. 10th ed. IDF; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korean Diabetes Association . Diabetes fact sheet in Korea 2024. Korean Diabetes Association; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rett K, Gottwald-Hostalek U. Understanding prediabetes: definition, prevalence, burden and treatment options for an emerging disease. Curr Med Res Opin. 2019;35:1529&#x2013;1534. doi: 10.1080/03007995.2019.1601455. 
 https://doi.org/10.1080/03007995.2019.1601455
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2019.1601455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30935247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee  5. Facilitating positive health behaviors and well-being to improve health outcomes: standards of care in diabetes-2025. Diabetes Care. 2025;48:S86&#x2013;S127. doi: 10.2337/dc25-S005. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc25-S005
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc25-S005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11635047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39651983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Kang SM, Choi JH, Ko SH, Koo BK, Kwon HS, Kim MK, Kim SY, Kim SK, Kim YE, Kim ES, Kim JH, Kim CH, Kim JM, Kim HJ, Moon MK, Moon SJ, Moon JS, Moon JH, Min SH, Park JH, Bae J, Song K, Ahn JY, Yun JS, Lee WJ, Lee YB, Chon S, Jeon E, Jin SM, Han E, Hwang YC, Bae JH, Song Y, Lim JH, Cho JW, Choi JY, Hong YH, Lee J, Kim SE, Noh JY, Cha BS, Lee BW. 2025 Clinical Practice Guidelines for Diabetes Management in Korea: recommendation of the Korean Diabetes Association. Diabetes Metab J. 2025;49:582&#x2013;783. doi: 10.4093/dmj.2025.0469. 
 https://doi.org/10.4093/dmj.2025.0469
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2025.0469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12270580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40631460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayenigbara IO. Diabetes prevention and measures to ensuring a healthy lifestyle during COVID-19 pandemic and after. Korean J Fam Med. 2023;44:11&#x2013;20. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.21.0216. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.21.0216
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.21.0216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9887446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36709956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evert AB, Dennison M, Gardner CD, Garvey WT, Lau KH, MacLeod J, Mitri J, Pereira RF, Rawlings K, Robinson S, Saslow L, Uelmen S, Urbanski PB, Yancy WS. Nutrition therapy for adults with diabetes or prediabetes: a consensus report. Diabetes Care. 2019;42:731&#x2013;754. doi: 10.2337/dci19-0014. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dci19-0014
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dci19-0014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7011201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady KA, Cienfuegos S, Ezpeleta M, Gabel K. Clinical application of intermittent fasting for weight loss: progress and future directions. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2022;18:309&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1038/s41574-022-00638-x. 
 https://doi.org/10.1038/s41574-022-00638-x
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41574-022-00638-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JH, Cho YJ, Kim HJ, Ko SH, Chon S, Kang JH, Kim KK, Kim EM, Kim HJ, Song KH, Nam GE, Kim KI. Effect of carbohydrate-restricted diets and intermittent fasting on obesity, type 2 diabetes mellitus, and hypertension management: consensus statement of the Korean Society for the Study of Obesity, Korean Diabetes Association, and Korean Society of Hypertension. Diabetes Metab J. 2022;46:355&#x2013;376. doi: 10.4093/dmj.2022.0038. 
 https://doi.org/10.4093/dmj.2022.0038
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2022.0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9171155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35656560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes and Nutrition Study Group (DNSG) of the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD)  Evidence-based European recommendations for the dietary management of diabetes. Diabetologia. 2023;66:965&#x2013;985. doi: 10.1007/s00125-023-05894-8. 
 https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-023-05894-8
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-023-05894-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somagutta MK, Uday U, Shama N, Bathula NR, Pendyala S, Mahadevaiah A, Mahmutaj G, Ngardig NN. Dietary changes leading to euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis in sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor users: a challenge for primary care physicians? Korean J Fam Med. 2022;43:361&#x2013;366. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.22.0003. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.22.0003
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.22.0003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9708850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36444120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Carbohydrate intake for adults and children: WHO guideline. World Health Organization; 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37490573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins DJ, Willett WC, Yusuf S, Hu FB, Glenn AJ, Liu S, Mente A, Miller V, Bangdiwala SI, Gerstein HC, Sieri S, Ferrari P, Patel AV, McCullough ML, Le Marchand L, Freedman ND, Loftfield E, Sinha R, Shu XO, Touvier M, Sawada N, Tsugane S, van den Brandt PA, Shuval K, Khan TA, Paquette M, Sahye-Pudaruth S, Patel D, Siu TF, Srichaikul K, Kendall CW, Sievenpiper JL. Association of glycaemic index and glycaemic load with type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease, cancer, and all-cause mortality: a meta-analysis of mega cohorts of more than 100&#x2008;000 participants. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2024;12:107&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(23)00344-3. 
 https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(23)00344-3
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(23)00344-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38272606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TA, Smart CE, Howley PP, Lopez PE, King BR. For a high fat, high protein breakfast, preprandial administration of 125% of the insulin dose improves postprandial glycaemic excursions in people with type 1 diabetes using multiple daily injections: a cross-over trial. Diabet Med. 2021;38:e14512.  doi: 10.1111/dme.14512. 
 https://doi.org/10.1111/dme.14512
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.14512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yan N, Jiang H, Cui M, Wu M, Wang L, Mi B, Li Z, Shi J, Fan Y, Azalati MM, Li C, Chen F, Ma M, Wang D, Ma L. Consumption of sugar sweetened beverages, artificially sweetened beverages and fruit juices and risk of type 2 diabetes, hypertension, cardiovascular disease, and mortality: a meta-analysis. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1019534. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1019534. 
 https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1019534
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1019534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37006931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlynn ND, Khan TA, Wang L, Zhang R, Chiavaroli L, Au-Yeung F, Lee JJ, Noronha JC, Comelli EM, Blanco Mejia S, Ahmed A, Malik VS, Hill JO, Leiter LA, Agarwal A, Jeppesen PB, Rahelic D, Kahleova H, Salas-Salvado J, Kendall CW, Sievenpiper JL. Association of low- and no-calorie sweetened beverages as a replacement for sugar-sweetened beverages with body weight and cardiometabolic risk: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e222092.  doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.2092. 
 https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.2092
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.2092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9907347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RK, Lichtenstein AH, Anderson CA, Carson JA, Despres JP, Hu FB, Kris-Etherton PM, Otten JJ, Towfighi A, Wylie-Rosett J. Low-calorie sweetened beverages and cardiometabolic health: a science advisory from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2018;138:e126&#x2013;e140. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000569. 
 https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000569
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Lee CM, Oh SW. Fruits and the risk of type 2 diabetes: the Korean Genome and Epidemiology Study Cohort. Korean J Fam Med. 2024;45:44&#x2013;50. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.23.0201. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.23.0201
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.23.0201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10822724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37993763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan VK, Kim H, Caulfield LE, Steffen LM, Selvin E, Rebholz CM. Plant-based dietary patterns and incident diabetes in the atherosclerosis risk in communities (ARIC) study. Diabetes Care. 2024;47:803&#x2013;809. doi: 10.2337/dc23-2013. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc23-2013
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc23-2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11043224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38349856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng L, Gao Q, Hu K, Wu M, Wang Z, Chen F, Mei F, Zhao L, Ma B. Prevalence and risk factors of sarcopenia in patients with diabetes: a meta-analysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2022;107:1470&#x2013;1483. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgab884. 
 https://doi.org/10.1210/clinem/dgab884
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgab884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34904651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland IJ, Linge J, Birkenfeld AL. Changes in lean body mass with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapies and mitigation strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26 Suppl 4:16&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1111/dom.15728. 
 https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.15728
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.15728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julibert A, Bibiloni MD, Tur JA. Dietary fat intake and metabolic syndrome in adults: a systematic review. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;29:887&#x2013;905. doi: 10.1016/j.numecd.2019.05.055. 
 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.numecd.2019.05.055
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2019.05.055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31377181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee of Clinical Practice Guideline of the Korean Society of Lipid and Atherosclerosis . Korean Guidelines for the Management of Dyslipidemia. 5th ed. The Korean Society of Lipid and Atherosclerosis; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Welfare. The Korean Nutrition Society . Dietary reference intakes for Koreans 2020. Ministry of Health and Welfare; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodson EM, Cooper TE. Altered dietary salt intake for preventing diabetic kidney disease and its progression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;1:CD006763. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub3. 
 https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub3
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9841968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36645291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suckling RJ, He FJ, Macgregor GA. Altered dietary salt intake for preventing and treating diabetic kidney disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010;(12):CD006763. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub2. 
 https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub2
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006763.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21154374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azadbakht L, Fard NR, Karimi M, Baghaei MH, Surkan PJ, Rahimi M, Esmaillzadeh A, Willett WC. Effects of the dietary approaches to stop hypertension (DASH) eating plan on cardiovascular risks among type 2 diabetic patients: a randomized crossover clinical trial. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:55&#x2013;57. doi: 10.2337/dc10-0676. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc10-0676
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc10-0676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20843978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi A, Ryul Shim S, Jamali N, Hassanzadeh-Rostami Z, Soltani S, Sasani N, Mohsenpour MA, Firoozi D, Basirat R, Hosseini R, Clark CC, Babajafari S, Soltanmohammadi M. Comparison of nutritional supplements for glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomized trials. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;191:110037. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110037. 
 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110037
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2022.110037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35963372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazidi M, Kammoun E, Oueslati I, Chihaoui M. Metformin-induced vitamin B12 deficiency in patients with type 2 diabetes: a narrative review with a practical approach for screening, diagnosing, and managing vitamin B12 deficiency. Korean J Fam Med. 2024;45:189&#x2013;198. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.24.0090. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.24.0090
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.24.0090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11273170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39054838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett DK, Blumenthal RS, Albert MA, Buroker AB, Goldberger ZD, Hahn EJ, Himmelfarb CD, Khera A, Lloyd-Jones D, McEvoy JW, Michos ED, Miedema MD, Munoz D, Smith SC, Virani SS, Williams KA, Yeboah J, Ziaeian B. 2019 ACC/AHA Guideline on the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2019;140:e596&#x2013;e646. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678. 
 https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Wasserman DH, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Physical activity/exercise and type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2004;27:2518&#x2013;2539. doi: 10.2337/diacare.27.10.2518. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.27.10.2518
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.27.10.2518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillen JB, Little JP, Punthakee Z, Tarnopolsky MA, Riddell MC, Gibala MJ. Acute high-intensity interval exercise reduces the postprandial glucose response and prevalence of hyperglycaemia in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2012;14:575&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1111/j.1463-1326.2012.01564.x. 
 https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1463-1326.2012.01564.x
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1326.2012.01564.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22268455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Blair SN, Cocreham S, Johannsen N, Johnson W, Kramer K, Mikus CR, Myers V, Nauta M, Rodarte RQ, Sparks L, Thompson A, Earnest CP. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on hemoglobin A1c levels in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2010;304:2253&#x2013;2262. doi: 10.1001/jama.2010.1710. 
 https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2010.1710
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2010.1710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Committee . 2018 Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Committee Scientific Report. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters A, Laffel L. The American Diabetes Association/JDRF Type 1 Diabetes Sourcebook. American Diabetes Association; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Sigal RJ, Yardley JE, Riddell MC, Dunstan DW, Dempsey PC, Horton ES, Castorino K, Tate DF. Physical activity/exercise and diabetes: a position statement of the American Diabetes Association. Diabetes Care. 2016;39:2065&#x2013;2079. doi: 10.2337/dc16-1728. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc16-1728
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc16-1728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27926890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rietz M, Lehr A, Mino E, Lang A, Szczerba E, Schiemann T, Herder C, Saatmann N, Geidl W, Barbaresko J, Neuenschwander M, Schlesinger S. Physical activity and risk of major diabetes-related complications in individuals with diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Diabetes Care. 2022;45:3101&#x2013;3111. doi: 10.2337/dc22-0886. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc22-0886
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc22-0886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9862380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemaster JW, Reiber GE, Smith DG, Heagerty PJ, Wallace C. Daily weight-bearing activity does not increase the risk of diabetic foot ulcers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1093&#x2013;1099. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000074459.41029.75. 
 https://doi.org/10.1249/01.MSS.0000074459.41029.75
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000074459.41029.75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12840628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AG, Russell J, Feldman EL, Goldstein J, Peltier A, Smith S, Hamwi J, Pollari D, Bixby B, Howard J, Singleton JR. Lifestyle intervention for pre-diabetic neuropathy. Diabetes Care. 2006;29:1294&#x2013;1299. doi: 10.2337/dc06-0224. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc06-0224
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc06-0224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spallone V, Ziegler D, Freeman R, Bernardi L, Frontoni S, Pop-Busui R, Stevens M, Kempler P, Hilsted J, Tesfaye S, Low P, Valensi P. Cardiovascular autonomic neuropathy in diabetes: clinical impact, assessment, diagnosis, and management. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2011;27:639&#x2013;653. doi: 10.1002/dmrr.1239. 
 https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.1239
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.1239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21695768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal J, Rakhra G. Sedentarism and chronic health problems. Korean J Fam Med. 2024;45:239&#x2013;257. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.24.0099. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.24.0099
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.24.0099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11427223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39327094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S, Salmani B, LeSarge J, Dillon-Rossiter K, Morava A, Prapavessis H. Interventions to reduce sedentary behaviour in adults with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2024;19:e0306439.  doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0306439. 
 https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0306439
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0306439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11288443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39078846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Lang W, Wadden TA, Safford M, Knowler WC, Bertoni AG, Hill JO, Brancati FL, Peters A, Wagenknecht L. Benefits of modest weight loss in improving cardiovascular risk factors in overweight and obese individuals with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:1481&#x2013;1486. doi: 10.2337/dc10-2415. 
 https://doi.org/10.2337/dc10-2415
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc10-2415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babor TF, Higgins-Biddle JC, World Health Organization . World Health Organization. Brief intervention for hazardous and harmful drinking: a manual for use in primary care. World Health Organization; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson BO, Berdzuli N, Ilbawi A, Kestel D, Kluge HP, Krech R, Mikkelsen B, Neufeld M, Poznyak V, Rekve D, Slama S, Tello J, Ferreira-Borges C. Health and cancer risks associated with low levels of alcohol consumption. Lancet Public Health. 2023;8:e6&#x2013;e7. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00317-6. 
 https://doi.org/10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00317-6
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00317-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9831798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36603913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DY, Yoo MG, Kim HJ, Jang HB, Kim JH, Lee HJ, Park SI. Association between alcohol consumption pattern and the incidence risk of type 2 diabetes in Korean men: a 12-years follow-up study. Sci Rep. 2017;7:7322. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-07549-2. 
 https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-07549-2
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-07549-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5544746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28779170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son JS. The interconnected nature of smoking, depression, and obesity in behavioral medicine. Korean J Fam Med. 2024;45:181&#x2013;182. doi: 10.4082/kjfm.45.4E. 
 https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.45.4E
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.45.4E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11273169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39054837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leone FT, Zhang Y, Evers-Casey S, Evins AE, Eakin MN, Fathi J, Fennig K, Folan P, Galiatsatos P, Gogineni H, Kantrow S, Kathuria H, Lamphere T, Neptune E, Pacheco MC, Pakhale S, Prezant D, Sachs DP, Toll B, Upson D, Xiao D, Cruz-Lopes L, Fulone I, Murray RL, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Pavalagantharajah S, Ross S, Zhang Y, Zhu M, Farber HJ. Initiating pharmacologic treatment in tobacco-dependent adults: an official American Thoracic Society Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202:e5&#x2013;e31. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202005-1982ST. 
 https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.202005-1982ST
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202005-1982ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anothaisintawee T, Reutrakul S, Van Cauter E, Thakkinstian A. Sleep disturbances compared to traditional risk factors for diabetes development: systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev. 2016;30:11&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.smrv.2015.10.002. 
 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.smrv.2015.10.002
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2015.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McVoy M, Hardin H, Fulchiero E, Caforio K, Briggs F, Neudecker M, Sajatovic M. Mental health comorbidity and youth onset type 2 diabetes: a systematic review of the literature. Int J Psychiatry Med. 2023;58:37&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1177/00912174211067335. 
 https://doi.org/10.1177/00912174211067335
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00912174211067335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>