<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41853883</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intra-set rest preserves barbell velocity during a free-weight back squat exercise by shifting energy system contribution.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093514</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this study, we compared acute metabolic responses and barbell velocity loss (VL) during cluster set (CS) versus traditional set (TS) resistance exercise. Six strength-trained individuals completed two randomized crossover sessions of back squats. The CS protocol included 30&#xa0;s intra-set rest intervals after the second and fourth repetitions, whereas the TS protocol used continuous repetitions. Barbell velocity, oxygen uptake and blood lactate concentrations were measured to derive model-based indices of energy system engagement. CS were associated with better preservation of barbell velocity and lower blood lactate concentrations compared with TS. Model-based indices suggested distinct metabolic patterns between set structures, with CS being associated with a higher alactic and lower lactic component than TS. Inter-individual responses were consistent across most participants. These findings indicate that acute metabolic and mechanical responses differ between CS and TS configurations. CS were associated with reduced indices of metabolic stress alongside improved velocity preservation, highlighting that set structure can influence the acute physiological-performance profile of resistance exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hobein</LastName><ForeName>Erik</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-3859-1270</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Training and Exercise Science, Faculty of Sport Science, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edel</LastName><ForeName>Antonia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3044-0288</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Training and Exercise Science, Faculty of Sport Science, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Angiology, Contilia Group, Essen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jukic</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0900-9410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Sport and Wellbeing, Faculty of Social and Applied Sciences, Abertay University, Dundee, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrauti</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9807-2755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Training and Exercise Science, Faculty of Sport Science, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiewelhove</LastName><ForeName>Thimo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1020-8780</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness and Health, IST University of Applied Sciences, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCr&#x2010;La&#x2010;O2 method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cluster set</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxygen consumption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41853883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ambaum, C., &amp; Hoppe, M. W. (2025). Evaluation of methods to quantify aerobic&#x2010;anaerobic energy contributions during sports and exercise&#x2014;A systematic review and best&#x2010;evidence synthesis. Frontiers in Sports and Active Living, 7, 1650741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli, G. G., Bertuzzi, R. C., Roschel, H., Mendes, S. H., Lancha, A. H., &amp; Franchini, E. (2012). Determining the contribution of the energy systems during exercise. Journal of Visualized Experiments: JoVE, 61, 3413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beneke, R., Pollmann, C., Bleif, I., Leith&#xe4;user, R. M., &amp; H&#xfc;tler, M. (2002). How anaerobic is the wingate anaerobic test for humans? European Journal of Applied Physiology, 87, 388&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, T. B., Tran, D. L., Hogan, C. M., Haff, G. G., &amp; Latella, C. (2021). Chronic effects of altering resistance training set configurations using cluster sets: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine, 51(4), 707&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edel, A., Vuong, J., Kaufmann, S., Hoos, O., Wiewelhove, T., &amp; Ferrauti, A. (2024). Metabolic profile in elite badminton match play and training drills. European Journal of Sport Science, 24(11), 1639&#x2013;1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini, E., Takito, M. Y., &amp; Dal&#x2019;Molin Kiss, M. A. P. (2016). Performance and energy systems contributions during upper&#x2010;body sprint interval exercise. Journal of Exercise Rehabilitation, 12(6), 535&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Ramos, A., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, J. M., Ba&#xf1;os&#x2010;Pelegr&#xed;n, E., Casta&#xf1;o&#x2010;Zambudio, A., Capelo&#x2010;Ram&#xed;rez, F., Boullosa, D., Haff, G. G., &amp; Jim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;Reyes, P. (2020). Mechanical and metabolic responses to traditional and cluster set configurations in the bench press exercise. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research, 34(3), 663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy, S. N., Kendall, K. L., &amp; Haff, G. G. (2024). Velocity&#x2010;based training&#x2014;A critical review. Strength &amp; Conditioning Journal, 46(3), 295&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff, G. G., Burgess, S. J., &amp; Stone, M. H. (2008). Cluster training: Theoretical and practical applications for the strength and conditioning professional. Professional Strength &amp; Conditioning Journal, 12, 12&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff, G. G., Hobbs, R. T., Haff, E. E., Sands, W. A., Pierce, K. C., &amp; Stone, M. H. (2008). Cluster training: A novel method for introducing training program variation. Strength &amp; Conditioning Journal, 30(1), 67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickmott, L. M., Chilibeck, P. D., Shaw, K. A., &amp; Butcher, S. J. (2022). The effect of load and volume autoregulation on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine&#x2014;Open, 8(1), 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic, I., Helms, E. R., McGuigan, M. R., &amp; Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Ramos, A. (2022). Using cluster and rest redistribution set structures as alternatives to resistance training prescription method based on velocity loss thresholds. PeerJ, 10, e13195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic, I., Ramos, A. G., Helms, E. R., McGuigan, M. R., &amp; Tufano, J. J. (2020). Acute effects of cluster and rest redistribution set structures on mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual fatigue during and after resistance training: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine, 50(12), 2209&#x2013;2236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic, I., Van Hooren, B., Ramos, A. G., Helms, E. R., McGuigan, M. R., &amp; Tufano, J. J. (2021). The effects of set structure manipulation on chronic adaptations to resistance training: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine, 51(5), 1061&#x2013;1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann, S., Latzel, R., Beneke, R., &amp; Hoos, O. (2022). Reliability of the 3&#x2010;component model of aerobic, anaerobic lactic, and anaerobic alactic energy distribution (PCr&#x2010;LA&#x2010;O2) for energetic profiling of continuous and intermittent exercise. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 17(11), 1642&#x2013;1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latzel, R., Hoos, O., Stier, S., Kaufmann, S., Fresz, V., Reim, D., &amp; Beneke, R. (2018). Energetic profile of the basketball exercise simulation test in junior elite players. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 13(6), 810&#x2013;815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite, T. C., Coelho, R. G., Silva, D. D., Coelho, W. S., Marinho&#x2010;Carvalho, M. M., &amp; Sola&#x2010;Penna, M. (2011). Lactate downregulates the glycolytic enzymes hexokinase and phosphofructokinase in diverse tissues from mice. Federation of European Biochemical Societies Letters, 585(1), 92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite, T. C., Da Silva, D., Coelho, R. G., Zancan, P., &amp; Sola&#x2010;Penna, M. (2007). Lactate favours the dissociation of skeletal muscle 6&#x2010;phosphofructo&#x2010;1&#x2010;kinase tetramers down&#x2010;regulating the enzyme and muscle glycolysis. Biochemical Journal, 408(1), 123&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora&#x2010;Custodio, R., Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Rosell, D., Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a, J. M., S&#xe1;nchez&#x2010;Moreno, M., Pareja&#x2010;Blanco, F., &amp; Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Badillo, J. J. (2018). Effect of different inter&#x2010;repetition rest intervals across four load intensities on velocity loss and blood lactate concentration during full squat exercise. Journal of Sports Sciences, 36(24), 2856&#x2013;2864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez&#x2010;Medina, L., &amp; Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Badillo, J. J. (2011). Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 43(9), 1725&#x2013;1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel, T. J., Nimphius, S., Bellon, C. R., &amp; Stone, M. H. (2018). The importance of muscular strength: Training considerations. Sports Medicine, 48(4), 765&#x2013;785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel, T. J., Nimphius, S., &amp; Stone, M. H. (2016). The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Medicine, 46(10), 1419&#x2013;1449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano, J. J., Conlon, J. A., Nimphius, S., Brown, L. E., Seitz, L. B., Williamson, B. D., &amp; Haff, G. G. (2016). Maintenance of velocity and power with cluster sets during high&#x2010;volume back squats. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 11(7), 885&#x2013;892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulup&#x131;nar, S., Haz&#x131;r, T., &amp; Kin &#x130;&#x15f;ler, A. (2023). The contribution of energy systems in repeated&#x2010;sprint protocols: The effect of distance, rest, and repetition. Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport, 94(1), 173&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulup&#x131;nar, S., &#xd6;zbay, S., Gen&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu, C., Franchini, E., Kishal&#x131;, N. F., &amp; &#x130;nce, &#x130;. (2021). Effects of sprint distance and repetition number on energy system contributions in soccer players. Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness, 19(3), 182&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulup&#x131;nar, S., &#xd6;zbay, S., Gen&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu, C., Ouergui, I., &#xd6;get, F., Kishal&#x131;, N. F., K&#x131;y&#x131;c&#x131;, F., Y&#x131;lmaz, H. H., &amp; Ardig&#xf2;, L. P. (2024). Evaluating bioenergetic pathway contributions from single to multiple sprints. Scientific Reports, 14(1), 27295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varela&#x2010;Olalla, D., Romero&#x2010;Caballero, A., Del Campo&#x2010;Vecino, J., &amp; Balsalobre&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez, C. (2020). A cluster set protocol in the half squat exercise reduces mechanical fatigue and lactate concentrations in comparison with a traditional set configuration. Sports, 8(4), 45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley, J., Mann, B., Banyard, H., McLaren, S., Scott, T., &amp; Garcia&#x2010;Ramos, A. (2021). Velocity&#x2010;based rtaining: From theory to application. Strength &amp; Conditioning Journal, 43(2), 31&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>