<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41246792</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2769-2558</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PCN reports : psychiatry and clinical neurosciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PCN Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Peer support in acute psychiatric inpatient settings: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70248</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70248</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pcn5.70248</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Peer support, grounded in lived experiences, plays an important role in advancing recovery-oriented mental healthcare. Although widely implemented in community settings, its adoption in acute psychiatric inpatient care remains limited because of structural and cultural factors that constrain recovery-oriented practices. This scoping review aimed to map existing evidence on peer support in acute psychiatric inpatient settings, focusing on (1) implementation formats, (2) peer roles, and (3) facilitators and challenges. Following the Arksey and O'Malley framework, we conducted a scoping review using the participants, concepts, and context framework. We systematically searched the PubMed, Scopus, MEDLINE, CINAHL, and ProQuest databases. We included studies that involved individuals with mental health conditions, described peer support provided by persons with lived experiences, and were conducted in acute psychiatric inpatient settings. Eleven studies, published between 1995 and 2024, met the inclusion criteria. Peer support was reported as being implemented through informal and structured formats that vary in frequency, continuity, and delivery contexts. Peer roles included emotional, practical, advocacy, and relational support. The reported benefits include increased activity participation, emotional reassurance, social engagement, and recovery-related gains for both patients and peer workers. Facilitators include training, supervision, leadership support, and collaborative relationships with staff. The reported challenges include unclear role boundaries, staff resistance, emotional strain, and structural limitations, including space, resources, and barriers to team integration. The findings suggest that peer support may help promote recovery-oriented practices in acute psychiatric settings, although further rigorous studies are needed to confirm its impact and inform sustainable integration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences Reports published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Japanese Society of Psychiatry and Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maruta</LastName><ForeName>Michio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0820-7738</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Nagasaki University Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Gwanghee</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, School of Health Sciences at Fukuoka International University of Health and Welfare Okawa Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eguchi</LastName><ForeName>Kikuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Reiwa Health Sciences University Fukuoka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamazono</LastName><ForeName>Daiki</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Nagasaki University Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawano</LastName><ForeName>Tomofusa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NPO Nagasaki Nozomi-kai Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onomichi</LastName><ForeName>Yuri</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NPO Nagasaki Nozomi-kai Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamashita</LastName><ForeName>Miki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NPO Nagasaki Nozomi-kai Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higashi</LastName><ForeName>Toshio</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Nagasaki University Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imamura</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Nagasaki University Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimokihara</LastName><ForeName>Suguru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Nagasaki University Nagasaki Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Goro</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Reiwa Health Sciences University Fukuoka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>PCN Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918451287106676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2769-2558</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inpatients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peer group</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">review literature</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41246792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12616875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pcn5.70248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PCN570248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lorien L, Blunden S, Madsen W. Implementation of recovery&#x2010;oriented practice in hospital&#x2010;based mental health services: a systematic review. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2020;29(6):1035&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. World mental health report: transforming mental health for all. World Health Organization. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldemar AK, Arnfred SM, Petersen L, Korsbek L. Recovery&#x2010;oriented practice in mental health inpatient settings: a literature review. Psychiatr Serv. 2016;67(6):596&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26927572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon B, Sutton D, McKenna B. The experience and meaning of recovery&#x2010;oriented practice for nurses working in acute mental health services. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2021;30(4):963&#x2013;974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niimura J, Tanoue M, Nakanishi M. Challenges following discharge from acute psychiatric inpatient care in Japan: patients' perspectives. J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2016;23(9&#x2013;10):576&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27624838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary M, Horsfall J, O'Hara&#x2010;Aarons M, Hunt GE. Mental health nurses' views of recovery within an acute setting. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2013;22(3):205&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22882297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolosa&#x2010;Merlos D, Moreno&#x2010;Poyato AR, Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Palau F, P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Toribio A, Casanova&#x2010;Garrig&#xf3;s G, Delgado&#x2010;Hito P, et al. Exploring the therapeutic relationship through the reflective practice of nurses in acute mental health units: a qualitative study. J Clin Nurs. 2023;32(1&#x2013;2):253&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10078778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35075705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shattell MM, Andes M, Thomas SP. How patients and nurses experience the acute care psychiatric environment. Nurs Inquiry. 2008;15(3):242&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18786217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary M, Hunt GE, Horsfall J, Deacon M. Nurse&#x2010;patient interaction in acute adult inpatient mental health units: a review and synthesis of qualitative studies. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2012;33(2):66&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22273340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortuna KL, Solomon P, Rivera J. An update of peer support/peer provided services underlying processes, benefits, and critical ingredients. Psychiatr Q. 2022;93(2):571&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8855026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35179660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper RE, Saunders KRK, Greenburgh A, Shah P, Appleton R, Machin K, et al. The effectiveness, implementation, and experiences of peer support approaches for mental health: a systematic umbrella review. BMC Med. 2024;22(1):72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10902990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jambawo SM, Owolewa R, Jambawo TT. The effectiveness of peer support on the recovery and empowerment of people with schizophrenia: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Schizophr Res. 2024;274:270&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39423701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SN, Yu HJ. Effectiveness of peer support programs for severe mental illness: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Healthcare. 2024;12(12):1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11203176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38921293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repper J, Carter T. A review of the literature on peer support in mental health services. J Ment Health. 2011;20(4):392&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21770786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillard S. Peer support in mental health services: where is the research taking us, and do we want to go there? J Ment Health. 2019;28(4):341&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31070066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SP, Shattell M, Martin T. What's therapeutic about the therapeutic milieu? Arch Psychiatr Nurs. 2002;16(3):99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones J, Nolan P, Bowers L, Simpson A, Whittington R, Hackney D, et al. Psychiatric wards: places of safety? J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2010;17(2):124&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20465757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niimura J, Tanoue M, Nakanishi M. Challenges following discharge from acute psychiatric inpatient care in Japan: patients' perspectives. J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2016;23(9&#x2013;10):576&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27624838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O'Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Method. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O'Brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5(1):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aromataris ELC, Porritt K, Pilla B, Jordan Z. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. JBI; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O'Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA&#x2010;ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong QS, Yang HZ, Kuek JHL, Goh YS. Implementation of peer&#x2010;support services in Asia: a scoping review. J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2023;30(3):309&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ser HXE, Pua XYV, Li Z, Goh YS. Experiences of certified peer support specialist providing formal peer support in mental health services: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;synthesis. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2024;33(6):1988&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39252191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard L, Montreuil M, Gros C. Peer support among inpatients in an adult mental health setting. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2010;31(9):589&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20701422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper A, Jenkin G, Morton E, Peterson D, McKenzie SK. &#x2018;We have to band together&#x2019;: service user experiences of naturally occurring peer support on the acute mental health unit. K&#x14d;tuitui. 2023;18(2):118&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway A, Pistrang N. We're stronger if we work together: experiences of naturally occurring peer support in an inpatient setting. J Ment Health. 2019;28(4):419&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30328759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco H, Galanter M, Casta&#xf1;eda R, Patterson J. Combining behavioral and self&#x2010;help approaches in the inpatient management of dually diagnosed patients. J Subst Abuse Treat. 1995;12(3):227&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7474031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migdole S, Tondora J, Silva MA, Barry AD, Milligan JC, Mattison E, et al. Exploring new frontiers: recovery&#x2010;oriented peer support programming in a psychiatric ED. Am J Psychiatr Rehabil. 2011;14(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfendale T, Musaabi A. The implementation of a peer support scheme in an assertive rehabilitation ward in high secure forensic services. Ment Health Soc Incl. 2017;21(4):222&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TE, Abraham M, Bivona M, Brakman MJ, Brown IS, Enders G, et al. &#x201c;Just be a light&#x201d;: Experiences of peers working on acute inpatient psychiatric units. Psychiatr Rehabil J. 2017;40(4):387&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27736114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lorenzo R, D'Amore J, Amoretti S, Bonisoli J, Gualtieri F, Ragazzini I, et al. Group therapy with peer support provider participation in an acute psychiatric ward: 1&#x2010;year analysis. Healthcare. 2023;11(20):2772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10606331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37893846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badouin J, Bechdolf A, Bermpohl F, Baumgardt J, Weinmann S. Preventing, reducing, and attenuating restraint: a prospective controlled trial of the implementation of peer support in acute psychiatry. Front Psychiatry. 2023;14:1089484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9941159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36824670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwan McManus J, Gkika S, Swift E. Facilitating a hearing voices group on acute and psychiatric intensive care units to promote acceptance and hope: preliminary learning and reflections. Ment Health Soc Incl. 2023;28(5):821&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone N, Warren F, Napier C. Peer support workers' experience of an intentional peer support scheme on an acute psychiatric ward. Ment Health Learn Disabil Res Pract. 2010;7(1):93&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiste E, Stevanovic M, Uusitalo L&#x2010;L, Toiviainen H. Peer support for accepting distressing reality: Expertise and experience&#x2010;sharing in psychiatric peer&#x2010;to&#x2010;peer group discussions. Health. 2023;28(3):450&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11041083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36851862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Repper J. Peer support workers: Theory and practice. Centre for Mental Health &amp; NHS Confederation Mental Health Network; 2013. Retrieved from https://www.imroc.org/publications/peer-support-workers-theory-and-practice
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillard S, Foster R, Gibson S, Goldsmith L, Marks J, White S. Describing a principles&#x2010;based approach to developing and evaluating peer worker roles as peer support moves into mainstream mental health services. Ment Health Soc Incl. 2017;21(3):133&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foye U, Lyons N, Shah P, Mitchell L, Machin K, Chipp B, et al. Understanding the barriers and facilitators to delivering peer support effectively in England: a qualitative interview study. BMC Psychiatry. 2025;25(1):480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12070543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40355846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray B, Sisto M. Peer support work in hospital: a first person and lived experience guide. Schizophr Bull Open. 2024;5(1):sgad035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11207897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39144111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson L, Bellamy C, Guy K, Miller R. Peer support among persons with severe mental illnesses: a review of evidence and experience. World Psychiatry. 2012;11(2):123&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3363389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22654945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock N, Berry B, Banfield M, Pike&#x2010;Rowney G, Scanlan JN, Norris S. Peer worker&#x2010;supported transition from hospital to home&#x2010;outcomes for service users. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(5):2743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson N, Trojanowski L, Dewa CS. What do peer support workers do? A job description. BMC Health Serv Res. 2012;12:205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22812608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillard SG, Edwards C, Gibson SL, Owen K, Wright C. Introducing peer worker roles into UK mental health service teams: a qualitative analysis of the organisational benefits and challenges. BMC Health Serv Res. 2013;13:188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3673834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23705767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams WE, Duquette R, de Wet A, Rogers ES. Competing allegiance in an unclear role: peer and non&#x2010;peer understanding of peer support in Massachusetts, United States. SSM&#x2014;Mental Health. 2023;4:100245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11872228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40028154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks J, Foster R, Gibson SL, Simpson A, Rinaldi M, Repper J, et al. Development of a peer support intervention to improve the experience and outcomes of discharge from inpatient mental health care: the role of experiential knowledge in a coproduced approach. BMC Res Notes. 2021;14(1):320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker G, Bryant W. Peer support in adult mental health services: a metasynthesis of qualitative findings. Psychiatr Rehabil J. 2013;36(1):28&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23477647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LD, Vasquez D, Wolf J, Robison J, Hartigan L, Hollman R. Supporting peer support workers and their supervisors: cluster&#x2010;randomized trial evaluating a systems&#x2010;level intervention. Psychiatr Serv. 2024;75(6):514&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38204374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez G, K&#xfc;sel M, von Peter S. Changes in attitudes of mental health care staff surrounding the implementation of peer support work: a qualitative study. PLoS One. 2025;20(4):e0319830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11961008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40168294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh M, Charles A, Grayzman A, Hiltensperger R, Kalha J, Kulkarni A, et al. Societal and organisational influences on implementation of mental health peer support work in low&#x2010;income and high&#x2010;income settings: a qualitative focus group study. BMJ Open. 2023;13(8):e058724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10450133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molin J, Graneheim UH, Lindgren BM. Quality of interactions influences everyday life in psychiatric inpatient care&#x2010;&#x2010;patients' perspectives. Int J Qual Stud Health Well&#x2010;Being. 2016;11:29897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26806313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>