<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41924744</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of exercise programs on cardiopulmonary function and signs and symptoms in patients with post-COVID-19 condition: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1772741</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1772741</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1772741</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2026.1772741</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Exercise is increasingly recognized as an effective adjuvant therapy for individuals with post-COVID-19 condition. However, exercise interventions vary widely in intensity, frequency, setting, and duration. To date, no systematic review and meta-analysis has evaluated programs lasting at least 6&#x202f;weeks in this population. This study aimed to assess the effects of exercise on cardiopulmonary function and clinical symptoms in patients with post-COVID-19 condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We systematically searched for studies involving patients with post-COVID-19 condition in the Embase, MEDLINE/PubMed, and Scopus databases. The databases were searched using keywords including COVID-19 OR coronavirus OR SARS-CoV-2, AND exercise OR physical exercise OR rehabilitation program, AND pulmonary function OR lung function OR signs and symptoms, AND randomiz* contro* trial OR clinical trial OR RCT on July 2024. The risk of bias of individual trials and the certainty of the body of evidence were evaluated using the Physiotherapy Evidence Database scale and the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation approach, respectively. The PRISMA (Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses) statement was used to describe the study selection process. The mean (&#xb1; standard deviation) for continuous data and the frequency (<i>n</i>) and percentage (%) for dichotomous data were estimated, and the effects across trials were combined using a meta-analysis with random-effects models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We included 10 randomized controlled trials comprising 602 participants. The age of participants ranged from 18 to 70&#x202f;years. The average exercise duration across the 10 studies was 8.6&#x202f;weeks (ranging from 6 to 16&#x202f;weeks). Most exercise programs included aerobic exercise, resistance exercise, breathing exercise, thoracic mobility exercise, chest expansion exercise, and respiratory muscle training. The exercise programs included home-based or telehealth-based programs, center-based programs, and combined center- and home-based programs. Compared with control groups (e.g., usual care, exercise advice, or no structured exercise), exercise interventions significantly improved exercise capacity (6-min walk distance), pulmonary function (forced vital capacity and forced expiratory volume in 1&#x202f;s), dyspnea (the modified Medical Research Council scale), physical pain, and health-related quality of life domains. The overall certainty of evidence for all outcome measures ranged from moderate to high.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Exercise programs of at least 6&#x202f;weeks are associated with improved cardiopulmonary function, reduced dyspnea and pain, and enhanced physical and health-related outcomes in patients with post-COVID-19 condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYSTEMATIC REVIEW REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/PROSPERO/view/CRD42024538786.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Khuna, Sriarmad, Pang and Longlalerng.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khuna</LastName><ForeName>Lalita</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Songkhla, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sriarmad</LastName><ForeName>Ruschada</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Allied Health Sciences, Walailak University, Nakhon Si Thammarat, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Movement and Exercise Research Center-Walailak University, Nakhon Si Thammarat, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pang</LastName><ForeName>Marco Y C</ForeName><Initials>MYC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longlalerng</LastName><ForeName>Khomkrip</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Allied Health Sciences, Walailak University, Nakhon Si Thammarat, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Movement and Exercise Research Center-Walailak University, Nakhon Si Thammarat, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiopulmonary function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41924744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13035521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2026.1772741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kadam SB, Sukhramani GS, Bishnoi P, Pable AA, Barvkar VT. SARS-CoV-2, the pandemic coronavirus: molecular and structural insights. J Basic Microbiol. (2021) 61:180&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1002/jobm.202000537,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jobm.202000537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8013332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  (2024). Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Epidemiological Updates and Monthly Operational Updates. Available online at: https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attaway AH, Scheraga RG, Bhimraj A, Biehl M, Hatipo&#x11f;lu U. Severe covid-19 pneumonia: pathogenesis and clinical management. BMJ. (2021) 372:n436. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long term effects of COVID-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. (2021) 372:n136. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n136,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco JVA, Garegnani LI, Metzendorf MI, Heldt K, Mumm R, Scheidt-Nave C. Post-covid-19 conditions in adults: systematic review and meta-analysis of health outcomes in controlled studies. BMJ Med. (2024) 3:e000723. doi: 10.1136/bmjmed-2023-000723,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjmed-2023-000723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10826558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38293681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. (2021) 11:16144. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Mustafaoglu R, Yeldan I, Yasaci Z, Erhan B. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation approaches on dyspnea, exercise capacity, fatigue, lung functions and quality of life in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. (2022) 103:2051&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9334878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laguarta-Val S, Varillas-Delgado D, Lizcano-&#xc1;lvarez &#xc1;, Molero-S&#xe1;nchez A, Melian-Ortiz A, Cano-de-la-Cuerda R, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise therapy through Nordic walking program in lactate concentrations, fatigue and quality-of-life in patients with long-COVID syndrome: a non-randomized parallel controlled trial. J Clin Med. (2024) 13:1035. doi: 10.3390/jcm13041035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13041035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10889227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romanet C, Wormser J, Fels A, Lucas P, Prudat C, Sacco E, et al. Effectiveness of exercise training on the dyspnoea of individuals with long COVID: a randomised controlled multicentre trial. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. (2023) 66:101765. doi: 10.1016/j.rehab.2023.101765,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2023.101765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37271020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;nal R, Kutay Ordu G&#xf6;kkaya N, Korkmaz S, Utku B, Ya&#x15f;ar E. Effect of yoga-based exercises on functional capacity, dyspnea, quality of life, depression, anxiety, and sleep of infected healthcare workers during the COVID-19 pandemic: a prospective clinical trial. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. (2023) 69:488&#x2013;99. doi: 10.5606/tftrd.2023.11605,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5606/tftrd.2023.11605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11099861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38766577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherzadeh-Rahmani B, Kordi N, Haghighi AH, Clark CCT, Brazzi L, Marzetti E, et al. Eight weeks of Pilates training improves respiratory measures in people with a history of COVID-19: a preliminary study. Sports Health. (2023) 15:710&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1177/19417381221124601,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381221124601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhamrawy MY, el Mohammad sherbini A, Mokhtar MM, Mashaal A, Elkady SM, Elsadany SM, et al. Effect of tai chi versus aerobic training on improving hand grip strength, fatigue, and functional performance in older adults post-COVID-19: a randomized controlled trial. J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol. (2023) 30:190&#x2013;8. doi: 10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsharidah AS, Kamel FH, Alanazi AA, Alhawsah EA, Alharbi HK, Alrshedi ZO, et al. A pulmonary telerehabilitation program improves exercise capacity and quality of life in young females post-COVID-19 patients. Ann Rehabil Med. (2023) 47:502&#x2013;10. doi: 10.5535/arm.23060,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5535/arm.23060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10767219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37980910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elyazed TIA, Alsharawy LA, Salem SE, Helmy NA, El-Hakim A. Effect of home-based pulmonary rehabilitation on exercise capacity in post COVID-19 patients: a randomized controlled trail. J Neuroeng Rehabil. (2024) 21:40. doi: 10.1186/s12984-024-01340-x,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-024-01340-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10964649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38528512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo W, Xi Y, Tian Z. The role of exercise in rehabilitation of discharged COVID-19 patients. Sports Med Health Sci. (2021) 3:194&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1016/j.smhs.2021.09.001,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smhs.2021.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai B, Xu M, Zhou H, Liao Y, Liu F, Liu Y, et al. Effects of aerobic training on cardiopulmonary fitness in patients with long COVID-19: a randomized controlled trial. Trials. (2024) 25:649. doi: 10.1186/s13063-024-08473-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-024-08473-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11448255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39363376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mel&#xe9;ndez-Oliva E, Mart&#xed;nez-Pozas O, Cuenca-Zald&#xed;var JN, Villafa&#xf1;e JH, Jim&#xe9;nez-Ortega L, S&#xe1;nchez-Romero EA. Efficacy of pulmonary rehabilitation in post-COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biomedicine. (2023) 11:2213. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines11082213,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11082213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10452542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37626710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramson MJ, Crockett AJ, Frith PA, McDonald CF. COPDX: an update of guidelines for the management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease with a review of recent evidence. Med J Aust. (2006) 184:342&#x2013;5. doi: 10.5694/j.1326-5377.2006.tb00268.x,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/j.1326-5377.2006.tb00268.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16584369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Liu B, Wang Z, El-Ansary D, Adams R, Han J, et al. Efficacy of a 6-week home-based online supervised exercise program conducted during COVID-19 in patients with post percutaneous coronary intervention: a single-blind randomized controlled trial. Front Cardiovasc Med. (2022) 9:853376. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2022.853376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.853376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35463794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Shi H, Liu X, Sun T, Wu J, Liu Z. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with post-COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med. (2022) 9:837420. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2022.837420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.837420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis JR, Koch GG. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. Biometrics. (1977) 33:159&#x2013;74. doi: 10.2307/2529310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2529310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">843571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale. J Physiother. (2020) 66:59. doi: 10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31521549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. (2003) 327:557&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva MMC, Viana DR, Colucci MG, Gonzaga LA, Arcuri JF, Frade MCM, et al. Effects of a cardiopulmonary telerehabilitation using functional exercises in individuals after COVID-19 hospital discharge: a randomized controlled trial. J Telemed Telecare. (2025) 31:311&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1177/1357633X231188394,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X231188394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37559399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fares HM, Elsary AY, Elrefaey BH, Ghanem AAM, Fares EM, Farhat ES. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation program on post hospitalization severe COVID-19 patients (experimental study). J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol. (2023) 30:130&#x2013;40. doi: 10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47750/jptcp.2023.30.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz BJ, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, et al. Effects of a concurrent training, respiratory muscle exercise, and self-management recommendations on recovery from post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J Appl Physiol (1985). (2023) 134:95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00489.2022,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00489.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaddoussi R, Rejeb H, Kalai A, Zaara E, Rouetbi N, Salah Frih ZB, et al. Effects of a cardiopulmonary rehabilitation programme on submaximal exercise in Tunisian patients with long-COVID19: a randomized clinical trial. Biol Sport. (2024) 41:197&#x2013;217. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.139072,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.139072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11474993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Xia W, Zhan C, Liu S, Yin Z, Wang J, et al. A telerehabilitation programme in post-discharge COVID-19 patients (TERECO): a randomised controlled trial. Thorax. (2022) 77:697&#x2013;706. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217382,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-217382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8318721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. (2020) 39:101166. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longobardi I, Goessler K, de Oliveira J&#xfa;nior GN, Prado D, Santos JVP, Meletti MM, et al. Effects of a 16-week home-based exercise training programme on health-related quality of life, functional capacity, and persistent symptoms in survivors of severe/critical COVID-19: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. (2023) 57:1295&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2022-106681,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37164620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira DOAV, Viana AA, Heubel AD, Linares SN, Martinelli B, Witzler PHC, et al. Cardiovascular, respiratory, and functional effects of home-based exercise training after COVID-19 hospitalization. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2022) 54:1795&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter H, Jones AM, Barstow TJ, Burnley M, Williams C, Doust JH. Effect of endurance training on oxygen uptake kinetics during treadmill running. J Appl Physiol. (2000) 89:1744&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1152/jappl.2000.89.5.1744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.89.5.1744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Hu D, Xu Y, Wu L, Lou L. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ann Med. (2022) 54:262&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1080/07853890.2021.1999494,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2021.1999494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8765243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35037535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathan SD, du Bois RM, Albera C, Bradford WZ, Costabel U, Kartashov A, et al. Validation of test performance characteristics and minimal clinically important difference of the 6-minute walk test in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Med. (2015) 109:914&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2015.04.008,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2015.04.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25956020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nantakool S, Sa-Nguanmoo P, Konghakote S, Chuatrakoon B. Effects of exercise rehabilitation on cardiorespiratory fitness in long-COVID-19 survivors: a meta-analysis. J Clin Med. (2024) 13:3621. doi: 10.3390/jcm13123621,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13123621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11204731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PW, Beeh KM, Chapman KR, Decramer M, Mahler DA, Wedzicha JA. Minimal clinically important differences in pharmacological trials. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. (2014) 189:250&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201310-1863PP,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201310-1863PP</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24383418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz-Ortigosa L, G&#xe1;lvez-&#xc1;lvarez P, Vi&#xf1;olo-Gil MJ, Rodriguez-Huguet M, G&#xf3;ngora-Rodr&#xed;guez J, Mart&#xed;n-Valero R. Effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation programmes and/or respiratory muscle training in patients with post-COVID conditions: a systematic review. Respir Res. (2024) 25:248. doi: 10.1186/s12931-024-02857-4,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-024-02857-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11186160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38890699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandao-Rangel MA, Brill B, Furtado GE, Freitas-Rolim CC, Silva-Reis A, Souza-Palmeira VH, et al. Exercise-driven comprehensive recovery: pulmonary rehabilitation&#x2019;s impact on lung function, mechanics, and immune response in post-COVID-19 patients. Infect Dis Rep. (2025) 17:1. doi: 10.3390/idr17010001,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/idr17010001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11755557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39846704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Castro R, Vasconcello-Castillo L, Alsina-Restoy X, Solis-Navarro L, Burgos F, Puppo H, et al. Respiratory function in patients post-infection by COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulmonology. (2021) 27:328&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1016/j.pulmoe.2020.10.013,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2020.10.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7687368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>