<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41201748</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle Stretching: Exploring the Impact of Different Modalities on Maximal Range of Motion and Strength with Practical Recommendations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>126</StartPage><MedlinePgn>126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">126</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00925-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Muscle stretching comprises various modalities that differ in methodological aspects and provide distinct acute and long-term effects on maximal range of motion (ROM<sub>max</sub>) and muscle strength. This narrative review aims to: i) describe each stretching modality in detail, including current approaches to quantifying intensity and volume; ii) examine how variations in these parameters influence acute and chronic adaptations in ROM<sub>max</sub> and strength; and iii) provide practical guidance by highlighting each method's advantages, limitations, and effectiveness in achieving flexibility improvements with minimal impact on strength. The reviewed modalities include passive or active static stretching, dynamic or ballistic stretching, and proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF). Intensity is commonly measured as stretch-induced discomfort (static), movement velocity or frequency (dynamic/ballistic), or contraction effort (PNF). Volume is quantified as total time at a given %ROM<sub>max</sub> (static), number of repetitions (dynamic/ballistic), or contraction-relaxation cycles (PNF). Passive static stretching is effective for increasing ROM<sub>max</sub> but may transiently reduce maximal isometric strength, particularly with higher intensities and durations. Dynamic stretching improves ROM<sub>max</sub> without affecting strength, while ballistic stretching carries a greater risk of strength impairment. PNF techniques enhance ROM<sub>max</sub> across intensity levels, and modified protocols may reduce associated discomfort. Long-term stretching interventions improve flexibility without negatively impacting strength, supporting their strategic use in training. Static stretching may even produce small strength gains when sustained for at least eight weeks. While all modalities acutely enhance ROM<sub>max</sub>, chronic effects vary depending on protocol design. Selecting an appropriate stretching technique should align with specific performance goals, particularly in sports requiring extreme ROM<sub>max</sub> or when combined with resistance training. Practical considerations such as safety, control, and participant familiarity are essential for effective long-term program implementation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5806-8305</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; Degli Studi Di Milano, 20133, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>C&#xe8;</LastName><ForeName>Emiliano</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0691-3153</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; Degli Studi Di Milano, 20133, Milan, Italy. emiliano.ce@unimi.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toninelli</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3693-971X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; Degli Studi Di Milano, 20133, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esposito</LastName><ForeName>Fabio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4420-2611</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; Degli Studi Di Milano, 20133, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coratella</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7523-9102</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; Degli Studi Di Milano, 20133, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elongation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flexibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PNF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Passive Lengthening</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: All authors certify that they have (i) no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose, (ii) no conflicts of interest to declare that are relevant to the content of this article, (iii) no affiliations with or involvement in any organization or entity with any financial interest or non-financial interest in the subject matter or materials discussed in this manuscript, and (iv) no financial or proprietary interests in any material discussed in this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41201748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12595194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00925-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00925-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Behm DG, Negra Y, Granacher U. Acute Effects of Static Stretching on Muscle Strength and Power An Attempt to Clarify Previous Caveats. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opplert J, Babault N. Acute effects of dynamic stretching on muscle flexibility and performance: an analysis of the current literature. Sports Med. 2018;48:299&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0797-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29063454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntz F, Markov A, Behm DG, Behrens M, Negra Y, Nakamura M, et al. Chronic effects of static stretching exercises on muscle strength and power in healthy individuals across the lifespan: a systematic review with multi-level meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:723&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01806-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Chaouachi A. A review of the acute effects of static and dynamic stretching on performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2633&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1879-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21373870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masugi Y, Obata H, Inoue D, Kawashima N, Nakazawa K, Sakakibara M, editor. Neural effects of muscle stretching on the spinal reflexes in multiple lower-limb muscles. PLoS ONE. 2017;12:e0180275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0180275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5491176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28662201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Mendes B, Le Sant G, Andrade RJ, Nordez A, Milanovic Z. Can chronic stretching change the muscle-tendon mechanical properties? A review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28:794&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Lima CS. Influence of chronic stretching on muscle performance: systematic review. Hum Mov Sci. 2017;54:220&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2017.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Kvorning T, Kay AD, Goh AG, Hilton B, et al. No effect of muscle stretching within a full, dynamic warm-up on athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:1258&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29300214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Blazevich AJ, Kay AD, McHugh M. Acute effects of muscle stretching on physical performance, range of motion, and injury incidence in healthy active individuals: a systematic review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26642915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe8; E, Coratella G, Bisconti AV, Venturelli M, Limonta E, Doria C, et al. Neuromuscular versus Mechanical Stretch-induced Changes in Contra- versus Ipsilateral Muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52:1294&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, C&#xe8; E, Doria C, Borrelli M, Longo S, Esposito F. Neuromuscular correlates of the contralateral stretch-induced strength loss. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:2066&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33831897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG. The science and physiology of flexibility and stretching: implications and applications in sport performance and health. Abingdon, Oxon; New York, NY: Routledge; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G. Appropriate reporting of exercise variables in resistance training protocols: much more than load and number of repetitions. Sports Med. 2022;8:99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Coyle EF. Endurance exercise performance: the physiology of champions. J Physiol. 2008;586:35&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2007.143834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM. The fourth dimension: physiological resilience as an independent determinant of endurance exercise performance. J Physiol. 2023;0:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37606604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Thomas E, Blazevich AJ, Afonso J, Behm DG, Marchetti PH, et al. Practical recommendations on stretching exercise: a Delphi consensus statement of international research experts. J Sport Health Sci. 2025. 10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12305623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40513717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, Thuku M, Hamel C, Moran J, et al. Online Appendix 2: Inter-rater reliability of AMSTAR 2 items and references for studies included in the analyses Online Appendix 2: Inter-rater reliability of AMSTAR 2 items and references for studies included in the analyses. BMJ. 2017;2:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Waugh CM, Fath F, Miller SC, Kay AD. Neuromuscular factors influencing the maximum stretch limit of the human plantar flexors. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:1446&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00882.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22923509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brusco CM, Blazevich AJ, Pinto RS. The effects of 6 weeks of constant-angle muscle stretching training on flexibility and muscle function in men with limited hamstrings&#x2019; flexibility. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119:1691&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04159-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostolopoulos N, Metsios GS, Flouris AD, Koutedakis Y, Wyon MA. The relevance of stretch intensity and position&#x2014;a systematic review. Front Psychol. 2015;6:1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukaya T, Sato S, Yahata K, Yoshida R, Takeuchi K, Nakamura M. Effects of stretching intensity on range of motion and muscle stiffness: a narrative review. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2022;32:68&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2022.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36180161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti PH, Miyatake MMS, Magalhaes RA, Gomes WA, Da Silva JJ, Brigatto FA, et al. Different volumes and intensities of static stretching affect the range of motion and muscle force output in well-trained subjects. Sports Biomech. 2022;21:155&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2019.1648540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31464179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos CX, Beltr&#xe3;o NB, Pirau&#xe1; ALT, Durigan JLQ, Behm D, de Ara&#xfa;jo RC. Static stretching intensity does not influence acute range of motion, passive torque, and muscle architecture. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;29:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Kibele A. Effects of differing intensities of static stretching on jump performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:587&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0533-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17674024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Vaz JR, Gomes L, Silvestre R, Hilario E, Cordeiro N, et al. A new tool to assess the perception of stretching intensity. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2666&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25763516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandy WD, Irion JM, Briggler M. The effect of time and frequency of static stretching on flexibility of the hamstring muscles. Phys Ther. 1997;77:1090&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/77.10.1090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto MD, Wilhelm EN, Tricoli V, Pinto R, Blazevich A. Differential effects of 30- vs. 60-second static muscle stretching on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:3440&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24936897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Mo&#x10d;nik R, Nakamura M, Sudi K, Tilp M. The impact of a single stretching session on running performance and running economy: a scoping review. Front Physiol. 2021;11:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.630282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay AD, Blazevich AJ. Effect of acute static stretch on maximal muscle performance: a systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:154&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318225cb27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzopoulos D, Galazoulas C, Patikas D, Kotzamanidis C. Acute effects of static and dynamic stretching on balance, agility, reaction time and movement time. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13:403&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3990897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24790497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira DCL, Opplert J, Babault N. Acute effects of dynamic stretching on neuromechanical properties: an interaction between stretching, contraction, and movement. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:957&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04583-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhiria-Turki L, Chaouachi A, Turki O, Hammami R, Chtara M, Amri M, et al. Greater volumes of static and dynamic stretching within a warm-up do not impair star excursion balance performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2014;54:279&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24739290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher IM. The effect of different dynamic stretch velocities on jump performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109:491&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1386-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20162300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herda TJ, Cramer JT, Ryan ED, McHugh MP, Stout JR. Acute effects of static versus dynamic stretching on isometric peak torque, electromyography, and mechanomyography of the biceps femoris muscle. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:809&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a82ec</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto MD, Wilson CJ, Kay AD, Blazevich AJ. Reliability of isokinetic tests of velocity- and contraction intensity-dependent plantar flexor mechanical properties. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1009&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical PP, Rehabilitation CCCIMSFEA. The International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy. 2014;7:109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witvrouw E, Mahieu N, Danneels L, McNair P. Stretching and injury prevention: an obscure relationship. Sports Med. 2004;34:443&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434070-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15233597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay AD, Husbands-Beasley J, Blazevich A. Effects of contract-relax, static stretching, and isometric contractions on muscle-tendon mechanics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:2181&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindle K, Whitcomb T, Briggs W, Hong J. Proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF): its mechanisms and effects on range of motion and muscular function. J Hum Kinet. 2012;31:105&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10078-012-0011-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharman MJ, Cresswell AG, Riek S. Proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching: mechanisms and clinical implications. Sports Med. 2006;36:929&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636110-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17052131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanderley D, Lemos A, Moretti E, Barros MMMB, Valen&#xe7;a MM, de Oliveira DA. Efficacy of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation compared to other stretching modalities in range of motion gain in young healthy adults: a systematic review. Physiother Theory Pract. 2019;35:109&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593985.2018.1440677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29474101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szafraniec R, Chromik K, Poborska A, Kawczy&#x144;ski A. Acute effects of contract-relax proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching of hip abductors and adductors on dynamic balance. PeerJ. 2018;6:e6108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.6108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6295325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30581683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunning E, Uszynski MK. Effectiveness of the proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation method on gait parameters in patients with stroke: a systematic review. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2019;100:980&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2018.11.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30582917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cayco CS, Labro AV, Gorgon EJR. Hold-relax and contract-relax stretching for hamstrings flexibility: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;35:42&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30423500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay AD, Dods S, Blazevich AJ. Acute effects of contract &#x2013; relax ( CR ) stretch versus a modified CR technique. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:611&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3320-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley S. Exercise-induced muscle cramp: proposed mechanisms and management. Sports Med. 1996;21:409&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199621060-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8784961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher IM, Jones B. The effect of different warm-up stretch protocols on 20 meter sprint performance in trained Rugby Union players. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant J, Cooper DJ, Peters DM, Cook MD. The effects of static stretching intensity on range of motion and strength&#x202f;: a systematic review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2023;8:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk8020037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10123604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37092369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Vilarinho D, Vaz JR, Bruno PM, Costa PB, Mil-homens P. Responses to static stretching are dependent on stretch intensity and duration. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2015;35:478&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25164268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Sato S, Murakami Y, Kiyono R, Yahata K, Sanuki F, et al. The Comparison of Different Stretching Intensities on the Range of Motion and Muscle Stiffness of the Quadriceps Muscles. Front Physiol. 2021;11:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.628870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues P, Hernandez SG, de Macedo Salgueirosa F, Novack LF, Wassmansdorf R, Wharton L, et al. The influence of two static stretching protocols with different intensities on concentric knee extension strength. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2017;25:41&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-160643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataura S, Suzuki S, Matsuo S, Hatano G, Iwata M, Yokoi K, et al. Acute effects of the different intensity of static stretching on flexibility and isometric muscle force. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3403&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27984497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oba K, Samukawa M, Nakamura K, Mikami K, Suzumori Y, Ishida Y, et al. Influence of constant torque stretching at different stretching intensities on flexibility and mechanical properties of plantar flexors. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:709&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30052602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabido CET, Bergamini JC, Andrade AGP, Lima FV, Menzel HJ, Chagas MH. Acute effect of constant torque and angle stretching on range of motion, muscle passive properties, and stretch discomfort perception. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:1050&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herda TJ, Costa PB, Walter AA, Ryan ED, Hoge KM, Kerksick CM, et al. Effects of two modes of static stretching on muscle strength and stiffness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318215cda9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21364485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Budini F, Tilp M. Acute effects of constant torque and constant angle stretching on the muscle and tendon tissue properties. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:1649&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3654-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28624851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trajano GS, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ. Neurophysiological Mechanisms Underpinning Stretch-Induced Force Loss. Sports Med. 2017;47:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0682-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28120238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisconti A, Ce E, Longo S, Venturelli M, Coratella G, Limonta E, et al. Evidence for improved systemic and local vascular function after long-term passive static stretching training of the musculoskeletal system. Journal of Physiology. 0:1&#x2013;22 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Mo&#x10d;nik R, Titze S, Nakamura M, Tilp M. The influence of stretching the hip flexor muscles on performance parameters. A systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18041936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7922112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simic L, Sarabon N, Markovic G. Does pre-exercise static stretching inhibit maximal muscular performance? A meta-analytical review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23:131&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01444.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22316148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH. Revisiting the stretch-induced force deficit: a systematic review with multilevel meta-analysis of acute effects. J Sport Health Sci. 2024. 10.1016/j.jshs.2024.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2024.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11336295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38735533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trajano GS, Nosaka K, B. Seitz L, Blazevich AJ. Intermittent stretch reduces force and central drive more than continuous stretch. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46:902&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24121249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donti O, Papia K, Toubekis A, Donti A, Sands WA, Bogdanis GC. Acute and long-term effects of two different static stretching training protocols on range of motion and vertical jump in preadolescent athletes. Biol Sport. 2021;38:579&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.101127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oba K, Samukawa M, Abe Y, Suzuki Y, Komatsuzaki M, Kasahara S, et al. Effects of intermittent and continuous static stretching on range of motion and musculotendinous viscoelastic properties based on a duration-matched protocol. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:10632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182010632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donti O, Gaspari V, Papia K, Panidi I, Donti A, Bogdanis GC. Acute effects of intermittent and continuous static stretching on hip flexion angle in athletes with varying flexibility training background. Sports. 2020;8:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports8030028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7183084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32138183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowles JR, Sale DG, Macdougall JD. Reduced strength after passive stretch of the human plantarflexors. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:1179&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.89.3.1179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avela J, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Komi PV. Altered reflex sensitivity after repeated and prolonged passive muscle stretching. J Appl Physiol. 1999;86:1283&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1999.86.4.1283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10194214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Button DC, Butt JC. Factors affecting force loss with prolonged stretching. Can J Appl Physiol. 2001;26:261&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h01-017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11441230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan ED, Beck TW, Herda TJ, Hull HR, Hartman MJ, Stout JR, et al. Do practical durations of stretching alter muscle strength? A dose-response study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1529&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31817242eb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18614936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power K, Behm D, Cahill F, Carroll M, Young W. An acute bout of static stretching: effects on force and jumping performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:1389&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000135775.51937.53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Anvar SH, Graham A, Zahiri A, et al. Acute effects of various stretching techniques on range of motion&#x202f;: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;9:107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10645614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37962709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budini F, Tilp M. Changes in H-reflex amplitude to muscle stretch and lengthening in humans. Rev Neurosci. 2016;27:511&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/revneuro-2016-0001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27089411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weppler CH, Magnusson SP. Increasing muscle extensibility: a matter of increasing length or modifying sensation? Phys Ther. 2010;90:438&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20090012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20075147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magid A, Law DJ. Myofibrils bear most of the resting tension in frog skeletal muscle. Science. 1979;1985(230):1280&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4071053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, McCarter R, Wright J, Beverly J, Ramirez-Mitchell R. Viscoelasticity of the sarcomere matrix of skeletal muscles. The titin-myosin composite filament is a dual-stage molecular spring. Biophys J. 1993;64:1161&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-3495(93)81482-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1262434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8494977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado LG, Makarenko I, Andresen C, Kr&#xfc;ger M, Opitz CA, Linke WA. Isoform diversity of giant proteins in relation to passive and active contractile properties of rabbit skeletal muscles. J Gen Physiol. 2005;126:461&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1085/jgp.200509364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2266601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16230467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson MC, Kr&#xfc;ger M, Meyer L, Ahnlund L, Gransberg L, Linke WA, et al. Fibre type-specific increase in passive muscle tension in spinal cord-injured subjects with spasticity. J Physiol. 2006;577:339&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.116749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2000690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16931550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajdosik RL. Passive extensibility of skeletal muscle: review of the literature with clinical implications. Clin Biomech. 2001;16:87&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0268-0033(00)00061-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11222927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg TK, Caulfield JB. Morphology of connective tissue in skeletal muscle. Tissue Cell. 1980;12:197&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0040-8166(80)90061-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7361300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama K, Kimura S, Yoshidomi H, Sawada H, Kikuchi M. Molecular size and shape of &#x3b2;-connectin, an elastic protein of striated muscle1. The Journal of Biochemistry. 1984;95:1423&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.jbchem.a134750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6746614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Waugh CM, Miller SC, Thorlund JB, Aagaard P, et al. Range of motion, neuromechanical, and architectural adaptations to plantar flexor stretch training in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117:452&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00204.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24947023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert RD, Bolsterlee B, Gandevia SC. Passive changes in muscle length. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:1445&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00673.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto MD, Nosaka K, Wakeling JM, Blazevich AJ. Human in vivo medial gastrocnemius gear during active and passive muscle lengthening: effect of inconsistent methods and nomenclature on data interpretation. Biol Open. 2023. 10.1242/bio.060023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/bio.060023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37584384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Shiotani H, Evangelidis PE, Sado N, Kawakami Y. Three-dimensional architecture of human medial gastrocnemius fascicles <i>in vivo</i>: regional variation and its dependence on muscle size. J Anat. 2022;241:1324&#x2013;35.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.13750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9644967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin DD, Hodgson JA, Reggie Edgerton V, Sinha S. In vivo intramuscular fascicle-aponeuroses dynamics of the human medial gastrocnemius during plantarflexion and dorsiflexion of the foot. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:1276&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.91598.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Behm DG, Wirth K, Keiner M, Schiemann S, et al. Effects of chronic static stretching on maximal strength and muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis with meta-regression. Sports Med Open. 2024;10:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00706-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11026323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38637473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazett-Jones DM, Gibson MH, McBride JM. Sprint and vertical jump performances are not affected by six weeks of static hamstring stretching. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815f99a4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaRoche DP, Lussier MV, Roy SJ. Chronic stretching and voluntary muscle force. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:589&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181636aef</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross MD. Effect of a 15-day pragmatic hamstring stretching program on hamstring flexibility and single hop for distance test performance. Res Sports Med. 2007;15:271&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438620701693298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18158692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanziano DC, Roos BA, Perry AC, Lai S, Signorile JF. The effects of an active-assisted stretching program on functional performance in elderly persons: a pilot study. Clin Interv Aging. 2009;4:115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2685233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19503774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batista LH, Vilar AC, de Almeida Ferreira JJ, Rebelatto JR, Salvini TF. Active stretching improves flexibility, joint torque, and functional mobility in older women. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2009;88:815&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e3181b72149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Kokkonen J, Arnall DA, Li L. Acute stretching increases postural stability in nonbalance trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:3095&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182430185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Kokkonen J, Winchester JB, Kalani W, Peterson K, Kenly MS, et al. A 10-week stretching program increases strength in the contralateral muscle. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:832&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182281b41</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22297415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima KMM, Carneiro SP, Alves DDS. Assessment of muscle architecture of the biceps femoris and vastus lateralis by ultrasound after a chronic stretching program. Clin J Sport Med. 2015;25:55&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24451696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda N, Ryushi T. Effects of 6-week static stretching of knee extensors on flexibility, muscle strength, jump performance, and muscle endurance. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:715&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30161088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell SL, Bilodeau RLS, Cox MJ, Behm DG. Cross education training effects are evident with twice daily, self-administered band stretch training. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18:544&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6683624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31427877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moltubakk MM, Villars FO, Magulas MM, Magnusson SP, Seynnes OR, Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J. Altered triceps surae muscle-tendon unit properties after 6 months of static stretching. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:1975&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa GM, Trajano GS, Dantas GAF, Silva BR, Vieira WHB. Chronic Effects of Static and Dynamic Stretching on Hamstrings Eccentric Strength and Functional Performance: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:2031&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Nosaka K, Chen HL, Lin MJ, Tseng KW, Chen TC. Effects of flexibility training on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:491&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181f315ad</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E, Bianco A, Paoli A, Palma A. The relation between stretching typology and stretching duration: the effects on range of motion. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39:243&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0044-101146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29506306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala F, de Sainz Baranda P, De Ste Croix M, Santonja F. Comparison of active stretching technique in males with normal and limited hamstring flexibility. Phys Ther Sport. 2013;14:98&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2012.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23007137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala F, de Sainz Baranda And&#xfa;jar P. Effect of 3 different active stretch durations on hip flexion range of motion. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:430&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c0674f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20072058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sainz Baranda P, Ayala F. Chronic flexibility improvement after 12 week of stretching program utilizing the ACSM recommendations: hamstring flexibility. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31:389&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0030-1249082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20309785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Bedoya J, Vernetta-Santana M, Robles-Fuentes A, Ariza-Vargas L. Effect of three types of flexibility training on active and passive hip range of motion. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2013;53:304&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23715256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyon M, Felton L, Galloway S. A comparison of two stretching modalities on lower-limb range of motion measurements in recreational dancers. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:2144&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b3e198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriani DJ, Terry ME, Haines MA, Tabibnia AP, Lyssanova O. Effect of stretch frequency and sex on the rate of gain and rate of loss in muscle flexibility during a hamstring-stretching program. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:2119&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823b862a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22027850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coledam DHC, Arruda GAde, Oliveira ARde. Chronic effect of static stretching performed during warm-up on flexibility in children. Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum. 2012;14:296&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Ikezoe T, Takeno Y, Ichihashi N. Effects of a 4-week static stretch training program on passive stiffness of human gastrocnemius muscle-tendon unit in vivo. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(7):2749&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2250-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkonen J, Nelson AG, Eldredge C, Winchester JB. Chronic static stretching improves exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1825&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3181238a2b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Freitas J, Almeida N, Vaz JR, Freitas SR. Which stretching instruction should be given to assess joint maximal range of motion? J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2022;31:45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2022.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35710220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Freundorfer P, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Behm DG, Konrad A, Schmidt T. Effects of chronic static stretching interventions on jumping and sprinting performance&#x2013;a systematic review with multilevel meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1372689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38595642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson SP, Simonsen EB, Aagaard P, So&#xf8;rensen H, Kj&#xe6;r M. A mechanism for altered flexibility in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 1996;497:291&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1996.sp021768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1160931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8951730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes BT, Harter RA, Widrick JJ, Williams DP, Hoffman MA, Hicks-Little CA. Lack of neuromuscular origins of adaptation after a long-term stretching program. J Sport Rehabil. 2012;21:99&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.21.2.99</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22387809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Tilp M. Increased range of motion after static stretching is not due to changes in muscle and tendon structures. Clin Biomech. 2014;29:636&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2014.04.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Konrad A. Critical evaluation and recalculation of current systematic reviews with meta-analysis on the effects of acute and chronic stretching on passive properties and passive peak torque. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:3153&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05564-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39066912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson CL, Kim BDH, Bourcet MR, Jones GR, Jakobi JM. Stretch training induces unequal adaptation in muscle fascicles and thickness in medial and lateral gastrocnemii. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27:1597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade RJ, Freitas SR, Hug F, Le Sant G, Lacourpaille L, Gross R, et al. Chronic effects of muscle and nerve-directed stretching on tissue mechanics. J Appl Physiol. 2020;129:1011&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00239.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo S, C&#xe8; E, Bisconti A, Rampichini S, Doria C, Borrelli M, et al. The effects of 12 weeks of static stretch training on the functional, mechanical, and architectural characteristics of the triceps surae muscle-tendon complex. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1743&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04654-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8144166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Anvar SH, Graham A, Zahiri A, et al. Chronic effects of stretching on range of motion with consideration of potential moderating variables: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:186&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2023.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno T. Effects of dynamic stretching velocity on joint range of motion, muscle strength, and subjective fatigue. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36:2440&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno T. Changes in joint range of motion and muscle&#x2013;tendon unit stiffness after varying amounts of dynamic stretching. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:2157&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1260149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27892823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan ED, Everett KL, Smith DB, Pollner C, Thompson BJ, Sobolewski EJ, et al. Acute effects of different volumes of dynamic stretching on vertical jump performance, flexibility and muscular endurance. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2014;34:485&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa PB, Herda TJ, Herda AA, Cramer JT. Effects of dynamic stretching on strength, muscle imbalance, and muscle activation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46:586&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24042312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Xin Y, Lee KW, Lin MJ, Lin JJ. Acute effects of different dynamic exercises on hamstring strain risk factors. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0191801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0191801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29390001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaggers JR, Swank AM, Frost KL, Lee CD. The acute effects of dynamic and ballistic stretching on vertical jump height, force, and power. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1844&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181854a3d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18841078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahieu NN, McNair P, De Muynck M, Stevens V, Blanckaert I, Smits N, et al. Effect of Static and Ballistic Stretching on the Muscle-Tendon Tissue Properties. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:494&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000247004.40212.f7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Tilp M. Effects of ballistic stretching training on the properties of human muscle and tendon structures. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117:29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00195.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. Warm up i: potential mechanisms and the effects of passive warm up on exercise performance. Sports Med. 2003;33:439&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333060-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12744717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordez A, McNair PJ, Casari P, Cornu C. The effect of angular velocity and cycle on the dissipative properties of the knee during passive cyclic stretching: a matter of viscosity or solid friction. Clin Biomech. 2009;24:77&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2008.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19064307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E, Ficarra S, Nunes JP, Paoli A, Bellafiore M, Palma A, et al. Does stretching training influence muscular strength? A systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37:1145&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36525533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opplert J, Babault N. Acute effects of dynamic stretching on mechanical properties result from both muscle-tendon stretching and muscle warm-up. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18:351&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opplert J, Genty JB, Babault N. Do stretch durations affect muscle mechanical and neurophysiological properties? Int J Sports Med. 2016;37:673&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-104934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skopal LK, Drinkwater EJ, Behm DG. Application of mobility training methods in sporting populations: a systematic review of performance adaptations. J Sports Sci. 2024;42:46&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2321006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38433623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feland JB, Marin HN. Effect of submaximal contraction intensity in contract-relax proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38:e18&#x2013;e18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2003.010967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15273211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowlands AV, Marginson VF, Lee J. Chronic flexibility gains: effect of isometric contraction duration during proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching techniques. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2003;74:47&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2003.10609063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12659475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laporte Y, Lloyd DPC. Nature and significance of the reflex connections established by large afferent fibers of muscular origin. American Journal of Physiology-Legacy Content. 1952;169:609&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajplegacy.1952.169.3.609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14943853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzullo J. The gate control theory of pain. Br Med J. 1978;2:586&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.2.6137.586-a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1607474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">698601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melzack R. Pain: Past, present and future. Can J Exp Psychol. 1993;47:615&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0078871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8124287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarczuk SL, Maniar N, Opar DA, Duhig SJ, Shield A, Barrett RS, et al. Mechanical, material and morphological adaptations of healthy lower limb tendons to mechanical loading: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52:2405&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01695-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35657492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Gad M, Tilp M. Effect of PNF stretching training on the properties of human muscle and tendon structures. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25:346&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24716522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahieu NN, Cools A, De Wilde B, Boon M, Witvrouw E. Effect of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching on the plantar flexor muscle-tendon tissue properties. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19:553&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2008.00815.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18627559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempke L, Wilkinson R, Murray C, Stanek J. The effectiveness of PNF versus static stretching on increasing hip-flexion range of motion. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27:289&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2016-0098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28182516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>