<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41131075</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Machine learning models for mechanical properties prediction of basalt fiber-reinforced concrete incorporating graphical user interface.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37029</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37029</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37029</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-20304-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>One of the most significant advancements in basalt fiber (BF) technology is its application in Basalt fiber reinforced polymers (BFRP). The production of BFRP utilizes basalt rock, a naturally abundant resource, resulting in a composite that generates approximately 74% less carbon emissions compared to traditional steel, aligning with global sustainability goals. This study employs previously published experimental datasets on basalt fiber-reinforced concrete (BFRC) to statistically predict compressive strength (CS) and splitting tensile strength (STS) using advanced machine learning. The dataset includes 270 CS and 267 STS samples, split into 70% training and 30% testing, enabling accurate, data-driven predictions without the need for new laboratory experiments. In addition to the parametric analysis of Shapley additive explanation (SHAP), machine learning models were used, namely support vector regression (SVR), random forest regression (RFR), decision tree (DT), bagging regressor (BR), and gradient boosting regression (GBR) with grid search hyper-tuning. Additionally, the model generated SHAP interaction plots to show the impact of each characteristic on an individual prediction. The results found that GBR model performance is the most precise prediction of compressive strength compared to other models, achieving an R<sup>2</sup> of 0.99 for training phase and R<sup>2</sup> of 0.86 for testing phase. But SVR model outperforms the other four models in STS prediction, with the coefficient of determination (R<sup>2</sup>) value of 0.99 during the training stage and R<sup>2</sup> of 0.97 for the testing stage. The Shapley additive explanations (SHAP) method was used to display the effect of each input parameters on model prediction. The cement and silica fume were found to have the highest positive influence on BFRC compressive and tensile strength. The basalt fiber (BF) diameter as an input parameter was found to have the highest effect on STC. Finally, the concrete designers can now easily and affordably predict CS and STS using a graphical user interface, without conducting expensive computations or experiments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haque</LastName><ForeName>Md Ehtesamul</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, CCSIT, King Faisal University, P.O. Box 380, 31982, Al-Ahsa, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arifuzzaman</LastName><ForeName>Md</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, College of Engineering, King Faisal University, P.O. Box 380, 31982, Al-Ahsa, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. marifuzzaman@kfu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Kaffayatullah</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, College of Engineering, King Faisal University, P.O. Box 380, 31982, Al-Ahsa, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azad</LastName><ForeName>A K M</ForeName><Initials>AKM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Faculty of Science, Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), 13318, Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alluqmani</LastName><ForeName>Ayed Eid</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Islamic University of Madinah, Prince Naif Ibn Abdulaziz, 42351, Medina, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kashem</LastName><ForeName>Abul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Leading University, Sylhet, 3112, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>(Grant No. KFU25014Y).</GrantID><Agency>This work was supported by the Deanship of Scientific Research, Vice Presidency for Graduate Studies and Scientific Research, King Faisal University, Saudi Arabia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basalt fiber-reinforced concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compressive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GUI-based prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SHAP analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Splitting tensile strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41131075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12549939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-20304-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-20304-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chin, S. C. et al. Predictive models for mechanical properties of hybrid fibres reinforced concrete containing bamboo and basalt fibres. <i>Structures</i>10.1016/j.istruc.2024.106093 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2024.106093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abood, E. A. et al. Machine learning-based prediction models for punching shear strength of fiber-reinforced polymer reinforced concrete slabs using a gradient-boosted regression tree. <i>Materials</i>10.3390/ma17163964 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17163964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basaran, B. Effect of steel&#x2013;FRP ratio and FRP wrapping layers on tensile properties of glass FRP-wrapped ribbed steel reinforcing bars. <i>Mater. Struct. Materiaux et Constr.</i>10.1617/s11527-021-01775-x (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-021-01775-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, J., Yao, T., Yue, J., Wang, M. &amp; Xia, S. Compressive strength prediction of BFRC based on a novel hybrid machine learning model. <i>Buildings</i>10.3390/buildings13081934 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13081934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, J., Wang, M., Yao, T., Tang, Y. &amp; Liu, H. Dynamic mechanical strength prediction of BFRC based on stacking ensemble learning and genetic algorithm optimization. <i>Buildings</i>10.3390/buildings13051155 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13051155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abed, M. A. et al. Structural performance of lightweight aggregate concrete reinforced by glass or basalt fiber reinforced polymer bars. <i>Polymers (Basel)</i><b>14</b>, 2142. 10.3390/polym14112142 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14112142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9182972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35683814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Y. et al. Study on the effect of salt solution on durability of basalt-fiber-reinforced polymer joints in high-temperature environment. <i>Polymers (Basel)</i><b>14</b>, 2250. 10.3390/polym14112250 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14112250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9183193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35683925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogrodowska, K., &#x141;uszcz, K. &amp; Garbacz, A. Nanomodification, hybridization and temperature impact on shear strength of basalt fiber-reinforced polymer bars. <i>Polymers (Basel)</i><b>13</b>, 2585. 10.3390/polym13162585 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym13162585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8398858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34451124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, M. et al. Prediction of constitutive model for basalt fiber reinforced concrete based on PSO-KNN. <i>Heliyon</i>10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e32240 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e32240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11637177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39668966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czig&#xe1;ny, T., Vad, J. &amp; P&#xf6;l&#xf6;skei, K. Basalt fiber as a reinforcement of polymer composites. <i>Period. Polytech. Mech. Eng.</i><b>49</b>(1), 3&#x2013;14 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Jia, B., Huang, H. &amp; Mou, Y. Experimental study on basic mechanical properties of basalt fiber reinforced concrete. <i>Materials</i><b>13</b>, 1362. 10.3390/ma13061362 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13061362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7143040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D., Ju, Y., Shen, H. &amp; Xu, L. Mechanical properties of high performance concrete reinforced with basalt fiber and polypropylene fiber. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>197</b>, 464&#x2013;473. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.181 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, C. &amp; Wu, W. Using ESEM to analyze the microscopic property of basalt fiber reinforced asphalt concrete. <i>Int. J. Pavement Res. Technol.</i><b>11</b>, 374&#x2013;380. 10.1016/j.ijprt.2017.09.010 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijprt.2017.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari, D. F. A. et al. Assessing the impact of pozzolanic materials on the mechanical characteristics of UHPC: Analysis, and modeling study. <i>Discov. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2</b>, 96. 10.1007/s44290-025-00231-x (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44290-025-00231-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahjoubi, S., Barhemat, R., Meng, W. &amp; Bao, Y. AI-guided auto-discovery of low-carbon cost-effective ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC) (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severcan, M. H. Prediction of splitting tensile strength from the compressive strength of concrete using GEP. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>21</b>, 1937&#x2013;1945. 10.1007/s00521-011-0597-3 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-011-0597-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, M. C., Yoo, D. Y. &amp; Gupta, R. Machine learning-based prediction for compressive and flexural strengths of steel fiber-reinforced concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121117 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, S. &amp; Sihag, P. Prediction of the compressive strength of concrete using various predictive modeling techniques. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>34</b>, 6535&#x2013;6545. 10.1007/s00521-021-06820-y (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-021-06820-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhi, S. K. &amp; Patro, S. K. Application of R-curve, ANCOVA, and RSM techniques on fracture toughness enhancement in PET fiber-reinforced concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>411</b>, 134644. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134644 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Lin, J., Zhao, D., Shi, G., Wu, H., Wei, T., Li, D. &amp; Zhang, J. A BFRC compressive strength prediction method via kernel extreme learning machine-genetic algorithm (2022). https://www.elsevier.com/open-access/userlicense/1.0/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanzadeh, A., Vatin, N. I., Hematibahar, M., Kharun, M. &amp; Shooshpasha, I. Prediction of the mechanical properties of basalt fiber reinforced high-performance concrete using machine learning techniques. <i>Materials</i>10.3390/ma15207165 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15207165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9607351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36295231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari, D. F. A., Shkur, S. S., Rafiq, S. K., Hilmi, H. D. M. &amp; Ahmad, S. A. Prediction model of compressive strength for eco-friendly palm oil clinker light weight concrete: A review and data analysis. <i>Discov. Civ. Eng.</i>10.1007/s44290-024-00119-2 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44290-024-00119-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhi, S. K., Dwibedy, S. &amp; Patro, S. K. Managing waste for production of low-carbon concrete mix using uncertainty-aware machine learning model. <i>Environ. Res.</i>10.1016/j.envres.2025.121918 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.121918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40409446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, D. A., AlGoody, A. Y., Askari, D. F. A., Ahmad, M. R. J. &amp; Ahmad, S. A. Evaluating the effect of using waste concrete as partial replacement of coarse aggregate in concrete, experimental and modeling. <i>J. Build. Pathol. Rehabil.</i>10.1007/s41024-024-00521-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41024-024-00521-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, S. A., Ahmed, H. U., Rafiq, S. K., Jafer, F. S. &amp; Fqi, K. O. A comparative analysis of simulation approaches for predicting permeability and compressive strength in pervious concrete. <i>Low-Carbon Mater. Green Constr.</i>10.1007/s44242-024-00041-x (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44242-024-00041-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almohammed, F. &amp; Soni, J. Using random forest and random tree model to predict the splitting tensile strength for the concrete with basalt fiber reinforced concrete. <i>IOP Conf. Ser. Earth Environ. Sci.</i>10.1088/1755-1315/1110/1/012072 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/1110/1/012072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota, S. C., Yadav, A., Khatri, A., Singh, T. &amp; Dahal, D. Explainable hybridized ensemble machine learning for the prognosis of the compressive strength of recycled plastic-based sustainable concrete with experimental validation. <i>Multiscale Multidiscip. Model. Exp. Des.</i><b>7</b>, 6073&#x2013;6096. 10.1007/s41939-024-00567-4 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41939-024-00567-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakiroglu, C. et al. Explainable ensemble learning data-driven modeling of mechanical properties of fiber-reinforced rubberized recycled aggregate concrete. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i>10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107279 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abushanab, A., Wakjira, T. G. &amp; Alnahhal, W. Machine learning-based flexural capacity prediction of corroded RC beams with an efficient and user-friendly tool. <i>Sustainability (Switzerland)</i>10.3390/su15064824 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15064824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, D. C., Wang, W. J., Mangalathu, S., Hu, G. &amp; Wu, T. Implementing ensemble learning methods to predict the shear strength of RC deep beams with/without web reinforcements. <i>Eng. Struct.</i>10.1016/j.engstruct.2021.111979 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2021.111979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, D., Li, M., Kang, J., Liu, C. &amp; Li, C. Experimental studies on the seismic behavior of reinforced concrete beam-column joints strengthened with basalt fiber-reinforced polymer sheets. <i>Constr. Build Mater.</i>10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122901 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoque, M. A., Shrestha, A., Sapkota, S. C., Ahmed, A. &amp; Paudel, S. Prediction of autogenous shrinkage in ultra-high-performance concrete (UHPC) using hybridized machine learning. <i>Asian J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>26</b>, 649&#x2013;665. 10.1007/s42107-024-01212-8 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42107-024-01212-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota, S. C. et al. Optimizing high-strength concrete compressive strength with explainable machine learning, multiscale and multidisciplinary modeling. <i>Exp. Des.</i>10.1007/s41939-025-00737-y (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41939-025-00737-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Y. &amp; Unluer, C. Modeling the mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete using hybrid machine learning algorithms. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl.</i>10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106812 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Dai, C., Li, W. &amp; Chen, Y. Prediction of compressive strength of recycled aggregate concrete using machine learning and Bayesian optimization methods. <i>Front. Earth Sci. (Lausanne)</i>10.3389/feart.2023.1112105 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2023.1112105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota, S. C. et al. Enhancing shear strength predictions of UHPC beams through hybrid machine learning approaches. <i>Sci. Rep.</i>10.1038/s41598-025-13444-y (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-13444-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12318006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40753130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota, S.C., Sapkota, S. &amp; Saini, G. Prediction of split tensile strength of recycled aggregate concrete leveraging explainable hybrid XGB with optimization algorithm (2024). 10.21203/rs.3.rs-4019630/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhi, S. K. &amp; Patro, S. K. Compressive strength prediction of PET fiber-reinforced concrete using Dolphin echolocation optimized decision tree-based machine learning algorithms. <i>Asian J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>25</b>, 977&#x2013;996. 10.1007/s42107-023-00826-8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42107-023-00826-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najmoddin, A., Etemadfard, H., Hosseini, A. &amp; Ghalehnovi, S. M. Multi-output machine learning for predicting the mechanical properties of BFRC. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02818 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, Z. W. et al. Study of the flexural behavior of basalt fiber-reinforced concrete beams with basalt fiber-reinforced polymer bars and steel bars. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04433 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duranay, Z. B., Aslan Top&#xe7;uo&#x11f;lu, Y. &amp; G&#xfc;rocak, Z. Estimation of compressive strength of basalt fiber-reinforced kaolin clay mixture using extreme learning machine. <i>Materials</i>10.3390/ma18020245 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18020245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11766673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39859715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Ke, Z., Liu, W., Zhang, P., Cui, S. &amp; Zhao, N. Compressive strength prediction of basalt fiber reinforced concrete based on interpretive machine learning (2024). 10.21203/rs.3.rs-4493851/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeagwuani, C. C. Estimation of modified expansive soil CBR with multivariate adaptive regression splines, random forest and gradient boosting machine. <i>Innov. Infrastruct. Solut.</i>10.1007/s41062-021-00568-z (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41062-021-00568-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Jabeur, S., Gharib, C., Mefteh-Wali, S. &amp; Ben Arfi, W. CatBoost model and artificial intelligence techniques for corporate failure prediction. <i>Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change</i>10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120658 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang, N. D. Machine learning-based estimation of the compressive strength of self-compacting concrete: A multi-dataset study. <i>Mathematics</i>10.3390/math10203771 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10203771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawagreh, K., Gaber, M. M. &amp; Elyan, E. Random forests: From early developments to recent advancements. <i>Syst. Sci. Control Eng.</i><b>2</b>, 602&#x2013;609. 10.1080/21642583.2014.956265 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21642583.2014.956265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bbeiman, L. Bagging predictors (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir Amin, M. et al. Prediction model for rice husk ash concrete using AI approach: Boosting and bagging algorithms. <i>Structures</i><b>50</b>, 745&#x2013;757. 10.1016/j.istruc.2023.02.080 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.02.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdal, H. I. Two-level and hybrid ensembles of decision trees for high performance concrete compressive strength prediction. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>26</b>, 1689&#x2013;1697. 10.1016/j.engappai.2013.03.014 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2013.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Chaabene, W., Flah, M. &amp; Nehdi, M. L. Machine learning prediction of mechanical properties of concrete: Critical review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119889 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J., Sun, Y. &amp; Zhang, J. Reduction of computational error by optimizing SVR kernel coefficients to simulate concrete compressive strength through the use of a human learning optimization algorithm. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>38</b>, 3151&#x2013;3168. 10.1007/s00366-021-01305-x (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-021-01305-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabduljabbar, H. et al. Modeling the capacity of engineered cementitious composites for self-healing using AI-based ensemble techniques. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>18</b>, e01805. 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01805 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go, C. et al. On developing accurate prediction models for residual tensile strength of GFRP bars under alkaline-concrete environment using a combined ensemble machine learning methods. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>18</b>, e02157. 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02157 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhi, S. K., Dwibedy, S. &amp; Patro, S. K. Managing waste for production of low-carbon concrete mix using uncertainty-aware machine learning model. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>279</b>, 121918. 10.1016/j.envres.2025.121918 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.121918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40409446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakjira, T. G., Abushanab, A. &amp; Alam, M. S. Hybrid machine learning model and predictive equations for compressive stress-strain constitutive modelling of confined ultra-high-performance concrete (UHPC) with normal-strength steel and high-strength steel spirals. <i>Eng. Struct.</i>10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.117633 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.117633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulasooriya, W. K. V. J. B. et al. Modeling strength characteristics of basalt fiber reinforced concrete using multiple explainable machine learning with a graphical user interface. <i>Sci. Rep.</i>10.1038/s41598-023-40513-x (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-40513-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10423212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakiroglu, C., Ayd&#x131;n, Y., Bekda&#x15f;, G. &amp; Geem, Z. W. Interpretable predictive modelling of basalt fiber reinforced concrete splitting tensile strength using ensemble machine learning methods and SHAP approach. <i>Materials</i><b>16</b>, 4578. 10.3390/ma16134578 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16134578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37444890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulasooriya, W. K. V. J. B. et al. Modeling strength characteristics of basalt fiber reinforced concrete using multiple explainable machine learning with a graphical user interface. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 13138. 10.1038/s41598-023-40513-x (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-40513-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10423212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>