<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41422756</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-2782</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>196</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neural networks : the official journal of the International Neural Network Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neural Netw</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>CSCL: Bridging the plasticity-stability gap in continuous supervised contrastive learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108179</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108179</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neunet.2025.108179</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0893-6080(25)01059-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In real-world scenarios characterized by non-stationary data streams, Continual Learning (CL) aims to enable learners to acquire information from new classes without interrupting previously learned knowledge. Recently, several empirical studies have indicated that incorporating Supervised Contrastive Learning (SCL) into CL results in notable performance improvements. This paper delves into its underlying reason and theoretically suggests the SCL's potential to bolster the model's resistance to forgetting. However, despite the advancements, this paper also notes that models trained under SCL still exhibit challenges in learning plasticity and memory stability within representation space throughout the continual learning process. To address these challenges, this paper proposes a novel framework named Continual Supervised Contrastive Learning (CSCL). CSCL incorporates its key components, the De-redundant Interpolation Method and the Magnetic Force Method, into the SCL training paradigm, aiming to enhance the model's adaptability to new tasks and its ability to retain the knowledge of previously learned tasks. The De-redundant Interpolation Method enhances negative sample diversity through intra-class de-redundancy and inter-class linear interpolation, promoting better learning plasticityof new class representations. Concurrently, the Magnetic Force Method ensures inter-class separation via magnetic repulsion while fostering intra-class aggregation through magnetic attraction, thus forming a uniform distribution of all classes in latent space and supporting the memory stability of old class representations. Extensive experimental validations under popular benchmark image classification datasets indicate the advanced performance of the proposed framework. Additionally, the De-redundant Interpolation Method and Magnetic Force Method demonstrate their flexibility by seamlessly integrating with existing SCL-based continual learning frameworks as plug-ins, boosting classification accuracy by 2.20 to 15.56 points.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: xiongyi@mail.ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Liqi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Software Engineering, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: xiangliqi@mail.ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Qianyue</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: cqy_1999@mail.ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Zongwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Software Engineering, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: zzw1988@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lian</LastName><ForeName>Zirui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: ustclzr@mail.ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: congjia@mail.ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xuehai</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230026, China; Suzhou Institute for Advanced Research, University of Science and Technology of China, Suzhou, 215123, China. Electronic address: xhzhou@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neural Netw</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8805018</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-6080</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007858" MajorTopicYN="Y">Learning</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069553" MajorTopicYN="Y">Supervised Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Catastrophic forgetting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Continual learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contrastive learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Representation knowledge</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41422756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2025.108179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0893-6080(25)01059-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>