<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792683</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2466</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of combined inspiratory muscle training and positive expiratory pressure therapy on pulmonary function, respiratory muscle strength, exercise capacity and dyspnea in stable group E COPD patients.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12890-025-04078-x</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jalal</LastName><ForeName>Latifullah</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aksakal</LastName><ForeName>Alperen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey. alperen.aksakal@atauni.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerget</LastName><ForeName>Bu&#x11f;ra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Diseases, Aksaray University School of Medicine, Aksaray, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>U&#xe7;ar</LastName><ForeName>Elif Y&#x131;lmazel</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Araz</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;mer</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sa&#x11f;lam</LastName><ForeName>Leyla</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Ataturk University School of Medicine, Yakutiye, Erzurum, 25240, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akg&#xfc;n</LastName><ForeName>Metin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, A&#x11f;r&#x131; &#x130;brahim &#xc7;e&#xe7;en University School of Medicine, A&#x11f;r&#x131;, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968563</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2466</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COPD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inspiratory muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positive expiratory pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary function tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The Institutional Review Board at Erzurum Atat&#xfc;rk University Faculty of Medicine Ethics Committee approved this study (Board date: 06.07.2023, protocol number: B.30.2ATA.0.01.00/487), which was conducted in compliance with the 2013 version of the 1975 Helsinki Declaration. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-025-04078-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12890-025-04078-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; A, Celli BR, Criner GJ, Halpin D, Anzueto A, Barnes P, et al. Global initiative for chronic obstructive lung disease 2023 report: GOLD executive summary. J Pan Afr Thorac Soc. 2022;4(2):58&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putcha N, Drummond MB, Wise RA, Hansel NN, editors. Comorbidities and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: prevalence, influence on outcomes, and management. Seminars in respiratory and critical care medicine. Thieme Medical; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahaije AJ, van Helvoort HA, Dekhuijzen P, Heijdra YF. Physiologic limitations during daily life activities in COPD patients. Respir Med. 2010;104(8):1152&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer J, Rebbapragada V, Borson S, Goldstein R, Kunik ME, Yohannes AM, et al. Anxiety and depression in COPD: current understanding, unanswered questions, and research needs. Chest. 2008;134(4):S43&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ur Rehman A, Hassali MAA, Abbas S, Ali IABH, Harun SN, Muneswarao J, et al. Pharmacological and non-pharmacological management of COPD; limitations and future prospects: a review of current literature. J Public Health. 2020;28(4):357&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korkmaz C, Demirbas S, Vatansev H, Yildirim E, Teke T, Zamani A. Effects of comprehensive and intensive pulmonary rehabilitation and nutritional support on quality of life and functional status in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. J Int Med Res. 2020;48(4):0300060520919567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahnert K, J&#xf6;rres RA, Behr J, Welte T. The diagnosis and treatment of COPD and its comorbidities. Deutsches &#xc4;rzteblatt International. 2023;120(25):434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Hu D, Xu Y, Wu L, Lou L. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ann Med. 2022;54(1):262&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Zhu Y, Wang Y, Mo Y, Shi X, Liang WM, et al. Effects of pulmonary rehabilitation combined with inspiratory muscle training on lung function and exercise capacity in older patients with COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2025;12:1621375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JA, Whitelaw WA. The assessment of maximal respiratory mouth pressures in adults. Respir Care. 2009;54(10):1348&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson JL, Kim MJ, Sharp JT, Larson DA. Inspiratory muscle training with a pressure threshold breathing device in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1988;138(3):689&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. GOLD COPD report: 2023 update. Lancet Respiratory Med. 2023;11(1):18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cri&#xe9;e C, Sorichter S, Smith H, Kardos P, Merget R, Heise D, et al. Body plethysmography&#x2013;its principles and clinical use. Respir Med. 2011;105(7):959&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Society ER, Society AT. ATS/ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166(4):518&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macintyre N, Crapo R, Viegi G, Johnson D, Van Der Grinten C, Brusasco V, et al. Standardisation of the single-breath determination of carbon monoxide uptake in the lung. Eur Respir J. 2005;26(4):720&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bestall J, Paul E, Garrod R, Garnham R, Jones P, Wedzicha J. Usefulness of the medical research Council (MRC) dyspnoea scale as a measure of disability in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Thorax. 1999;54(7):581&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PW, Tabberer M, Chen W-H. Creating scenarios of the impact of COPD and their relationship to COPD assessment test (CAT&#x2122;) scores. BMC Pulm Med. 2011;11(1):42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mador MJ, Rodis A, Magalang UJ. Reproducibility of Borg scale measurements of dyspnea during exercise in patients with COPD. Chest. 1995;107(6):1590&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HIRATSUKA T. Quality of life measurements using a linear analog scale for elderly patients with chronic lung disease. Intern Med. 1993;32(11):832&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright PL, McBurnie MA, Bittner V, Tracy RP, McNamara R, Arnold A, et al. The 6-min walk test: a quick measure of functional status in elderly adults. Chest. 2003;123(2):387&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi M, Froutan R, Moghadam AB. Impact of inspiratory muscle training and positive expiratory pressure on lung function and extubation success of ICU patients: a randomized controlled trial. Archives Acad Emerg Med. 2024;12(1):e59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Society AT. ATS/ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:518&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagevik Ols&#xe9;n M, Westerdahl E. Positive expiratory pressure in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#x2013;a systematic review. Respiration. 2009;77(1):110&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lommatzsch M, Niewerth A, Klotz J, Schulte-Herbr&#xfc;ggen O, Zingler C, Schuff-Werner P, et al. Platelet and plasma BDNF in lower respiratory tract infections of the adult. Respir Med. 2007;101(7):1493&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner P, McConnell A. Respiratory muscle training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: inspiratory, expiratory, or both? Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2005;11(2):140&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Shin M-J, Lee JM, Huh S, Shin YB. Effects of a new respiratory muscle training device in community-dwelling elderly men: an open-label, randomized, non-inferiority trial. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehani SHM. Comparative study of two different respiratory training protocols in elderly patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Clin Interv Aging. 2017:1705&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo RI, Azambuja AM, Cureau FV, Sbruzzi G. Inspiratory muscle training in COPD. Respir Care. 2020;65(8):1189&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Sarmiento A, Orozco-Levi M, Guell R, Barreiro E, Hernandez N, Mota S, et al. Inspiratory muscle training in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: structural adaptation and physiologic outcomes. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166(11):1491&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner P, Magadle R, Beckerman M, Weiner M, Berar-Yanay N. Maintenance of inspiratory muscle training in COPD patients: one year follow-up. Eur Respir J. 2003;23(1):61&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harver A, Mahler DA, Daubenspeck JA. Targeted inspiratory muscle training improves respiratory muscle function and reduces dyspnea in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Ann Intern Med. 1989;111(2):117&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisner C, Colby LA, Borstad J. Therapeutic exercise: foundations and techniques. Fa Davis; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussos CS, Macklem P. Diaphragmatic fatigue in man. J Appl Physiol. 1977;43(2):189&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell DE, Webb KA. The major limitation to exercise performance in COPD is dynamic hyperinflation. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105(2):753&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goligher EC, Laghi F, Detsky ME, Farias P, Murray A, Brace D, et al. Measuring diaphragm thickness with ultrasound in mechanically ventilated patients: feasibility, reproducibility and validity. Intensive Care Med. 2015;41(4):642&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>