<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41906071</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2466</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of inspiratory muscle training on exercise capacity, muscle oxygenation and strength, physical activity, and dyspnea in patients with post-COVID-19 syndrome and pulmonary involvement: a randomized controlled triple-blinded study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12890-026-04249-4</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kavalc&#x131; Kol</LastName><ForeName>Ba&#x15f;ak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5346-8753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Gazi University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye. basak.kavalci@ahievran.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pilot Health Coordinatorship, Geothermal Resource Rehabilitation Application and Research Center, K&#x131;r&#x15f;ehir Ahi Evran University, K&#x131;r&#x15f;ehir, T&#xfc;rkiye. basak.kavalci@ahievran.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bo&#x15f;nak G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc;</LastName><ForeName>Meral</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3861-9912</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Cardiopulmonary Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Gazi University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baytok</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0745-4251</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Cardiopulmonary Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Gazi University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, K&#x131;rklareli University, K&#x131;rklareli, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Y&#x131;lmaz Demirci</LastName><ForeName>Nilg&#xfc;n</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6160-3778</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Pulmonology, Gazi University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>TDK-2022-7639</GrantID><Agency>Gazi University Projects of Scientific Investigation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TDK-2022-7639</GrantID><Agency>Gazi University Projects of Scientific Investigation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968563</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2466</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise tolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle oxygenation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Gazi University Ethics Committee (11.01.2022, ID: 2022-093). All participants were informed of the purpose and procedures of the study, and written informed consent to participate was obtained prior to inclusion. Constent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41906071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-026-04249-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12890-026-04249-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Han X, Jiang N, Cao Y, Alwalid O, Gu J, et al. Radiological findings from 81 patients with COVID-19 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:425&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Jian W, Su Z, Chen M, Peng H, Peng P, et al. Abnormal pulmonary function in COVID-19 patients at time of hospital discharge. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:2001217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, Hishmeh L. Managing the long-term effects of COVID-19: summary of NICE, SIGN, and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ. 2021;372:n136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, Who clinical case definition working group on post-COVID-19 condition. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D, G&#xf3;mez-Mayordomo V, Florencio LL, Cuadrado ML, Plaza-Manzano G, et al. Prevalence of post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized survivors. Eur J Intern Med. 2021;92:55&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Murray B, Varsavsky T, Graham MS, Penfold RS, Bowyer RC, et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennigs JK, Huwe M, Hennigs A, Oqueka T, Simon M, Harbaum L, et al. Respiratory muscle dysfunction in long-COVID patients. Infection. 2022;50:1391&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Gu X, et al. 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital. Lancet. 2021;397:220&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324:603&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pleguezuelos E, Del Carmen A, Llorensi G, Carcole J, Casarramona P, Moreno E, et al. Severe loss of mechanical efficiency in COVID-19 patients. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2021;12:1056&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baratto C, Caravita S, Faini A, Perego GB, Senni M, Badano LP, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on exercise pathophysiology. J Appl Physiol. 2021;130:1470&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo FG, Fiotti N, Sisto UG, Nunnari A, Colla S, Mearelli F, et al. Skeletal muscle in hypoxia and inflammation: insights on the COVID-19 pandemic. Front Nutr. 2022;9:865402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Almeida K, Nogueira Alves IG, de Queiroz RS, de Castro MR, Gomes VA, Santos Fontoura FC, Brites C, Neto MG. A systematic review on physical function, activities of daily living and health-related quality of life in COVID-19 survivors. Chronic Illn. 2023;19(2):279&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1177/17423953221089309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menges D, Ballouz T, Anagnostopoulos A, Aschmann HE, Domenghino A, Fehr JS, Puhan MA. Burden of post-COVID-19 syndrome and implications for healthcare service planning: a population-based cohort study. PLoS ONE. 2021;12(7):e0254523. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0254523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell AK, Lomax M. The influence of inspiratory muscle work history and specific inspiratory muscle training upon human limb muscle fatigue. J Physiol. 2006;577:445&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt JD, Guenette JA, Rupert JL, McKenzie DC, Sheel AW. Inspiratory muscle training attenuates the human respiratory muscle metaboreflex. J Physiol. 2007;584:1019&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosnak-Guclu M, Arikan H, Savci S, Inal-Ince D, Tulumen E, Aytemir K, et al. Effects of inspiratory muscle training in patients with heart failure. Respir Med. 2011;105:1671&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katay&#x131;f&#xe7;&#x131; N, Bo&#x15f;nak G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc; M, &#x15e;en F. A comparison of inspiratory muscle strength and endurance training in pacemaker patients with heart failure. Heart Lung. 2022;55:49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marco E, Ram&#xed;rez-Sarmiento AL, Coloma A, Sartor M, Comin-Colet J, Vila J, et al. High-intensity versus sham inspiratory muscle training in patients with chronic heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2013;15:892&#x2013;901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno AM, Toledo-Arruda AC, Lima JS, Duarte CS, Villacorta H, N&#xf3;brega ACL. Inspiratory muscle training improves intercostal and forearm muscle oxygenation in patients with chronic heart failure. J Card Fail. 2017;23:672&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner LA, Tecklenburg-Lund SL, Chapman RF, Shei RJ, Wilhite DP, Mickleborough TD. The effect of inspiratory muscle training on respiratory and limb locomotor muscle deoxygenation. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37:598&#x2013;606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illi SK, Held U, Frank I, Spengler CM. Effect of respiratory muscle training on exercise performance in healthy individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2012;42(8):707&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geddes EL, Reid WD, Crowe J, O&#x2019;Brien K, Brooks D. Inspiratory muscle training in adults with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: an update of a systematic review. Thorax. 2008;63(10):893&#x2013;902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charususin N, Gosselink R, Decramer M, McConnell AK, Saey D, Maltais F, et al. Randomised controlled trial of inspiratory muscle training in COPD. Thorax. 2018;73(10):942&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karadall&#x131; MN, Bo&#x15f;nak G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc; M, Camc&#x131;o&#x11f;lu B, Kokturk N, T&#xfc;rkta&#x15f; H. Effects of inspiratory muscle training in subjects with sarcoidosis. Respir Care. 2016;61:483&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozalp O, Inal-Ince D, Cakmak A, Calik-Kutukcu E, Saglam M, Savci S, et al. High-intensity inspiratory muscle training in bronchiectasis. Respirology. 2019;24:246&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Corral T, Fabero-Garrido R, Plaza-Manzano G, Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Navarro-Santana M, L&#xf3;pez-de-Uralde-Villanueva I. Home-based respiratory muscle training on quality of life and exercise tolerance in long-term post-COVID-19. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2023;66:101709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNarry MA, Berg RMG, Shelley J, Hudson J, Saynor ZL, Duckers J, et al. Inspiratory muscle training enhances recovery post-COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2022;60:2103101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abodonya AM, Abdelbasset WK, Awad EA, Elalfy IE, Salem HA, Elsayed SH. Inspiratory muscle training for recovered COVID-19 patients after weaning from mechanical ventilation. Med (Baltim). 2021;100:e25339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan F, Ye T, Sun P, Gui S, Liang B, Li L, Zheng D, Wang J, Hesketh RL, Yang L, Zheng C. Time course of lung changes at chest CT during recovery from coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Radiology. 2020;295(3):715&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;lmaz Demirci N, U&#x11f;ra&#x15f; Dikmen A, Ta&#x15f;&#xe7;&#x131; C, Do&#x11f;an D, Arslan Y, &#xd6;cal N, Ta&#x15f;ar M, Bozlar U, Artuk C, Y&#x131;lmaz G, et al. Relationship between chest computed tomography findings and clinical conditions of coronavirus disease (COVID-19): a multicentre experience. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(9):e14459. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.14459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizzi F, Agosti A, Brero F, Cabini RF, Fantacci ME, Figini S, et al. Quantification of pulmonary involvement in COVID-19 pneumonia. Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg. 2022;17:229&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR, Gordon NF, Pescatello LS. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 8th ed. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanjer PH, Tammeling GJ, Cotes JE, Pedersen OF, Peslin R, Yernault JC. Lung volumes and forced ventilatory flows. Eur Respir J Suppl. 1993;16:5&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATS committee on proficiency standards for clinical pulmonary function laboratories. ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:111&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amput P, Poncumhak P, Konsanit S, Wongphon S. Test&#x2013;retest reliability and minimal detectable change of functional tests in post-COVID-19 patients. Adv Respir Med. 2025;93:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons WJ, Fruchter N, Sloan S, Levy RD. Reference values for a multiple repetition 6-minute walk test. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2001;21:87&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crum EM, O&#x2019;Connor WJ, Van Loo L, Valckx M, Stannard SR. Validity and reliability of the Moxy oxygen monitor. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:1037&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skotzke P, Engel FA, Sperlich B, Behrens M. Side differences and reproducibility of the Moxy muscle oxygenation signal. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews AW, Thomas MW, Bohannon RW. Normative values for isometric muscle force measurements obtained with hand-held dynamometers. Phys Ther. 1996;76:248&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentiplay BF, Perraton LG, Bower KJ, Adair B, Pua YH, Williams GP, et al. Assessment of lower limb muscle strength using hand-held dynamometry. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0140822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark T, Walker B, Phillips JK, Fejer R, Beck R. Hand-held dynamometry correlation with isokinetic dynamometry. PM R. 2011;3:472&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATS/ERS. ATS/ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:518&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadis Z, Kapreli E, Konstantinidou I, Oldham JA, Strimpakos N. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of maximal mouth pressure measurements. Respir Care. 2011;56:776&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lista-Paz A, Langer D, Barral-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Quintela-Del-R&#xed;o A, Gimeno-Santos E, Arbillaga-Etxarri A, et al. Maximal respiratory pressure reference equations. Arch Bronconeumol. 2023;59:813&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watz H, Waschki B, Meyer T, Magnussen H. Physical activity in patients with COPD. Eur Respir J. 2009;33:262&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth BE, Haskell WL, Herrmann SD, Meckes N, Bassett DR Jr, Tudor-Locke C, et al. Compendium of physical activities. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1575&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudor-Locke C, Bassett DR. How many steps/day are enough? Sports Med. 2004;34:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheers T, Philippaerts R, Lefevre J. Variability in physical activity patterns as measured by the SenseWear Armband. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1653&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrod R, Bestall JC, Paul EA, Wedzicha JA, Jones PW. Development of a standardized measure of activity of daily living in patients with severe COPD. Respir Med. 2000;94:589&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saka S, Savc&#x131; S, K&#xfc;t&#xfc;kc&#xfc; E, Sa&#x11f;lam M, Ya&#x11f;l&#x131; NV, &#x130;nce D, et al. Validity and reliability of the Turkish version of the London chest activity of daily living scale. Turk Thorac J. 2020;21:116&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armutlu K, Korkmaz NC, Keser I, Sumbuloglu V, Akbiyik DI, Guney Z, et al. The validity and reliability of the fatigue severity scale. Int J Rehabil Res. 2007;30:81&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, Babb T, Barreiro E, Dres M, et al. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmari KA, Rengaramanujam K, Reddy RS, Samuel PS, Kakaraparthi VN, Ahmad I, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness as a correlate of cardiovascular, anthropometric, and physical risk factors: using the Ruffier test as a template. Can Respir J. 2020;8:3407345. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/3407345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liu X, Tong Z. Can inspiratory muscle training benefit patients with COVID-19? J Med Virol. 2023;95:e28956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell AK. Respiratory Muscle Training: Theory and Practice. 1st ed. London: Churchill Livingstone; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadek Z, Salami A, Joumaa WH, Awada C, Ahmaidi S, Ramadan W. Best mode of inspiratory muscle training in heart failure patients. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2018;25:1691&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei RJ, Paris HL, Sogard AS, Mickleborough TD. Time to move beyond a one-size-fits-all approach to inspiratory muscle training. Front Physiol. 2021;12:766346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei RJ, Paris HL, Wilhite DP, Chapman RF, Mickleborough TD, Stickford JL. Inspiratory muscle training reduces respiratory muscle metaboreflex. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55:830&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hockele LF, Sachet Affonso JV, Rossi D, Eibel B. Pulmonary and functional rehabilitation in post-COVID-19 patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:14899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheel AW, Derchak PA, Morgan BJ, Pegelow DF, Jacques AJ, Dempsey JA. Fatiguing inspiratory muscle work causes reflex reduction in leg blood flow. J Physiol. 2001;537:277&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Romer L, Rodman J, Miller J, Smith C. Consequences of exercise-induced respiratory muscle work. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2006;151:242&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;stergaard L. SARS-CoV-2 related microvascular damage and symptoms during and after COVID-19. Physiol Rep. 2021;9:e14726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh I, Joseph P, Heerdt PM, Cullinan M, Lutchmansingh DD, Gulati M, et al. Persistent exertional intolerance after COVID-19. Respir Med. 2022;196:106819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavalc&#x131; Kol B, Bo&#x15f;nak G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc; M, Baytok E, Y&#x131;lmaz Demirci N. Comparison of muscle oxygenation during exercise tests in post-COVID-19 syndrome. Physiother Theory Pract. 2025;41:275&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavalc&#x131; Kol B, Baytok E, Y&#x131;lmaz Demirci N, Bo&#x15f;nak G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc; M. Exercise capacity and muscle oxygenation in post-COVID-19 patients. Eurasian J Pulmonol. 2024;26:51&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Ram&#xed;rez M, Moya-Gallardo E, Araya-Rom&#xe1;n F, Riquelme-S&#xe1;nchez S, Rodriguez-Garc&#xed;a G, Reid WD, et al. Sex-differences in muscle oxygenation during incremental exercise. Front Physiol. 2021;12:738063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz BJ, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, et al. Effects of concurrent training in post-COVID-19 conditions: the RECOVE trial. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134:95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahham A, McDonald CF, Holland AE. Exercise training alone or with activity counseling improves physical activity levels in COPD. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2016;11:3121&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ida FS, Ferreira HP, Vasconcelos AKM, Furtado IAB, Fontenele C, Pereira AC. Post-COVID-19 syndrome: functional impact, quality of life, return to work and costs. Cad Saude Publica. 2024;40:e00022623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann-Vold AM, Allanore Y, Alves M, Brunborg C, Air&#xf3; P, Ananieva LP, et al. Progressive interstitial lung disease in systemic sclerosis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:219&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont M, Forget P, Couturaud F, Reychler G. Effects of inspiratory muscle training in COPD patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Respir J. 2018;12:2178&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirenayat MS, Moradkhani A, Abedi M, Abedini A, Zahiri R, Karimzadeh S, Fakharian A. Role of inspiratory muscle training on pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with COVID-19. Tanaffos. 2022;21:466&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, et al. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020;395:497&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze H, Charles James J, Trampe N, Richter D, Pakeerathan T, Siems N, et al. Clinical aspects in patients with long-COVID and post-COVID syndrome. Front Neurol. 2022;13:979152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TJ, Chau B, Lui M, Lam GT, Lin N, Humbert S. Physical medicine and rehabilitation and pulmonary rehabilitation for COVID-19. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;99:769&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cares-Marambio K, Montenegro-Jim&#xe9;nez Y, Torres-Castro R, Vera-Uribe R, Torralba Y, Alsina-Restoy X, et al. Prevalence of potential respiratory symptoms after COVID-19 hospitalization. Chron Respir Dis. 2021;18:14799731211002240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik P, Patel K, Pinto C, Jaiswal R, Tirupathi R, Pillai S, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and health-related quality of life: a systematic review. J Med Virol. 2022;94:253&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossein Pour AH, Gholami M, Saki M, Birjandi M. The effect of inspiratory muscle training on fatigue and dyspnea in patients with heart failure. Jpn J Nurs Sci. 2020;17:e12290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Beekvelt MC, Colier WN, Wevers RA, Van Engelen BG. Performance of near-infrared spectroscopy in measuring local O2 consumption and blood flow in skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90(2):511&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>