<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41788915</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1559-8284</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of lifestyle medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Lifestyle Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Review of Concurrent Training Versus Moderate Intensity Continuous Training Cardiac Rehabilitation Modalities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15598276261432129</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15598276261432129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15598276261432129</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15598276261432129</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Moderate intensity continuous training (MICT) is the standard for exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation (CR) of patients with coronary artery disease (CAD). Traditionally, resistance training has been used as an adjunctive modality; however, new evidence suggests aerobic exercise and resistance training are complementary, a combined approach called concurrent training (CT). The present review analyzed emergent scientific evidence of programmatic efficacy of CT vs MICT. Analyses focused on five primary outcomes: aerobic capacity, cardiovascular performance, cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk factors, recurrent cardiac events, and psychosocial changes. A PubMed search for eligible studies used Boolean phrases that included both sexes, CAD, MICT and CT treatment groups, 18-to-36 CR sessions, and both pre-post program measurements from two or more outcome categories. Sixteen investigations met eligibility criteria, and findings indicated strength gains with CT exceeded those of traditional MICT programming. Separately, patients assigned to CT demonstrated similar changes in VO<sub>2</sub>peak, peak heart rate, and body composition as MICT. Despite reduced time spent on the moderate intensity aerobic exercise component, patients assigned to CT had similar improvements in VO<sub>2</sub>peak as compared with MICT. Both exercise formats demonstrated comparable adherence rates, whereas collective patient hours of observed CT were insufficient to draw conclusions regarding safety or adverse events.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alfaro-Chaverri</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrative Physiology &amp; Athletic Training, University of Montana, Missoula, MT, USA (AC, ML, JQ).</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">307078</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trejos-Montoya</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sciences of Human Movement and Quality of Life, National University of Costa Rica, Heredia, Costa Rica (JM, FR).</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">27929</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rojas-Ledezma</LastName><ForeName>Mariam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-7640-7101</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrative Physiology &amp; Athletic Training, University of Montana, Missoula, MT, USA (AC, ML, JQ).</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">307078</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Araya-Ram&#xed;rez</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4226-7817</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sciences of Human Movement and Quality of Life, National University of Costa Rica, Heredia, Costa Rica (JM, FR).</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">27929</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franklin</LastName><ForeName>Barry</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Preventive Cardiology and Cardiac Rehabilitation, Corewell Health, William Beaumont University Hospital, Royal Oak, MI, USA (BF).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quindry</LastName><ForeName>John C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4655-0086</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrative Physiology &amp; Athletic Training, University of Montana, Missoula, MT, USA (AC, ML, JQ).</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">307078</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Lifestyle Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101300023</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1559-8276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41788915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12956624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15598276261432129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_15598276261432129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tsao CW, Aday AW, Almarzooq ZI, et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics-2023 update: a report from the American heart association. Circulation. 2023;147(8):e93-e621. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12135016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Benjamin EJ, Go AS, et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics--2015 update: a report from the American heart association. Circulation. 2015;131(4):e29-e322. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen JK, Scott LB, Stewart KJ, Young DR. Disparities in women's referral to and enrollment in outpatient cardiac rehabilitation. J Gen Intern Med. 2004;19(7):747-753. doi: 10.1111/j.1525-1497.2004.30300.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1497.2004.30300.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1492482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15209588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Tsai JC, Liou YM, Chan P. Effectiveness of endurance exercise training in patients with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2017;16(5):397-408. doi: 10.1177/1474515116684407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1474515116684407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28565969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAvoy CR, Batrakoulis A, Camhi SM, Sansone JS, Stanfield JT, Reed R. 2026 ACSM worldwide fitness trends: future directions of the health and fitness industry: erratum. ACSM's Health &amp; Fit J. 2026;30(1):64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA, Quindry J. High level physical activity in cardiac rehabilitation: implications for exercise training and leisure-time pursuits. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2022;70:22-32. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2021.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2021.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34971650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quindry JC, Franklin BA, Chapman M, Humphrey R, Mathis S. Benefits and risks of high-intensity interval training in patients with coronary artery disease. Am J Cardiol. 2019;123(8):1370-1377. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.01.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30732854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RJ, King M, Lui K, et al. AACVPR/ACC/AHA 2007 performance measures on cardiac rehabilitation for referral to and delivery of cardiac rehabilitation/secondary prevention services endorsed by the American college of chest physicians, American college of sports medicine, American physical therapy association, Canadian association of cardiac rehabilitation, european association for cardiovascular prevention and rehabilitation, inter-american heart foundation, national association of clinical nurse specialists, preventive cardiovascular nurses association, and the society of thoracic surgeons. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;50(14):1400-1433. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2007.04.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2007.04.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17903645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Oh PI, Brooks D. Effect of combined aerobic and resistance training versus aerobic training alone in individuals with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2012;19(1):81-94. doi: 10.1177/1741826710393197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1741826710393197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21450617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckingham SA, Taylor RS, Jolly K, et al. Home-based versus centre-based cardiac rehabilitation: abridged cochrane systematic review and meta-analysis. Open Heart. 2016;3(2):e000463. doi: 10.1136/openhrt-2016-000463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/openhrt-2016-000463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5030549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27738516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AS, Franklin BA, Costa F, et al. Cardiac rehabilitation and secondary prevention of coronary heart disease: an American heart association scientific statement from the council on clinical cardiology (subcommittee on exercise, cardiac rehabilitation, and prevention) and the council on nutrition, physical activity, and metabolism (subcommittee on physical activity), in collaboration with the American association of cardiovascular and pulmonary rehabilitation. Circulation. 2005;111(3):369-376. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.0000151788.08740.5C</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000151788.08740.5C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15668354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen LR, Olsen RH, Anholm C, et al. Effects of 1 year of exercise training versus combined exercise training and weight loss on body composition, low-grade inflammation and lipids in overweight patients with coronary artery disease: a randomized trial. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2019;18(1):127. doi: 10.1186/s12933-019-0934-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-019-0934-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6774219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31575375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quindry JC, Franklin BA. Exercise preconditioning as a cardioprotective phenotype. Am J Cardiol. 2021;148:8-15. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2021.02.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2021.02.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33675772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie CJ, Milani RV. Cardiac rehabilitation and exercise training in secondary coronary heart disease prevention. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2011;53(6):397-403. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2011.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2011.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21545925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjarnason-Wehrens B. Recommendations for resistance exercise in cardiac rehabilitation: do they need reconsideration? Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2019;26(14):1479-1482. doi: 10.1177/2047487319856124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487319856124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Alghannam AF, Alkhamees NH, et al. Impact of concurrent aerobic and resistance training on body composition, lipid metabolism and physical function in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2025;13:e19537. doi: 10.7717/peerj.19537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.19537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12166852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40520633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Batrakoulis A, Wan Ghazali WS, et al. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training on glycemic control, blood pressure, inflammation, cardiorespiratory fitness and quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2024;12:e17525. doi: 10.7717/peerj.17525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.17525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11182026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38887616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A, Jamurtas AZ, Metsios GS, et al. Comparative efficacy of 5 exercise types on cardiometabolic health in overweight and Obese adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 81 randomized controlled trials. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2022;15(6):e008243. doi: 10.1161/circoutcomes.121.008243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circoutcomes.121.008243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Franklin BA, Jakicic JM, et al. Impact of resistance training on cardiometabolic health-related indices in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(10):733-746. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2024-108947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2024-108947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39773835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiuza-Luces C, Santos-Lozano A, Joyner M, et al. Exercise benefits in cardiovascular disease: beyond attenuation of traditional risk factors. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2018;15(12):731-743. doi: 10.1038/s41569-018-0065-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-018-0065-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Haskell WL, Ades PA, et al. Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American heart association council on clinical cardiology and council on nutrition, physical activity, and metabolism. Circulation. 2007;116(5):572-584. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.185214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.185214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xanthos PD, Gordon BA, Kingsley MI. Implementing resistance training in the rehabilitation of coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2017;230:493-508. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.12.076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.12.076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28040292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banz WJ, Maher MA, Thompson WG, et al. Effects of resistance versus aerobic training on coronary artery disease risk factors. Exp Biol Med. 2003;228(4):434-440. doi: 10.1177/153537020322800414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/153537020322800414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12671188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibben GO, Faulkner J, Oldridge N, et al. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation for coronary heart disease: a meta-analysis. Eur Heart J. 2023;44(6):452-469. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehac747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehac747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9902155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36746187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AcoS M. Acsm&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 12 ed. Wolters Kluwer; 2025:688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiraud T, Labrunee M, Besnier F, et al. Whole-body strength training with huber motion lab and traditional strength training in cardiac rehabilitation: a randomized controlled study. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2017;60(1):20-26. doi: 10.1016/j.rehab.2016.07.385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2016.07.385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27650531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kida K, Osada N, Akashi YJ, Sekizuka H, Omiya K, Miyake F. The exercise training effects of skeletal muscle strength and muscle volume to improve functional capacity in patients with myocardial infarction. Int J Cardiol. 2008;129(2):180-186. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2008.04.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2008.04.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18635275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor G, Stohr EJ, Oxborough D, Kimani P, Shave R. Effect of exercise training on left ventricular mechanics after acute myocardial infarction-an exploratory study. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;61(3):119-124. doi: 10.1016/j.rehab.2018.01.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2018.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29408714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehani SHM. Novel molecular biomarkers&#x2019; response to a cardiac rehabilitation programme in patients with ischaemic heart diseases. European J Physiotherapy. 2018;20(4):235-243. doi: 10.1080/21679169.2018.1464597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21679169.2018.1464597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokmakidis SP, Volaklis KA. Training and detraining effects of a combined-strength and aerobic exercise program on blood lipids in patients with coronary artery disease. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2003;23(3):193-200. doi: 10.1097/00008483-200305000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-200305000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12782903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepretre PM, Ghannem M, Bulvestre M, et al. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation in coronary disease: training impulse or modalities? Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(14):1144-1149. doi: 10.1055/s-0042-112591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-112591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27832671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Oh PI, Thomas SG, Goodman JM. Aerobic and resistance training in coronary disease: single versus multiple sets. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(9):1557-1564. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318177eb7f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318177eb7f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18685538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierson LM, Herbert WG, Norton HJ, et al. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training versus aerobic training alone in cardiac rehabilitation. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2001;21(2):101-110. doi: 10.1097/00008483-200103000-00007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-200103000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11314283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santa-Clara H, Fernhall B, Baptista F, Mendes M, Bettencourt Sardinha L. Effect of a one-year combined exercise training program on body composition in men with coronary artery disease. Metabolism. 2003;52(11):1413-1417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14624399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santa-Clara H, Fernhall B, Mendes M, Sardinha LB. Effect of a 1 year combined aerobic- and weight-training exercise programme on aerobic capacity and ventilatory threshold in patients suffering from coronary artery disease. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;87(6):568-575. doi: 10.1007/s00421-002-0675-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0675-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12355198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beniamini Y, Rubenstein JJ, Faigenbaum AD, Lichtenstein AH, Crim MC. High-intensity strength training of patients enrolled in an outpatient cardiac rehabilitation program. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 1999;19(1):8-17. doi: 10.1097/00008483-199901000-00001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-199901000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10079415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler RM, Palmer G, Rogers FJ. Circuit weight training in early cardiac rehabilitation. J Am Osteopath Assoc. 1992;92(1):77-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1559860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gayda M, Choquet D, Ahmaidi S. Effects of exercise training modality on skeletal muscle fatigue in men with coronary heart disease. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2009;19(2):e32-e39. doi: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2007.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2007.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17951074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelemen MH, Stewart KJ, Gillilan RE, et al. Circuit weight training in cardiac patients. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1986;7(1):38-42. doi: 10.1016/s0735-1097(86)80256-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0735-1097(86)80256-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3941214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney N, McKelvie RS, Haslam DR, Jones NL. Usefulness of weightlifting training in improving strength and maximal power output in coronary artery disease. Am J Cardiol. 1991;67(11):939-945. doi: 10.1016/0002-9149(91)90164-g</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0002-9149(91)90164-g</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2018011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid JP, Anderegg M, Romanens M, et al. Combined endurance/resistance training early on, after a first myocardial infarction, does not induce negative left ventricular remodelling. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2008;15(3):341-346. doi: 10.1097/HJR.0b013e3282f5dbf5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJR.0b013e3282f5dbf5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18525391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart KJ, McFarland LD, Weinhofer JJ, Cottrell E, Brown CS, Shapiro EP. Safety and efficacy of weight training soon after acute myocardial infarction. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 1998;18(1):37-44. doi: 10.1097/00008483-199801000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-199801000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9494881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorou AA, Panayiotou G, Volaklis KA, et al. Aerobic, resistance and combined training and detraining on body composition, muscle strength, lipid profile and inflammation in coronary artery disease patients. Res Sports Med. 2016;24(3):171-184. doi: 10.1080/15438627.2016.1191488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2016.1191488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27258806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vona M, Codeluppi GM, Iannino T, Ferrari E, Bogousslavsky J, von Segesser LK. Effects of different types of exercise training followed by detraining on endothelium-dependent dilation in patients with recent myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2009;119(12):1601-1608. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.821736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.821736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigiene A, Petruseviciene D, Barasaite V, Kubilius R, Macijauskiene J. Cardiac rehabilitation and complementary physical training in elderly patients after acute coronary syndrome: a pilot study. Medicina. 2021;57(6):529. doi: 10.3390/medicina57060529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina57060529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8225116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34070257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coke LA, Staffileno BA, Braun LT, Gulanick M. Upper-body progressive resistance training improves strength and household physical activity performance in women attending cardiac rehabilitation. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2008;28(4):238-245. doi: 10.1097/01.HCR.0000327180.29122.83. quiz 246-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.HCR.0000327180.29122.83</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18628653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daub WD, Knapik GP, Black WR. Strength training early after myocardial infarction. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 1996;16(2):100-108. doi: 10.1097/00008483-199603000-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-199603000-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8681154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dor-Haim H, Barak S, Horowitz M, et al. Improvement in cardiac dysfunction with a novel circuit training method combining simultaneous aerobic-resistance exercises. A randomized trial. PLoS One. 2018;13(1):e0188551. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0188551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0188551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5788332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29377893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen D, Eijnde BO, Roelants M, et al. Clinical benefits of the addition of lower extremity low-intensity resistance muscle training to early aerobic endurance training intervention in patients with coronary artery disease: a randomized controlled trial. J Rehabil Med. 2011;43(9):800-807. doi: 10.2340/16501977-0853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-0853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21874215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung C, Daub B, Black B, Welsh R, Quinney A, Haykowsky M. Exercise training improves overall physical fitness and quality of life in older women with coronary artery disease. Chest. 2004;126(4):1026-1031. doi: 10.1378/chest.126.4.1026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.126.4.1026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15486358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quindry JC, McNamara M, Oser C, Fogle C. Cardiac rehabilitation and resting blood pressure: Montana outcomes project cardiac rehabilitation registry findings. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2022;42(2):E23-E31. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quindry JC, McNamara M, Oser C, Fogle C. Assessment of clinical depression metrics in cardiac patients using the patient health Questionnaire-9 before and after phase-II cardiac rehabilitation. Sports Med Health Sci. 2023;6:240-245. doi: 10.1016/j.smhs.2023.09.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smhs.2023.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11369830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39234489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA, Kokkinos P, Lavie CJ. Bolstering health outcomes by emerging from the least fit population cohort: the impact of exercise training intensities &gt; 3 metabolic equivalents. Heart and Mind. 2025;9(4):285-289. doi: 10.4103/hm.HM-D-25-00038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/hm.HM-D-25-00038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama S, Saito K, Tanaka S, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness as a quantitative predictor of all-cause mortality and cardiovascular events in healthy men and women: a meta-analysis. JAMA. 2009;301(19):2024-2035. doi: 10.1001/jama.2009.681</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2009.681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19454641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brellenthin AG, Bennie JA, Lee DC. Aerobic or muscle-strengthening physical activity: which is better for health? Curr Sports Med Rep. 2022;21(8):272-279. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0000000000000981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9373235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney N, McKelvie RS, Martin J, Sale DG, MacDougall JD. Weight-training-induced attenuation of the circulatory response of older males to weight lifting. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74(3):1056-1060. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1993.74.3.1056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.74.3.1056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8482642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grafe K, Bendick P, Burr M, Boura J, Franklin BA. Effects of resistance training on vascular and hemodynamic responses in patients with coronary artery disease. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2018;89(4):457-464. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2018.1519385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2018.1519385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers S, Howley E, Quindry J. Exercise Physiology: Theory and Application to Fitness and Performance. 12th ed. ed. McGraw Hill; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA, Eijsvogels TMH, Pandey A, Quindry J, Toth PP. Physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and cardiovascular health: a clinical practice statement of the American society for preventive cardiology part II: physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, minimum and goal intensities for exercise training, prescriptive methods, and special patient populations. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2022;12:100425. doi: 10.1016/j.ajpc.2022.100425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpc.2022.100425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9586849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36281325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA, Eijsvogels TMH, Pandey A, Quindry J, Toth PP. Physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and cardiovascular health: a clinical practice statement of the ASPC part I: bioenergetics, contemporary physical activity recommendations, benefits, risks, extreme exercise regimens, potential maladaptations. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2022;12:100424. doi: 10.1016/j.ajpc.2022.100424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpc.2022.100424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9586848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36281324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhumaid W, Small SD, Kirkham AA, et al. A contemporary review of the effects of exercise training on cardiac structure and function and cardiovascular risk profile: insights from imaging. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:753652. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2022.753652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.753652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8898950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannuzzi P, Tavazzi L, Temporelli PL, et al. Long-term physical training and left ventricular remodeling after anterior myocardial infarction: results of the exercise in anterior myocardial infarction (EAMI) trial. EAMI study group. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1993;22(7):1821-1829. doi: 10.1016/0735-1097(93)90764-r</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0735-1097(93)90764-r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewiss D, Ostman C, Smart NA. The effect of resistance training on clinical outcomes in heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2016;221:674-681. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.07.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.07.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker WJ, Beaudry RI, Liang Y, et al. Meta-analysis of exercise training on left ventricular ejection fraction in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: a 10-year update. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;62(2):163-171. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2018.08.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2018.08.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30227187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mital A, Shrey DE, Govindaraju M, Broderick TM, Colon-Brown K, Gustin BW. Accelerating the return to work (RTW) chances of coronary heart disease (CHD) patients: part 1--development and validation of a training programme. Disabil Rehabil. 2000;22(13-14):604-620. doi: 10.1080/09638280050138287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638280050138287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11052210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Franklin BA, Jakicic JM, et al. Impact of aerobic exercise on cardiometabolic health in patients with diabesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Diabet Complicat. 2025;39(12):109203. doi: 10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2025.109203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2025.109203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41135244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Poon ET, Franklin BA, et al. Comparative effectiveness of high-intensity interval training and moderate-intensity continuous training on cardiometabolic health in patients with diabesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2025;17(1):331. doi: 10.1186/s13098-025-01909-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-025-01909-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12344893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40804647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balady GJ, Williams MA, Ades PA, et al. Core components of cardiac rehabilitation/secondary prevention programs: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American heart association exercise, cardiac rehabilitation, and prevention committee, the council on clinical cardiology; the councils on cardiovascular nursing, epidemiology and prevention, and nutrition, physical activity, and metabolism; and the American association of cardiovascular and pulmonary rehabilitation. Circulation. 2007;115(20):2675-2682. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.180945</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.180945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digenio AG, Sim JG, Krige K, et al. The johannesburg cardiac rehabilitation programme. S Afr Med J. 1991;79(4):183-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1996433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA, Bonzheim K, Gordon S, Timmis GC. Safety of medically supervised outpatient cardiac rehabilitation exercise therapy: a 16-year follow-up. Chest. 1998;114(3):902-906. doi: 10.1378/chest.114.3.902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.114.3.902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9743182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL. Cardiovascular complications during exercise training of cardiac patients. Circulation. 1978;57(5):920-924. doi: 10.1161/01.cir.57.5.920</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.57.5.920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">639213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Camp SP, Peterson RA. Cardiovascular complications of outpatient cardiac rehabilitation programs. JAMA. 1986;256(9):1160-1163. doi: 10.1001/jama.256.9.1160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.256.9.1160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3735650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vongvanich P, Paul-Labrador MJ, Merz CN. Safety of medically supervised exercise in a cardiac rehabilitation center. Am J Cardiol. 1996;77(15):1383-1385. doi: 10.1016/s0002-9149(96)00215-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0002-9149(96)00215-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8677889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SS, Aday AW, Allen NB, et al. Correction to: 2025 heart disease and stroke statistics: a report of US and global data from the American heart association. Circulation. 2025;151(25):e1096. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40549850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata K, Kameshima M, Adachi T, et al. Association between outpatient cardiac rehabilitation and all-cause mortality after cardiovascular surgery: a propensity score-matched analysis. JTCVS Open. 2023;15:313-323. doi: 10.1016/j.xjon.2023.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xjon.2023.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10556827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37808037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RJ, Balady G, Banka G, et al. 2018 ACC/AHA clinical performance and quality measures for cardiac rehabilitation: a report of the American college of cardiology/American heart association task force on performance measures. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;71(16):1814-1837. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.01.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2018.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29606402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rognmo O, Moholdt T, Bakken H, et al. Cardiovascular risk of high-versus moderate-intensity aerobic exercise in coronary heart disease patients. Circulation. 2012;126(12):1436-1440. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.112.123117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.112.123117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittleman MA, Maclure M, Tofler GH, Sherwood JB, Goldberg RJ, Muller JE. Triggering of acute myocardial infarction by heavy physical exertion. Protection against triggering by regular exertion. Determinants of myocardial infarction onset study investigators. N Engl J Med. 1993;329(23):1677-1683. doi: 10.1056/NEJM199312023292301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199312023292301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8232456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YJ, He XH, Guo HY, Wang XQ, Zhu Y. Efficiency of muscle strength training on motor function in patients with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015;8(10):17536-17550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4694245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26770345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>House CM, Anstadt MA, Stuck LH, Nelson WB. The association between cardiac rehabilitation attendance and hospital readmission. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2018;12(6):513-520. doi: 10.1177/1559827616670118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1559827616670118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6367883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30783406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin BJ, Hauer T, Arena R, et al. Cardiac rehabilitation attendance and outcomes in coronary artery disease patients. Circulation. 2012;126(6):677-687. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.066738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.066738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keteyian SJ, Jackson SL, Chang A, et al. Tracking cardiac rehabilitation utilization in medicare beneficiaries: 2017 update. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2022;42(4):235-245. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10865223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>