<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41480955</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors Determining the Need for Ultrafiltration in Cardiorenal Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000858</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the factors determining the need for ultrafiltration (UF) in patients with cardiorenal syndrome presenting with hypervolemia-related symptoms and signs. A total of 88 patients hospitalized for hypervolemia were treated according to current guidelines, with UF employed as a rescue therapy when diuretic treatment failed to achieve adequate decongestion. Data collected included medical history, laboratory findings, blood pressures, diuretic doses, spot urine sodium (measured 6 hours after diuretic therapy), response to diuretics, postdischarge creatinine levels, rehospitalization rates, and mortality rates. UF was required in 23.90% of patients due to insufficient response to diuretics, with a higher rate observed in men (34.10%) compared with women (13.64%). Patients needing UF had lower systolic blood pressure, higher initial serum creatinine levels, and elevated pro-B-type natriuretic peptide levels. Statistical analysis showed that an increase in initial creatinine levels raised the risk of requiring UF by 6.443 times, while a one-unit decrease in urine sodium increased the risk by 1.037 times. These findings suggest that male gender, high pro-B-type natriuretic peptide levels, low spot urine sodium, low systolic blood pressure, and high initial creatinine levels may predict the need for UF. Further research involving larger patient cohorts is necessary to refine these criteria and develop a risk score.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Co&#x15f;kuner</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed Ali</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Antalya City Hospital, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x130;nci</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#xe7;a</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Antalya Training and Research Hospital, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xf6;ker</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf6;khan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Antalya Training and Research Hospital, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yilmaz</LastName><ForeName>&#xdc;st&#xfc;n</ForeName><Initials>&#xdc;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Antalya Training and Research Hospital, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>&#x15e;akir</ForeName><Initials>&#x15e;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Antalya Training and Research Hospital, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiorenal syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diuretic resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diuretics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrafiltration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41480955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ronco C, Haapio M, House AA, et al. Cardiorenal syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2008;52:1527&#x2013;1539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta R, Testani J, Collins S. Diuretic resistance in heart failure. Curr Heart Fail Rep. 2019;16:57&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbrugge FH, Mullens W, Tang WHW. Management of cardio-renal syndrome and diuretic resistance. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2016;18:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcox CS, Testani JM, Pitt B. Pathophysiology of diuretic resistance and its implications for the management of chronic heart failure. Hypertension. 2020;76:1045&#x2013;1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SY, Kim S. Pathophysiology of cardiorenal syndrome and use of diuretics and ultrafiltration as volume control. Korean Circ J. 2021;51:656&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponikowski P, Voors AA, Anker SD, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2016;37:2129&#x2013;2200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronson D, Burger AJ. Diuretic response: clinical and hemodynamic predictors and relation to clinical outcome. J Card Fail. 2016;22:193&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ter Maaten JM, Dunning AM, Valente MAE, et al. Diuretic response in acute heart failure&#x2014;an analysis from ASCEND-HF. Am Heart J. 2015;170:313&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costanzo MR, Negoianu D, Jaski BE, et al. Aquapheresis versus intravenous diuretics and hospitalizations for heart failure. JACC Heart Fail. 2016;4:95&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costanzo MR, Guglin ME, Saltzberg MT, et al.; UNLOAD Trial Investigators. Ultrafiltration versus intravenous diuretics for patients hospitalized for acute decompensated heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;49:675&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bart BA, Boyle A, Bank AJ, et al. Ultrafiltration versus usual care for hospitalized patients with heart failure: the relief for acutely fluid-overloaded patients with decompensated congestive heart failure (RAPID-CHF) trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;46:2043&#x2013;2046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marenzi G, Muratori M, Cosentino ER, et al. Continuous ultrafiltration for congestive heart failure: the CUORE trial. J Card Fail. 2014;20:9&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valente MAE, Voors AA, Damman K, et al. Diuretic response in acute heart failure: clinical characteristics and prognostic significance. Eur Heart J. 2014;35:1284&#x2013;1293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voors AA, Davison BA, Teerlink JR, et al.; RELAX-AHF Investigators. Diuretic response in patients with acute decompensated heart failure: characteristics and clinical outcome&#x2014;an analysis from RELAX-AHF. Eur J Heart Fail. 2014;16:1230&#x2013;1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MS, Stevens SR, Tang WHW, et al.; NHLBI Heart Failure Clinical Trials Network Investigators. Determinants of diuretic responsiveness and associated outcomes during acute heart failure hospitalization: an analysis from the NHLBI Heart Failure Network Clinical Trials. J Card Fail. 2018;24:428&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biegus J, Zymli&#x144;ski R, Sokolski M, et al. Serial assessment of spot urine sodium predicts effectiveness of decongestion and outcome in patients with acute heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2019;21:624&#x2013;633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luk A, Groarke JD, Desai AS, et al. First spot urine sodium after initial diuretic identifies patients at high risk for adverse outcome after heart failure hospitalization. Am Heart J. 2018;203:95&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi&#xf1;ana G, Ll&#xe0;cer P, Sanchis I, et al.; on behalf of IMPROVE-HF Investigators. Early spot urinary sodium and diuretic efficiency in acute heart failure and concomitant renal dysfunction. Cardiorenal Med. 2020;10:362&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda S, Nagai T, Nishimura K, et al.; NaDEF investigators. Long-term prognostic significance of urinary sodium concentration in patients with acute heart failure. Int J Cardiol. 2018;254:189&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes da SF, Cal&#xe7;a R, Martins A R, et al. Diuretic-resistant heart failure and the role of ultrafiltration: a proposed protocol. Rev Port Cardiol. 2023;42:797&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libetta C, Sepe V, Zucchi M, et al. Intermittent haemodiafiltration in refractory congestive heart failure: BNP and balance of inflammatory cytokines. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2007;22:2013&#x2013;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Reis D, Fraticelli L, Bassand A, et al. Impact of renal dysfunction on the management and outcome of acute heart failure: results from the French prospective, multicentre, DeFSSICA survey. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e022776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen XL, Li L, Ma J, et al. Safety and efficacy of ultrafiltration on heart failure patients with reduced ejection fraction and diuretic resistance: results from a single-center randomized controlled trial. Zhonghua Xin Xue Guan Bing Za Zhi. 2021;49:340&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giglioli C, Landi D, Cecchi E, et al. Effects of ULTRAfiltration vs. DIureticS on clinical, biohumoral and haemodynamic variables in patients with deCOmpensated heart failure: the ULTRADISCO study. Eur J Heart Fail. 2011;13:337&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Bao J, Zhang H, et al. Patients with high-dose diuretics should get ultrafiltration in the management of decompensated heart failure: a meta-analysis. Heart Fail Rev. 2019;24:927&#x2013;940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wobbe B, Wagner J, Szab&#xf3; DK, et al. Ultrafiltration is better than diuretic therapy for volume-overloaded acute heart failure patients: a meta-analysis. Heart Fail Rev. 2021;26:577&#x2013;585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bart BA, Goldsmith SR, Lee KL, et al. Cardiorenal rescue study in acute decompensated heart failure: rationale and design of CARRESS-HF, for the heart failure clinical research network. J Card Fail. 2012;18:176&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bart BA, Goldsmith SR, Lee KL, et al.; Heart Failure Clinical Research Network. Ultrafiltration in decompensated heart failure with cardiorenal syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2012;367:2296&#x2013;2304.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>