<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41568350</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2297-1769</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in veterinary science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Vet Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fostering learning among the next generation of veterinarians: incorporating one health and antimicrobial stewardship into veterinary medicine training curricula in Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1690392</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1690392</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1690392</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fvets.2025.1690392</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Universities play a crucial role in educating and training veterinarians, and their fostering of learning among the next generation of students is widely regarded as key to bringing about the cultural change required to realise a transition towards a 'One Health' approach to managing human, animal, and environmental health and underpin widespread adoption of antimicrobial stewardship practices. In Africa, there is a paucity of studies that have explored how veterinary training curricula are influencing veterinary medicine students' perceptions of 'One Health' and the importance of antimicrobial stewardship. This study takes Ethiopia as a case study and explores how veterinary medicine students' training influences perceptions regarding the benefits of taking a 'One Health' approach to managing public health risks and adhering to rational antimicrobial prescription practices and drug use. Data for this study were collected through an online questionnaire survey administered to 154 veterinary students at universities across Ethiopia. We found that the veterinary students were interested in receiving training related to the 'One Health' concept and indicated that such training would increase the likelihood that, upon graduation, they would be competent practitioners who could collaborate with other health sectors practitioners in addressing public health challenges. The students perceived a gap in the veterinary training curricula regarding rational antimicrobial prescribing and drug use; this is a concern given that antimicrobial resistance is an emerging problem in Ethiopia and worldwide. The results of this study underscore that veterinary training curricula play a key role in shaping students' mindsets and practice, and that the provision of information, interdisciplinary and transdisciplinary practical training, and mentorship is key to fostering the learning required to ensure that students are holistic practitioners with the knowledge and capacity to implement at 'One Health' approach and antimicrobial stewardship in the future careers. The results highlight the imperative and opportunity for higher education institutions, particularly universities, and policymakers to ensure that national veterinary curricula are cognisant of and aligned with emerging approaches-such as the One Health approach, which advocates for interdisciplinary and multidisciplinary collaboration and communication - to managing the risks posed by infectious diseases to public health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Nyokabi, Phelan, Berg, Lindahl, Korir, Bett, Muunda, Mihret, Moore and Wood.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nyokabi</LastName><ForeName>Ndungu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Prosperity, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Edinburgh Business School, Edinburgh, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phelan</LastName><ForeName>Lisette</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Food and Farming, Harper Adams University, Newport, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berg</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bernhard Nocht Institute for Tropical Medicine, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindahl</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Livestock Research Institute (ILRI), Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biochemistry and Microbiology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korir</LastName><ForeName>Lilian</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lincoln Institute for Agri-Food Technology, University of Lincoln, Lincoln, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bett</LastName><ForeName>Bernard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Livestock Research Institute (ILRI), Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muunda</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Livestock Research Institute (ILRI), Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mihret</LastName><ForeName>Adane</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Armauer Hansen Research Institute (AHRI), Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Henrietta</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Prosperity, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wood</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Vet Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101666658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2297-1769</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AMR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biosecurity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infection prevention and control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary curriculum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zoonoses</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41568350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12815772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2025.1690392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Steele SG, Toribio JA, Booy R, Mor SM. What makes an effective one health clinical practitioner? Opinions of Australian one health experts. One Health. (2019) 8:100108. doi: 10.1016/j.onehlt.2019.100108,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2019.100108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31720358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyene T, Endalamaw D, Tolossa Y, Feyisa A. Evaluation of rational use of veterinary drugs especially antimicrobials and anthelmintics in Bishoftu, Central Ethiopia veterinary research. BMC Res Notes. (2015) 8:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1186/s13104-015-1466-4,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-015-1466-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4584433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26415926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varer Akpinar C, Durmaz S. Medical interns&#x2019; attitudes towards one health approach, Turkish. J Biochem. (2022) 47:137&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1515/tjb-2021-0078,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/tjb-2021-0078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrian AM, Wilkes M, Gilardi K, Smith W, Conrad PA, Crook PZ, et al. Developing a global one health workforce: the &#x201c;Rx one health Summer Institute&#x201d; approach. EcoHealth. (2020) 17:222&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1007/s10393-020-01481-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10393-020-01481-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32685999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaddock M. Academic veterinary medicine and one health education: it is more than clinical applications. J Vet Med Educ. (2012) 39:241&#x2013;6. doi: 10.3138/jvme.0612-062,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme.0612-062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22940444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyokabi NS, Moore H, Berg S, Lindahl J, Phelan L, Worku GG, et al. Implementing a one health approach to strengthen the management of zoonoses in Ethiopia. One Health. (2023) 16:100521. doi: 10.1016/j.onehlt.2023.100521,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2023.100521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37363216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobbold RN, Simmons HL, Cargill J, Lasley J, Oosthuizen J, Sherman DM. An international collaborative approach to developing training guidelines for veterinary paraprofessionals. J Vet Med Educ. (2020) 47:546&#x2013;54. doi: 10.3138/JVME-2019-0086,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/JVME-2019-0086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32516076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pappaioanou M. Veterinarians in global public health. J Vet Med Educ. (2003) 30:105&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3138/jvme.30.2.105,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme.30.2.105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roopnarine R, Boeren E. Applying the readiness for Interprofessional learning scale (RIPLS) to medical, veterinary and dual degree master of public health (MPH) students at a private medical institution. PLoS One. (2020) 15:e0234462. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0234462,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0234462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32525910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benfield CTO, Heymann D, Clark JMA, Trees AJ, Sethia B. We must take a one health approach to improve pandemic infection control. Vet Rec. (2020) 187:e66. doi: 10.1136/vr.m4020,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/vr.m4020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33077682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessler AL, Hoet AE, Nigatu S, Swisher S, Fentie T, Admassu B, et al. Advancing one health through veterinary education: a mixed methods needs assessment for implementing a WOAH-harmonized national veterinary medicine curriculum in Ethiopia. Front Vet Sci. (2024) 11:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.3389/fvets.2024.1357855,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2024.1357855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11005791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38601911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Africa One Health University Network (AFROHUN)  Welcome to Africa one health university network (AFROHUN) (2020). Kampala, Uganda. Available online at: https://afrohun.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/WELCOME-TO-AFROHUN.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nstermann S. Overview of capacity building opportunities in &#x201c;one health&#x201d;, internationally and with focus on Africa - a desk top study (2022). Available online at: https://www.giz.de/en/downloads/giz2022-en-overview-of-capacity-building-opportunities-in-one-health.pdf (Accessed June 15, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaitsa M, Ejobi F, Majalija S, Tumwine G, Sente C, Okech S, et al. Tropical veterinary medicine and one health: a case study of a study-abroad course with one health principles integrated into veterinary medical training. Pan Afr Med J. (2017) 27:9. doi: 10.11604/pamj.supp.2017.27.4.12447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.supp.2017.27.4.12447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayen F. A status report of veterinary education in Ethiopia: perceived needs, past history, recent changes, and current and future concerns. J Vet Med Educ. (2006) 33:244&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3138/jvme.33.2.244,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme.33.2.244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16849305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyango D., Fascendini M., Wieland B., Ikiror D., Sircely J., Tefera S. 2019. One health policy context of Ethiopia, Somalia and Kenya. Nairobi, Kenya: International Livestock Research Institute.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkyihun GA, Gari FR, Edao BM, Kassa GM. A review on one health approach in Ethiopia. One Health Outlook. (2022) 4:8. doi: 10.1186/s42522-022-00064-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42522-022-00064-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35449083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasina FO, LeRoux-Pullen L, Smith P, Debusho LK, Shittu A, Jajere SM, et al. Knowledge, attitudes, and perceptions associated with antimicrobial stewardship among veterinary students: a multi-country survey from Nigeria, South Africa, and Sudan. Front Public Health. (2020) 8:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2020.517964,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2020.517964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33194938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbo LM, Cosgrove SE, Pottinger PS, Pereyra M, Sinkowitz-Cochran R, Srinivasan A, et al. Medical students&#x2019; perceptions and knowledge about antimicrobial stewardship: how are we educating our future prescribers? Clin Infect Dis. (2013) 57:631&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1093/cid/cit370,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cit370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alafiatayo R, Galipo E, Ekiri AB, Dineva M, Endacott I, Tesfaye T, et al. Training needs assessment of veterinary practitioners in Ethiopia. Trop Anim Health Prod. (2022) 54:72&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/s11250-022-03075-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-022-03075-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asfaw YT, Teklehaimanot BG, Garadew L, Gulima D. Veterinary professionals and paraprofessionals development in Ethiopia: retrospective survey. Ethiop Vet Assoc Special ed. (2017) 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardefeldt L, Nielsen T, Crabb H, Gilkerson J, Squires R, Heller J, et al. Veterinary students&#x2019; knowledge and perceptions about antimicrobial stewardship and biosecurity&#x2014;a national survey. Antibiotics. (2018) 7:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics7020034,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics7020034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29670064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClelland JW, Norris JM, Dominey-Howes D, Govendir M. Knowledge and perceptions of Australian postgraduate veterinary students prior to formal education of antimicrobial use and antimicrobial resistance. One Health. (2022) 14:100366. doi: 10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100366,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasina FO, Bett B, Dione M, Mutua F, Roesel K, Thomas L, et al. One health gains momentum in Africa but room exists for improvement. One Health. (2022) 15:100428. doi: 10.1016/j.onehlt.2022.100428,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2022.100428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36277101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasina FO, Fasanmi OG, Makonnen YJ, Bebay C, Bett B, Roesel K. (2021). The one health landscape in Sub-Saharan African countries. One Health, 13, 100325. doi: 10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8455361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34584927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper P. Review of animal health service delivery in the mixed crop-livestock system in Ethiopia, LIVES Work. Pap. 18. (2016). Nairobi, Kenya: International Livestock Research Institute.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JS, Dahal R, Kakkar M, Debnath N, Rahman M, Dorjee S, et al. One health research and training and government support for one health in South Asia. Infect Ecol Epidemiol. (2016) 6:1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.3402/IEE.V6.33842,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/IEE.V6.33842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5131453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27906123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerner H, Berg C. A comparison of three holistic approaches to health: one health, Ecohealth, and planetary health. Front. Vet. Sci. (2017) 4:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3389/fvets.2017.00163,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2017.00163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5649127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29085825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catley A, Leyland T, Mariner JC, Akabwai DMO, Admassu B, Asfaw W, et al. Para-veterinary professionals and the development of quality, self-sustaining community-based services. OIE Rev Sci Tech. (2004) 23:225&#x2013;52. doi: 10.20506/rst.23.1.1476,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20506/rst.23.1.1476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15200100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golding SE, Higgins HM, Ogden J. Assessing knowledge, beliefs, and behaviors around antibiotic usage and antibiotic resistance among UK veterinary students: a multi-site, cross-sectional survey. Antibiotics. (2022) 11:1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics11020256,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics11020256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doucet MY, Vrins A. The importance of knowledge, skills, and attitude attributes for veterinarians in clinical and non-clinical fields of practice: a survey of licensed veterinarians in Quebec, Canada. J Vet Med Educ. (2009) 36:331&#x2013;42. doi: 10.3138/jvme/014,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme/014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19861721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman EJ. A study of in-training evaluation of veterinary students. Manawat&#x16b;, New Zealand: Massey University; (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon G, Hiwot D, Dagim B, Barbara W. A narrative review of animal health interventions for designing herd health interventions for Ethiopia. Joint ILRI and EVA Project Report (2019). 33 p. Nairobi, Kenya: International Livestock Research Institute.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez A, Prats-Van Der Ham M, Tatay-Dualde J, Paterna A, De La Fe C, G&#xf3;mez-Mart&#xed;n &#xc1;, et al. Zoonoses in veterinary students: a systematic review of the literature. PLoS One. (2017) 12:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0169534,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0169534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5215727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28052113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Cawthorne GA. One health/EcoHealth/planetary health and their evolution In: One Planet One Health. Eds. Merrilyn Walton (2019). 1&#x2013;20. Sydney, Australia: Sydney University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand S., Gu&#xe9;gan J., Laurans Y. From one health to Ecohealth, mapping the incomplete integration of human, animal and environmental health (2020), 1&#x2013;4. Available online at: https://www.unescap.org/blog/towards-post-covid19 (Accessed June 15, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talukder B, Ganguli N, Choi E, Tofighi M, vanloon GW, Obrinski J. Exploring the nexus: comparing and aligning planetary health. One Health EcoHealth Glob Transitions. (2024) 6:66&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1016/j.glt.2023.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glt.2023.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyokabi NS, Phelan L, Lindahl JF, Berg S, Muunda E, Mihret A, et al. Exploring veterinary students&#x2019; awareness and perception of zoonoses risks, infection control practices, and biosecurity measures in Ethiopia. Front. Vet. Sci. (2024) 11:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.3389/fvets.2024.1385849,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2024.1385849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11263103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39044741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jibat T, Mengistu A, Girmay K. Assessment of veterinary services in Central Ethiopia: a case study in Ada&#x2019; a district of Oromia region, Ethiopia. Ethiop Vet J. (2015) 19:1. doi: 10.4314/evj.v19i2.9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/evj.v19i2.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adekanye UO, Ekiri AB, Galip&#xf3; E, Muhammad AB, Mateus A, La Ragione RM, et al. Knowledge, attitudes and practices of veterinarians towards antimicrobial resistance and stewardship in Nigeria. Antibiotics. (2020) 9:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics9080453,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics9080453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestri S, Richard M, Edward B, Dharmesh G, Dannie R. Going digital in agriculture: how radio and SMS can scale-up smallholder participation in legume-based sustainable agricultural intensification practices and technologies in Tanzania. Int J Agric Sustain. (2020) 19:583&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1080/14735903.2020.1750796,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14735903.2020.1750796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufa TB, Gurmu F, Beyi AF, Hogeveen H, Beyene TJ, Ayana D, et al. Veterinary medicinal product usage among food animal producers and its health implications in Central Ethiopia. BMC Vet Res. (2018) 14:409&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1186/s12917-018-1737-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-018-1737-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endacott IC, Ekiri AB, Alafiatayo R, Galipo E, Okech SG, Kasirye FM, et al. Continuing education of animal health professionals in Uganda: a training needs assessment. J Vet Med Educ. (2022) 49:503&#x2013;14. doi: 10.3138/jvme-2020-0161,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/jvme-2020-0161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Casta&#xf1;eda RR, Villers J, Guzm&#xe1;n CAF, Eslanloo T, de Paula N, Machalaba C, et al. One health and planetary health research: leveraging differences to grow together. Lancet Planet Heal. (2023) 7:e109&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/S2542-5196(23)00002-5,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2542-5196(23)00002-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9901939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>