<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41782413</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2648</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Correlates of Mortal Distress Among Healthcare Staff in Hospitals: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jan.70454</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Mortal distress encompasses emotional, cognitive, physical and behavioural responses to death and dying among healthcare staff who frequently encounter mortality in hospital settings. Healthcare workers often experience heightened levels of mortal distress due to their regular exposure to patient deaths, which can negatively impact both their personal and professional lives, leading to burnout and high turnover rates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify and quantitatively synthesise correlates of mortal distress among hospital healthcare staff and examine moderating factors affecting these relationships.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic review and meta-analysis following PRISMA 2020 guidelines METHODS: Two independent reviewers screened and extracted data from studies published between January 1990 and December 2024 across eight databases (five English: CINAHL, MEDLINE, ProQuest, PubMed, Scopus; three Chinese: Airiti, CNKI, Wanfang). Quality assessment was conducted using the Mixed Methods Appraisal Tool. Meta-analysis was performed using Comprehensive Meta-Analysis 3.0.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Analysis of 94 studies identified three factor domains: personal, job-related and situational. Four job-related factors demonstrated the strongest correlations with mortal distress: competence in coping with death in healthcare contexts, needs for death-related or hospice care training, quality of end-of-life communication, and working in departments with high patient mortality rates. Four significant moderators influenced correlation strength: publication language, geographic region, study quality, and measurement tools used for assessing mortal distress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This synthesis provides evidence regarding the magnitude and strength of factors associated with mortal distress among healthcare staff. The identification of main and moderator effects emphasises the critical need for developing culturally sensitive, tailored interventions to help healthcare workers navigate mortality-related challenges.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results can guide healthcare organisations in developing targeted interventions and training programs, inform medical and nursing education curricula by encouraging the inclusion of life and death education, and ultimately enhance staff well-being while improving the quality of patient and family care, especially in palliative care contexts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="NO PATIENT OR PUBLIC CONTRIBUTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study did not include patient or public involvement in its design, conduct, or reporting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO number: CRD42021275460.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Journal of Advanced Nursing published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Joy Juan</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6514-0827</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Nethersole School of Nursing, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Work and Social Administration, Faculty of Social Sciences, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jiu Li</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8014-6280</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Resources, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ng</LastName><ForeName>Yong Hao</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Work, Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Western Australia and Perron Institute for Neurological and Translational Science, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chui</LastName><ForeName>Ernest Wing-Tak</ForeName><Initials>EW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Work and Social Administration, Faculty of Social Sciences, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7609811</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0309-2402</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">correlates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">death and dying</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">death anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fear of death</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare staff</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41782413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jan.70454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Alhusamiah, B., and R. S. Zeilani. 2023. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Associated Factors Among Oncology Nurses and Physicians.&#x201d; Omega, 302228231174573. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228231174573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artico, M., M. Piredda, D. D'Angelo, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;Palliative Care Organization and Staffing Models in Residential Hospices: Which Makes the Difference?&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Studies 126: 104135. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2021.104135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif, M., M. Bakhtiari, R. Tahir, A. H. Khan, and M. A. Chaudhry. 2022. &#x201c;Influence of Death Anxiety on the Preventive Practices of Healthcare Staff During COVID&#x2010;19 Outbreak.&#x201d; Khyber Medical University Journal 14, no. 4: 273&#x2013;277. https://doi.org/10.35845/kmuj.2022.21656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xe9;, B., and M. J. Foxall. 1991. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Job Stress in Hospice and Medical&#x2010;Surgical Nurses.&#x201d; Hospice Journal 7, no. 3: 25&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1080/0742&#x2010;969X.1991.11882703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian, Y. 2020. &#x201c;Hu Xi Nei Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Yu Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du de Diao Cha Yan Jiu [Investigation on the Attitudes of Respiratory Nurses Towards Death and End&#x2010;Of&#x2010;Life Care].&#x201d; Chinese General Practice Nursing 18, no. 7: 872&#x2013;874. https://doi.org/10.12104/j.issn.1674&#x2010;4748.2020.07.024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black, K. 2005. &#x201c;Social Workers' Personal Death Attitudes, Experiences, and Advance Directive Communication Behavior.&#x201d; Journal of Social Work in End&#x2010;of&#x2010;Life &amp; Palliative Care 1, no. 3: 21&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1300/J457v01n03_03.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black, K. 2007. &#x201c;Health Care Professionals' Death Attitudes, Experiences, and Advance Directive Communication Behavior.&#x201d; Death Studies 31, no. 6: 563&#x2013;572. https://doi.org/10.1080/07481180701356993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein, M., L. V. Hedges, J. P. T. Higgins, and H. R. Rothstein. 2021. Introduction to Meta&#x2010;Analysis. 2nd ed. Wiley.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein, M., J. P. T. Higgins, M. Egger, and G. Davey Smith. 2022. &#x201c;Comprehensive Meta&#x2010;Analysis Software.&#x201d; In Systematic Reviews in Health Research, 535&#x2013;548. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119099369.ch27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, H., L. Liu, and S. Xing. 2019. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Ke Hushi Si Wang Tai du de Liang Xing Yu Zhi Xing Yan Jiu [Quantitative and Qualitative Study on the Attitudes of Oncology Nurses Towards Death].&#x201d; Chinese General Practice Nursing 17, no. 10: 1267&#x2013;1273. https://doi.org/10.12104/j.issn.1674&#x2010;4748.2019.10.04.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;eki&#xe7;, Y., E. &#xd6;. Yazgan, and V. Duyan. 2022. &#x201c;Nurses' Experiences, Fear of Covid&#x2010;19, and Death Anxiety During the Covid&#x2010;19 Pandemic: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study From Turkey.&#x201d; Journal of Psychosocial Nursing and Mental Health Services 60, no. 12: 39&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.3928/02793695&#x2010;20220621&#x2010;01.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, W. P., and Y. K. Lin. 2023. &#x201c;Influence of Basic Attributes and Attitudes of Nurses Toward Death on Nurse Turnover: A Prospective Study.&#x201d; International Nursing Review 70, no. 4: 476&#x2013;484. https://doi.org/10.1111/inr.12781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Y., S. Hwang, C. Chang, and H. Tai. 2016. &#x201c;Jia Hu Bing Fang Hu Li Ren Yuan Mian Dui Si Wang Kong Ju Zhi Xiang Guan Yin Su Tan Tao &#x2010; Yi Nan Bu Mou Yi Xue Zhong Xin Wei Li [Factors Associated With the Fear of Death Among Intensive Care Nurses at a Medical Center in Southern Taiwan].&#x201d; Hua Yi Xue Bao 44: 127&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., and C. Wu. 2008. &#x201c;Hu Li Ren Yuan Si Wang Kong Ju Yu Lin Zhong Zhao Hu Zhi Tan Tao [Fear of Death and Terminal Care in Nurses].&#x201d; Taiwan Journal of Hospice Palliative Care 13, no. 1: 14&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.6537/TJHPC.2008.13(1).2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, P., M. Wang, Y. Liu, J. Sun, and F. Han. 2014. &#x201c;Bei Jing Shi 157 Ming Hushi de Si Wang Tai du Ji Lin Zhong Guan Huai Jiao Yu Xu Qiu Diao Cha Fen Xi [Nurses' Attitude Toward Death and Needs for Hospice Care Education].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing (China) 21, no. 16: 29&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., and S. Yang. 2020. &#x201c;Ji Ceng Yi Yuan Hushi Si Wang Jiao lv Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su [Status of Anxiety About Death and Influencing Factors Form Nurses in Primary Hospitals].&#x201d; Hu Li Shi Jian Yu Yan Jiu 17, no. 18: 27&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;9676.2020.18.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., and P. Lin. 2004. &#x201c;The Influential Factors Toward Caring Dying Patients of ICU Nurses.&#x201d; Tzu Chi Nursing Journal 3, no. 4: 49&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, J., L. Zhu, B. Shi, and L. Zhang. 2012. &#x201c;Jun Dui Yi Yuan He Tong Zhi Hushi Si Wang Tai du Yu Zhu Guan Xing Fu Gan de Xiang Guan Xing Yan Jiu [Study on Correlation Between Attitude to Death and Subjective Well&#x2010;Being of Contract Nurses in Military Hospital].&#x201d; Hu Li Yan Jiu 26, no. 10: 891&#x2013;893. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6493.2012.10.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf, E., M. Grant, F. van der Baan, M. Ausems, C. Leget, and S. Teunissen. 2024. &#x201c;The Impact of Hospice Care Structures on Care Processes: A Retrospective Cohort Study.&#x201d; American Journal of Hospice &amp; Palliative Care 41, no. 12: 1423&#x2013;1430. https://doi.org/10.1177/10499091241228254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delafontaine, A. C., R. Anders, B. Mathieu, C. R. Salath&#xe9;, and B. Putois. 2024. &#x201c;Impact of Confrontation to Patient Suffering and Death on Wellbeing and Burnout in Professionals: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; BMC Palliative Care 23, no. 1: 74. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12904&#x2010;024&#x2010;01393&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, C., and J. F. Jin. 2020. &#x201c;Ji Zhen Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Dui Qi Lin Zhong Zhao Hu Tai du Ying Xiang de Yan Jiu [the Influence of Death Attitude on Hospice Care Attitude Among Emergency Nurses].&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Nursing Education 17, no. 3: 275&#x2013;278. https://doi.org/10.3761/j.issn.1672&#x2010;9234.2020.03.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper, E. J., M. A. Hillen, M. Moors, J. C. F. Ket, H. W. M. van Laarhoven, and I. Henselmans. 2019. &#x201c;Relationship Between Physicians' Death Anxiety and Medical Communication and Decision&#x2010;Making: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Patient Education and Counseling 102, no. 2: 266&#x2013;274. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2018.09.019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, H., M. Wu, Y. Q. Pan, P. Q. Gan, C. L. Ding, and Y. Lv. 2020. &#x201c;An Hui Sheng Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi an Ning Liao Hu Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su [Current Status and Influencing Factors of Palliative Care Attitudes of Nurses From the Oncology Department in Anhui Province].&#x201d; Hu Li Shi Jian Yu Yan Jiu 17, no. 15: 1&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;9676.2020.15.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn, K., C. Otten, and E. Stephens. 2005. &#x201c;Nursing Experience and the Care of Dying Patients.&#x201d; Oncology Nursing Forum 32, no. 1: 97&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1188/05.ONF.97&#x2010;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzier&#x17c;anowski, T., and M. Kozlowski. 2022. &#x201c;Personal Fear of Their Own Death and Determination of Philosophy of Life Affects the Breaking of Bad News by Internal Medicine and Palliative Care Clinicians.&#x201d; Archives of Medical Science 18, no. 6: 1505&#x2013;1512. https://doi.org/10.5114/aoms.2019.85944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhadi, A., H. Javadian, and P. Farokhnezhad Afshar. 2022. &#x201c;Prediction of Mental Health by Religious Orientation and the Mediating Role of Death Anxiety Among Nurses in the Covid&#x2010;19 Pandemic.&#x201d; Journal of Health Sciences and Surveillance System 10, no. 4: 495&#x2013;501. https://doi.org/10.30476/jhsss.2021.92795.1390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gama, G., F. Barbosa, and M. Vieira. 2012. &#x201c;Factors Influencing Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death.&#x201d; International Journal of Palliative Nursing 18, no. 6: 267&#x2013;273. https://doi.org/10.12968/ijpn.2012.18.6.267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gama, G., F. Barbosa, and M. Vieira. 2014. &#x201c;Personal Determinants of Nurses' Burnout in End of Life Care.&#x201d; European Journal of Oncology Nursing 18, no. 5: 527&#x2013;533. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejon.2014.04.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, R., Y. Cai, Y. Li, C. Song, and T. Shi. 2018. &#x201c;Hu Shi Sheng Ming Yi Yi Gan Dui Si Wang Tai du Ying Xiang de Yan Jiu [the Relationship Between the Meaning in Life and Attitude Death of Nurses].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Management 18, no. 4: 461&#x2013;465. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1756.2018.04.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazanfari, M. J., R. C. Arani, A. Mollaei, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Related Factors Among Nurses During the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Jorjani Biomedicine Journal 10, no. 3: 35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gignac, G. E., and E. T. Szodorai. 2016. &#x201c;Effect Size Guidelines for Individual Differences Researchers.&#x201d; Personality and Individual Differences 102: 74&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2016.06.069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, X. 2020. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Nei Ke Hu Shi Dui Si Wang Tai du de Diao Cha Ji Dui Lin Zhong Hu Li Zhi Liang de Ying Xiang [Death Attitude of Nurses in Oncology Department and Its Influences on Quality of Hospice Nursing].&#x201d; Shi Yong Yi Yuan Lin Chuang Za Zhi 17, no. 4: 163&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., J. Liu, M. Xu, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi an Ning Liao Hu Zhao Hu Tai du Xian Kuang Diao Cha Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Survey on the Current Situation of Oncology Nurses' Attitudes Toward Palliative Care and Analysis of Influencing Factors].&#x201d; Jian Kang Bi Du 25: 285&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamama&#x2010;Raz, Y., Z. Solomon, and A. Ohry. 2000. &#x201c;Fear of Personal Death Among Physicians.&#x201d; Omega: Journal of Death and Dying 41, no. 2: 139&#x2013;149. https://doi.org/10.2190/7G35&#x2010;4CH6&#x2010;KDRG&#x2010;MH38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna, R., B. Jolanta, B. Katarzyna, Z. Kornelia, and J. Mariusz. 2024. &#x201c;The Impact of Patient Death on the Risk of Developing Occupational Burnout in Midwives a Preliminary Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; Scientific Reports 14, no. 1: 25634. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;024&#x2010;77607&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y., X. Huang, A. Yin, and S. Liu. 2019. &#x201c;ICU Hu Shi Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Yan Jiu [Attitudes Toward Hospice Care of ICU Nurses and Its Influence Factors].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing (China) 26, no. 11: 5&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.16460/j.issn1008&#x2010;9969.2019.11.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y., A. Yin, X. Huang, and S. Liu. 2020. &#x201c;Gong Qing Neng Li Zai ICU Hu Shi Si Wang Jiao lv Yu Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du Zhong de Zhong Jie Zuo Yong [Mediating Role of Empathy Ability in Death Anxiety and Attitude Toward Hospice Care of ICU Nurses].&#x201d; Shanghai Nursing 20, no. 2: 32&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1009&#x2010;8399.2020.02.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemphill, J. F. 2003. &#x201c;Interpreting the Magnitudes of Correlation Coefficients.&#x201d; American Psychologist 58, no. 1: 78&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1037/0003&#x2010;066X.58.1.78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J. P., S. G. Thompson, J. J. Deeks, and D. G. Altman. 2003. &#x201c;Measuring Inconsistency in Meta&#x2010;Analyses.&#x201d; BMJ 327, no. 7414: 557&#x2013;560. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoelter, J. W. 1979. &#x201c;Multidimensional Treatment of Fear of Death.&#x201d; Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 47, no. 5: 996&#x2013;999. https://doi.org/10.1037//0022&#x2010;006x.47.5.996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, Q. N., S. F&#xe0;bregues, G. Bartlett, et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;The Mixed Methods Appraisal Tool (MMAT) Version 2018 for Information Professionals and Researchers.&#x201d; Education for Information 34, no. 4: 285&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, C., Y. Tao, N. Ding, and S. Chen. 2015. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Yi Yuan Hu Shi Si Wang Jiao lv Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su Yan Jiu [the Death Anxiety Status and Influencing Factors Among Nurses in a Cancer Hospital].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Management 15, no. 8: 1007&#x2013;1010. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1756.2015.08.034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, S., and S. Yang. 2021. &#x201c;Quan Zhou Shi Ji Ceng Yi Yuan Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Analysis of Attitude to Death and Influencing Factors Among Nurse in Primary Hospital of Quanzhou City].&#x201d; Occupational Health 37, no. 05: 653&#x2013;656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J., L. Sun, D. Gu, and Q. Wei. 2020. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi Sheng Ming Yi Yi Gan Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Investigation of Nurses' Meaning of Life in the Oncology Department and Analysis of Influencing Factors].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Research 34, no. 20: 3594&#x2013;3600. https://doi.org/10.12102/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6493.2020.20.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izadi, F., and P. Farokhzad. 2022. &#x201c;Predicting the Risk of COVID&#x2010;19 Among Healthcare Staff Based on the Components of Depression and Death Anxiety.&#x201d; Journal of Research &amp; Health 12, no. 5: 347&#x2013;354. https://doi.org/10.32598/JRH.12.5.2030.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jazaiery, M., K. Rezaeifar, M. Sayyah, and M. Cheraghi. 2022. &#x201c;Relationship Between Mental Health and Death Anxiety During COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic in Dental Staff and Students: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychiatry 13: 849868. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2022.849868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagan, M. 2021. &#x201c;Social Support Moderates the Relationship Between Death Anxiety and Psychological Distress Among Israeli Nurses.&#x201d; Psychological Reports 124, no. 4: 1502&#x2013;1514. https://doi.org/10.1177/0033294120945593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karkhah, S., A. Jafari, E. Paryad, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Related Factors Among Iranian Critical Care Nurses: A Multicenter Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; Omega (Westport) 88, no. 3: 1153&#x2013;1167. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228211062368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavakl&#x131;, M., M. Ak, F. U&#x11f;uz, and O. O. T&#xfc;rkmen. 2020. &#x201c;The Mediating Role of Selfcompassion in the Relationship Between Perceived COVID&#x2010;19 Threat and Death Anxiety (eng).&#x201d; Turkish Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 23, no. 50: 15&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.5505/kpd.2020.59862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelvens, C. 1997. &#x201c;Fear and Anxiety.&#x201d; Retrieved on Oct 15, 2021 from Northridge: California State University. https://www.csun.edu/~vcpsy00h/students/fear.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khajoei, R., M. Dehghan, N. Heydarpour, M. Mazallahi, S. Shokohian, and M. Azizzadeh Forouzi. 2022. &#x201c;Comparison of Death Anxiety, Death Obsession, and Humor in Nurses and Medical Emergency Personnel in COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic.&#x201d; Journal of Emergency Nursing 48, no. 5: 559&#x2013;570. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jen.2022.02.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latha, K. S., M. Sahana, D. Mariella, K. Subbannayya, and K. Asha. 2013. &#x201c;Factors Related to Life Satisfaction, Meaning of Life, Religiosity, and Death Anxiety in Health Care Staff and Students: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study From India.&#x201d; Online Journal of Health and Allied Science 12, no. 2: 7. http://www.ojhas.org/issue46/2013&#x2010;2&#x2010;7.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe1;zaro&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez, C., J. &#xc1;. Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez, J. G&#xf3;mez&#x2010;Gal&#xe1;n, and E. L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Meneses. 2020. &#x201c;Anxiety About the Risk of Death of Their Patients in Health Professionals in Spain: Analysis at the Peak of the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17, no. 16: 5938. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17165938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehto, R. H., and K. F. Stein. 2009. &#x201c;Death Anxiety: An Analysis of an Evolving Concept.&#x201d; Research and Theory for Nursing Practice 23, no. 1: 23&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1891/1541&#x2010;6577.23.1.23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenhard, W., and A. Lenhard. 2022. &#x201c;Computation of Effect Sizes.&#x201d; Psychometrica. https://www.psychometrica.de/effect_size.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letzner, R. D. 2024. &#x201c;Death Anxiety in Connection to Anxiety and Depressive Disorders: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis on Emotional Distress in Clinical and Community Samples.&#x201d; Death Studies 48, no. 4: 393&#x2013;406. https://doi.org/10.1080/07481187.2023.2230556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., C. Sun, X. Chen, and S. Chen. 2022. &#x201c;Xin Sheng er Zhong Zheng Jian Hu Shi Dui Si Wang Tai du Yu an Ning Liao Hu Jiao Yu Xu Qiu de Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [Correlation Analysis Between Death Attitude and Hospice Education Needs of the Nurses in Neonatal Intensive Care Unit].&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Emergency and Critical Care Nursing 3, no. 5: 431&#x2013;436. https://doi.org/10.3761/j.issn.2096&#x2010;7446.2022.05.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C., H. Kao, and H. Hong. 2010. &#x201c;Hu Li Zai Zhi Jin Xiu Zhuan Ban Xue Sheng Zhi Ya Yi Yin Ying Lei Xing Yu Si Wang Jiao lv, Sheng Huo Man Yi du Ji Zhu Guan Xing Fu Gan Zhi Xiang Guan Yan Jiu [Relationship Between a Repressive Coping Style and Death Anxiety, Satisfaction With Life, and Subjective Well&#x2010;Being Among the Clinical Nursing Degree Program Students].&#x201d; Chinese Journal of School Health 57: 23&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.30026/CJSH.201012.0002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y., Q. Gao, D. Xie, L. Xie, S. Yin, and Y. Xu. 2022. &#x201c;San Ji Yi Yuan Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Xian Zhuang Fen Xi Yu Ling Xing Jiao Yu Shi Shi Tan Tao [Analysis on Status Quo of Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death in Tertiary Hospitals and Discussion on Implementation of Spiritual Education].&#x201d; Shanghai Nursing 22, no. 3: 38&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1009&#x2010;8399.2022.03.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsey, M. W., and D. B. Wilson. 2001. Practical Meta&#x2010;Analysis. Sage Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, P. 2013. &#x201c;Zhong Zheng Jian Hu Shi Wang Tai du Yu Gong Zuo Juan Dai de Xiang Guan Xing Yan Jiu [Correlative Study of Attitude to Death and Job Burnout for Icu Nurses of Army Hospital].&#x201d; Medical Information 26, no. 4: 87&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, N. H., S. Thanasilp, T. T. Anh, and N. T. Minh Chinh. 2022. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Its Related Factors Among Advanced Nurse Practitioner Candidates: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; Nursing Forum 2023: 6403193. https://doi.org/10.1155/2023/6403193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y., W. Yu, J. Zhang, and R. Li. 2024. &#x201c;Advancements in Hospice and Palliative Care in China: A Five&#x2010;Year Review.&#x201d; Asia&#x2010;Pacific Journal of Oncology Nursing 11, no. 3: 100385. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apjon.2024.100385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, D. 2023. &#x201c;Jian Hu Shi Hu Shi Dui Si Wang Tai du Yi Ji an Ning Liao Hu Jiao Yu Xu Qiu de Xian Zhuang Diao Cha [Survey on Intensive Care Unit Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death and Needs for Hospice Care Education].&#x201d; Chinese General Practice Nursing 21, no. 12: 1712&#x2013;1715. https://doi.org/10.12104/j.issn.1674&#x2010;4748.2023.12.032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, J., X. Chun, Q. Ye, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;331 Ming ICU Hu Shi de Si Wang Tai du Shui Ping Fen Xi [Analysis of Death Attitude Levels Among 331 Icu Nurses].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing (China) 27, no. 9: 42&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.16460/j.issn1008&#x2010;9969.2020.09.042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, L., F. Li, J. Zhang, Y. Li, Q. Cheng, and Y. Wen. 2021. &#x201c;An Ning Liao Hu Zhuan Ke Hu Shi de Si Wang Tai du Yu Si Wang Jiao Yu Xu Qiu Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [the Correlation Between the Attitude to Death and Death Education of the Palliative Care Specialist Nurses].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Management 21, no. 2: 195&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1756.2021.02.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, X., B. Jiang, J. Liao, G. Wang, X. Liu, and Y. Jiang. 2019. &#x201c;Si Chuan di Qu Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi Zhao Gu Lin Zhong Bing Ren Tai du Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su [Status and Influencing Factors of Caring Attitude Toward Dying Patients Among Oncology Nurses in Sichuan].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Research 33, no. 22: 3830&#x2013;3835. https://doi.org/10.12102/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6493.2019.22.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez, J. &#xc1;., C. L&#xe1;zaro&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez, and J. G&#xf3;mez&#x2010;Gal&#xe1;n. 2021. &#x201c;Death Anxiety in Social Workers as a Consequence of the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic.&#x201d; Behavioral Science 11, no. 5: 61. https://doi.org/10.3390/bs11050061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n&#x2010;Parrilla, M. &#xc1;., N. Dur&#xe1;n&#x2010;G&#xf3;mez, M. D. C. Marques, C. F. L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Jurado, M. Goes, and M. C. C&#xe1;ceres. 2025. &#x201c;Cross&#x2010;Cultural Differences in Fear of Death, Emotional Intelligence, Coping With Death, and Burnout Among Nursing Students: A Comparative Study Between Spain and Portugal.&#x201d; Behavioral Science 15, no. 7: 993. https://doi.org/10.3390/bs15070993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez, J., N. Y. Torres&#x2010;Soto, K. Casco&#x2010;Gallardo, A. Ruiz&#x2010;Lara, B. Mart&#xed;nezRam&#xed;rez, and E. Fuentes&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez. 2023. &#x201c;Fear and Coping With Death in Intensive Care Nurses: A Structural Model Predictor of Compassion Fatigue.&#x201d; Investigacion y Educacion en Enfermeria 41, no. 1: e12. https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.iee.v41n1e12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo, C. G., and D. Oliver. 2011. &#x201c;Can Addressing Death Anxiety Reduce Health Care Workers' Burnout and Improve Patient Care?&#x201d; Journal of Palliative Care 27, no. 4: 287&#x2013;295. https://doi.org/10.1177/082585971102700405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Z., Y. Li, C. Zhi, and L. Gao. 2014. &#x201c;Hu Shi Zhao Gu Lin Zhong Huan Zhe Tai du Yu Ge Ren Si Wang Tai du de Xiang Guan Xing Yan Jiu [Correlation Between Nurses' Attitudes to Terminal Patients and Their Personal Attitudes Toward Death].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Science 29, no. 2: 51&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.3870/hlxzz.2014.02.051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzies, R. E., K. McMullen, G. D. Riotto, S. Iliescu, B. Petrovic, and M. Remfrey. 2024. &#x201c;From Dread to Disorder: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis of the Impact of Death Anxiety on Mental Illness Symptoms.&#x201d; Clinical Psychology Review 113: 102490. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2024.102490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudi, S., A. Bijani, M. T. Tayebi, and S. Habibi. 2017. &#x201c;Relationship Between Death Anxiety and Mental Health Status Among Nurses in Hospitals Affiliated to Babol University of Medical Sciences.&#x201d; Journal of Babol University of Medical Sciences 19, no. 2: 47&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nia, H. S., R. H. Lehto, A. Ebadi, and H. Peyrovi. 2016. &#x201c;Death Anxiety Among Nurses and Health Care Professionals: A Review Article.&#x201d; International Journal of Community Based Nursing and Midwifery 4, no. 1: 2&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norouzi, M., P. Ghorbani Vajargah, A. Falakdami, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;A Systematic Review of Death Anxiety and Related Factors Among Nurses.&#x201d; Omega&#x2010;Journal of Death and Dying 89: 302228221095710. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228221095710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zk&#x131;ri&#x15f;, A., G. G&#xfc;le&#xe7;, &#xc7;. Yenilmez, A. Musmul, and M. Yana&#x15f;. 2011. &#x201c;A Study on the Attitudes of Physicians: Approach Towards Death and Terminally ill.&#x201d; Dusunen Adam Journal of Psychiatry and Neurological Sciences 24, no. 2: 89&#x2013;100. https://doi.org/10.5350/DAJPN2011240201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, M. J., J. E. McKenzie, P. M. Bossuyt, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;The PRISMA 2020 Statement: An Updated Guideline for Reporting Systematic Reviews.&#x201d; BMJ (Clinical Research ed.) 372: n71. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, Y., H. Chang, and H. Shin. 2021. &#x201c;Factors of Hospitals Associated With an Independent Hospice Care Unit.&#x201d; Journal of Hospice &amp; Palliative Nursing 23, no. 6: 584&#x2013;590. https://doi.org/10.1097/njh.0000000000000806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, L., R. Cant, S. Payne, et&#xa0;al. 2013. &#x201c;Emergency and Palliative Care Nurses' Levels of Anxiety About Death and Coping With Death: A Questionnaire Survey.&#x201d; Australasian Emergency Nursing Journal 16, no. 4: 152&#x2013;159. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aenj.2013.08.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, F., Y. Wu, and Y. Wang. 2020. &#x201c;Ji Wei Zhong Zheng Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Dui Qi Lin Zhong Zhao Hu Tai du Ying Xiang de Yan Jiu [Study on the Impact of Critical Care Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death on Their Attitudes Toward End&#x2010;of&#x2010;Life Care].&#x201d; Electronic Journal of Practical Clinical Nursing Science 5, no. 50: 168&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, S., H. Elbi, A. Cakmakci Cetinkaya, S. Altan, E. Ozan, and E. Pirincci. 2021. &#x201c;Factors That Predict the Perception of Spirituality and Spiritual Care of Nurses Working in High&#x2010;Risk Units and the Effect of Death Anxiety.&#x201d; Perspectives in Psychiatric Care 57, no. 2: 473&#x2013;480. https://doi.org/10.1111/ppc.12651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratiu, L., P. L. Curseu, and O. C. Fodor. 2022. &#x201c;Death Anxiety, Job Satisfaction and Counterproductive Work Behaviors During the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic: A Comparative Study of Healthcare and Non&#x2010;Healthcare Staff.&#x201d; Psychology, Health &amp; Medicine 27, no. 9: 2030&#x2013;2042. https://doi.org/10.1080/13548506.2021.2007965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roff, L. L., R. Butkeviciene, and D. L. Klemmack. 2002. &#x201c;Death Anxiety and Religiosity Among Lithuanian Health and Social Service Professionals.&#x201d; Death Studies 26, no. 9: 731&#x2013;742. https://doi.org/10.1080/07481180290106517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe3;o, M. E., G. Belli, S. Jumayeva, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Death Education in Practice: A Scoping Review of Interventions, Strategies, and Psychosocial Impact.&#x201d; Omega&#x2014;Journal of Death and Dying. Advance online publication.&#xa0;https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228251338643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidi, S., and F. Hamidi. 2024. &#x201c;The Relationship Between Religiosity and Spirituality With Death Anxiety Among Nurses: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Reports in Clinical Practice 2, no. Issue 2: 82&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.32598/JNRCP.23.108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson, T., and P. Shvartzman. 2018. &#x201c;Association Between Level of Exposure to Death and Dying and Professional Quality of Life Among Palliative Care Workers.&#x201d; Palliative &amp; Supportive Care 16, no. 4: 442&#x2013;451. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1478951517000487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfraz, M., I. Mushtaque, M. A. Mamun, and M. Raza. 2025. &#x201c;Death Anxiety Among Pakistani HCWs: The Role of COVID&#x2010;19 Vaccine Acceptance and Positive Religious Coping Strategy.&#x201d; Omega 92, no. 1: 511&#x2013;531. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228231186360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng, M., and X. Huang. 2022. &#x201c;Zhong Zheng Jian Hu Shi Dui Si Wang Tai du Yu an Ning Liao Hu Jiao Yu Xu Qiu de Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [Analysis of the Correlation Between Icu Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death and Their Educational Needs in Palliative Care].&#x201d; Sheng Ming Ke Xue Yi Qi 20, no. z1: 409&#x2013;410. https://doi.org/10.11967/2022006185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, H., B. Shan, Y. Zhang, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;She Qu Yi Hu Ren Yuan Dui Dai Lin Zhong Guan Huai, Si Wang He Zhao Gu Lin Zhong Huan Zhe de Tai du Ji Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [Community Health Care Providers' Attitude Towards End&#x2010;Of&#x2010;Life Care, Death and Caring for Dying Patients].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Management 19, no. 6: 830&#x2013;835. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1756.2019.06.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne, J. A., M. J. Bradburn, and M. Egger. 2008. &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis in Stata.&#x201d; In Systematic Reviews in Health Care: Meta&#x2010;Analysis in Context, edited by M. Egger, G. Davey Smith, and D. G. Altman, 2nd ed., 347&#x2013;369. BMJ Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne, J. A., A. J. Sutton, J. P. Ioannidis, et&#xa0;al. 2011. &#x201c;Recommendations for Examining and Interpreting Funnel Plot Asymmetry in Meta&#x2010;Analyses of Randomised Controlled Trials.&#x201d; BMJ 343: d4002. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d4002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J., C. Yan, S. Chen, S. Kuo, P. Chen, and M. Huang. 2005. &#x201c;An Ning Liao Hu Ke Cheng Dui Er Zhuan Zai Zhi Ban Hu Sheng Si Wang Kong Ju Yu Tai du Zhi Ying Xiang [Effect of Hospice Education Program on Fear and Attitude Toward Death Among Associate Degree of Post&#x2010;Register Nurse].&#x201d; Journal of Yuanpei University of Science and Technology 12: 53&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.30171/JYUST.200512.0004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, C., X. Li, L. He, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;San Ji Zong He Yi Yuan Hu Shi Lin Zhong Guan Huai Yu Si Wang Tai du Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Analysis of Nurses' Hospice Care and Attitude Towards Death and Its Influencing Factors in Tertiary General Hospitals].&#x201d; Journal of Medical Information 34, no. 15: 71&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1006&#x2010;1959.2021.15.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, D., F. Xu, and S. Li. 2022. &#x201c;Zhong Zheng Jian Hu Shi Qing Xu Zhi Li Yu Si Wang Jiao lv de Xian Zhuang Diao Cha Ji Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [Investigation and Correlation Analysis of Emotional Intelligence and Death Anxiety in Patients in Acute Intensive Care Unit].&#x201d; Yi Yao Gao Zhi Jiao Yu Yu Xian Dai Hu Li 5, no. 3: 253&#x2013;256. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.2096&#x2010;501X.2022.03.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, J., M. Shen, and Z. Li. 2022. &#x201c;When Cultural Values Meet Professional Values: A Qualitative Study of Chinese Nurses' Attitudes and Experiences Concerning Death.&#x201d; BMC Palliative Care 21: 181. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12904&#x2010;022&#x2010;01067&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentine, J. C., T. D. Pigott, and H. R. Rothstein. 2010. &#x201c;How Many Studies Do You Need? A Primer on Statistical Power for Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics 35, no. 2: 215&#x2013;247. https://doi.org/10.3102/1076998609346961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a, D., M. De&#x2010;la&#x2010;Rica&#x2010;Escu&#xed;n, C. Germ&#xe1;n&#x2010;Bes, and A.&#x2010;L. Caballero&#x2010;Navarro. 2023. &#x201c;Anxiety and Fear of Death in Health Professionals in Hospital Emergency Services in Arag&#xf3;n.&#x201d; Enfermer&#xed;a Cl&#xed;nica (English Edition) 33, no. 4: 269&#x2013;277. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enfcle.2023.03.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, X., W. Feng, R. Zhu, J. Zhang, Y. Ren, and S. Zang. 2023. &#x201c;Ji Zhen Ke Hu Shi Zhi Ye Bei Shang Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Emergency Department Nurses' Professional Grief Status and Analysis of Influencing Factors].&#x201d; Chinese General Practice Nursing 21, no. 16: 2267&#x2013;2271. https://doi.org/10.12104/j.issn.1674&#x2010;4748.2023.16.029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. J. 2025. Mortal Distress of Healthcare Professionals (HCPs): Conceptualization, Measurement and Outcomes [Doctoral dissertation, The University of Hong Kong]. HKU Scholars Hub.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. 2017. &#x201c;Mei Long Zhen She Qu Hu Shi de Si Wang Tai du Ji Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du de Xian Zhuang Diao Cha Ji Fen Xi [Investigation on Death Attitude and Hospice Care Attitude of Community Nurses in Meilong Town].&#x201d; Systems Medicine 2, no. 22: 36&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.19368/j.cnki.2096&#x2010;1782.2017.22.036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., F. Dong, and R. Zheng. 2013. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Yi Yuan Hu Shi Dui Dai Si Wang Ji Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du de Diao Cha Yan Jiu [Survey Study on Nurses' Attitudes Toward Death and End&#x2010;of&#x2010;Life Care in Oncology Hospitals].&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Practical Nursing 29, no. 25: 73&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.issn.1672&#x2010;7088.2013.25.035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., and J. Zhang. 2020. &#x201c;Xin Ru Zhi Hu Shi Dui Dai Lin Zhong Guan Huai Ji Si Wang Tai du de Diao Cha Yan Jiu [Survey Study on New Nurses' Attitudes Toward End&#x2010;of&#x2010;Life Care and Death].&#x201d; Today Nurse 27, no. 11: 33&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.19791/j.cnki.1006&#x2010;6411.2020.31.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., Y. Jin, S. Li, et&#xa0;al. 2016. &#x201c;Tian Jin Shi 8 Jia San Ji Jia Deng Yi Yuan Ji Zhen Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Yan Jiu [the Current Status on Attitude to Death and Its Influencing Factors in Emergency Nurses in Tianjin ].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Management 16, no. 3: 340&#x2013;344. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1756.2016.03.015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., and J. Lu. 2019. &#x201c;Ji Zhen Hu Shi Zhi Mian Huan Zhe Si Wang Shi Qing Xu Ti Yan de Zhi Xing Yan Jiu [A Qualitative Study of Emotional Experience of Emergency Nurses Facing Death].&#x201d; Today Nurse 26, no. 12: 6&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Q. Gao, R. Wang, D. Wang, and Y. Lin. 2021. &#x201c;Lin Chuang Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Dui Qi Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du Ying Xiang de Yan Jiu [Study on the Influence of Clinical Nurses' Attitudes Towards Death on Their Attitudes Towards Hospice Care].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Administration 21, no. 11: 795&#x2013;800. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1671&#x2010;315x.2021.11.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., C.&#x2010;M. Yang, S. Guo, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;San ji jia deng yi yuan ICU hu shi zhi ye si wang hui bi xian zhuang ji ying xiang yin su [Status quo and Influencing Factors of Professional Death Avoidance Among ICU Nurses in Tertiary Grade Hospitals].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Research 38, no. 16: 2916&#x2013;2921. https://doi.org/10.12102/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6493.2024.16.019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, N., X. Gao, Y. Li, H. He, S. Lv, and Y. Liu. 2020. &#x201c;He Bei Sheng Mou San Ji Yi Yuan Gan Ran Ke Hu Li Tuan Dui Si Wang Jiao lv de Xian Zhuang Diao Cha [Investigation on the Status of Death Anxiety of the Nursing Team in the Infection Department of a Tertiary Hospital in Hebei Province].&#x201d; Hebei Medical Journal 42, no. 24: 3806&#x2013;3809. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1002&#x2010;7386.2020.24.029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H., D. Zhao, H. Zhong, and L. Yu. 2023. &#x201c;Hu Nan Sheng Ji Zhen Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Yu Si Wang Jiao Yu Xu Qiu Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Xiang Guan Xing Fen Xi [Current Situation and Correlation Analysis of Attitude Towards Death and Demands for Death Education Among Emergency Nurses in Hunan Province].&#x201d; Chongqing Medicine 52, no. 8: 1219&#x2013;1224. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1671&#x2010;8348.2023.08.020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S., Y. Lv, H. Xin, S. Hu, X. Ji, and B. Yu. 2022. &#x201c;Bu Tong Deng Ji Yi Yuan di Nian Zi Hu Shi de Si Wang Jiao lv Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Current Status of Death Anxiety in Nurses With Low Seniority at Hospitals of Different Tiers and Its Influencing Factors].&#x201d; Guangxi Medical Journal 44, no. 11: 1265&#x2013;1269. https://doi.org/10.11675/j.issn.0253&#x2010;4304.2022.11.16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y., and X. Liang. 2023. &#x201c;Yin Chuan Shi Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Analysis on the Status Quo and Influencing Factors of Death Attitude of Oncology Nurses in Yinchuan City].&#x201d; Chinese Evidence&#x2010;Based Nursing 9, no. 2: 278&#x2013;282. https://doi.org/10.12102/j.issn.2095&#x2010;8668.2023.02.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zana, &#xc1;., A. Kegye, E. Czegl&#xe9;di, and K. Heged&#x171;s. 2020. &#x201c;Differences in Well&#x2010;Being and Fear of Death Among Female Hospice Employees and Volunteers in Hungary.&#x201d; BMC Palliative Care 19, no. 1: 58. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12904&#x2010;020&#x2010;00550&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, C., D. Lin, L. Zeng, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;San Ji Zong He Yi Yuan Yi Hu Ren Yuan Dui Dai Si Wang de Tai du Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Analysis of the Attitudes Towards Death and the Influencing Factors Among the Medical Staff of Tertiary General Hospitals].&#x201d; Journal of Chengdu Medical College 14, no. 4: 511&#x2013;516. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1674&#x2010;2257.2019.04.026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, L., C.&#x2010;Y. Li, C.&#x2010;Y. Zeng, S.&#x2010;Y. Li, Y.&#x2010;H. Wang, and H.&#x2010;M. Liu. 2022. &#x201c;San Ji Zong He Yi Yuan Yi Hu Ren Yuan Si Wang Tai du He Zhi Ye Juan Dai Xian Zhuang Ji Xiang Guan Xing Yan Jiu [the Situation and Correlation Between Death Attitudes and Job Burnout Among Medical Staff in Nei Jiang].&#x201d; Modern Nurse 29, no. 2: 122&#x2013;127. https://doi.org/10.19792/j.cnki.1006&#x2010;6411.2022.05.038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., T. Lv, L. Li, F. Chen, S. He, and D. Ding. 2024. &#x201c;Nurse Life&#x2010;and&#x2010;Death Education From the Perspective of Chinese Traditional Culture.&#x201d; Omega&#x2010; Journal of Death and Dying. https://doi.org/10.1177/00302228241236981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., and L. Wu. 2018. &#x201c;Xin Jiang Lin Chuang Hu Shi Si Wang Tai du Dui Qi Lin Zhong Zhao Hu Tai du de Ying Xiang Yan Jiu [Influence of Death Attitude on Hospice Care Attitude of Clinical Nurses in Xinjiang].&#x201d; Chinese General Practice Nursing 16, no. 11: 1291&#x2013;1294. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1674&#x2010;4748.2018.11.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., L. Liu, and H. Yang. 2022. &#x201c;Huo Yi Zhi Chi Zai NICU Hu Shi Xin Li Fu Yuan Li Yu Si Wang Jiao lv Jian de Zhong Jie Zuo Yong [the Mediating Role of Benefit Support Between Psychological Resilience and Death Anxiety Among NICU Nurses].&#x201d; Bengbu Yi Xue Yuan Xue Bao 47, no. 5: 675&#x2013;679. https://doi.org/10.13898/j.cnki.issn.1000&#x2010;2200.2022.05.030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S., L. Wen, S. Lv, and L. Chen. 2024. &#x201c;Lin chuang hu shi si wang ying dui neng li yu si wang tai du, zhi ye ren dong de xiang guan xing fen xi [Correlation of Competence in Coping With Death, Attitude Towards Death, and Professional Identity Among Clinical Nurses].&#x201d; Chinese Nursing Research 38, no. 19: 3550&#x2013;3555. https://doi.org/10.12102/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6493.2024.19.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., and Y. Li. 2020. &#x201c;ICU Hu Shi Lin Zhong Guan Huai Tai du Xian Zhuang Ji Qi Ying Xiang Yin Su [the Current Situation and Influencing Factors of ICU Nurses' Hospice Attitude].&#x201d; Medical Information 33, no. 8: 150&#x2013;152. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1006&#x2010;1959.2020.08.049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H., Z. Wang, J. Piao, Y. Li, S. Di, and X. Yin. 2022. &#x201c;Xin Ru Zhi Hu Shi Si Wang Jiao Yu Xu Qiu Zhuang Kuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Death Education Needs and Its Influencing Factors Among Newly Recruited Nurses].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Science 37, no. 2: 41&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.3870/j.issn.1001&#x2010;4152.2022.02.041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H., Z. Wang, W. Yan, S. Di, H. Bi, and J. Ye. 2023. &#x201c;Zhong Liu Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Jiao lv Xian Zhuang Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Death Anxiety and the Associated Factors Among Oncology Nurses].&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Science 38, no. 4: 79&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.3870/j.issn.1001&#x2010;4152.2023.04.079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, N., B. Liu, and Y. Wang. 2022. &#x201c;Examining the Relationship Between Death Anxiety and Well&#x2010;Being of Frontline Medical Staff During the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 19, no. 20: 13430. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph192013430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, R., M. J. Bloomer, Q. Guo, and S. F. Lee. 2021. &#x201c;New Graduate Nurses' Coping With Death and the Relationship With Death Self&#x2010;Efficacy and Death Anxiety: A Multicentre Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; Journal of Advanced Nursing 77, no. 2: 795&#x2013;804. https://doi.org/10.1111/jan.14621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, R., S. F. Lee, and M. J. Bloomer. 2016. &#x201c;How New Graduate Nurses Experience Patient Death: A Systematic Review and Qualitative Meta&#x2010;Synthesis.&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Studies 53: 320&#x2013;330. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2015.09.013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L., J. Wu, and Y. Guo. 2021. &#x201c;Gan Dan Wai Ke Hu Shi Si Wang Jiao lv Xian Zhuang Diao Cha Ji Ying Xiang Yin Su Fen Xi [Investigation on Death Anxiety of Nurses in Hepatobiliary Surgery and Analysis of Influencing Factors].&#x201d; China Medical Herald 18, no. 35: 58&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuccala, M., R. E. Menzies, C. J. Hunt, and M. J. Abbott. 2022. &#x201c;A Systematic Review of the Psychometric Properties of Death Anxiety Self&#x2010;Report Measures.&#x201d; Death Studies 46, no. 2: 257&#x2013;279. https://doi.org/10.1080/07481187.2019.1699203.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>