<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41838377</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Complex, Plyometric, and Traditional Resistance Training on Neuromuscular Performance in Highly Trained Male Soccer Players: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">31</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-026-01002-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The modality of resistance training (e.g., plyometric training [PLYO], traditional resistance training [TRT]) can specifically affect gains in muscle strength and power measures in soccer players. Further, effects of resistance training modality on neuromuscular performance measures (e.g., electromechanical delay [EMD]) are inconsistent in non-athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the effects of PLYO, TRT, and combined PLYO and TRT (i.e., complex training [CT]) on muscle strength, power, and EMD in highly trained male soccer players (age: 21.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.6 years).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Participants were randomly assigned to eight weeks of CT (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;30), PLYO (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;28), and TRT (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;26) in addition to their regular soccer training, or soccer training control condition (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;29). Pre- and post-measurements comprised tests for maximal eccentric knee flexor and concentric knee extensor peak torque (PT), their functional ratio (FUNC-H/Q), and the corresponding EMD of the knee flexors at three angular velocities (60, 180, and 300&#xb0;/s).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Results showed a significant main effect of group for concentric and eccentric PT (p&lt;.001, 1.67&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;3.17). Concentric and eccentric PT were larger for CT, PLYO, and TRT groups compared to control group (CG) with the greatest effects for CT across all angular velocities (p&lt;.001, 0.95&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;3.57). Additionally, a significant group effect was identified for FUNC-H/Q at 300&#xb0;/s (p=.002, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.83) with lower ratios in PLYO and TRT groups but not CT compared with CG (p&lt;.001, -0.94&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2264;-0.83). Further, significant and large-sized group effects for EMD were found at 60, 180, and 300&#xb0;/s (p&lt;.001, 0.96&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;2.89). Post-hoc test showed lower EMD values in CT compared with PLYO, TRT, and CG (p&lt;.001, -2.88&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2264;-0.87). Moreover, EMD was lower in PLYO and TRT compared with CG at 60 and 300&#xb0;/s (p&lt;.001, -1.84&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;d&#x2264;-1.10).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Complex training, PT, and TRT were effective training modalities in improving neuromuscular performance (i.e., maximal eccentric knee flexor/concentric knee extensor PT, knee flexor EMD) in highly trained soccer players. More specifically, CT appears to be superior in maintaining higher FUNC-H/Q values compared with PLYO and TRT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study does not report results related to healthcare interventions using human participants and therefore it was not prospectively registered on a clinical trial registry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Ashker</LastName><ForeName>Said</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8145-2775</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Self&#x2011;Development Department, Deanship of Preparatory Year, Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University, 31441, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaabene</LastName><ForeName>Helmi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7812-7931</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology and Angiology, University Hospital Magdeburg, 39120, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Sup&#xe9;rieur de Sport et de l'Education Physique du Kef, Universit&#xe9; de Jendouba, 7100, Le Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chamari</LastName><ForeName>Karim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9178-7678</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Naufar, Wellness and Recovery Center, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeterbakken</LastName><ForeName>Atle H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5592-6551</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Food and Natural Sciences, Faculty of Education, Arts, and Sports, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behm</LastName><ForeName>David G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9406-6056</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prieske</LastName><ForeName>Olaf</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4475-4413</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Exercise and Movement, University of Applied Sciences for Sports and Management Potsdam, Olympischer Weg 7, 14471, Potsdam, Germany. prieske@fhsmp.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combined resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contrast training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hamstrings to quadriceps ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: The participants were informed on the characteristics of their participation, agreed to participate, and signed the informed consent form. The study was approved by the ethics committee of the Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University (IRB-2022.19.175) and was conducted in accordance with the latest revision of the Declaration of Helsinki (2013). Competing Interests: Said El-Ashker, Helmi Chaabene, Karim Chamari, Atle H. Saeterbakken, David G. Behm, and Olaf Prieske declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41838377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12992747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-026-01002-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-026-01002-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;len T, Chamari K, Castagna C, Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Physiology of Soccer. Sports Med. 2005;35(6):501&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535060-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15974635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cometti G, Maffiuletti NA, Pousson M, Chatard JC, Maffulli N. Isokinetic strength and anaerobic power of elite, subelite and amateur French soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2001;22(1):45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2001-11331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11258641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fran&#xe7;a C, Martins F, Przednowek K, Marques A, Ihle A, Sarmento H, et al. Knee and Hip Muscle Strength of Male Soccer Players from Different Competitive Levels. J Hum Kinet. 2024;93:17&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/jhk/185217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11307174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39132414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green B, Bourne MN, Pizzari T. Isokinetic strength assessment offers limited predictive validity for detecting risk of future hamstring strain in sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2018;52(5):329&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29187349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Milanese C, Longo S, Limonta E, Rampichini S, et al. Specific Adaptations in Performance and Muscle Architecture After Weighted Jump-Squat vs. Body Mass Squat Jump Training in Recreational Soccer Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):921&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29420390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Trolle M, Bangsbo J, Klausen K. Specificity of training velocity and training load on gains in isokinetic knee joint strength. Acta Physiol Scand. 1996;156(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201X.1996.438162000.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8868268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormier P, Freitas TT, Loturco I, Turner A, Virgile A, Haff GG, et al. Within session exercise sequencing during programming for complex training: historical perspectives, terminology, and training considerations. Sports Med. 2022;52(10):2371&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01715-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer P, Uebellacker F, Mitter B, Aigner AJ, Hasenoehrl T, Ristl R, et al. Combining higher-load and lower-load resistance training exercises: A systematic review and meta-analysis of findings from complex training studies. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(7):838&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30683485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa RK, Lum D, Moran J, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of Complex Training on Sprint, Jump, and Change of Direction Ability of Soccer Players: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Front Psychol. 2020;11:627869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.627869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33551937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nu&#xf1;ez J, Suarez-Arrones L, de Hoyo M, Loturco I. Strength Training in Professional Soccer: Effects on Short-sprint and Jump Performance. Int J Sports Med. 2022;43(6):485&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Li R, Zheng W, Ramirez-Campillo R, de Villarreal ES, Zhang M. The Effect of Combined Strength, Plyometric, and Sprint Training on Repeated Sprint Ability in Team-Sport Athletes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(4):718&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Lawson DL, Morrison WE, Fairweather I. Electromechanical delay in isometric muscle contractions evoked by voluntary, reflex and electrical stimulation. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1995;70(2):138&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00361541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7768236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ste Croix MB, Priestley AM, Lloyd RS, Oliver JL. ACL injury risk in elite female youth soccer: Changes in neuromuscular control of the knee following soccer-specific fatigue. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(5):e531&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25556396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah R, Minshull C, Smith SL, Folland JP. Longer electromechanical delay impairs hamstrings explosive force versus quadriceps. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(5):963&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Buckner SL, Bergstrom HC, Smith CM, Cochrane KC, et al. Four weeks of high- versus low-load resistance training to failure on the rate of torque development, electromechanical delay, and contractile twitch properties. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2016;16(2):135&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Fukunaga T. Effects of isometric training on the elasticity of human tendon structures in vivo. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2001;91(1):26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2001.91.1.26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11408409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosset J-F, Piscione J, Lambertz D, P&#xe9;rot C. Paired changes in electromechanical delay and musculo-tendinous stiffness after endurance or plyometric training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;105(1):131&#x2013;9. 2009/01/01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-008-0882-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18853177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zghal F, Colson SS, Blain G, Behm DG, Granacher U, Chaouachi A. Combined Resistance and Plyometric Training Is More Effective Than Plyometric Training Alone for Improving Physical Fitness of Pubertal Soccer Players. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31447705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining Training and Performance Caliber: A Participant Classification Framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2022 01 Feb. 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coren S. The lateral preference inventory for measurement of handedness, footedness, eyedness, and earedness: Norms for young adults. Bull Psychon Soc. 1993;31(1):1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03334122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Ashker S, Carson BP, Ayala F, De Ste Croix M. Sex-related differences in joint-angle-specific functional hamstring-to-quadriceps strength ratios. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25(3):949&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-015-3684-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26149462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delecluse C. Influence of strength training on sprint running performance. Current findings and implications for training. Sports Med. 1997;24(3):147&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199724030-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ste Croix MB, ElNagar YO, Iga J, Ayala F, James D. The impact of joint angle and movement velocity on sex differences in the functional hamstring/quadriceps ratio. Knee. 2017;24(4):745&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2017.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Magnusson SP, Larsson B, Dyhre-Poulsen P. A new concept for isokinetic hamstring: quadriceps muscle strength ratio. Am J Sports Med. 1998;26(2):231&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465980260021201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9548116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi S, Wong del P, Dellal A, Croisier JL, Ellouze Z, Chamari K. Improving Functional Performance and Muscle Power 4-to-6 Months After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10(4):655&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campenella B, Mattacola CG, Kimura IF. Effect of visual feedback and verbal encouragement on concentric quadriceps and hamstrings peak torque of males and females. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2000;8(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-2000-0033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Ashker S, Chaabene H, Prieske O, Abdelkafy A, Ahmed MA, Muaidi QI, et al. Effects of neuromuscular fatigue on eccentric strength and electromechanical delay of the knee flexors: the role of training status. Front Physiol. 2019;10:782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6606703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31293448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzardo M, Wessel J, Bay G. Eccentric and concentric torque and power of the knee extensors of females. Can J Sport Sci. 1988;13(2):166&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3395925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sole G, Hamr&#xe9;n J, Milosavljevic S, Nicholson H, Sullivan SJ. Test-retest reliability of isokinetic knee extension and flexion. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2007;88(5):626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2007.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17466732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1050-6411(00)00027-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacourpaille L, Hug F, Nordez A. Influence of passive muscle tension on electromechanical delay in humans. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(1):e53159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0053159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3537731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23308153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Glaister M, Brouner J, van Someren KA. The reliability of electromechanical delay and torque during isometric and concentric isokinetic contractions. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2009;19(5):975&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2008.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G. Appropriate reporting of exercise variables in resistance training protocols: much more than load and number of repetitions. Sports Med Open. 2022;8(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00492-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s exercise testing and prescription. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinlay BJ, Wallace P, Dotan R, Long D, Tokuno C, Gabriel DA, et al. Effects of Plyometric and Resistance Training on Muscle Strength, Explosiveness, and Neuromuscular Function in Young Adolescent Soccer Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(11):3039&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29337833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. A series of studies on the training of high-intensity muscle power in rugby league football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(2):198&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ. Analysis of variance is easily misapplied in the analysis of randomized trials: a critique and discussion of alternative statistical approaches. Psychosom Med. 2005;67(4):652&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.psy.0000172624.52957.a8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Young D, Stiff A, Coratella G. Lower-Limb Muscle Strength, Anterior-Posterior and Inter-Limb Asymmetry in Professional, Elite Academy and Amateur Soccer Players. J Hum Kinet. 2021;77:135&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Styles WJ, Matthews MJ, Comfort P. Effects of Strength Training on Squat and Sprint Performance in Soccer Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(6):1534&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26473518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco-M&#xe1;rquez F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Su&#xe1;rez JM, Pareja-Blanco F, Mora-Custodio R, Ya&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, et al. Effects of Combined Resistance Training and Plyometrics on Physical Performance in Young Soccer Players. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(11):906&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0035-1548890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald CJ, Lamont HS, Garner JC. A comparison of the effects of 6 weeks of traditional resistance training, plyometric training, and complex training on measures of strength and anthropometrics. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(2):422&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220df79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JL, Ramachandran AK, Singh U, Ramirez-Campillo R, Lloyd RS. The Effects of Strength, Plyometric and Combined Training on Strength, Power and Speed Characteristics in High-Level, Highly Trained Male Youth Soccer Players: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2024;54(3):623&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01944-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10978689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37897637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferley DD, Scholten S, Vukovich MD. Combined Sprint Interval, Plyometric, and Strength Training in Adolescent Soccer Players: Effects on Measures of Speed, Strength, Power, Change of Direction, and Anaerobic Capacity. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(4):957&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31977836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de S&#xe1;ez-S&#xe1;ez E, Requena B, Newton RU. Does plyometric training improve strength performance? A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(5):513&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2009.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieske O, Behrens M, Chaabene H, Granacher U, Maffiuletti NA. Time to differentiate postactivation potentiation from performance enhancement in the strength and conditioning community. Sports Med. 2020;50(9):1559&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01300-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32495254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iguchi J, Tateuchi H, Taniguchi M, Ichihashi N. The effect of sex and fatigue on lower limb kinematics, kinetics, and muscle activity during unanticipated side-step cutting. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22(1):41&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-013-2526-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23666380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieske O, Muehlbauer T, Krueger T, Kibele A, Behm D, Granacher U. Sex-specific effects of surface instability on drop jump and landing biomechanics. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Katis A. Biomechanical characteristics and determinants of instep soccer kick. J Sports Sci Med. 2007;6(2):154&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waasdorp R, Mugge W, Vos HJ, Groot JHd, Verweij MD, Jong, Nd, et al. Combining Ultrafast Ultrasound and High-Density EMG to Assess Local Electromechanical Muscle Dynamics: A Feasibility Study. IEEE Access. 2021;9:45277&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3067162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toninelli N, Coratella G, Longo S, Romani GM, Doria C, Rampichini S, et al. Synergistic difference in the effect of stretching on electromechanical delay components. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(3):e0300112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0300112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10965097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38530855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>