<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41524330</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2105-0686</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>219</Volume><Issue>3-4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biologie aujourd'hui</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Aujourdhui</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Reinforcing the mind-muscle connection: Mental Imagery as a tool for strength enhancement in athletes].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>117</StartPage><EndPage>124</EndPage><MedlinePgn>117-124</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1051/jbio/2025011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Motor imagery (MI), the mental representation of an action without intention to physical execution, activates neural networks largely overlapping with those involved in actual motor performance. While MI has long been used as an adjunct to physical training, its potential to induce corticomotor plasticity and optimize elite performance remains insufficiently understood. Bridging fundamental neuroscience and applied sport science, we investigated how MI reshapes perception-action coupling and supports force enhancement, inter-skill transfer, and neuromuscular efficiency in high-level athletes. Our findings demonstrate that MI can induce measurable cortico-muscular connectivity changes, prime the central nervous system, and improve force production when integrated into resistance training. In field-based studies with elite CrossFit athletes, MI enhanced power performance and enabled performance gains to transfer across distinct yet biomechanically related tasks. Furthermore, we show that MI's effects are magnified when applied concomitantly with physical practice or when combined with non-invasive peripheral stimulation techniques (e.g. tendon vibration, transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation). We propose MI as an active endogenous neuromodulation strategy, moving beyond its classical role as a cognitive training tool. By integrating MI with multimodal interventions, we aim to develop new neuromotor reprogramming paradigms prompting corticomotor remapping to facilitate elite sports performance and neurorehabilitation. Our approach positions MI at the crossroads of motor control, applied neurophysiology, and sports science to delineate original perspectives regarding how perception-action networks adapt to achieve elite performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; de Biologie, 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Rienzo</LastName><ForeName>Franck</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Claude Bernard Lyon&#x2009;1, Laboratoire Interuniversitaire de Biologie de la Motricit&#xe9;, UR 7424, F-69622 Villeurbanne, France - Institut Universitaire de France (IUF), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>fre</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Visualisation et am&#xe9;lioration de la force&#xa0;: vers un renforcement de la liaison cerveau-muscles chez l&#x2019;athl&#xe8;te.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Aujourdhui</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101544020</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2105-0678</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007092" MajorTopicYN="Y">Imagination</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre"><AbstractText Label="TITLE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Visualisation et am&#xe9;lioration de la force&#xa0;: vers un renforcement de la liaison cerveau-muscles chez l&#x2019;athl&#xe8;te.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">La repr&#xe9;sentation mentale d&#x2019;une activit&#xe9; motrice fictive, c&#x2019;est-&#xe0;-dire pens&#xe9;e mais non r&#xe9;alis&#xe9;e, qu&#x2019;on d&#xe9;nomme Imagerie Motrice (IM), active des r&#xe9;seaux enc&#xe9;phaliques proches de ceux impliqu&#xe9;s dans l&#x2019;ex&#xe9;cution motrice r&#xe9;elle et constitue un levier original d&#x2019;optimisation des performances neuromotrices. Nos travaux, &#xe0; l&#x2019;interface entre neurosciences fondamentales et applications de terrain, montrent que l&#x2019;IM peut induire une plasticit&#xe9; c&#xe9;r&#xe9;brale, am&#xe9;liorer la force musculaire et favoriser le transfert inter-habilet&#xe9;s chez des athl&#xe8;tes experts. Nous proposons de consid&#xe9;rer l&#x2019;IM comme une strat&#xe9;gie de neuromodulation endog&#xe8;ne, dont le potentiel s&#x2019;amplifie lorsqu&#x2019;elle est int&#xe9;gr&#xe9;e &#xe0; la pratique physique ou combin&#xe9;e &#xe0; des stimulations p&#xe9;riph&#xe9;riques non invasives. Cette approche ouvre la voie &#xe0; de nouveaux paradigmes de reprogrammation neuromotrice, visant &#xe0; identifier les conditions optimales de remodelage des r&#xe9;seaux perception-action. Nos r&#xe9;sultats sugg&#xe8;rent que l&#x2019;IM pourrait devenir un outil central pour l&#x2019;entra&#xee;nement de la tr&#xe8;s haute performance et la r&#xe9;&#xe9;ducation neuromotrice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; de Biologie, 2026.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corticomotor plasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">expertise motrice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">force musculaire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">imagerie motrice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor expertise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor imagery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromodulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plasticit&#xe9; corticomotrice</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41524330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/jbio/2025011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jbio250011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baeck, J.-S., Kim, Y.-T., Seo, J.-H., Ryeom, H.-K., Lee, J., Choi, S.-M., et&#xa0;al. (2012). Brain activation patterns of motor imagery reflect plastic changes associated with intensive shooting training. Behav Brain Res, 234, 26-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collet, C. (2001). Mouvements &amp; cerveau&#xa0;: neurophysiologie des activit&#xe9;s physiques et sportives. De Boeck Universit&#xe9;, Bruxelles, 230 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collet, C., Di Rienzo, F., Hoyek, N., Guillot, A. (2013). Autonomic nervous system correlates in movement observation and motor imagery. Front Hum Neurosci, 7, 1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornwall, M.W., Bruscato, M.P., Barry, S. (1991). Effect of mental practice on isometric muscular strength. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther, 13, 231-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Rienzo, F., Blache, Y., Kanthack, T.F.D., Monteil, K., Collet, C., Guillot, A. (2015). Short-term effects of integrated motor imagery practice on muscle activation and force performance. Neuroscience, 305, 146-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Rienzo, F., Debarnot, U., Daligault, S., Saruco, E., Delpuech, C., Doyon, J., et&#xa0;al. (2016). Online and offline performance gains following motor imagery practice: A comprehensive review of behavioral and neuroimaging studies. Front Hum Neurosci, 10, 315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Anjos, T., Guillot, A., Kerautret, Y., Daligault, S., Di Rienzo, F. (2022). Corticomotor plasticity underlying priming effects of motor imagery on force performance. Brain Sci, 12, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. (1999). Mind, muscles and motoneurones. J Sci Med Sport, 2, 167-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grospr&#xea;tre, S., Ruffino, C., Lebon, F. (2016). Motor imagery and cortico-spinal excitability: A review. Eur J Sport Sci, 16, 317-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillot, A., Lebon, F., Rouffet, D., Champely, S., Doyon, J., Collet, C. (2007). Muscular responses during motor imagery as a function of muscle contraction types. Int J Psychophysiol, 66, 18-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillot, A., Daligault, S., Schwartz, D., Di Rienzo, F. (2023). Timing-specific patterns of cerebral activations during motor imagery: A case study of the expert brain signature. Brain Cogn, 167, 105971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;nggi, J., Koeneke, S., Bezzola, L., J&#xe4;ncke, L. (2010). Structural neuroplasticity in the sensorimotor network of professional female ballet dancers. Hum Brain Mapp, 31, 1196-1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardwick, R.M., Caspers, S., Eickhoff, S.B., Swinnen, S.P. (2018). Neural correlates of action: Comparing meta-analyses of imagery, observation, and execution. Neurosci Biobehav Rev, 94, 31-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;tu, S., Gr&#xe9;goire, M., Saimpont, A., Coll, M.-P., Eug&#xe8;ne, F., Michon, P.-E., et&#xa0;al. (2013). The neural network of motor imagery: An ALE meta-analysis. Neurosci Biobehav Rev, 37, 930-949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ncke, L., Koeneke, S., Hoppe, A., Rominger, C., H&#xe4;nggi, J. (2009). The architecture of the golfer&#x2019;s brain. PLoS One, 4,&#xa0;e4785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeannerod, M. (2001). Neural simulation of action: A unifying mechanism for motor cognition. Neuroimage, 14, S103-S109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraeutner, S.N., McWhinney, S.R., Solomon, J.P., Dithurbide, L., Boe, S.G. (2018). Experience modulates motor imagery-based brain activity. Eur J Neurosci, 47, 1221-1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacourse, M.G., Turner, J.A., Randolph-Orr, E., Schandler, S.L., Cohen, M.J. (2004). Cerebral and cerebellar sensorimotor plasticity following motor imagery-based mental practice of a sequential movement. J Rehabil Res Dev, 41, 505-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Ge, S., Cordova, A., Yaghi, Z., Jiang, B., Yue, G., et&#xa0;al. (2023). Elderly may benefit more from motor imagery training in gaining muscle strength than young adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Psychol, 13, 1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milton, J., Solodkin, A., Hlu&#x161;t&#xed;k, P., Small, S.L. (2007). The mind of expert motor performance is cool and focused. Neuroimage, 35, 804-813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlandi, A., Arno, E., Proverbio, A.M. (2020). The effect of expertise on kinesthetic motor imagery of complex actions. Brain Topogr, 33, 238-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paravlic, A.H., Slimani, M., Tod, D., Marusic, U., Milanovic, Z., Pisot, R. (2018). Effects and dose-response relationships of motor imagery practice on strength development in healthy adult populations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med, 48, 1165-1187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual-Leone, A., Nguyet, D., Cohen, L.G., Brasil-Neto, J.P., Cammarota, A., Hallett, M. (1995). Modulation of muscle responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation during the acquisition of new fine motor skills. J Neurophysiol, 74, 1037-1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piveteau, E., Di Rienzo, F., Bolliet, O., Guillot, A. (2023). Inter-task transfer of force gains is facilitated by motor imagery. Front Neurosci, 17, 1228062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piveteau, E., Guillot, A., Di Rienzo, F. (2025). New insights on mind-muscle connection: Motor imagery concomitant to actual resistance training enhances force performance. J Sci Med Sport, 28, 666-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffino, C., Gaveau, J., Papaxanthis, C., Lebon, F. (2019). An acute session of motor imagery training induces use-dependent plasticity. Sci Rep, 9, 20002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinear, C.M. (2010). Corticospinal facilitation during motor imagery, in: A. Guillot, C. Collet (Eds.), The neurophysiological foundations of mental and motor imagery. Oxford University Press, pp. 47-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, J., Yang, K., Zhou, C., Dang, J. (2025).&#xa0;Motor expertise modulates cortical activation during imagery of simple and complex actions. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA, 122, e2515027122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, G., Cole, K.J. (1992). Strength increases from the motor program: Comparison of training with maximal voluntary and imagined muscle contractions. J Neurophysiol, 67, 1114&#x2013;1123.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>