<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41590979</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2075-4663</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Training Interventions on Physical Fitness and Performance in Kabaddi Players: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/sports14010037</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kabaddi is a contact sport that demands high physical fitness and specific technical skills. Although multiple training programs have been designed to improve performance, no systematic review had previously synthesized their effects on physical, physiological, and performance-related outcomes. This systematic review of randomized controlled trials aimed to evaluate the impact of different training interventions on physical fitness, physiological parameters, and sport performance in kabaddi players. A systematic review was performed in the Web of Science, PubMed, and Scopus databases up to May 2025. Randomized controlled trials analyzing training interventions in kabaddi players were included. Ten studies with a total of 458 participants were included. Interventions lasted between 6 and 12 weeks and comprised modalities such as strength training, plyometrics, combined training, circuit training, SAQ (speed, agility, and quickness), and Tabata. Nine studies reported significant within-group improvements in variables such as strength, speed, agility, and flexibility. In studies with between-group comparisons, training interventions could be more effective than control conditions. One study also reported improvements in physiological and hematological parameters. Overall, training interventions in kabaddi players may improve physical fitness, sport-specific performance, and certain physiological and hematological parameters. However, the evidence should be interpreted with caution given the predominantly fair methodological quality of the included trials. PROSPERO (CRD420251272758).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Devesa</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6254-6461</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grupo de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Actividad F&#xed;sica, Educaci&#xf3;n, y Salud (GIAFES), Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de &#xc1;vila, C/Canteros, 05005 &#xc1;vila, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iglesias Vieites</LastName><ForeName>Lidia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-3359-9303</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IES de Teis, Conseller&#xed;a de Educaci&#xf3;n, Ciencia, Universidades y Formaci&#xf3;n Profesional, Xunta de Galicia, 36216 Vigo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blanco-Mart&#xed;nez</LastName><ForeName>Nerea</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-0657-6708</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Did&#xe1;cticas Especi&#xe1;is, Universidade de Vigo, 36310 Vigo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Well-Move Research Group, Galicia Sur Health Research Institute (IIS Galicia Sur), SERGAS-UVIGO, 36310 Vigo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101722684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2075-4663</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical conditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41590979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports14010037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sports14010037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pal S., Kalra S., Kumar S., Pawaria S., Rishi P. A Literature Review on Common Injuries and Their Prevention in Kabaddi. Eur. J. Sport. Exerc. Sci. 2021;9:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Sudhakara G. Selected Physical Fitness Components and Kabaddi Performance. Int. J. Acad. Res. Dev. 2018;3:908&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu H. Kabaddi. J. Phys. Educ. Recreat. Danc. 1986;57:75&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1080/07303084.1986.10606141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07303084.1986.10606141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel D.M.P., Singh A., Ghosh S., Adhikari D.R. Season-Wise Performance Analysis of the Gujarat Giants Team in the Pro Kabaddi League. J. Adv. Sport. Phys. Educ. 2025;8:155&#x2013;167. doi: 10.36348/jaspe.2025.v08i08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36348/jaspe.2025.v08i08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon M.S., John R., Sharma S., Prabhakar S., Behera P., Saxena S., Singh H., Chouhan D. Epidemiology of Knee Injuries in Indian Kabaddi Players. Asian J. Sports Med. 2017;8:e31670. doi: 10.5812/asjsm.31670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.31670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P., Parashar B., Agrawal S., Mudgal K., Singh P. Kabaddi: A Quantitative Approach to Machine Learning Model in Pro Kabaddi; Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Computational Electronics for Wireless Communications; Surathkal, India. 9&#x2013;10 June 2022; Singapore: Springer; 2023. pp. 243&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-19-6661-3_22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D., Nara K., Dhull S. The Advantage and Disadvantage of Body Composition on Athletic Success: A Kabaddi Player Perspective. Int. J. Yogic Hum. Mov. Sport. Sci. 2023;8:151&#x2013;153. doi: 10.22271/yogic.2023.v8.i2c.1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/yogic.2023.v8.i2c.1448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudhakar H.H., Majumdar P., Umesh V., Panda K. Second to Fourth Digit Ratio Is a Predictor of Sporting Ability in Elite Indian Male Kabaddi Players. Asian J. Sports Med. 2014;5:31&#x2013;34. doi: 10.5812/asjsm.23073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.23073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4267485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar S.B., Borkar P. Effect of Ladder Drills Training in Female Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Phys. Educ. Sport. Health. 2018;5:180&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shobha S. Selected Physical Fitness Components of Kabaddi and Kho-Kho Intercollegiate Male Players of Bangalore University: A Comparative Study. Int. J. Multidiscip. Res. Dev. 2019;6:23&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D., Kumar S., Kumar N., Sagre S. Effects of Circuit Training on Selected Physical Fitness Components of Kabaddi Players. Sport. Sci. Health Adv. 2023;1:143&#x2013;148. doi: 10.60081/SSHA.1.2.2023.143-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.60081/SSHA.1.2.2023.143-148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey S.K., Khanna G.L., Batra M. Morphological and Physiological Studies on Indian National Kabaddi Players. Br. J. Sports Med. 1993;27:237&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.27.4.237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.27.4.237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8130960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deepak, Kumar N., Yadav A., Sagre S. Relationship between Motor Ability and Anthropometric Components of Kho-Kho and Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Physiol. Nutr. Phys. Educ. 2022;7:200&#x2013;203. doi: 10.22271/journalofsport.2022.v7.i2d.2590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/journalofsport.2022.v7.i2d.2590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur J.S. Association of Obesity with Agility and Speed of University Level Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Phys. Educ. Sport. Health. 2016;3:254&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelke A., Bawari B., Adhikari R., Kamath S., Kumar R. Anthropometric Characteristics and Somatotypes in Elite Pro Kabaddi League Players. Int. J. Kinanthropometry. 2024;4:57&#x2013;62. doi: 10.34256/ijk2426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34256/ijk2426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao Kagitha V., Kumar P.P.S.P. Effect of Complex Training with Yogic Practices on Selected Motor Fitness Variables and Playing Ability Among Kabaddi Men Players. Int. J. Humanit. Soc. Sci. Invent. 2013;2:10&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arumugam S. Effect of Complex Training on Muscular Strength Among Men Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Adv. Res. Innov. Ideas Educ. 2016;2:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakthivel S., Kumaresan G. Influence of Specific Skill Training with Kinematic Instructional Analysis Training on Physical Fitness Components and Overall Playing Ability of Male Kabaddi Players. Rev. Res. 2019;8:48514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T.C., Mulrow C.D., Shamseer L., Tetzlaff J.M., Akl E.A., Brennan S.E., et al. The PRISMA 2020 Statement: An Updated Guideline for Reporting Systematic Reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjunan R. Effect of Rope Skipping Dands and Baithaks Exercises on Selected Physical Fitness Variables Among Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Humanit. Arts Med. Sci. 2015;3:69&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nithin B.S., Singh R.M., Kaur D., Astuti Y., Chaeroni A., Elayaraja M., Orhan B.E., Singh Y., Kumasi B., Balaji E., et al. Effects of Bulgarian Bag Training on Bio-Motor Fitness, Physiological, Haematological, and Performance in Young Adult Male Kabaddi Players. Retos. 2024;61:868&#x2013;877. doi: 10.47197/retos.v61.108952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v61.108952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irandoust K., Taheri M. Effects of 8-Week Plyometric and Strengthtr Aining Programs on Selected Physical Fitness Factors of Elite Kabbadi Players. Indian J. Fundam. Appl. Life Sci. 2014;4:3942&#x2013;3948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuppaiah M., Kumar M.S. Examination of the Changes on Selected Performance Parameters in Response to Circuit Training among Kabaddi Players. Asian Pac. J. Health Sci. 2022;9:25&#x2013;26. doi: 10.21276/apjhs.2022.9.3.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21276/apjhs.2022.9.3.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmugam S.V., Rameshkumar S., Balasundar G. Impact of Unilateral Bilateral and Complex Training on Selected Motor Fitness Components and Physiological Variables among College Level Men Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Sport. Exerc. Phys. Educ. 2024;6:202&#x2013;204. doi: 10.33545/26647281.2024.v6.i2c.128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/26647281.2024.v6.i2c.128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureshkumar R., Venkatachalam K., Sankar A. Effect of Isolated Mixed Interval and Continued Training on Speed Components among College Level Kabaddi Players. Indian J. Nat. Sci. 2022;13:51189&#x2013;51194. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1024685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureshkumar R., Venkatachalam K., Sankar A., Mohankumar K. Impact of Isolated Mixed Interval and Continues Training on Physical Fitness and Skill Related Performance Variables Among College Level Kabaddi Players. Eur. Chem. Bull. 2023;12:1758&#x2013;1772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandel B.S. Effect of Strength Training on elected Physical Variables of Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Physiol. Nutr. Phys. Educ. 2018;3:39&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thinakaran S., Balasundar G., Kumar S.R. The Impact of Tabata Training and Resistance Training on Motor Performance Component among School Level Kabaddi Players. Int. J. Sport. Exerc. Phys. Educ. 2024;6:243&#x2013;246. doi: 10.33545/26647281.2024.v6.i2d.133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/26647281.2024.v6.i2d.133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay V.H. Effects of Speed Agility Quickness Training and Plyometric Training on Selected Physical Fitness Variable among College Men Kabaddi Players. Int. Res. J. Manag. Sociol. Humanit. 2023;14:86&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman S.R., Schertz L.A., Yuen H.K., Lowman J.D., Bickel C.S. Systematic Review of the Methodological Quality and Outcome Measures Utilized in Exercise Interventions for Adults with Spinal Cord Injury. Spinal Cord. 2012;50:718&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1038/sc.2012.78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sc.2012.78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardar S., Kumar Pandey A. An Estimation of Kabaddi Performance on the Basis of Selected Physical Fitness Components. Indian J. Phys. Educ. Sport. Appl. Sci. 2016;6:27&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S., Liu J., Wang Z., Geok S.K. The Effects of Functional Training on Physical Fitness and Skill-Related Performance among Basketball Players: A Systematic Review. Front. Physiol. 2024;15:1391394. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2024.1391394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1391394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38784117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao W., Bu T., Zhao F., Zhang J., Bai X., Geok S.K. Effects of Functional Training on Skill Performance and Movement Quality among Skilled Youth Male Tennis Players: A Cluster Randomized Control Trial. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 2025;17:43. doi: 10.1186/s13102-025-01085-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01085-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11889926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40057803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G., Mikulic P. Neuro-Musculoskeletal and Performance Adaptations to Lower-Extremity Plyometric Training. Sport. Med. 2010;40:859&#x2013;895. doi: 10.2165/11318370-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11318370-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20836583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seirulo F. La T&#xe9;cnica y Su Entrenamiento. Apunts. 1987;24:189&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newell K.M. What Are Fundamental Motor Skills and What Is Fundamental about Them? J. Mot. Learn. Dev. 2020;8:280&#x2013;314. doi: 10.1123/jmld.2020-0013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jmld.2020-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennasar-Garc&#xed;a M.I., Romero O.S., Dur&#xe1;n &#xc1;.L. Importancia de La Coordinaci&#xf3;n Motriz Para El Desarrollo de Capacidades F&#xed;sicas En Estudiantes de Primaria. Rev. Multi-Ensayos. 2024;10:64&#x2013;76. doi: 10.5377/multiensayos.v10i19.17562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5377/multiensayos.v10i19.17562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony B., Maheswri M.U., Maheswri U., Palanisamy A. Impact of Battle Rope and Bulgarian Bag High Intensity Interval Training Protocol on Selected Strength and Physiological Variables among School Level Athletes. Int. J. Appl. Res. 2015;1:403&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Fayez Fouad A. The Effectiveness of Using the Bulgarian Bag on the Level of Some Physical Variables and the Digital Level of Javelin Throwers. Assiut J. Sport Sci. Arts. 2020;2020:305&#x2013;315. doi: 10.21608/ajssa.2020.236714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ajssa.2020.236714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskara D.R., Murthy D.K. Physical Fitness Components As Predictors Of Kabaddi Performance. Indian Fed. Comput. Sci. Sport. 2016;23:103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajji S., Aldimkhi B. Effect of Bulgarian Bag Exercises on Anticipation and Certain Physical Variables for Kuwaiti Sabre Fencers. Sci. Mov. Health. 2022;22:172&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasim N.M., Rahim H.R., Kazem T. Bulgarian Bag Exercises and Their Effect on Some Physical and Motor Abilities to Develop Handball Scoring Skills; Proceedings of the ZAC Conference Series: Social Sciences and Humanities; Baghdad, Iraq. 9&#x2013;10 June 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan T., Alacam H. The Effects of Acute Aerobic and Anaerobic Exercise on Blood Parameters. Anthropologist. 2015;19:87&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1080/09720073.2015.11891642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09720073.2015.11891642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>