<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41152838</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A standardized rehabilitation protocol following two-stage surgery for nonunion of lateral humeral condyle fracture with cubitus valgus in children: functional and radiographic outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1005</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1005</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1005</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-025-09247-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Treating nonunion of the lateral humeral condyle with cubitus valgus deformity in children is challenging. While various surgical strategies exist, the role of a structured, standardized rehabilitation protocol in achieving optimal functional outcomes remains underexplored. This retrospective study aimed to evaluate the clinical and functional results of a two-stage surgical strategy (primary in situ fixation with bone grafting followed by secondary corrective osteotomy) coupled with a standardized, closely monitored rehabilitation protocol for pediatric lateral humeral condyle nonunion with cubitus valgus.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was conducted on nine pediatric patients with humeral lateral condyle nonunion combined with cubitus valgus deformity who were treated at Honghui Hospital, Xi&#x2019;an Jiaotong University, from January 2016 to March 2020. All underwent the two-stage surgery. In stage I, we performed debridement of the nonunion site, autologous iliac bone grafting, and in situ fixation using cannulated compression screws. Once bone union was achieved and elbow joint function had recovered, we performed corrective supracondylar medial closing wedge osteotomy to address the cubitus valgus deformity in stage II. The key focus of this study is the detailed, phase-specific rehabilitation protocol implemented after each stage: immobilization followed by graduated active-assisted and active range-of-motion exercises post-Stage I, and progressive resistance training post-Stage II. Elbow range of motion (ROM), carrying angle, and Mayo Elbow Performance Score (MEPS) were recorded and compared between the preoperative period and the final follow-up to evaluate treatment outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">All patients were followed up postoperatively, with a mean duration of 45.5 months (range: 30&#x2013;66 months). The mean time to union after the first-stage surgery for nonunion of lateral condyle fractures was 81.3 days (range: 55&#x2013;120 days). All osteotomy sites in the second-stage corrective surgery achieved union, with an mean healing time of 51.1 days (range: 45&#x2013;60 days). The elbow ROM improved significantly from a preoperative mean of 128.0&#xb0; &#xb1; 4.6&#xb0; to 138.5&#xb0; &#xb1; 5.4&#xb0; at the final follow-up (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The mean carrying angle of the unaffected side was 5.5&#xb0; (range: 3&#xb0;&#x2013;8&#xb0;). On the affected side, the carrying angle significantly improved from 31.8&#xb0; &#xb1; 4.7&#xb0; (range: 25&#xb0;&#x2013;42&#xb0;) preoperatively to 4.0&#xb0; &#xb1; 2.2&#xb0; (range: 1&#xb0;&#x2013;8&#xb0;) at final follow-up (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The MEPS improved from a preoperative mean of 58.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.5 (4 fair, 5 poor) to 96.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.4 (7 excellent, 2 good) at final follow-up (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), indicating significant functional recovery. No avascular necrosis occurred. Transient hardware irritation occurred in one patient (11.1%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The two-stage surgical approach, when integrated with a standardized, phased rehabilitation protocol, is an effective strategy for managing pediatric lateral humeral condyle nonunion with cubitus valgus, yielding significant functional improvements and reproducible outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Dang</LastName><ForeName>Yuze</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Jining</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaowei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Qingda</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yishan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yating</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jie</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Orthopaedic Hospital, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710000, China. jieqiangchina@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cubitus valgus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lateral humeral condyle nonunion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric elbow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation protocol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Two-stage surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the ethics committee of Honghui hospital, Xi&#x2019;an Jiaotong University. All parents or guardians of the minors provided written informed consent prior to participation in the study. All methods were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations (declaration of Helsinki). This is a retrospective study, therefore, clinical trial number is not applicable. Consent for publication: All patients or guardians of these children signed the written informed consent before surgery and provided consent to publish and report individual clinical data. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41152838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12570559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-025-09247-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-025-09247-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zorrilla S, de Neira J, Prada-Ca&#xf1;izares A, Marti-Ciruelos R, Pretell-Mazzini J. Supracondylar humeral fractures in children: current concepts for management and prognosis. Int Orthop. 2015;39(11):2287&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-015-2975-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26311512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landin LA, Danielsson LG. Elbow fractures in children. An epidemiological analysis of 589 cases. Acta Orthop Scand. 1986;57(4):309&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17453678608994398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3788491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalenak A. Ununited fracture of the lateral condyle of the humerus. A 50 year follow-up. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1977;(124):181&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">598074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakob R, Fowles JV, Rang M, Kassab MT. Observations concerning fractures of the lateral humeral condyle in children. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1975;57(4):430&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.57B4.430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1104630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toh S, Tsubo K, Nishikawa S, Inoue S, Nakamura R, Harata S. Long-standing nonunion of fractures of the lateral humeral condyle. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2002;84(4):593&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/00004623-200204000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11940620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada K, Masada K, Tada K, Yamamoto T. Osteosynthesis for the treatment of non-union of the lateral humeral condyle in children. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1997;79(2):234&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/00004623-199702000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9052545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris S, McKenna J, Cassidy N, Stephens M. A new technique for treatment of a non-union of a lateral humeral condyle. Injury. 2000;31(7):557&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0020-1383(00)00033-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10908754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eamsobhana P, Kaewpornsawan K. Should we repair nonunion of the lateral humeral condyle in children? Int Orthop. 2015;39(8):1579&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-015-2805-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26047656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tien YC, Chen JC, Fu YC, Chih TT, Hunag PJ, Wang GJ. Supracondylar dome osteotomy for cubitus valgus deformity associated with a lateral condylar nonunion in children. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87(7):1456&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrey BF, An KN. Functional evaluation of the elbow[M]// Morrey BF. The elbow and its disorders. Philadelphia: Saunders, 2000:74-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du MQ, Wang QG. Diagnosis and treatment of elbow instability. Chin J Orthop Trauma, 2005, 7(11): 1079-1081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masada K, Kawai H, Kawabata H, Masatomi T, Tsuyuguchi Y, Yamamoto K. Osteosynthesis for old, established non-union of the lateral condyle of the humerus. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1990 Jan; 72(1): 32-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/00004623-199072010-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2295670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badelon O, Bensahel H, Mazda K, Vie P. Lateral humeral condylar fractures in children: a report of 47 cases. J Pediatr Orthop. 1988 Jan-Feb; 8(1): 31-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01241398-198801000-00008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3335619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu TJ, Wang EB, Dai Q, Zhang LJ, Li QW, Zhao Q. Open reduction and internal fixation for the treatment of fractures of the lateral humeral condyle with an early delayed presentation in children: a radiological and clinical prospective study. Bone Joint J. 2016 Feb; 98-B (2): 244-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.98B2.34429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26850431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, Hwang JH, Kwon YU, Kim HW. Osteosynthesis in situ for lateral condyle nonunion in children. J Pediatr Orthop. 2015 Jun; 35(4): 334-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPO.0000000000000353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25393572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HARALDSSON S. On osteochondrosis deformas juvenilis capituli humeri including investigation of intra-osseous vasculature in distal humerus. Acta Orthop Scand Suppl. 1959; 38: 1-232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14399666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wang Y, Gilula LA, Yamaguchi K. Microcirculation of the distal humeral epiphyseal cartilage: implications for post-traumatic growth deformities. J Hand Surg Am. 1998 Jan; 23(1): 165-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0363-5023(98)80107-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9523973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik P, Nagda T, Patwardhan S. Role of Percutaneous Screw Fixation in Children with Delayed Presentation and Nonunion of Lateral Condyle Humerus Fractures with Elbow Stiffness. Indian J Orthop. 2022 Dec 16; 57(2): 245-252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43465-022-00789-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36777115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirley E, Anderson M, Neal K, Mazur J. Screw fixation of lateral condyle fractures: results of treatment. J Pediatr Orthop. 2015;35(8):821&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPO.0000000000000377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25494024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo MM, Sahoo US, Jena M. Exposed versus buried K-wire fixation in paediatric lateral condyle humerus fractures: preliminary communication of a prospective comparative study. J Pediatr Orthop B. 2022;31(3):281&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPB.0000000000000880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanfour AA. Long-standing Nonunited Fracture Lateral Humeral Condyle in Children. Evaluating a Two-stage Surgical Treatment Strategy With Critical Review. J Pediatr Orthop. 2024 May-Jun 01;44(5):e426-e432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPO.0000000000002656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38454784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>