<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41869145</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of M-Cube Wave Versus Low-Frequency Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation on the Strength and Thickness of the Quadriceps Muscles: A Within-Subject Comparison in Healthy Young Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103742</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103742</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103742</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103742</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background and objectives This study compared the effects of M-cube wave and conventional low-frequency neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) on the strength and thickness of quadriceps muscles in healthy young men using a within-subject design. Materials and methods This study included 15 untrained, healthy young adults. Each participant received two NMES protocols: an M-cube wave protocol on the quadriceps and low-frequency stimulation on the contralateral side. Sessions were performed twice per week for six weeks. Muscle strength was assessed using isometric or concentric maximal voluntary contraction (MVC-ISO and MVC-CON) torque. Muscle thickness of the rectus femoris, vastus lateralis, and vastus intermedius, and subcutaneous fat thickness were measured using ultrasonography. Results Both protocols significantly increased the strength (MVC-ISO: 18.9% vs. 23.3%; MVC-CON: 35.1% vs. 44.8%) and thickness of the quadriceps muscles across all examined muscles. No significant differences were observed between the two NMES waveform protocols. Both groups showed reduced thickness of the subcutaneous fat in the lateral thigh. Conclusion M-cube wave and conventional low-frequency NMES protocols effectively improved the strength and muscle morphology of the quadriceps muscles in healthy young men. These findings support the use of waveforms in clinical and rehabilitative settings, with waveform selection tailored to individual needs and comfort.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Sato et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Shigeru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bio-Environmental Adaptation Sciences, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Masatoshi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Nishikyushu University, Saga, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">m-cube wave</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Nishikyushu University issued approval 24WHN14. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41869145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12999367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Does neuromuscular electrical stimulation training of the lower limb have functional effects on the elderly?: a systematic review. Langeard A, Bigot L, Chastan N, Gauthier A. Exp Gerontol. 2017;91:88&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review of the effectiveness of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in the treatment of dysphagia - an update. Miller S, Peters K, Ptok M. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35875244/ Ger Med Sci. 2022;20:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of whole-body electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) on body composition and muscle strength in non-athletic adults. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Kemmler W, Shojaa M, Steele J, et al. Front Physiol. 2021;12:640657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in patients with acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Okura K, Nonoyama T, Shibuya M, Yamamoto S, Kawachi S, Nishie K, Nakayama K. Physiother Res Int. 2024;29:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38411350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation and resistance training on knee extensor/flexor muscles. Pantovi&#x107; M, Popovi&#x107; B, Madi&#x107; D, Obradovi&#x107; J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26434024/ Coll Antropol. 2015;39:153&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26434024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eight-week neuromuscular electrical stimulation training produces muscle strength gains and hypertrophy, and partial muscle quality improvement in the knee extensors. Akagi R, Miyokawa Y, Shiozaki D, et al. J Sports Sci. 2023;41:2209&#x2013;2228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of early implementation of electrical muscle stimulation to prevent muscle atrophy and weakness in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Hasegawa S, Kobayashi M, Arai R, Tamaki A, Nakamura T, Moritani T. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2011;21:622&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The acute effect of foam rolling on eccentrically-induced muscle damage. Nakamura M, Yasaka K, Kiyono R, Onuma R, Yahata K, Sato S, Konrad A. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7795530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:2691&#x2013;2703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intra- and intermuscular variation in human quadriceps femoris architecture assessed in vivo. Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Zhou S. J Anat. 2006;209:289&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2100333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16928199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Stat Power Anal Behav Sci. 2nd edition. Routledge, New York. New York: Routledge; 2013. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiological and methodological considerations for the use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation. Maffiuletti NA. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:223&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20473619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic resistance training: is it time to rethink the time course of neural contributions to strength gain? Pearcey GE, Alizedah S, Power KE, Button DC. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:2413&#x2013;2422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34052876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neural adaptations to electrical stimulation strength training. Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Maffiuletti NA. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2439&#x2013;2449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3175340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21643920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation for neuromuscular rehabilitation: what are we overlooking? Maffiuletti NA, Gondin J, Place N, Stevens-Lapsley J, Vivodtzev I, Minetto MA. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99:806&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29233625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise, nutrition, and neuromuscular electrical stimulation for sarcopenic obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of management in middle-aged and older adults. Xu S, Tu S, Hao X, et al. Nutrients. 2025;17:1504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12073358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40362811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of electromyostimulation training on intramuscular fat accumulation determined by ultrasonography in older adults. Hioki M, Takahashi H, Saito A, Imai M, Yasuda H. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123:271&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36260185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of neuromuscular electrical stimulation parameters for postoperative quadriceps strength in patients after knee surgery: a systematic review. Conley CE, Mattacola CG, Jochimsen KN, Dressler EV, Lattermann C, Howard JS. Sports Health. 2021;13:116&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8167342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unlocking the potential of neuromuscular electrical stimulation: achieving physical activity benefits for all abilities. Ackermann PW, Juthberg R, Flodin J. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1507402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11660796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39712079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contralateral effects of unilateral strength and skill training: modified Delphi consensus to establish key aspects of cross-education. Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Carroll TJ, et al. Sports Med. 2021;51:11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross-education of muscle strength is greater with stimulated than voluntary contractions. Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Scott K, Lambert J, Hamilton G, Tracy J. Motor Control. 1999;3:205&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>