<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41623456</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-0042</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>iScience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>iScience</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural and functional asymmetry of the lower limb related to gravitational acceleration tolerance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114506</StartPage><MedlinePgn>114506</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">114506</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.isci.2025.114506</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the physiological effects of intensive physical training on femoral cartilage morphology and limb asymmetry in strength in air force cadets. Thirty male cadets were evaluated using ultrasonography to measure femoral cartilage thickness, isokinetic testing to assess knee flexor and extensor strength, and the functional movement screen (FMS) to examine movement patterns. Participants were divided into pass and fail groups based on the G test, a measure of gravitational acceleration tolerance. Cadets in the fail group exhibited significantly thinner cartilage in the medial condyle of the right knee and greater knee flexion asymmetry at 180&#xb0;/s. The pass group demonstrated superior FMS performance, greater muscular strength, and less limb asymmetry. These findings suggest that repetitive mechanical loading during military training may lead to cartilage thinning and functional asymmetry, increasing the risk of musculoskeletal injury. Periodic musculoskeletal screening and targeted interventions could mitigate injury risks in occupational environments characterized by high physical demands.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Young</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Medicine and Science, Kwangwoon University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>In-Ki</ForeName><Initials>IK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aero Fitness, Republic of Korea Air Force Academy, Cheongju-si, Chungcheongbuk-do, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Kyu-Lim</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division in Anatomy and Developmental Biology, Department of Oral Biology, Human Identification Research Institute, BK21 FOUR Project, Yonsei University College of Dentistry, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>iScience</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101724038</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-0042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human physiology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest regarding the publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41623456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12856277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isci.2025.114506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-0042(25)02767-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sophia Fox A.J., Bedi A., Rodeo S.A. The basic science of articular cartilage: structure, composition, and function. Sports Health. 2009;1:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam C., Eckstein F., Milz S., Putz R. The distribution of cartilage thickness within the joints of the lower limb of elderly individuals. J. Anat. 1998;193:203&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1467840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9827636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody L.T. Knee osteoarthritis: clinical connections to articular cartilage structure and function. Phys. Ther. Sport. 2015;16:301&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25783021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNary S.M., Athanasiou K.A., Reddi A.H. Engineering lubrication in articular cartilage. Tissue Eng. Part B Rev. 2012;18:88&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21955119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein F., Hudelmaier M., Putz R. The effects of exercise on human articular cartilage. J. Anat. 2006;208:491&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2100201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16637874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bini R.R., Bini A.F. Effects of exercise mode in knee cartilage thickness. J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther. 2020;24:490&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33218552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halonen K.S., Mononen M.E., Jurvelin J.S., T&#xf6;yr&#xe4;s J., Salo J., Korhonen R.K. Deformation of articular cartilage during static loading of a knee joint: Experimental and finite element analysis. J. Biomech. 2014;47:2467&#x2013;2474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24813824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putignano C., Burris D., Moore A., Dini D. Cartilage rehydration: The sliding-induced hydrodynamic triggering mechanism. Acta Biomater. 2021;125:90&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein F., Lemberger B., Gratzke C., Hudelmaier M., Glaser C., Englmeier K.H., Reiser M. In vivo cartilage deformation after different types of activity and its dependence on physical training status. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2005;64:291&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15647438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore A.C., Burris D.L. Tribological rehydration of cartilage and its potential role in preserving joint health. Osteoarthr. Cartil. 2017;25:99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer S.J., Davis-Wilson H.C., Pexa B., Szymczak J., Wistreich C., Sorensen R., Wikstrom E.A., Blackburn J.T., Pietrosimone B. Assessing step-count dependent changes in femoral articular cartilage using ultrasound. J. Ultrasound Med. 2020;39:957&#x2013;965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31763713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkey M.S., Blackburn J.T., Davis H., Sierra-Ar&#xe9;valo L., Nissman D., Pietrosimone B. Ultrasonographic assessment of medial femoral cartilage deformation acutely following walking and running. Osteoarthr. Cartil. 2017;25:907&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28043940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkey M.S., Blackburn J.T., Hackney A.C., Lewek M.D., Schmitz R.J., Nissman D., Pietrosimone B. Comprehensively assessing the acute femoral cartilage response and recovery after walking and drop-landing: An ultrasonographic study. Ultrasound Med. Biol. 2018;44:311&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29198383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim J., Lee J., Park S., Lee J., Kim J., Park J. Change in femoral cartilage cross-sectional area after aerobic and resistance exercise. Int. J. Sports Med. 2024;45:705&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38631375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J., Kim J., Ko B. Bilateral patella cartilage debridement and exercise rehabilitation for chondromalacia and plica syndrome: A case report. Appl Sci. 2021;11:4078&#x2013;4085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Zheng B., Meng X., Lv Y., Lu H., Wang K., Huang D., Ren J. A novel ultrasound scanning approach for evaluating femoral cartilage defects of the knee: Comparison with routine magnetic resonance imaging. J. Orthop. Surg. Res. 2018;13:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6048893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30012149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein F., Reiser M., Englmeier K.H., Putz R. In vivo morphometry and functional analysis of human articular cartilage with quantitative magnetic resonance imaging: From image to data, from data to theory. Anat. Embryol. 2001;203:147&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11303902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung J.Y., Lee K.L. Physical strength, body composition, and G-test results of air force cadets based on nutrition knowledge differences. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:3083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10847096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;ggemann G.P., Br&#xfc;ggemann L., Heinrich K., M&#xfc;ller M., Niehoff A. Biological tissue response to impact-like mechanical loading. Footwear Sci. 2011;3:13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh S.H., Kim R.B., Cho Y.J. The evaluation of lower extremity muscles in combat shoes custom foot orthotics. Korean J Sport Biomech. 2008;18:115&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung J.Y., Jeong D.H., Lee K.L. Analysis of the relationship between body imbalance characteristics and physical ability in air force cadets: Physical function and gravity acceleration resistance. Sci. Rep. 2024;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11347663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39187518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong D.H., Lee D.R., Lee K.L., Sung J.Y. Gravitational acceleration test results according to functional movement screen and morphological symmetry results of air force cadets. Symmetry. 2023;15:804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong D.H., Jeong H.M., Park D.J., Sung J.Y., Lee K.L. Effects of toe-strengthening exercises on medial longitudinal arch height, muscle stiffness, and functional movement. Appl Sci. 2024;14:9842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rausch M., Weber F., K&#xfc;hn S., Ledderhos C., Zinner C., Sperlich B. The effects of 12 weeks of functional strength training on muscle strength, volume and activity upon exposure to elevated Gz forces in high-performance aircraft personnel. Mil. Med. Res. 2021;8:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodden J.G., Needham R.A., Chockalingam N. The effect of an intervention program on functional movement screen test scores in mixed martial arts athletes. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2015;29:219&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler R.J., Contreras M., Burton L.C., Plisky P.J., Goode A., Kiesel K. Modifiable risk factors predict injuries in firefighters during training academies. Work. 2013;46:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23324700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost D.M., Beach T.A.C., Callaghan J.P., McGill S.M. FMS scores change with performers&#x2019; knowledge of the grading criteria: Are general whole-body movement screens capturing &#x201c;dysfunction&#x201d;. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2015;29:3037&#x2013;3044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26502271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>