<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41369543</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of a 10-Week Strength and Conditioning Intervention on Physical Capacity and Golf Shot Performance in University Male and Female Golfers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e32</StartPage><EndPage>e40</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e32-e40</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005274</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bishop, C, Muir, I, Gartshore, A, Scott, D, Coughlan, D, Turner, A, and Murray, A. The effects of a 10-week strength and conditioning intervention on physical capacity and golf shot performance in university male and female golfers. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): e32-e40, 2026-The aim of the present study was to undertake a 10-week strength and conditioning training intervention and determine the effects on golf shot data and physical capacity in both high-level male and female university golfers. A total of 11 golfers (males = 6; females = 5) undertook a comprehensive testing battery preintervention and postintervention, consisting of golf shot data (with a driver), an isometric midthigh pull, isometric bench press, countermovement jump, seated medicine ball throw, and thoracic spine mobility. For the 10-week intervention, all players undertook 6 weeks of strength training twice per week, followed by 4 weeks of power training twice per week. No statistically significant differences were evident in the male group; however, large improvements (as defined by Hedges g effect size analysis) were observed for force at 100 milliseconds in the isometric bench press (g = 1.13), carry distance (g = 0.98), and ball speed (g = 0.82). In the female group, significant large improvements were evident in all isometric bench press metrics-force at 100 milliseconds (g = 3.79; p &lt; 0.05), force at 200 milliseconds (g = 3.04; p &lt; 0.05), and peak force (g = 1.54; p &lt; 0.05), in addition to nonsignificant large increases in carry distance (g = 0.84). In summary, this intervention showed that large improvements in golf shot data can be made from undertaking strength and power training twice a week for 10 weeks, for both male and female players. Furthermore, and aligned with previous research in female golf, the importance of maximal and rapid force production in the upper body seems to be of particular importance for female golfers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Faculty of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, Virginia Water, Surrey, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muir</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of St. Andrews Golf Programme, University of St. Andrews, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gartshore</LastName><ForeName>Allan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of St. Andrews Golf Programme, University of St. Andrews, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of St. Andrews Golf Programme, University of St. Andrews, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coughlan</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, Virginia Water, Surrey, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>England Golf, Woodhall Spa, Lincolnshire, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Faculty of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Scotland, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, Virginia Water, Surrey, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>England Golf, Woodhall Spa, Lincolnshire, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Golf</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ball speed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carry distance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rapid force production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202601000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Banyard H, Nosaka K, Haff GG. Reliability and validity of the load&#x2013;velocity relationship to predict the 1RM back squat. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1897&#x2013;1904, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Brennan A, Ehlert A, Wells J, Brearley S, Coughlan D. Strength and conditioning for golf athletes: Biomechanics, common injuries and physical requirements. Prof Strength Cond J 63: 7&#x2013;18, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Wells J, Ehlert A, et al. Trackman 4: Within and between-session reliability and inter-relationships of launch monitor metrics during indoor testing in high-level golfers. J Sports Sci 41: 2138&#x2013;2143, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biz C, Stecco C, Perissinotto S, et al. Diagnostic predictors of recovery outcomes following open reduction and internal fixation for tibial plateau fractures: A retrospective study based on the Schatzker classification. Diagnostics 15: 1304&#x2013;1324, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brearley S, Buckthorpe M, Xu J, Bishop C. The dynamic strength index: Is it a useful tool when making programming decisions? Prof Strength Cond J 71: 13&#x2013;22, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Ehlert A, Wells J, et al. Monitoring performance in golf: More than just clubhead speed. Strength Cond J 45: 631&#x2013;641, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Validity and reliability of the FlightScope Mevo+ launch monitor for assessing golf performance. J Strength Cond Res 38: e174&#x2013;e181, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Associations and within-group differences in physical characteristics and golf performance data in high-level amateur players. Appl Sci 14: 1854&#x2013;1871, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Mountjoy M, et al. Associations between physical characteristics and golf clubhead speed: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 54: 1553&#x2013;1577, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadie M. Every Shot Counts. New York: Penguin Group, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Hannah R, Pain T, Folland J. Reliability of neuromuscular measurements during explosive isometric contractions, with special reference to electromyography normalization techniques. Muscle Nerve 46: 566&#x2013;576, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioural Sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Dos'Santos T, Beckham G, Stone M, Guppy S, Haff GG. Standardization and methodological considerations for the isometric midthigh pull. Strength Cond J 41: 57&#x2013;79, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan D, Taylor M, Jackson J, Ward N, Beardsley C. Physical characteristics of youth elite golfers and their relationship with driver clubhead speed. J Strength Cond Res 34: 212&#x2013;217, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlert A. The effects of strength and conditioning interventions on golf performance: A systematic review. J Sports Sci 38: 2720&#x2013;2731, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland J, Williams A. The adaptations to strength training: Morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med 37: 145&#x2013;168, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Ruben R, Lider J, Twine C, Cormie P. A comparison of methods for determining the rate of force development during isometric midthigh clean pulls. J Strength Cond Res 29: 386&#x2013;395, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus E, Hardesty K, Sunderland K, Hegedus R, Smoliga J. A randomized trial of traditional and golf-specific resistance training in amateur female golfers: Benefits beyond golf performance. Phys Ther Sport 22: 41&#x2013;53, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung G, Hong S, Shin D, et al. Effects of upper-body flexibility exercise on golf performance of amateur female golfer: A case report. Am J Case Rep 23: e936022, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K. Effects of core muscle strengthening training on flexibility, muscular strength and driver shot performance in female professional golfers. Int J Appl Sports Sci 22: 111&#x2013;127, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson L, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Relationships and within-group differences in physical attributes and golf performance in elite amateur female players. Life 14: 674&#x2013;688, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson L, Murray A, Ehlert A, et al. Effects of physical training and associations between physical performance characteristics and golf performance in female players: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38: 374&#x2013;383, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells J, Mitchell A, Charalambous L, Fletcher I. Relationships between highly skilled golfers' clubhead velocity and force producing capabilities during vertical jumps and an isometric mid-thigh pull. J Sports Sci 36: 1847&#x2013;1851, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells J, Mitchell A, Charalambous L, Fletcher I. Relationships between highly skilled golfers' clubhead velocity and kinetic variables during a countermovement jump. Sports Biomech 23: 2598&#x2013;2610, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>