<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41225648</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Limb strength asymmetries in elite academy volleyball players: impacts on performance outcomes and insights derived from principal component analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>332</StartPage><MedlinePgn>332</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">332</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01298-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The purpose of this study is twofold: (1) to investigate intra- and inter-limb strength imbalances and asymmetries in elite academy volleyball players and their relationships with sprint performance, kinetics, kinematics, countermovement jump (CMJ), squat jump (SJ), and agility performances and (2) to apply principle component analysis (PCA) to identify and better understand the underlying factors that contributing to volleyball performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty-seven elite academy volleyball players completed four testing sessions, assessing pro-agility, sprint, isokinetic strength at 60&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup> and 180&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup>, and jump performance. Intra-limb asymmetries were calculated using hamstring-to-quadriceps ratios, whereas inter-limb asymmetries were determined using the percentage difference method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 60&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup>, the intra-limb<sub>NDL</sub> ratio showed negative correlations with dominant and non-dominant leg ground contact time (GCT<sub>DL</sub> and GCT<sub>NDL</sub>, respectively) and a positive correlation with dominant leg flight time (FT<sub>DL</sub>) and difference between CMJ and SJ heights (CMJSJ<sub>diff</sub>). Hamstring asymmetry (H<sub>asymmetry</sub>) at 60&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup> correlated positively with 5&#xa0;m (S<sub>5m</sub>) and 20&#xa0;m (S<sub>20m</sub>) sprint performances and negatively with theoretical maximal velocity (V<sub>0</sub>) while at 180&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup>, it showed small negative correlations with V<sub>0</sub>. At 180&#xb0;s<sup>-1</sup>, quadriceps asymmetry (Q<sub>asymmetry</sub>) correlated positively with S<sub>5m</sub>, relative theoretical maximum force (F<sub>0rel</sub>), and relative theoretical maximum power (P<sub>maxrel</sub>) but negatively with V<sub>0</sub>, CMJ<sub>DL</sub>, and CMJ. The PCA results showed that the first four principal components, explaining 51.0% of the total variance and contributing to 88.2% across 12 dimensions, were mainly linked to jump performance, lower-limb strength, sprint performance, and intra-limb ratios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Intra-limb and inter-limb strength imbalances and asymmetries were found to be weakly to moderately associated with sprint performance, sprint kinetics, kinematics, and jump-related outcomes. PCA results further identified jump variables, lower-limb strength, sprint metrics, and intra-limb ratios as key, interconnected contributors to volleyball performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye&#x15f;ilyurt</LastName><ForeName>Hakk&#x131;</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Anatomy, Y&#xfc;ksek &#x130;htisas University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;abuk</LastName><ForeName>Salih</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Department of Coaching Education, Erzurum Technical University, Erzurum, T&#xfc;rkiye. salih.cabuk@erzurum.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x130;nce</LastName><ForeName>&#x130;zzet</ForeName><Initials>&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Department of Coaching Education, Ankara Yildirim Beyazit University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tortu</LastName><ForeName>Erkan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Department of Coaching Education, Trabzon University, Trabzon, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ulup&#x131;nar</LastName><ForeName>S&#xfc;leyman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Department of Coaching Education, Erzurum Technical University, Erzurum, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Horizontal force-velocity profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Principle component analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sprint kinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength imbalances and asymmetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Volleyball</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Erzurum Technical University Scientific Research and Publication Ethics Committee (Meeting Number: 08, Decision Number: 7, Date: 04.07.2024). This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their inclusion in the study. Participants were provided with detailed information about the study&#x2019;s purpose, procedures, potential risks, and benefits. Written consent forms were signed by all participants, and for participants under the age of 18, parental or guardian consent was also secured. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41225648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12613624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01298-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01298-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu C, Ulup&#x131;nar S, &#xd6;zbay S, Turan M, Sava&#x15f; B&#xc7;, Asan S, et al. Validity and reliability of my jump app to assess vertical jump performance: a meta-analytic review. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):20137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46935-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10656545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ple&#x161;a J, Kozinc &#x17d;, &#x160;arabon N. The association between force-velocity relationship in countermovement jump and sprint with approach jump, linear acceleration and change of direction ability in volleyball players. Front Physiol. 2021;12:763711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.763711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8637321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34867467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer M, Bishop D, Dawson B, Goodman C. Physiological and metabolic responses of repeated-sprint activities: specific to field-based team sports. Sports Med. 2005;35:1025&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535120-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16336007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forthomme B, Croisier J-L, Ciccarone G, Crielaard J-M, Cloes M. Factors correlated with volleyball Spike velocity. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(10):1513&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546505274935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattler T, Sekuli&#x107; D, Spasi&#x107; M, Peri&#x107; M, Krolo A, Uljevi&#x107; O, et al. Analysis of the association between motor and anthropometric variables with change of direction speed and reactive agility performance. J Hum Kinetics. 2015;47:137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2015-0069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schons P, Da Rosa RG, Fischer G, Berriel GP, Fritsch CG, Nakamura FY et al. The relationship between strength asymmetries and jumping performance in professional volleyball players. Sports Biomech. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29578379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinci &#x130;, &#x130;nce &#x130;. Maturation-dependent variations in force-velocity profiles and relationship with Spike jump performance in female volleyball players. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2024;24(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40024227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewit JK, Cronin JB, Hume PA. Asymmetry in multi-directional jumping tasks. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13(4):238&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2011.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23068899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ujakovi&#x107; F, &#x160;arabon N. Change of direction performance is influenced by asymmetries in jumping ability and hip and trunk strength in elite basketball players. Appl Sci. 2020;10(19):6984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10196984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Turner A, Maloney S, Maestroni L, Jarvis P, Bishop C. The effects of training interventions on interlimb asymmetries: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Strength Conditioning J. 2022;44(5):69&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning J, Pickup L. Symmetry and performance in middle distance runners. Int J Sports Medicine. 1998;19(03):205&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-971905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9630027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Fekete G, Baker JS, Liang M, Xuan R, Gu Y. Effects of running fatigue on lower extremity symmetry among amateur runners: from a Biomechanical perspective. Front Physiol. 2022;13:899818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.899818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9478459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36117699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A, Bishop C, Busc&#xe0; B, Aguilera-Castells J, Vicens-Bordas J, Gonzalo-Skok O. Inter-limb asymmetries are associated with decrements in physical performance in youth elite team sports athletes. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(3):e0229440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0229440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32126107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Ford KR, Myer GD, Heyl R, Hewett TE. Limb asymmetries in landing and jumping 2 years following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Clin J Sport Med. 2007;17(4):258&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0b013e31804c77ea</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Read P, McCubbine J, Turner A. Vertical and horizontal asymmetries are related to slower sprinting and jump performance in elite youth female soccer players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2021;35(1):56&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;nce &#x130;, Tortu E. Association between intra and inter-limb strength asymmetry with sprint kinematics and force-velocity profile in youth team athletes. Knee. 2025;52:99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2024.10.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39549657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt LC, Paterno MV, Hewett TE. The impact of quadriceps femoris strength asymmetry on functional performance at return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2012;42(9):750&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.4194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4157226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22813542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney SJ. The relationship between asymmetry and athletic performance: A critical review. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2019;33(9):2579&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik B, Ayberk B, &#xd6;zg&#xfc;l B, Polat MG. The association between isokinetic strength and strength asymmetry and jump performance in female volleyball players. Sport Sci Health. 2024;20(1):79&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-023-01068-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soylu &#xc7;, Altunda&#x11f; E, Akar&#xe7;e&#x15f;me C, &#xdc;n Yildirim N. The relationship between isokinetic knee flexion and extension muscle strength, jump performance, dynamic balance and injury risk in female volleyball players. 2020;15(3):502&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struzik A, Pietraszewski B. Relationships between Hamstrings-to&#x2010;Quadriceps ratio and variables describing countermovement and drop jumps. Appl Bionics Biomech. 2019;2019(1):4505481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6589293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31281414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Read P, Lake J, Chavda S, Turner A. Interlimb asymmetries: Understanding how to calculate differences from bilateral and unilateral tests. Strength Conditioning J. 2018;40(4):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozinc &#x17d;, &#x160;arabon N. Inter-limb asymmetries in volleyball players: differences between testing approaches and association with performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19(4):745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Caama&#xf1;o M, Carballo-L&#xf3;pez J, &#xc1;lvarez-Yates T, Cuba-Dorado A, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a O. Intrasession reliability of the tests to determine lateral asymmetry and performance in volleyball players. Symmetry. 2018;10(9):416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym10090416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madruga-Parera M, Bishop C, Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A, Beltran-Valls MR, Skok OG, Romero-Rodr&#xed;guez D. Interlimb asymmetries in youth tennis players: relationships with performance. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2020;34(10):2815&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardos-Mainer E, Bishop C, Gonzalo-Skok O, Nobari H, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Lozano D. Associations between inter-limb asymmetries in jump and change of direction speed tests and physical performance in adolescent female soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(7):3474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18073474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Schena F. Correlation between quadriceps and hamstrings inter-limb strength asymmetry with change of direction and sprint in U21 elite soccer-players. Hum Mov Sci. 2018;59:81&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2018.03.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arboix-Ali&#xf3; J, Busc&#xe0; B, Busquets A, Aguilera-Castells J, de Pablo B, Montalvo AM, et al. Relationship between inter-limb asymmetries and physical performance in rink hockey players. Symmetry. 2020;12(12):2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym12122035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox KT, Pearson LT, Hicks KM. The effect of lower inter-limb asymmetries on athletic performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(6):e0286942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0286942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10249853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z. The effect of application of asymmetry evaluation in competitive sports: A systematic review. Phys Activity Health. 2022;6(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmar N, James N, Hearne G, Jones B. Using principal component analysis to develop performance indicators in professional rugby league. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2018;18(6):938&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24748668.2018.1528525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady CJ, Harrison AJ, Flanagan EP, Haff GG, Comyns TM. The relationship between the isometric squat and stretch shortening cycle function and sprint acceleration performance in hurling players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2024;38(6):e288&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38489584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SA, McKay HA, Macdonald H, Nettlefold L, Baxter-Jones AD, Cameron N, et al. Enhancing a somatic maturity prediction model. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(8):1755&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25423445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Bennett T, Thomas A, Pollitt L, Hopkinson M, Crespo R, et al. Inter-limb asymmetries and kicking limb preference in english premier league soccer players. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:982796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.982796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9428458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36060629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parpa K, Michaelides M. Anterior-posterior and inter-limb lower body strength asymmetry in soccer, basketball, futsal, and volleyball players. Medicina. 2022;58(8):1080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina58081080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9415573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36013546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;liwowski R, Paillard T, Bojkowski &#x141;, Dudzi&#x144;ski W, Patek M, Marynowicz J. Intra-and inter-limb strength imbalance and asymmetry in soccer: A comparison of elite senior and junior players. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(4):e0302474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0302474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11051617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38669272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasquez-Bonilla A, Tomas-Carus P, Brazo-Sayavera J, Malta J, Folgado H, Olcina G. Muscle oxygenation is associated with bilateral strength asymmetry during isokinetic testing in sport teams. Sci Sports. 2023;38(4):426. e1-. e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2022.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekir U, Arabaci R, Akova B. Acute effects of static stretching on peak and end-range hamstring-to-quadriceps functional ratios. World J Orthop. 2015;6(9):719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v6.i9.719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26495249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown SR, Brughelli M, Bridgeman LA. Profiling isokinetic strength by leg preference and position in rugby union athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(4):500&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Read P, Chavda S, Jarvis P, Brazier J, Bromley T, et al. Magnitude or direction? Seasonal variation of interlimb asymmetry in elite academy soccer players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2022;36(4):1031&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera J, Figueiredo AJ, Duarte J, Field A, Sarmento H. Predictors of linear sprint performance in professional football players. Biology Sport. 2023;40(2):359&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.114289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vescovi JD, Jovanovi&#x107; M. Sprint mechanical characteristics of female soccer players: a retrospective pilot study to examine a novel approach for correction of timing gate starts. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:629694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.629694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8192793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34124653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen TA, T&#xf8;nnessen E, Seiler SK. The difference is in the start: impact of timing and start procedure on sprint running performance. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2012;26(2):473&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318226030b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22233797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samozino P, Rabita G, Dorel S, Slawinski J, Peyrot N, Saez de Villarreal E, et al. A simple method for measuring power, force, velocity properties, and mechanical effectiveness in sprint running. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26(6):648&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25996964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Samozino P, Murata M, Cross MR, Nagahara R. A simple method for computing sprint acceleration kinetics from running velocity data: replication study with improved design. J Biomech. 2019;94:82&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2019.07.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovanovi&#x107; M, Vescovi J, {shorts}. An R package for modeling short sprints. Int J Strength Conditioning. 2022;2(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes S, Chapman DW, Haff GG, Nimphius S. The use of a functional test battery as a non-invasive method of fatigue assessment. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(2):e0212870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0212870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards T, Weakley J, Woods CT, Breed R, Benson AC, Suchomel TJ, et al. Comparison of countermovement jump and squat jump performance between 627 state and non-state representative junior Australian football players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2023;37(3):641&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35916875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazo-Sayavera J, Nikolaidis PT, Camacho-Cardenosa A, Camacho-Cardenosa M, Tim&#xf3;n R, Olivares PR. Acute effects of block jumps in female volleyball players: the role of performance level. Sports. 2017;5(2):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports5020030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulupinar S, &#xd6;zbay S, Gen&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu C. Counter movement jump and sport specific frequency speed of kick test to discriminate between elite and sub-elite kickboxers. Acta Gymnica. 2021;50(4):141&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/ag.2020.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Janicijevic D, Delgado-Garc&#xed;a G, De la Cruz JC, Rojas FJ, et al. Between-session reliability of performance and asymmetry variables obtained during unilateral and bilateral countermovement jumps in basketball players. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(7):e0255458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0255458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8323888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34329366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Harackiewicz DV, Harman EA, Frykman PN, Rosenstein MT. Cross-validation of three jump power equations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(4):572&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199904000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10211854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva H, Nakamura FY, Roriz P, Marcelino R. Are the peak accelerations and decelerations registered during the pro-agility test replicated during matches and training sessions? Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2024;1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Loturco I, Pereira LA, Cesari R, Pratdesaba J, Madruga-Parera M, et al. Relationship between sprint, change of direction, jump, and hexagon test performance in young tennis players. J Sports Sci Med. 2021;20(2):197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2021.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33948097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A spreadsheet for deriving a confidence interval, mechanistic inference and clinical inference from a <i>P</i> value. Sportscience. 2007;11:16&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Callaghan SJ, Berry SP, Cooke ER, Jordan CA, Luczo TM, et al. Relationship between unilateral jumping ability and asymmetry on multidirectional speed in team-sport athletes. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2014;28(12):3557&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24942166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka S, Nagano A, Hay DC, Fukashiro S. The effect of bilateral asymmetry of muscle strength on jumping height of the countermovement jump: A computer simulation study. J Sports Sci. 2010;28(2):209&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410903428566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20054738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka S, Nagano A, Hay DC, Fukashiro S. The effect of bilateral asymmetry of muscle strength on the height of a squat jump: a computer simulation study. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(8):867&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.568512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21506038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Cormie P, Abbiss CR, Ahmaidi S, Nosaka KK, Laursen P. Muscle deoxygenation during repeated sprint running: effect of active vs. passive recovery. Int J Sports Med. 2009;30(06):418&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0028-1105933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19437381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Wilkau L, Bezodis HC, Morin NE, Irwin J-B, Simpson G, Bezodis S. The importance of duration and magnitude of force application to sprint performance during the initial acceleration, transition and maximal velocity phases. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(20):2359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1785193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32627681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;abuk S, &#x130;nce &#x130;. The acute effects of hip thrust and glute Bridge exercises with different loads on sprint performance and horizontal force&#x2013;velocity profile in adolescent soccer players: A post-activation performance enhancement approach. Eur J Sport Sci. 2025;25(2):e12255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejsc.12255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11745155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39832164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Gimenez P, Edouard P, Arnal P, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Samozino P, et al. Sprint acceleration mechanics: the major role of hamstrings in horizontal force production. Front Physiol. 2015;6:404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2015.00404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tottori N, Suga T, Miyake Y, Tsuchikane R, Otsuka M, Nagano A, et al. Hip flexor and knee extensor muscularity are associated with sprint performance in sprint-trained preadolescent boys. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2018;30(1):115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2016-0226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28787247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber JA, Hart NH, Rantalainen T, Connick M, Newton RU. Assessment of ground contact time in the field: evaluation of validity and reliability. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2024;38(1):e34&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38085634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Murphy AJ, Spinks CD. Effects of resisted sled towing on sprint kinematics in field-sport athletes. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2003;17(4):760&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exell T, Irwin G, Gittoes M, Kerwin D. Strength and performance asymmetry during maximal velocity sprint running. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1273&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>