<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41924915</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-1462</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bone &amp; joint open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bone Jt Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Anterior cruciate ligament injury prevention: who is responsible for implementation and what are the challenges?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>491</StartPage><EndPage>498</EndPage><MedlinePgn>491-498</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1302/2633-1462.74.BJO-2026-0019</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The incidence of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries is increasing in the UK, with a particularly sharp increase among young female athletes participating in sport. ACL injuries result in significant morbidity, with a profound impact on the physical, mental and social health of individuals, alongside lengthy rehabilitation. Therefore, primary prevention of ACL injuries is desirable. The intrinsic and extrinsic risk factors associated with ACL injury, such as deficits in neuromuscular control, impaired movement quality, fatigue, strength imbalances, and suboptimal load management, are shared with a spectrum of other lower-limb musculoskeletal injuries. This overlap supports the concept that ACL injury prevention may not be best considered a condition-specific endeavour, but rather as a component of a comprehensive lower-limb injury prevention strategy. ACL prevention interventions typically include multi-component training methods designed to improve neuromuscular control, functional performance, balance, strength and power. while often framed around ACL injury reduction, their effects extend beyond the knee, conveying protection against other lower-limb injuries and improving overall performance. Despite a growing body of evidence demonstrating the efficacy of neuromuscular injury prevention programmes, their translation into routine practice has been inconsistent. This annotation outlines the current best evidence relating to ACL injury epidemiology and the effectiveness of injury prevention strategies, supporting a transition to integrate ACL injury prevention into wider, sport-specific lower-limb injury prevention programmes. In doing so, it highlights key stakeholders and barriers relevant to large-scale implementation of injury prevention programmes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Super et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Super</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2082-2813</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edinburgh Orthopaedics, Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spalding</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire National Health Service Trust, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Orthopaedics, Rheumatology and Musculoskeletal Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust, Nuffield Orthopaedic Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowditch</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, East Suffolk and North Essex NHS Foundation Trust, Colchester and Ipswich, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Morgan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Portsmouth University Hospital, Portsmouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>LaPrade</LastName><ForeName>Robert F</ForeName><Initials>RF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9823-2306</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Twin Cities Orthopedics, Edina, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haddad</LastName><ForeName>Fares S</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London Hospitals, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Iain R</ForeName><Initials>IR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edinburgh Orthopaedics, Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Bone Jt Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2633-1462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>M. Bowditch is the British Orthopaedic Association executive and past president. F. S. Haddad reports multiple study grants from Stryker, Smith &amp; Nephew, Corin, National Institute for Health and Care Research, and International Olympic Committee, royalties or licenses from Smith &amp; Nephew, Stryker, Corin, and MatOrtho, consulting fees from Stryker, payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Stryker, Smith &amp; Nephew, Zimmer, AO Recon, and Mathys, support for attending meetings and/or travel from Stryker, Mathys, AO Recon, and The Bone &amp; Joint Journal, all of which are unrelated to this article. F. S. Haddad is also Editor-in-Chief of The Bone &amp; Joint Journal, President of the International Hip Society, Vice President of the European Hip Society, and an ISTA board member. I. R. Murray reports grants or contracts and consulting fees from Stryker, payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Stryker, Smith &amp; Nephew, and Arthrex. K. Jackson is the recipient of a yearly grant given to Power Up To Play from the Alastair Pilkington Trust, receives UCL honorary lecturer fees for injury prevention teaching on the MSc Sport Medicine course, and is director and trustee of The Manor Preparatory School, UK. R. F. LaPrade receives grants or contracts from Arthroscopy Association of North America, American Orthopaedic Society of Sports Medicine, Ossur Americas, Smith &amp; Nephew, and Arthrex, royalties or licenses from Ossur, Smith &amp; Nephew, and Elsevier, consulting fees and patents planned, issued, or pending from Ossur and Smith &amp; Nephew. T. Spalding receives royalties from Conmed for implants and instruments, consulting fees from Orthonika, payment for honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Conmed UK, and patents planned, issued, or pending from Conmed. W. Jackson declares royalties or licenses from Medacta, Zimmer Biomet, and FH Ortho, consulting fees from Zimmer Biomet, Medacata, FH Orth, and Joint Operations, stock or stock options from Smith &amp; Nephew, Amodisc, and Physiolab, and being a trustee for Power up To Play charity, and on the committee of the Personalized Arthroplasty Society.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41924915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13044835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2633-1462.74.BJO-2026-0019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">BJO-2026-0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Moses B, Orchard J, Orchard J. Systematic review: annual incidence of ACL injury and surgery in various populations. Res Sports Med. 2012;20(3&#x2013;4):157&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1080/15438627.2012.680633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2012.680633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22742074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendt EA, Agel J, Dick R. Anterior cruciate ligament injury patterns among collegiate men and women. J Athl Train. 1999;34(2):86&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1322895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancino F, Gabr A, Plastow R, Haddad FS. Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes. Bone Joint J. 2023;105-B(10):1033&#x2013;1037. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.105B10.BJJ-2023-0881.R1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.105B10.BJJ-2023-0881.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons JL, Coen SE, Bekker S. Anterior cruciate ligament injury: towards a gendered environmental approach. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(17):984&#x2013;990. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-103173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan T, Alvand A, Prieto-Alhambra D, et al. ACL and meniscal injuries increase the risk of primary total knee replacement for osteoarthritis: a matched case-control study using the Clinical Practice Research Datalink (CPRD) Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(15):965&#x2013;968. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29331994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frobell RB, Roos EM, Roos HP, Ranstam J, Lohmander LS. A randomized trial of treatment for acute anterior cruciate ligament tears. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(4):331&#x2013;342. doi: 10.1056/NEJMOA0907797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMOA0907797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BOASt - Best Practice for Management of Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) Injuries.  [21 November 2025]. https://www.boa.ac.uk/resource/best-practice-management-for-acl-injuries-pdf.html date last. accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abram SGF, Price AJ, Judge A, Beard DJ. Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction and meniscal repair rates have both increased in the past 20 years in England: hospital statistics from 1997 to 2017. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(5):286&#x2013;291. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2018-100195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-100195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30661013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay J, Elliott S, Crossman S, Drummond M, Petersen JM. Organized sport engagement interventions for female adolescents: a systematic review using the Youth Sport System. Sport Soc. 2025:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1080/17430437.2025.2460486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17430437.2025.2460486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogaro MC, Abram SGF, Alvand A, Bottomley N, Jackson WFM, Price A. Paediatric and adolescent anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Bone Joint J. 2020;102-B(2):239&#x2013;245. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.102B2.BJJ-2019-0420.R2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.102B2.BJJ-2019-0420.R2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32009437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden C, Hancock MV, Stokes KA, Roberts SP, McKay CD. Effectiveness of the Activate injury prevention exercise programme to prevent injury in schoolboy rugby union. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(14):812&#x2013;817. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2021-105170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-105170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35387776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hislop MD, Stokes KA, Williams S, et al. Reducing musculoskeletal injury and concussion risk in schoolboy rugby players with a pre-activity movement control exercise programme: a cluster randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(15):1140&#x2013;1146. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5530334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Concussion Guidelines for Non-Elite (Grassroots) Sport Contents; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty-five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543&#x2013;1552. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullough KA, Phelps KD, Spindler KP, et al. Return to high school- and college-level football after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a Multicenter Orthopaedic Outcomes Network (MOON) cohort study. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(11):2523&#x2013;2529. doi: 10.1177/0363546512456836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512456836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3692362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22922520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones M, Hugo Pinheiro V, Balendra G, Borque K, Williams A. No difference in return to play rates between different elite sports after primary autograft ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(12):5924&#x2013;5931. doi: 10.1007/s00167-023-07654-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-023-07654-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37947828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy RH, Schmitz L, Wright RW, et al. Return to play and future ACL injury risk after ACL reconstruction in soccer athletes from the Multicenter Orthopaedic Outcomes Network (MOON) group. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(11):2517&#x2013;2522. doi: 10.1177/0363546512459476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512459476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3692367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23002201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes F.Sportsmetrics.  [30 March 2026]. https://sportsmetrics.org date last. accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizzini M, Dvorak J. FIFA 11+: an effective programme to prevent football injuries in various player groups worldwide-a narrative review. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(9):577&#x2013;579. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2015-094765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4413741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelbaum BR, Silvers HJ, Watanabe DS, et al. Effectiveness of a neuromuscular and proprioceptive training program in preventing anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes: 2-year follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(7):1003&#x2013;1010. doi: 10.1177/0363546504272261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546504272261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15888716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers-Granelli H, Silverman R, Bizzini M, Thorborg K, Brophy RH. The 11+ injury prevention programme decreases rate of hamstring strain injuries in male collegiate soccer players. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58(13):701&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2023-107323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-107323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38599679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Myer GD, Ford KR, Hewett TE. Neuromuscular training improves single-limb stability in young female athletes. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2004;34(6):305&#x2013;316. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2004.34.6.305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2004.34.6.305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15233392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStefano LJ, Padua DA, Blackburn JT, Garrett WE, Guskiewicz KM, Marshall SW. Integrated injury prevention program improves balance and vertical jump height in children. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(2):332&#x2013;342. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cc2225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cc2225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20072067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;man M, Lars&#xe9;n K, Forssblad M, N&#xe4;smark A, Wald&#xe9;n M, H&#xe4;gglund M. A nationwide follow-up survey on the effectiveness of an implemented neuromuscular training program to reduce acute knee injuries in soccer players. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(12):2325967118813841. doi: 10.1177/2325967118813841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967118813841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6304704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lind M, Menhert F, Pedersen AB. The first results from the Danish ACL reconstruction registry: epidemiologic and 2 year follow-up results from 5,818 knee ligament reconstructions. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2009;17(2):117&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1007/s00167-008-0654-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-008-0654-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18974970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reframing sport for teenage girls: tackling teenage disengagement. 2022. https://womeninsport.org/resource/reframing-sport-for-teenage-girls-tackling-teenage-disengagement/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill D. Survival of the Fit: How Physical Education Ensures Academic Achievement and a Healthy Life. Teachers College Press; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka MJ, Jones LC, Forman JM. Awareness of anterior cruciate ligament injury-preventive training programs among female collegiate athletes. J Athl Train. 2020;55(4):359&#x2013;364. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-150-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-150-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32160059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halvorsen KC, Marx RG, Wolfe I, et al. Higher adherence to anterior cruciate ligament injury prevention programs is associated with lower injury rates: a meta-analysis and meta-regression. HSS J. 2023;19(2):154&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1177/15563316221140860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15563316221140860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37065096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norcross MF, Johnson ST, Bovbjerg VE, Koester MC, Hoffman MA. Factors influencing high school coaches&#x2019; adoption of injury prevention programs. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(4):299&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25866072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whalan M, Lovell R, Steele JR, Sampson JA. Rescheduling Part 2 of the 11+ reduces injury burden and increases compliance in semi&#x2010;professional football. Scandinavian Med Sci Sports. 2019;29(12):1941&#x2013;1951. doi: 10.1111/sms.13532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins L, Farrey T, Janosky J, Minjares V, Mandelbaum BR, Pearle A. Preventing Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) injuries in high school sports participants: an executive summary of the inaugural meeting of the national ACL injury coalition. HSS J. 2024;20(3):333&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1177/15563316231211320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15563316231211320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11299321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>No authors listed . RIIP REPS;  [30 March 2026]. Reduce injuries improve performance.https://www.riipreps.com date last. accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Janosky J, Bode L, et al. Prevention of ACL injury is better than repair or reconstruction&#x2014;Implementing the ESSKA&#x2010;ESMA &#x2018;Prevention for All&#x2019; ACL programme. Knee surg sports traumatol arthrosc. 2025;33(6):1954&#x2013;1958. doi: 10.1002/ksa.12681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.12681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40260666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross A, Kim J, McKay M, et al. The economics of a national anterior cruciate ligament injury prevention program for amateur football players: a Markov model analysis. Med J Aust. 2024;221(3):149&#x2013;155. doi: 10.5694/mja2.52385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja2.52385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38992929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall DA, Lopatina E, Lacny S, Emery CA. Economic impact study: neuromuscular training reduces the burden of injuries and costs compared to standard warm-up in youth soccer. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(22):1388&#x2013;1393. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27034127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalen-Lorentsen T, Ranvik A, Bj&#xf8;rneboe J, Clarsen B, Andersen TE. Facilitators and barriers for implementation of a load management intervention in football. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2021;7(2):e001046. doi: 10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34249374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers-Granelli H, Bizzini M, Mandelbaum B, Arundale A, Pohlig R, Snyder-Mackler L. High compliance with the 11+ injury prevention program results in better win-loss records. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18(5):1065&#x2013;1075. doi: 10.26603/001c.87502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.87502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10547084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37795333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>