<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41913671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1336-0329</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Endocrine regulations</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Endocr Regul</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Circulating CXCL1 in newly diagnosed type 2 diabetes: context-dependent association with inflammatory load and metabolic indices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><EndPage>28</EndPage><MedlinePgn>20-28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/enr-2026-0003</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Objective.</b> Metabolic syndrome (MS) and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) share a chronic low-grade inflammatory milieu driven by adiposity. C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1 (CXCL1) has been linked to insulin resistance and endothelial dysfunction, but its diagnostic relevance remains unclear. <b>Methods.</b> Our study employed a cross-sectional design and enrolled 104 adults: 52 newly diagnosed treatment-naive T2DM patients and 52 normoglycemic controls matched for age and sex. Serum CXCL1, high-sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP), and metabolic parameters were measured. Logistic regression models to discriminate MS and T2DM status were constructed (base model: age, sex, BMI) and then expanded by adding hs-CRP, CXCL1, or both. Model performance was assessed for discrimination (AUC), calibration (Integrated Calibration Index [ICI], Expected Calibration Error [ECE]), and clinical utility (decision curve analysis, DCA) in accordance with TRIPOD 2024. <b>Results.</b> CXCL1 correlated with BMI (r=0.33, q=0.004) and hs-CRP (r=0.29, q=0.021), but not glycemic indices. For MS, CXCL1 marginally improved the base model (&#x394;AUC=+0.003, p=0.81); for T2DM, &#x394;AUC=+0.007 (p=0.60). hs-CRP performed better (AUC=0.744 for T2DM; 0.743 for MS) and the combined panel achieved the highest discrimination (AUC=0.769 and 0.745, respectively). <b>Conclusions.</b> CXCL1 reflects adiposity-related inflammation but provides only minimal incremental discrimination for metabolic syndrome and T2DM beyond conventional markers such as age, sex, BMI, and hs-CRP. The combined hs-CRP+CXCL1 panel achieved the best overall statistical performance, although its clinical utility remains limited. These findings emphasize the need for integrated multi-marker approaches rather than single-biomarker screening in metabolic risk assessment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Ali Zeynettin et al., published by Slovak Academy of Sciences, Biomedical Research Center, Institute of Experimental Endocrinology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeynettin</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Department of Internal Medicine, University of Health Sciences, Izmir Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balikci</LastName><ForeName>Orhan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>2Department of Internal Medicine, Izmir City Hospital Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akan</LastName><ForeName>Ozden Yildirim</ForeName><Initials>OY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Department of Internal Medicine, University of Health Sciences, Izmir Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dilaver</LastName><ForeName>Erdi</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Department of Internal Medicine, University of Health Sciences, Izmir Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demir</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Department of Internal Medicine, University of Health Sciences, Izmir Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Endocr Regul</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112018</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1210-0668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054360">Chemokine CXCL1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-41-4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002097">C-Reactive Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C475829">CXCL1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054360" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chemokine CXCL1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002097" MajorTopicYN="N">C-Reactive Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CXCL1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bio-marker modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decision curve analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hs-CRP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41913671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/enr-2026-0003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">enr-2026-0003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alberti KG, Eckel RH, Grundy SM, Zimmet PZ, Cleeman JI, Donato KA, Fruchart JC, James WP, Loria CM, Smith SC Jr. Harmonizing the metabolic syndrome: a joint interim statement of the International Diabetes Federation Task Force on Epidemiology and Prevention; National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; American Heart Association; World Heart Federation; International Atherosclerosis Society; and International Association for the Study of Obesity. Circulation 120, 1640&#x2013;1645, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC, Steyerberg EW. The Integrated Calibration Index (ICI) and related metrics for quantifying the calibration of logistic regression models. Stat Med 38, 4051&#x2013;4065, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin PC, Harrell FE Jr, van Klaveren D. Graphical calibration curves and the integrated calibration index (ICI) for survival models. Stat Med 39, 2714&#x2013;2742, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Moons KGM, Dhiman P, Riley RD, Beam AL, Van Calster B, Ghassemi M, Liu X, Reitsma JB, van Smeden M, Boulesteix AL, Camaradou JC, Celi LA, Denaxas S, Denniston AK, Glocker B, Golub RM, Harvey H, Heinze G, Hoffman MM, Kengne AP, Lam E, Lee N, Loder EW, Maier-Hein L, Mateen BA, McCradden MD, Oakden-Rayner L, Ordish J, Parnell R, Rose S, Singh K, Wynants L, Logullo P. TRIPOD+AI statement: updated guidance for reporting clinical prediction models that use regression or machine learning methods. BMJ 385, e078378, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckel RH, Grundy SM, Zimmet PZ. The metabolic syndrome. Lancet 365, 1415&#x2013;1428, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, Bannuru RR, Brown FM, Bruemmer D, Collins BS, Hilliard ME, Isaacs D, Johnson EL, Kahan S, Khunti K, Leon J, Lyons SK, Perry ML, Prahalad P, Pratley RE, Seley JJ, Stanton RC, Gabbay RA. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: Standards of Care in Diabetes&#x2014;2023. Diabetes Care 46, S19&#x2013;S40, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guria S, Hoory A, Das S, Chattopadhyay D, Mukherjee S. Adipose tissue macrophages and their role in obesity-associated insulin resistance: an overview of the complex dynamics at play. Biosci Rep 43, BSR20220200, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Wang H, Yang G, Zhu L, Liu X. The role of chemokines in obesity and exercise-induced weight loss. Biomolecules 14, 1121, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu C, Jia W. Multi-omics profiling: the way towards precision medicine in metabolic diseases. J Mol Cell Biol 13, 576&#x2013;593, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ion G, Bostan M, Hardman WE, Putt McFarland M, Bleotu C, Radu N, Diaconu CC, Mihaila M, Caramihai MD, Hotnog CM. Nutrients lowering obesity-linked chemokines blamable for metastasis. Int J Mol Sci 26, 2275, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Lim JS. The association between C-reactive protein, metabolic syndrome, and prediabetes in Korean children and adolescents. Ann Pediatr Endocrinol Metab 27, 273&#x2013;280, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korbecki J, Gassowska-Dobrowolska M, Wojcik J, Szatkowska I, Barczak K, Chlubek M, Baranowska-Bosiacka I. The importance of CXCL1 in physiology and noncancerous diseases of bone, bone marrow, muscle and the nervous system. Int J Mol Sci 23, 4205, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazennec G, Rajarathnam K, Richmond A. CXCR2 chemokine receptor - a master regulator in cancer and physiology. Trends Mol Med 30, 37&#x2013;55, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Chu D, Kalantar-Zadeh K, George J, Young HA, Liu G. Cytokines: from clinical significance to quantification. Adv Sci 8, e2004433, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo HM, Lai TH, Li CH, Wu WB. TNF-&#x3b1; induces CXCL1 chemokine expression and release in human vascular endothelial cells in vitro via two distinct signaling pathways. Acta Pharmacol Sin 35, 339&#x2013;350, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moin ASM, Sathyapalan T, Diboun I, Atkin SL, Butler AE. Identification of macrophage activation-related biomarkers in obese type 2 diabetes that may be indicative of enhanced respiratory risk in COVID-19. Sci Rep 11, 6428, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monickaraj F, Acosta G, Cabrera AP, Das A. Transcriptomic profiling reveals chemokine CXCL1 as a mediator for neutrophil recruitment associated with blood-retinal barrier alteration in diabetic retinopathy. Diabetes 72, 781&#x2013;794, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan X, Tan X, McDonald J, Kaminga AC, Chen Y, Dai F, Qiu J, Zhao K, Peng Y. Chemokines in diabetic eye disease. Diabetol Metab Syndr 16, 115, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini V, La Grotta R, Carreras F, Giuliani A, Sabbatinelli J, Olivieri F, Berra CC, Ceriello A, Prattichizzo F. Inflammatory trajectory of type 2 diabetes: novel opportunities for early and late treatment. Cells 13, 1662, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips BE, Lantier L, Engman C, Garciafigueroa Y, Singhi A, Trucco M, Mantzoros C, Wasserman D, Giannoukakis N. Improvement in insulin sensitivity and prevention of high fat diet-induced liver pathology using a CXCR2 antagonist. Cardiovasc Diabetol 21, 130, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajadi SM, Khoramdelazad H, Hassanshahi G, Rafatpanah H, Hosseini J, Mahmoodi M, Arababadi MK, Derakhshan R, Hasheminasabzavareh R, Hosseini-Zijoud SM, Ahmadi Z. Plasma levels of CXCL1 (GRO-alpha) and CXCL10 (IP-10) are elevated in type 2 diabetic patients: evidence for the involvement of inflammation and angiogenesis/angiostasis in this disease state. Clin Lab 59, 133&#x2013;137, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw A, Toth BB, Kiraly R, Arianti R, Csomos I, Poliska S, Vamos A, Korponay-Szabo IR, Bacso Z, Gyory F, Fesus L, Kristof E. Irisin stimulates the release of CXCL1 from differentiating human subcutaneous and deep-neck derived adipocytes via upregulation of NF&#x3ba;B pathway. Front Cell Dev Biol 9, 737872, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitaru S, Budke A, Bertini R, Sperandio M. Therapeutic inhibition of CXCR1/2: where do we stand? Intern Emerg Med 18, 1647&#x2013;1664, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Saeedi P, Karuranga S, Pinkepank M, Ogurtsova K, Duncan BB, Stein C, Basit A, Chan JCN, Mbanya JC, Pavkov ME, Ramachandaran A, Wild SH, James S, Herman WH, Zhang P, Bommer C, Kuo S, Boyko EJ, Magliano DJ. IDF Diabetes Atlas: global, regional and country-level diabetes prevalence estimates for 2021 and projections for 2045. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 183, 109119, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toya S, Struyf S, Huerta L, Morris P, Gavioli E, Minnella EM, Cesta MC, Allegretti M, Proost P. A narrative review of chemokine receptors CXCR1 and CXCR2 and their role in acute respiratory distress syndrome. Eur Respir Rev 33, 230172, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ, Van Calster B, Steyerberg EW. Net benefit approaches to the evaluation of prediction models, molecular markers, and diagnostic tests. BMJ 352, i6, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Ballantyne CM. Metabolic inflammation and insulin resistance in obesity. Circ Res 126, 1549&#x2013;1564, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zlotnik A, Yoshie O. Chemokines: a new classification system and their role in immunity. Immunity 12, 121&#x2013;127, 2000.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>