<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41291891</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the comparative efficacy of leg cycle ergometry exercise versus conventional physiotherapy on scar healing, muscle strength, functional capacity, and quality of life in coronary artery bypass graft subjects with saphenous vein graft in phase 1: a protocol for randomised controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>545</StartPage><MedlinePgn>545</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">545</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-025-09255-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) is a common surgical treatment for coronary artery disease. The saphenous vein's advantageous anatomical features make it a popular choice for graft vessels. However, saphenous vein harvesting often results in lower limb complications such as edema, poor scar healing, pain, and reduced functional mobility. These issues can delay recovery and diminish quality of life. Early rehabilitation using leg cycle ergometry may improve outcomes, but comparative evidence with conventional physiotherapy in Phase I post-CABG care is limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the relative benefits of leg cycle ergometry training for CABG patients with saphenous vein graft in phase 1 in terms of scar healing, muscle strength, functional ability, and quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the comparative efficacy of leg cycle ergometry exercise versus conventional physiotherapy on scar healing, muscle strength, functional capacity, and quality of life in CABG subjects with saphenous vein grafts during Phase I rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A randomized controlled trial will be conducted at Shalini Tai Meghe Super Speciality Centre with 70 CABG patients aged 45-65 years. Participants will be randomly allocated to Group A (conventional physiotherapy) and Group B (leg cycle ergometry with physiotherapy) for a 10-day intervention. Outcome measures include the Vancouver Scar Scale, Manual Muscle Testing, 6-Minute Walk Test, and Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9). Data will be analysed using the Mann-Whitney U test and the Wilcoxon signed-rank test; p&lt;0.05 was deemed statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">As this is a study protocol, no results are available yet. It is hypothesized that leg cycle ergometry, when added to conventional physiotherapy, will lead to greater improvements in scar healing, lower limb strength, functional capacity, and short-term quality of life during Phase I cardiac rehabilitation following CABG surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Clinical Trial Registry-India (CTRI/2025/03/084291). Registered on 15 April 2025.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vinerkar</LastName><ForeName>Deepali</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-5358-0938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular and Respiratory physiotherapy, Ravi Nair physiotherapy college, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Sawangi (Meghe), 442001, Wardha, India. deepalivinerkar13@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vardhan</LastName><ForeName>Vishnu</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3780-2854</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular and Respiratory physiotherapy, Ravi Nair physiotherapy college, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Sawangi (Meghe), 442001, Wardha, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002921" MajorTopicYN="N">Cicatrix</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001026" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Artery Bypass</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003324" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Artery Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Saphenous Vein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000637" MajorTopicYN="N">transplantation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014945" MajorTopicYN="N">Wound Healing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CABG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cycle ergometry</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Institutional Ethics Committee of Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research (DMIHER-DU), Sawangi (Meghe), Wardha, Maharashtra (Reference No: DMIHER(DU)/IEC/2025/626, dated January 30, 2025). The results of this trial will be disseminated through publication in peer-reviewed scientific journals, presentations at national and international conferences, and submission of final trial outcomes to the Clinical Trials Registry&#x2013;India (CTRI) in compliance with regulatory requirements. Consent for publication: Written informed consent will be obtained from all participants prior to enrollment, after a detailed explanation of the study objectives, procedures, potential risks, and expected benefits. Participants will be informed of their right to withdraw at any time without any impact on their standard medical care. Stringent measures will be implemented to maintain confidentiality and protect personal information in compliance with institutional and national ethical standards. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing financial or non-financial interests related to this clinical trial. This study is investigator-initiated, conducted solely for academic and research purposes without any sponsorship or financial support from commercial entities or pharmaceutical companies. There are no personal, professional, or institutional conflicts of interest that could influence the study outcomes.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41291891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12649097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-025-09255-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-025-09255-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vervoort D, Malik A, Fremes SE. The evolving evidence base for coronary artery bypass grafting and arterial grafting: how to improve vein graft patency. JTCVS Tech. 2021;10:102&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xjtc.2021.09.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34977712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethares KA, Chin E, Costa I. Pain intensity, interference, and patient pain management strategies during the first 12 weeks after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. Appl Nurs Res. 2013;26(4):174&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apnr.2013.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24075734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins RO. Early activity in the ICU: beyond safety and feasibility. Respir Care. 2010;55(4):481&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20406518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch JC, Lillou D, Wittig G, Bartsch P, Willemsen D, Oldridge N, et al. Resistance and balance training improve functional capacity in very old participants attending cardiac rehabilitation after coronary bypass surgery. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012;60(12):2270&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.12030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu AS, Noone MS, Haneef M, Narayanan SM. Protocol-guided phase 1 cardiac rehabilitation in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction in a rural hospital. Heart Views. 2010;11(2):52&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1995-705X.73209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3000912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21187997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghashghaei FE, Sadeghi M, Marandi SM, Ghashghaei SE. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation improves hemodynamic responses after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. ARYA Atheroscler. 2012;7(4):151&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3413083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23205048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hambrecht R, Gielen S, Linke A, Fiehn E, Yu J, Walther C, et al. Effects of exercise training on left ventricular function and peripheral resistance in patients with chronic heart failure: A randomized trial. JAMA. 2000;283(23):3095&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.283.23.3095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay GM, Hanlon WP, Smith LN, Belcher PR. Experience of cardiac rehabilitation after coronary artery surgery: effects on health and risk factors. Int J Cardiol. 2003;87(1):67&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0167-5273(02)00208-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12468056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumide T, Shimada K, Ohmura H, Onishi T, Kawakami K, Masaki Y, et al. Relationship between exercise tolerance and muscle strength following cardiac rehabilitation: comparison of patients after cardiac surgery and patients with myocardial infarction. J Cardiol. 2009;54(2):273&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjcc.2009.05.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid MF, Nazar QUA, Akash NKA, Khalid Z, Shaukat Ali M, Farooqi A, et al. Comparison of phase 1 cardiac rehabilitation with and without lower limb paddling effects in post-CABG patients. Pak J Med Health Sci. 2022;16(1):342&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53350/pjmhs22161342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires-Neto RC, Kawaguchi YMF, Hirota AS, Fu C, Tanaka C, Caruso P, et al. Very early passive cycling exercise in mechanically ventilated critically ill patients: physiological and safety aspects. PLoS One. 2013;8(9):e74182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0074182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24040200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lordello GGG, Gama GGG, Rosier GL, Viana PADC, Correia LC, Ritt LEF. Effects of cycle ergometer use in early mobilization following cardiac surgery: A randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2020;34(4):450&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215520901763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31994405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschhorn AD, Richards DAB, Mungovan SF, Morris NR, Adams L. Does the mode of exercise influence recovery of functional capacity in the early postoperative period after coronary artery bypass graft surgery? A randomized controlled trial. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2012;15(6):995&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icvts/ivs403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed K, Niazi R, Waheed A, Rasheed N, Khalil S, Awan IZ. Effects of physical therapy in preventing complications of postoperative coronary artery bypass grafting: physical therapy in post-CABG patients. HJPRS. 2023;3(6):578&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari S, Baig MO, Baig UA. Effect of cardiac rehabilitation phase II training on calf strength in CABG patients. Annals. 2012;18(2):147&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordeiro R, Silva T, Oliveira M, Almeida A. Effects of cycloergometer on cardiopulmonary function in elderly patients after coronary artery bypass grafting: A clinical trial. Cardiol Res Pract. 2024;2024:3808437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/3808437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39345876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L, Thompson DR, Oldridge N, Zwisler AD, Rees K, Martin N, et al. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation for coronary heart disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;2016(1):CD001800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6491180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26730878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>