<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41902367</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-3479</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of gynaecology and obstetrics: the official organ of the International Federation of Gynaecology and Obstetrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Gynaecol Obstet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>FIGO best practice recommendations for the mental health of women at menopausal age.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ijgo.70943</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mental health during the menopausal transition requires focused attention to ensure supportive experiences for women. This review presents the International Federation of Gynecology and Obstetrics (FIGO) recommendations and summarizes the evidence, addressing 13 key questions framed by members of the FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age. Although the literature on mental health during menopause is extensive, a gap exists in consolidated best practice recommendations. The FIGO committee members assessed the evidence quality and recommendation strength using a 5-point Likert scale. Over 70% of the experts agreed with a strong recommendation level (score of 5) for eight questions, while five questions were agreed with high and moderate recommendations. Symptoms of anxiety and depression are prevalent during the perimenopause. Menopause-related mental health issues are often overlooked in low- and middle-income countries. Mental health issues impact quality of life, necessitating psychological support during menopause care. Early detection requires training primary care providers to identify symptoms. Treatment should be individualized and may include lifestyle changes, cognitive-behavioral therapy, and hormone therapy. Transdermal estradiol is preferred for managing mood swings, particularly in women with metabolic risks. Escitalopram and venlafaxine effectively manage depressive symptoms and vasomotor instability in patients with major depressive disorder. Non-pharmacological interventions, such as lifestyle changes, therapy, mindfulness, and exercise have shown benefits. Partner and family support helps reduce the stigma associated with mental health issues during menopause. Advocacy is required for policies that support menopause awareness and mental health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). International Journal of Gynecology &amp; Obstetrics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of International Federation of Gynecology and Obstetrics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khadilkar</LastName><ForeName>Suvarna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6316-6352</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gynecology and Obstetrics Department, Bombay Hospital Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Bombay Hospital Medical Research Center, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Divakar</LastName><ForeName>Hema</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Division of Well Woman Health Care, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divakar Specialty Hospital, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benedetto</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Reproductive Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Sant'Anna University Hospital, Torino, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genazzani</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Diana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California Surgeon General, ACOG District IX, Women's Preventive Services Initiative Implementation Committee, Keck University of Southern California School of Medicine, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Argale</LastName><ForeName>Elizabete</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Riga Stradins University, Riga, Latvia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deshpande</LastName><ForeName>Gandhali</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Affairs, Mind's Lab Publishing India, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hicky</LastName><ForeName>Martha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynaecology and Newborn Health, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filho</LastName><ForeName>Agnaldo Lopes Da Silva</ForeName><Initials>ALDS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Faculty of Medicine, UFMG (Federal University of Minas Gerais), Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herrera</LastName><ForeName>Enrique</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FIGO Committee on Women at Menopausal Age, FIGO, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Universidad del Valle, Cali, Valle del Cauca, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balkrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Milan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Masina Hospital Trust and Medical Research Centre, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Gynaecol Obstet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0210174</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-7292</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical tools</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle changes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopausal hormone therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mood</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recommendations</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijgo.70943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hill K. The demography of menopause. Maturitas. 1996;23(2):113&#x2010;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro N, Epperson CN, Mathews SB. Menopausal symptoms and their management. Endocrinol Metab Clin N Am. 2015;44(3):497&#x2010;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro N, Roeca C, Peters BA, Neal&#x2010;Perry G. The menopause transition: signs, symptoms, and management options. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106(1):1&#x2010;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchengast S. Menopause in a globalized world &#x2010; a systematic literature review focussing on the challenge of health problems associated with menopausal transition among women with a migration background. Maturitas. 2024;187:108045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Liu F, Zhang X, et&#xa0;al. Mapping global prevalence of menopausal symptoms among middle&#x2010;aged women: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):1767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang DR, Goodship A, Webber I, et&#xa0;al. Experience and severity of menopause symptoms and effects on health&#x2010;seeking behaviours: a cross&#x2010;sectional online survey of community dwelling adults in the United Kingdom. BMC Womens Health. 2023;23(1):373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Kumar A, Singh V. Mental health issues in menopause. Indian J Clinl Psych. 2023;3(1):22&#x2010;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fidecicchi T, Giannini A, Chedraui P, et&#xa0;al. Neuroendocrine mechanisms of mood disorders during menopause transition: a narrative review and future perspectives. Maturitas. 2024;188:108087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop BW, Nemeroff CB. The role of dopamine in the pathophysiology of depression. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2007;64(3):327&#x2010;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouba BR, Camargo A, Gil&#x2010;Mohapel J, Rodrigues ALS. Molecular basis underlying the therapeutic potential of vitamin D for the treatment of depression and anxiety. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:7077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracious BL, Messing S, Finucane TL, Friedman&#x2010;Campbell M, Parkhurst MN. Vitamin D deficiency and psychotic features in mentally ill adolescents: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. BMC Psychiatry. 2012;12:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg G, Gustafsson T, H&#xe4;llstr&#xf6;m T, Petersson M, Klawitter B, Gustafsson SA. Depressed adolescents in a case&#x2010;series were low in vitamin D and depression was ameliorated by vitamin D supplementation. Acta Paediatr. 2012;101:779&#x2010;783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C, Zhang Y, Wang T, et&#xa0;al. Vitamin D supplementation improves anxiety but not depression symptoms in patients with vitamin D deficiency. Brain Behav. 2020;10:e01760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatkar A, Kale S, Shyam A, Srivastava S. Understanding the levels of evidence in medical research. J Orthop Case Rep. 2025;15(5):6&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen IE, Seaman CA. Likert scales and data analyses. Qual Prog. 2007;40:64&#x2010;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit AE, Giltay EJ, de Boer MK, et&#xa0;al. Predictors of irritability symptoms in mildly depressed perimenopausal women. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2021;126:105128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Wan Y, Geng L. Unraveling the core and bridge menopausal symptoms of perimenopausal women: a network analysis. Menopause. 2024;31(11):996&#x2010;1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coslov N, Richardson MK, Woods NF. &#x201c;Not feeling like myself&#x201d; in perimenopause &#x2010; what does it mean? Observations from the women living better survey. Menopause. 2024;31(5):390&#x2010;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberger JT, Assmann SF, Avis NE, Schocken M, Kravitz HM, Cordal A. Persistent mood symptoms in a multiethnic community cohort of pre&#x2010; and perimenopausal women. Am J Epidemiol. 2003;158(4):347&#x2010;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maki PM, Kornstein SG, Joffe H, et&#xa0;al. Guidelines for the evaluation and treatment of perimenopausal depression: summary and recommendations. Menopause. 2018;25(10):1069&#x2010;1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badawy Y, Spector A, Li Z, Desai R. The risk of depression in the menopausal stages: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Affect Disord. 2024;357:126&#x2010;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Longitudinal Study on Women's Health. Women's Health Australia. 2025. https://alswh.org.au/about/the&#x2010;study/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey M, Schoenaker DA, Joffe H, et&#xa0;al. Depressive symptoms across the menopause transition: findings from a large population&#x2010;based cohort study. Menopause. 2016;23(12):1287&#x2010;1293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberger JT, Schott L, Kravitz HM, Joffe H. Risk factors for major depression during midlife among a community sample of women with and without prior major depression: are they the same or different? Psychol Med. 2015;45(8):1653&#x2010;1664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang R, Luo M, Li J, et&#xa0;al. Symptoms of anxiety and depression among Chinese women transitioning through menopause: findings from a prospective community&#x2010;based cohort study. Fertil Steril. 2019;112(6):1160&#x2010;1171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston RC, Thomas HN, Castle AJ, Gibson CJ. Menopause as a biological and psychological transition. Nat Rev Psychol. 2025;4:530&#x2010;543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown L, Hunter MS, Chen R, et&#xa0;al. Promoting good mental health over the menopause transition. Lancet. 2024;403(10430):969&#x2010;983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung HF, Pandeya N, Dobson AJ, et&#xa0;al. The role of sleep difficulties in the vasomotor menopausal symptoms and depressed mood relationships: an international pooled analysis of eight studies in the InterLACE consortium. Psychol Med. 2018;48(15):2550&#x2010;2561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberger JT, Epperson CN. Depression during and after the perimenopause: impact of hormones, genetics, and environmental determinants of disease. Obstet Gynecol Clin N Am. 2018;45(4):663&#x2010;678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberger JT, Kravitz HM. Mood and menopause: findings from the study of Women's health across the nation (SWAN) over 10&#x2009;years. Obstet Gynecol Clin N Am. 2011;38(3):609&#x2010;625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman EW. Depression in the menopause transition: risks in the changing hormone milieu as observed in the general population. Womens Midlife Health. 2015;1:2. doi:10.1186/s40695-015-0002-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey M, LaCroix AZ, Doust J, et&#xa0;al. An empowerment model for managing menopause. Lancet. 2024;403(10430):947&#x2010;957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namazi M, Sadeghi R, Behboodi Moghadam Z. Social determinants of health in menopause: an integrative review. Int J Women's Health. 2019;11:637&#x2010;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlow SD, Burnett&#x2010;Bowie SM, Greendale GA, et&#xa0;al. Disparities in reproductive aging and midlife health between black and white women: the study of Women's health across the nation (SWAN). Womens Midlife Health. 2022;8(1):3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madaan S, Acharya N, Jaiswal A, Dewani D, Kotdawala K. Anxiety and depression in post&#x2010;menopausal women: a short review. Ann Geriatr Educ Med Sci. 2021;8(2):38&#x2010;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam RM, Rana J, Katha S, et&#xa0;al. Menopause in low and middle&#x2010;income countries: a scoping review of knowledge, symptoms and management. Climacteric. 2025;28(3):242&#x2010;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AM, Ahmed AH, Smail L. Psychological climacteric symptoms and attitudes toward menopause among Emirati women. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(14):5028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SC, Marshall VB, Becker CB, LaCroix AZ, Keel PK, Kilpela LS. Mental health and quality of life in postmenopausal women as a function of retrospective menopause symptom severity. Menopause. 2022;29(6):707&#x2010;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, Kim K. Depression and its association with health&#x2010;related quality of life in postmenopausal women in Korea. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(11):2327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesco KK, Haney EM, Humphrey L, Fu R, Nelson HD. Influence of menopause on mood: a systematic review of cohort studies. Climacteric. 2007;10(6):448&#x2010;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman SA, Zainudin SR, Mun VL. Assessment of menopausal symptoms using modified menopause rating scale (MRS) among middle&#x2010;aged women in Kuching, Sarawak, Malaysia. Asia Pac Fam Med. 2010;9(1):5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Fu Z, Bo Q, Mao Z, Ma X, Wang C. The reliability and validity of PHQ&#x2010;9 in patients with major depressive disorder in psychiatric hospital. BMC Psychiatry. 2020;20(1):474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilditch JR, Lewis J, Peter A, et&#xa0;al. A menopause&#x2010;specific quality of life questionnaire: development and psychometric properties. Maturitas. 1996;24(3):161&#x2010;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novaes C, Almeida OP, de Melo NR. Mental health among perimenopausal women attending a menopause clinic: possible association with premenstrual syndrome? Climacteric. 1998;1(4):264&#x2010;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breedvelt JJF, Zamperoni V, South E, et&#xa0;al. A systematic review of mental health measurement scales for evaluating the effects of mental health prevention interventions. Eur J Pub Health. 2020;30(3):539&#x2010;545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newson JJ, Thiagarajan TC. Assessment of population well&#x2010;being with the mental health quotient (MHQ): development and usability study. JMIR Ment Health. 2020;7(7):e17935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Agteren J, Bartholomaeus J, Fassnacht DB, et&#xa0;al. Using internet&#x2010;based psychological measurement to capture the deteriorating community mental health profile during COVID&#x2010;19: observational study. JMIR Ment Health. 2020;7(6):e20696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husain W, Ijaz F, Ahmad Husain M, Zulfiqar M, Khalique J. Simplifying the understanding and measurement of mental disorders thru a comprehensive framework of psychosocial health. OBM Inte Com Med. 2024;9(1):11&#x2010;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ssler W, Ajdacic&#x2010;Gross V, Riecher&#x2010;R&#xf6;ssler A, Angst J, Hengartner MP. Does menopausal transition really influence mental health? Findings from the prospective long&#x2010;term Zurich study. World Psychiatry. 2016;15(2):146&#x2010;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron CR, Cohen S, Sewell K, Lee M. The art of hormone replacement therapy (HRT) in menopause management. J Pharm Pract. 2024;37(3):736&#x2010;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey M, Bryant C, Judd F. Evaluation and management of depressive and anxiety symptoms in midlife. Climacteric. 2012;15(1):3&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini J, Wittchen HU, Soares CN, Rieder A, Steiner M. New women&#x2010;specific diagnostic modules: the composite international diagnostic interview for women (CIDI&#x2010;VENUS). Arch Womens Ment Health. 2009;12(5):281&#x2010;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The 2022 Hormone Therapy Position Statement of the North American Menopause Society Advisory Panel. The 2022 hormone therapy position statement of the North American Menopause Society. Menopause. 2022;29(7):767&#x2010;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni J, Gurvich C, Mu E, et&#xa0;al. Menopause depression: under recognised and poorly treated. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2024;58(8):636&#x2010;640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood K, McCarthy S, Pitt H, Randle M, Thomas SL. Women's experiences and expectations during the menopause transition: a systematic qualitative narrative review. Health Promot Int. 2025;40(1):daaf005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrman S, Crockett C. Severe mental illness and the perimenopause. BJPsych Bull. 2023;48:364&#x2010;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly K, McDermid F, McInnes S, Peters K. &#x201c;I was just a shell&#x201d;: mental health concerns for women in perimenopause and menopause. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2024;33(3):693&#x2010;702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews R, Lacey A, Bache K, Kidd EJ. The role of menopausal symptoms on future health and longevity: a systematic scoping review of longitudinal evidence. Maturitas. 2024;190:108130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genazzani AR, Divakar H, Khadilkar SS, et&#xa0;al. Counseling in menopausal women: how to address the benefits and risks of menopause hormone therapy. A FIGO position paper. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2024;164(2):516&#x2010;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). Menopause: Diagnosis and Management. NICE Guideline NG23. NICE; 2015. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter MS, Chilcot J. Is cognitive behaviour therapy an effective option for women who have troublesome menopausal symptoms? Br J Health Psychol. 2021;26(3):697&#x2010;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garay RP, Charpeaud T, Logan S, et&#xa0;al. Pharmacotherapeutic approaches to treating depression during the perimenopause. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2019;20(15):1837&#x2010;1845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duralde ER, Sobel TH, Manson JE. Management of perimenopausal and menopausal symptoms. BMJ. 2023;382:e072612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacQueen GM, Frey BN, Ismail Z, et&#xa0;al. Canadian network for mood and anxiety treatments (CANMAT) 2016 clinical guidelines for the management of adults with major depressive disorder: section&#xa0;6. Special populations: youth, women, and the elderly. Can J Psychiatr. 2016;61(9):588&#x2010;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostis P, Lambrinoudaki I, Bosdou JK, Vaitsi K, Goulis DG. Estrogen and bones after menopause: a reappraisal of data and future perspectives. Hormones. 2020;20:13&#x2010;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borozan S, Kamrul&#x2010;Hasan ABM, Pappachan JM. Hormone replacement therapy for menopausal mood swings and sleep quality: the current evidence. World J Psychiatry. 2024;14(10):1605&#x2010;1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg G, Wu P, Wenger N. Menopausal hormone therapy: a comprehensive review. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2020;22:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temkin SM, Wenham RM, Rubinsak L, Mallen A, Bellavance E. The role of menopausal hormone therapy in women with or at risk of ovarian and breast cancers: misconceptions and current directions. Cancer. 2018;125:499&#x2010;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson JC, Ren M, Kahler E, et&#xa0;al. Ultra&#x2010;low dose estradiol and dydrogesterone for the treatment of menopausal symptoms in a pooled, multi&#x2010;ethnic population. Maturitas. 2024;190:108117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostis P, Lambrinoudaki I, Krikidis D, Paschou SA, Katsiki N, Goulis DG. Menopausal hormone therapy and cardiovascular risk: where are we now? Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2019;17:564&#x2010;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indian Menopause Society. Module 3 Prescription Writing of MHT. https://indianmenopausesociety.org/assets/pdf/gynaecologist/Menopause&#x2010;PPT&#x2010;management.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey DA. Menopausal hormone therapy: a better and safer future. Climacteric. 2018;21:454&#x2010;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper&#x2010;Harrison G, Carlson K, Shanahan MM. Hormone Replacement Therapy. StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing; 2025. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK493191/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Femring&#xae; (estradiol acetate vaginal ring) &#x2010; accessdata.fda.gov. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2024/021367s021lbl.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CK, Tseng PT, Wu MK, et&#xa0;al. Antidepressants during and after menopausal transition: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):8026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans ML, Pritts E, Vittinghoff E, McClish K, Morgan KS, Jaffe RB. Management of postmenopausal hot flushes with venlafaxine hydrochloride: a randomized, controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;105(1):161&#x2010;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter M. Cognitive behavioural interventions for premenstrual and menopausal symptoms. J Reprod Infant Psychol. 2003;21:183&#x2010;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elavsky S, McAuley E. Physical activity and mental health outcomes during menopause: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Behav Med. 2007;33(2):132&#x2010;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondarev D, Sipil&#xe4; S, Finni T, et&#xa0;al. The role of physical activity in the link between menopausal status and mental well&#x2010;being. Menopause. 2020;27(4):398&#x2010;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue H, Yang Y, Xie F, et&#xa0;al. Effects of physical activity on depressive and anxiety symptoms of women in the menopausal transition and menopause: a comprehensive systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2025;22(1):13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin SM, El&#x2010;Gazar HE, Zoromba MA, El&#x2010;Sayed MM, Awad AGE, Atta MHR. Mindfulness for menopausal women: enhancing quality of life and psychological well&#x2010;being through a randomized controlled intervention. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2025;57(4):563&#x2010;575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Cai K, Wang J, Zhang H. The effects of mindfulness&#x2010;based interventions on anxiety, depression, stress, and mindfulness in menopausal women: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Front Public Health. 2023;10:1045642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The 2023 nonhormone therapy position statement of the North American Menopause Society. Menopause. 2023;30(6):573&#x2010;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo RA, Marino JL, Hickey M. Managing menopausal symptoms after cancer. Climacteric. 2019;22(6):572&#x2010;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halverson T, Alagiakrishnan K. Gut microbes in neurocognitive and mental health disorders. Ann Med. 2020;52(8):423&#x2010;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Mental Healthcare Act 2017. https://cmhlp.org/wp&#x2010;content/uploads/2022/05/Visual&#x2010;Summary&#x2010;Resource&#x2010;on&#x2010;Indias&#x2010;Mental&#x2010;Health&#x2010;for&#x2010;Youth&#x2010;Participants.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleymani M, Siassi F, Qorbani M, et&#xa0;al. Dietary patterns and their association with menopausal symptoms: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Menopause. 2019;26(4):365&#x2010;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butola LK, Kanyal D, Ambad R, Jha RK. Role of omega 3 fatty acids, vitamin D, vitamin B12, vitamin B6 and folate in mental wellbeing&#x2010;a short review of literature. Indian J Forensic Med Toxicol. 2021;15(2):283&#x2010;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appleton KM, Peters TJ, Hayward RC, et&#xa0;al. Depressed mood and n&#x2010;3 polyunsaturated fatty acid intake from fish: non&#x2010;linear or confounded association? Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2007;42(2):100&#x2010;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panagiotakos DB, Mamplekou E, Pitsavos C, et&#xa0;al. Fatty acids intake and depressive symptomatology in a Greek sample: an epidemiological analysis. J Am Coll Nutr. 2010;29(6):586&#x2010;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colangelo LA, He K, Whooley MA, Daviglus ML, Liu K. Higher dietary intake of long&#x2010;chain omega&#x2010;3 polyunsaturated fatty acids is inversely associated with depressive symptoms in women. Nutrition. 2009;25(10):1011&#x2010;1019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkarainen R, Partonen T, Haukka J, Virtamo J, Albanes D, L&#xf6;nnqvist J. Is low dietary intake of omega&#x2010;3 fatty acids associated with depression? Am J Psychiatry. 2004;161(3):567&#x2010;569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra S, Sharma KA, Ranjan P, Malhotra A, Vikram NK, Kumari A. Weight management module for Perimenopausal women: a practical guide for gynecologists. J Midlife Health. 2019;10(4):165&#x2010;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlo G, Vela A. Mental health in lifestyle medicine: a call to action. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2021;16(1):7&#x2010;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth J, Solmi M, Wootton RE, et&#xa0;al. A meta&#x2010;review of &#x201c;lifestyle psychiatry&#x201d;: the role of exercise, smoking, diet and sleep in the prevention and treatment of mental disorders. World Psychiatry. 2020;19(3):360&#x2010;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdkhasti M, Simbar M, Abdi F. Empowerment and coping strategies in menopause women: a review. Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2015;17(3):e18944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Roozbeh N, Ziraeie A. Efficacy of the complementary and alternative therapies for the Management of Psychological Symptoms of menopause: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. J Menopausal Med. 2021;27(3):115&#x2010;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maki PM, Jaff NG. Brain fog in menopause: a health&#x2010;care professional's guide for decision&#x2010;making and counseling on cognition. Climacteric. 2022;25(6):570&#x2010;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moseley RL, Druce T, Turner&#x2010;Cobb JM. Autism research is &#x2018;all about the blokes and the kids&#x2019;: autistic women breaking the silence on menopause. Br J Health Psychol. 2021;26(3):709&#x2010;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahri N, Yoshany N, Morowatisharifabad MA, Noghabi AD, Sajjadi M. The effects of menopausal health training for spouses on women's quality of life during menopause transitional period. Menopause. 2016;23(2):183&#x2010;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S, McMahon J. The importance of relationship in understanding the experiences of spouse mental health carers. Qual Health Res. 2014;24(2):254&#x2010;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang M, Chen Y, Ji JS, Zhang Y, Chen C, Zhang Z. The association between household and family composition and mental health of the elderly: mediating role of lifestyle. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):2055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehane CM, Hofs&#xf6;e SM, Wittich W, Dammeyer J. Mental health and spouse support among older couples living with sensory loss. J Aging Health. 2018;30(8):1205&#x2010;1223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;bel L&#x2010;M, Jacobsen J. Waiting for kin: a longitudinal study of family reunification and refugee mental health in Germany. J Ethn Migr Stud. 2021;47:2916&#x2010;2937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods NF. Employment, family roles, and mental ill health in young married women. Nurs Res. 1985;34(1):4&#x2010;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis Johnson T, Rowland LM, Ashraf MS, et&#xa0;al. Key findings from mental Health Research during the menopause transition for racially and ethnically Minoritized women living in the United States: a scoping review. J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2024;33(2):113&#x2010;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill MT, Jones V, Reid A. Impact of menopausal symptoms on work and careers: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Occup Med (Lond). 2023;73(6):332&#x2010;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menopause in the Workplace: Guidance for Employers. 2024. https://www.equalityhumanrights.com/guidance/menopause&#x2010;workplace&#x2010;guidance&#x2010;employers</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>