<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41140995</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Attitudes of Pediatric Nursing Staff Regarding Parental Presence During Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93037</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93037</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93037</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93037</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This narrative review examines the attitudes of pediatric nursing staff toward parental presence during cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR), highlighting both international perspectives and findings from the Greek healthcare context. A thematic analysis of existing Greek and international literature was conducted using databases such as PubMed, Scopus, and Excerpta Medica Database (EMBASE), with studies selected based on predefined inclusion and exclusion criteria focusing on pediatric CPR, healthcare professionals' attitudes, and the presence of parents during resuscitation. The studies reviewed support the inclusion of parents during pediatric resuscitation, reporting emotional, ethical, and psychological benefits for families. Pediatric nurses, in particular, tend to be more supportive of parental presence compared to their counterparts in adult care. This reflects a stronger alignment with family-centered care models. However, significant barriers remain, including institutional resistance, lack of formal guidelines, and insufficient staff training, especially in Greece. We also found that the majority of nursing staff reported having no personal experience with the presence of family during resuscitation and expressed disagreement with allowing parents to be present. Concerns about team performance and parental distress are also reported, though these are often mitigated by clear communication, staff preparation, and structured support roles. Overall, parental presence during pediatric CPR offers meaningful benefits when implemented within a supportive institutional framework. Targeted education, culturally sensitive communication, and the empowerment of pediatric nurses are essential to facilitate this practice. Adopting evidence-based policies and enhancing interdisciplinary collaboration can further promote ethically sound and family-centered resuscitation care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Charalampopoulos et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charalampopoulos</LastName><ForeName>Dimitris</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Agia Sofia Children's Hospital, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, School of Health and Care Sciences, University of West Attica, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xanthos</LastName><ForeName>Theodoros</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, School of Health and Care Sciences, University of West Attica, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iacovidou</LastName><ForeName>Nicoletta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neonatology, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Aretaieion Hospital, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metallinou</LastName><ForeName>Dimitra</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, School of Health and Care Sciences, University of West Attica, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyrkou</LastName><ForeName>Giannoula A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, School of Health and Care Sciences, University of West Attica, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crna clinical training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family-centered care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurses' attitudes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parental presence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric cpr</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resuscitation team</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: The article processing charge (APC) was funded by the &#x201c;Special Account for Research Grants&#x201d; of the University of West Attica, Athens, Greece. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41140995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12548975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of nurses' and doctors' knowledge of basic and advanced life support resuscitation guidelines. Passali C, Pantazopoulos I, Dontas I, Patsaki A, Barouxis D, Troupis G, Xanthos T. Nurse Educ Pract. 2011;11:365&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21474382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiologists' knowledge of the 2005 American Heart Association Resuscitation Guidelines: The Athens Study. Pantazopoulos I, Aggelina A, Barouxis D, et al. Heart Lung. 2011;40:278&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21724040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basic life support skill retention of medical interns and the effect of clinical experience of cardiopulmonary resuscitation. Na JU, Sim MS, Jo IJ, Song HG, Song KJ. Emerg Med J. 2012;29:833&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of staff's retention of ACLS and BLS skills. Smith KK, Gilcreast D, Pierce K. Resuscitation. 2008;78:59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18406037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physicians' and nurses' retention of knowledge and skill after training in cardiopulmonary resuscitation. Gass DA, Curry L. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC1874955/ Can Med Assoc J. 1983;128:550&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1874955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6825021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motivation and adult learning: a survey among hospital personnel attending a CPR course. Hopstock LA. Resuscitation. 2008;76:425&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An evaluation of objective feedback in basic life support (BLS) training. Spooner BB, Fallaha JF, Kocierz L, Smith CM, Smith SC, Perkins GD. Resuscitation. 2007;73:417&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17275158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technique for chest compressions in adult CPR. Rajab TK, Pozner CN, Conrad C, Cohn LH, Schmitto JD. World J Emerg Surg. 2011;6:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3261806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of bystander cardiopulmonary resuscitation and survival following out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. Gallagher EJ, Lombardi G, Gennis P. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8568985/ JAMA. 1995;274:1922&#x2013;1925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8568985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chest compression rates during cardiopulmonary resuscitation are suboptimal: a prospective study during in-hospital cardiac arrest. Abella BS, Sandbo N, Vassilatos P, et al. Circulation. 2005;111:428&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quality of cardiopulmonary resuscitation during out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. Wik L, Kramer-Johansen J, Myklebust H, S&#xf8;reb&#xf8; H, Svensson L, Fellows B, Steen PA. JAMA. 2005;293:299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15657322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation feedback improves the quality of chest compression provided by hospital health care professionals. Pozner CN, Almozlino A, Elmer J, Poole S, McNamara D, Barash D. Am J Emerg Med. 2011;29:618&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20825844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of traditional versus high-fidelity simulation in the retention of ACLS knowledge. Lo BM, Devine AS, Evans DP, et al. Resuscitation. 2011;82:1440&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resuscitation training. Shepherd A. Postgrad Med J. 1995;71:143&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2398155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7746771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric basic and advanced life support: an update on practice and education. Al-Shamsi M, Al-Qurashi W, de Caen A, Bhanji F. Oman Med J. 2012;27:450&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3515044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23226814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of a newly developed media-supported 4-step approach for basic life support training. Sopka S, Biermann H, Rossaint R, et al. Scand J Trauma Resusc Emerg Med. 2012;20:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22647148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acquisition and retention of basic life support skills in an untrained population using a personal resuscitation manikin and video self-instruction (VSI) Nielsen AM, Henriksen MJ, Isbye DL, Lippert FK, Rasmussen LS. Resuscitation. 2010;81:1156&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Resuscitation Council Guidelines for Resuscitation 2010 Section 1. Executive summary. Nolan JP, Soar J, Zideman DA, et al. Resuscitation. 2010;81:1219&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing basic life support skills without an instructor: is it possible? Mpotos N, De Wever B, Valcke MA, Monsieurs KG. BMC Med Educ. 2012;12:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22824338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring virtual worlds for scenario-based repeated team training of cardiopulmonary resuscitation in medical students. Creutzfeldt J, Hedman L, Medin C, Heinrichs WL, Fell&#xe4;nder-Tsai L. J Med Internet Res. 2010;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20813717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact on retention: comparison of two CPR training programs. Gombeski WR Jr, Effron DM, Ramirez AG, Moore TJ. Am J Public Health. 1982;72:849&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1650359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7091483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basic life support skill retention by medical students: a comparison of two teaching curricula. Papaioannou A, Fraidakis O, Volakakis N, et al. Emerg Med J. 2010;27:762&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basic life support skills of high school students before and after cardiopulmonary resuscitation training: a longitudinal investigation. Meissner TM, Kloppe C, Hanefeld C. Scand J Trauma Resusc Emerg Med. 2012;20:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22502917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retention of mouth-to-mouth, mouth-to-mask and mouth-to-face shield ventilation. Paal P, Falk M, Gruber E, et al. Emerg Med J. 2008;25:42&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18156544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bystander CPR, ventricular fibrillation, and survival in witnessed, unmonitored out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. Swor RA, Jackson RE, Cynar M, et al. Ann Emerg Med. 1995;25:780&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7755200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmacy students' retention of knowledge and skills following training in automated external defibrillator use. Kopacek KB, Dopp AL, Dopp JM, Vardeny O, Sims JJ. Am J Pharm Educ. 2010;74:109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac arrest in children. Tress EE, Kochanek PM, Saladino RA, Manole MD. J Emerg Trauma Shock. 2010;3:267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20930971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Better outcome after pediatric resuscitation is still a dilemma. Sahu S, Kishore K, Lata I. J Emerg Trauma Shock. 2010;3:243&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20930968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiorespiratory arrest in children (out of hospital) Krmpotic K, Writer H. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3217789/ BMJ Clin Evid. 2010;2010:307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4684149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resuscitation training of paediatricians. Jewkes F, Phillips B. Arch Dis Child. 2003;88:118&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1719456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12538311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Resuscitation Council Guidelines for Resuscitation 2010 Section 6. Paediatric life support. Biarent D, Bingham R, Eich C, et al. Resuscitation. 2010;81:1364&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skill retention in adults and in children 3 months after basic life support training using a simple personal resuscitation manikin. Isbye DL, Meyhoff CS, Lippert FK, Rasmussen LS. Resuscitation. 2007;74:296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17376582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge and skill retention of in-service versus preservice nursing professionals following an informal training program in pediatric cardiopulmonary resuscitation: a repeated-measures quasiexperimental study. Sankar J, Vijayakanthi N, Sankar MJ, Dubey N. Biomed Res Int. 2013;2013:403415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3736513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23971033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paediatric cardiac resuscitation: can we do better? Tasker RC. Arch Dis Child. 2005;90:1102&#x2013;1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1720183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16243857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoretical knowledge and skill retention 4 months after a European Paediatric Life Support course. Charalampopoulos D, Karlis G, Barouxis D, et al. Eur J Emerg Med. 2016;23:56&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoretical knowledge and skill retention 3 and 6 months after a European Newborn Life Support provider course. Paliatsiou S, Xanthos T, Wyllie J, et al. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;49:83&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34089968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The advocacy role of nurses in cardiopulmonary resuscitation. T&#xed;scar-Gonz&#xe1;lez V, Gea-S&#xe1;nchez M, Blanco-Blanco J, Moreno-Casbas MT, Peter E. Nurs Ethics. 2020;27:333&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Experience of families during cardiopulmonary resuscitation in a pediatric intensive care unit. Tinsley C, Hill JB, Shah J, Zimmerman G, Wilson M, Freier K, Abd-Allah S. Pediatrics. 2008;122:0&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18829777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paediatric critical care nurses' attitudes and experiences of parental presence during cardiopulmonary resuscitation: a European survey. Fulbrook P, Latour JM, Albarran JW. Int J Nurs Stud. 2007;44:1238&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16836999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospital care of children in four countries. Shields L, Nixon J. J Adv Nurs. 2004;45:475&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15009350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family presence during cardiopulmonary resuscitation and invasive procedures in children. Ferreira CA, Balbino FS, Balieiro MM, Mandetta MA. Rev Paul Pediatr. 2014;32:107&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family presence during resuscitation - the experiences and views of Polish nurses. Gutysz-Wojnicka A, Ozga D, Dyk D, M&#x119;drzycka-D&#x105;browska W, Wojtaszek M, Albarran J. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2018;46:44&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family presence during resuscitation and invasive procedures: physicians' and nurses' attitudes working in pediatric departments in Greece. Vavarouta A, Xanthos T, Papadimitriou L, Kouskouni E, Iacovidou N. Resuscitation. 2011;82:713&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21398020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence updates 2023: parental presence during pediatric resuscitation. ILCOR ILCOR. https://ilcor.org/uploads/EIT-2025-Appendix-B-Evidence-Updates.pdf International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation. 2023:1&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nursing care through the perception of hospitalized children. Santos PM, Silva LF, Depianti JR, Cursino EG, Ribeiro CA. Rev Bras Enferm. 2016;69:646&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27508468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trust in the nurse: findings from a survey of hospitalised children. Sheehan R, Fealy G. J Clin Nurs. 2020;29:4289&#x2013;4299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32815219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauchamp TL, Childress JF. New York: Oxford University Press; 2019. Principles of Biomedical Ethics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nursing staff attitudes and behaviours regarding family presence in the hospital setting. Fisher C, Lindhorst H, Matthews T, Munroe DJ, Paulin D, Scott D. J Adv Nurs. 2008;64:615&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19120576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caring for dying children: assessing the needs of the pediatric palliative care nurse. Morgan D. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19472671/ Pediatr Nurs. 2009;35:86&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19472671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortality in parents after death of a child in Denmark: a nationwide follow-up study. Li J, Precht DH, Mortensen PB, Olsen J. Lancet. 2003;1:363&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12573371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parents&#x2019; experience during a child&#x2019;s resuscitation: getting through it. Stewart SA. J Pediatr Nurs. 2019;47:58&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does witnessing resuscitation help parents come to terms with the death of their child? A review of the literature. Shaw K, Ritchie D, Adams G. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2011;27:253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family presence during resuscitation and invasive procedures in pediatric critical care: a systematic review. McAlvin SS, Carew-Lyons A. Am J Crit Care. 2014;23:477&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25362671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The experiences of parents witnessing their child's resuscitation in hospital. Brunt J, Alnababtah K. Br J Nurs. 2023;32:136&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parents' and healthcare professionals' experiences and perceptions of parental readiness for resuscitation in Iranian paediatric hospitals: a qualitative study. Ghavi A, Hassankhani H, Powers K, Arshadi-Bostanabad M, Namdar Areshtanab H, Heidarzadeh M. BMJ Open. 2022;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35613813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Part 4: Pediatric basic and advanced life support: 2020 American Heart Association guidelines for Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation and Emergency Cardiovascular Care. Topjian AA, Raymond TT, Atkins D, et al. Circulation. 2020;142:0&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Resuscitation Council Guidelines 2021: paediatric life support. Van de Voorde P, Turner NM, Djakow J, et al. Resuscitation. 2021;161:327&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>