<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41665740</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2509-2723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>GeroScience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Geroscience</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise and brain aging clocks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11357-026-02141-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Exercise improves cognition, mental wellbeing, and protects against neurodegeneration. However, most prior neuroscience studies have focused on localized brain changes without quantifying their impact on brain ageing. To quantify the effect of resistance training on brain health using longitudinal assessments. Using resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging (rs-fMRI) data from 2,433 healthy adults, we trained models to predict brain age and applied them to 309 participants from the Live Active Successful Aging (LISA) randomized trial. Participants in this trial were assigned to one of three groups: heavy-resistance training, moderate-intensity training, or a non-exercise control group. They underwent repeated rs-fMRI and physical fitness assessments at baseline, with follow-up assessments at 1 and 2&#xa0;years. First, we examined changes in local connectivity between groups. Second, we assessed the impact of resistance training on brain ageing using brain clock models trained on the independent dataset of 2,433 adults. Local analyses revealed increased prefrontal functional connectivity following heavy training, while moderate- and heavy-resistance training significantly reduced brain age (-1.4 to -2.3&#xa0;years, p<sub>FDR</sub>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). These effects emerged at the whole-brain level, rather than within isolated networks such as the default mode, motor, or cerebellar systems. These findings suggest a hierarchical organization of brain aging, driven by distributed network-level changes and expressed through focal regional patterns. Resistance exercise training decelerates brain ageing, as indexed by brain clocks, reinforcing its role as a preventive strategy for brain health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez-Gomez</LastName><ForeName>Raul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Latin American Brain Health Institute (BrainLat), Universidad Adolfo Iba&#xf1;ez, Santiago de Chile, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology and Neurosurgery Department, Montreal Neurological Institute, Montreal, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demnitz</LastName><ForeName>Naiara</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital - Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coronel</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Latin American Brain Health Institute (BrainLat), Universidad Adolfo Iba&#xf1;ez, Santiago de Chile, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trinity College Dublin, The University of Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Global Brain Health Institute (GBHI), Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gates</LastName><ForeName>Anne Theil</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen (ISMC), Bispebjerg Hospital, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kjaer</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen (ISMC), Bispebjerg Hospital, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences, Copenhagen University, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siebner</LastName><ForeName>Hartwig R</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital - Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boraxbekk</LastName><ForeName>Carl-Johan</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen (ISMC), Bispebjerg Hospital, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark. boraxbekk@sund.ku.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences, Copenhagen University, Copenhagen, Denmark. boraxbekk@sund.ku.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg, Copenhagen, Denmark. boraxbekk@sund.ku.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibanez</LastName><ForeName>Agustin M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6758-5101</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Latin American Brain Health Institute (BrainLat), Universidad Adolfo Iba&#xf1;ez, Santiago de Chile, Chile. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trinity College Dublin, The University of Dublin, Dublin, Ireland. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Global Brain Health Institute (GBHI), Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience Center, Universidad de San Andr&#xe9;s, Buenos Aires, Argentina. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biophysics, School of Medicine, Istanbul Medipol University, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barcelona&#x3b2;eta Brain Research Center (BBRC), Pasqual Maragall Foundation, Barcelona, Spain. agustin.ibanez@gbhi.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG057234</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG075775</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R380-2021-1269</GrantID><Agency>H. Lundbeck A/S</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Geroscience</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101686284</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2509-2723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain clocks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: Hartwig R. Siebner has received honoraria as speaker and consultant from Lundbeck AS, Denmark, and as editor (Neuroimage Clinical) from Elsevier Publishers, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. He has received royalties as book editor from Springer Publishers, Stuttgart, Germany, Oxford University Press, Oxford, UK, and from Gyldendal Publishers, Copenhagen, Denmark.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41665740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-026-02141-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11357-026-02141-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Boa Sorte Silva NC, Barha CK, Erickson KI, Kramer AF, Liu-Ambrose T. Physical exercise, cognition, and brain health in aging. Trends Neurosci. 2024;47(6):402&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38811309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonasson LS, Nyberg L, Kramer AF, Lundquist A, Riklund K, Boraxbekk C-J. Aerobic exercise intervention, cognitive performance, and brain structure: results from the physical influences on brain in aging (PHIBRA) study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2017;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Voss MW, Prakash RS, Basak C, Szabo A, Chaddock L, et al. Exercise training increases size of hippocampus and improves memory. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108(7):3017&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3041121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1015950108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demnitz N, Hulme OJ, Siebner HR, Kjaer M, Ebmeier KP, Boraxbekk CJ, et al. Characterising the covariance pattern between lifestyle factors and structural brain measures: a multivariable replication study of two independent ageing cohorts. Neurobiol Aging. 2023;131:115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37619515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2023.07.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flodin P, Jonasson LS, Riklund K, Nyberg L, Boraxbekk CJ. Does aerobic exercise influence intrinsic brain activity? An aerobic exercise intervention among healthy old adults. Front Aging Neurosci. 2017. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00267 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2017.00267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5554511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demnitz N, Baar&#xe9; WFC, Binnewies J, Brandmaier AM, Fjell AM, Gates AT, et al. No significant association between self-reported physical activity and brain volumes in women and men from five European cohorts. Sci Rep. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-98601-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-98601-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40447870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12125180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maass A, D&#xfc;zel S, Goerke M, Becke A, Sobieray U, Neumann K, et al. Vascular hippocampal plasticity after aerobic exercise in older adults. Mol Psychiatry. 2015;20(5):585&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25311366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2014.114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Cederwald BF, Johansson J, Riklund K, Karalija N, Boraxbekk C-J. White matter lesion load determines exercise-induced dopaminergic plasticity and working memory gains in aging. Transl Psychiatry. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-022-02270-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-022-02270-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36720847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9889313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman CM, Esteban-Cornejo I, Brown B, Bender CM, Erickson KI. Effects of Exercise on Brain and Cognition Across Age Groups and Health States. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(7):533&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9068803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2020.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demnitz N, Gates AT, Mortensen EL, Garde E, Wimmelmann CL, Siebner HR, et al. Is it all in the baseline? Trajectories of chair stand performance over 4 years and their association with grey matter structure in older adults. Hum Brain Mapp. 2023;44(11):4299&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37219945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10318211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.26346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillman CH, Erickson KI, Kramer AF. Be smart, exercise your heart: exercise effects on brain and cognition. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008;9(1):58&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18094706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer AF. How to better study the associations between physical activity, exercise, and cognitive and brain health. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(3):e215153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.5153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greendale GA, Han W, Huang M, Upchurch DM, Karvonen-Gutierrez C, Avis NE, et al. Longitudinal assessment of physical activity and cognitive outcomes among women at midlife. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(3):e213227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8013795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.3227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moguilner S, Baez S, Hernandez H, Migeot J, Legaz A, Gonzalez-Gomez R, et al. Brain clocks capture diversity and disparities in aging and dementia across geographically diverse populations. Nat Med. 2024;30:3646&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian YE, Cropley V, Maier AB, Lautenschlager NT, Breakspear M, Zalesky A. Heterogeneous aging across multiple organ systems and prediction of chronic disease and mortality. Nat Med. 2023;29(5):1221&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-023-02296-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baecker L, Garcia-Dias R, Vieira S, Scarpazza C, Mechelli A. Machine learning for brain age prediction: introduction to methods and clinical applications. EBioMedicine. 2021;72:103600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34614461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8498228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legaz A, Moguilner S, Barttfeld P, Cuadros Castro J, Galv&#xe1;n Rial DS, Migeot J, et al. The exposome of brain aging across 34 countries. Nature medicine. 2026; Accepted.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez A, Duran-Aniotz C, Migeot J, Baez S, Fittipaldi S, Coronel-Oliveros C, et al. Computational whole-body-exposome models for global precision brain health. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):11078. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-67448-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41372244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12698732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-67448-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronel-Oliveros C, Migeot J, Lehue F, Amoruso L, Kowalczyk-Gr&#x119;bska N, Jakubowska N, et al. Creative experiences and brain clocks. Nat Commun. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64173-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-64173-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41372244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12698732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoruso L, Hernandez H, Santamaria-Garcia H, Moguilner S, Legaz A, Prado P, et al. Multilingualism protects against accelerated aging in cross-sectional and longitudinal analyses of 27 European countries. Nat Aging. 2025;5(11):2340&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43587-025-01000-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dun&#xe5;s T, W&#xe5;hlin A, Nyberg L, Boraxbekk C-J. Multimodal image analysis of apparent brain age identifies physical fitness as predictor of brain maintenance. Cereb Cortex. 2021;31(7):3393&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33690853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8196254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhab019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch-Ibenfeldt M, Theil Gates A, Karlog K, Demnitz N, Kjaer M, Boraxbekk CJ. Heavy resistance training at retirement age induces 4-year lasting beneficial effects in muscle strength: a long-term follow-up of an RCT. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2024;10(2):e001899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38911477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11191791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2024-001899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstr&#xf6;m Levik S, Simonsson E, Hedlund M, Rosendahl E, Boraxbekk CJ. Working memory improvements following supramaximal HIT predicted by increased prefrontal activation and leg strength gains. Cereb Cortex. 2025;35(10):bhaf277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhaf277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen CS, Garde E, Reislev NL, Wimmelmann CL, Bieler T, Ziegler AK, et al. Physical activity as intervention for age-related loss of muscle mass and function: protocol for a randomised controlled trial (the LISA study). BMJ Open. 2016;6(12):e012951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27913559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5168596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2016-012951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gylling AT, Eriksen CS, Garde E, Wimmelmann CL, Reislev NL, Bieler T, et al. The influence of prolonged strength training upon muscle and fat in healthy and chronically diseased older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2020;136:110939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2020.110939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteban O, Markiewicz CJ, Blair RW, Moodie CA, Isik AI, Erramuzpe A, et al. fMRIPrep: a robust preprocessing pipeline for functional MRI. Nat Methods. 2019;16(1):111&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30532080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41592-018-0235-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N, Landeau B, Papathanassiou D, Crivello F, Etard O, Delcroix N, et al. Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. Neuroimage. 2002;15:273&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2001.0978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Gomez R, Cruzat J, Hern&#xe1;ndez H, Migeot J, Legaz A, Santamaria-Garc&#xed;a H, et al. Qualitative and quantitative educational disparities and brain signatures in healthy aging and dementia across global settings. Eclinmed. 2025;82:103187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez&#x2010;Gomez R, Legaz A, Moguilner S, Cruzat J, Hern&#xe1;ndez H, Baez S, et al. Educational disparities in brain health and dementia across Latin America and the United States. Alzheimers Dement. 2024;20(9):5912&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39136296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11497666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.14085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto-Castanon A. Handbook of functional connectivity magnetic resonance imaging methods in CONN. Hilbert Press; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56441/hilbertpress.2207.6598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tari AR, Walker TL, Huuha AM, Sando SB, Wisloff U. Neuroprotective mechanisms of exercise and the importance of fitness for healthy brain ageing. Lancet. 2025;405(10484):1093&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40157803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(25)00184-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Zhang H, Liang J, Huang J, Chen N. Exercise suppresses neuroinflammation for alleviating Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Neuroinflammation. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-023-02753-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-023-02753-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38115100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10729399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Vetrovsky T, Balbim GM, Sorte Silva NCB, Manca A, Deriu F, et al. The impact of aerobic and resistance training intensity on markers of neuroplasticity in health and disease. Ageing Res Rev. 2022;80:101698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35853549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2022.101698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulraheem Y. Unveiling the significance and challenges of integrating prevention levels in healthcare practice. J Prim Care Community Health. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1177/21501319231186500 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501319231186500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37449436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10350749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y, Dan X, Babbar M, Wei Y, Hasselbalch SG, Croteau DL, et al. Ageing as a risk factor for neurodegenerative disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2019;15(10):565&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31501588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41582-019-0244-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman NP, Robbins TW. The role of prefrontal cortex in cognitive control and executive function. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2022;47(1):72&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-021-01132-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon V, D&#x2019;Esposito M. The role of PFC networks in cognitive control and executive function. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2022;47(1):90&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-021-01152-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagni V, Drogos LL, Tyndall AV, Davenport MH, Anderson TJ, Eskes GA, et al. Aerobic exercise improves cognition and cerebrovascular regulation in older adults. Neurology. 2020;94(21):e2245&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7357295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000009478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein AM, Voss MW, Prakash RS, Chaddock L, Szabo A, White SM, et al. The association between aerobic fitness and executive function is mediated by prefrontal cortex volume. Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26(5):811&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22172477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2011.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold F, T&#xf6;rpel A, Schega L, M&#xfc;ller NG. Functional and/or structural brain changes in response to resistance exercises and resistance training lead to cognitive improvements &#x2013; a systematic review. Eur. Rev. Aging Phys. Act. 2019;16(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffener J, Habeck C, O&#x2019;Shea D, Razlighi Q, Bherer L, Stern Y. Differences between chronological and brain age are related to education and self-reported physical activity. Neurobiol Aging. 2016;40:138&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26973113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4792330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2016.01.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann T, Van Der Meer D, Doan NT, Schwarz E, Lund MJ, Agartz I, et al. Common brain disorders are associated with heritable patterns of apparent aging of the brain. Nat Neurosci. 2019;22(10):1617&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6823048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-019-0471-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole JH, Ritchie SJ, Bastin ME, Vald&#xe9;s Hern&#xe1;ndez MC, Mu&#xf1;oz Maniega S, Royle N, et al. Brain age predicts mortality. Mol Psychiatry. 2018;23(5):1385&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28439103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2017.62</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott ML, Belsky DW, Knodt AR, Ireland D, Melzer TR, Poulton R, et al. Brain-age in midlife is associated with accelerated biological aging and cognitive decline in a longitudinal birth cohort. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26(8):3829&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31822815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-019-0626-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moguilner S, Baez S, Hernandez H, Migeot J, Legaz A, Gonzalez-Gomez R, et al. Brain clocks capture diversity and disparities in aging and dementia across geographically diverse populations. Nat Med. 2024;30:3646&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39187698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11645278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-03209-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wen J, Erus G, Govindarajan ST, Melhem R, Mamourian E, et al. Brain aging patterns in a large and diverse cohort of 49,482 individuals. Nat Med. 2024;30(10):3015&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11483219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-03144-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Cao Z, Zhang J, Li D, Wang Y, Xu C. Accelerometer-measured physical activity and neuroimaging-driven brain age. Health Data Sci. 2025;5:0257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40321644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/hds.0257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donovan G, Petermann-Rocha F, Ferrari G, Medina C, Ochoa-Rosales C, Sarmiento OLL, et al. Associations of the &#x2018;weekend warrior&#x2019; physical activity pattern with mild dementia: findings from the Mexico City Prospective Study. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(5):325&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39472031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2024-108460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Kirk BJC, Nosaka K. Resistance exercise minimal dose strategies for increasing muscle strength in the general population: an overview. Sports Med. 2024;54(5):1139&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38509414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11127831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02009-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman CM, Cohen J, Lehman ME, Erickson KI. Mediators of physical activity on neurocognitive function: A review at multiple levels of analysis. Front Hum Neurosci 2016;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noone J, Mucinski JM, DeLany JP, Sparks LM, Goodpaster BH. Understanding the variation in exercise responses to guide personalized physical activity prescriptions. Cell Metab. 2024;36(4):702&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38262420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2023.12.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson ML, Allen JM, Beavers DP, Collins LM, Davidson KW, Erickson KI, et al. Understanding heterogeneity of responses to, and optimizing clinical efficacy of, exercise training in older adults: NIH NIA Workshop summary. GeroScience. 2023;45(1):569&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36242693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-022-00668-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>