<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41552783</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-744X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2026</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>TheScientificWorldJournal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ScientificWorldJournal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Tool Velocity Ratio on Welding Loads and Mechanical Properties in Friction Stir-Welded AA7075/AA2024 Plates.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6123056</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6123056</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6123056</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/tswj/6123056</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The emphasis on dissimilar joining of aluminum alloys has increased due to the growing need for lightweight, highly durable structures in the transportation and aerospace industries. For these applications, friction stir welding (FSW), a solid-state joining technology that offers better structural integrity than traditional fusion techniques, has proven very successful. The force-torque behavior and mechanical characteristics of friction stir welded dissimilar aluminum alloys, AA7075 and AA2024, with and without titanium diboride (TiB<sub>2</sub>) reinforcement, are investigated in this work in relation to the tool velocity ratio (<i>&#x3c9;</i>/<i>v</i>). With a constant rotational speed of 1000&#x2009;rpm and a 1.5&#xb0; tilt angle, a cylindrical taper tool (3&#x2009;mm tip, 6&#x2009;mm length) was used. The traverse speeds were varied to 1, 2, 3, and 4&#x2009;mm/s, yielding velocity ratios of 1000, 500, 333, and 250, respectively. To evaluate the impact of the TiB<sub>2</sub> powder on joint performance, it was injected via machined grooves at the faying surfaces. The microstructural improvement, primarily grain refinement through dynamic recrystallization and Zener pinning effects from TiB<sub>2</sub> particles, significantly enhanced the hardness and tensile strength of the welds. Enhanced particle dispersion and metallurgical bonding were responsible for the superior mechanical response. Because of better metallurgical bonding, grain refinement, and particle dispersion, reinforced welds demonstrated superior characteristics in microstructural, tensile, and hardness tests, particularly at higher velocity ratios (lower traverse speeds). At a velocity ratio of 1000 (1&#x2009;mm/s), the reinforced samples showed the highest tensile strength (219.5&#x2009;MPa), elongation (6.9%), and improved microhardness, resulting in peak joint performance. Conversely, unreinforced welds with coarser microstructures and worse mechanical properties were found at lower velocity ratios. These results provide practical advice for dissimilar alloy FSW applications in advanced engineering systems and validate that a high tool velocity ratio in conjunction with TiB<sub>2</sub> reinforcement is essential for maximizing weld integrity and mechanical behavior.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Mutyala Rama Durga Rao et al. The Scientific World Journal published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Mutyala Rama Durga</ForeName><Initials>MRD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering Research Centre, Sasi Institute of Technology and Engineering, Tadepalligudem, India, sasi.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Bunga Kiran</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering Research Centre, Sasi Institute of Technology and Engineering, Tadepalligudem, India, sasi.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Billa</LastName><ForeName>Kiran Kumar</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6835-0996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering Research Centre, Sasi Institute of Technology and Engineering, Tadepalligudem, India, sasi.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhowmik</LastName><ForeName>Abhijit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Additive Manufacturing, Mechanical Engineering, SIMATS, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai, India, saveetha.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University, Rajpura, Punjab, India, chitkara.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashok</LastName><ForeName>N</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-8553-2929</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Jimma Institute of Technology, Jimma, Ethiopia, ju.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ScientificWorldJournal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101131163</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1537-744X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AA2024</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AA7075</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FSW</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TiB2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tool velocity ratio</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41552783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12809051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/tswj/6123056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">TSWJ6123056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chakravarthi G., Giridharan K., Stalin B., Padmanabhan S., Sekar S., Nagaprasad N., Jule L. T., and Krishnaraj R., Investigation on the Effect of Process Parameters on Mechanical and Microstructural Properties of AA8011 Similar FSW Weld Joints, Advances in Mechanical Engineering. (2022) 14, no. 7, 16878132221112146, 10.1177/16878132221112146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16878132221112146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S. P., Bhowmik A., and Ashok N., Exploring Drilling Control Variables for Enhanced Electric Discharge Machining Performance in Aluminum Hybrid Nanocomposite, Engineering Reports. (2025) 7, no. 9, e70403, 10.1002/eng2.70403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eng2.70403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesharwani G. S., Billa K. K., Verma J., Garg S. K., Katiyar J. K., and Kumar S., Influence of Tool Velocity Ratio on Force-Torque and Mechanical Properties of Friction Stir Welded 2050-T84 Al-Li Alloy Plates, Physica Scripta. (2024) 99, no. 7, 075008, 10.1088/1402-4896/ad505f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1402-4896/ad505f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billa K. K. and Murthy B. K., Prediction of Performance-Emission Profile With Varying Nozzle Injection Pressures of a Diesel&#x2013;Biodiesel Fueled Diesel Engine by Adopting Artificial Neural Networks, Proceedings of the 2024 International Conference on Social and Sustainable Innovations in Technology and Engineering (SASI-ITE), 2024, IEEE, 29&#x2013;34, 10.1109/SASI-ITE58663.2024.00013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/SASI-ITE58663.2024.00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumawat A., Dhanka S., Kumar A., Sharma A., Kaur S., Kumar N., Bhowmik A., Kumar A., Pant R., and Singh H., Investigation of Structural and Dielectric Characteristics of La-Doped BZT Ceramics, Journal of Materials Science: Materials in Electronics. (2025) 36, no. 28, 10.1007/s10854-025-15841-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10854-025-15841-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh H., Sen B., Kumar N., Singh B., Bhowmik A., Kumar A., Kumar K., and John V., Artificial Neural Network Modeling and Experimental Analysis of Erosion Resistance in Tungsten Carbide-Coated CA6NM Stainless Steel, International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology. (2025) 139, no. 5-6, 2327&#x2013;2347, 10.1007/s00170-025-16018-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-025-16018-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanavel V. and Ravichandran M., Experimental Investigation on Mechanical Properties of AA7075-AlN composites, Materials Testing. (2019) 61, no. 6, 554&#x2013;558, 10.3139/120.111354, 2-s2.0-85067110036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3139/120.111354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamer F. B., &#xc7;anak&#xe7;&#x131; A., and &#xc7;elebi M., Impact of Thixoforging and Post-Thixoforging T6 Heat Treatment on the Microstructural, Mechanical, and Tribological Properties of AA2024 Alloy Fabricated by Powder Metallurgy, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. (2025) 174, 106239, 10.1016/j.jtice.2025.106239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtice.2025.106239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billa K. K., Deb M., Sastry G. R. K., and Dey S., Experimental Investigation on Dispersing Graphene-Oxide in Biodiesel/Diesel/Higher Alcohol Blends on Diesel Engine Using Response Surface Methodology, Environmental Technology. (2022) 43, no. 20, 3131&#x2013;3148, 10.1080/09593330.2021.1916091, 33843482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593330.2021.1916091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giridharan K., Chakravarthi G., Karthick S., Muthu Kumaran S., Padmanaban S., and Kabeerr M., Investigation on Mechanical Properties of AA6082-AA7075 Friction Stir Welded Dissimilar Aluminum Alloys, Innovative Design, Analysis and Development Practices in Aerospace and Automotive Engineering: Proceedings of I-DAD 2020, 2020, Springer Singapore, 295&#x2013;302, 10.1007/978-981-15-6619-6_31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-15-6619-6_31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He P., Kong H., Liu Q., Ferry M., Kruzic J. J., and Li X., Elevated Temperature Mechanical Properties of TiCN Reinforced AlSi10Mg Fabricated by Laser Powder Bed Fusion Additive Manufacturing, Materials Science and Engineering A. (2021) 811, 141025, 10.1016/j.msea.2021.141025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2021.141025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Zheng Y., 
Xu L., 
Chen Z., 
Wang X., 
Xue X., 
Xiao S., 
Tian J., and 
Chen Y., Effects of Hybrid Reinforcements to the High Temperature Tensile and Creep Properties of a (TiB+TiC+Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>)/<i>&#x3b1;</i>-Ti composite, Materials Characterization. (2022) 190, 112067, 10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen B., Murali Krishnam Raju V. V., Kumar R., Ramachandran T., Jacob A., Nanda J., Singh G., Bhowmik A., and Panda J. K., Technoeconomic and Environmental Analysis of Cryogenic and MQL-Assisted Machining of Hastelloy X, Scientific Reports. (2025) 15, no. 1, 10.1038/s41598-025-07526-0, 40595198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-07526-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12214503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40595198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Dawes C. J. and 
Thomas W. M., Friction Stir Process Welds Aluminum alloys, Welding Journal. (1995) 74, no. 3, 41&#x2013;45, https://cir.nii.ac.jp/crid/1573387449011970304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathinasuriyan C., Puviyarasan M., Sankar R., and Selvakumar V., Effect of Process Parameters on Weld Geometry and Mechanical Properties in Friction Stir Welding of AA2024 and AA7075 Alloys, Journal of Alloys and Metallurgical Systems. (2024) 7, 100091, 10.1016/j.jalmes.2024.100091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalmes.2024.100091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih O. S., Ou H., Sun W., and McCartney D., A Review of Friction Stir Welding of Aluminium Matrix Composites, Materials &amp; Design. (2015) 86, 61&#x2013;71, 10.1016/j.matdes.2015.07.071, 2-s2.0-84942256846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2015.07.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi A., Jhaveri N., Gor M., and Sahlot P., Parwani A. K., Ramkumar P., Abhishek K., and Yadav S. K., A Review on Improving the Surface Characteristics of Aluminum Alloy via Friction Stir Processing, Recent Advances in Mechanical Infrastructure, 2022, Springer, Lecture Notes in Intelligent Transportation and Infrastructure, 10.1007/978-981-16-7660-4_38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-16-7660-4_38</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feddal I., Chairi M., and Di Bella G., Analysis of Friction Stir Welding of Aluminum Alloys, Meta. (2025) 15, no. 5, 10.3390/met15050532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met15050532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ma S. M., 
Zhang P., 
Ji G., 
Chen Z., 
Sun G. A., 
Zhong S. Y., 
Ji V., and 
Wang H. W., Microstructure and Mechanical Properties of Friction Stir Processed Al&#x2013;Mg&#x2013;Si Alloys Dispersion-Strengthened by Nanosized TiB<sub>2</sub> Particles, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. (2014) 616, 128&#x2013;136, 10.1016/j.jallcom.2014.07.092, 2-s2.0-84905573866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2014.07.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi S. G. and Eghbali B., Evolution of High Strength and Ductile Ultrafine Grained Dual Phase Superferrite Low Carbon V-Nb-Mo Steel, Materials Science and Engineering: A. (2017) 705, 32&#x2013;41, 10.1016/j.msea.2017.07.094, 2-s2.0-85027703927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2017.07.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo H., Wu T., Wang P., Zhao F., Wang H., and Li Y., Numerical Simulation of Material Flow and Analysis of Welding Characteristics in Friction Stir Welding Process, Meta. (2019) 9, no. 6, 10.3390/met9060621, 2-s2.0-85067983303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met9060621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark A. and Ragai I., Adaptive Torque Control for Process Optimization in Friction Stir Welding of Aluminum 6061-T6 Using a Horizontal 5-Axis CNC Machine, Journal Of Manufacturing And Materials Processing. (2025) 9, no. 7, 10.3390/jmmp9070232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmmp9070232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Murr L. E., Niou C. S., McClure J. C., and Vega F. R., Microstructural Aspects of the Friction-Stir Welding of 6061-T6 Aluminum, Scripta Materialia. (1997) 37, no. 3, 355&#x2013;361, 10.1016/S1359-6462(97)00093-6, 2-s2.0-0031210296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1359-6462(97)00093-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Ma Z. Y., and Chen L., Effect of Particle Distribution on Microstructure and Mechanical Properties of Friction Stir Welded Al&#x2013;SiC Composite, Composites Part A: Applied Science and Manufacturing. (2012) 43, no. 2, 456&#x2013;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avinash P., Manikandan M., Arivazhagan N., Ramkumar K. D., and Narayana S., Influence of Tool Design and Reinforcement on Dissimilar Aluminum Alloy FSW Joints, Materials Today: Proceedings. (2022) 56, 1124&#x2013;1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd Elnabi M. M., El Mokadem A., and Osman T., Optimization of Process Parameters for Friction Stir Welding of Dissimilar Aluminum Alloys Using Different Taguchi Arrays, International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology. (2022) 121, no. 5-6, 3935&#x2013;3964, 10.1007/s00170-022-09531-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-022-09531-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathinasuriyan C., Puviyarasan M., Sankar R., and Selvakumar V., Optimization of FSW Parameters for Dissimilar Aluminum Alloys Using Experimental Design, Materials and Manufacturing Processes. (2021) 36, no. 7, 854&#x2013;865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinodh D. and Lakshmaiya N., Integration of Ceramic Reinforcements in AA5083 Composites for Enhanced Mechanical and Thermal Properties in Friction Stir Welding, Engineering Research Express. (2025) 7, no. 3, 035519, 10.1088/2631-8695/adef90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/adef90</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Huang G., Cao Y., Zhu Y., and Liu Q., On the Microstructure and Mechanical Properties of Similar and Dissimilar AA7075 and AA2024 Friction Stir Welding Joints: Effect of Rotational Speed, Journal of Manufacturing Processes. (2019) 37, 470&#x2013;487, 10.1016/j.jmapro.2018.12.014, 2-s2.0-85058952575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2018.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Singh T., 
Tiwari S. K., and 
Shukla D. K., Influence of Nano-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> Particles on Mechanical Performance of FSW Joints, Defence Technology. (2021) 17, no. 1, 203&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>