<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41170266</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiological Study of Lactose- and Non-lactose-Fermenting Gram-Negative Bacterial Isolates From Clinical Specimens in the Middle Al-Furat Region of Iraq.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93461</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93461</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93461</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93461</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The study included a collection of 682 clinical samples from the hospital laboratories all over Iraq's Middle Euphrates region, which encompasses the governorates of Najaf, Karbala, Babylon, and Diwaniyah. The study lasted for seven months, from April 2022 to the end of October 2022, and aimed to isolate and diagnose Gram-negative lactose-fermentative bacterial species while determining the extent of multidrug resistance (MDR) of the isolated bacteria to antibiotics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">Swabs were quickly taken to the lab in a special solution and placed on different types of growth media, like blood agar, nutrition agar, and MacConkey agar, and then the Vitek Compact 2 system was also used to confirm the identification of the bacteria. Susceptibility to antimicrobials was assessed according to the CLSI guideline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Six hundred and eighty-two Gram-negative bacterial isolates revealed that 468 (68.6%) were lactose-fermenting species, including E. coli (47.7%, 325/682), Klebsiella pneumoniae (13.9%, 95/682), and Enterobacter cloacae (7.0%, 48/682), while 214 (31.4%) were non-lactose-fermenters, predominantly Pseudomonas aeruginosa (10.6%, 72/682), Acinetobacter baumannii (8.5%, 58/682), Salmonella typhi (8.9%, 61/682), and Proteus mirabilis (3.4%, 23/682). Antibiotic susceptibility testing showed the highest efficacy for ampicillin (84.2%) and amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (75.5%), followed by cefotaxime (75.5%), ceftazidime (71%), imipenem (58.4%), and meropenem (63.8%), with all isolates exhibiting significant resistance (p&#xa0;&lt; 0.0001) Conclusion: This work emphasizes the place of the Gram-negative bacteria as nosocomial and community-acquired pathogens. The rates of resistance are in accordance with a public health problem in the Middle Euphrates region.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Alaltoganee et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alaltoganee</LastName><ForeName>Ehsan A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine "Ibn El Jazzar" of Sousse, Sousse, TUN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muhammed</LastName><ForeName>Hayder A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, University of Kerbala, Kerbala, IRQ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotics pathogen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactose fermentation g-ve bacteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidrug resistant (mdr)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-lactose fermentation g-ve bacteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nosocomial epidemiology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ethics Research Centre in the Research Unit/National Centre for Training and Human Development/Training and Development Center issued approval 29932. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41170266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12569721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bacterial resistance of the most locally isolated pathogens to commonly used antibiotics in Kerbala/Iraq. Omran TZ, Ali BA, Ali HM, Ali M. Multidiscip Sci J. 2024;6:96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pneumonia. Torres A, Cilloniz C, Niederman MS, Men&#xe9;ndez R, Chalmers JD, Wunderink RG, van der Poll T. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2021;7:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of multiple drug resistance Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae isolated from patients with urinary tract infections. Jalil MB, Al Atbee MY. J Clin Lab Anal. 2022;36:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9459318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35870190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current treatment strategies against multidrug-resistant bacteria: a review. Parmanik A, Das S, Kar B, Bose A, Dwivedi GR, Pandey MM. http://10.1007. Curr Microbiol. 2022;79:388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9633024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36329256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practical Guidance for Clinical Microbiology Laboratories: updated guidance for processing respiratory tract samples from people with cystic fibrosis. Saiman L, Waters V, LiPuma JJ, et al. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2024;37:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11391703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39158301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosocomial infection and antibiotic-resistant threat in the Middle East. Nimer NA. Infect Drug Resist. 2022;15:631&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8887909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35241915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of typing techniques as molecular epidemiology tools for bacterial characterization. Almasian-Tehrani N, Alebouyeh M, Armin S, Soleimani N, Azimi L, Shaker-Darabad R. Cell Mol Biomed Rep. 2021;1:69&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotic resistance patterns of common uropathogens isolated from females at Zakho city, Kurdistan region, Iraq. Issa FA. Sci J University of Zakho. 2024;18:490&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbapenem resistance in Acinetobacter baumannii, and their importance in hospital-acquired infections: a scientific review. Nguyen M, Joshi SG. https://doi.org/10.1111/jam.15130. J Appl Microbiol. 2021;131:2715&#x2013;2738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of neuroinflammation in glaucoma: an update on molecular mechanisms and new therapeutic options. Rolle T, Ponzetto A, Malinverni L. Front Neurol. 2020;11:612422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of multidrug-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa in the Middle East and North Africa Region. Al-Orphaly M, Hadi HA, Eltayeb FK, Al-Hail H, Samuel BG, Sultan AA, Skariah S. mSphere. 2021;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in 2019: a systematic analysis. Lancet. 2022;399:629&#x2013;655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of ESKAPE pathogens in the environment: antibiotic resistance status, community-acquired infection and risk to human health. Denissen J, Reyneke B, Waso-Reyneke M, Havenga B, Barnard T, Khan S, Khan W. Int J Hyg Environ Health. 2022;244:114006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35841823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bioremediation potential of hydrocarbon degrading bacteria: isolation, characterization, and assessment. Hossain MF, Akter MA, Sohan MS, Sultana DN, Reza MA, Hoque KM. Saudi J Biol Sci. 2022;29:211&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8717088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35002411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molecular identification of antibiotic resistance genes in E. coli isolated from dairy cattle. Omara W, Mustapha A, Salama H. Benha Vet Med J. 2024;47:124&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molecular characterization of antibiotic resistance in Escherichia coli strains from a dairy cattle farm and its surroundings. Navajas-Benito EV, Alonso CA, Sanz S, et al. J Sci Food Agric. 2017;97:362&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of MicroScan and VITEK 2 systems for susceptibility testing of Enterobacterales with updated breakpoints. Richter SS, Dominguez EL, Hupp AA, Griffis M, MacVane SH. J Clin Microbiol. 2025;63:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12153288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40304515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in microbial composition and interaction patterns of female urogenital tract and rectum in response to HPV infection. Dong YH, Luo YH, Liu CJ, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-024-04916-2. J Transl Med. 2024;22:125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10832222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38303030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotic susceptibility testing using minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) assays. Kade&#x159;&#xe1;bkov&#xe1; N, Mahmood AJ, Mavridou DA. https://doi.org/10.1038/s44259-024-00051-6. NPJ Antimicrob Resist. 2024;2:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11721449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39843555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The female urethra: urethral function throughout a woman's lifetime. van Geelen H, Sand PK. Int Urogynecol J. 2023;34:1175&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36757487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The epidemiology of 32 selected communicable diseases in Iraq, 2004-2016. Zhao Y, Lafta R, Hagopian A, Flaxman AD. Int J Infect Dis. 2019;89:102&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31560993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almuqbil M, Rabbani SM, Alharbi FG, et al. Crit Public Health. Vol. 35. Saudi Arabia: 2025. Seasonal patterns of infectious diseases in Riyadh Province, Saudi Arabia: a retrospective analysis; p. 2472686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uropathogenic Escherichia coli in Iran: serogroup distributions, virulence factors and antimicrobial resistance properties. Momtaz H, Karimian A, Madani M, Safarpoor Dehkordi F, Ranjbar R, Sarshar M, Souod N. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2013;12:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23627669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice guidelines for managing genitourinary symptoms associated with menopause. Christmas M, Huguenin A, Iyer S. Clin Obstet Gynecol. 2024;67:101&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38126460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strategies to decolonize uropathogens in urethra and bladder for prevention of urinary tract infections among pregnant women: a comprehensive narrative analysis. Mohda A, Abhishek S, Kumar A, Akshd C. Urol Sci. 2025;36:11&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The incidence, clinical features and outcome of urinary tract infections in geriatric patients: a prospective longitudinal study. Al Qahtani M, Naghib ME, Alshamrani AM, Al Mazroua AM, Alayyaf AS, Ofisan SB, Kamal SM. IJID Reg. 2024;13:100469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11539122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39507391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and molecular epidemiology of carbapenem resistance in Asia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Jayathilaka N, Shehana S, Nakkawita D, Senaratne T. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-025-02776-5. Syst Rev. 2025;14:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12139192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40474248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urinary tract infections: pathogenesis, host susceptibility and emerging therapeutics. Timm MR, Russell SK, Hultgren SJ. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41579-024-01092-4. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2025;23:72&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39251839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotics over usage: a vital contributor of antibiotic resistance. Otia M, Dubey A. https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Antibiotics-over-usage%3A-a-vital-contributor-of-Otia/30ac062ddfcdb781771e6f22dc3c5681527cc3ea Int J Ther Innov. 2024;2:130&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acquired bacterial resistance to antibiotics and resistance genes: from past to future. Galgano M, Pellegrini F, Catalano E, et al.  https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics14030222. Antibiotics (Basel) 2025;14:222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11939227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40149034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RND efflux pump induction: a crucial network unveiling adaptive antibiotic resistance mechanisms of gram-negative bacteria. Novelli M, Bolla JM. Antibiotics (Basel) 2024;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11200565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38927168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of COVID-19 pandemic on the management of patients with chronic urticaria: an observational two-center study from Turkey. Erdem Y, Polat Ekinci A, Altunay IK, et al. Dermatol Ther. 2021;34:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and molecular characterization of extended-spectrum beta-lactamase-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. Al-Agamy MH, Shibl AM, Tawfik AF. Ann Saudi Med. 2009;29:253&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19587523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of extended-spectrum &#xdf;-lactamases (ESBLs) and AmpC &#xdf;-lactamases in clinical isolates of multiple drug-resistant Escherichia coli. Al-Hasani HM, Al-Rubaye DS, Abdelhameed A. Clin Obstet Gynecol. 2024</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>