<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41832510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-422X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virol J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leveraging the Oxford Nanopore MinION sequencing platform for HIV-1 drug resistance surveillance in resource-limited settings: a post-COVID implementation opportunity.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12985-026-03134-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">HIV drug resistance (HIVDR) testing remains essential for optimizing antiretroviral therapy (ART), yet access remains constrained by high cost, low throughput, and limited availability of Sanger sequencing in resource-limited settings (RLS). Recent improvements in Oxford Nanopore Technologies (ONT) sequencing offer a potential alternative, especially following the expansion of genomic surveillance infrastructure established during the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional laboratory validation study was conducted comparing ONT MinION sequencing with Sanger sequencing for HIV-1 protease/reverse transcriptase (PR/RT) and integrase (IN) genotyping. Sixty-four stored amplicons from patients with virological failure on second-line protease inhibitor (PI)- or integrase strand transfer inhibitor (INSTI)-based regimens were sequenced on the MinION Mk1C (R10.4.1). ONT-derived consensus sequences were generated using a custom pipeline and compared to Sanger reference sequences to assess nucleotide identity and drug resistance mutation (DRM) concordance using the Stanford HIVdb v9.8. We also evaluated the cost and scalability of ONT to determine its feasibility for broader implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ONT MinION sequencing produced high-quality consensus sequences with a median pairwise identity of 99.4% (IQR: 99.2-99.7). After resolving initial discrepancies through chromatogram review and high-depth Nanopore data, high concordance for major DRMs was observed across PR, RT, and IN coding regions. Using a 48-sample multiplexing configuration, the estimated reagent and consumable cost for ONT sequencing was approximately US$23.47 per sample. Published Sanger-based HIV drug resistance assays report per-sample costs in the range of approximately US$43 to US$100, although costs vary depending on laboratory workflow and testing volume. Moreover, ONT provided a substantially shorter turnaround time (~&#x2009;5&#xa0;h from library prep to sequence data), offering a more efficient and cost-effective workflow overall.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ONT MinION sequencing provides an accurate, rapid, and cost-effective alternative to Sanger sequencing for HIVDR genotyping in RLS. Its scalability, ability to detect minority variants, and compatibility with infrastructure setup up in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, make it a viable platform for both national HIVDR surveillance and decentralized clinical testing. Integrating ONT workflows into routine HIVDR monitoring could expand diagnostic access and enable more timely ART optimization in high-burden settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Washaya</LastName><ForeName>Tendai</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Unit, Department of Laboratory Diagnostic and Investigative Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Zimbabwe, Harare, Zimbabwe. washayatendai@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research and Training Institute, Harare, Zimbabwe. washayatendai@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Zimbabwe , Harare, Zimbabwe. washayatendai@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chimukangara</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care Medicine Department, NIH Clinical Centre, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AmpSeq LLC, Gaithersburg, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayini</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research and Training Institute, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bote</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AIDS Healthcare Foundation, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chin'ombe</LastName><ForeName>Nyasha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Unit, Department of Laboratory Diagnostic and Investigative Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Zimbabwe, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munyati</LastName><ForeName>Shungu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research and Training Institute, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manasa</LastName><ForeName>Justen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Unit, Department of Laboratory Diagnostic and Investigative Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Zimbabwe, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research and Training Institute, Harare, Zimbabwe.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>D43 TW011326</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Virol J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231645</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-422X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxford Nanopore Technologies</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study obtained research ethics approval from the local institutional review board of the University of Zimbabwe Joint Research Ethics Committee. Additional approvals were obtained from the BRTI Ethics Research Board, the Parirenyatwa Group of Hospitals (JREC/362/2021), and the Medical Research Council of Zimbabwe (MRCZ/A/2847). Consent for publication: This study did not obtain informed consent from individuals because it used anonymized routine HIVDR samples for genotyping. The Ministry of Health of Zimbabwe approved this study and waived the need for individual participant consent. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41832510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12985-026-03134-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12985-026-03134-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>HIV drug resistance. &#x2013; brief report 2024 [Internet]. [cited 2025 Jul 9]. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240086319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyana S, Gounder L, Pillay M, Manasa J, Naidoo K, Chimukangara B. HIV-1 Drug Resistance Genotyping in Resource Limited Settings: Current and Future Perspectives in Sequencing Technologies. Viruses. 2021;13(6):6. https://doi.org/10.3390/v13061125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosta S, Moreno K, Schuab G, Fonseca V, Segovia FMC, Kashima S, et al. Global SARS-CoV-2 genomic surveillance: What we have learned (so far). Infect Genet Evol. 2023;108:105405. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meegid.2023.105405. PubMed PMID: 36681102; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC9847326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;vila-R&#xed;os S, Parkin N, Swanstrom R, Paredes R, Shafer R, Ji H, et al. Next-Generation Sequencing for HIV Drug Resistance Testing: Laboratory, Clinical, and Implementation Considerations. Viruses. 2020;12(6):617. https://doi.org/10.3390/v12060617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osahan G, Ji H. Point-of-care tests for HIV drug resistance monitoring: an update of the literature and future viewpoints. Expert Rev Anti-infective Therapy. 2025;23(12):1173&#x2013;83. 2025.2605685 PubMed PMID: 41401032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu W, Wang J, Qin X, Duan M, Wang M, Guan Y, et al. The performance of nanopore sequencing in rapid detection of pathogens and antimicrobial resistance genes in blood cultures. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2025;111(3):116720. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2025.116720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule DB, Ssemwanga D, Kaleebu P, Tully DC. The utility of integrating nanopore sequencing into routine HIV-1 drug resistance surveillance. Microb Genomics. 2025;11(3):001375. https://doi.org/10.1099/mgen.0.001375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washaya T, Chimukangara B, Mayini J, Bote S, Chin&#x2019;ombe N, Munyati S, et al. Pan-Resistant HIV-1 Drug Resistance Among Highly Treated Patients with Virological Failure on Dolutegravir-Based Antiretroviral Therapy in Zimbabwe. Viruses. 2025;17(10):1348. https://doi.org/10.3390/v17101348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearse M, Moir R, Wilson A, Stones-Havas S, Cheung M, Sturrock S, et al. Geneious Basic: An integrated and extendable desktop software platform for the organization and analysis of sequence data. Bioinformatics. 2012;28(12):1647&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/bts199. PubMed PMID: 22543367; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC3371832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu TF, Shafer RW. Web resources for HIV type 1 genotypic-resistance test interpretation. Clin Infect Dis. 2006;42(11):1608&#x2013;18. doi:10.1086/503914 PubMed PMID: 16652319; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC2547473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wensing AM, Calvez V, Ceccherini-Silberstein F, Charpentier C, G&#xfc;nthard HF, Jacobsen DM et al. 2025 Update of the Drug Resistance Mutations in HIV-1. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landmarks of the HIV genome [Internet]. [cited 2026 Mar 2]. Available from: https://www.hiv.lanl.gov/content/sequence/HIV/MAP/landmark.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shop DNA. Sequencers For Sale, New and Used Prices | LabX.com [Internet]. [cited 2025 Oct 11]. Available from: https://www.labx.com/categories/dna-sequencers</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxford Nanopore Technologies [Internet]. [cited 2025 Oct 11]. Welcome to Oxford Nanopore Technologies. Available from: https://nanoporetech.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaney KE, Ngobeni T, Woods CK, Gordijn C, Claassen M, Parikh U, et al. Nano-RECall provides an integrated pipeline for HIV-1 drug resistance testing from Oxford Nanopore sequence data. Trop Med Int Health. 2023;28(3):186&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1111/tmi.13851. PubMed PMID: 36599816; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC10230441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of Illumina and Oxford Nanopore Sequencing Technologies for Pathogen Detection from Clinical Matrices Using Molecular Inversion Probes. J Mol Diagn. 2022;24(4):395&#x2013;405. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmoldx.2021.12.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buddle S, Forrest L, Akinsuyi N, Martin Bernal LM, Brooks T, Venturini C, et al. Evaluating metagenomics and targeted approaches for diagnosis and surveillance of viruses. Genome Med. 2024;16(1):111. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13073-024-01380-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poliakov E, Kaplun L, Rogozin IB, Editorial. Novel applications of ONT technologies in genomics and transcriptomics. Front Genet. 2024;15:1384584. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene. 2024.1384584 PubMed PMID: 38572417; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC10987952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenhende MA, Bellecave P, Recordon-Pinson P, Reigadas S, Bidet Y, Bruyand M, et al. Prevalence and Evolution of Low Frequency HIV Drug Resistance Mutations Detected by Ultra Deep Sequencing in Patients Experiencing First Line Antiretroviral Therapy Failure. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(1):e86771. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0086771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Li S, Zheng Z, Lam TW, Luo R. ClusterV-Web: a user-friendly tool for profiling HIV quasispecies and generating drug resistance reports from nanopore long-read data. Bioinf Adv. 2024;4(1):vbae006. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioadv/vbae006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyana S, Pillay M, Gounder L, Khan A, Moodley P, Naidoo K, et al. Affordable drug resistance genotyping of HIV-1 reverse transcriptase, protease and integrase genes, for resource limited settings. AIDS Res Ther. 2023;20(1):9. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12981-023-00505-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gachogo RW, Mwai DN, Onyambu FG. Cost analysis of implementing HIV drug resistance testing in Kenya: a case study of a service delivery site at a tertiary level hospital in Kenya. F1000Res. 2020;9:793. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.23379.1. PubMed PMID: 32983418; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC7495211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade M, Belmok A, Silva L, Vieira A, Vieira C, Velasco L, et al. A-248 Assessment of Nanopore Sequencing for HIV Genotyping: A Comparative Study with Sanger Sequencing. Clin Chem. 2024;70(Supplement1):hvae106245. https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvae106.245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ode H, Matsuda M, Shigemi U, Mori M, Yamamura Y, Nakata Y, et al. Population-based nanopore sequencing of the HIV-1 pangenome to identify drug resistance mutations. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):12099. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-63054-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SY, Faraci G, Ganesh K, Dub&#xe9; MP, Lee HY. Portable Nanopore Sequencing Solution for Next-Generation HIV Drug Resistance Testing. J Clin Virol. 2024;171:105639. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcv.2024.105639. PubMed PMID: 38219684; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC10947882.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>