<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41670421</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5725</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Blood pressure monitoring</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Blood Press Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 20 weeks of different power training protocols involving exercises with elastic bands on cardiovascular health in hypertensive young-old adults.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MBP.0000000000000794</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to investigate the effects of different power training protocols on pulse pressure, systolic blood pressure (SBP), diastolic blood pressure (DBP), autonomic cardiac control, and physical performance in hypertensive ung.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-five participants were randomly assigned to either the dynamic power training group (DPTG; n&#x2005;=&#x2005;13) or the power training group (PTG; n&#x2005;=&#x2005;12). The DPTG performed dynamic power training without absolute rest intervals, whereas the PTG performed power training with short rest periods. Both protocols were carried out three times per week over 20 weeks. Pulse pressure, SBP, DBP, autonomic cardiac control, and physical performance were assessed at baseline and after 20 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant improvements were observed in pulse pressure, SBP, autonomic cardiac control, and physical performance following the 20-week intervention (P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that both protocols - dynamic power training (without absolute rest intervals) and power training (with short rest periods) - promoted enhancements in pulse pressure, SBP, autonomic cardiac control, lower limb functional capacity, and dynamic balance in hypertensive young-old adults. Thus, strength and conditioning professionals may consider incorporating power training protocols as a viable exercise intervention for managing systemic arterial hypertension in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bavaresco Gambassi</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ceuma University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Management and Health Care, Ceuma University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Physical Education, Federal University of Maranh&#xe3;o, S&#xe3;o Lu&#xed;s, Maranh&#xe3;o.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interuniversity Network for Healthy Aging, Latin America and the Caribbean.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Laboratory, University of Pernambuco, Petrolina, Pernambuco, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grij&#xf3; Viana</LastName><ForeName>Davi</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macieira</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bianco</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ceuma University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaves</LastName><ForeName>Luiz Filipe</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Physical Education, Federal University of Maranh&#xe3;o, S&#xe3;o Lu&#xed;s, Maranh&#xe3;o.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Benedita de F&#xe1;tima Ara&#xfa;jo</ForeName><Initials>BFA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mota</LastName><ForeName>Beatriz de S&#xe1;</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marques</LastName><ForeName>David Guilherme</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yakovi Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Vin&#xed;cius</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwingel</LastName><ForeName>Paulo Adriano</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Education and Research in Exercise and Cardiovascular Health in Older Adults, Department of Physical Education.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Laboratory, University of Pernambuco, Petrolina, Pernambuco, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Blood Press Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606438</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1359-5237</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41670421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBP.0000000000000794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00126097-990000000-00187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pugh KG, Wei JY. Clinical implications of physiological changes in the aging heart. Drugs Aging 2001; 18:263&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW. Hypertension and aging. Ageing Res Rev 2016; 26:96&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swaminathan RV, Alexander KP. Pulse pressure and vascular risk in the elderly: associations and clinical implications. Am J Geriatr Cardiol 2006; 15:226&#x2013;232; quiz 133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacher J, Staessen JA, Girerd X, Gasowski J, Thijs L, Liu L, et al. Pulse pressure not mean pressure determines cardiovascular risk in older hypertensive patients. Arch Intern Med 2000; 160:1085&#x2013;1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco Gambassi B, Nobre I, Prazeres J, de Melo MH, Bianco R, Novais TM, et al. Impact of dynamic explosive resistance exercise with elastic bands on pulse pressure in hypertensive older adults: a randomized crossover study. Blood Press Monit 2023; 28:208&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaman S, Raj IS, Yang AWH, Lindner R, Denham J. Exercise training reduces arterial stiffness in women with high blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Hypertens 2024; 42:197&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider VM, Domingues LB, Umpierre D, Tanaka H, Ferrari R. Exercise characteristics and blood pressure reduction after combined aerobic and resistance training: a systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. J Hypertens 2023; 41:1068&#x2013;1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Afreixo V, Teixeira M, Garcia C, Leit&#xe3;o C, Gouveia M, et al. Exercise training reduces arterial stiffness in adults with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Hypertens 2021; 39:214&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Rodrigues B, de Jesus Furtado Almeida F, Sot&#xe3;o SS, da Silva Souza TM, Chaves LFC, et al. Acute effect of resistance training without recovery intervals on the blood pressure of comorbidity-free elderly women: a pilot study. Sport Sci Health 2016; 12:315&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AC, McCartney N, Kamath MV, Wiley RL. Isometric training lowers resting blood pressure and modulates autonomic control. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2003; 35:251&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Sharman JE, Coombes JS. Reduced central blood pressure in older adults following progressive resistance training. J Hum Hypertens 2007; 21:96&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fahs CA, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Kim D, Mouser JG, et al. Arterial stiffness and blood flow adaptations following eight weeks of resistance exercise training in young and older women. Exp Gerontol 2014; 53:48&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HB, Seo MW, Jung HC. Effects of aerobic vs. resistance exercise on vascular function and vascular endothelial growth factor in older women. Healthcare (Basel) 2023; 11:2479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhati P, Moiz JA, Menon GR, Hussain ME. Does resistance training modulate cardiac autonomic control? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Auton Res 2019; 29:75&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Schwingel PA, Mesquita F, da Penha Carnevali M, de Oliveira D, Sot&#xe3;o SS, et al. Influence of resistance training practice on autonomic cardiac control of hypertensive elderly women. JEPonline 2019; 22:37&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco Gambassi B, Lopes Dos Santos MD, Furtado Almeida FJ. Basic guide for the application of the main variables of resistance training in elderly. Aging Clin Exp Res 2019; 31:1019&#x2013;1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Trajano GS, Freitas SR, Izquierdo M, Cadore EL, Pinto RS. Power training prescription in older individuals: is it safe and effective to promote neuromuscular functional improvements? Sports Med 2023; 53:569&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Merchant RA, Morley JE, Anker SD, Aprahamian I, Arai H, et al. International Exercise Recommendations in Older Adults (ICFSR): expert consensus guidelines. J Nutr Health Aging 2021; 25:824&#x2013;853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Rech A, Petropoulou M, Newton RU, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Does high-velocity resistance exercise elicit greater physical function benefits than traditional resistance exercise in older adults? A systematic review and network meta-analysis of 79 trials. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2023; 78:1471&#x2013;1482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco Gambassi B, Cadore EL, Chaves LFC, da Silva Sousa TM, Mostarda CT, Lopes de Siqueira AF, Schwingel PA. Effects of combined muscle power and endurance training with different volumes on functional and hemodynamic parameters in previously trained older adults. Aging Clin Exp Res 2023; 35:2623&#x2013;2631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feter N, Schaun GZ, Smith EC, Cassuriaga J, Alt R, Redig L, et al. High-velocity resistance training improves executive function in mobility-limited older adults. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 2023; 114:105081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoulis K, Amara CE. The effects of power training frequency on muscle power and functional performance in older women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 2023; 37:2289&#x2013;2297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte Martins A, Fernandes O, Paulo Brito J, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Oliveira R, Batalha N. Effects of a 16-week high-speed resistance training program on heart rate variability indices in community-dwelling independent older adults: a clinical trial. J Appl Gerontol 2026; 45:177&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gearhart RF Jr, Lagally KM, Riechman SE, Andrews RD, Robertson RJ. Strength tracking using the OMNI resistance exercise scale in older men and women. J Strength Cond Res 2009; 23:1011&#x2013;1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Furtado GE, Teixeira AM, Flandez J, Naclerio F. Concurrent and construct validation of a new scale for rating perceived exertion during elastic resistance training in the elderly. J Sports Sci Med 2020; 19:175&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Gene-Morales J, Jim&#xe9;nez-Mart&#xed;nez P, Saez-Berlanga A, Ferri-Caruana AM, Garcia-Ramos A, et al. Concurrent validation of the resistance intensity scale for exercise for monitoring velocity-based training with elastic bands. Heliyon 2024; 10:e28298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feitosa ADM, Barroso WKS, Mion Junior D, Nobre F, Mota-Gomes MA, Jardim PCBV, et al. Brazilian Guidelines for In-office and Out-of-office Blood Pressure Measurement &#x2013; 2023. Diretrizes Brasileiras de Medidas da Press&#xe3;o Arterial Dentro e Fora do Consult&#xf3;rio &#x2013; 2023. Arq Bras Cardiol 2024; 121:e20240113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Neves VR, Brito EZA, da Silva Fernandes DS, S&#xe1; CA, da Rocha Nogueira RM, et al. A validation study of a smartphone application for heart rate variability assessment in asymptomatic adults. Am J Cardiovasc Dis 2020; 10:219&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias AA, Albin IF, Glickman L, Califano PA, Faller JM, Layec G, Ives SJ. Impact of high intensity interval exercise with and without heat stress on cardiovascular and aerobic performance: a pilot study. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 2023; 15:83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha ASL, de Barros Siqueira V, Maduro PA, Batista LDSP, Neves VR, Gambassi BB, Schwingel PA. Do older people with poor sleep quality have worse cardiac autonomic control? Can Geriatr J 2023; 26:276&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, et al. A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol 1994; 49:M85&#x2013;M94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsiadlo D, Richardson S. The timed &#x2018;Up &amp; Go&#x2019;: a test of basic functional mobility for frail elderly persons. J Am Geriatr Soc 1991; 39:142&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: a practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 2013; 4:863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espirito Santo H, Daniel F. Calculating and reporting effect sizes on scientific papers (3): guide to report regression models and ANOVA effect sizes. Rev Port Inv Comport Soc 2018; 4:43&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Effects of low-intensity resistance training with slow lifting and lowering on vascular function. J Hum Hypertens 2008; 22:509&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selig SE, Carey MF, Menzies DG, Patterson J, Geerling RH, Williams AD, et al. Moderate-intensity resistance exercise training in patients with chronic heart failure improves strength, endurance, heart rate variability, and forearm blood flow. J Card Fail 2004; 10:21&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso FR, Arena R, Phillips SA, Bonjorno JC Jr, Mendes RG, Arakelian VM, et al. Resistance exercise training improves heart rate variability and muscle performance: a randomized controlled trial in coronary artery disease patients. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2015; 51:281&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco Gambassi B, Chaves LFC, Sousa TMDS, Ribeiro MJS, Souza TA, Schwingel PA. Short-duration dynamic power training with elastic bands combined with endurance training: a promising approach to hypertension management in older adults. J Hypertens 2024; 42:735&#x2013;742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavaresco Gambassi B, Schwingel PA. Dynamic power training combined with endurance training reduces arterial stiffness and improves hemodynamic parameters in older adults diagnosed with grade 1 hypertension? J Hypertens 2024; 42:1461&#x2013;1462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira-Dantas FF, Browne RAV, Oliveira RS, Cabral LLP, de Farias Junior LF, Costa EC. Effect of high-velocity resistance exercise on 24-h blood pressure in hypertensive older women. Int J Sports Med 2021; 42:41&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson KB, Potiaumpai M, Widdowson K, Jaghab AM, Chowdhari S, Armitage C, et al. Effects of high-velocity circuit resistance and treadmill training on cardiometabolic risk, blood markers, and quality of life in older adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2018; 43:822&#x2013;832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-J&#xfa;nior HJ, Silva Aguiar S, Calvani R, Picca A, de Azevedo Carvalho D, Rodrigues B, et al. Acute and chronic effects of traditional and high-speed resistance training on blood pressure in older adults: a crossover study and systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Gerontol 2022; 163:111775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Coelho-Junior HJ, Paix&#xe3;o Dos Santos C, de Oliveira Gon&#xe7;alves I, Mostarda CT, Marzetti E, et al. Dynamic resistance training improves cardiac autonomic modulation and oxidative stress parameters in chronic stroke survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2019; 2019:5382843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsano VSM, de Moraes WMAM, de Sousa NMF, de Moura FC, Tibana RA, Silva AO, et al. Comparison of the acute effects of traditional versus high velocity resistance training on metabolic, cardiovascular, and psychophysiological responses in elderly hypertensive women. Clin Interv Aging 2018; 13:1331&#x2013;1340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gama G, Farinatti P, Rangel MVDS, Mira PAC, Laterza MC, Crisafulli A, Borges JP. Muscle metaboreflex adaptations to exercise training in health and disease. Eur J Appl Physiol 2021; 121:2943&#x2013;2955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanegusuku H, Queiroz AC, Silva VJ, de Mello MT, Ugrinowitsch C, Forjaz CL. High-intensity progressive resistance training increases strength with no change in cardiovascular function and autonomic neural regulation in older adults. J Aging Phys Act 2015; 23:339&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerage AM, Forjaz CL, Nascimento MA, Janu&#xe1;rio RS, Polito MD, Cyrino ES. Cardiovascular adaptations to resistance training in elderly postmenopausal women. Int J Sports Med 2013; 34:806&#x2013;813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanderley FA, Moreira A, Sokhatska O, Palmares C, Moreira P, Sandercock G, et al. Differential responses of adiposity, inflammation and autonomic function to aerobic versus resistance training in older adults. Exp Gerontol 2013; 48:326&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardeli AV, Griffith GJ, Dos Santos MVMA, Ito MSR, Nadruz W, Chacon-Mikahil MPT. Do baseline blood pressure and type of exercise influence level of reduction induced by training in hypertensive older adults? A meta-analysis of controlled trials. Exp Gerontol 2020; 140:111052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez R, Soliz P, Campbell NRC, Lackland DT, Whelton PK, Ord&#xfa;&#xf1;ez P. Association between population hypertension control and ischemic heart disease and stroke mortality in 36 countries of the Americas, 1990-2019: an ecological study. Rev Panam Salud Publica 2023; 47:e124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shailendra P, Baldock KL, Li LSK, Bennie JA, Boyle T. Resistance training and mortality risk: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Prev Med 2022; 63:277&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki KI, Fukumoto Y. Sarcopenia as a comorbidity of cardiovascular disease. J Cardiol 2022; 79:596&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>