<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41772729</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Complementary effect of a combined exercise and dietary supplement intervention in individuals with knee osteoarthritis: study protocol for a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09594-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Osteoarthritis is a common joint disease, especially among individuals aged 50 and older, leading to symptoms such as pain, stiffness, and functional limitations, particularly in weight-bearing joints like the knees. Knee osteoarthritis (KOA) is increasingly prevalent, making effective treatment strategies critical. Exercise and dietary supplements are commonly used to manage symptoms, but the combination of these two approaches has not been widely studied. This study aims to evaluate the effects of combining exercise with dietary supplements on pain, physical function, and quality of life in individuals with KOA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This trial will involve KOA patients, aged 55 and older. Participants will be assigned to one of three groups: (1) dietary supplement, (2) exercise with dietary supplement, (3) exercise with placebo dietary supplement. Randomization and double-blinding apply only to the dietary supplement in the exercise groups, while the supplement-only group serves as a non-randomized group. The exercise regimen will consist of resistance training, conducted under supervision. The dietary supplement will be a combination of glucosamine and collagen. The primary outcomes include pain levels and physical function, which will be assessed through questionnaires (WOMAC, SF-36), numeric rating scale, and various physical function tests (30&#xa0;s chair stand test, 40-m fast-paced walk, timed up and go test, star climbing test, 6-min walk test, static balance, and maximal isometric voluntary contraction of knee flexor and extensor). Data will be collected at baseline (week 0), after completion of the 12-week intervention (week 13), and at 6&#xa0;weeks post intervention (week 18).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study seeks to provide valuable insights into the combined effects of exercise and dietary supplements in managing KOA. It will fill the gap in current research by exploring whether the addition of a dietary supplement to an exercise regimen provides additional benefits. The findings could have important implications for clinical practices, offering a potential, non-invasive treatment strategy for improving pain management, physical function, and quality of life in individuals with KOA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov, NCT06269549. Registered on 13th February 2024, https://inclinicaltrials.com/osteoarthritis-knee/NCT06269549/.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x10c;eh</LastName><ForeName>Tina</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-9172-3186</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, Community Healthcare Center Dr. Adolf Drolc, Maribor, Slovenia. tina.ceh@zd-mb.si.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Primorska, Izola, Slovenia. tina.ceh@zd-mb.si.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zavr&#x161;nik</LastName><ForeName>Jernej</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, Community Healthcare Center Dr. Adolf Drolc, Maribor, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x160;arabon</LastName><ForeName>Nejc</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Primorska, Izola, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ludwig Boltzmann Institute for Rehabilitation Research, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06269549</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical function</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate {24}: The study was approved by the Ethics Commission of Community Healthcare Center dr. Adolf Drolc, registration number: 02/010/03&#x2013;022/01/22. Consent will be obtained from all participants in the study. Consent for publication {32}: This manuscript contains images of patient. Written informed consent for the publication of these images was obtained from participant. Competing interests {28}: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41772729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09594-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09594-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cross M, Smith E, Hoy D, Nolte S, Ackerman I, Fransen M, et al. The global burden of hip and knee osteoarthritis: estimates from the global burden of disease 2010 study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73(7):1323&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-204763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbassy AA, Trebinjac S, Kotb N. The use of cellular matrix in symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. Bosn J Basic Med Sci. 2020;20(2):271&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.17305/bjbms.2019.4205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteoarthritis Research Society International. OARSI. Standardization of osteoarthritis definitions. Available from: https://oarsi.org/research/standardization-osteoarthritis-definitions. Cited 2024 Feb 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui A, Li H, Wang D, Zhong J, Chen Y, Lu H. Global, regional prevalence, incidence and risk factors of knee osteoarthritis in population-based studies. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;29:100587. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannuru RR, Osani MC, Vaysbrot EE, Arden NK, Bennell K, Bierma-Zeinstra SMA, et al. OARSI guidelines for the non-surgical management of knee, hip, and polyarticular osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2019;27(11):1578&#x2013;89. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joca.2019.06.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolasinski SL, Neogi T, Hochberg MC, Oatis C, Guyatt G, Block J, et al. 2019 American College of Rheumatology/Arthritis Foundation Guideline for the Management of Osteoarthritis of the Hand, Hip, and Knee. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2020;72(2):149&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1002/acr.24131. PubMed PMID: 31908149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Ma B, Wang G, Wang P, Long H, Niu S, et al. Dose-response relationships of resistance training in adults with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1519/JPT.0000000000000394.&#xa0;PubMed PMID: 37774094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo L, Jiang B, Mei T, Zhou D. Exercise therapy for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11(5):23259671231172772. https://doi.org/10.1177/23259671231172773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan X, Wei W, Zhou P, Liu X, Yu J, Xu Y, et al. Effectiveness of aquatic exercise in lower limb osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Rehabil Res. 2022;45(2):126&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1097/MRR.0000000000000527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Wang Y, Zhang Y, Lu Y, Wen Y. Efficacy and safety of aquatic exercise in knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Rehabil. 2023;37(3):330&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1177/02692155221134240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirayeh N, Kazemi K, Rahimi F, Mostafaee N, Shaterzadeh-Yazdi MJ. The effect of balance training on functional outcomes in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2022;36:107. https://doi.org/10.47176/mjiri.36.107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan L, El-Ansary D, Adams R, Wu S, Han J. Knee osteoarthritis pain and stretching exercises: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiotherapy. 2022;114:16&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physio.2021.10.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua J, Sun L, Teng Y. Effects of high-intensity strength training in adults with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;102(4):292&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/PHM.0000000000002088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat S, Tan MP, Kamaruzzaman SB, Ng CT. Physical therapies for improving balance and reducing falls risk in osteoarthritis of the knee: a systematic review. Age Ageing. 2015;44(1):16&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afu112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You Y, Liu J, Tang M, Wang D, Ma X. Effects of Tai Chi exercise on improving walking function and posture control in elderly patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore). 2021;100(16):e25655. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000025655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh SL, Persson MSM, Stocks J, Hou Y, Lin J, Hall MC, et al. Efficacy and potential determinants of exercise therapy in knee and hip osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2019;62(5):356&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rehab.2019.04.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kus G, Yeldan I. Strengthening the quadriceps femoris muscle versus other knee training programs for the treatment of knee osteoarthritis. Rheumatol Int. 2019;39(2):203&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00296-018-4199-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng CY, Zhang ZR, Tang ZM, Hua FZ. Benefits and mechanisms of exercise training for knee osteoarthritis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:794062. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.794062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruy&#xe8;re O, Altman RD, Reginster JY. Efficacy and safety of glucosamine sulfate in the management of osteoarthritis: evidence from real-life setting trials and surveys. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2016;45(4, Supplement):S12&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semarthrit.2015.11.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh JA, Noorbaloochi S, MacDonald R, Maxwell LJ. Chondroitin for osteoarthritis. Cochrane Database System Rev. 2015;(1). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD005614.pub2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Machado GC, Eyles JP, Ravi V, Hunter DJ. Dietary supplements for treating osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):167&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-097333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo NX, Le NNH, Chu TDP, Pham HL, Dinh KXA, Che UTT, et al. Effectiveness and safety of glucosamine in osteoarthritis: a systematic review. Pharmacy. 2023;11(4):117. https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmacy11040117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu S, Soubrier M, Peirs C, Monfoulet LE, Boirie Y, Tournadre A. A meta-analysis of the impact of nutritional supplementation on osteoarthritis symptoms. Nutrients. 2022;14(8):1607. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14081607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W, Sun C, He SQ, Chen JY, Wang Y, Zhuo Q. The efficacy and safety of disease-modifying osteoarthritis drugs for knee and hip osteoarthritis-a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(7):2085&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-021-06755-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honvo G, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Reginster JY. Update on the role of pharmaceutical-grade chondroitin sulfate in the symptomatic management of knee osteoarthritis. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2019;31(8):1163&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-019-01253-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honvo G, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Geerinck A, Veronese N, Reginster JY. Efficacy of chondroitin sulfate in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a comprehensive meta-analysis exploring inconsistencies in randomized, placebo-controlled trials. Adv Ther. 2019;36(5):1085&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12325-019-00921-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Coronado JM, Mart&#xed;nez-Olvera L, Elizondo-Oma&#xf1;a RE, Acosta-Olivo CA, Vilchez-Cavazos F, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, et al. Effect of collagen supplementation on osteoarthritis symptoms: a meta-analysis of randomized placebo-controlled trials. Int Orthop. 2019;43(3):531&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00264-018-4211-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lugo JP, Saiyed ZM, Lane NE. Efficacy and tolerability of an undenatured type II collagen supplement in modulating knee osteoarthritis symptoms: a multicenter randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Nutr J. 2016;15(1):14. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12937-016-0130-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overton C, Nelson AE, Neogi T. Osteoarthritis treatment guidelines from six professional societies: similarities and differences. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2022;48(3):637&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rdc.2022.03.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostu D, Lucaciu O, Mester A, Oltean-Dan D, Baciut M, Baciut G, et al. Systemic drugs with impact on osteoarthritis. Drug Metab Rev. 2019;51(4):498&#x2013;523. https://doi.org/10.1080/03602532.2019.1687511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello AE, Oesser S. Collagen hydrolysate for the treatment of osteoarthritis and other joint disorders: a review of the literature. Curr Med Res Opin. 2006;22(11):2221&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1185/030079906X148373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deal CL, Moskowitz RW. Nutraceuticals as therapeutic agents in osteoarthritis. The role of glucosamine, chondroitin sulfate, and collagen hydrolysate. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 1999;25(2):379&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0889-857x(05)70074-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito-Ruiz P, Camacho-Zambrano MM, Carrillo-Arcentales JN, Mestanza-Peralta MA, Vallejo-Flores CA, Vargas-L&#xf3;pez SV, et al. A randomized controlled trial on the efficacy and safety of a food ingredient, collagen hydrolysate, for improving joint comfort. Int J Food Sci Nutr. 2009;60(2):99&#x2013;113. https://doi.org/10.1080/09637480802498820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;eh T, &#x160;arabon N. Effects of adding glucosamine or glucosamine combined with chondroitin to exercise on pain and physical function in adults with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Transl Myol. 2023;33(4):12013. https://doi.org/10.4081/ejtm.2023.12013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayhan FF, Demirci &#xc7;oban A, Utkan Karasu A, Karao&#x11f;lan B, &#xc7;&#x131;nar E, Eyig&#xf6;r S, et al. The effect of combined hydrolyzed type 2 collagen, methylsulfonylmethane, glucosamine sulfate and chondroitin sulfate supplementation on knee osteoarthritis symptoms. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. 2024;70(2):259&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.5606/tftrd.2024.13735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Huo S, Huang C, Cheng W, Liang S, Chen W, et al. Additive effects of curcumin and glucosamine on knee function, cartilage protection, and subchondral bone preservation in a posttraumatic osteoarthritis rat model. Guidelines and Standards Chin Med. 2025;3(1):69. https://doi.org/10.1097/gscm.0000000000000053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincivero DM, Coelho AJ, Campy RM. Perceived exertion and maximal quadriceps femoris muscle strength during dynamic knee extension exercise in young adult males and females. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(2):150&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-002-0768-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante Y, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Saavedra JM. Effects of exercise on functional aerobic capacity in lower limb osteoarthritis: a systematic review. J Sci Med Sport. 2011;14(3):190&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2010.10.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhl C, Christensen R, Roos EM, Zhang W, Lund H. Impact of exercise type and dose on pain and disability in knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2014;66(3):622&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1002/art.38290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Trial Randomization Tool. The National Cancer Institute&#x2019;s Division of Cancer Prevention. Available from: https://ctrandomization.cancer.gov. Cited 2025 Feb 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy N, Buchanan WW, Goldsmith CH, Campbell J, Stitt LW. Validation study of WOMAC: a health status instrument for measuring clinically important patient relevant outcomes to antirheumatic drug therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee. J Rheumatol. 1988;15(12):1833&#x2013;40. PubMed PMID: 3068365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware J, Snow KK, Kosinski M, Gandek B. SF-36 health survey: manual &amp; interpretation guide. Boston, Massachusetts: The Health Institute, New England Medical Center; 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardier C, Melfi CA, Paul J, Green R, Hawker G, Wright J, et al. Comparison of a generic and a disease-specific measure of pain and physical function after knee replacement surgery. Med Care. 1995;33(4 Suppl):AS131&#x2013;144. PubMed PMID: 7723441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marn-Vukadinovic D, Jamnik H. Validation of the short form-36 health survey supported with isokinetic strength testing after sport knee injury. J Sport Rehabil. 2011;20(3):261&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1123/jsr.20.3.261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker G, Melfi C, Paul J, Green R, Bombardier C. Comparison of a generic (SF-36) and a disease specific (WOMAC) (Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index) instrument in the measurement of outcomes after knee replacement surgery. J Rheumatol. 1995;22(6):1193&#x2013;6. PubMed PMID: 7674255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derman P, Malchau H. Validity and reliability of Swedish WOMAC osteoarthritis index: a self-administered disease-specific questionnaire (WOMAC) versus generic instruments (SF-36 and NHP). Acta Orthop Scand. 2000;71(1):39&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1080/00016470052943874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar JT, Young JP, LaMoreaux L, Werth JL, Poole MR. Clinical importance of changes in chronic pain intensity measured on an 11-point numerical pain rating scale. Pain. 2001;94(2):149&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-3959(01)00349-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson F, Hinman RS, Roos EM, Abbott JH, Stratford P, Davis AM, et al. OARSI recommended performance-based tests to assess physical function in people diagnosed with hip or knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2013;21(8):1042&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joca.2013.05.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell K, Dobson F, Hinman R. Measures of physical performance assessments: Self-Paced Walk Test (SPWT), Stair Climb Test (SCT), Six-Minute Walk Test (6MWT), Chair Stand Test (CST), Timed Up &amp; Go (TUG), Sock Test, Lift and Carry Test (LCT), and Car Task. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63(11):S350-370. https://doi.org/10.1002/acr.20538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rikli RE, Jones CJ. Senior fitness test manual. 2nd Edition. Chapaing: Human Kinetics; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers C, Dall P, Grant M, Stansfield B. Validity and reliability of the activPAL3 for measuring posture and stepping in adults and young people. Gait Posture. 2016;43:42&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.10.020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan CG, Grant PM, Tigbe WW, Granat MH. The validity and reliability of a novel activity monitor as a measure of walking. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40(9):779&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsm.2006.027276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastelic K, &#x160;arabon N, Burnard MD, Pedi&#x161;i&#x107; &#x17d;. Validity and reliability of the Daily Activity Behaviours Questionnaire (DABQ) for assessment of time spent in sleep, sedentary behaviour, and physical activity. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5362. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19095362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozinc &#x17d;, &#x160;arabon N. The effects of leg preference and leg dominance on static and dynamic balance performance in highly-trained tennis players. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(11):e0259854. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0259854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giorgetti MM, Harris BA, Jette A. Reliability of clinical balance outcome measures in the elderly. Physiother Res Int. 1998;3(4):274&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1002/pri.150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta SK. Intention-to-treat concept: a review. Perspect Clin Res. 2011;2(3):109&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.4103/2229-3485.83221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernards JR, Sato K, Haff GG, Bazyler CD. Current research and statistical practices in sport science and a need for change. Sports. 2017;5(4):4. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports5040087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Stuart EA, Allison DB. Multiple imputation: a flexible tool for handling missing data. JAMA. 2015;314(18):1966&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.15281.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>