<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41239708</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>46</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of cardiorespiratory physiotherapy on cardiovascular fitness in patients with stroke: A systematic review and network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45286</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45286</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45286</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000045286</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study aimed to investigate the effectiveness and ranking of different cardiorespiratory-physiotherapy interventions on cardiovascular fitness in patients with stroke.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In total, 21 randomized controlled trials published between 2000 and 2024 were retrieved from PubMed, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, Web of Science, and CINAHL and analyzed. Outcome measures were resting heart rate (RHR), rating of perceived exertion (RPE), and peak oxygen uptake (VO2peak). A network meta-analysis was conducted using the R netmeta package (version 4.3.2), with rankings based on probability scores (p-scores) representing the likelihood of each intervention being the most effective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">RHR rankings were as follows: combined inspiratory and expiratory training (CIET) (p-score: 94.02%), conventional training (CT) (68.16%), robot-assisted training (RAT) (61.27%), aquatic training (AT) (48.90%), ground-based aerobic training (GBAT) (31.61%), combined aerobic and resistance training (CART) (28.01%), and resistance training (RT) (18.03%). However, CIET did not show statistically significant differences in effect compared to other interventions. RPE rankings were as follows: CIET (89.12%), GBAT (72.23%), CT (66.19%), AT (66.01%), CART (30.20%), RAT (19.70%), and inspiratory training (IT) (6.55%). VO2peak rankings were as follows: RT (88.26%), GBAT (73.22%), AT (64.73%), RAT (45.10%), CART (43.34%), sham training (42.88%), IT (39.61%), CIET (28.29%), and CT (24.56%). The evidence quality ranked from very low to moderate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">CIET ranked highest in reducing RHR and RPE; RT ranked highest in improving VO2peak. Although CIET did not show significant superiority in RHR reduction, its consistent high ranking in RHR and RPE outcomes indicates its potential clinical utility. These findings suggest incorporating targeted respiratory and strength training into stroke-rehabilitation programs to optimize cardiovascular-fitness outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>So Hyun</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2329-8666</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Health and Medical Science, Cheongju University, Cheongju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Sung Hyoun</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5108-4342</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Nambu University, Gwangju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiorespiratory Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071939" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Rehabilitation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiorespiratory physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41239708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12622685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000045286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202511140-00131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bailey RR. Promoting physical activity and nutrition in people with stroke. Am J Occup Ther. 2017;71:7105360010p1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5557223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28809663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billinger SA, Coughenour E, Mackay-Lyons MJ, Ivey FM. Reduced cardiorespiratory fitness after stroke: biological consequences and exercise-induced adaptations. Stroke Res Treat. 2012;2012:959120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21876848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English C, Healy GN, Coates A, Lewis L, Olds T, Bernhardt J. Sitting and activity time in people with stroke. Phys Ther. 2016;96:193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews CE, George SM, Moore SC, et al. Amount of time spent in sedentary behaviors and cause-specific mortality in US adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;95:437&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22218159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirks ML, Wall BT, van de Valk B, et al. One week of bed rest leads to substantial muscle atrophy and induces whole-body insulin resistance in the absence of skeletal muscle lipid accumulation. Diabetes. 2016;65:2862&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Zhao J, Li X, et al. ; Chinese Stroke Association Stroke Council Guideline Writing Committee. Chinese Stroke Association guidelines for clinical management of cerebrovascular disorders: executive summary and 2019 update of clinical management of stroke rehabilitation. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2020;5:250&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7548515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordan R, Gwathmey JK, Xie LH. Autonomic and endocrine control of cardiovascular function. World J Cardiol. 2015;7:204&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25914789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Meng H, Wang Z, et al. Effect of high-intensity exercise on cardiorespiratory fitness in stroke survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2020;63:59&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31465865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polese JC, Scianni AA, Kuys S, Ada L, Teixaira-Salmela LF. Cardiorespiratory stress is not achieved during routine physiotherapy in chronic stroke. Int J Phys Med Rehabil. 2014;2:211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinyemi RO, Owolabi MO, Ihara M, et al. Stroke, cerebrovascular diseases and vascular cognitive impairment in Africa. Brain Res Bull. 2019;145:97&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6252289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29807146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baert I, Daly D, Dejaeger E, Vanroy C, Vanlandewijck Y, Feys H. Evolution of cardiorespiratory fitness after stroke: a 1-year follow-up study. Influence of prestroke patients&#x2019; characteristics and stroke-related factors. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2012;93:669&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22336102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Saunders DH, Mead G. Cardiorespiratory fitness after stroke: a systematic review. Int J Stroke. 2012;7:499&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22568786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouse B, Chaimani A, Li T. Network meta-analysis: an introduction for clinicians. Intern Emerg Med. 2017;12:103&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5247317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27913917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Yin H, Yi Y, Liu C, Li C. Effects of different rehabilitation training on balance function in stroke patients: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Arch Med Sci. 2023;19:1671&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10696991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38058731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenberg S, Mueller S, Vogt L, et al. Comparative effectiveness of upper limb exercise interventions in individuals with stroke: a network meta-analysis. Stroke. 2023;54:1839&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37293804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alatawi SF. A Comparison of three common rehabilitation interventions used to improve cardiovascular fitness after stroke: an overview of the literature. Biomed Res Int. 2023;2023:4350851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37082188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Almeida FJF, Almeida AEAF, et al. Effects of exercise training on cardiovascular and autonomic parameters in stroke survivors: a systematic review. Int J Cardiovasc Sci. 2019;32:408&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi KB, Cho SH. Are physical therapeutics important for stroke patients to recover their cardiorespiratory fitness? Medicina (Kaunas). 2021;57:1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8619703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34833400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Murad MH, et al. ; for the GRADE Working Group. A GRADE working group approach for rating the quality of treatment effect estimates from network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2014;349:g5630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25252733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper H, Hedges LV, Valentine JC. The Handbook of Research Synthesis and Meta-analysis. 3rd ed. New York: Russell Sage Foundation; 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness LA, Higgins JPT. Risk-of-bias VISualization (Robvis): an R package and Shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods. 2021;12:55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balduzzi S, R&#xfc;cker G, Nikolakopoulou A, et al. Netmeta: an R package for network meta-analysis using frequentist methods. J Stat Soft. 2023;106:1&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim SR, Kim SJ, Lee J, R&#xfc;cker G. Network meta-analysis: application and practice using R software. Epidemiol Health. 2019;41:e2019013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6635665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30999733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JW. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Science. 2nd ed. New York: Lawrence Erlbaum, Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson M, Chantigian DP, Asirvatham-Jeyaraj N, Van de Winckel A, Keller-Ross ML. Slow-paced breathing and autonomic function in people post-stroke. Front Physiol. 2020;11:573325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Y, Zhao X, Hou YY, et al. Meta-analysis of effects of voluntary slow breathing exercises for control of heart rate and blood pressure in patients with cardiovascular diseases. Am J Cardiol. 2017;120:148&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28502461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park BJ, Lee HR, Shim JY, Lee JH, Jung DH, Lee YJ. Association between resting heart rate and arterial stiffness in Korean adults. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2010;103:246&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A, Figueroa A. Effects of acute stretching exercise and training on heart rate variability: a review. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:1459&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato M, Green FN, Hotta K, et al. The efficacy of stretching exercises on arterial stiffness in middle-aged and older adults: a meta-analysis of randomized and non-randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:5643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashor AW, Lara J, Siervo M, Celis-Morales C, Mathers JC. Effects of exercise modalities on arterial stiffness and wave reflection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One. 2014;9:e110034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4198209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25333969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimers AK, Knapp G, Reimers CD. Effects of exercise on the resting heart rate: a systematic review and meta-analysis of interventional studies. J Clin Med. 2018;7:503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30513777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manresa-Rocamora A, Sarabia JM, Javaloyes A, Flatt AA, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Heart rate variability-guided training for enhancing cardiac-vagal modulation, aerobic fitness, and endurance performance: a methodological systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:10299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8507742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34639599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Afreixo V, Teixeira M, et al. Exercise training reduces arterial stiffness in adults with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Hypertens. 2021;39:214&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hm M, Cotton D, Foster L, et al. Impact of resting heart rate on mortality, disability and cognitive decline in patients after ischaemic stroke. Eur Heart J. 2012;33:2804&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22922507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Zera T, Paton JFR. Respiratory-cardiovascular interactions. Handb Clin Neurol. 2022;188:279&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35965029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Morris M, Hicklen L, Izadi H, Dawes H. The impact of high and low-intensity exercise in adolescents with movement impairment. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0195944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5919484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29698495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefeber N, De Keersmaecker E, Henderix S, et al. Physiological responses and perceived exertion during robot-assisted treadmill walking in non-ambulatory stroke survivors. Disabil Rehabil. 2021;43:1576&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31588811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabero-Garrido R, Del Corral T, Angulo-D&#xed;az-Parre&#xf1;o S, et al. Respiratory muscle training improves exercise tolerance and respiratory muscle function/structure post-stroke at short term: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2022;65:101596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomczak CR, Jelani A, Haennel RG, Haykowsky MJ, Welsh R, Manns PJ. Cardiac reserve and pulmonary gas exchange kinetics in patients with stroke. Stroke. 2008;39:3102&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18703810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeva-Andany M, L&#xf3;pez-Oj&#xe9;n M, Funcasta-Calder&#xf3;n R, et al. Comprehensive review on lactate metabolism in human health. Mitochondrion. 2014;17:76&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24929216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han EY, Im SH, Kim BR, Seo MJ, Kim MO. Robot-assisted gait training improves brachial-ankle pulse wave velocity and peak aerobic capacity in subacute stroke patients with totally dependent ambulation: randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltim). 2016;95:e5078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5072950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27741123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsden DL, Dunn A, Callister R, Levi CR, Spratt NJ. Characteristics of exercise training interventions to improve cardiorespiratory fitness after stroke: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2013;27:775&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD. VO2max: what do we know, and what do we still need to know? J Physiol. 2008;586:25&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18006574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Leigh JS, Wagner PD, Noyszewski EA. Cellular PO2 as a determinant of maximal mitochondrial O2 consumption in trained human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1999;87:325&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10409591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Coelho-Junior HJ, Schwingel PA, et al. Resistance training and stroke: a critical analysis of different training programs. Stroke Res Treat. 2017;2017:4830265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5750509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher S, Smart NA, Pearson MJ. Resistance training in heart failure patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Heart Fail Rev. 2022;27:1665&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34542742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Resistance training induced increase in VO2max in young and older subjects. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2013;10:107&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>