<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41234957</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of Preoperative Home Physiotherapy in Anterior Cruciate Ligament Deficiency.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e94439</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e94439</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e94439</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.94439</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury frequently compromises knee stability and function. Preoperative physiotherapy has been shown to improve surgical outcomes by enhancing periarticular muscle strength, mobility, and recovery. However, many existing protocols require exercise equipment and frequent supervision, limiting feasibility in resource-constrained settings. To date, no study has evaluated a simplified, equipment-free home-based physiotherapy program for chronic ACL deficiency. This prospective study assessed the effectiveness of a structured home-based physiotherapy program on 27 (male) patients with ACL deficiency awaiting reconstruction. The program focused on quadriceps and hamstring strengthening, range of motion, and proprioceptive training. Clinical outcomes were measured using the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) score, Lysholm score, and knee range of motion at baseline and upon program completion. Participants demonstrated statistically significant improvements in quadriceps strength, IKDC and Lysholm scores, and range of motion compared with baseline (p &lt; 0.05), along with reduced pain and improved knee stability. Adherence was high, and the program was well tolerated. These findings suggest that a structured, equipment-free home-based physiotherapy program is effective in improving function, strength, and mobility in patients with ACL-deficient knees. Incorporating such programs preoperatively may facilitate enhanced postoperative recovery and long-term knee function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Fakru et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fakru</LastName><ForeName>Nor Hamdam</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Universiti Sains Malaysia School of Medical Sciences, Kota Bharu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yahaya</LastName><ForeName>Sahran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Universiti Sains Malaysia School of Medical Sciences, Kota Bharu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Samhani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Sultan Zainal Abidin, Kuala Terengganu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamudin</LastName><ForeName>Nur Azree Ferdaus</ForeName><Initials>NAF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Sultan Zainal Abidin, Kuala Terengganu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Hospital Pengajar Universiti Sultan Zainal Abidin, Kuala Terengganu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamarul Zaman</LastName><ForeName>Wan Mahafeez</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Universiti Sains Malaysia Specialist Hospital, Kota Bharu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shihabudin</LastName><ForeName>Muzaffar T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Universiti Sains Malaysia School of Medical Sciences, Kota Bharu, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic acl deficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">equipment-free physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy modalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. The Human Research Ethics Committee, Hospital Sains Malaysia (FWA Reg. No: 00007718, IRB Reg. No: 00004494) issued approval USMKK/PPP/JEPeM|263.4/[1.8]|. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41234957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12605373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.94439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Functional outcomes following arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction using the Sironix titanium button and the polyetheretherketone (PEEK) button: a retrospective observational study. Dash SK, Mishra D, Sahu H, Moharana AK, Angrish S, Ts D. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10613784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in a cohort of Division I NCAA athletes from a single institution. Zampogna B, Vasta S, Torre G, et al. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9:2325967120982281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7900794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo H, Marappa-Ganeshan R. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Anatomy, bony pelvis and lower limb, knee anterior cruciate ligament.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparative analysis of quadriceps tendon, patellar tendon bone allograft, and cadaver graft in anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) repair and reconstructive surgery. Krumbach B, Meretsky C, Schiuma AT, Ajebli M. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11156480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38846230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to sports after ACL injury 5&#xa0;years from now: 10 things we must do. Gokeler A, Grassi A, Hoogeslag R, et al.  https://link.springer.com/article/10.1186/s40634-022-00514-7. J Exp Orthop. 2022;9:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9672288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical diagnosis of ruptures of the anterior cruciate ligament: a comparative study of the Lachman test and the anterior drawer sign. Jonsson T, Althoff B, Peterson L, Renstr&#xf6;m P. Am J Sports Med. 1982;10:100&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7081521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahaya S. Kelantan, Malaysia: School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia; 2015. Effectiveness of Home-based Physiotherapy Programme for Chronic Anterior Cruciate Ligament Deficiency [Thesis]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative quadriceps strength is a significant predictor of knee function two years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Eitzen I, Holm I, Risberg MA. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43:371&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19224907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of proprioceptive training on sports performance: a systematic review. Y&#x131;lmaz O, Soylu Y, Erkmen N, Kaplan T, Batalik L. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11225257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38965588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of home versus physical therapy-supervised rehabilitation programs after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized clinical trial. Grant JA, Mohtadi NG, Maitland ME, Zernicke RF. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33:1288&#x2013;1297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supervised rehabilitation may lead to better outcome than home-based rehabilitation up to 1 year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Rhim HC, Lee JH, Lee SJ, Jeon JS, Kim G, Lee KY, Jang KM. Medicina (Kaunas) 2020;57:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7824668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33379403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effectiveness of a pre-operative home-based physiotherapy programme for chronic anterior cruciate ligament deficiency. Keays SL, Bullock-Saxton JE, Newcombe P, Bullock MI. Physiother Res Int. 2006;11:204&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17236528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanism of quadriceps femoris muscle weakness in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Konishi Y, Fukubayashi T, Takeshita D. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2002;12:371&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quantifying quadriceps muscle strength in patients with ACL injury, focal cartilage lesions, and degenerative meniscus tears: differences and clinical implications. Eitzen I, Grindem H, Nilstad A, Moksnes H, Risberg MA. Orthop J Sports Med. 2016;4:2325967116667717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5063093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27766275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint position sense and rehabilitation in the anterior cruciate ligament deficient knee. Carter ND, Jenkinson TR, Wilson D, Jones DW, Torode AS. Br J Sports Med. 1997;31:209&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9298555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>