<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41286784</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2407</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tumor metabolic heterogeneity based on <sup>18</sup>F-FDG PET/CT is a predictor of outcome in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1807</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1807</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1807</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12885-025-15149-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Tumor metabolic heterogeneity (MH) assessed by 18-fluorine fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography computed tomography (<sup>18</sup>F-FDG PET/CT) is established as a marker of drug resistance in solid tumors. Its prognostic significance in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) remains inadequately explored. This study aims to investigate the prognostic value of tumor MH assessed by <sup>18</sup>F-FDG PET/CT in DLBCL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study retrospectively included 297 patients diagnosed with DLBCL at the Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University from August 2012 to December 2022. We evaluated tumor MH using the area under the curve of cumulative standardized uptake value-volume histogram (AUC-CSH). In addition to obtaining conventional PET metabolic metrics, including maximum standardized uptake value (SUVmax), mean standardized uptake value (SUVmean), total metabolic tumor volume (TMTV), and total lesion glycolysis (TLG), we also collected baseline clinical data. This study developed a survival prediction model based on Cox regression analysis and compared its prognostic performance with the National Comprehensive Cancer Network-International prognostic index (NCCN-IPI). We evaluated the model&#x2019;s calibration, discrimination, and clinical utility, and conducted an internal validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Multivariable Cox regression analysis indicated age (hazard ratio [HR], HR,1.62, 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.13&#x2009;~&#x2009;2.34, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01; HR, 2.15, 95% CI, 1.35&#x2009;~&#x2009;3.42, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001), TMTV (HR, 3.24, 95% CI, 1.56&#x2009;~&#x2009;6.73, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002; HR, 3.35, 95% CI, 1.30&#x2009;~&#x2009;8.62, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.012), and AUC-CSH (HR, 0.64, 95% CI, 0.45&#x2009;~&#x2009;0.92, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.015; HR, 0.59, 95% CI, 0.38&#x2009;~&#x2009;0.92, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.018) as independent predictive factors for both progression-free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS). Lower AUC-CSH value corresponded to higher tumor MH, indicating poorer survival outcome. The combined model outperformed the NCCN-IPI, achieving C-index of 0.688, 0.630 for PFS and 0.721, 0.688 for OS. The calibration curve showed good consistency, and the decision curve analysis (DCA) also confirmed its potential application value in individualized treatment decisions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Tumor MH, assessed by <sup>18</sup>F-FDG PET/CT, demonstrates potential as a prognostic biomarker in DLBCL. Its incorporation into predictive models may improve individualized prognostic evaluation and facilitate more precise treatment stratification for these patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This research has been retrospectively registered in the Ethics Committee institutional of the Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University [approval number (2022) KD155].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12885-025-15149-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xin</LastName><ForeName>Wenchong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Translation of Nuclear Medicine and Molecular Imaging, Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Linyi People's Hospital, Linyi, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Luo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zang</LastName><ForeName>Haoyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Bai</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Weiying</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China. guweiying2001@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuetao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2859-8625</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China. yuetao-w@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Translation of Nuclear Medicine and Molecular Imaging, Soochow University, Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, China. yuetao-w@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CZZX202204, PI: Yuetao Wang</GrantID><Agency>Changzhou Clinical Medical Center (Nuclear Medicine)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PI: Yuetao Wang</GrantID><Agency>Clinical Medical Science and Technology High-end Platform and Transformation Base Construction Project of Soochow University (Characteristic Discipline)-Nuclear Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-260, PI: Yuetao Wang</GrantID><Agency>Outstanding Talent of Changzhou "The 14th Five-Year Plan" High-Level Health Talents Training Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2407</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deoxyglucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffuse large B-Cell lymphoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positron emission tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor metabolic heterogeneity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol adhered to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and received approval from the ethics committee of the Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University. Given the nature of this study being retrospective, the requirement for written informed consent was exempted. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41286784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12641985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-15149-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12885-025-15149-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Giaquinto AN, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2024. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74(1):12&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sehn LH, Salles G. Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(9):842&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra2027612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanibar-Adaniya S, Barta SK. 2021 Update on Diffuse large B cell lymphoma: A review of current data and potential applications on risk stratification and management. Am J Hematol. 2021;96(5):617&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfreundschuh M, Schubert J, Ziepert M, Schmits R, Mohren M, Lengfelder E, et al. Six versus eight cycles of bi-weekly CHOP-14 with or without rituximab in elderly patients with aggressive CD20&#x2009;+&#x2009;B-cell lymphomas: a randomised controlled trial (RICOVER-60). Lancet Oncol. 2008;9(2):105&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(08)70002-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18226581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crump M, Neelapu SS, Farooq U, Van Den Neste E, Kuruvilla J, Westin J, et al. Outcomes in refractory diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: results from the international SCHOLAR-1 study. Blood. 2017;130(16):1800&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2017-03-769620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5649550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28774879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisselbrecht C, Glass B, Mounier N, Singh Gill D, Linch DC, Trneny M, et al. Salvage regimens with autologous transplantation for relapsed large B-cell lymphoma in the rituximab era. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28(27):4184&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2010.28.1618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer MJ, Ghesqui&#xe8;res H, Jais JP, Witzig TE, Haioun C, Thompson CA, et al. Event-free survival at 24 months is a robust end point for disease-related outcome in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma treated with immunochemotherapy. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(10):1066&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2013.51.5866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3965261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrington SF, Mikhaeel NG, Kostakoglu L, Meignan M, Hutchings M, M&#xfc;eller SP, et al. Role of imaging in the staging and response assessment of lymphoma: consensus of the International Conference on Malignant Lymphomas Imaging Working Group. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(27):3048&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2013.53.5229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5015423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheson BD, Fisher RI, Barrington SF, Cavalli F, Schwartz LH, Zucca E, et al. Recommendations for initial evaluation, staging, and response assessment of Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphoma: the Lugano classification. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(27):3059&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2013.54.8800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4979083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikhaeel NG, Heymans MW, Eertink JJ, de Vet HCW, Boellaard R, D&#xfc;hrsen U, et al. Proposed new dynamic prognostic index for diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: international metabolic prognostic index. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40(21):2352&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.21.02063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35357901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercellino L, Cottereau AS, Casasnovas O, Tilly H, Feugier P, Chartier L, et al. High total metabolic tumor volume at baseline predicts survival independent of response to therapy. Blood. 2020;135(16):1396&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2019003526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostakoglu L, Martelli M, Sehn LH, Belada D, Trn&#x11b;n M. Baseline PET-derived metabolic tumor volume metrics predict progression-free and overall survival in DLBCL after first-line treatment: results from the phase 3 GOYA study. Blood. 2017;130(Suppl1):824&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.V130.Suppl_1.824.824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGranahan N, Swanton C. Clonal heterogeneity and tumor evolution: past, present, and the future. Cell. 2017;168(4):613&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2017.01.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28187284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Naqa I, Grigsby P, Apte A, Kidd E, Donnelly E, Khullar D, et al. Exploring feature-based approaches in PET images for predicting cancer treatment outcomes. Pattern Recogn. 2009;42(6):1162&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2008.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20161266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinho DF, King B, Xi Y, Albuquerque K, Lea J, Subramaniam RM. Value of intratumoral metabolic heterogeneity and quantitative (18)F-FDG PET/CT parameters in predicting prognosis for patients with cervical cancer. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2020;214(4):908&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.19.21604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32069078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Ren Q, Xiao H, Li S, Zheng L, Yang X, et al. Whole-tumoral metabolic heterogeneity in (18)F-FDG PET/CT is a novel prognostic marker for neuroblastoma. Cancer Imaging. 2024;24(1):72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40644-024-00718-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11167917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38863073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G, Nie P, Yan L, Zhang M, Wang Y, Zhao L, et al. The radiomics-based tumor heterogeneity adds incremental value to the existing prognostic models for predicting outcome in localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma: a multicenter study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49(8):2949&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-022-05773-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35344062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JW, Park JY, Lee HJ, Lee JJ, Moon SH, Kang SY, et al. Preoperative [(18)F]FDG PET/CT tumour heterogeneity index in patients with uterine leiomyosarcoma: a multicentre retrospective study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2018;45(8):1309&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-018-3975-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29492644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Ha S, Lee SH, Paeng JC, Keam B, Kim TM, et al. Intratumoral heterogeneity characterized by pretreatment PET in non-small cell lung cancer patients predicts progression-free survival on EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(1):e0189766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0189766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5791940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriani L, Milan L, Martelli M, Ferreri AJM, Cascione L, Zinzani PL, et al. Metabolic heterogeneity on baseline 18FDG-PET/CT scan is a predictor of outcome in primary mediastinal B-cell lymphoma. Blood. 2018;132(2):179&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2018-01-826958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriani L, Gritti G, Cascione L, Pirosa MC, Polino A, Ruberto T, et al. SAKK38/07 study: integration of baseline metabolic heterogeneity and metabolic tumor volume in DLBCL prognostic model. Blood Adv. 2020;4(6):1082&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2019001201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32196557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senjo H, Hirata K, Izumiyama K, Minauchi K, Tsukamoto E, Itoh K, et al. High metabolic heterogeneity on baseline 18FDG-PET/CT scan as a poor prognostic factor for newly diagnosed diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2020;4(10):2286&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020001816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32453838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SH, Kang SY, Cheon GJ, Oh DY, Bang YJ. Predictive role of Temporal changes in intratumoral metabolic heterogeneity during palliative chemotherapy in patients with advanced pancreatic cancer: A prospective cohort study. J Nucl Med. 2020;61(1):33&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.119.226407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma G, Gu B, Hu J, Kong L, Zhang J, Li Z, et al. Pretreatment (18)F-FDG uptake heterogeneity can predict treatment outcome of carbon ion radiotherapy in patients with locally recurrent nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Ann Nucl Med. 2021;35(7):834&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12149-021-01621-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33913102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Heiden MG. Targeting cancer metabolism: a therapeutic window opens. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2011;10(9):671&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrd3504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21878982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinfeld BI, Madden MZ, Wolf MM, Chytil A, Bader JE, Patterson AR, et al. Cell-programmed nutrient partitioning in the tumour microenvironment. Nature. 2021;593(7858):282&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03442-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33828302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasanelli M, Meignan M, Haioun C, Berriolo-Riedinger A, Casasnovas RO, Biggi A, et al. Pretherapy metabolic tumour volume is an independent predictor of outcome in patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2014;41(11):2017&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-014-2822-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24902639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz C, H&#xfc;ttmann A, M&#xfc;ller SP, Hanoun M, Boellaard R, Brinkmann M, et al. Dynamic risk assessment based on positron emission tomography scanning in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: Post-hoc analysis from the PETAL trial. Eur J Cancer. 2020;124:25&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2019.09.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31710995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrington SF, Meignan M. Time to prepare for risk adaptation in lymphoma by standardizing measurement of metabolic tumor burden. J Nucl Med. 2019;60(8):1096&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.119.227249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meignan M, Cottereau AS, Versari A, Chartier L, Dupuis J, Boussetta S, et al. Baseline metabolic tumor volume predicts outcome in High-Tumor-Burden follicular lymphoma: A pooled analysis of three multicenter studies. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34(30):3618&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2016.66.9440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27551111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thieblemont C, Chartier L, D&#xfc;hrsen U, Vitolo U, Barrington SF, Zaucha JM, et al. A tumor volume and performance status model to predict outcome before treatment in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2022;6(23):5995&#x2013;6004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2021006923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9691911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36044385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shagera QA, Cheon GJ, Koh Y, Yoo MY, Kang KW, Lee DS, et al. Prognostic value of metabolic tumour volume on baseline (18)F-FDG PET/CT in addition to NCCN-IPI in patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: further stratification of the group with a high-risk NCCN-IPI. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2019;46(7):1417&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-019-04309-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cottereau AS, Nioche C, Dirand AS, Clerc J, Morschhauser F, Casasnovas O, et al. (18)F-FDG PET dissemination features in diffuse large B-Cell lymphoma are predictive of outcome. J Nucl Med. 2020;61(1):40&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.119.229450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eertink JJ, van de Brug T, Wiegers SE, Zwezerijnen GJC, Pfaehler EAG, Lugtenburg PJ, et al. (18)F-FDG PET baseline radiomics features improve the prediction of treatment outcome in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49(3):932&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05480-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>