<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41891384</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1557-0681</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Musculoskeletal care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Musculoskeletal Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Sling Exercise Training Compared to Standard Physiotherapy to Improve Muscle Strength, Joint Range of Motion and Functional Outcomes Following Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70212</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70212</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/msc.70212</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recovery following total knee arthroplasty (TKA) is frequently incomplete, highlighting the need for more effective rehabilitation approaches.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This single-blind pilot randomized controlled trial allocated 40 women undergoing unilateral total knee arthroplasty (TKA) to either Sling Training (ST) or Standard Physiotherapy Training (SPT) (1:1). Both groups completed supervised outpatient rehabilitation three times weekly for 8&#xa0;weeks, beginning 1-week post-surgery. Outcomes included quadriceps and hamstring isometric strength, knee range of motion, and WOMAC total score, assessed at baseline and week 8 by a blinded assessor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both groups improved significantly; however, ST produced larger gains in quadriceps strength (+60% vs. +30%), hamstring strength, knee flexion ROM (+19.2&#xb0; vs. +12.2&#xb0;), and WOMAC reduction (-41.9 vs. -35.7; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.003). Approximately 90% of ST participants versus 75% of SPT participants exceeded the &#x2265;&#xa0;12-point MCID threshold.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Sling-based exercise training may offer superior early functional and strength recovery compared with standard physiotherapy after TKA, supporting its potential role as an adjunct to early rehabilitation. Larger, multi-centre trials are needed to confirm effectiveness and generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">IRCT20221226056934N1.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajaeian</LastName><ForeName>Nooshin</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajaeian</LastName><ForeName>Bijan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1231-9399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Islamic Azad University, Shahin Shahr Branch, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghasemi</LastName><ForeName>Gholam Ali</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Injuries and Corrective Exercises, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kahrizsangi</LastName><ForeName>Negin Ghasemi</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Growth and Development Research Center, Research Institute for Primordial Prevention of Noncommunicable Disease, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Musculoskeletal Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101181344</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1478-2189</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019645" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthroplasty, Replacement, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="Y">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">suspension exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41891384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/msc.70212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Amiresmaili, M., M. Nekoei Moghadam, R. Goudarzi, V. Yazdi Feyzabadi, M. Karimi Mobarakeh, and A. Jahad Sarvestani. 2021. &#x201c;Study of Total Knee Arthroplasty in Iran: Implications for Health Managers and Policy Makers.&#x201d; Health Management and Information Science 8, no. 3: 210&#x2013;216. https://sid.ir/paper/1018674/en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryankhesal, A., M. Behzadifar, A. Bakhtiari, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Exploring the Landscape of Health Technology Assessment in Iran: Perspectives From Stakeholders on Needs, Demand and Supply.&#x201d; Health Research Policy and Systems 22, no. 1: 11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12961&#x2010;023&#x2010;01097&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castrodad, I. M. D., T. M. Recai, M. M. Abraham, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;Rehabilitation Protocols Following Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Review of Study Designs and Outcome Measures.&#x201d; Supplement, Annals of Translational Medicine 7, no. S7: S255. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm.2019.08.15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, W.&#x2010;D., W.&#x2010;S. Huang, C.&#x2010;L. Lee, H.&#x2010;Y. Lin, and P.&#x2010;T. Lai. 2014. &#x201c;Effects of Open and Closed Kinetic Chains of Sling Exercise Therapy on the Muscle Activity of the Vastus Medialis Oblique and Vastus Lateralis.&#x201d; Journal of Physical Therapy Science 26, no. 9: 1363&#x2013;1366. https://doi.org/10.1589/jpts.26.1363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciolac, E. G., J. M. R. d. Silva, and J. M. D. A. Greve. 2015. &#x201c;Effects of Resistance Training in Older Women With Knee Osteoarthritis and Total Knee Arthroplasty.&#x201d; Clinics 70, no. 1: 7&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.6061/clinics/2015(01)02.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobar, A., J. M. Quintana, A. Bilbao, I. Ar&#xf3;stegui, I. Lafuente, and I. Vidaurreta. 2007. &#x201c;Responsiveness and Clinically Important Differences for the WOMAC and SF&#x2010;36 After Total Knee Replacement.&#x201d; Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 15, no. 3: 273&#x2013;280. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joca.2006.09.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrokhi, N., M. M. Sarzaeem, and D. Feizi. 2024. &#x201c;Feasibility and Acceptability of a Telerehabilitation Intervention on Patients Undergoing Total Knee Arthroplasty in Iran: Randomised Controlled Trial Protocol.&#x201d; BMJ Open 14, no. 6: e083784. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen&#x2010;2023&#x2010;083784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, S., E. Ruffin, W. Brewer, and A. Ortiz. 2017. &#x201c;Muscle Activation Patterns During Suspension Training Exercises.&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy 12, no. 1: 42&#x2013;52. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28217415/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung, K. M., and J. D. Choi. 2019. &#x201c;The Effects of Active Shoulder Exercise With a Sling Suspension System on Shoulder Subluxation, Proprioception, and Upper Extremity Function in Patients With Acute Stroke.&#x201d; Medical Science Monitor: International Medical Journal of Experimental and Clinical Research 25: 4849&#x2013;4855. https://doi.org/10.12659/MSM.915277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M.&#x2010;k., J.&#x2010;m. Jung, J.&#x2010;S. Chang, and S.&#x2010;k. Lee. 2012. &#x201c;Radiographic Imaging Analysis After Sling Exercises for Hemiplegic Shoulder Subluxation.&#x201d; Journal of Physical Therapy Science 24, no. 11: 1099&#x2013;1101. https://doi.org/10.1589/jpts.24.1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, W. K., D.&#x2010;K. Kim, K. M. Seo, and S. H. Kang. 2014. &#x201c;Reliability and Validity of Isometric Knee Extensor Strength Test With Hand&#x2010;Held Dynamometer Depending on Its Fixation: A Pilot Study.&#x201d; Annals of Rehabilitation Medicine 38, no. 1: 84&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.5535/arm.2014.38.1.84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkesola, G. 2001. &#x201c;Sling Exercise Therapy (SET): A Total Concept for Exercise and Active Treatment of Musculoskeletal Disorders.&#x201d; Journal of Korean Academy of Orthopedic Manual Physical Therapy 7, no. 1: 87&#x2013;106. https://www.earticle.net/Article/A49265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lathabhavan, R., Z. H. Marznaki, R. N. Nukpezah, S. K. Mudgal, A. M. Afshar, and M. Khalilizad. 2024. Psychological Factors and Clinical Outcomes After Total Knee Arthroplasty Surgery in Patients. https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs&#x2010;3896905/v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, B., B. Kaplanek, and W. L. Jaffe. 2009. &#x201c;Pilates Training for Use in Rehabilitation After Total Hip and Knee Arthroplasty: A Preliminary Report.&#x201d; Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research 467, no. 6: 1468&#x2013;1475. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11999&#x2010;009&#x2010;0779&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., H. Liu, K.&#x2010;y. Lin, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Effects of Different Sling Settings on Electromyographic Activities of Selected Trunk Muscles: A Preliminary Research.&#x201d; BioMed Research International 2020, no. 1: 2945952. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/2945952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmon, A. R., B. I. Milcarek, and L. Snyder&#x2010;Mackler. 2014. &#x201c;Associations Between Knee Extensor Power and Functional Performance in Patients After Total Knee Arthroplasty and Normal Controls Without Knee Pain.&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy 9, no. 2: 168&#x2013;178. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24790778/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mau&#x2010;Moeller, A., M. Behrens, S. Finze, S. Bruhn, R. Bader, and W. Mittelmeier. 2014. &#x201c;The Effect of Continuous Passive Motion and Sling Exercise Training on Clinical and Functional Outcomes Following Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Randomized Active&#x2010;Controlled Clinical Study.&#x201d; Health and Quality of Life Outcomes 12, no. 1: 68. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477&#x2010;7525&#x2010;12&#x2010;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morat, T., D. Holzer, and R. Trumpf. 2019. &#x201c;Trunk Muscle Activation During Dynamic Sling Training Exercises.&#x201d; International Journal of Exercise Science 12, no. 1: 590&#x2013;601. https://doi.org/10.70252/MONR8675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakai, T., M. Tamaki, T. Nakamura, T. Nakai, A. Onishi, and K. Hashimoto. 2013. &#x201c;Controlling Pain After Total Knee Arthroplasty Using a Multimodal Protocol With Local Periarticular Injections.&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedics 10, no. 2: 92&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jor.2013.02.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi, F., D. K. White, L. Snyder&#x2010;Mackler, and J. A. Zeni. 2020. &#x201c;Restoring Physical Function After Knee Replacement: A Cross Sectional Comparison of Progressive Strengthening vs Standard Physical Therapy.&#x201d; Physiotherapy Theory and Practice 36, no. 1: 122&#x2013;133. https://doi.org/10.1080/09593985.2018.1479475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese, N. B., and W. D. Bandy. 2016. Joint Range of Motion and Muscle Length Testing&#x2010;E&#x2010;Book: Joint Range of Motion and Muscle Length Testing&#x2010;E&#x2010;Book. Elsevier Health Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo, S.&#x2010;C., J.&#x2010;Y. Choi, M.&#x2010;Y. Joo, J.&#x2010;H. Kim, and S.&#x2010;K. Chang. 2012. &#x201c;Effects of Sling Exercise and McKenzie Exercise Program on Neck Disability, Pain, Muscle Strength and Range of Motion in Chronic Neck Pain.&#x201d; Physical Therapy Rehabilitation Science 1, no. 1: 40&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani, M., S. Barkhordari, F. Mardam, N. Shaarbafchizadeh, and F. Naghavi&#x2010;Al&#x2010;Hosseini. 2020. &#x201c;Rationing Access to Total Hip and Total Knee Replacement in the Islamic Republic of Iran to Reduce Unnecessary Costs: Policy Brief.&#x201d; Eastern Mediterranean Health Journal 26, no. 11: 1396&#x2013;1402. https://doi.org/10.26719/emhj.20.109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayfur, A., F. &#xd6;zyurt, M. &#x130;. Kodak, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;The Efficacy of Pain Neuroscience Education in Patients After Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Single Blind Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Physiotherapy Theory and Practice 41, no. 12: 1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1080/09593985.2025.2526025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubach, F., P. Ravaud, G. Baron, et&#xa0;al. 2005. &#x201c;Evaluation of Clinically Relevant Changes in Patient Reported Outcomes in Knee and Hip Osteoarthritis: The Minimal Clinically Important Improvement.&#x201d; Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 64, no. 1: 29&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1136/ard.2004.022905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C., Z. Gu, J. Yu, P. Zhang, and F. Yang. 2022. &#x201c;Clinical Observation of Long Chiropractic Treatment on Patients With Neurogenic Cervical Spondylosis: Study Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Medicine 101, no. 9: e28861. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000028861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, T., D. Yang, K. Liu, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Efficacy and Safety of a Self&#x2010;Developed Home&#x2010;Based Enhanced Knee Flexion Exercise Program Compared With Standard Supervised Physiotherapy to Improve Mobility and Quality of Life After Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Randomized Control Study.&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research 16, no. 1: 382. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018&#x2010;021&#x2010;02516&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, Y.&#x2010;L., T.&#x2010;K. Su, L.&#x2010;J. Liaw, W.&#x2010;L. Wu, I.&#x2010;H. Chu, and L.&#x2010;Y. Guo. 2015. &#x201c;The Effect of Six Weeks of Sling Exercise Training on Trunk Muscular Strength and Endurance for Clients With Low Back Pain.&#x201d; Journal of Physical Therapy Science 27, no. 8: 2591&#x2013;2596. https://doi.org/10.1589/jpts.27.2591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, B., H. Liu, K. Du, W. Zhou, and Y. Li. 2023. &#x201c;Effectiveness and Safety of Outpatient Rehabilitation Versus Home&#x2010;Based Rehabilitation After Knee Arthroplasty: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research 18, no. 1: 704. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018&#x2010;023&#x2010;04160&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zietek, P., J. Zietek, K. Szczypior, and K. Safranow. 2014. &#x201c;Effect of Adding One 15&#x2010;Minute&#x2010;Walk on the Day of Surgery to Fast&#x2010;Track Rehabilitation After Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Randomized, Single&#x2010;Blind Study.&#x201d; European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine 51, no. 3: 245&#x2013;252. PMID: 25230888.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>