<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41345701</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative evaluation of ChatGPT versions in training program design: scientific approach, accuracy, and practical applicability.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01409-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to comparatively evaluate the scientific approach, accuracy, and practical applicability of different versions of ChatGPT in generating training programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">Adopting a mixed-methods design, the study employed seven distinct instruction sets, each developed with input from seven experts possessing a minimum of 10 years of professional experience (Certified Strength and Conditioning Specialists (CSCS), academicians holding PhDs in Sports Sciences with research focus on exercise physiology and training methodology) in their respective fields. Using these instruction sets, three versions of ChatGPT (ChatGPT-3.5, ChatGPT-4o, and ChatGPT-4.1) were tasked with generating 12-week resistance training programs for a hypothetical, healthy young adult male with a moderate training background. Using a rubric scoring scale, the generated programs were systematically evaluated and scored separately based on the following criteria: compliance with the initial program request, inclusion of literature references, adherence to exercise variety and progressive loading principles, individualization of progression and justification, program modifications, inclusion of warm-up and cool-down components, injury risk considerations, presence of incorrect recommendations and practical applicability, and accessibility.To determine whether differences in mean scores were statistically significant, the Friedman non-parametric test was applied. When significant differences were identified, pairwise comparisons were conducted using the Wilcoxon signed-rank test to determine which groups accounted for these differences. In addition, qualitative data analysis was performed to explore expert evaluations in depth, employing both content analysis and descriptive analysis techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Statistically significant differences were identified among the ChatGPT versions examined in this study: between ChatGPT-4o and ChatGPT-3.5 (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.018), ChatGPT-4.1 and ChatGPT-3.5 (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.018), and ChatGPT-4.1 and ChatGPT-4o (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.018). Expert content analysis further indicated that ChatGPT-4.1 produced responses that were more detailed, internally consistent, and better supported by scientific literature compared to the other versions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although the ChatGPT versions examined in this study exhibited certain limitations, they demonstrated the potential to deliver structured exercise programs aligned with established training principles and relevant scientific literature. Nonetheless, to ensure that AI-assisted training plans provide safe, evidence-based, and individualized content, the involvement of qualified human expertise remains essential.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">No official trial registration number was assigned.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gen&#xe7;</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#xe7;a</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2498-7092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bart&#x131;n University, Faculty of Sport Science, Bartin, T&#xfc;rkiye. aycagenc@bartin.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayd&#x131;n</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf6;khan Recep</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8755-226X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bart&#x131;n University, Faculty of Sport Science, Bartin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasap</LastName><ForeName>Murat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4740-7118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bart&#x131;n University, Faculty of Sport Science, Bartin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zkan</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2859-2824</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yozgat Bozok University, Faculty of Sport Science, Yozgat, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakhymzhanov</LastName><ForeName>Alpamys</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7261-8641</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Khoja Akhmet Yassawi International Kazakh-Turkish University, Turkekistan, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;rcan</LastName><ForeName>Hasan H&#xfc;seyin</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2319-0981</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bart&#x131;n University, Faculty of Sport Science, Bartin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;ll&#xfc;</LastName><ForeName>Sevim</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8027-8891</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul University-Cerrahpa&#x15f;a, Faculty of Sport Science, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demirhan</LastName><ForeName>Bilal</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3063-9863</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kyrgyz-Turkish Manas University, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-Assisted coaching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise program design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This research is exempt from ethics committee approval. Ethics committee exemption approval was obtained from Bartin University Social and Human Sciences Ethics Committee (approval: 2025/E-23688910-050.04.04-2500092548). The ethics committee stated, &#x201c;The content, method, and data collection process of the research were reviewed; it was determined that no data was collected directly from living individuals within the scope of the study. Therefore, there is no need for ethics committee approval for this research.&#x201d; Although the study did not involve direct interaction with human subjects, the principles of research ethics and academic integrity were respected throughout, in alignment with the general spirit of the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained prior to the participation of expert contributors. Experts who provided input were assured of the confidentiality and anonymity of their responses, and their right to withdraw from the study at any time without any consequences. Not applicable (no data was collected directly from living individuals within the scope of the study). Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41345701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12797729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01409-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01409-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Varner C. Understanding different ChatGPT models: key details to consider. Team AI. 2025. Available from:&#xa0;https://teamai.com/blog/large-language-models-llms/understanding-different-chatgpt-models/. Cited 15 Jul 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Pagaduan J, James C, Dergaa I, Beaven CM. Artificial intelligence in sport: exploring the potential of using ChatGPT in resistance training prescription. Biol Sport. 2024;41(2):209&#x2013;20. 10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenAI. OpenAI. Available from:&#xa0;https://openai.com/. Cited 15 Jul 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani M, Majedi N, Hemmatinejad M, Jamshidi A. Application of artificial intelligence in the sports industry: a review article. AI Tech Behav Soc Sci. 2024;2(2):20&#x2013;7. 10.61838/kman.aitech.2.2.4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61838/kman.aitech.2.2.4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallam M. ChatGPT utility in healthcare education, research, and practice: systematic review on the promising perspectives and valid concerns. Healthcare. 2023;11(6):887. 10.3390/healthcare11060887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11060887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayed AM, Mansur NSB, de Carvalho KA, et al. Artificial intelligence and chatgpt in orthopaedics and sports medicine. J Exp Orthop. 2023;10:74. 10.1186/s40634-023-00642-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40634-023-00642-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10371934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37493985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7; N. Artificial intelligence in physical education and sports: new horizons with ChatGPT. Mediterranean J Sport Sci. 2023;6(1):17&#x2013;32. 10.38021/asbid.1291604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.38021/asbid.1291604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;king P, Sperlich B, Voigt L, van Hooren B, Zanini M, Zinner C. ChatGPT-generated training plans for runners are not rated optimal by coaching experts, but increase in quality with additional input information. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23:56&#x2013;72. 10.52082/jssm.2024.56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.56</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10915606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guelmami N, Fekih-Romdhane F, Mechraoui O, Bragazzi N. Injury prevention, optimized training and rehabilitation: how is AI reshaping the field of sports medicine. North Asian J Med. 2023;1(1):30&#x2013;4. 10.61186/najm.1.1.30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61186/najm.1.1.30</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terblanche NH. Comparing artificial intelligence and human coaching goal attainment efficacy. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(7):e0270255. 10.1371/journal.pone.0270255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0270255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35727801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, D&#xfc;king P, Leppich R, Holmberg HC. Strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats associated with the application of artificial intelligence in connection with sport research, coaching, and optimization of athletic performance: a brief SWOT analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1258562. 10.3389/fspor.2023.1258562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1258562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10618674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37920303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;king P, Achtzehn S, Holmberg HC, Sperlich B. Integrated framework of load monitoring by a combination of smartphone applications, wearables and point-of-care testing provides feedback that allows individual responsive adjustments to activities of daily living. Sensors. 2018;18(5):1632. 10.3390/s18051632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18051632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5981295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29783763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H. Neural network-oriented big data model for yoga movement recognition. Comput Intell Neurosci. 2021;2021:10. 10.1155/2021/4334024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/4334024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8572125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Qin S, Ren D. Artificial intelligence coaches on the sidelines: evaluating readability and quality of soccer training plans from six generative models. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2025;17479541251369593. 10.1177/17479541251369593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed DK, Nashwan AJ. Harnessing artificial intelligence in lifestyle medicine: opportunities, challenges, and future directions. Cureus. 2025;17(6):e85580. 10.7759/cureus.85580. PMID: 40636636; PMCID: PMC12238731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.85580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12238731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40636636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Zhang X, Li H, Ye J. More details, less variability? A crossover design study on the impact of information granularity on chatgpt&#x2019;s training program stability. Biol Sport. 2026;43(1):379&#x2013;92. 10.5114/biolsport.2026.154148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.154148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Saad HB, El Omri A. Using artificial intelligence for exercise prescription in personalised health promotion: a critical evaluation of OpenAI&#x2019;s GPT-4 model. Biol Sport. 2024;41(2):221&#x2013;41. 10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saadati S. The need for more attention to the validity and reliability of AI-generated exercise programs. Health Nexus. 2023;1(1):77&#x2013;81. 10.61838/kman.hn.1.1.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61838/kman.hn.1.1.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7; A, Aydin R, Canuzakov K, Abdurrahmanova D, G&#xfc;rcan HH, Dere G, et al. Digital coaches: an alternative to expert coaches for men&#x2019;s fitness goals. Phys Act Rev. 2025;13(2):35&#x2013;44. 10.16926/par.2025.13.18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16926/par.2025.13.18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karasar N. Scientific research method: concepts, principles, and techniques. 1st ed. Ankara: Nobel; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, Izquierdo M, Kraemer WJ, Peterson MD, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2019&#x2013;52. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 11th ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering statistics using SPSS. 3rd ed. London: SAGE; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparkes AC, Smith B. Qualitative research methods in sport, exercise and health: from process to product. 1st ed. London: Routledge; 2013. 10.4324/9780203852187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havers T, Masur L, Isenmann E, Geisler S, Zinner C, Sperlich B, et al. Reproducibility and quality of hypertrophy-related training plans generated by GPT-4 and Google Gemini as evaluated by coaching experts. Biol Sport. 2025;42(2):289&#x2013;329. 10.5114/biolsport.2025.145911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.145911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Liu Q, Pang J, Zeng C, Ma X, Li P, Xie H, et al. Assessment of personalized exercise prescriptions issued by ChatGPT 4.0 and intelligent health promotion systems for patients with hypertension comorbidities based on the transtheoretical model: a comparative analysis. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2024;17:5063&#x2013;78. 10.2147/JMDH.S477452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JMDH.S477452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11559245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39539514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M, Lim ZW, Pushpanathan K, Cheung CY, Wang YX, Chen D, et al. Review of emerging trends and projection of future developments in large language models research in ophthalmology. Br J Ophthalmol. 2024;108(10):1362&#x2013;70. 10.1136/bjo-2023-324734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38164563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaleski AL, Berkowsky R, Craig KJT, Pescatello LS. Comprehensiveness, accuracy, and readability of exercise recommendations provided by an AI-based chatbot: mixed methods study. JMIR Med Educ. 2024;10:e51308. 10.2196/51308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/51308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38206661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masagca RC. The AI coach: a 5-week AI-generated calisthenics training program on health-related physical fitness components of untrained collegiate students. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2025;20(1):39&#x2013;56. https://orcid.org/0009-0009-3390-2995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55860/13v7e679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puce L, Bragazzi NL, Curr&#xe0; A, Trompetto C. Harnessing generative artificial intelligence for exercise and training prescription: applications and implications in sports and physical activity&#x2014;a systematic literature review. Appl Sci (Basel). 2025;15(7):3497. 10.3390/app15073497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15073497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateo-Orcajada A, Vaquero-Crist&#xf3;bal R, Abenza-Cano L. Gender and academic year as moderators of the efficacy of mobile app interventions to promote physical activity in adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. Humanit Soc Sci Commun. 2023;10:980. 10.1057/s41599-023-02502-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-023-02502-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachholz F, Manno S, Schlachter D, Gamper N, Schnitzer M. Acceptance and trust in AI-generated exercise plans among recreational athletes and quality evaluation by experienced coaches: a pilot study. BMC Res Notes. 2025;18(1):112. 10.1186/s13104-025-07172-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-025-07172-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11908068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40082991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erol E, Ar&#x131;kan H. Does ChatGPT provide comprehensive and accurate information regarding the effects, types, and programming of core exercises? Turk J Kinesiol. 2024;10(3):178&#x2013;82. 10.31459/turkjkin.1516614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31459/turkjkin.1516614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philuek P, Kusump S, Sathianpoonsook T, Jansupom C, Sawanyawisuth P, Sawanyawisuth K, Chainarong A. The effects of ChatGPT-generated exercise program in healthy overweight young adults: a pilot study. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2025;20(1):169&#x2013;79. 10.55860/1epqgp77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55860/1epqgp77</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Geng W, Huang L, Qin X, Chen Z, Yan H. Who could and should give exercise prescription: physicians, exercise and health scientists, fitness trainers, or chatgpt? J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(3):368&#x2013;72. 10.1016/j.jshs.2024.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2024.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38176646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>