<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41517711</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strategies for overcoming challenges in implementing simulation in medical education: A qualitative leadership perspective.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47113</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47113</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47113</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047113</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Implementing simulation-based education in medical curricula presents distinct challenges, especially for educators newly assuming leadership roles. This study aimed to explore the lived experiences of medical educators who are simulation center leaders to understand the nature of the challenges they encountered and to offer strategic insights for other leaders navigating similar transitions. A qualitative, phenomenological research design was employed. Data were collected from 4 simulation leaders through semi-structured interviews, reflective writings, and institutional documents. Interpretative phenomenological analysis was used to explore how participants made sense of their experiences. An external qualitative expert contributed to the coding and analysis process to ensure trustworthiness. Three major themes emerged: First, the role of the medical educator as a leader: participants reported shifting from being content experts to reflective leaders, emphasizing strategic vision, emotional intelligence, and educational theory. Second, team spirit: the presence of a dedicated team and shared moral purpose supported resilience and collaboration. Communication strategies and informal advocacy strengthened engagement. Third, understanding the challenges: faculty resistance, institutional inertia, and limited resources were viewed through an empathetic lens. Participants addressed resistance via faculty development, research collaboration, and ongoing feedback mechanisms. Finally, institutional support and leadership alignment: administrative support was pivotal in legitimizing efforts and sustaining initiatives. Leadership continuity, policy alignment, and access to decision-making platforms shaped the success of simulation integration. Leadership in health professions education, particularly in simulation-based implementation, requires more than subject expertise; it demands emotional resilience, strategic communication, and relationship-building. Findings suggest that simulation-based change requires not only technical knowledge but also adaptive leadership grounded in context and collaboration. Leaders navigated resistance not as defiance, but as a sign of systemic gaps in understanding and preparation. The study emphasizes the importance of aligning simulation efforts with institutional structures and culture to achieve lasting transformation in medical education.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delibalta</LastName><ForeName>Bilge</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8350-4463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health Sciences, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daylan</LastName><ForeName>Pinar</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0116-8986</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Kocaeli University, &#x130;zmit, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007857" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leadership</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Simulation Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Faculty, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003479" MajorTopicYN="N">Curriculum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">change management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leadership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simulation-based education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41517711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12795081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202601090-00058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gaba DM. The future vision of simulation in health care. Qual Saf Health Care. 2004;13(Suppl 1):i2&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1765792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanwick T. Association for the study of medical education. In: Understanding Medical Education: Evidence, Theory and Practice. 2nd ed. Wiley Blackwell; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motola I, Devine LA, Chung HS, Sullivan JE, Issenberg SB. Simulation in healthcare education: a best evidence practical guide. AMEE Guide No. 82. Med Teach. 2013;35:e1511&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23941678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bearman M, Greenhill J, Nestel D. The power of simulation: a large-scale narrative analysis of learners&#x2019; experiences. Med Educ. 2019;53:369&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30334299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delibalta B, Delibalta ME. Reflections of simulation-based education on the national core curriculum of Turkey: a content analysis. Arch Curr Med Res. 2025;6:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nestel D, Bearman M. Simulated Patient Methodology: Theory, Evidence and Practice. 1st ed. Wiley; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland JA, Durning SJ. Researching Medical Education. 2nd ed. Wiley Blackwell; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanwick T, Forrest K, O&#x2019;Brien BC. Association for the Study of Medical Education. In: Understanding Medical Education: Evidence, Theory and Practice. 3rd ed. Wiley; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKimm J, Ramani S, Forrest K, et al. Adaptive leadership during challenging times: Effective strategies for health professions educators: AMEE Guide No. 148. Med Teach. 2023;45:128&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35543323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eppich W, Cheng A. Promoting excellence and reflective learning in simulation [PEARLS]: development and rationale for a blended approach to health care simulation debriefing. Simul Healthc. 2015;10:106&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25710312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussin CJ, Weinstock P. SimZones: an organizational innovation for simulation programs and centers. Acad Med. 2017;92:1114&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrukh K, Zehra F, Shahid F, Mehr Y. Health sciences faculty attitude and readiness towards simulation-based inter-professional education. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2024;34:212&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38342874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordquist J, Sundberg K. Institutional needs and faculty development for simulation. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol. 2015;29:13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25902462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert Y, Naismith L, Mann K. Faculty development initiatives designed to promote leadership in medical education. A BEME systematic review: BEME Guide No. 19. Med Teach. 2012;34:483&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22578043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert Y, Mann K, Anderson B, et al. A systematic review of faculty development initiatives designed to enhance teaching effectiveness: A 10-year update: BEME Guide No. 40. Med Teach. 2016;38:769&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27420193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell JW, Creswell JD. Research Design: Qualitative, Quantitative, and Mixed Methods Approaches. Sage Publications; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani S, Mann K. Introducing medical educators to qualitative study design: twelve tips from inception to completion. Med Teach. 2016;38:456&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25897710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons E, Coyle A. Analysing Qualitative Data in Psychology. Sage; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eatough V, Smith JA. Interpretative phenomenological analysis. In: The Sage Handbook of Qualitative Research in Psychology. Sage; 2017:193&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law RWM, Shafey O. The nature of interpretive phenomenological reflective practice for junior doctors. Reflective Pract. 2019;20:654&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis MH, Karunathilake I, Harden RM. AMEE Education Guide no. 28: The development and role of departments of medical education. Med Teach. 2005;27:665&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16451885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanwick T. Leadership in medical education. In: Swanwick T, O&#x2019;Brien BC, Forrest K, eds. Understanding Medical Education: Evidence, Theory, and Practice. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2018:151&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullan M. Leading in a Culture of Change. 1st ed. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Incorporated; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosun N, Ulusoy H. The relationship of organizational commitment, job satisfaction and burnout on physicians and nurses? J Econ Manag. 2017;28:90&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller CL, Cyr G, Bank I, et al. The Steinberg Centre for Simulation and Interactive Learning at McGill University. J Surg Educ. 2017;74:1135&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28688969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paige JT, Garbee DD, Yu Q, Rusnak V. Team training of inter-professional students [TTIPS] for improving teamwork. BMJ Simul Technol Enhanc Learn. 2017;3:127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8936634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35517834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams SE, Dewey CM. Identification of training opportunities in medical education for academic faculty. Med Teach. 2019;41:912&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30957598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deneen C, Boud D. Patterns of resistance in managing assessment change. Assess Eval High Educ. 2014;39:577&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moizer J, Lean J, Towler M, Abbey C. Simulations and games: overcoming the barriers to their use in higher education. Active Learning Higher Educ. 2009;10:207&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts PI, Peterson T, Brown M, et al. Faculty reflections on effective strategies utilized to implement simulation-enhanced IPE for future health care providers. Clin Simul Nurs. 2020;46:22&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden RM, Crosby JR, Davis MH, Friedman M. AMEE Guide No. 14: outcome-based education: part 5-From competency to meta-competency: a model for the specification of learning outcomes. Med Teach. 1999;21:546&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21281173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland J, Walker KG, Gale M, Nicol LG. Simulation&#x2010;based education: understanding the socio&#x2010;cultural complexity of a surgical training &#x201c;boot camp&#x201d;. Med Educ. 2016;50:829&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27402043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DA, Hatala R. Validation of educational assessments: a primer for simulation and beyond. Adv Simul. 2016;1:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29450000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney S, Haines T. Issues of cost-benefit and cost-effectiveness for simulation in health professions education. Adv Simul. 2016;1:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29449982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGaghie WC, Issenberg SB, Petrusa ER, Scalese RJ. A critical review of simulation-based medical education research: 2003&#x2013;2009. Med Educ. 2010;44:50&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20078756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo RA, Molloy E, Allen KJ, Francis J, Story D. Leaders&#x2019; experiences of embedding a simulation-based education programme in a teaching hospital: an interview study informed by normalisation process theory. Adv Simul. 2024;9:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11106868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38769574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenman ED, Vrablik MC, Brolliar SM, Chipman A, Fernandez R. Targeted simulation-based leadership training for trauma team leaders. Simul Healthc. 2019;20:520&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6526881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az-Navarro C, Armstrong R, Charnetski M, et al. Global consensus statement on simulation-based practice in h ealthcare. Clin Simul Nurs. 2024;93:101552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38771674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>