<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41188888</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Educating for equity, navigating reality: community health nurses implementing interventions to eradicate Chhaupadi in Karnali, Nepal.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1368</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1368</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1368</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-025-04012-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Chhaupadi&#x2014;a customary practice of menstrual seclusion rooted in notions of ritual impurity&#x2014;persists in parts of Nepal, including Karnali Province, despite legal prohibition. Contemporary evidence has associated this practice with adverse health risks and psychosocial distress among women and girls. Community Health Registered Nurses (CHRNs) operate on the frontline of health services and are strategically positioned to deliver educational interventions addressing Chhaupadi. However, their specific experiences in designing and implementing such interventions, as well as the challenges and perceived effectiveness within this complex context, remain critically under&#x2011;explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This qualitative study employed an interpretive description approach. In-depth, semi-structured interviews were conducted with eleven CHRNs, selected based on purposive sampling for their active involvement in Chhaupadi eradication efforts. Initial participant recruitment utilized convenience sampling through self-registration via advertised flyers, which was supplemented by snowball sampling to reach more participants. An overarching maximum variation strategy guided the final sample composition to ensure diverse perspectives. Data were analyzed inductively through thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Four interconnected themes emerged, depicting the operational realities faced by CHRNs: (1) Capacity Building at the Frontline, illustrating their pedagogical adaptations and culturally sensitive communication strategies; (2) Addressing Gaps and Navigating Complex Realities, highlighting the necessity for direct CHRN&#x2019;s interventions and the intricacies of stakeholder engagement amid concealed practices; (3) Gauging Ripple Effects, revealing the profound challenges in measuring training effectiveness and defining success within an environment characterized by systemic ambiguities; and (4) Navigating System Constraints, detailing the impact of resource scarcity, policy&#x2013;practice gaps, enduring cultural resistance, and workforce instability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study reveals the multifaceted interplay between CHRN&#x2019;s agency, community dynamics, and broader systemic factors in efforts to eradicate Chhaupadi. The results emphasize the need for targeted CHRN&#x2019;s support, culturally congruent intervention design, enhanced resource allocation, and inter-sectoral collaboration to ensure effective policy enforcement and sustainable program delivery. By illuminating the frontline challenges of translating health education policy into practice, these findings contribute critical evidence for advancing health equity and gender equality in Nepal and similarly affected contexts, reinforcing the essential role of Community Health Registered Nurses as skilled facilitators and strategic navigators of social change.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghimire</LastName><ForeName>Animesh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2167-5771</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sustainable Prosperity Initiative Nepal, Bhimsengola, Thulo Kharibot, Baneshwor-31, Kathmandu, Nepal. animesh.ghimire@spinepal.com.np.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Chitwan Medical College, Bharatpur-5, Kailashnagar, Chitwan, Nepal. animesh.ghimire@spinepal.com.np.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Chitwan Medical College, Bharatpur-5, Kailashnagar, Chitwan, Nepal. animesh.ghimire@spinepal.com.np.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neupane</LastName><ForeName>Mamata Sharma</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-4408-198X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Chitwan Medical College, Bharatpur-5, Kailashnagar, Chitwan, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Chitwan Medical College, Bharatpur-5, Kailashnagar, Chitwan, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Capacity building</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gender equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health policy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human rights</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stakeholder participation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical clearance was obtained from the Nepal Health Research Council (approval number &#x2013; 332/2024) and District Health Offices in Jajarkot and West Rukum districts. Written voluntary informed consent was obtained from each participant, who was assured of their right to withdraw from the study at any time. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41188888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12584512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-04012-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-025-04012-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thakuri DS, Thapa RK, Singh S, Khanal GN, Khatri RB. A harmful religio-cultural practice (Chhaupadi) during menstruation among adolescent girls in nepal: prevalence and policies for eradication. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(9):e0256968. 10.1371/journal.pone.0256968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0256968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34469491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi S, Acharya Y. Women&#x2019;s extreme seclusion during menstruation and children&#x2019;s health in Nepal. PLOS Global Public Health. 2022;2(7):e0000355. 10.1371/journal.pgph.0000355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0000355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bam AB. Negotiating pathways for the continuation of Chhaupadi system in remote parts of Nepal. Contemp Research: Interdisciplinary Acad J. 2020;4(1):3&#x2013;14. 10.3126/craiaj.v4i1.32712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/craiaj.v4i1.32712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amatya P, Ghimire S, Callahan KE, Baral BK, Poudel KC. Practice and lived experience of menstrual exiles (Chhaupadi) among adolescent girls in far-western Nepal. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(12):e0208260. 10.1371/journal.pone.0208260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0208260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6287853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30532183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary A. The menstrual impurity of women and girls: Chhaupadi practice and resistance. Asian J Popul Sci. 2023;2(1):90&#x2013;106. 10.3126/ajps.v2i1.51094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/ajps.v2i1.51094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee A, Lama M, Khakurel U, Jha AN, Ajose F, Acharya S, et al. Perception and practices of menstruation restrictions among urban adolescent girls and women in nepal: a cross-sectional survey. Reproductive Health. 2020;17(1):81. 10.1186/s12978-020-00935-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-020-00935-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7268527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32487096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serajuddin U, Hamadeh N. New World Bank country classifications by income level: 2020&#x2013;2021 Washington, DC: World Bank Group; 2020 [cited 2025 11th March]. Available from: https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/opendata/new-world-bank-country-classifications-income-level-2020-2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Group. Climbing Higher: Toward a Middle-Income Nepal Kathmandu: World Bank Group. 2024 [cited 2025 21st March]. Available from: https://www.worldbank.org/en/region/sar/publication/climbing-higher-toward-a-middle-income-country</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>City Population. Karnali: Province in Nepal Germany: City Population; 2021 [cited 2025 26th March ]. Available from: https://citypopulation.de/en/nepal/admin/6__karnali/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire A. Menstrual exile: nepal&#x2019;s Chhaupadi and the Policy-Practice divide. Int J Public Health. 2024. 10.3389/ijph.2024.1608202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ijph.2024.1608202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11682880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39737006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uma S. South Asian feminist engagements with law: some explorations in the context of violence against women. Jindal Global Law Rev. 2019;10(2):197&#x2013;221. 10.1007/s41020-019-00097-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41020-019-00097-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Nepal. Criminal (Code) Act Kathmandu: Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs. 2017 [cited 2025 29th March ]. Available from: https://www.moljpa.gov.np/en/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Penal-Code-English-Revised-1.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahal U, Tamang RL, Dr&#xe6;bel TA, Neupane D, Koirala Adhikari S, Soti PB, et al. Female community health volunteers&#x2019; experience in navigating social context while providing basic diabetes services in Western nepal: social capital and beyond from systems thinking. PLOS Global Public Health. 2023;3(11):e0002632. 10.1371/journal.pgph.0002632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0002632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10664953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37992049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire A. Beyond doctors and hospitals: Nepal&#x2019;s Female Community Health Volunteer model&#x2014;A new paradigm for global health. Front Public Health. 2025;13(2025). 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1587360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12098329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40416700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire A, Qiu Y, Thapa B, Ranabhat M. Exploring the factors affecting undergraduate nursing students&#x2019; migration intention: A qualitative study. Nurse Educ Today. 2024;143:106414. 10.1016/j.nedt.2024.106414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2024.106414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39288606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaya Mental Health. Community nursing &#x2013; a new healthcare workforce in Nepal London: Jaya Mental Health. 2023 [cited 2025 26th March]. Available from: https://jayamentalhealth.org.uk/2021/11/24/community-nursing-a-new-healthcare-workforce-in-nepal/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari Job. CHO, Community Nurse and School Nurse Kathmandu, Nepal KJ. 2024 [cited 2025 29th March]. Available from: https://www.kumarijob.com/administrator/49977-cho-community-nurse-and-school-nurse</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poudel A. Karnali Province to provide nursing care at the community level Kathmandu, Nepal: The Kathmandu Post; 2019 [cited 2025 26th March ]. Available from: https://kathmandupost.com/health/2019/11/05/karnali-province-to-provide-nursing-care-at-the-community-level</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall S, Bryar R, Higginbottom GA. A global approach to promoting research and evidence-based practice for community nurses. Br J Community Nurs. 2024;29(1):16&#x2013;9. 10.12968/bjcn.2024.29.1.16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/bjcn.2024.29.1.16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38147451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukewich J, Asghari S, Marshall EG, Mathews M, Swab M, Tranmer J, et al. Effectiveness of registered nurses on system outcomes in primary care: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):440. 10.1186/s12913-022-07662-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-07662-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panday S, Bissell P, van Teijlingen E, Simkhada P. The contribution of female community health volunteers (FCHVs) to maternity care in nepal: a qualitative study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2017;17(1):623. 10.1186/s12913-017-2567-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-017-2567-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5584032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28870185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann SE, RM A, Mary H, Bhimsen D, Kajol U, Raj SG, et al. From stigma to solutions: Harnessing local wisdom to tackle harms associated with menstrual seclusion (chhaupadi) in Nepal. Cult Health Sex. 2025;27(3):299&#x2013;320. 10.1080/13691058.2024.2373793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13691058.2024.2373793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11701209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betron M, Anil T, Roshani A, Kusum T, Elizabeth A-P, Anne S, et al. Should female community health volunteers (FCHVs) facilitate a response to gender-based violence (GBV)? A mixed methods exploratory study in Mangalsen, Nepal. Glob Public Health. 2021;16(10):1604&#x2013;17. 10.1080/17441692.2020.1839929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17441692.2020.1839929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33186506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyaguchi M, Yasuoka J, Poudyal AK, Silwal RC, Jimba M. Female community health volunteers service utilization for childhood illness- improving quality of health services only is not enough: a cross-sectional study in mid-western region, Nepal. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14(1):383. 10.1186/1472-6963-14-383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-14-383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4168066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhurtel KK, Basnet P, Sigdel S, Magar KJ, Ghimire SR, Paudel GR. Health equity through structural adjustment by Nepal for public health. Orchid Acad Siraha. 2023;2(1):80&#x2013;6. 10.3126/oas.v2i1.65607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/oas.v2i1.65607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns M, Bally J, Burles M, Holtslander L, Peacock S. Constructivist grounded theory or interpretive phenomenology? Methodological choices within specific study contexts. Int J Qualitative Methods. 2022;21:16094069221077758. 10.1177/16094069221077758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069221077758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle L, McCabe C, Keogh B, Brady A, McCann M. An overview of the qualitative descriptive design within nursing research. J Res Nurs. 2020;25(5):443&#x2013;55. 10.1177/1744987119880234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1744987119880234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34394658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocean M, Montgomery R, Jamison Z, Hicks K, Thorne S. Exploring the expansive properties of interpretive description: an invitation to anti-oppressive researchers. Int J Qualitative Methods. 2022;21:16094069221103665. 10.1177/16094069221103665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069221103665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devkota H. Rural general surgical care in a remote area of nepal: our experience at Karnali academy of health Sciences, Jumla. J Karnali Acad Health Sci. 2019;1(1):13&#x2013;6. https://jkahs.org.np/jkahs/index.php/jkahs/article/view/121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jkahs.v1i1.24305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Nepal. SDG baseline report of Karnali Province Kathmandu, Nepal: United Nations. 2021 [cited 2025 26th March]. Available from: https://un.org.np/resource/sdg-baseline-report-karnali-province</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palinkas LA, Horwitz SM, Green CA, Wisdom JP, Duan N, Hoagwood K. Purposeful sampling for qualitative data collection and analysis in mixed method implementation research. Adm Policy Ment Health. 2015;42(5):533&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s10488-013-0528-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10488-013-0528-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4012002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24193818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton SJ. Population research: convenience sampling strategies. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2021;36(4):373&#x2013;4. 10.1017/S1049023X21000649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1049023X21000649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34284835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu A, Baysari MT, Stocker SL, Leow LJ, Day RO, Carland JE. Researchers&#x2019; views on, and experiences with, the requirement to obtain informed consent in research involving human participants: a qualitative study. BMC Med Ethics. 2020;21(1):93. 10.1186/s12910-020-00538-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12910-020-00538-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7531157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderifar M, Goli H, Ghaljaie F. Snowball sampling: a purposeful method of sampling in qualitative research. Strides Dev Med Educ. 2017;14(3). 10.5812/sdme.67670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapley T, The SAGE Handbook of Qualitative Data Analysis. 2014 2024/09/13. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; [49&#x2013;63]. Available from: https://methods.sagepub.com/book/the-sage-handbook-of-qualitative-data-analysis</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadka BK. English in education in nepal: A comprehensive overview. J NELTA Gandaki. 2024;7(1&#x2013;2):43&#x2013;55. 10.3126/jong.v7i1-2.70184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jong.v7i1-2.70184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elo S, Kyng&#xe4;s H. The qualitative content analysis process. J Adv Nurs. 2008;62(1):107&#x2013;15. 10.1111/j.1365-2648.2007.04569.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2648.2007.04569.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18352969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V. Toward good practice in thematic analysis: avoiding common problems and be(com)ing a knowing researcher. Int J Transgender Health. 2023;24(1):1&#x2013;6. 10.1080/26895269.2022.2129597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26895269.2022.2129597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9879167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36713144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi S, Khatooni M. Saturation in qualitative research: an evolutionary concept analysis. Int J Nurs Stud Adv. 2024;6:100174. 10.1016/j.ijnsa.2024.100174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnsa.2024.100174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11080421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38746797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. To saturate or not to saturate? Questioning data saturation as a useful concept for thematic analysis and sample-size rationales. Qualitative Res Sport Exerc Health. 2021;13(2):201&#x2013;16. 10.1080/2159676X.2019.1704846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2019.1704846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasileiou K, Barnett J, Thorpe S, Young T. Characterising and justifying sample size sufficiency in interview-based studies: systematic analysis of qualitative health research over a 15-year period. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):148. 10.1186/s12874-018-0594-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-018-0594-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6249736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30463515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forero R, Nahidi S, De Costa J, Mohsin M, Fitzgerald G, Gibson N, et al. Application of four-dimension criteria to assess rigour of qualitative research in emergency medicine. BMC Health Serv Res. 2018;18(1):120. 10.1186/s12913-018-2915-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-018-2915-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5816375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29454350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urry K, Anna C-H, Scholz B. From member checking to collaborative reflection: a novel way to use a familiar method for engaging participants in qualitative research. Qualitative Res Psychol. 2024;21(3):357&#x2013;74. 10.1080/14780887.2024.2355972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14780887.2024.2355972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan-Trimmer S, Wood F. Ethnographic methods for process evaluations of complex health behaviour interventions. Trials. 2016;17(1):232. 10.1186/s13063-016-1340-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-016-1340-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27142662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmos-Vega FM, SR E, Lara V, Kahlke R. A practical guide to reflexivity in qualitative research: AMEE guide 149. Med Teach. 2023;45(3):241&#x2013;51. 10.1080/0142159X.2022.2057287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2022.2057287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35389310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Nursing personnel by sex (%) Geneva: WHO; 2025 [cited 2025 25th March]. Available from: https://www.who.int/data/gho/data/indicators/indicator-details/GHO/nurses-by-sex-(-)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire A, Neupane MS. Between duty and despair: the ethical toll of brain drain on Nepalese nurse managers. BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):229. 10.1186/s12912-025-02878-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-02878-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11869638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40022057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore MN, Patil R, Pathak R. Cultural perspectives on health communication: the case of Katkari tribals in Western Maharashtra, India. In: Aiseng K, Fadipe IA, editors. Public health communication challenges to minority and Indigenous communities. Hershey, PA, USA: IGI Global; 2024. pp. 76&#x2013;91. 10.4018/979-8-3693-0624-6.ch006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udoudom U, Igiri A, George K, Aruku KJ. Promoting health education through effective communication for development. J Educ Technol. 2023;2(1):68&#x2013;88. 10.58578/alsystech.v2i1.2399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58578/alsystech.v2i1.2399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki TB, Khadka K. False belief and harmful cultural practices of Chhaupadi system in Nepal. Nepal J Multidisciplinary Res. 2019;2(3):19&#x2013;24. 10.3126/njmr.v2i3.26971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/njmr.v2i3.26971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah DK, Maharjan SK. Chhaupadi practice in Chaukune surkhet district through the lens of shamanism and bandura&#x2019;s social learning theory. Mangal Res J. 2024;5(01):47&#x2013;56. 10.3126/mrj.v5i01.73484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/mrj.v5i01.73484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavrilets S, Tverskoi D, S&#xe1;nchez A. Modelling social norms: an integration of the norm-utility approach with beliefs dynamics. Philosophical Trans Royal Soc B: Biol Sci. 2024;379(1897):1&#x2013;16. 10.1098/rstb.2023.0027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rstb.2023.0027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10799741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38244599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamin P, Fei M, Lahlou S, Levy S. Using social norms to change behavior and increase sustainability in the real world: a systematic review of the literature. Sustainability. 2019;11(20):5847. https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/11/20/5847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su11205847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminah S, Mahmudiono T. Application of the leadership model in health services: a systematic review. J Public Health Afr. 2023;14(2):6. 10.4081/jphia.2023.2571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/jphia.2023.2571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez AR, Hurtig A-K, Dahlblom K, San Sebasti&#xe1;n M. More than a checklist: a realist evaluation of supervision of mid-level health workers in rural Guatemala. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14(1):112. 10.1186/1472-6963-14-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-14-112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3973852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24602196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masefield SC, Msosa A, Chinguwo FK, Grugel J. Stakeholder engagement in the health policy process in a low income country: a qualitative study of stakeholder perceptions of the challenges to effective inclusion in Malawi. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):984. 10.1186/s12913-021-07016-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-07016-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauer PJJ, Neubauer D. Female genital mutilation: a hidden epidemic (statement from the European academy of Paediatrics). Eur J Pediatrics. 2014;173(2):237&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00431-013-2126-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-013-2126-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinde R, Dalvi K. Genital mutilation in India - An evil practice. Int J Multidisciplinary Res. 2022;4(6):1&#x2013;18. 10.36948/ijfmr.2022.v04i06.1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36948/ijfmr.2022.v04i06.1099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guetterman TC, Fetters MD, Creswell JW, in Health Science Mixed Methods Research Through Joint Displays. Integrating quantitative and qualitative results. Annals Family Med. 2015;13(6):554&#x2013;61. 10.1370/afm.1865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.1865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4639381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasti SP, Simkhada P, van Teijlingen E, Sathian B, Banerjee I. The growing importance of Mixed-Methods research in health. Nepal J Epidemiol. 2022;12(1):1175&#x2013;8. 10.3126/nje.v12i1.43633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/nje.v12i1.43633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9057171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35528457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balogun AK, Atta JA, Oyetubo OM, Ibiam VA, Bakare-Adesokan KA, Ojo TO. Developing culturally competent models for inclusive social work and healthcare interventions. 2025;14(1):1396&#x2013;406. 10.30574/ijsra.2025.14.1.0226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair L, Adetayo OA. Cultural competence and ethnic diversity in Healthcare. Plastic and reconstructive surgery. &#x2013; Global Open. 2019;7(5):e2219. 10.1097/gox.0000000000002219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/gox.0000000000002219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, McCall-Hosenfeld JS, Cuffee Y. Systematic review of menstrual health and hygiene in Nepal employing a social ecological model. Reproductive Health. 2022;19(1):154. 10.1186/s12978-022-01456-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-022-01456-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9245245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35773696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>