<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41934812</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-3984</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>70</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Geriatric nursing (New York, N.Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Geriatr Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Healthcare professionals' perspectives on optimising hip fracture rehabilitation: Insights from the 'Rehabilitation for Life' intervention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104044</StartPage><MedlinePgn>104044</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.gerinurse.2026.104044</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0197-4572(26)00250-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hip fractures in older adults significantly affect functionality, mortality, and healthcare costs. Effective rehabilitation is crucial for restoring mobility and quality of life. However, fragmented rehabilitation processes and discrepancies between patient needs and healthcare services create challenges. This study explores healthcare professionals' experiences with the intervention Rehabilitation for Life, concentrating on optimising rehabilitation strategies for older adults with hip fractures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative study included 16 experienced nurses and physiotherapists from hospitals and municipalities. Data were collected through semi-structured focus group interviews guided by an interview protocol. Thematic analysis was conducted using Malterud's systematic text condensation methodology to identify key themes in participants' responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis revealed three central themes: (1) the importance of structured rehabilitation plans in enhancing outcomes, (2) the transformative role of healthcare centres in providing support and motivation, and (3) the challenge of balancing strength and functionality in patient-centred rehabilitation. These insights specifically relate to the Rehabilitation for Life intervention, demonstrating its impact on rehabilitation strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights the importance of well-structured rehabilitation plans, the pivotal role of healthcare centres, and the necessity of balancing strength training with functional recovery in hip fracture rehabilitation. The findings indicate that a common understanding of rehabilitation processes among healthcare professionals is vital for optimising patient outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PRACTICE IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Prioritising interdisciplinary collaboration, early intervention, and ongoing professional development is essential for enhancing the quality of rehabilitation. Implementing structured yet adaptable rehabilitation programmes within healthcare centres may increase adherence, bolster patient motivation, and support overall recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedersen</LastName><ForeName>Lars Tobiesen</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy, Lillebaelt Hospital, University Hospital of Southern Denmark, Kolding, DK; Department of Regional Health Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, DK; Department for Applied Health Science, University College South Denmark, Esbjerg, DK. Electronic address: ltpe@ucsyd.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ipsen</LastName><ForeName>Jonas Ammundsen</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy, Lillebaelt Hospital, University Hospital of Southern Denmark, Kolding, DK; Department of Regional Health Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, DK; Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Orthopedic Research Unit, Odense and Svendborg University Hospital, DK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egeb&#xe6;k</LastName><ForeName>Heidi Klakk</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Clinical Research and Prevention, Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg Hospital, Frederiksberg, The Capital Region, DK; Department of Applied Health Science, University College Lillebaelt, Odense, DK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Pernille Tanggaard</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Unit for Health Promotion, University of Southern Denmark, Odense &amp; Esbjerg, DK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viberg</LastName><ForeName>Bjarke</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Lillebaelt Hospital, University Hospital of Southern Denmark, Odense, DK; Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Orthopedic Research Unit, Odense and Svendborg University Hospital, DK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruun</LastName><ForeName>Inge H</ForeName><Initials>IH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Occupational Therapy, Lillebaelt Hospital, University Hospital of Southern Denmark, Kolding, DK; Department of Regional Health Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, DK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Geriatr Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8309633</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0197-4572</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare professionals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hip fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intervention &#x2018;Rehabilitation of Life&#x2019;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-centered care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no affiliations with or involvement in any organisation or entity with any financial interest in the subject matter or materials discussed in this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41934812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gerinurse.2026.104044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0197-4572(26)00250-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>