<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41503493</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Upconversion materials: a new frontier in solar water-splitting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1643</StartPage><EndPage>1661</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1643-1661</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra07342a</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Limited utilization of the solar spectrum is a major bottleneck in photocatalytic water-splitting, as most semiconductor photocatalysts only harness UV or visible light, leaving a large fraction of infrared photons unused. Upconversion materials have emerged as a promising solution by converting two or more low-energy photons into a single higher-energy photon, thereby extending the photoresponse of water-splitting systems. This review provides a technical overview of the two leading upconversion strategies for solar hydrogen generation: lanthanide (Ln)-based upconversion phosphors and triplet-triplet annihilation (TTA) upconversion systems, including purely organic and metal-organic approaches. We discuss how Ln-doped upconverters can enable near-infrared-driven photocatalysis, while highlighting their efficiency limitations under 1-sun illumination. We then examine TTA-based upconversion, which leverages molecular sensitizer-emitter pairs to achieve efficient upconversion under solar light intensities, and summarize recent demonstrations of TTA systems boosting H<sub>2</sub> production and even enabling overall water splitting under visible light. A comparative analysis of Ln-based <i>vs.</i> TTA-based systems is presented, underscoring their respective advantages (spectral range, stability, efficiency) and constraints. Finally, we outline future research directions and integration strategies aimed at combining the strengths of both upconversion approaches to maximize solar-to-hydrogen efficiency. The insights from this review suggest that upconversion materials can play a complementary and transformative role in next-generation solar water-splitting technologies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magazov</LastName><ForeName>Yerbolat</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0902-3140</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Lab, National Laboratory Astana Astana 010000 Kazakhstan guldana.zhigerbaeva@nu.edu.kz nurxat.nuraje@nu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of New Materials and Energy Technologies Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aliyev</LastName><ForeName>Asset</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-2471-3757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Lab, National Laboratory Astana Astana 010000 Kazakhstan guldana.zhigerbaeva@nu.edu.kz nurxat.nuraje@nu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of New Materials and Energy Technologies Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhumabay</LastName><ForeName>Nursaya</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Lab, National Laboratory Astana Astana 010000 Kazakhstan guldana.zhigerbaeva@nu.edu.kz nurxat.nuraje@nu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of New Materials and Energy Technologies Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taubaldiyeva</LastName><ForeName>Zhamilya</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, Nazarbayev University Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhigerbayeva</LastName><ForeName>Guldana</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8556-4865</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Lab, National Laboratory Astana Astana 010000 Kazakhstan guldana.zhigerbaeva@nu.edu.kz nurxat.nuraje@nu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of New Materials and Energy Technologies Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nuraje</LastName><ForeName>Nurxat</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4335-8905</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Lab, National Laboratory Astana Astana 010000 Kazakhstan guldana.zhigerbaeva@nu.edu.kz nurxat.nuraje@nu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of New Materials and Energy Technologies Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, Nazarbayev University Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Teqnovate LLC Astana 010000 Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41503493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12771292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra07342a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra07342a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jiang C. Moniz S. J. A. Wang A. Zhang T. Tang J. Photoelectrochemical devices for solar water splitting-materials and challenges. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2017;46:4645&#x2013;4660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28644493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fountaine K. T. Lewerenz H. J. Atwater H. A. Efficiency limits for photoelectrochemical water-splitting. Nat. Commun. 2016;7:13706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5146289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27910847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao L. Zhang Q. Su Z. Zhao Z. Wang Y. Li Y. Lu X. Wei D. Feng G. Yu Q. Cai X. Zhao J. Ren Z. Fang H. Robles-Hernandez F. Baldelli S. Bao J. Efficient solar water-splitting using a nanocrystalline CoO photocatalyst. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2014;9:69&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magazov Y. Aliyev A. Moldabekov K. Kurbanova A. Rakymbekova A. Amze M. Ibrayev N. Kudryashov V. Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting Using Cuprous Oxide (Cu2O)-Based Photocathode &#x2013; A Review. ES Energy &amp; Environment. 2024;26:1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magazov Y., Kudryashov V., Asmatulu D. D. and Nuraje N., in Nanotechnology Safety, ed. R. Asmatulu, W. S. Khan and E. Asmatulu, Elsevier, 2nd edn, 2025, pp. 321&#x2013;333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memmino R. Solar Energy Conversion By Photoelectrochemical Processes. Electrochim. Acta. 1980;25:77&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bard A. J. Fox M. A. Artificial Photosynthesis: Solar Splitting of Water to Hydrogen and Oxygen. Acc. Chem. Res. 1995;28:141&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;tzel M. Photoelectrochemical cells. Nature. 2001;414:338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11713540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B. K. Polity A. Reppin D. Becker M. Hering P. Klar P. J. Sander T. Reindl C. Benz J. Eickhoff M. Heiliger C. Heinemann M. Bl&#xe4;sing J. Krost A. Shokovets S. M&#xfc;ller C. Ronning C. Binary copper oxide semiconductors: From materials towards devices. Phys. Status Solidi B. 2012;249:1487&#x2013;1509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu W. Moehl T. Cui W. Wick-Joliat R. Zhu L. Tilley S. D. Extended Light Harvesting with Dual Cu2O-Based Photocathodes for High Efficiency Water Splitting. Adv. Energy Mater. 2018;8:1702323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siol S. Hellmann J. C. Tilley S. D. Graetzel M. Morasch J. Deuermeier J. Jaegermann W. Klein A. Band Alignment Engineering at Cu2O/ZnO Heterointerfaces. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2016;8:21824&#x2013;21831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27452037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afroz K. Moniruddin M. Bakranov N. Kudaibergenov S. Nuraje N. A heterojunction strategy to improve the visible light sensitive water splitting performance of photocatalytic materials. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2018;6:21696&#x2013;21718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paracchino A. Mathews N. Hisatomi T. Stefik M. Tilley S. D. Gr&#xe4;tzel M. Ultrathin films on copper(i) oxide water splitting photocathodes: A study on performance and stability. Energy Environ. Sci. 2012;5:8673&#x2013;8681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moniruddin M. Oppong E. Stewart D. McCleese C. Roy A. Warzywoda J. Nuraje N. Designing CdS-Based Ternary Heterostructures Consisting of Co-Metal and CoOx Cocatalysts for Photocatalytic H2 Evolution under Visible Light. Inorg. Chem. 2019;58:12325&#x2013;12333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31483615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilley S. D. Schreier M. Azevedo J. Stefik M. Graetzel M. Ruthenium oxide hydrogen evolution catalysis on composite cuprous oxide Water-splitting photocathodes. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2014;24:303&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Guio C. G. Tilley S. D. Vrubel H. Gra&#x1e97;zel M. Hu X. Hydrogen evolution from a copper(I) oxide photocathode coated with an amorphous molybdenum sulphide catalyst. Nat. Commun. 2014;5:3059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24402352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehmin M. N. I. Jeffery Minggu L. Mark-Lee W. F. Mohamed M. A. Arifin K. Jumali M. H. H. Kassim M. B. Highly photoactive Cu2O nanowire film prepared with modified scalable synthesis method for enhanced photoelectrochemical performance. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2018;182:237&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J. Steier L. Son M. K. Schreier M. Mayer M. T. Gr&#xe4;tzel M. Cu2O Nanowire Photocathodes for Efficient and Durable Solar Water Splitting. Nano Lett. 2016;16:1848&#x2013;1857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26866762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L. Kim J. H. Mayer M. T. Son M. K. Ummadisingu A. Lee J. S. Hagfeldt A. Luo J. Gr&#xe4;tzel M. Boosting the performance of Cu2O photocathodes for unassisted solar water splitting devices. Nat. Catal. 2018;1:412&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai J. Li Y. Wang R. Huang K. Zeng Q. Li J. Zhou B. A novel 3D ZnO/Cu2O nanowire photocathode material with highly efficient photoelectrocatalytic performance. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2015;3:22996&#x2013;23002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdani I. R. Bhaskarwar A. N. Cu2O nanowires based p&#x2013;n homojunction photocathode for improved current density and hydrogen generation through solar-water splitting. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2021;46:28064&#x2013;28077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>(Feng) Tao F., Schneider W. F. and Kamat P. V., Heterogeneous Catalysis at Nanoscale for Energy Applications, Wiley, 2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auzel F. Upconversion and Anti-Stokes Processes with f and d Ions in Solids. Chem. Rev. 2004;104:139&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14719973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q. Yang F. Xu Z. Chaker M. Ma D. Are lanthanide-doped upconversion materials good candidates for photocatalysis? Nanoscale Horiz. 2019;4:579&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F. Liu X. Upconversion Multicolor Fine-Tuning: Visible to Near-Infrared Emission from Lanthanide-Doped NaYF4 Nanoparticles. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2008;130:5642&#x2013;5643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18393419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madbak E. Osborn D. J. Small T. Ishwara T. Schmidt T. W. Domen K. Metha G. F. Utilising triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion for overall photocatalytic water splitting. Chem. Commun. 2024;61:157&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39625009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucchieri M. Freyria F. S. Bonelli B. Triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion sensitized with nanocrystals for a new generation of photocatalytic systems. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:18115&#x2013;18145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J. Chen Y. Zhu C. Li X. Wang W. Lu C. Ni Y. Fang L. Xu Z. Enhanced triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion by photonic crystals and Au plasma resonance for efficient photocatalysis. Catal. Sci. Technol. 2020;10:8325&#x2013;8331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao B. Sun H. He Y. Wang S. Liu X. Recent Advances in the Photoreactions Triggered by Porphyrin-Based Triplet&#x2013;Triplet Annihilation Upconversion Systems: Molecular Innovations and Nanoarchitectonics. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2022;23 doi: 10.3390/ijms23148041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23148041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9323209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35887385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavridi-Printezi A. Menichetti A. Guernelli M. Montalti M. Extending photocatalysis to the visible and NIR: The molecular strategy. Nanoscale. 2021;13:9147&#x2013;9159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B. Hu Y. Shen Z. Ji Z. Yao L. Zhang S. Zou Y. Tang D. Qing Y. Wang S. Zhao G. Wang X. Photocatalysis Driven by Near-Infrared Light: Materials Design and Engineering for Environmentally Friendly Photoreactions. ACS ES&amp;T Eng. 2021;1:947&#x2013;964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L. Yang J. Zhou S. Yu H. Liang J. Chu W. Li H. Wang H. Wu Z. Yuan X. Strategies to extend near-infrared light harvest of polymer carbon nitride photocatalysts. Coord. Chem. Rev. 2021;439:213947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J. Xu K. Yang W. Wang Z. Zhong F. The triplet excited state of Bodipy: Formation, modulation and application. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2015;44:8904&#x2013;8939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26465741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X. Tang M. L. Triplet transport in thin films: fundamentals and applications. Chem. Commun. 2017;53:4429&#x2013;4440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28379239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K. Zhou M. Yu C. Li X. Yang K. Yang S. Dai W. Huang W. Fan Q. Zhu L. High value-added fluorescence upconversion agents-assisted nano-semiconductors for efficient wide spectral response photocatalysis: Exerting energy transfer effect and applications. J. Rare Earths. 2021;39:243&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher L. Marschall R. Recent Advances in Semiconductor Heterojunctions and Z-Schemes for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Generation. Top. Curr. Chem. 2022;380:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36269440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L. Zhou S. Yang J. Wang H. Yu H. Chen H. Zhao Y. Yuan X. Chu W. Li H. Near-Infrared Light Responsive TiO2 for Efficient Solar Energy Utilization. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022;32:2108977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash J. Samriti Kumar A. Dai H. Janegitz B. C. Krishnan V. Swart H. C. Sun S. Novel rare earth metal&#x2013;doped one-dimensional TiO2 nanostructures: Fundamentals and multifunctional applications. Mater. Today Sustain. 2021;13:100066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal O. Ali H. Li N. Al-Sulami A. I. F Alshammari K. Abd-Rabboh H. S. M. Al-Hadeethi Y. Din I. U. Alharthi A. I. Altamimi R. Hayat A. Zahid Ansari M. A review on the synthesis, properties, and characterizations of graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) for energy conversion and storage applications. Mater. Today Phys. 2023;34:101080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan W. Bai H. Shi W. Semiconductors with NIR driven upconversion performance for photocatalysis and photoelectrochemical water splitting. CrystEngComm. 2014;16:3059&#x2013;3067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadort A. Zhao J. Goldys E. M. Lanthanide upconversion luminescence at the nanoscale: fundamentals and optical properties. Nanoscale. 2016;8:13099&#x2013;13130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26986473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J. Ye J. Ma L. Ouyang S. Jing D. Guo L. Site-selected doping of upconversion luminescent Er 3+ into SrTiO 3 for visible-light-driven photocatalytic H 2 or O 2 evolution. Chem.&#x2014;Eur. J. 2012;18:7543&#x2013;7551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22532311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. Deng R. Guo H. Song S. Cao F. Li X. Su S. Zhang H. Lanthanide doped Y6O5F8/YF3 microcrystals: Phase-tunable synthesis and bright white upconversion photoluminescence properties. Dalton Trans. 2010;39:9153&#x2013;9158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20714629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. Su S. Song S. Deng R. Zhang H. Raisin-like rare earth doped gadolinium fluoride nanocrystals: Microwave synthesis and magnetic and upconversion luminescent properties. CrystEngComm. 2012;14:4266&#x2013;4269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L. Li Y. Wang J. Zhai Y. Wang J. Kong Y. Wang B. Zhang X. Preparation of Er3+:Y3Al5O 12/TiO2-ZnO composite and application of solar energy in photocatalytic degradation of organic dyes. Environ. Prog. Sustainable Energy. 2013;32:697&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W. Huang W. Ni Y. Lu C. Tan L. Xu Z. Graphene supported &#x3b2;naYF 4 :Yb 3+ ,Tm 3+ and N doped P25 nanocomposite as an advanced NIR and sunlight driven upconversion photocatalyst. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2013;282:832&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X. Yin S. Dong Q. Liu B. Wang Y. Sekino T. Lee S. W. Sato T. UV, visible and near-infrared lights induced NOx destruction activity of (Yb,Er)-NaYF4/C-TiO2 composite. Sci. Rep. 2013;3:2918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. Wang F. Zhu J. Yu J. C. NaYF4:Yb,Tm/CdS composite as a novel near-infrared-driven photocatalyst. Appl. Catal., B. 2010;100:433&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. Li C. Mei Y. Wang L. Du G. Xiong Y. Synthesis of rhombic hierarchical YF3 nanocrystals and their use as upconversion photocatalysts after TiO2 coating. Nanoscale. 2013;5:3030&#x2013;3036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23463420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S. Gu L. Miao C. Lou Z. Zhu N. Yuan H. Shan A. Near-infrared photocatalyst of Er3+/Yb3+ codoped (CaF2@TiO2) nanoparticles with active-core/active-shell structure. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2013;1:7874&#x2013;7879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevallos-Toledo R. B. Bellezza D. Ferrera-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Giussani A. Ort&#xed; E. Gonz&#xe1;lez-B&#xe9;jar M. P&#xe9;rez-Prieto J. Cooperative Sensitization Upconversion in Ytterbium(III)-Based Eosin Lake Pigments. ChemPhotoChem. 2023;7:e202300156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S. Recent advances in fundamental research on photon avalanches on the nanometre scale. Nanoscale. 2025;17:6329&#x2013;6361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39951321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auzel F. Upconversion and Anti-Stokes Processes with f and d Ions in Solids. Chem. Rev. 2004;104:139&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14719973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerbous L. Krachni O. The 4f-5d luminescence transitions in cerium-doped LuF3. J. Mod. Opt. 2006;53:2043&#x2013;2053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazubovich S. V Laguta V. Machek P. Kamada K. Yoshikawa A. Nikl M. Effect of Li+ co-doping on the luminescence and defects creation processes in Gd3(Ga,Al)5O12:Ce scintillation crystals. J. Lumin. 2022;242:118548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J. Xie Y. Zhang Z. Li J. Chen X. Zhang L. Xu R. Zhang X. Photocatalytic degradation of organic dyes with Er3+:YAlO3/ZnO composite under solar light. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2009;93:355&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R. Li J. Wang J. Wang X. Liu B. Wang B. Luan X. Zhang X. Photocatalytic degradation of organic dyes under solar light irradiation combined with Er3+:YAlO3/Fe- and Co-doped TiO2 coated composites. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2010;94:1157&#x2013;1165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin W. Zhang D. Zhao D. Wang L. Zheng K. Near-infrared photocatalysis based on YF3:Yb3+, Tm3+/TiO2 core/shell nanoparticles. Chem. Commun. 2010;46:2304&#x2013;2306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20234940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J. Luan X. Wang J. Wang B. Li K. Li Y. Kang P. Han G. Preparation of Er3+:YAlO3/Fe-doped TiO2-ZnO and its application in photocatalytic degradation of dyes under solar light irradiation. Desalination. 2011;268:68&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L. Gao J. Wang J. Luan X. Kang P. Li Y. Li K. Zhang X. Synthesis of Er 3+:Y 3Al 5O 12 and its effects on the solar light photocatalytic activity of TiO 2-ZrO 2 composite. Res. Chem. Intermed. 2012;38:523&#x2013;536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W. Huang W. Ni Y. Lu C. Xu Z. Different Upconversion Properties of &#x3b2;-NaYF4:Yb3+,Tm3+/Er3+ in Affecting the Near-Infrared-Driven Photocatalytic Activity of High-Reactive TiO2. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2014;6:340&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24245742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X. Song W. Chen C. Di W. Qin W. Near-infrared photocatalysis of &#x3b2;-NaYF4:Yb 3+,Tm3+@ZnO composites. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2013;15:14681&#x2013;14688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23897044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y. Di W. Zhai X. Yang R. Qin W. NIR-responsive photocatalytic activity and mechanism of NaYF 4:Yb,Tm@TiO2 core-shell nanoparticles. ACS Catal. 2013;3:405&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y. Hong Z. Synthesis of lanthanide-doped NaYF4@TiO2 core&#x2013;shell composites with highly crystalline and tunable TiO2 shells under mild conditions and their upconversion-based photocatalysis. Nanoscale. 2013;5:8930&#x2013;8933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23955272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J. Jin D. Schartner E. P. Lu Y. Liu Y. Zvyagin A. V. Zhang L. Dawes J. M. Xi P. Piper J. A. Goldys E. M. Monro T. M. Single-nanocrystal sensitivity achieved by enhanced upconversion luminescence. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2013;8:729&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23995455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai L. Jiang W. Gao C. Zhong S. Zhao L. Li Z. Bai S. Facet engineered interface design of NaYF4:Yb,Tm upconversion nanocrystals on BiOCl nanoplates for enhanced near-infrared photocatalysis. Nanoscale. 2016;8:19014&#x2013;19024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27808315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. Cao H. Yin Z. Dong X. Hao J. Song Z. Yang Z. Qiu J. Li Y. Photon upconversion in Bi3Ti2O8F:Yb3+, Er3+ nanoplates for enhanced near-infrared light harvesting and their application in wastewater purification. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:115661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Z. Lai F. You W. Wang B. Huang J. Near-infrared responsive upconversion of lanthanide doped Bi-based glass ceramics for norfloxacin degradation. Ceram. Int. 2025;51:8353&#x2013;8361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. Xia C. Yang T. Wang H. Liu N. Liang C. Spindle-like porous N-doped TiO2 encapsulated (Ca,Y)F2:Yb3+,Tm3+ as the efficient photocatalyst near-infrared range. Nanotechnology. 2020;31:025601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31518998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Callaghan P. Jarosz-Duda A. Kuncewicz J. Dzier&#x17c;&#x119;ga K. Macyk W. Upconverting particles in near-infrared light-induced TiO2 photocatalysis: towards the optimal architecture of upconverter/photocatalyst systems. RSC Adv. 2024;14:36930&#x2013;36936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11576942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39569132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z. Song X. Lu Y. Zhu F. Xie Y. Zhao L. Yang Z. Zhang J. Joint Electrons and Photons Transfer from Dual-Functional WO3:Yb,Er to Zn0.5Cd0.5S for Efficient H2 Evolution. Adv. Energy Mater. 2025;15:2403307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng K. Cai Z. Huang D. Li L. Wang K. Li Y. Wang C. Song J. Zhao L. Wei W. Jiang F. Near-infrared-driven water splitting for hydrogen evolution using a Cu2ZnSnS4-based photocathode by the application of upconversion nanoparticles. Sustainable Energy Fuels. 2020;4:2669&#x2013;2674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X. Yang N. Feng J. Liao J. Hou S. Ma X. Su D. Yu X. Yang Z. Safaei J. Wang D. Wang G. Defect and interface control on graphitic carbon nitrides/upconversion nanocrystals for enhanced solar hydrogen production. Natl. Sci. Open. 2023;2 doi: 10.1360/nso/20220037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1360/nso/20220037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.-W. Cho K.-H. Yoon J.-S. Sung Y.-M. Enhanced IR-driven photoelectrochemical responses of CdSe/ZnO heterostructures by up-conversion UV/visible light irradiation. Nanoscale. 2020;12:8525&#x2013;8535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32242580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali G. V Prabhakar Vattikuti S. Kshetri Y. K. Lee H. Modigunta J. K. R. Seshendra Reddy Ch. Park S. Lee S. Poornaprakash B. Lee H. Park Y. H. Lee J. Park S. Y. In I. Near-infrared-activated Z-scheme NaYF4:Yb/Tm@Ag3PO4/Ag@g-C3N4 photocatalyst for enhanced H2 evolution under simulated solar light irradiation. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;421:129687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Ramos J. Borges M. E. Torres-Garc&#xed;a S. Medina-Alay&#xf3;n M. Acosta-Mora P. del-Castillo J. Men&#xe9;ndez-Vel&#xe1;zquez A. Garc&#xed;a-Delgado A. B. Mullins C. B. Esparza P. &#x201c;There is plenty of energy at the bottom&#x201d;: A spectral conversion approach for upconversion-powered water-splitting PEC cell. J. Power Sources. 2025;625:235668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Ramos J. Ruiz-Morales J. C. Acosta-Mora P. Del-Castillo J. Yanes A. C. Rare-earth doped nano-glass-ceramics for extending spectral response of water-splitting semiconductor electrodes by high intense UV-blue up-conversion: Turning the sun into blue. J. Power Sources. 2013;238:313&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W. Wu Y. Lu G. 980 nm NIR light driven overall water splitting over a combined CdS-RGO-NaYF4-Yb3+/Er3+ photocatalyst. Catal. Sci. Technol. 2020;10:2389&#x2013;2397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M. Lin Y. Mullen T. J. Lin W. F. Sun L. D. Yan C. H. Patten T. E. Wang D. Liu G. Y. Improving hematites solar water splitting efficiency by incorporating rare-earth upconversion nanomaterials. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2012;3:3188&#x2013;3192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C. K. Chen H. M. Chen C. J. Liu R. S. Plasmon-enhanced near-infrared-active materials in photoelectrochemical water splitting. Chem. Commun. 2013;49:7917&#x2013;7919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23900347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A. K. Tripathi P. Kumar H. Singh P. Sinha A. S. K. Singh S. Engineering Upconversion Semiconductor Nanostructures: Unravelling the Morphology&#x2013;Performance Relationship for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Generation. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2025;8:11977&#x2013;11987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z. Wu M. Cui X. Ge F. Xiao P. Li M. Fu H. Triplet&#x2013;Triplet Annihilation Upconversion with Large Anti-Stokes Shift. ACS Nano. 2025;19:25596&#x2013;25616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40626830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L. Han G. Triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation photon upconversion-mediated photochemical reactions. Nat. Rev. Chem. 2024;8:238&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38514833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye C. Wang J. Wang X. Ding P. Liang Z. Tao X. A new medium for triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilated upconversion and photocatalytic application. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2016;18:3430&#x2013;3437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran S. Ngo Y.-L. T. Sui L. Kim E. J. Dang D. K. Chung J. S. Hur S. H. Highly enhanced visible light water splitting of CdS by green to blue upconversion. Dalton Trans. 2017;46:13912&#x2013;13919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28972224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi D. Nam S. K. Kim K. Moon J. H. Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting through Bismuth Vanadate with a Photon Upconversion Luminescent Reflector. Angew. Chem. 2019;131:6965&#x2013;6969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30937999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J. Chen Y. Wang W. Fang L. Lu C. Zhu C. Kou J. Ni Y. Xu Z. Highly efficient photocatalytic hydrogen generation of g-C3N4-CdS sheets based on plasmon-enhanced triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation upconversion. Appl. Catal., B. 2019;258:117762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barawi M. Fresno F. P&#xe9;rez-Ruiz R. de la Pe&#xf1;a O'Shea V. A. Photoelectrochemical Hydrogen Evolution Driven by Visible-to-Ultraviolet Photon Upconversion. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2019;2:207&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu T. Liu Y. Zeng Y. Chen J. Yang G. Li Y. Triplet&#x2013;Triplet Annihilation Upconversion for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution. Chem. - Eur. J. 2019;25:16270&#x2013;16276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageshima Y. Tateyama S. Kishimoto F. Teshima K. Domen K. Nishikiori H. Photocatalytic oxygen evolution triggered by photon upconverted emission based on triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2021;23:5673&#x2013;5679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S. Liu H. Hu Y. Zhao C. Huang H. Yu G. Li Z. Liu Z. Chen Y. Li X. Boosting photocatalytic hydrogen evolution via triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation upconversion. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;452:139203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magazov Y. Kudryashov V. Moldabekov K. Amze M. Nurmanova A. Aliyev A. Nuraje N. Copper oxide coupled with photon upconversion for solar water splitting. Commun. Mater. 2024;5:126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X. Hao Y. Gong Y. Zhou P. Ma D. Liu Z. Sun Y. Sun H. Chen Y. Jia S. Li W. Guo C. Zhou Y. Huo P. Yan Y. Ma W. Yuan S. Zhao J. Solar overall water-splitting by a spin-hybrid all-organic semiconductor. Nat. Commun. 2024;15:5047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11176302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38871750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. Lin J.-Y. Roy D. Aloni P. Lin Z.-F. Doong R.-A. Enhanced solar-driven photoelectrocatalytic water treatment and hydrogen evolution with triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion with Mo-doped BiVO4 nanocomposite films. Appl. Catal. B Environ. Energy. 2025;365:124913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X. Xian Z. Gao S. Bai L. Liang S. Tian H. Wang C. Gu C. Mechanistic insights into surface catalytic oxidation of fluoroquinolone antibiotics on sediment mackinawite. Water Res. 2023;232:119651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. Lin J. Y. Roy D. Aloni P. Lin Z. F. Doong R. A. Enhanced solar-driven photoelectrocatalytic water treatment and hydrogen evolution with triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion with Mo-doped BiVO4 nanocomposite films. Appl. Catal., B. 2025;365:124913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharmoria P. Hisamitsu S. Nagatomi H. Ogawa T. Morikawa M. Yanai N. Kimizuka N. Simple and Versatile Platform for Air-Tolerant Photon Upconverting Hydrogels by Biopolymer&#x2013;Surfactant&#x2013;Chromophore Co-assembly. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018;140:10848&#x2013;10855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30052038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H. Weon S. Kang H. Hagstrom A. L. Kwon O. S. Lee Y.-S. Choi W. Kim J.-H. Plasmon-Enhanced Sub-Bandgap Photocatalysis via Triplet&#x2013;Triplet Annihilation Upconversion for Volatile Organic Compound Degradation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2016;50:11184&#x2013;11192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27684445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J. Wang W. Zhu C. Fang L. Jin J. Ni Y. Lu C. Xu Z. CdS/Pt photocatalytic activity boosted by high-energetic photons based on efficient triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation upconversion. Appl. Catal., B. 2017;217:100&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J. Zhou C. Chen Y. Fang L. Wang W. Zhu C. Ni Y. Lu C. Efficient Photocatalysis of Composite Films Based on Plasmon-Enhanced Triplet&#x2013;Triplet Annihilation. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12:717&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J. Zhu C. Ni Y. Lu C. Xu Z. Double local electromagnetic fields collaboratively enhanced triplet&#x2013;triplet annihilation upconversion for efficient photocatalysis. Catal. Sci. Technol. 2023;13:2151&#x2013;2159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho H. Seo S. E. Kwon O. S. Kim H. Photonic crystal-assisted sub-bandgap photocatalysis via triplet-triplet annihilation upconversion for the degradation of environmental organic pollutants. J. Hazard. Mater. 2024;477:135208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39067295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. Sui T. Zhang Y. Bian H. Lu Y. Zhu C. Mechanistic and Kinetic Insights into Hydroxyl Radical-Mediated Tetracycline Transformation in Photocatalytic Oxidation Processes. Catalysts. 2025;15 doi: 10.3390/catal15050420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/catal15050420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cates E. L. Chinnapongse S. L. Kim J.-H. Kim J.-H. Engineering Light: Advances in Wavelength Conversion Materials for Energy and Environmental Technologies. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2012;46:12316&#x2013;12328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23113803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haase M. Sch&#xe4;fer H. Upconverting Nanoparticles. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2011;50:5808&#x2013;5829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21626614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X. Zhou J. Yue J. Wei Y. Gao C. Xie X. Huang L. Recent Development in Sensitizers for Lanthanide-Doped Upconversion Luminescence. Chem. Rev. 2022;122:15998&#x2013;16050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36194772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards B. S. Hudry D. Busko D. Turshatov A. Howard I. A. Photon Upconversion for Photovoltaics and Photocatalysis: A Critical Review. Chem. Rev. 2021;121:9165&#x2013;9195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uji M. Z&#xe4;hringer T. J. B. Kerzig C. Yanai N. Visible-to-UV Photon Upconversion: Recent Progress in New Materials and Applications. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023;62:e202301506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu S. P. Cates S. L. Kim H.-I. Kim J.-H. Cates E. L. The Myth of Visible Light Photocatalysis Using Lanthanide Upconversion Materials. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2018;52:2973&#x2013;2980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>