<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41904496</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between lifestyle and combined general and abdominal obesity in Korean adults during the pre-pandemic and pandemic periods: using the Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (2019-2020).</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-026-26884-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The COVID-19 pandemic has profoundly influenced lifestyle behaviors and increased prevalence of obesity worldwide, with varying effects across socioeconomic groups. We aimed to examine the association between lifestyle and combined general and abdominal obesity between 2019 (pre-pandemic period) and 2020 (pandemic period) by income level in South Korea.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used data from the 8th Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (KNHANES) in 2019 and 2020. We compared differences in demographic and lifestyle variables during pre-pandemic and pandemic period, considering income level (high and low) and obesity type (normal weight, general obesity, abdominal obesity, and combined general and abdominal obesity). Logistic regression analysis was conducted to examine the association between lifestyle and combined general and abdominal obesity stratified by income level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The prevalence of combined general and abdominal obesity was higher during pandemic period than during pre-pandemic period. During pandemic period, the alcohol consumption in the normal-weight and high perceived stress in the abdominal obesity were lower, while strength training in the combined general and abdominal obesity was higher than during pre-pandemic period in the low-income group. In contrast, in the high-income and normal-weight groups, walking was lowered, and the skipping breakfast was higher during pandemic period than during pre-pandemic period. In the high-income group, lack of strength training, perceived stress, and excessive energy intake were associated with combined general and abdominal obesity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results suggest that modifiable behavioral variables such as physical activity, dietary factors, and stress were associated with combined general and abdominal obesity in high-income level during the pandemic period. Our findings underscore the importance of these variables as core strategies for obesity prevention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Doyeon</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9389-8483</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Health and Nutrition Survey and Analysis, Department of Chronic Disease Prevention and Control, Korea Disease Control and Prevention Agency, Cheongju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woo</LastName><ForeName>YeonHee</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9957-2207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Chodang University, Muan, Republic of Korea. Khappen2@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combined general and abdominal obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">South Korea</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41904496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-026-26884-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-026-26884-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Obesity and overweight. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2024. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/obesity-and-overweight. Accessed 20 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Draft recommendations for the prevention and management of obesity over the life course, including potential targets. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2021. Available from: https://www.who.int/teams/noncommunicable-diseases/governance/obesityrecommendations. Accessed 20 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global action plan for the prevention and control of noncommunicable diseases 2013&#x2013;2020. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013. p. 55. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241506236. Accessed 20 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Welfare. The 5th National Health Promotion Plan (Health Plan 2030, 2021&#x2013;2030). Sejong: Ministry of Health and Welfare; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam GE. Current status and epidemiology of adult obesity in Korea. J Korean Med Assoc. 2022;65(7):394&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.5124/jkma.2022.65.7.394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YS, Han BD, Han K, Jung JH, Son JW. Obesity fact sheet in Korea, 2021: trends in obesity prevalence and obesity-related comorbidity incidence stratified by age from 2009 to 2019. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2022;31(2):169&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.7570/jomes22024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Disease Control and Prevention Agency. Key findings from the 2023 Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Osong: Korea Disease Control and Prevention Agency; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Katzmarzyk PT, Srinivasan SR, Chen W, Malina RM, Bouchard C, Berenson GS. Combined influence of body mass index and waist circumference on coronary artery disease risk factors among children and adolescents. Pediatrics. 2005;115(6):1623&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2004-2588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parra-Soto S, Petermann-Rocha F, Boonpor J, Gray SR, Pell JP, Celis-Morales C, et al. Combined association of general and central obesity with incidence and mortality of cancers in 22 sites. Am J Clin Nutr. 2021;113(2):401&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/nqaa335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Yang H, Xu Z, Tang X. Association between different obesity patterns and the risk of developing type 2 diabetes mellitus among adults in eastern China: a cross-sectional study. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2021;14:2631&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.2147/DMSO.S309400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Y, Yang X, Liu G. Association of combined body mass index and central obesity with cardiovascular disease in middle-aged and older adults: a population-based prospective cohort study. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2024;24(1):443. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12872-024-04079-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi D, Choi S, Son JS, Oh SW, Park SM. Impact of discrepancies in general and abdominal obesity on major adverse cardiac events. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8(18):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.119.013471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Salas S, Gonzalez-Arias M. Behavior modification for lifestyle improvement. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Lifestyle risk factors: tracking program. Atlanta (GA): Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2023. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/environmental-health-tracking/php/data-research/lifestyle-risk-factors.html. Accessed 20 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Health promotion glossary. Geneva, World Health Organization. : 1998. 24 p. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-HPR-HEP-98.1. Accessed 20 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WY, Seo DI. Lifestyle factors and obesity among Korean adults. Iran J Public Health. 2013;42(2):114&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YJ. Slender women and overweight men: gender differences in the educational gradient in body weight in South Korea. Int J Equity Health. 2017;16(1):202&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12939-017-0685-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon HK, Kim EG. Food intake of Koreans by economic status using 1998 Korean national health examination nutrition survey. In: proceedings of the 2004 fall symposium of the Korean Nutrition Society of Community Nutrition. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman DS, Kompaniyets L, Daymont C, Zhao L, Blanck HM. Weight gain among US adults during the COVID-19 pandemic through May 2021. Obesity. 2022;30(10):2064&#x2013;2070.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.1002/oby.23511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Renzo L, Gualtieri P, Pivari F, Soldati L, Attin&#xe0; A, Cinelli G, et al. Eating habits and lifestyle changes during COVID-19 lockdown: an Italian survey. J Transl Med. 2020;18(1):229. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-020-02399-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes-Olavarr&#xed;a D, Latorre-Rom&#xe1;n PA, Guzm&#xe1;n-Guzm&#xe1;n IP, Jerez-Mayorga D, Caama&#xf1;o-Navarrete F, Delgado-Floody P. Positive and negative changes in food habits, physical activity patterns, and weight status during COVID-19 confinement: associated factors in the Chilean population. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(15):5431. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17155431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim S, Shin SM, Nam GE, Jung CH, Koo BK. Proper management of people with obesity during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2020;29(2):84&#x2013;98.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.7570/jomes20056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherikh F, Frey S, Bel C, Attanasi G, Alifano M, Iannelli A. Behavioral food addiction during lockdown: time for awareness, time to prepare the aftermath. Obes Surg. 2020;30(9):3585&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-020-04649-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shon BD, Moon HJ. Who suffers the most financial hardships due to COVID-19. Korean J Soc Welf. 2021;73(3):9&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo S, Kim DY, Lim H. Sarcopenia in relation to nutrition and lifestyle factors among middle-aged and older Korean adults with obesity. Eur J Nutr. 2020;59(8):3451&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-020-02179-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Park HS, Kim SM, Kwon HS, Kim DY, Kim DJ, et al. Cut-off points of waist circumference for defining abdominal obesity in the Korean population. Korean J Obes. 2006;15(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang JH, Kang JG, Kang JH, Kim KG, Kim D, Kim KS. Clinical practice guidelines for overweight and obesity in Korea. Seoul: Korean Society for the Study of Obesity; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Welfare. The Korean Nutrition Society. Dietary Reference Intakes for Koreans 2015. Sejong: Ministry of Health and Welfare; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Disease Control and Prevention Agency. Trend analysis and association study of chronic diseases and risk factors: findings from the KNHANES 1998&#x2013;2018. Osong: KDCA; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelps NH, Singleton RK, Zhou B, Heap RA, Mishra A, Bennett JE, et al. Worldwide trends in underweight and obesity from 1990 to 2022: a pooled analysis of 3663 population-representative studies with 222 million children, adolescents, and adults. Lancet. 2024;403(10431):1027&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(23)02750-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan RM, Arslan S, Tari Sel&#xe7;uk K. Health behind bars: obesity and cardiometabolic risk according to different indicators in incarcerated men. Int J Prison Health. 2025;21(1):103&#x2013;115.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.1108/IJOPH-07-2024-0037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan S, Sahin K, Dal N, Atan RM, Selcuk KT. The relationship between anthropometric indices and cardiovascular risk in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2025;224:112243. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2025.112243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nal AM, Y&#x131;lmaz S, Arslan S. Most vulnerable diet and health profiles: identifying countries at risk through a three-theme clustering. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1569755. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2025.1569755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tari Selcuk K, Atan RM, Dal N, Arslan S. Obesity awareness reduces food craving and improves metabolic parameters: a study on adults with overweight and obesity. Mediterr J Nutr Metab. 2025;18(3):184&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1177/1973798X251349610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park MY, Chung N. Changes in physical activity and energy intake according to abdominal obesity in Korean adult men before and after COVID-19: data from 2019 and 2020 Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (KNHANES). Phys Act Nutr. 2022;26(3):6&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.20463/pan.2022.0013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Bahk J, Park S, Oh K, Jung-Choi K. Smoking, drinking, and physical activity among Korean adults before and during the COVID-19 pandemic: a special report of the 2020 Korea National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Epidemiol Health. 2022;44:e2022043. https://doi.org/10.4178/epih.e2022043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knell G, Robertson MC, Dooley EE, Burford K, Mendez KS. Health behavior changes during COVID-19 pandemic and subsequent stay-at-home orders. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(17):6268.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17176268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunton GF, Wang SD, Do B, Courtney J. Early effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on physical activity locations and behaviors in adults living in the United States. Prev Med Rep. 2020;20:101241. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2020.101241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Yoo DM, Min C, Choi HG. Changes in dietary habits and exercise pattern of Korean adolescents from prior to during the COVID-19 pandemic. Nutrients. 2021;13(10):3314. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13103314. .&#x200b; doi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dakanalis A, Mentzelou M, Papadopoulou SK, Papandreou D, Spanoudaki M, Vasios GK, et al. The association of emotional eating with overweight/obesity, depression, anxiety/stress, and dietary patterns: a review of the current clinical evidence. Nutrients. 2023;15(5):1173. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15051173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yau YHC, Potenza MN. Stress and eating behaviors. Minerva Endocrinol. 2013;38(3):255&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drewnowski A, Specter SE. Poverty and obesity: the role of energy density and energy costs. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;79(1):6&#x2013;16.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/79.1.6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na HM, Jung BM. Dietary behavior and diet quality in the Korean adult population by income level before and after the COVID-19 pandemic: using the Korean National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (2019&#x2013;2020). Korean J Community Living Sci. 2022;33(3):397&#x2013;413. https://doi.org/10.7856/kjcls.2022.33.3.397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huangfu P, Pearson F, Abu-Hijleh FM, Wahlich C, Willis K, Awad SF, et al. Impact of price reductions, subsidies, or financial incentives on healthy food purchases and consumption: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Planet Health. 2024;8(3):e197&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard E, Brewer N, Prorok JC, Kim P, Muscedere J. Community-based physical activity and nutrition interventions in low-income and/or rural older adults: a scoping review. J Frailty Aging. 2025;14(2):100034.&#x200b; https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tjfa.2025.100034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagappan A, Krasniansky A, Knowles M. Patterns of ownership and usage of wearable devices in the United States, 2020&#x2013;2022: survey study. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e56504. https://doi.org/10.2196/56504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LE, Wang J, Sevick MA. Self-monitoring in weight loss: a systematic review of the literature. J Am Diet Assoc. 2011;111(1):92&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jada.2010.10.008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>