<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41645670</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of exercise on resistant hypertension: what do we know in 2025?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>533</StartPage><EndPage>541</EndPage><MedlinePgn>533-541</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HJH.0000000000004242</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review examines current evidence on the effects of physical exercise in individuals with resistant hypertension, a population for whom the effects of exercise are less well understood compared to those with general hypertension. Emerging evidence indicates that aerobic exercise promotes clinically meaningful reductions in blood pressure in individuals with resistant hypertension, with potential to reduce medication reliance and improve cardiovascular health. Combined aerobic and dynamic resistance exercise, particularly in heated-water environments, may offer additional benefits. However, important research gaps remain, including limited data on resistance training (dynamic or isometric), and mind-body exercises such as Tai Chi or Yoga. While aerobic exercise is well established as an effective strategy for lowering blood pressure, further studies are needed to evaluate other exercise modalities and digital or remote interventions to enhance adherence. Expanding the evidence base will allow for more personalized and flexible exercise prescriptions, ultimately improving long-term blood pressure control and cardiovascular outcomes in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (iBiMED), School of Health Sciences, University of Aveiro, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalton-Alves</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ExCE Research Group, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte, Natal, RN, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (iBiMED), School of Health Sciences, University of Aveiro, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo Caldas</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ExCE Research Group, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte, Natal, RN, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (iBiMED), School of Health Sciences, University of Aveiro, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8306882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0263-6352</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41645670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000004242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004872-990000000-00828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC). Worldwide trends in hypertension prevalence and progress in treatment and control from 1990 to 2019: a pooled analysis of 1201 population-representative studies with 104 million participants. Lancet 2021; 398:957&#x2013;980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Mensah GA, Turco JV, Fuster V, Roth GA. The global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risk: a compass for future health. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022; 80:2361&#x2013;2371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global report on hypertension: the race against a silent killer. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee M, Jones DW, Ferdinand KC, Taler SJ, Johnson HM, Shimbo D, et al. 2025 AHA/ACC/AANP/AAPA/ABC/ACCP/ACPM/AGS/AMA/ASPC/NMA/PCNA/SGIM Guideline for the prevention, detection, evaluation and management of high blood pressure in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Hypertension 2025; 82:e212&#x2013;e316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypertension Prevalence, Treatment and Control Estimates Among US Adults. Available at: https://millionhearts.hhs.gov/data-reports/hypertension-prevalence.html . [Accessed 1 September 2025]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KT, Stefanescu A, He J. The global epidemiology of hypertension. Nat Rev Nephrol 2020; 16:223&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearney PM, Whelton M, Reynolds K, Muntner P, Whelton PK, He J. Global burden of hypertension: analysis of worldwide data. The lancet 2005; 365:217&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey RM, Calhoun DA, Bakris GL, Brook RD, Daugherty SL, Dennison-Himmelfarb CR, et al. American Heart Association Professional/Public Education and Publications Committee of the Council on Hypertension; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Clinical Cardiology; Council on Genomic and Precision Medicine; Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease; Council on Quality of Care and Outcomes Research; and Stroke Council. Resistant hypertension: detection, evaluation, and management: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hypertension 2018; 72:e53&#x2013;e90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noubiap JJ, Nansseu JR, Nyaga UF, Sime PS, Francis I, Bigna JJ. Global prevalence of resistant hypertension: a meta-analysis of data from 3.2 million patients. Heart 2019; 105:98&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey RM, Sakhuja S, Calhoun DA, Whelton PK, Muntner P. Prevalence of apparent treatment-resistant hypertension in the United States. Hypertension 2019; 73:424&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarafidis PA, Bakris GL. Resistant hypertension: an overview of evaluation and treatment. J Am Coll Cardiol 2008; 52:1749&#x2013;1757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Kreutz R, Brunstr&#xf6;m M, Burnier M, Grassi G, Januszewicz A, et al. 2023 ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension The Task Force for the management of arterial hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension: endorsed by the International Society of Hypertension (ISH) and the European Renal Association (ERA). J Hypertens 2023; 41:1874&#x2013;2071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEvoy JW, McCarthy CP, Bruno RM, Brouwers S, Canavan MD, Ceconi C, et al. ESC Scientific Document Group. 2024 ESC Guidelines for the management of elevated blood pressure and hypertension. Eur Heart J 2024; 45:3912&#x2013;4018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agasthi P, Shipman J, Arsanjani R, Ashukem M, Girardo ME, Yerasi C, et al. Renal denervation for resistant hypertension in the contemporary era: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific reports 2019; 9:6200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cluett JL, Blazek O, Brown AL, East C, Ferdinand KC, Fisher NDL, et al. American Heart Association Council on Hypertension; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on the Kidney in Cardiovascular Disease; and Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease. Renal denervation for the treatment of hypertension: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hypertension 2024; 81:e135&#x2013;e148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gierthmuehlen M, Plachta DT, Zentner J. Implant-mediated therapy of arterial hypertension. Curr Hypertens Rep 2020; 22:16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piepoli MF, Hoes AW, Agewall S, et al . 2016 European Guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice: The Sixth Joint Task Force of the European Society of Cardiology and Other Societies on Cardiovascular Disease Prevention in Clinical Practice (constituted by representatives of 10 societies and by invited experts) Developed with the special contribution of the European Association for Cardiovascular Prevention &amp; Rehabilitation (EACPR). Eur Heart J 2016; 37:2315&#x2013;2381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naci H, Salcher-Konrad M, Dias S, Blum MR, Sahoo SA, Nunan D, Ioannidis JPA. How does exercise treatment compare with antihypertensive medications? A network meta-analysis of 391 randomised controlled trials assessing exercise and medication effects on systolic blood pressure. Br J Sports Med 2019; 53:859&#x2013;869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanssen H, Boardman H, Deiseroth A, Moholdt T, Simonenko M, Krankel N, et al. Personalized exercise prescription in the prevention and treatment of arterial hypertension: a Consensus Document from the European Association of Preventive Cardiology (EAPC) and the ESC Council on Hypertension. Eur J Prev Cardiol 2022; 29:205&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Kreutz R, Brunstrom M, Burnier M, Grassi G, Januszewicz A, et al. 2023 ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension The Task Force for the management of arterial hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension: Endorsed by the International Society of Hypertension (ISH) and the European Renal Association (ERA). J Hypertens 2023; 41:1874&#x2013;2071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger T, Borghi C, Charchar F, Khan NA, Poulter NR, Prabhakaran D, et al. 2020 International Society of Hypertension Global Hypertension Practice Guidelines. Hypertension 2020; 75:1334&#x2013;1357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Xu R, Cai Z, Zheng X, Zheng M, Ni C. Association between physical activity and resistant hypertension in treated hypertension patients: analysis of the national health and nutrition examination survey. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 2023; 23:289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Mesquita-Bastos J, Garcia C, Figueiredo D, Carvalho P, Oliveira J, et al. Are subjective measures the answer to assess physical inactivity on a daily basis in patients with resistant hypertension? J Hum Hypertens 2021; 35:1180&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saco-Ledo G, Valenzuela PL, Ruilope LM, Lucia A. Physical exercise in resistant hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Cardiovasc Med 2022; 9:893811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dassanayake S, Sole G, Wilkins G, Gray E, Skinner M. Effectiveness of physical activity and exercise on ambulatory blood pressure in adults with resistant hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev 2022; 29:275&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimeo F, Pagonas N, Seibert F, Arndt R, Zidek W, Westhoff TH. Aerobic exercise reduces blood pressure in resistant hypertension. Hypertension 2012; 60:653&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P. Effects of endurance training on ambulatory blood pressure and exercise capacity in refractory hypertension patients. J Shenyang Sport Univ 2013; 32:89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Mesquita-Bastos J, Garcia C, Bertoquini S, Ribau V, Teixeira M, et al. Effect of exercise training on ambulatory blood pressure among patients with resistant hypertension: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Cardiol 2021; 6:1317&#x2013;1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal JA, Hinderliter AL, Smith PJ, Mabe S, Watkins LL, Craighead L, et al. Effects of lifestyle modification on patients with resistant hypertension: results of the TRIUMPH Randomized Clinical Trial. Circulation 2021; 144:1212&#x2013;1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos LP, Moraes RS, Vieira PJ, Ash GI, Waclawovsky G, Pescatello LS, Umpierre D. Effects of aerobic exercise intensity on ambulatory blood pressure and vascular responses in resistant hypertension: a crossover trial. J Hypertens 2016; 34:1317&#x2013;1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Almeida N, Ferreira R, Oliveira N, Oliveira J, Alves AJ, Mesquita-Bastos J. Central and peripheral blood pressure response to a single bout of an exercise session in patients with resistant hypertension. Hypertens Res 2019; 42:114&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk PJ, Nowicki M. Effect of the physical activity program on the treatment of resistant hypertension in primary care. Prim Healthcare Res Dev 2018; 19:575&#x2013;583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandini S, Conconi F, Mori E, Caruso L, Grazzi G, Mazzoni G. Guided walking reduces blood pressure in hypertensive sedentary subjects including those with resistant hypertension. J Hum Hypertens 2021; 35:226&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinel E, Azancot MA, Gomez A, Beneria A, Caraben A, Andurell L, et al. Compliance to multidisciplinary lifestyle intervention decreases blood pressure in patients with resistant hypertension: a cross-sectional pilot study. J Clin Med 2023; 12:679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa EC, Hay JL, Kehler DS, Boreskie KF, Arora RC, Umpierre D, et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on blood pressure in adults with pre to established hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. Sports Med 2018; 48:2127&#x2013;2142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal JM, Galliano LM, Del Vecchio FB. Effectiveness of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training in hypertensive patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Curr Hypertens Rep 2020; 22:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza Mesquita FO, Gambassi BB, de Oliveira Silva M, Moreira SR, Neves VR, Gomes-Neto M, Schwingel PA. Effect of high-intensity interval training on exercise capacity, blood pressure, and autonomic responses in patients with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Health 2023; 15:571&#x2013;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molmen-Hansen HE, Stolen T, Tjonna AE, Aamot IL, Ekeberg IS, Tyldum GA, et al. Aerobic interval training reduces blood pressure and improves myocardial function in hypertensive patients. Eur J Prev Cardiol 2012; 19:151&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Moraes JA, De Barcelos GT, Coneglian JC, Do Espirito Santo BCR, Delevatti RS, Gerage AM. Combined training with aerobic exercise performed outdoors can promote better blood pressure and affective responses in individuals with cardiovascular risk factors. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022; 19:16009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baruki SB, MI DELM, Pazzianotto-Forti EM. Physical training in outdoor fitness gym improves blood pressure, physical fitness, and quality of life of hypertensive patients: a randomized controlled trial. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 2022; 62:997&#x2013;1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho CJd, Marins JCB, Lade CGd, Castilho PdR, Reis HHT, Amorim PRdS, et al. Aerobic and resistance exercise in patients with resistant hypertension. Revista Brasileira de Medicina do Esporte 2019; 25:107&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires NF, Coelho-Junior HJ, Gambassi BB, de Faria APC, Ritter AMV, de Andrade Barboza C, et al. Combined aerobic and resistance exercises evokes longer reductions on ambulatory blood pressure in resistant hypertension: a randomized crossover trial. Cardiovasc Ther 2020; 2020:8157858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Way D, Carlson D, Millar P, McGowan C, Swaine I, et al. Effects of isometric resistance training on resting blood pressure: individual participant data meta-analysis. J Hypertens 2019; 37:1927&#x2013;1938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Valenciano A, Ruiz-Perez I, Ayala F, Sanchez-Meca J, Vera-Garcia FJ. Updated systematic review and meta-analysis on the role of isometric resistance training for resting blood pressure management in adults. J Hypertens 2019; 37:1320&#x2013;1333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards JJ, Coleman DA, Ritti-Dias RM, Farah BQ, Stensel DJ, Lucas SJE, et al. Isometric exercise training and arterial hypertension: an updated review. Sports Med 2024; 54:1459&#x2013;1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards JJ, Deenmamode AHP, Griffiths M, Arnold O, Cooper NJ, Wiles JD, O&#x2019;Driscoll JM. Exercise training and resting blood pressure: a large-scale pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med 2023; 57:1317&#x2013;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansford HJ, Parmenter BJ, McLeod KA, Wewege MA, Smart NA, Schutte AE, Jones MD. The effectiveness and safety of isometric resistance training for adults with high blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hypertens Res 2021; 44:1373&#x2013;1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Johnson BT, Acabchuk RL, Chen S, Lewis HK, Livingston J, et al. Yoga as antihypertensive lifestyle therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mayo Clin Proc 2019; 94:432&#x2013;446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Huang Y, Li L, Zhang J, Li C, Liu M, et al. An RCT META analysis based on the efficacy of Tai Chi exercise therapy on blood pressure and blood lipids in patients with essential hypertension. Front Cardiovasc Med 2025; 12:1506912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimar&#xe3;es GV, Cruz LGB, Tavares AC, Dorea EL, Fernandes-Silva MM, Bocchi EA. Effects of short-term heated water-based exercise training on systemic blood pressure in patients with resistant hypertension. Blood Press Monit 2013; 18:342&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimaraes GV, de Barros Cruz LG, Fernandes-Silva MM, Dorea EL, Bocchi EA. Heated water-based exercise training reduces 24-h ambulatory blood pressure levels in resistant hypertensive patients: a randomized controlled trial (HEx trial). Int J Cardiol 2014; 172:434&#x2013;441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz LG, Bocchi EA, Grassi G, Guimaraes GV. Neurohumoral and endothelial responses to heated water-based exercise in resistant hypertensive patients. Circ J 2017; 81:339&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimaraes GV, Fernandes-Silva MM, Drager LF, de Barros Cruz LG, Castro RE, Ciolac EG, et al. Hypotensive effect of heated water-based exercise persists after 12-week cessation of training in patients with resistant hypertension. Can J Cardiol 2018; 34:1641&#x2013;1647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Pescatello LS, Alves AJ. Exercise and resistant hypertension-is exercise enough?-reply. JAMA Cardiol 2022; 7:571&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Mesquita-Bastos J, Garcia C, Figueiredo D, Oliveira J, Guimaraes GV, et al. The blood pressure response to acute exercise predicts the ambulatory blood pressure response to exercise training in patients with resistant hypertension: results from the EnRicH trial. Hypertens Res 2022; 45:1392&#x2013;1397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Felix G, Mesquita-Bastos J, Figueiredo D, Oliveira J, Ribeiro F. Determinants of exercise adherence and maintenance among patients with hypertension: a narrative review. Rev Cardiovasc Med 2021; 22:1271&#x2013;1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Diniz F, Mesquita Bastos J, et al . &#x201c;What do we think?&#x201d;: a qualitative exploratory study of acceptability and experiences of individuals with resistant hypertension after completing a physical exercise program (the EnRICH trial). Disabil Rehabil 2024; 46:2662&#x2013;2669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forechi L, Mill JG, Griep RH, Santos I, Pitanga F, Molina MDCB. Adherence to physical activity in adults with chronic diseases: ELSA-Brasil. Rev Saude Publica 2018; 52:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzun &#x15e;, Kara B, Yoku&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu M, Arslan F, Birhan Yilmaz M, Karaeren H. The assessment of adherence of hypertensive individuals to treatment and lifestyle change recommendations. Anadolu Kardiyol Derg 2009; 9:102&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbur AI. Level of adherence to lifestyle changes and medications among male hypertensive patients in two hospitals in Taif; Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. Int J Pharm Pharmaceut Sci 2015; 7:168&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos-Carrillo K, Reyes-Morales H, Pelcastre-Villafuerte B, Garc&#xed;a-Pe&#xf1;a C, Lobelo F, Salmeron J, Salgado-de-Snyder N. Understanding adherence of hypertensive patients in Mexico to an exercise-referral scheme for increasing physical activity. Health Promot Int 2020; 36:952&#x2013;963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suriyawong W, Kao TA, Robbins LB, Ling J, Malete L. Psychosocial determinants of recommended lifestyle behaviors among hypertensive patients: an integrative literature review. West J Nurs Res 2023; 45:455&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherrenberg M, Falter M, Abreu A, Aktaa S, Busnatu S, Casado-Arroyo R, et al. Standards for cardiac telerehabilitation. Eur Heart J 2025; 46:3714&#x2013;3737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lison JF, Palomar G, Mensorio MS, Banos RM, Cebolla-Marti A, Botella C, et al. Impact of a web-based exercise and nutritional education intervention in patients who are obese with hypertension: randomized wait-list controlled trial. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22:e14196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt C, Magalhaes S, Gois Basilio P, Santos C, Oliveira MI, Ferreira JP, et al. Center- vs home-based cardiac rehabilitation in patients with heart failure: EXIT-HF Randomized Controlled Trial. JACC Heart Fail 2025; 13:695&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto D, Dias N, Garcia C, Teixeira M, Marques MJ, Amaral T, et al. Effect of home-based isometric training on blood pressure in older adults with high normal BP or stage I hypertension: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc 2025; 73:574&#x2013;582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay-Perez A, Jurdon R, King T, Koffman L, Roberts N, McManus RJ, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of digital interventions targeting lifestyle factors in patients with hypertension. J Hum Hypertens 2025; 39:690&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Teixeira M, Alves AJ, Sherwood A, Blumenthal JA. Lifestyle medicine as a treatment for resistant hypertension. Curr Hypertens Rep 2023; 25:313&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baffour-Awuah B, Man M, Goessler KF, Cornelissen VA, Dieberg G, Smart NA, Pearson MJ. Effect of exercise training on the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system: a meta-analysis. J Hum Hypertens 2024; 38:89&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besnier F, Labrunee M, Pathak A, Pavy-Le Traon A, Gales C, Senard JM, Guiraud T. Exercise training-induced modification in autonomic nervous system: an update for cardiac patients. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 2017; 60:27&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Francescomarino S, Sciartilli A, Di Valerio V, Di Baldassarre A, Gallina S. The effect of physical exercise on endothelial function. Sports Med 2009; 39:797&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dassanayake S, Gisela S, Gerard W, Skinner M. Exercise: a therapeutic modality to treat blood pressure in resistant hypertension. Phys Ther Rev 2020; 25:149&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagan LU, Gomes MJ, Okoshi MP. Endothelial function and physical exercise. Arq Bras Cardiol 2018; 111:540&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Mesquita-Bastos J, Garcia C, Leitao C, Ribau V, Teixeira M, et al. Aerobic exercise improves central blood pressure and blood pressure variability among patients with resistant hypertension: results of the EnRicH trial. Hypertens Res 2023; 46:1547&#x2013;1557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi G, Mark A, Esler M. The sympathetic nervous system alterations in human hypertension. Circ Res 2015; 116:976&#x2013;990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlers TS, Sverrisdottir Y, Bangsbo J, Gunnarsson TP. High-intensity interval training decreases muscle sympathetic nerve activity in men with essential hypertension and in normotensive controls. Front Neurosci 2020; 14:841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manresa-Rocamora A, Ribeiro F, Sarabia JM, Ibias J, Oliveira NL, Vera-Garcia FJ, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation and parasympathetic function in patients with coronary artery disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Auton Res 2021; 31:187&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triebel H, Castrop H. The renin angiotensin aldosterone system. Pflugers Arch 2024; 476:705&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsioufis C, Kordalis A, Flessas D, Anastasopoulos I, Tsiachris D, Papademetriou V, Stefanadis C. Pathophysiology of resistant hypertension: the role of sympathetic nervous system. Int J Hypertens 2011; 2011:642416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crea F. Physical exercise, inflammation, and hypertension: how to improve cardiovascular prevention. Eur Heart J 2022; 43:4763&#x2013;4766.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>