<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41306143</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Abdominal Weight Training on Diaphragm Thickening Fraction and Respiratory Muscle Strength in Healthy People: A Quasi-Experimental Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95429</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e95429</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e95429</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.95429</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Abdominal weight training (AWT) is a simple technique that applies external resistance to the diaphragm during breathing by placing weights on the abdomen. Although it is an accessible method for respiratory muscle training, its physiological effects remain unclear. This quasi-experimental study in healthy young adults evaluated the immediate and four-week effects of AWT on diaphragm thickening fraction (DTF) and maximal inspiratory pressure (MIP). Methods A quasi-experimental study was conducted with 26 healthy participants allocated to either an AWT group or a control group. The AWT group performed diaphragmatic breathing with abdominal weights for four weeks, while the control group performed unloaded diaphragmatic breathing. DTF was assessed under different weight conditions to examine immediate effects, and both DTF and MIP were measured on days 0, 14, and 28 to evaluate longitudinal effects using mixed-effects models. Results No significant immediate effect of abdominal loading on DTF was observed (&#x3b2; = 0.15; 95% confidence interval: -3.81 to 4.10; <i>p</i> = 0.94), with DTF decreasing under the 5-kg load condition. Over the four-week intervention, no significant group &#xd7; time interaction was found for DTF (&#x3b2; = -0.13; 95%CI: -0.51-0.26; <i>p</i> = 0.53) or MIP (&#x3b2; = -0.00; 95%CI: -0.17-0.17; <i>p</i> = 0.99). However, both groups showed modest increases in DTF and MIP over time. Conclusion AWT did not significantly improve DTF or respiratory muscle strength compared to unloaded diaphragmatic breathing in healthy young adults. These findings suggest that AWT, in its current form, may have limited utility, and optimization of training parameters is necessary before broader application.&#xa0;Key limitations include a small sample, non-random allocation, and a short four-week period; longer, optimized trials are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Hasegawa et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasegawa</LastName><ForeName>Kakeru</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation, Akita University Hospital, Akita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sai</LastName><ForeName>Ayano</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nagamachi Hospital, Sendai, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okura</LastName><ForeName>Kazuki</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rehabilitation, Akita University Hospital, Akita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satake</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Akita University School of Health Sciences, Akita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal weight training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diaphragm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quasi-experimental</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound imaging</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ethics Committee, Akita University Graduate School of Medicine issued approval 2927. In accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, the study objectives and methods were explained to the participants using the prescribed form, and written informed consent was obtained prior to enrollment . Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41306143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12645337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.95429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Two-dimensional ultrasound imaging of the diaphragm: quantitative values in normal subjects. Boon AJ, Harper CJ, Ghahfarokhi LS, Strommen JA, Watson JC, Sorenson EJ. Muscle Nerve. 2013;47:884&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23625789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaphragmatic motion studied by m-mode ultrasonography: methods, reproducibility, and normal values. Boussuges A, Gole Y, Blanc P. Chest. 2009;135:391&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19017880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Three-dimensional reconstruction of the in vivo human diaphragm shape at different lung volumes. Loring SH. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1994;76:493&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaphragm: pathophysiology and ultrasound imaging in neuromuscular disorders. Fayssoil A, Behin A, Ogna A, et al. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5836400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of abdominal sandbag training in enhancing diaphragm muscle function and exercise tolerance in patients with chronic respiratory failure. Lin TK, Chen MY, Cheng HH, Chow J, Chen CM, Chou W. J Formos Med Assoc. 2024;123:1087&#x2013;1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38302365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of two breathing exercise programs for patients with quadriplegia. Derrickson J, Ciesla N, Simpson N, Imle PC. Phys Ther. 1992;72:763&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1409873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of abdominal weight training with and without cough machine assistance on lung function in the patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation: a randomized trial. Hung TY, Wu WL, Kuo HC, et al. Crit Care. 2022;26:153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Respiratory muscle strength training with nonrespiratory maneuvers. DePalo VA, Parker AL, Al-Bilbeisi F, McCool FD. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2004;96:731&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measuring diaphragm thickness with ultrasound in mechanically ventilated patients: feasibility, reproducibility and validity. Goligher EC, Laghi F, Detsky ME, et al. Intensive Care Med. 2015;41:642&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25693448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, et al. Eur Respir J. 2019;53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of abdominal muscle training on respiratory muscle strength and forced expiratory flows in sedentary, healthy adolescents. Rodr&#xed;guez-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez I, Navarro X, Gatica D, Manterola C. Arch Argent Pediatr. 2016;114:434&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27606641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Respiratory muscle training in healthy humans: resolving the controversy. McConnell AK, Romer LM. Int J Sports Med. 2004;25:284&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15162248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of high-intensity inspiratory muscle training on lung volumes, diaphragm thickness, and exercise capacity in subjects who are healthy. Enright SJ, Unnithan VB, Heward C, Withnall L, Davies DH. Phys Ther. 2006;86:345&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16506871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The variations in intra-abdominal pressure and the activity of the abdominal muscles during breathing; a study in man. CA EJ, GR JH. J Physiol. 1953;122:282&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1366115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13118539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How the abdominal muscles act on the rib cage. De Troyer A, Sampson M, Sigrist S, Kelly S. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1983;54:465&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6219975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiology of obesity and effects on lung function. Salome CM, King GG, Berend N. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2010;108:206&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19875713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study of diaphragmatic muscle function during abdominal weight in normal subjects [Article in Spanish] Monteiro SG, Pessolano FA, Su&#xe1;rez AA, De Vito EL. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22522848/ Medicina (B Aires) 2012;72:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22522848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of inspiratory muscle training in COPD patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Beaumont M, Forget P, Couturaud F, Reychler G. Clin Respir J. 2018;12:2178&#x2013;2188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29665262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-intensity inspiratory muscle training in COPD. Hill K, Jenkins SC, Philippe DL, et al. Eur Respir J. 2006;27:1119&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of inspiratory muscle training in patients with COPD: what is the evidence? Gosselink R, De Vos J, van den Heuvel SP, Segers J, Decramer M, Kwakkel G. Eur Respir J. 2011;37:416&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle training for intensive care patients: a multidisciplinary practical guide for clinicians. Bissett B, Leditschke IA, Green M, Marzano V, Collins S, Van Haren F. Aust Crit Care. 2019;32:249&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30007823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyspnoea in COPD: can inspiratory muscle training help? Hill K, Jenkins SC, Hillman DR, Eastwood PR. Aust J Physiother. 2004;50:169&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>