<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41396195</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-5022</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2026 Mar-Apr 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of public health management and practice : JPHMP</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Public Health Manag Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Academic-Nonprofit Partnership for Public Health: Document Analysis and Systematization of the Implementation of a Multijurisdictional Long COVID Surveillance Platform.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>227</StartPage><EndPage>236</EndPage><MedlinePgn>227-236</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHH.0000000000002316</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Health information exchanges (HIEs) are generally underutilized as data sources for public health surveillance, potentially decreasing the ability of public health practitioners to leverage the rich, real-time, clinical, and public health data therewith contained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematize the process of implementing an academic-nonprofit partnership (ANPP) designed to leverage multijurisdictional HIE data for public health surveillance of Long COVID by Systematizing the ANPP's. Implementation, with a focus on its operational strengths, opportunities, challenges, and strategies for its sustained growth.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Document review and analysis informed by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's Surveillance System Evaluation framework. We employed a systematic approach to the collection and interpretation of 5 types of documents to describe the experience of implementing a multistakeholder, multijurisdictional, HIE-based ANPP for public health surveillance from 2022 to 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Multijurisdictional settings in the US.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The ANPP and its constituent organizations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION" NlmCategory="METHODS">Implementation of the ANPP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Identification of critical lessons learned including key partnership elements, encountered challenges, surveillance framework application, and strategies for implementing a multistakeholder, multijurisdictional ANPP for public health surveillance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A participatory, iterative approach was used to engage stakeholders on ANPP implementation. Foundational strengths included complementary partner expertise and robust data environments, which created unique opportunities for comprehensive Long COVID surveillance. Challenges involved navigating varied institutional, legal, and regulatory requirements, complex data permission structures, and coordinating teams across different time zones. Key lessons learned highlighted that extensive initial investment in legal frameworks, data environments, and communication protocols, though time-consuming, significantly improves surveillance capabilities. Strategies to ensure success included replacing large meetings with focused working groups, fostering frequent communication, and implementing rigorous inter-team data quality control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Implementing multistakeholder, multijurisdictional, HIE-based surveillance necessitates substantial upfront investment. Continuous refinement and strategic efforts are vital for overcoming operational complexities and maximizing HIE potential for robust public health surveillance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Vinita</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5944-6264</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Author Affiliations: Department of Community and Global Health, Richard M. Fairbanks School of Public Health, Indiana University Indianapolis, Indianapolis, Indiana (Dr Reina Ortiz and Dr Sharma); Operations, Bronx Regional Health Information Organization (Bronx RHIO), New York City, New York (Ms Epstein and Ms Arora); Data Solutions Department, Comagine Health, Seattle, Washington (Dr Edinger and Ms Dahlquist); School of Medicine, Oregon Health &amp; Science University, Portland, Oregon (Dr Edinger); Utah Health Information Network, Murray, Utah (Mr Flessner); School of Public and Population Health, Boise State University, Boise, Idaho (Dr McCullough); Department of Health Policy and Management, Richard M. Fairbanks School of Public Health, Indiana University Indianapolis, Indiana (Mr Ghimire); and College of Health and Human Services, Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, Michigan (Dr Smith).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Epstein</LastName><ForeName>Rebekah</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arora</LastName><ForeName>Megha K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-1056-3077</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edinger</LastName><ForeName>Tracy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7411-5108</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dahlquist</LastName><ForeName>McKenna</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flessner</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCullough</LastName><ForeName>J Mac</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0070-4943</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghimire</LastName><ForeName>Umesh</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4246-8379</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Lillian Upton</ForeName><Initials>LU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8391-7970</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reina Ortiz</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3309-6881</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Public Health Manag Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9505213</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-4659</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011634" MajorTopicYN="Y">Public Health</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062486" MajorTopicYN="Y">Public Health Surveillance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009939" MajorTopicYN="Y">Organizations, Nonprofit</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066275" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Information Exchange</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055818" MajorTopicYN="N">Public-Private Sector Partnerships</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092002" MajorTopicYN="N">Document Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic-nonprofit partnership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health information exchange</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-COVID conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surveillance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41396195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHH.0000000000002316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124784-202603000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chu L, Bishof K, Dumes AA, Wesley Ely E, Joseph PV, Troxel AB. National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, Medicine (NASEM) committee on examining the working definition for long COVID. the 2024 national academies of sciences, engineering, and medicine long COVID definition: what clinicians need to know. J Gen Intern Med. 2025;40(9):2024-2027. doi:10.1007/s11606-025-09415-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-025-09415-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saydah SH, Brooks JT, Jackson BR. Surveillance for post-COVID conditions is necessary: addressing the challenges with multiple approaches. J Gen Intern Med. 2022;37(7). doi:10.1007/s11606-022-07446-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-022-07446-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Lu R, Tian Y, et al. Prevalence of and factors associated with long COVID among US adults: a nationwide survey. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):1-10. doi:10.1186/s12889-025-22987-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-22987-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchey MD, Rosenblum HG, Del Guercio K, et al. COVID-19 self-test data: challenges and opportunities &#x2014; United States, October 31, 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(32):1005-1010. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm7132a1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7132a1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santillana M, Uslu AA, Urmi T, et al. Tracking COVID-19 infections using survey data on rapid at-home tests. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(9):e2435442&#x2013;e2435442. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.35442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.35442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klompas M, McVetta J, Lazarus R, et al. Integrating clinical practice and public health surveillance using electronic medical record systems. Am J Prev Med. 2012;42(6 SUPPL. 2):S154&#x2013;S162. doi:10.1016/j.amepre.2012.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2012.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisball J, Grimson J, Grimson W, Berry D, Hederman L. From passive to active electronic healthcare records. Methods Inf Med. 2003;42(5). doi:10.1055/s-0038-1634380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0038-1634380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham M, Patel K, McCall TC, et al. Current implementation in information technology systems by size of population served. Washington, DC: National Association of County and City Health Officials; 2022. 2022 National profile of local health departments. https://www.naccho.org/resources/lhd-research/national-profile-of-local-health-departments . Accessed June 4, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buntin MB, Jain SH, Blumenthal D. Health information technology: laying the infrastructure for national health reform. Health Aff. 2010;29(6):1214-1219. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.2010.0503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2010.0503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vest JR, Gamm LD. Health information exchange: persistent challenges and new strategies. J Am Med Inform Assoc: JAMIA. 2010;17(3):288. doi: 10.1136/jamia.2010.003673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jamia.2010.003673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RM, Andrews JG, Dalton AF, Dixon BE, Dzomba BJ, Fernando SI, Pogreba-Brown KM, Reina Ortiz M, Sharma V, Simmons N, Saydah SH. Tracking the burden, distribution, and impact of Post-COVID conditions in diverse populations for children, adolescents, and adults (Track PCC): passive and active surveillance protocols. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):2345. doi: 10.1186/s12889-024-19772-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-19772-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon BE, Allen KS, Simmons N, Brinkley J, Andrews JG, Dzomba BJ, Feiler MO, Jones RM, Reina Ortiz M, Sharma V, Dalton AF, Pratt C, Grannis SJ, Saydah S. Incidence of long COVID among US children and adults during the omicron era-tracking post-COVID conditions (Track-PCC) Network, 2022-2023. J Infect Public Health. 2025;18(11):102935. doi: 10.1016/j.jiph.2025.102935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiph.2025.102935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Updated guidelines for evaluating public health surveillance systems: recommendations from the guidelines working group. MMWR Recomm Rep. 2001;50(RR-13):1-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comagine Health. Company. 2025. https://comagine.org/company . Accessed September 15, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BeyondHIE. About BeyondHIE. 2025. https://beyondhie.org/about-beyondhie/ . Accessed September 15, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronx RHIO Inc. Bronx Regional Health Information Organization (Bronx RHIO). https://bronxrhio.org/about-us/ . Accessed June 4, 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UHIN. About us. https://uhin.org/company/about/ . Accessed September 15, 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fife ST, Gossner JD. Deductive qualitative analysis: evaluating, expanding, and refining theory. Int J Qual Methods. 2024;23:16094069241244856. doi:10.1177/16094069241244856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069241244856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyatzis RE. Transforming Qualitative Information: Thematic Analysis and Code Development. Sage; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fereday J, Muir-Cochrane E. Demonstrating rigor using thematic analysis: a hybrid approach of inductive and deductive coding and theme development. Int J Qual Methods. 2005;5(1):80-92. doi: 10.1177/160940690600500107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/160940690600500107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuendorf KA. Content analysis and thematic analysis. Advanced Research Methods for Applied Psychology. Routledge; 2018:211-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainscough E, Smith SN, Greenwell K, Hoare DJ. Findings and ethical considerations from a thematic analysis of threads within tinnitus online support groups. Am J Audiol. 2018;27(3S):503-512. doi: 10.1044/2018_AJA-IMIA3-18-0013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1044/2018_AJA-IMIA3-18-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osamika D, Adelusi BS, Kelvin-Agwu MTC, Mustapha AY, Forkuo AY, Ikhalea N. A critical review of health data interoperability standards: FHIR, HL7, and beyond. Wsn. 2025;203:194-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact Technical Resources. HL7 v2 vs. HL7 v3: key Differences and Industry Adoption. https://www.itrvn.com/blogs/hl7-v2-vs-hl7-v3-key-differences-and-industry-adoption , 2025. Accessed September 16, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotter JP. Leading Change. Boston: Harvard Business School Press; 1996</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>