<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41562412</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rehabilitation interventions for oropharyngeal dysphagia in people with Parkinson's disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD015816</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD015816</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD015816</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD015816.pub2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="RATIONALE">Oropharyngeal dysphagia is a common and disabling symptom in people with Parkinson's disease, affecting the safety and efficiency of swallowing and increasing the risk of malnutrition and aspiration pneumonia. Despite its clinical relevance, the effectiveness of rehabilitation interventions for managing dysphagia in this population remains uncertain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To assess the effectiveness of rehabilitation interventions for oropharyngeal dysphagia in improving swallowing safety and efficiency in people with Parkinson's disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">We searched the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), MEDLINE, Embase, Cumulative Index to Nursing and Allied Health Literature, Web of Science, and Speech Pathology Database for Best Interventions and Treatment Efficacy up to 26 September 2025. We also searched ClinicalTrials.gov and the World Health Organization International Clinical Trials Registry Platform to retrieve ongoing and recently completed trials, and OpenGrey for grey literature.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA">We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) of rehabilitation interventions aimed at improving oropharyngeal dysphagia in people with Parkinson's disease. We included any rehabilitation intervention for oropharyngeal dysphagia, alone or in combination with another rehabilitation intervention, with or without concurrent pharmacological treatments. Comparators included no intervention, usual care, a placebo/sham stimulation or attention control intervention, or any other rehabilitation intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES">Critical outcomes: swallowing safety and swallowing efficiency Important outcomes: dysphagia severity, saliva management, quality of life, respiratory outcomes, nutritional and dietary outcomes, and adverse events RISK OF BIAS: We assessed the risk of bias in the included studies using Cochrane's revised risk of bias (RoB 2) tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYNTHESIS METHODS">When two or more studies were pooled, we conducted a random-effects meta-analysis to calculate standardised mean differences (SMDs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs). When only one study was available, we used a fixed-effect model to estimate the effect, calculating mean differences (MDs) or odds ratios (ORs) with 95% CIs for all outcomes. We used the GRADE approach to assess the certainty of the evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INCLUDED STUDIES">We included 18 studies (1216 participants). Five studies were conducted in Europe, four in the USA, and nine in the rest of the world. Generally, studies were heterogeneous and often poorly reported. We included only two studies in the meta-analysis. Ten studies tested behavioural interventions, while eight studies tested one or more stimulation interventions: neuromuscular treatments (three studies), repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (two studies), deep brain stimulation (two studies), and transcranial direct current stimulation (one study).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYNTHESIS OF RESULTS">Compared to sham expiratory muscle strength training (EMST), EMST may improve swallowing safety at the end of four weeks of treatment (SMD -0.66, 95% CI -1.04 to -0.28; I&#xb2; = 0%; 2 studies; 113 participants; very low-certainty evidence), but the evidence is very uncertain. Similarly, the evidence is very uncertain about the effect of EMST compared to sham EMST on all the following outcomes: swallowing safety after three months of follow-up (MD -0.18, 95% CI -0.69 to 0.33; 1 study, 45 participants); swallowing efficiency at the end of treatment (MD -4.4, 95% CI -7.5 to -1.3; 1 study, 45 participants), and after three months (MD -1.7, 95% CI -4.58 to 1.18; 1 study, 45 participants); dysphagia severity at the end of treatment (MD -2.78, 95% CI -18.04 to 12.48; 1 study; 45 participants) and after three months (MD -2.9, 95% CI -16.94 to 11.14; 1 study; 45 participants); quality of life at the end of treatment (MD 14.69, 95% CI -63.52 to 92.90; 1 study, 45 participants) and after three months (MD 11.4, 95% CI -67.95 to 90.75; 1 study, 45 participants). Lastly, EMST may result in little to no difference in peak expiratory flow after five weeks of treatment (MD -0.5 L/second, 95% CI -1.05 to 0.05; 1 study, 58 participants; low-certainty evidence). The evidence is very uncertain about the effect of video-assisted swallowing therapy (VAST) plus speech-language therapy (SLT) compared to SLT alone on all the following outcomes: quality of life at the end of treatment (MD 1.62, 95% CI 0.33 to 2.91; 1 study, 42 participants), and after six months (MD 1.86, 95% CI 0.82 to 2.9; 1 study, 42 participants); and dysphagia severity at the end of treatment (MD -0.7, 95% CI -5.13 to 3.73; 1 study, 42 participants) and in the long term (MD -4.03, 95% CI -7.85 to -0.21; 1 study, 42 participants). The evidence is very uncertain about the effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) plus SLT compared to sham NMES plus SLT on swallowing safety (MD -1.34, 95% CI -2.32 to -0.36; 1 study, 18 participants; very low-certainty evidence), and swallowing efficiency at the end of four weeks of treatment (MD -2.34, 95% CI -7.16 to 2.48; 1 study, 18 participants; very low-certainty evidence). The evidence is also very uncertain about the effect of tongue strength training plus SLT compared to SLT alone on dysphagia severity after eight weeks of treatment (MD 0.13, 95% CI -0.17 to 0.43; 1 study, 60 participants; very low-certainty evidence). Our certainty in these findings is very low due to imprecision (small sample size), high risk of bias related to deviations from intended interventions, measurement of the outcome, and the randomisation process, and poor reporting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Although the number of RCTs has increased since the publication of a previous Cochrane review on the topic in 2001, uncertainty remains regarding the effectiveness of swallowing rehabilitation in individuals with Parkinson's disease. Behavioural interventions, particularly EMST, may improve swallowing safety by reducing penetration and aspiration, but the evidence is very uncertain. Most included studies were small and methodologically limited, constraining the robustness of conclusions. Large, well-designed, placebo-controlled trials are required to assess the effectiveness of rehabilitation interventions for oropharyngeal dysphagia in people with Parkinson's disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING">No funding was received for this work.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION">Protocol (2024) DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD015816.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Battel</LastName><ForeName>Irene</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical, Surgical and Dental Sciences, University "La Statale", Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arienti</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0787-6075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology and Research Center, Department of Biomedical Sciences, Humanitas University, Pieve Emanuele, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Humanitas Research Hospital, Rozzano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Furia</LastName><ForeName>Matteo Johann</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical, Surgical and Dental Sciences, University "La Statale", Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mental and Physical Health and Preventive Medicine, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Istituto Ortopedico Galeazzi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lazzarini</LastName><ForeName>Stefano Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Quantitative Methods, University of Milano-Bicocca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warnecke</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurorehabilitation, Klinikum Osnabr&#xfc;ck - Academic Teaching Hospital of the University of M&#xfc;nster, Osnabr&#xfc;ck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walshe</LastName><ForeName>Margaret</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Speech and Language Studies, Trinity College, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD015816</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015982" MajorTopicYN="N">Bias</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Irene Battel declares no conflicts of interest. Chiara Arienti declares no conflicts of interest. Matteo Johann Del Furia declares no conflicts of interest. Stefano Giuseppe Lazzarini declares no conflicts of interest. Tobias Warnecke received speaker fees/honoraria from Bial, Abbvie, Merz, Desitin, Pfizer, Britannia, Zambon, Neuraxpharm, Esteve, and Licher. He also received payment for travel, accommodation, subsistence, and conference registration from Abbvie. He received payment for expert advice from Stadapharm, Bial, Merz, Abbvie, and Phagenesis. He received funding for research from Abbvie and Ever Pharma. He is also a co&#x2010;author of two included studies (Cebi 2025; Claus 2021). Margaret Walshe died in March 2025. No declarations of interest are available.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41562412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12821585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD015816.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Balestrino R, Schapira AH. Parkinson disease. European Journal of Neurology 2020;27(1):27-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball N, Teo WP, Chandra S, Chapman J. Parkinson's disease and the environment. Frontiers in Neurology 2019;10:218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch MA, Iyer SS, Sanjak M. Exercise-induced neuroplasticity in human Parkinson's disease: what is the evidence telling us? Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2016;22 Suppl 1:S78-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller N. Swallowing in Parkinson's disease: clinical issues and management. Neurodegenerative Disease Management 2017;7(3):205-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suttrup I, Warnecke T. Dysphagia in Parkinson's Disease. Dysphagia 2016;31(1):24-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalf JG, Swart BJ, Bloem BR, Munneke M. Prevalence of oropharyngeal dysphagia in Parkinson's disease: a meta-analysis. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2012;18(4):311-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilmaghani S, Atieh J, Khanna L, Hosfield EA, Camilleri M, Katzka DA. Severity of dysphagia is associated with hospitalizations and mortality in patients with Parkinson's disease. Neurogastroenterology and Motility 2022;34(6):e14280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson P, Meara J. Mortality and quality of death certification in a cohort of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and matched controls in North Wales, UK at 18 years: a community-based cohort study. BMJ Open 2018;8(2):e018969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman-Prine EK, Sapienza CM, Okun MS, Pollock SL, Jacobson C, Wu SS, et al. The relationship between quality of life and swallowing in Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders 2009;24(9):1352-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battel I, Calvo I, Walshe M. Interventions involving biofeedback to improve swallowing in people with Parkinson disease and dysphagia: a systematic review. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2020;102(2):314-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang MC, Park JS, Lee BJ, Park D. Effectiveness of pharmacologic treatment for dysphagia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a narrative review. Neurological Sciences 2021;42(2):513-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng I, Sasegbon A, Hamdy S. Dysphagia treatments in Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility 2023;35(8):e14517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar U, Dham B, He Y, Hack N, Wu S, Troche M, et al. Incidence and mortality trends of aspiration pneumonia in Parkinson's disease in the United States, 1979-2010. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2015;21(9):1082-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi D, Imbalzano G, Galli S, Bianchini E, Ledda C, De Carolis L, et al. The impact of dysphagia in Parkinson's disease patients treated with levodopa/carbidopa intestinal gel. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2023;109:105368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabbri M, Coelho M, Abreu D, Guedes LC, Rosa MM, Godinho C, et al. Dysphagia predicts poor outcome in late-stage Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2019;64:73-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller J, Wenning GK, Verny M, McKee A, Chaudhuri KR, Jellinger K, et al. Progression of dysarthria and dysphagia in postmortem-confirmed parkinsonian disorders. Archives of Neurology 2001;58(2):259-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhmann C, Bihler M, Emich K, Hidding U, Potter-Nerger M, Gerloff C, et al. Pill swallowing in Parkinson's disease: a prospective study based on flexible endoscopic evaluation of swallowing. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2019;62:51-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Healy DG, Schapira AH. Non-motor symptoms of Parkinson's disease: diagnosis and management. Lancet Neurology 2006;5(3):235-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter PC, Crameri J, Austin S, Woodward MC, Hughes AJ. Response of parkinsonian swallowing dysfunction to dopaminergic stimulation. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry 1997;63(5):579-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandell LA, Niederman MS. Aspiration pneumonia. New England Journal of Medicine 2019;380(7):651-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nienstedt JC, Bihler M, Niessen A, Plaetke R, Potter-Nerger M, Gerloff C, et al. Predictive clinical factors for penetration and aspiration in Parkinson's disease. Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility Journal 2019;31(3):e13524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won JH, Byun SJ, Oh BM, Park SJ, Seo HG. Risk and mortality of aspiration pneumonia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a nationwide database study. Scientific Reports 2021;11(1):6597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegland KW, Okun MS, Troche MS. Sequential voluntary cough and aspiration or aspiration risk in Parkinson's disease. Lung 2014;192(4):601-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitts T, Troche M, Mann G, Rosenbek J, Okun MS, Sapienza C. Using voluntary cough to detect penetration and aspiration during oropharyngeal swallowing in patients with Parkinson disease. Chest 2010;138(6):1426-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Okun MS, Rosenbek JC, Musson N, Fernandez HH, Rodriguez R, et al. Aspiration and swallowing in Parkinson disease and rehabilitation with EMST: a randomized trial. Neurology 2010;75(21):1912-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Schumann B, Brandimore AE, Okun MS, Hegland KW. Reflex cough and disease duration as predictors of swallowing dysfunction in Parkinson's disease. Dysphagia 2016;31(6):757-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler HK, Troche MS, Brandimore AE, Davenport PW, Okun MS. Comparison of voluntary and reflex cough effectiveness in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2014;20(11):1226-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons JA. Swallowing dysfunctions in Parkinson's disease. International Review of Neurobiology 2017;134:1207-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pflug C, Bihler M, Emich K, Niessen A, Nienstedt JC, Flugel T, et al. Critical dysphagia is common in Parkinson disease and occurs even in early stages: a prospective cohort study. Dysphagia 2018;33(1):41-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Sapienza CM, Rosenbek JC. Effects of bolus consistency on timing and safety of swallow in patients with Parkinson's disease. Dysphagia 2008;23(1):26-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labeit B, Claus I, Muhle P, Lapa S, Suntrup-Krueger S. Oropharyngeal freezing and its relation to dysphagia - an analogy to freezing of gait. Parkinsonism Related Disorders 2020;75:1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuoka T, Ono T, Hori K, Wada Y, Uchiyama Y, Kasama S, et al. Tongue pressure measurement and videofluoroscopic study of swallowing in patients with Parkinson's disease. Dysphagia 2019;34(1):80-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis JA, Molfenter S, Troche MS. Predictors of residue and airway invasion in Parkinson's disease. Dysphagia 2020;35(2):220-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis JA, Molfenter SM, Troche MS. Pharyngeal area changes in Parkinson's disease and its effect on swallowing safety, efficiency, and kinematics. Dysphagia 2020;35(2):389-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke T, Suttrup I, Schroder JB, Osada N, Oelenberg S, Hamacher C, et al. Levodopa responsiveness of dysphagia in advanced Parkinson's disease and reliability testing of the FEES-Levodopa-test. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2016;28:100-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke T, Labeit B, Schroeder J, Reckels A, Ahring S, Lapa S, et al. Neurogenic dysphagia: a systematic review and proposal of a classification system. Neurology 2020;96(6):e876-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battel I, Walshe M. An intensive neurorehabilitation programme with sEMG biofeedback to improve swallowing in idiopathic Parkinson's disease (IPD): a feasibility study. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders 2022;58(3):813-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzorni N, Ciammola A, Casazza G, Ginocchio D, Bianchi F, Feroldi S, et al. Predictors of malnutrition risk in neurodegenerative diseases: the role of swallowing function. European Journal of Neurology 2022;29(8):2493-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athukorala RP, Jones RD, Sella O, Huckabee ML. Skill training for swallowing rehabilitation in patients with Parkinson's disease. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2014;95(7):1374-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor Y, Mootanah R, Freud D, Giladi N, Cohen JT. Video-assisted swallowing therapy for patients with Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2013;19(2):207-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren MR, Baijens LW, Voskuilen S, Oosterloo M, Kremer B. Treatment effects for dysphagia in Parkinson's disease: a systematic review. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2014;20(8):800-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschwald J, Hofacker J, Duncan S, Walshe M. Swallowing outcomes in dysphagia interventions in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a scoping review. BMJ Evidence-Based Medicine 2022;28(2):111-8. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjebm-2022-112082]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjebm-2022-112082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry SE, Borders JC, Dakin AE, Troche MS. Characterizing quality of life in caregivers of people with Parkinson's disease and dysphagia. Dysphagia 2022;37(3):523-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attrill S, White S, Murray J, Hammond S, Doeltgen S. Impact of oropharyngeal dysphagia on healthcare cost and length of stay in hospital: a systematic review. BMC Health Services Research 2018;18(1):594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin S, Serra-Prat M, Ortega O, Audouard Fericgla M, Valls J, Palomera E, et al. Healthcare costs of post-stroke oropharyngeal dysphagia and its complications: malnutrition and respiratory infections. European Journal of Neurology 2021;28(11):3670-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Luca DG, McArthur EW, Willis A, Martino R, Marras C. Clinical and economic outcomes associated with dysphagia in hospitalized patients with Parkinson's disease. Journal of Parkinson's Disease 2021;11(4):1965-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbek JC, Robbins JA, Roecker EB, Coyle JL, Wood JL. A penetration-aspiration scale. Dysphagia 1996;11(2):93-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi P, Steele CM. Effectiveness of interventions for dysphagia in Parkinson disease: a systematic review. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology 2022;31(1):463-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menezes C, Melo A. Does levodopa improve swallowing dysfunction in Parkinson's disease patients? Journal of Clinical Pharmacy and Therapeutics 2009;34(6):673-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke T, Hamacher C, Oelenberg S, Dziewas R. Off and on state assessment of swallowing function in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2014;20(9):1033-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig P, Dieppe P, Macintyre S, Michie S, Nazareth I, Petticrew M. Developing and evaluating complex interventions: the new Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ 2008;337:a1655. [DOI: 10.1136/bmj.a1655]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.a1655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, Craig P, Baird J, Blazeby JM. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ 2021;374:n2061. [DOI: 10.1136/bmj.n2061]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n2061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Kim HH. Effects of behavioural swallowing therapy in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology 2023;25(2):269-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winiker K, Kertscher B. Behavioural interventions for swallowing in subjects with Parkinson's disease: a mixed methods systematic review. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders 2023;58(4):1375-404. [DOI: 10.1111/1460-6984.12865] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cichero JAY. Evaluating chewing function: expanding the dysphagia field using food oral processing and the IDDSI framework. Journal of Texture Studies 2020;51(1):56-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva N, Verri E, Palinkas M, Hallak J, Regalo S, Siessere S. Impact of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease on the efficiency of masticatory cycles: electromyographic analysis. Medicina Oral, Patolog&#xed;a Oral y Cirug&#xed;a Bucal 2019;24(3):e314-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuo K, Fujishima I. Textural changes by mastication and proper food texture for patients with oropharyngeal dysphagia. Nutrients 2020;12(6):1613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele M, Alsanei WA, Ayanikalath S, Barbon CE, Chen J, Cichero JA, et al. The influence of food texture and liquid consistency modification on swallowing physiology and function: a systematic review. Dysphagia 2015;30(1):2-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn E, Smith CH, Walsh CD, Walshe M. Modifying the consistency of food and fluids for swallowing difficulties in dementia. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 9. Art. No: CD011077. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011077.pub2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011077.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA, Gensler G, Robbins J, Lindblad AS, Brandt D, Hind JA, et al. A randomized study of three interventions for aspiration of thin liquids in patients with dementia or Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research 2008;51(1):173-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman R, Vilardell N, Clav&#xe9; P, Speyer R. Effect of bolus viscosity on the safety and efficacy of swallowing and the kinematics of the swallow response in patients with oropharyngeal dysphagia: white paper by the European Society for Swallowing Disorders (ESSD). Dysphagia 2016;31(2):232-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Gensler G, Hind J, Logemann JA, Lindblad AS, Brandt D, et al. Comparison of 2 interventions for liquid aspiration on pneumonia incidence: a randomized trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2008;148(7):509-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmore SE, Pisegna JM. Efficacy of exercises to rehabilitate dysphagia: a critique of the literature. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology 2015;17(3):222-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Butler SG, Daniels SK, Diez GR, Langmore S, Lazarus CL, et al. Swallowing and dysphagia rehabilitation: translating principles of neural plasticity into clinically oriented evidence. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research 2008;51(1):S276-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocks N, Rafols J, Embley E, Hill K. Expiratory muscle strength training for drooling in adults with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Dysphagia 2022;37(6):1525-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes A, Castillo A, Castillo J, Cornejo I. The effects of respiratory muscle training on peak cough flow in patients with Parkinson's disease: a randomized controlled study. Clinical Rehabilitation 2018;32(10):1317-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks J, Pitts LL. Effects of an intensive exercise-based swallowing program for persons with Parkinson's disease and complex medical history: a single-case experiment. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology 2019;28(3):1268-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegland KW, Troche M, Brandimore A. Relationship between respiratory sensory perception, speech, and swallow in Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders Clinical Practice 2019;6(3):243-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles A, Jardine M, Johnston F, Lisle M, Friary P, Allen J. Effect of Lee Silverman Voice Treatment (LSVT LOUD(R)) on swallowing and cough in Parkinson's disease: a pilot study. Journal of the Neurological Sciences 2017;383:180-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RE. Neuroplasticity and swallowing. Dysphagia 2009;24(2):218-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huckabee ML, Burnip E. Still rethinking rehab: motor learning treatment approaches for dysphagia. Perspectives of the ASHA Special Interest Groups 2018;3(13):146-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Brandimore AE, Foote KD, Morishita T, Chen D, Hegland KW, et al. Swallowing outcomes following unilateral STN vs. GPi surgery: a retrospective analysis. Dysphagia 2014;29(4):425-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Mohamed KO, Soliman RK, Hassan AM, Rothwell JC. The effect of high-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on advancing Parkinson's disease with dysphagia: double blind randomized clinical trial. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2019;33(6):442-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasegbon A, Hammerbeck U, Michou E, Cheng I, Zhang M, James C, et al. A feasibility pilot study of the effects of neurostimulation on swallowing function in Parkinson's Disease. Association of Medical Research Charities 2022;3:19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Oh DH, Hwang NK, Lee JH. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in patients with Parkinson's disease and dysphagia: a randomized, single-blind, placebo-controlled trial. NeuroRehabilitation 2018;42(4):457-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann J. Approaches to management of disordered swallowing. Clinical Gastroenterology 1991;5:269-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan J, Walshe M, Tobin WO. Immediate effects of thermal-tactile stimulation on timing of swallow in idiopathic Parkinson's disease. Dysphagia 2010;25(3):207-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krival K, Pelletier C, Kelchner L. Effects of carbonate vs thin and thickened liquids on swallowing in adults with stroke. Dysphagia 2008;23:428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price K, Isbister G, Long S, Mirams J, Smithard D. Are bubbles the future of dysphagia rehabilitation: a systematic review analysing evidence on the use of carbonated liquids in dysphagia rehabilitation. Geriatrics 2023;8(1):6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CW, Chen RD, Feng MT, Zhang MZ, Liu W, Liu XC, et al. The therapeutic effect of capsaicin on oropharyngeal dysphagia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience 2022;14:931016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitts T, Bolser D, Rosenbek J, Troche M, Okun MS, Sapienza C. Impact of expiratory muscle strength training on voluntary cough and swallow function in Parkinson disease. Chest 2009;135(5):1301-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaney R, Miller N, Vines J, Olivier P, Ladha K, Jackson D, et al. The feasibility and acceptability of using a novel wrist worn cueing device to self-manage drooling problems in people with Parkinson's disease: a pilot study. Journal of Rehabilitation and Assistive Technologies Engineering 2019;6:2055668319852529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sharkawi A, Ramig L, Logemann JA, Pauloski BR, Rademaker AW, Smith CH, et al. Swallowing and voice effects of Lee Silverman Voice Treatment (LSVT): a pilot study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry 2002;72(1):31-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deane KH, Whurr R, Clarke CE, Playford ED, Ben-Shlomo Y. Non-pharmacological therapies for dysphagia in Parkinson's disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2001, Issue 1. Art. No: CD002816. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD002816]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Lasserson T, Thomas J, Flemyng E, Churchill. Methodological Expectations of Cochrane Intervention Reviews. Cochrane: London, Version August 2023. Available from https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/mecir.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:n71. [DOI: 10.1136/bmj.n71]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg D, Postuma RB, Adler CH, Bloem BR, Chan P, Dubois B, et al. MDS research criteria for prodromal Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders 2015;30(12):1600-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neubauer PD, Rademaker AW, Leder SB. The Yale Pharyngeal Residue Severity Rating Scale: an anatomically defined and image-based tool. Dysphagia 2015;30(5):521-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rommel N, Borgers C, Van BD, Goeleven A, Dejaeger E, Omari TI. Bolus Residue Scale: an easy-to-use and reliable videofluoroscopic analysis tool to score bolus residue in patients with dysphagia. International Journal of Otolaryngology 2015;178(2):393-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhuber E, Schima W, Schober E, Pokieser P, Stadler A, Scharitzer M, et al. Videofluoroscopic assessment of patients with dysphagia: pharyngeal retention is a predictive factor for aspiration. American Journal of Roentgenology 2002;178(2):393-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neil KH, Purdy M, Falk J, Gallo L. The Dysphagia Outcome and Severity Scale. Dysphagia 1999;14(3):139-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohara H, Palmer JB, Reynolds K, Kuhlemeier KV, Palmer S. Dysphagia severity scale. Kokubyo Gakkai Zasshi 2003;70:242-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crary MA, Mann GD, Groher ME. Initial psychometric assessment of a functional oral intake scale for dysphagia in stroke patients. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2005;86(8):1516-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHorney CA, Robbins J, Lomax K, Rosenbek JC, Chignell K, Kramer AE, et al. The SWAL-QOL and SWAL-CARE outcomes tool for oropharyngeal dysphagia in adults: III. Documentation of reliability and validity. Dysphagia 2002;17(2):97-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton RJ, Hackston A, Longmore D, Dixon R, Price S, Stroud M, et al. Malnutrition in hospital outpatients and inpatients: prevalence, concurrent validity and ease of use of the 'malnutrition universal screening tool' ('MUST') for adults. British Journal of Nutrition 2004;92(5):799-808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence. Version accessed prior to 9 January 2026. Melbourne, Australia: Veritas Health Innovation, 2023. Available at https://www.covidence.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoehn MM, Yahr MD. Parkinsonism: onset, progression and mortality. Neurology 1967;17(5):427-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz CG, Fahn S, Martinez-Martin P, Poewe W, Sampaio C, Stebbins GT, et al. Movement Disorder Society-sponsored revision of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale (MDS-UPDRS): process, format, and clinimetric testing plan. Movement Disorders 2007;22(1):41-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, &#xa0;et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Sterne JA. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in a randomized trial (chapter last updated October 2019). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychological Bulletin 1992;112(1):155-9. [DOI: 10.1037//0033-2909.112.1.155]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0033-2909.112.1.155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ, editor(s). Chapter 6: Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect (chapter last updated August 2023). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Eldridge S, Li T. Chapter 23: Including variants on randomized trials (chapter last updated October 2019). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, Terrin N, Jones DR, Lau J, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ 2011;343:d4002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clinical Trials 1986;7(3):177-88. [DOI: 10.1016/0197-2456(86)90046-2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0197-2456(86)90046-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JE, Brennan SE. Chapter 12: Synthesizing and presenting findings using other methods (chapter last updated October 2019). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG, McKenzie JE, Veroniki AA, editor(s). Chapter 10: Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses (chapter last updated November 2024). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camerucci E, Stang CD, Hajeb M, Turcano P, Mullan AF, Martin P, et al. Early-onset Parkinsonism and early-onset Parkinson's disease: a population-based study (2010-2015). Journal of Parkinson's Disease 2021;11(3):1197-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Ramirez D, Almeida L, Giugni JC, Ahmed B, Higuchi MA, Little CS, et al. Rate of aspiration pneumonia in hospitalized Parkinson's disease patients: a cross-sectional study. BMC Neurology 2015;15:104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review Manager (RevMan). The Cochrane Collaboration: 9.17.0, 2025. Available at revman.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini S, Selb M, Kiekens C, Todhunter-Brown A, Arienti C, Stucki G, et al. Rehabilitation methodology meeting participants. Rehabilitation definition for research purposes: a global stakeholders' initiative by Cochrane Rehabilitation. American Journal of Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation 2022;101(7):e100-7. [DOI: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000002031] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti C, Armijo-Olivo S, Minozzi S, Tjosvold L, Lazzarini SG, Patrini M, et al. Methodological issues in rehabilitation research: a scoping review. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2021;102(8):1614-22.e14. [DOI: 10.1016/j.apmr.2021.04.006] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33989598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Higgins JP, Vist GE, Glasziou P, Akl EA, Skoetz N, Guyatt GH. Chapter 14: Completing &#x2018;Summary of findings&#x2019; tables and grading the certainty of the evidence (chapter last updated August 2023). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Vist GE, Higgins JP, Santesso N, Deeks JJ, Glasziou P, et al. Chapter 15: Interpreting results and drawing conclusions (chapter last updated August 2023). In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baijens LW, Speyer R, Passos VL, Pilz W, Van der Kruis J, Haarmans S, et al. Surface electrical stimulation in dysphagic Parkinson patients: a randomized clinical trial. Laryngoscope 2013;123(11):E38-44. [DOI: 10.1002/lary.24119]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lary.24119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baijens LW, Speyer R, Passos VL, Pilz W, Van der Kruis J, Haarmans S, et al. Surface electrical stimulation in dysphagic Parkinson patients: a randomized clinical trial. Dysphagia 2014;29(3):404. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-014-9536-7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-014-9536-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cebi I, Graf LH, Sch&#xfc;tt M, Hormozi M, Klocke P, L&#xf6;ffler M, et al. Oral transport, penetration, and aspiration in PD: insights from a RCT on STN&#x2009;+&#x2009;SNr stimulation. Dysphagia 2025;40(4):811-22. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-024-10779-y]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-024-10779-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cebi I, Graf LH, Hormozi M, Schneider M, Loffler MA, Gharabaghi A, et al. Restitution of oral transport, penetration, and aspiration with nigral stimulation in Parkinson's disease? In: Clinical Neurophysiology. 2022:e40. [DOI: 10.1016/j.clinph.2022.01.075]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2022.01.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoellmann A, Stoll L, Hobl B, Meisner C, Gharabaghi A, Weiss D. Clinical trial protocol: restitution of oral transport, penetration and aspiration with nigral stimulation in Parkinson's disease? In: Movement Disorders. 2018:S158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03470324. Combined stimulation of STN and SNr for dysphagia in Parkinson's disease. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT03470324 (first posted 19 March 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claus I, Muhle P, Czechowski J, Ahring S, Labeit B, Suntrup-Krueger S, et al. Expiratory muscle strength training for therapy of pharyngeal dysphagia in Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders 2021;36(8):1815-24. [DOI: 10.1002/mds.28552]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.28552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claus I, Muhle P, Suttrup J, Schroeder JB, Suntrup-Krueger S, Dziewas R, et al. Expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) for treatment of pharyngeal dysphagia in Parkinson's disease: a randomized controlled trial. Dysphagia 2020;35(1):143. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-019-10078-x]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-019-10078-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02461082. EMST and TMS for Treatment of Dysphagia in Parkinson's Disease [Expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) and transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) for treatment of swallowing disorders in Parkinson's Disease]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT02461082 (first posted 29 May 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashtelei AA, Nitsche MA, Salehinejad MA, Habibi AH, Bakhtyiari J, Khatoonabadi AR. Adjunctive transcranial direct current stimulation to improve swallowing functions in Parkinson's disease. Experimental and Clinical Sciences Journal 2024;23:95-107. [DOI: 10.17179/excli2023-6496]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17179/excli2023-6496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irct20190412043248N1. Effect of brain stimulation on the improvement of swallowing disorder in Parkinson's patients [The effectiveness of combined transcranial Direct Current Stimulation (tDCS) and conventional swallowing therapy on improvement of the swallowing disorder in persons with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease]. trialsearch.who.int/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=Irct20190412043248N1 (first posted 15 June 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Q, Cheng Y, Lie P, Zhou X, Wang Y, Chen R, et al. Effects of vocalization training on drooling severity in Parkinson's disease. Zhongguo xiandai sheng jing jibing zashi [Chinese Journal of Contemporary Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery] 2019;19(11):891-6. [DOI: 10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2043;6731.2019.11.014]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2043;6731.2019.11.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heijnen BJ, Speyer R, Baijens LW, Bogaardt HC. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation versus traditional therapy in patients with Parkinson's disease and oropharyngeal dysphagia: effects on quality of life. Dysphagia 2012;27(3):336-45. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-011-9371-z]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-011-9371-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan GS, Kiyani MN, Ijaz T, Yousaf T, Imran S. Effectiveness of biofeedback therapy versus traditional therapy on dysphagia: a randomized control trial. Medical Forum Monthly 2025;36(7):16-20. [DOI: 10.60110/medforum.360703]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.60110/medforum.360703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT07026032. Effects of biofeedback exercises on severity of dysphagia in Parkinson's clients. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT07026032 (first posted 18 June 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Mohamed KO, Soliman RK, Hassan AM, Rothwell JC. The effect of high-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on advancing Parkinson's disease with dysphagia: double blind randomized clinical trial. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2019;33(6):442-52. [DOI: 10.1177/1545968319847968]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968319847968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03317509. The effect of high frequency rTMS on advancing Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with dysphagia [The effect of high frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on advancing Parkinson's disease with dysphagia]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT03317509 (first posted 20 October 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA, Gensler G, Robbins J, Lindblad AS, Brandt D, Hind JA, et al. A randomized study of three interventions for aspiration of thin liquids in patients with dementia or Parkinson's disease. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research 2008;51(1):173-83. [DOI: 10.1044/1092-4388(2008/013)]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1044/1092-4388(2008/013)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT00000362. Randomized study of two Interventions for liquid aspiration: short-term and long-term effects. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT00000362 (first posted 23 June 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Gensler G, Hind J, Logemann JA, Lindblad AS, Brandt D, et al. Comparison of 2 interventions for liquid aspiration on pneumonia incidence: a randomized trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2008;148(7):509-18. [DOI: 10.7326/0003-4819-148-7-200804010-00007]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-148-7-200804010-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor Y, Mootanah R, Freud D, Giladi N, Cohen JT. Video-assisted swallowing therapy for patients with Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders 2013;19(2):207-11. [DOI: 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2012.10.004]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2012.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor Y, Freud D, Mootanah R, Gurevich T, Giladi N, Jacob CT. Video-assisted swallowing therapy improved quality of life measures more than traditional swallowing therapy in patients with Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders 2010;25:S427. [DOI: 10.1002/mds.23162]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohseni Z, Saffarian A, Mohamadi R, Abolghasemi J, Habibi SA. Effect of conventional speech therapy combined with music therapy on swallowing in patients with Parkinson's disease (telerehabilitation): a randomized-controlled trial. Middle East Journal of Rehabilitation &amp; Health Studies 2023;10(1):1-10. [DOI: 10.5812/mejrh-131572]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/mejrh-131572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Oh DH, Hwang NK, Lee JH. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in patients with Parkinson's disease and dysphagia: a randomized, single-blind, placebo-controlled trial. NeuroRehabilitation 2018;42(4):457-63. [DOI: 10.3233/nre-172306]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/nre-172306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KCT0002511. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation in patients with parkinson&#x2019;s disease and dysphagia. cris.nih.go.kr/cris/en/search/search_result_st01.jsp?seq=9144 (first posted 27 October 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaza E, Ruviaro Busanello-Stella A. Effects of a tongue training program in Parkinson's disease: analysis of electrical activity and strength of suprahyoid muscles. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 2022;63:102642. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2022.102642]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2022.102642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riboldazzi G, Spinazza G, Beccarelli L, Prato P, Grecchi B, D'Abrosca F, et al. Effectiveness of expiratory flow acceleration in patients with Parkinson's disease and swallowing deficiency: a preliminary study. Clinical Neurology and Neurosurgery 2020;199:106249. [DOI: 10.1016/j.clineuro.2020.106249]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clineuro.2020.106249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChiCTR2000029371. Effectiveness of the expiratory flow acceleration technique in the reduction of bronchial exacerbations in patients with Parkinson's disease and swallowing deficiency: a preliminary study. chictr.org.cn/showproj.html?proj=47874 (first posted 25 January 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Okun MS, Rosenbek JC, Musson N, Fernandez HH, Rodriguez R, et al. Aspiration and swallowing in Parkinson disease and rehabilitation with EMST: a randomized trial. Neurology 2010;75(21):1912-9. [DOI: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181fef115]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181fef115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche M, Rosenbek J, Okun M, Sapienza C. Swallowing and breathing related outcomes following detraining in EMST. In: Dysphagia. Vol. 26. 2011:443-4. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-011-9345-1]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-011-9345-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche M, Rosenbek JC, Okun MS, Sapienza CM. Detraining effects and EMST in Parkinson's disease. In: Neurodegenerative Diseases. Vol. 8. 2011:305-10. [DOI: 10.1159/000327701]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000327701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Rosenbek JC, Okun MS, Sapienza CM. Swallowing related quality of life and EMST in Parkinson's disease. In: Neurodegenerative Diseases. Vol. 8. 2011. [DOI: 10.1159/000327701]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000327701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche M, Okun M, Rosenbek J, Musson N, Sapienza C. Swallow outcomes following intervention with expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) in Parkinson's disease: results of a randomized clinical trial. In: Dysphagia. Vol. 24. 2009:455-6. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-009-9233-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-009-9233-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapienza C, Troche M, Silverman E, Rosenbek J, Musson N, Okun M. Strength training outcomes for airway protection in PD. In: Neurodegenerative Diseases. Vol. 8. 2011. [DOI: 10.1159/000327701]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000327701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT00843739. Expiratory muscle training in patients with Parkinson's Disease (EMST). clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT00843739 (first posted 12 February 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapienza CM, Troche M, Silverman EP, Rosenbek J, Musson N. Strength training outcomes for airway protection in PD. In: Movement Disorders. Vol. 27. 2012:S139. [DOI: 10.1002/mds.25051]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche MS, Curtis JA, Sevitz JS, Dakin AE, Perry SE, Borders JC, et al. Rehabilitating cough dysfunction in Parkinson's Disease: a randomized controlled trial. Movement Disorders 2023;38(2):201-11. [DOI: 10.1002/mds.29268]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.29268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doruk C, Curtis JA, Dakin AE, Troche MS. Cough and swallowing therapy and their effects on vocal fold bowing and laryngeal lesions. Laryngoscope 2023;134:1127-32. [DOI: 10.1002/lary.30922]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lary.30922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02927691. Novel management of airway protection in Parkinson's disease: a clinical trial. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT02927691 (first posted 13 September 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troche M, Curtis J, Dakin A, Sevitz J, Borders J, Perry S, et al. Sensorimotor training for airway protection (SMTAP) versus expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) to rehabilitate cough and swallowing in Parkinson's Disease: a clinical trial. In: Dysphagia. Vol. 38. 2023:S90. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-022-10456-y]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-022-10456-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie T, Bloom L, Padmanaban M, Bertacchi B, Kang W, MacCracken E, et al. Long-term effect of low frequency stimulation of STN on dysphagia, freezing of gait and other motor symptoms in PD. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 2018;89(9):989-94. [DOI: 10.1136/jnnp-2018-318060]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie T, Bloom L, Padmanaban M, Bertacchi B, Kang W, Dachman A, et al. Long-term effect of low frequency stimulation of STN on dysphagia, freezing of gait and other motor symptoms in PD. In: Movement Disorders. Vol. 33. 2018:S263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, He H, Zheng Y, Liu M, Wang L. Clinical study on high-frequency rTMS combined with motor imagery therapy for the treatment of Parkinson's disease with swallowing disorders. Zhongguo Liaoyang Yixue [Chinese Journal of Convalescent Medicine] 2025;34(3):53-6. [DOI: 10.13517/j.cnki.ccm.2025.03.011]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13517/j.cnki.ccm.2025.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor Y, Giladi N, Cohen A, Fliss DM, Cohen JT. Validation of a swallowing disturbance questionnaire for detecting dysphagia in patients with Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorder 2007;22(13):1917-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbergleit AK, Schultz L, Jacobson BH, Beardsley T, Johnson AF. The Dysphagia Handicap Index: development and validation. Dysphagia 2012;27(1):46-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Peto V, Greenhall R, Hyman N. The Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire (PDQ-39): development and validation of a Parkinson's disease summary index score. Age and Ageing 1997;26(5):353-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT05700825. Rehabilitation of airway protection in Parkinson's Disease [Rehabilitation of airway protection in Parkinson's Disease: comparing in-person and telehealth service delivery models]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05700825 (first posted 26 January 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT05837520. i-BiSSkApp for awallowing rehabilitation in Parkinson's Disease [At-home skill training using biofeedback for swallowing rehabilitation in Parkinson's disease]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05837520 (first posted 01 May 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT06328296. Impact of Myofascial Release on Dysphagia in Parkinson's Disease Patients [A Randomized Controlled Study to Explore Effect of Myofascial Release on Dysphagia in Parkinson's Patients]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06328296 (first posted 25 March 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT06370195. Effect of Stellate Ganglion Block on Drooling in Parkinson's Syndrome [Effect of Stellate Ganglion Block on Drooling in Parkinson's Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Study]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06370195 (first posted 17 April 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT06791590. Evaluating the Effects of Intermittent Oro-esophageal in Tracheotomy Patients With Neurogenic Dysphagia [Evaluating the Effects of Intermittent Oro-esophageal in Tracheotomy Patients With Neurogenic Dysphagia: a Randomized Study]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06791590 (first posted 24 January 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT07153692. Clinical Efficacy and Mechanism of tDCS for Dysphagia in PD [Clinical Efficacy and Mechanism of tDCS for Dysphagia in Patients With Parkinson's Disease]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT07153692 (first posted 04 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChiCTR2200060790. Clinical study on the effect of progressive inspiratory resistance training combined with swallowing exercise on swallowing function patients Parkinson's disease. chictr.org.cn/showproj.html?proj=159857 (first posted 11 June 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChiCTR2300076032. Application of percutaneous vagus nerve stimulation in dysphagia and rehabilitation of patients with Parkinson's disease. chictr.org.cn/showproj.html?proj=205707 (first posted 22 September 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RBR-3pmvvnx. Application of an application connected to a game with stimulation of mastication and swallowing muscle activity in elderly people with Parkinson's disease. ensaiosclinicos.gov.br/rg/RBR-3pmvvnx (first posted 04 April 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RBR-5ddt474. Effects of an intervention program in patients with swallowing difficulties and Parkinson's [Effects of an intervention program in dysphagic patients with dysphagia Parkinson's]. ensaiosclinicos.gov.br/rg/RBR-5ddt474 (first posted 17 November 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dismore L, Montague K, Carvalho L, Guerreiro T, Jackson D, Guan Y, Walker R. A protocol for the evaluation of a wearable device for monitoring of symptoms, and cueing for the management of drooling, in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. PLOS One 2023;18(2):e0280727. [DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0280727]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0280727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISRCTN59284050. A wearable device for people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease to help with drooling and other symptoms of Parkinson&#x2019;s [A wearable device for cueing for the management of drooling, and monitoring of symptoms, in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease]. isrctn.com/ISRCTN59284050 (first posted 04 May 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>JPRN-UMIN000056111. Randomized Controlled Trial on the Clinical Effectiveness of Somato-Cognitive Coordination Therapy using mediVR KAGURA in Parkinson's Disease at Hoehn &amp; Yahr Classification Stage III [Randomized Controlled Trial on the Clinical Effectiveness of Somato-Cognitive Coordination Therapy using mediVR KAGURA in Parkinson's Disease at Hoehn &amp; Yahr Classification Stage III - RCT of Somato-Cognitive Coordination Therapy using mediVR KAGURA in Parkinson's Disease at Hoehn &amp; Yahr Classification Stage III]. center6.umin.ac.jp/cgi-open-bin/ctr_e/ctr_view.cgi?recptno=R000064115 (first posted 09 November 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamori M, Matsuyama R, Toko M, Yamada H, Hayashi Y, Yoshikawa K, et al. Investigation of the improvement of swallowing function with low-frequency pulse waves or interference waves delivered via cervical electrical stimulation in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled study protocol. Contemporary Clinical Trials Communications 2025;44:101463. [DOI: 10.1016/j.conctc.2025.101463]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2025.101463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JPRN-jRCTs062240041. A Randomized Controlled Trial of Cervical Electrical Stimulation for Parkinson's Disease [A Randomized Study Investigating the Improvement of Swallowing Function with Low-Frequency Pulse Waves and Interference Waves in Cervical Electrical Stimulation Rehabilitation for Parkinson's Disease]. jrct.mhlw.go.jp/latest-detail/jRCTs062240041 (first posted 29 July 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarkhodjaeva ZA, Mirzaeva KS. Effectiveness of a Multidisciplinary Rehabilitation Program in Improving Motor Function and Quality of Life in Parkinson's Disease Patients. In: Parkinsonism Relatated Disorders. Vol. 134. 2025:99. [DOI: 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2025.107571 ]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nozaki S, Sugishita S, Imai T, Oguro D, Inokawa M, Matsui T, et al. Training for dysphagia with metronome improves swallowing function in parkinson disease. In: Dysphagia. Vol. 26. 2011:443. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-011-9345-1]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-011-9345-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nozaki S, Matsui T, Yoshikawa H, Kaneto T, Domen K, Daimon T. Metronome therapy to treat dysphagia in patients with parkinson's disease. In: Dysphagia. Vol. 28. 2013:298. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-013-9455-z]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-013-9455-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACTRN12618000090213. Expiratory Muscle Strength training (EMST) versus traditional dysphagia rehabilitation for intervention of dysphagia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in the community setting. anzctr.org.au/ACTRN12618000090213.aspx (first posted 19 January 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT01420796. Swallowing and breathing exercises for dysphagia in Parkinson Disease [Effect of oral motor exercises and breathing exercises for dysphagia in Parkinson disease: randomized clinical trial]. clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT01420796 (first posted 22 August 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Negrini S, Donzelli S, Kiekens C, Arienti C, Ceravolo MG, et al. Introduction to target trial emulation in rehabilitation: a systematic approach to emulate a randomized controlled trial using observational data. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine 2024;60(1):145-53. [DOI: 10.23736/S1973-9087.24.08435-1]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.24.08435-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levack WM, Gross DP, Martin RA, Every-Palmer S, Kiekens C, Cordani C, et al. Designing studies and reviews to produce informative, trustworthy evidence about complex interventions in rehabilitation: a narrative review and commentary. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine 2024;60(6):1088-99. [DOI: 10.23736/S1973-9087.24.08459-4]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.24.08459-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti C, Armijo-Olivo S, Ferriero G, Feys P, Hoogeboom T, Kiekens C, et al. The influence of bias in randomized controlled trials on rehabilitation intervention effect estimates: what we have learned from meta-epidemiological studies. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine 2024;60(1):135-44. [DOI: 10.23736/S1973-9087.23.08310-7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.23.08310-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evers LJ, Krijthe JH, Meinders MJ, Bloem BR, Heskes TM. Measuring Parkinson's disease over time: the real-world within-subject reliability of the MDS-UPDRS. Movement Disorders 2019;34(10):1480-7. [DOI: 10.1002/mds.27790]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.27790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skorvanek M, Martinez-Martin P, Kovacs N, Rodriguez-Violante M, Corvol JC, et al. Differences in MDS-UPDRS scores based on Hoehn and Yahr stage and disease duration. Movement Disorders Clinical Practice 2017;4(4):536-44. [DOI: 10.1002/mdc3.12476]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mdc3.12476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labeit B, Claus I, Muhle P, Regner L, Suntrup&#x2010;Krueger S, Dziewas R, Warnecke T. Effect of cognitive and motor dual&#x2010;task on oropharyngeal swallowing in Parkinson's disease. European Journal of Neurology 2021;28(3):754-762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista P, Aresta S, Tagliente S, Merlo F, Mongelli D. Exploring the neuropsychological correlates of swallowing disorders in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a cross-sectional study. Dysphagia 2025;40(1):292-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cichero JA, Lam P, Steele CM, Hanson B, Chen J, Dantas RO, et al. Development of international terminology and definitions for texture-modified foods and thickened fluids used in dysphagia management: the IDDSI framework. Dysphagia 2017;32(2):293-314. [DOI: 10.1007/s00455-016-9758-y.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-016-9758-y.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschwald J, Duncan S, Warnecke T, Boyle G, Regan J, Walshe M. Development of a Core Outcome Set for Dysphagia Interventions in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease (COS-DIP): study protocol. BMJ Open 2024;14(2):e076350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattaneo C, Flynn E, Walshe M. Treatment fidelity in behavioural interventions for oropharyngeal dysphagia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Dysphagia 2020;35(1):1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschwald J, Finnegan L, Hofacker J, Walshe M. Underserved groups in dysphagia intervention trials in Parkinson's disease: a scoping review. Ageing Research Reviews 2024;93:102150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labeit B, Berkovich E, Claus I, Roderigo M, Schwake AL. Dysphagia for medication in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. npj Parkinson's Disease 2022;8(1):156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst M, Folkerts AK, Gollan R, Lieker E, Caro-Valenzuela J, et al. Physical exercise for people with Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2024, Issue 4. Art. No: CD013856. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD013856.pub3]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD013856.pub3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;glinger G, Trenkwalder C; German Parkinson&#x2019;s Guidelines Committee. Diagnosis and treatment of Parkinson's disease (guideline of the German Society for Neurology). Neurological Research and Practice 2024;6(1):30. [DOI: 10.1186/s42466-024-00325-4]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42466-024-00325-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopewell S, Chan A, Collins GS, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Moher D, Schulz KF, et al. CONSORT 2025 explanation and elaboration: updated guideline for reporting randomised trials. BMJ 2025;389:e081124. [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11995452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40228832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann TC, Glasziou PP, Boutron I, Milne R, Perera R, Moher D, et al. Better reporting of interventions: template for intervention description and replication (TIDieR) checklist and guide. BMJ 2014;348:g1687. [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24609605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>