<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41273263</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2152-0895</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of geriatric physical therapy (2001)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Geriatr Phys Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Scoping Review of Principles of Multisensory Exercise Training Interventions in Older Adults Emphasizing Balance and Fall Incidence.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000477</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Multisensory exercises target visual, vestibular, and somatosensory systems to improve balance and mobility, thus reducing fall risk in older adults. Unlike traditional exercise interventions focusing on physical strength or motor skills, multisensory exercises challenge sensory inputs to enhance adaptability and stability. Despite their potential benefits, the role of sensory training in balance improvement and fall prevention has not been extensively explored. This scoping review aimed to examine and summarize multisensory exercise interventions' content, delivery, and outcomes in older adults without specific health diagnoses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A scoping review was conducted following Arksey and O'Malley's framework, encompassing stages such as identifying the research question, identifying relevant studies, study selection, charting the data, and synthesizing, summarizing, and reporting the results. Cochrane Library, Medline, PEDro, EMBASE, ProQuest, and Google Scholar were systematically searched using key terms such as "older adults," "multisensory," "balance," "exercise," and "fall." Studies were included if they evaluated the impact of multisensory exercises on balance and fall incidence in older adults without specific health diagnoses. The TIDieR checklist guided data extraction to ensure comprehensive reporting and analysis of intervention protocols.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS AND DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A total of 21 articles met the inclusion criteria, including 15 randomized controlled trials and 6 pre-post design studies without control groups. The total number of enrolled older adults was 1,018, 65% of whom were women. The review identified 4 principal categories of sensory interventions targeting visual, vestibular, proprioceptive modalities, and their combinations. Walking with sensory stimulation was the most common exercise intervention, featured in almost 60% of the studies. The Berg Balance Scale was the most frequently employed outcome measure, used in 42% of studies. However, the studies demonstrated considerable diversity in objectives, reporting, and intervention designs, including variations in exercise duration, frequency, intensity, and the specific sensory challenges applied. Additionally, inconsistencies were observed in the selection of outcome measures, with limited standardization across studies, making comparisons challenging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although multisensory interventions are widely used to improve balance, empirical evidence is limited by inconsistencies in study design, intervention delivery, and reporting. Greater theoretical clarity, operational definitions, intervention mapping, and codesign techniques are necessary to enhance the quality and impact of future research in clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 APTA Geriatrics, An Academy of the American Physical Therapy Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johari</LastName><ForeName>Sahar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9542-2182</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Western Ontario, Ontario, ON.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacDermid</LastName><ForeName>Joy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Western Ontario, London, ON.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Roth McFarlane Hand and Upper Limb Centre, St. Joseph's Health Centre, London, Ontario.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graham</LastName><ForeName>Laura J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Western Ontario, London, ON.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parkwood Institute Research, Lawson Health Sciences Research Institute, London, Ontario.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziebart</LastName><ForeName>Christina Tina</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Western Ontario, London, ON.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shafiee</LastName><ForeName>Erfan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Therapy, Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Geriatr Phys Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101142169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1539-8412</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fall incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-sensory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">older adults</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No conflicts of interest were declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41273263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00139143-990000000-00090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, Yang Y, Schwebele DC, et al. Population ageing and mortality during 1990&#x2013;2017: a global decomposition analysis. PLoS Med. 2020;17(6):1003138-1003141. doi:10.1371/journal.pmed.1003138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James SL, Lucchesi LR, Krohn KJ, et al. The global burden of falls: global, regional and national estimates of morbidity and mortality from the global burden of disease study 2017. Inj Prev. 2020;26(2):3-11. doi:10.1136/injuryprev-2019-043286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/injuryprev-2019-043286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H, Wang Z. Ageing changes the proprioceptive contribution to balance control under different types of mastoid vibration: a cross-sectional study. Exp Physiol. 2025;24(3):175-181. doi:10.1113/EP092548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP092548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC. Neural mechanisms of age-related loss of muscle performance and physical function. J Gerontol. 2023;78(1):8-13. doi:10.1093/gerona/glad029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glad029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasagawa S, Arakawa A, Furuyama A, Matsumoto Y. Age-related changes in static balance in older women aged in their early sixties to their late eighties: different aging patterns in the anterior&#x2013;posterior and mediolateral directions. Front Aging Neurosci. 2024;16(1):1361244-13612489. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2024.1361244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2024.1361244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunsky A. Effects of balance and coordination exercises on quality of life in older adults: a mini review. Front Aging Neurosci. 2019;11:318-325. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2019.00318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2019.00318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nematollahi A, Kamali F, Ghanbari A, Etminan Z, Sobhani S. Improving balance in older people: a double-blind randomized clinical trial of three modes of balance training. J Aging Phys Act. 2016;24(2):189-195. doi:10.1123/japa.2014-0286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.2014-0286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brach JS, Perera S, Gilmore S. Effectiveness of a timing and coordination group exercise program to improve mobility in community-dwelling older adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2017;77(10):1437-1444. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2017.3609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2017.3609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E, Battaglia G, Patti A, et al. Physical activity programs for balance and fall prevention in elderly: a systematic review. Med. 2019;98(27):16218.&#x2013;16225. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000016218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000016218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khurshid S, Saeed A, Kashif M, Nasreen A, Riaz H. Effects of multisystem exercises on balance, postural stability, mobility, walking speed, and pain in patients with diabetic peripheral neuropathy: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Neurosci. 2025;26(1):16-24. doi:10.1186/s12868-024-00924-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12868-024-00924-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao T, Yang L, Smith L, et al. Correlation between cognition and balance among middle-aged and older adults observed through a tai chi intervention program. Front Psychol. 2020;11(1):668-676. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2020.00668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.00668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Duijnhoven HJ, Heeren A, Peters Marlijn AM, et al. Effects of exercise therapy on balance capacity in chronic stroke: systematic review and meta-analysis. Stroke. 2016;47(10):2603-2610. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.116.013839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.116.013839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K, Zhu S, Tang Y, et al. Advances in balance training to prevent falls in stroke patients: a scoping review. Front Neurol. 2024;15(4):1167954-1167960. doi:10.3389/fneur.2024.1167954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2024.1167954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien J, Mason A, Chan J, Setti A. Can we train multisensory integration in adults? A systematic review. Multisens Res. 2023;36(2):111-180. doi:10.1163/22134808-bja10090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/22134808-bja10090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Liu D, Yu D, et al. Multisensory exercise improves balance in people with balance disorders: a systematic review. Curr Med Sci. 2021;41(4):635-648. doi:10.1007/s11596-021-2417-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-021-2417-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo IG, Do JH. Multisensory balance training for unsteady elderly people: a scoping review. Technol Disabil. 2021;33(1):1-9. doi:10.3233/TAD-200310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/TAD-200310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daudt HM, van Mossel C, Scott SJ. Enhancing the scoping study methodology: a large, inter-professional team&#x2019;s experience with Arksey and O&#x2019;Malley&#x2019;s framework. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013;13(1):11-19. doi:10.1186/1471-2288-13-48</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-13-48</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TT, Cheng LY, Chen CC, et al. Age-related influence on static and dynamic balance abilities: an inertial measurement unit-based evaluation. Sensors. 2024;24(21):7078-7085. doi:10.3390/s24217078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24217078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei A, Bhat SG, Cheng CH, et al. Age-related changes in gait, balance, and strength parameters: a cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2024;19(10):310764-310770. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0310764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0310764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfieri FM, de Jesus Guirro RR, Teodori RM. Postural stability of elderly submitted to multisensorial physical therapy intervention. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;50(2):113-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO global report on falls prevention in older age. 2008. Accessed September 27, 2024. https://www.who.int/ageing/publications/Falls_prevention7March.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lusardi MM, Fritz S, Middleton A, et al. Determining risk of falls in community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis using posttest probability. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2017;40(1):1-36. doi:10.1519/JPT.0000000000000099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger H, Tittle R. Comparison of the validity of the Timed Up and Go Test (TUG) and Activities-specific Balance Confidence questionnaire (ABC) to the &#x2018;Gold Standard&#x2019; Berg Balance Scale (BBS) in assessing fall risk in the elderly population. J Rehab Pract Res. 2022;3(2):133-138. doi:10.33790/jrpr1100133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33790/jrpr1100133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima CA, Ricci NA, Nogueira EC, Perracini MR. The Berg Balance Scale as a clinical screening tool to predict fall risk in older adults: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2018;104(4):383-394. doi:10.1016/j.physio.2018.02.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physio.2018.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson JL, Kuriyama A, Anton A, et al. The accuracy of Google Translate for abstracting data from non&#x2013;English-language trials for systematic reviews. Ann Intern Med. 2019;171(3):677-679. doi:10.7326/M19-0891</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M19-0891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann TC, Glasziou PP, Boutron I, et al. Better reporting of interventions: template for intervention description and replication (TIDieR) checklist and guide. BMJ. 2014;348(73):1687-1687. doi:10.1136/bmj.g1687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g1687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfieri FM, Riberto M, Silveira Gatz L, Paschoal Corsi Ribeiro C, Augusto Fernandes Lopes J, Rizzo Battistella L. Comparison of multisensory and strength training for postural control in the elderly. Clin Interv Aging. 2012;7(1):119-125. doi:10.2147/CIA.S27747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S27747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldursdottir B, Whitney SL, Ramel A. Multi-sensory training and wrist fractures: a randomized, controlled trial. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020;32(1):29-40. doi:10.1007/s40520-019-01143-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-019-01143-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beling J, Roller M. Multifactorial intervention with balance training as a core component among fall-prone older adults. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2009;32(3):125-133. doi:10.1519/00139143-200932030-00008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00139143-200932030-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira MR, da Silva RA, Dascal JB, Teixeira DC. Effect of different types of exercise on postural balance in elderly women: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2014;59(3):506-514. doi:10.1016/j.archger.2014.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2014.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira LGP, Genebra CVDS, Maciel NM, Arca EA, Fiorelli A, Vitta AD. Multisensory and closed kinetic chain exercises on the functional capacity and balance in elderly women: blinded randomized clinical trial. Fisioter Mov. 2017;30(1):259-266. doi:10.1590/1980-5918.030.S01.AO25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1980-5918.030.S01.AO25</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafstr&#xf6;m A, Malmstr&#xf6;m EM. Improved balance confidence and stability for elderly after 6 weeks of a multimodal self-administered balance-enhancing exercise program: a randomized single arm crossover study. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2016;22(2):233-246. doi:10.1177/2333721416644149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333721416644149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MM, Nasu E, Rogers ME, Koizumi D, Rogers NL, Takeshima N. Effects of combined sensory and muscular training on balance in Japanese older adults. J Prev Med. 2004;39(6):1148-1155. doi:10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.04.048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.04.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J, Yu D. Effect of multisensory stimulation training on cognitive function and balance ability of elderly people. Korean J Community Based Occup Ther. 2016;6(2):21-30. doi:10.18598/kcbot.2016.06.02.01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18598/kcbot.2016.06.02.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristinsdottir EK, Baldursdottir B. Effect of multi-sensory balance training for unsteady elderly people: pilot study of the &#x201c;Reykjavik model. Disabil Rehabil. 2014;36(14):1211-1228. doi:10.3109/09638288.2013.835452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638288.2013.835452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahaseth PK, Malani R. Effects of multisensory training on balance and gait among elderly populations for fall prevention: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Rom Soc Cell Biol. 2021;25(4):17269-17280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira NB, Gon&#xe7;alves G, da Silva T, Zanardini, Francisco Ernesto Halila., Bento, Paulo Cesar Barauce. Multisensory exercise programme improves cognition and functionality in institutionalized older adults: a randomized control trial. Physiother Res Int. 2018;23(2):1708-1722. doi:10.1002/pri.1708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.1708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa H, Yousaf A. Vestibular visual cues and proprioception exercises both improve postural control in elderly. J Nat Sci. 2023;19(8):457-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj YN, Vadivelan K. Comparison of multisensory versus strengthening exercises on functional mobility and balance in elders. Int J Phys Ther. 2016;3(5):557-561 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MR, Nascimento NG. Effects of the multi-sensory training on trunk mobility and balance in community-dwelling elderly. Medicina (B Aires). 2019;7(4):470-481. doi:10.18554/refacs.v7i4.3619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18554/refacs.v7i4.3619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza LA, Fernandes AB. Effects of a multisensory supervised training for six weeks in balance and quality of life of the elderly. Medicina (B Aires). 2016;49(3):223-231. doi:10.11606/issn.2176-7262.v49i3p223-231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11606/issn.2176-7262.v49i3p223-231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westlake KP, Culham EG. Sensory-specific balance training in older adults: effect on proprioceptive reintegration and cognitive demands. Phys Ther Rehabil. 2007;87(10):1274-1283. doi:10.2522/ptj.20060263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20060263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesmeier IK, Dalin D, Wehrle A, et al. Balance training enhances vestibular function and reduces overactive proprioceptive feedback in elderly. Front Aging Neurosci. 2017;9(4):273-285. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2017.00273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2017.00273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zak M. Physical rehabilitation regimens designed to assist the frail elderly in executing postural shifts safely and coping effectively after incidental falls. Adv Rehabil. 2006;8(4):31-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zak M, Swine C, Grodzicki T. Combined effects of functionally oriented exercise regimens and nutritional supplementation on both the institutionalized and free-living frail elderly (double-blind, randomized clinical trial). BMC Public Health. 2009;9(1):1-15. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-9-39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-9-39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schooling CM. Could androgens be relevant to partly explain why men have lower life expectancy than women? J Epidemiol Community Health. 2016;70(4):324-328. doi:10.1136/jech-2015-206336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech-2015-206336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass DC, Kelsall HL, Slegers C, et al. A telephone survey of factors affecting willingness to participate in health research surveys. BMC Public Health. 2015;15(1):111-125. doi:10.1186/s12889-015-2350-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-2350-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose DJ, Lucchese N, Wiersma LD. Development of a multidimensional balance scale for use with functionally independent older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87(11):1478-1485. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2006.07.263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2006.07.263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Van Ancum J, Bergquist R, et al. Concurrent validity and reliability of the community balance and mobility scale in young-older adults. BMC Geriatr. 2018;18(3):1-10. doi:10.1186/s12877-018-0845-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-018-0845-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn LB, Rice T, Stoskus JL, Lambert KH, Dannenbaum E, Scherer MR. Measurement characteristics and clinical utility of the clinical test of sensory interaction on balance (CTSIB) and modified CTSIB in individuals with vestibular dysfunction. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;96(9):1747-1748. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2015.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2015.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofheinz M, Mibs M. The prognostic validity of the timed up and go test with a dual task for predicting the risk of falls in the elderly. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2016;2(1):237-245. doi:10.1177/2333721416637798</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333721416637798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan V, Paing SL, Lee H. Characterizing postural balance on 2-dimensional compliant surfaces with directional virtual time-to-contact. Hum Mov Sci. 2023;91(2):10-29. doi:10.1016/j.humov.2023.103134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2023.103134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Cervantes E, Montesinos L, Gonzalez-Nucamendi A, Pecchia L. Recurrence quantification analysis of center of pressure trajectories for balance and fall-risk assessment in young and older adults. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2023;31(2):926-935. doi:10.1109/TNSRE.2023.3236454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2023.3236454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saftari LN, Kwon OS. Ageing vision and falls: a review. J Physiol Anthropol. 2018;37(1):1-4. doi:10.1186/s40101-018-0170-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40101-018-0170-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel GA, Harris LR, Gnanasegaram JJ, et al. Age-related changes to vestibular heave and pitch perception and associations with postural control. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):6426-6433. doi:10.1038/s41598-022-09807-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-09807-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung P, Rowland P. Impact of sensory reweighting strategies on postural control using the sensory organization test in older adults with and without fall risks. Physiother Res In. 2024;29(2):2075-2082. doi:10.1002/pri.2075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.2075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenti G, Bonomi AG, Westerterp KR. Walking as a contributor to physical activity in healthy older adults: 2-week longitudinal study using accelerometry and the doubly labeled water method. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2016;4(2):5445-5459. doi:10.26481/dis.20160610gv</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26481/dis.20160610gv</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherrington C, Tiedemann A, Fairhall N, et al. Exercise for preventing falls in older people living in the community. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;4(11):57-65. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD012424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD012424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toomey E, Hardeman W. Addressing intervention fidelity within physical therapy research and clinical practice. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(12):895-900. doi:10.2519/jospt.2017.0609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.0609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh SM, Riordan F, Curran GM, et al. Conceptual tensions and practical trade-offs in tailoring implementation interventions. Front Health Serv. 2022;17(2):974095-974100. doi:10.3389/frhs.2022.974095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frhs.2022.974095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Jackson C, Shaw S, Janamian T. Achieving research impact through co-creation in community-based health services: literature review and case study. Milbank Q. 2016;94(2):392-429. doi:10.1111/1468-0009.12197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1468-0009.12197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SM, Olson-Kellogg BJ, North SE, Davis JL, Staker JL. Telehealth physical therapy as an innovative clinical education model with positive patient impact: a case report in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic. J Phys Ther Educ. 2020;34(4):275-281. doi:10.1097/JTE.0000000000000163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JTE.0000000000000163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jixian W, Yongfang L, Yang G-Y, Jin K. Age-related dysfunction in balance: a comprehensive review of causes, consequences, and interventions. Aging Dis. 2024;16(2):714-737. doi:10.14336/AD.2024.0124-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14336/AD.2024.0124-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elangovan N, Herrmann A. Assessing proprioceptive function: evaluating joint position matching methods against psychophysical thresholds. Phys Ther Rehabil. 2014;94(4):553-561. doi:10.2522/ptj.20130103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20130103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns P, Quinn J. Clinical diagnosis of benign paroxysmal positional vertigo and vestibular neuritis. CMAJ. 2020;192(8):182-186. doi:10.1503/cmaj.190334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.190334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holladay JT. Visual acuity measurements. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2024;30(2):287-290. doi:10.1016/j.jcrs.2004.01.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrs.2004.01.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poonam K, Pardasaney NK, Latham AM, et al. Sensitivity to change and responsiveness of four balance measures for community-dwelling older adults. Phys Ther Rehabil. 2012;92(3):388-397. doi:10.2522/ptj.20100398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20100398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck JD, Robinson K, Ogliari G, et al. Predicting falls in older adults: an umbrella review of instruments assessing gait, balance, and functional mobility. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):615-622. doi:10.1186/s12877-022-03271-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-022-03271-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>