<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41492581</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of Rate of Force Development in Mediating the Relationship Between Task-Specific Fear and Chronic Low Back Pain Among Japanese Caregivers: A Pilot Cross-Sectional Mediation Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e98512</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e98512</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e98512</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.98512</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Chronic low back pain (CLBP) is prevalent among caregivers; however, the mechanisms linking psychological factors like fear of movement to pain are unclear. This study investigated whether the rate of force development (RFD), a measure of explosive strength, mediates the relationship between task-specific fear and CLBP intensity in this high-risk population. Methods Thirty-two Japanese care workers (13 CLBP, 19 healthy) performed sit-to-stand and stand-to-sit tasks on a force plate after rating their task-specific fear. Vertical ground reaction force was used to calculate early-phase RFD (0-100 ms) during stand-to-sit, the prespecified mediator. CLBP was defined as pain persisting for &gt;3 months. Associations were analyzed using Spearman's correlation and a 1,000-sample bootstrap mediation model. Results Early-phase RFD (0-100 ms) during stand-to-sit correlated negatively with both task-specific fear (&#x3c1; = -0.43) and CLBP intensity (&#x3c1; = -0.51). The mediation analysis confirmed a significant indirect effect of fear on CLBP through RFD (B = 0.39, 95% CI (0.06, 1.30)). The total effect of fear on pain was also significant (B = 5.58, 95% CI (0.39, 18.61)). Conclusion In caregivers, higher task-specific fear is associated with suppressed RFD during the stand-to-sit task, reflecting a force-control deficit linked to CLBP. Early-phase RFD is a promising biomarker for identifying fear-driven motor inhibition. These findings suggest that workplace interventions that combine graded exposure with explosive-strength training may effectively reduce the risk of chronic pain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Abiko et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abiko</LastName><ForeName>Teppei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Kyoto Tachibana University, Kyoto, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, AUS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murata</LastName><ForeName>Shin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Kyoto Tachibana University, Kyoto, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shigetoh</LastName><ForeName>Hayato</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Kyoto Tachibana University, Kyoto, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Norihisa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation, Reiwa Health Sciences University, Fukuoka, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hideaki</LastName><ForeName>Yamaguchi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Consultancy, Kyoto Tachibana University, Nagoya, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohyama</LastName><ForeName>Michie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Welfare Equipment, NPO (Non-Profit Organization) Fukushiyogunet, Fukuoka, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakata</LastName><ForeName>Eiji</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Welfare Equipment, NPO (Non-Profit Organization) Fukushiyogunet, Fukuoka, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hing</LastName><ForeName>Wayne</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, AUS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic low back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinesiophobia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mediation analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of force development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sit-to-stand</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Kyoto Tachibana University Ethics Committee issued approval No. 23-02. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41492581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12765356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.98512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global, regional, and national burden of low back pain, 1990-2020, its attributable risk factors, and projections to 2050: a systematic analysis of the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. GBD 2021 Low Back Pain Collaborators. Lancet Rheumatol. 2023;5:0&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10234592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37273833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational low back pain among Japanese caregivers: a large-scale cross-sectional study. Abiko T, Murata S, Shigetoh H, Ohyama M, Sakata E. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2024;37:1489&#x2013;1498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11612991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38968041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential risk factors for new onset of back pain disability in Japanese workers: findings from the Japan epidemiological research of occupation-related back pain study. Matsudaira K, Konishi H, Miyoshi K, et al. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2012;37:1324&#x2013;1333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22246538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does kinesiophobia mediate the relationship between pain intensity and disability in individuals with chronic low-back pain and obesity? Varallo G, Scarpina F, Giusti EM, Cattivelli R, Guerrini Usubini A, Capodaglio P, Castelnuovo G. Brain Sci. 2021;11:684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8224628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pain catastrophizing, kinesiophobia and fear-avoidance in non-specific work-related low-back pain as predictors of sickness absence. Mac&#xed;as-Toronjo I, Rojas-Oca&#xf1;a MJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Ramos JL, Garc&#xed;a-Navarro EB. PLoS One. 2020;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7728279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is kinesiophobia and pain catastrophising at baseline associated with chronic pain and disability in whiplash-associated disorders? A systematic review. Luque-Suarez A, Falla D, Morales-Asencio JM, Martinez-Calderon J. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:892&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31217158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relationship between pain-related threat and motor behavior in nonspecific low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ippersiel P, Teoli A, Wideman TH, Preuss RA, Robbins SM. Phys Ther. 2022;102:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34939120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motor control changes in low back pain: divergence in presentations and mechanisms. van Die&#xeb;n JH, Reeves NP, Kawchuk G, van Dillen LR, Hodges PW. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49:370&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7393576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fear of movement is related to trunk stiffness in low back pain. Karayannis NV, Smeets RJ, van den Hoorn W, Hodges PW. PLoS One. 2013;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3694850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23826339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association of fear of movement and postural sway in people with low back pain. Meinke A, Maschio C, Meier ML, Karlen W, Swanenburg J. Front Psychol. 2022;13:1006034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36467232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attention demands of postural control in non-specific chronic low back pain subjects with low and high pain-related anxiety. Shanbehzadeh S, Salavati M, Talebian S, Khademi-Kalantari K, Tavahomi M. Exp Brain Res. 2018;236:1927&#x2013;1938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29696316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinesiophobia modulates lumbar movements in people with chronic low back pain: a kinematic analysis of lumbar bending and returning movement. Osumi M, Sumitani M, Otake Y, et al. Eur Spine J. 2019;28:1572&#x2013;1578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31115684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altered trunk muscle coordination during rapid trunk flexion in people in remission of recurrent low back pain. D'hooge R, Hodges P, Tsao H, Hall L, Macdonald D, Danneels L. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2013;23:173&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23079004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modifying patterns of movement in people with low back pain -does it help? A systematic review. Laird RA, Kent P, Keating JL. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2012;13:169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3466154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between acceleration in a sit-to-stand movement and physical function in older adults. Tateoka K, Tsuji T, Shoji T, Tokunaga S, Okura T. Geriatrics (Basel) 2023;8:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10742784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between ground reaction force in sit-to-stand motion and falls in community-dwelling older Japanese individuals. Kera T, Kawai H, Takahashi J, et al. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2020;91:104221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32810735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between psychological factors and spinal motor behaviour in low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Christe G, Crombez G, Edd S, Opsommer E, Jolles BM, Favre J. Pain. 2021;162:672&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33591109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does occupational forward bending of the back increase long-term sickness absence risk? A 4-year prospective register-based study using device-measured compositional data analysis. Gupta N, Bjerregaard SS, Yang L, et al. Scand J Work Environ Health. 2022;48:651&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10546616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sample size of 12 per group rule of thumb for a pilot study. Julious SA. https://doi.org/10.1002/pst.185 Pharm Stat. 2005;4:287&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estimating the sample size for a pilot randomised trial to minimise the overall trial sample size for the external pilot and main trial for a continuous outcome variable. Whitehead AL, Julious SA, Cooper CL, Campbell MJ. Stat Methods Med Res. 2016;25:1057&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anticipatory postural adjustments mediate the changes in fear-related behaviors in individuals with chronic low back pain. Nishi Y, Osumi M, Morioka S. Scand J Pain. 2023;23:580&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36437116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task-specific fear influences abnormal trunk motor coordination in workers with chronic low back pain: a relative phase angle analysis of object-lifting. Fujii R, Imai R, Shigetoh H, Tanaka S, Morioka S. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23:161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8857807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standing up. Gotoh A, Takada T, Suehiro K. J Kansai Phys Ther. 2002;2:25&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The mediating effect of central sensitization on the relation between pain intensity and psychological factors: a cross-sectional study with mediation analysis. Shigetoh H, Tanaka Y, Koga M, Osumi M, Morioka S. Pain Res Manag. 2019;2019:3916135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6476126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31089402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of psychological factors on pain outcomes: lessons learned for the next generation of research. Crombez G, Veirman E, Van Ryckeghem D, Scott W, De Paepe A. Pain Rep. 2023;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10631620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38027466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task-specific fear rather than general kinesiophobia assessment is associated with kinematic differences in chronic low back pain during lumbar flexion: a preliminary investigation. Imai R, Imaoka M, Nakao H, Hida M, Fujii R, Shiba T, Nishigami T. Pain Rep. 2022;7:1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9529037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36203647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinematic analysis of movement impaired by generalization of fear of movement-related pain in workers with low back pain. Fujii R, Imai R, Tanaka S, Morioka S. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34534260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task-specific perceived harmfulness predicts protective movement behaviour in chronic low back pain. Matheve T, Timmermans A, Danneels L, De Baets L. J Clin Med. 2024;13:5025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11396003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The influence of pain-related fear on peak muscle activity and force generation during maximal isometric trunk exertions. Thomas JS, France CR, Sha D, Wiele NV. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2008;33:0&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New in vivo measurements of pressures in the intervertebral disc in daily life. Wilke HJ, Neef P, Caimi M, Hoogland T, Claes LE. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 1999;24:755&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10222525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>