<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41467961</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-6324</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of back and musculoskeletal rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Booster session prescription and outcomes in adults with chronic low back pain: Secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10538127251407665</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10538127251407665</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/10538127251407665</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BackgroundBooster sessions are suggested to maintain self-management behaviors and treatment effects in chronic low back pain (LBP) interventions, but the effects of boosters on outcomes and the best parameters for booster prescription are unclear.Objectives(1) Compare booster prescription for two LBP treatments in an RCT where prescription was based on self-management program independence, (2) Determine if participant-specific variables predict requiring additional boosters, (3) Explore effects of boosters on outcomes in those requiring additional boosters.MethodsSecondary analysis of an RCT where 154 participants with LBP were randomized to motor skill training (MST), MST&#x2009;+&#x2009;Boosters (MST&#x2009;+&#x2009;B), strength/flexibility exercise (SFE), or SFE&#x2009;+&#x2009;B. This analysis focuses only on the&#x2009;+&#x2009;Boosters groups (age: 40.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.2 years, 49 female, LBP duration 9.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.8 years). Participants received MST or SFE and six months later received up to 3 boosters. Self-management program independence was assessed at the first booster, and those who were not independent required additional (&gt;1) boosters. Chi-square tests were used to analyze booster prescription. Logistic regression analyses were used to examine predictors of requiring additional boosters. Descriptive statistics were calculated for outcomes for participants who did and did not require additional boosters.ResultsMST&#x2009;+&#x2009;B and SFE&#x2009;+&#x2009;B did not significantly differ in returning for the first booster, &#x3c7;<sup>2</sup>(1)&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.76, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.185. SFE&#x2009;+&#x2009;B were over 10 times more likely to require additional boosters than MST&#x2009;+&#x2009;B; OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;10.9, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[3.1, 38.1]. No participant-specific factors were statistically related to needing additional boosters. Attending additional boosters did not appear to change pain or function.ConclusionsIntervention type, not participant-specific factors, predicted the need for additional boosters. Attending additional boosters did not appear to change pain or function in the current sample.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanier</LastName><ForeName>Vanessa M</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3323-1302</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Physical Therapy, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lohse</LastName><ForeName>Keith R</ForeName><Initials>KR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7643-3887</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Physical Therapy, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hooker</LastName><ForeName>Quenten L</ForeName><Initials>QL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6336-3309</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Physical Therapy, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Civello</LastName><ForeName>Jesse M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Physical Therapy, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Dillen</LastName><ForeName>Linda R</ForeName><Initials>LR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3845-4783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Physical Therapy, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD047709</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TL1 TR002344</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 CA091842</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002345</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD108240</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9201340</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-8127</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>medRxiv. 2025 Jan 28:2025.01.27.25321189. doi: 10.1101/2025.01.27.25321189.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39974101</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">booster session</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor skills</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. van Dillen reports grant funding from the NIH, Academy of Orthopaedic Physical Therapy, and Advance Healthcare (Australia) during the conduct of the study. Drs. Hooker and Lohse report grant funding from the NIH during the conduct of the study. Dr. Lanier reports honoraria for teaching continuing education courses at University of Southern California and the California Physical Therapy Association during the conduct of the study. Dr. Civello reports no conflicts of interest. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41467961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2134548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12829321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10538127251407665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Disease GBD, Injury I, Prevalence C. Global, regional, and national incidence, prevalence, and years lived with disability for 310 diseases and injuries, 1990&#x2013;2015: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2015. Lancet. 2016;388(10053):1545&#x2013;1602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5055577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo LG, Saragiotto BT, Yamato TP, et al. Motor control exercise for acute non-specific low back pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;2:CD012085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8734597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26863390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo LG, Smeets RJ, Maher CG, Latimer J, McAuley JH. Graded activity and graded exposure for persistent nonspecific low back pain: a systematic review. Phys Ther. 2010;90(6):860&#x2013;879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20395306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke N, Ostelo RW, van Tulder MW, et al. Behavioural treatment for chronic low-back pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010(7):CD002014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7065591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20614428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assendelft WJ, Morton SC, Yu EI, Suttorp MJ, Shekelle PG. Spinal manipulative therapy for low back pain. A meta-analysis of effectiveness relative to other therapies. Ann Intern Med. 2003;138(11):871&#x2013;881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12779297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Middelkoop M, Rubinstein SM, Verhagen AP, Ostelo RW, Koes BW, van Tulder MW. Exercise therapy for chronic nonspecific low-back pain. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2010;24(2):193&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20227641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Middelkoop M, Rubinstein SM, Kuijpers T, et al. A systematic review on the effectiveness of physical and rehabilitation interventions for chronic non-specific low back pain. Eur Spine J. 2011;20(1):19&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3036018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20640863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peek K, Sanson-Fisher R, Mackenzie L, Carey M. Interventions to aid patient adherence to physiotherapist prescribed self-management strategies: a systematic review. Physiotherapy. 2016;102(2):127&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26821954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan T, Coburn P, Harcourt P, Zylinski M, Jull G. Justifying the on-going physiotherapy management of long-term patients. Man Ther. 2003;8(4):254&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14559049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan T, Green S. The concept of maintenance physiotherapy. Aust J Physiother. 2000;46(4):271&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangels M, Schwarz S, Worringen U, Holme M, Rief W. Evaluation of a behavioral-medical inpatient rehabilitation treatment including booster sessions: a randomized controlled study. Clin J Pain. 2009;25(5):356&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19454868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saper RB, Lemaster C, Delitto A, et al. Yoga, Physical Therapy, or Education for Chronic Low Back Pain: A Randomized Noninferiority Trial. Ann Intern Med. 2017;167(2):85&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6392183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28631003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hagan ET, Cashin AG, Rizzo RRN, et al. Development of a booster intervention for graded sensorimotor retraining (RESOLVE) in people with persistent low back pain: A nested, randomised, feasibility trial. Musculoskeletal Care. 2023;21(2):444&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36433897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen VM, Vasseljen O, Mork PJ, et al. Resistance band training or general exercise in multidisciplinary rehabilitation of low back pain? A randomized trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(9):2074&#x2013;2083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29603805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen IB, Bergstrom G, Ljungquist T, Bodin L. A 3-year follow-up of a multidisciplinary rehabilitation programme for back and neck pain. Pain. 2005;115(3):273&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15911154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo LG, Latimer J, Maher CG, et al. Effect of motor control exercises versus graded activity in patients with chronic nonspecific low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2012;92(3):363&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22135712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morone NE, Greco CM, Moore CG, et al. A Mind-Body Program for Older Adults With Chronic Low Back Pain: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2016;176(3):329&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent P, Haines T, O&#x2019;Sullivan P, et al. Cognitive functional therapy with or without movement sensor biofeedback versus usual care for chronic, disabling low back pain (RESTORE): a randomised, controlled, three-arm, parallel group, phase 3, clinical trial. Lancet. 2023;401(10391):1866&#x2013;1877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37146623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavafian SS, Jamshidi AR, Mohammad K. Treatment of Chronic Low Back Pain: A Randomized Clinical Trial Comparing Multidisciplinary Group-based Rehabilitation Program and Oral Drug Treatment With Oral Drug Treatment Alone. The Clinical Journal of Pain. 2011;27(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21642845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dillen LR, Lanier VM, Steger-May K, et al. Effect of Motor Skill Training in Functional Activities vs Strength and Flexibility Exercise on Function in People With Chronic Low Back Pain: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(4):385&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33369625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz JM, Irrgang JJ. A comparison of a modified Oswestry Low Back Pain Disability Questionnaire and the Quebec Back Pain Disability Scale. Phys Ther. 2001;81(2):776&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11175676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanier VM, Lang CE, Van Dillen LR. Motor skill training in musculoskeletal pain: a case report in chronic low back pain. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41(17):2071&#x2013;2079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29644888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marich AV, Lanier VM, Salsich GB, Lang CE, Van Dillen LR. Immediate effects of a single session of motor skill training on the lumbar movement pattern during a functional activity in people with low back pain: a repeated-measures study. Phys Ther. 2018;98(7):605&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Hayes M, Holtzman GW, Earley JA, Van Dillen LR. Development and preliminary reliability testing of an assessment of patient independence in performing a treatment program: standardized scenarios. J Rehabil Med. 2010;42(3):221&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3574865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20411216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dillen LR, Norton BJ, Sahrmann SA, et al. Efficacy of classification-specific treatment and adherence on outcomes in people with chronic low back pain. A one-year follow-up, prospective, randomized, controlled clinical trial. Man Ther. 2016;24:52&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4921225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27317505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzasi E, Kurakata H, Gandhi A, Birch HL, Zarnegar R, Best L. Effects of booster sessions on self-management interventions for chronic musculoskeletal pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Pain. 2022;163(2):214&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33863859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Sidani S. Effectiveness of Diabetes Self-management Education Intervention Elements: A Meta-analysis. Canadian Journal of Diabetes. 2009;33(1):18&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleig L, Pomp S, Schwarzer R, Lippke S. Promoting exercise maintenance: how interventions with booster sessions improve long-term rehabilitation outcomes. Rehabil Psychol. 2013;58(4):323&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24041250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, Turner JA, Romano JM. What is the maximum number of levels needed in pain intensity measurement? Pain. 1994;58(3):387&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7838588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewers ME, Lowe NK. A critical review of visual analogue scales in the measurement of clinical phenomena. Research in Nursing and Health. 1990;13(4):227&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2197679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Korff M Studying the natural history of back pain. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1994;19(18 Suppl):2041S&#x2013;2046S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7801181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry RW, Webster BS, Snook SH, Hsiang SM. The relation between pain intensity, disability, and the episodic nature of chronic and recurrent low back pain. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2000;25(7):834&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr., Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care. 1992;30(6):473&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHorney CA, Ware JE Jr., Raczek AE. The MOS 36-Item Short-Form Health Survey (SF-36): II. Psychometric and clinical tests of validity in measuring physical and mental health constructs. Med Care. 1993;31(3):247&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8450681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick DL, Deyo RA, Atlas SJ, Singer DE, Chapin A, Keller RB. Assessing health-related quality of life in patients with sciatica. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1995;20(17):1899&#x2013;1908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8560339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman C, Pelletier KR, Murray JF, et al. Stanford Presenteeism Scale: health status and employee productivity. J Occup Environ Med. 2002;44(1):14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11802460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpin RS, Ozminkowski RJ, Sharda CE, et al. Reliability and validity of the Stanford Presenteeism Scale. J Occup Environ Med. 2004;46(11):1123&#x2013;1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15534499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waddell G, Newton M, Henderson I, Somerville D, Main CJ. A Fear-Avoidance Beliefs Questionnaire (FABQ) and the role of fear-avoidance beliefs in chronic low back pain and disability. Pain. 1993;52(2):157&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8455963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeuw M, Goossens ME, Linton SJ, Crombez G, Boersma K, Vlaeyen JW. The fear-avoidance model of musculoskeletal pain: current state of scientific evidence. J Behav Med. 2007;30(1):77&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17180640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherkin D, Deyo RA, Berg AO. Evaluation of a physician education intervention to improve primary care for low-back pain. II. Impact on patients. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1991;16(10):1173&#x2013;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1836677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019;95:103208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team (2021). A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. URL https://www.R-project.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RStudio Team (2020). RStudio: Integrated Development for R RStudio, PBC, Boston, MA:  URL http://www.rstudio.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates F. Contingency Tables Involving Small Numbers and the &#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> Test. Supplement to the Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. 1934;1(2):217&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaina F, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Cancelliere C, et al. A Systematic Review of Clinical Practice Guidelines for Persons With Non-specific Low Back Pain With and Without Radiculopathy: Identification of Best Evidence for Rehabilitation to Develop the WHO&#x2019;s Package of Interventions for Rehabilitation. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;104(11):1913&#x2013;1927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36963709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz JM, Rhon DI, Teyhen DS, et al. A Sequential Multiple-Assignment Randomized Trial (SMART) for Stepped Care Management of Low Back Pain in the Military Health System: A Trial Protocol. Pain Med. 2020;21(Suppl 2):S73&#x2013;S82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skolasky RL, Wegener ST, Aaron RV, et al. The OPTIMIZE study: protocol of a pragmatic sequential multiple assessment randomized trial of nonpharmacologic treatment for chronic, nonspecific low back pain. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21(1):293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7216637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Salman D, McGregor AH. Recent clinical practice guidelines for the management of low back pain: a global comparison. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25(1):344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11061926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38693474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieminen LK, Pyysalo LM, Kankaanp&#xe4;&#xe4; MJ. Prognostic factors for pain chronicity in low back pain: a systematic review. Pain Rep. 2021;6(1):e919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>