<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41593498</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1813-7253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European review of aging and physical activity : official journal of the European Group for Research into Elderly and Physical Activity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimal type and dose of exercise to improve cognitive function in healthy and pre-sarcopenic older adults: a bayesian network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s11556-026-00404-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise is increasingly recognized as a non-pharmacological strategy for cognitive aging; however, comparative evidence across modalities, phenotypes, and doses is limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a Bayesian network meta-analysis of 38 randomized controlled trials (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;4,047; 88 arms). The interventions included aerobic, resistance, multimodal, and other exercise formats compared with non-exercise controls. The primary outcome was global cognition. Analyses were stratified by age (&lt;&#x2009;70 vs. &#x2265;70 years) and phenotype (healthy vs. pre-sarcopenic). Dose-response relationships were modeled using the weekly volume (MET&#xb7;min/week).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Aerobic (standardized mean difference [SMD] 0.58, 95% CI 0.33-0.83), resistance (0.62, 0.35-0.88), and multimodal programs (0.68, 0.40-0.95) significantly improved cognition compared to the control, with smaller effect sizes. Healthy older adults benefited most from aerobic (0.88, 0.55-1.20) and resistance training (0.80, 0.42-1.19), whereas multimodal programs were most effective for pre-sarcopenia (0.60, 0.29-0.90). Dose-response analysis showed clinically meaningful benefits from ~&#x2009;600 MET&#xb7;min/week, with optimal effects between 700 and 1,200 MET&#xb7;min/week. Higher volumes conferred no consistent additional gains in pre-sarcopenia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Exercise is a scalable, safe, and clinically effective approach for preserving late-life cognition. For healthy older adults, aerobic or resistance training at &#x2265;&#x2009;600 MET&#xb7;min/week is recommended; for pre-sarcopenic individuals, multimodal programs at approximately 700-800 MET&#xb7;min/week offer the best balance of efficacy and sustainability. These findings provide actionable targets for clinicians and policymakers, advancing precision exercise prescriptions for cognitive health in aging populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu Sport University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Neng</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yufei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Weiqiang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ossowski</LastName><ForeName>Zbigniew</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland. zbigniew.ossowski@awf.gda.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101284836</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1813-7253</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dose&#x2013;response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study is a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis of previously published randomized controlled trials. Therefore, ethics approval and informed consent to participate were not required. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41593498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12918418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-026-00404-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s11556-026-00404-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bai W, et al. Worldwide prevalence of mild cognitive impairment among community dwellers aged 50 years and older: a meta-analysis and systematic review of epidemiology studies. Age Ageing. 2022;51(8):afac173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35977150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown C, Losina E. Epidemiology of aging (Socioeconomic Impact). Springer; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou H, et al. The vision of younger-seniors-based elderly care in rural china: based on population aging predictions from 2020 to 2050. Humanit Social Sci Commun. 2025;12(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollset SE, et al. Fertility, mortality, migration, and population scenarios for 195 countries and territories from 2017 to 2100: a forecasting analysis for the global burden of disease study. Lancet. 2020;396(10258):1285&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, et al. Global burden of disease attributable to high systolic blood pressure in older adults, 1990&#x2013;2019: an analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2023;30(10):917&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36416196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan T, Li C, Zhou Y. Life course socioeconomic position and care dependency in later life: a longitudinal multicohort study from 17 countries. EClinical Medicine. 2025;79:102994. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11683273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39737217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudrazija S. Work-related opportunity costs of providing unpaid family care in 2013 and 2050. Health Aff. 2019;38(6):1003&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31158030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CQS, et al. Does a combined intervention of diet and exercise lead to a more positive impact on neurocognitive function? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Nutr. 2025;64(6):260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40828322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardini R, et al. Effects of high-intensity multimodal functional training on motor and cognitive functions in people with multiple sclerosis: A study protocol of a pilot randomized controlled trial. Digit Health. 2025;11:20552076251346694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12332357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40786702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai B, et al. The effect of exercise intervention on cognitive function and quality of life with autism spectrum disorder: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Actas Esp Psiquiatr. 2025;53(4):839&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12353249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40791034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleborn SG, et al. Sex differences in the outcomes of modifiable lifestyle factors for cognitive aging: neuroinflammation and microglia as key underlying mechanisms. Front Aging Neurosci. 2025;17:1642043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12321788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40766178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javelle F, et al. The role of physical exercise on hippocampal volume in depressive symptoms: A systematic review and Multi-level Meta-Analysis. NeuroImage. 2025;121386:p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40706727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, et al. Enhancing neuroprotection through exercise: the synergistic effects of bioactive plant compounds via the CREB-BDNF signaling pathway. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2025;20(1):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40587022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B, et al. The interplay between physical exercise and autophagy signaling in brain health, neurodegenerative diseases and aging. Front Aging Neurosci. 2025;17:1579208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12339460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40799366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias P. Muscle in endocrinology: from skeletal muscle hormone regulation to myokine secretion and its implications in endocrine&#x2013;metabolic diseases. J Clin Med. 2025;14(13):4490. 10.3390/jcm14134490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12249830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40648864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante BR, et al. Effects of instability resistance training on physical and cognitive function in adults. Int J Sports Med. 2025.10.1055/a-2674-4030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40744098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinders NP, et al. Exercise intensity improves performance on a Spatial memory task. Exp Brain Res. 2025;243(9):195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40824315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, et al. Effects of Tai Chi Chuan on balance function in adults 60 years or older with type 2 diabetes and mild cognitive impairment in China: a secondary analysis of a multicenter randomized clinical trial. J Diabetes Investig. 2025. 10.1111/jdi.70138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12578669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40820574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo-G&#xf3;mez D, et al. Optimal dose and type of exercise to improve cognitive function in older adults: A systematic review and bayesian model-based network meta-analysis of RCTs. Ageing Res Rev. 2022;76:101591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng N, et al. Effects of physical activity on motor skills and cognitive development in early childhood: A systematic review. Biomed Res Int. 2017;2017:2760716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29387718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(1):16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, et al. Asian working group for sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21(3):300&#x2013;e3072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gschwind YJ, et al. A best practice fall prevention exercise program to improve balance, strength / power, and psychosocial health in older adults: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. BMC Geriatr. 2013;13:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3852637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24106864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ner Oytun M, et al. Relationships of fall risk with Frailty, Sarcopenia, and balance disturbances in Mild-to-Moderate alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Clin Neurol. 2023;19(3):251&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merchant RA, et al. Association of intrinsic capacity with functional ability, sarcopenia and systemic inflammation in pre-frail older adults. Front Med (Lausanne). 2024;11:1374197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10953915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38510450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders LMJ, et al. Dose-response relationship between exercise and cognitive function in older adults with and without cognitive impairment: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(1):e0210036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6328108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagni V, et al. Aerobic exercise improves cognition and cerebrovascular regulation in older adults. Neurology. 2020;94(21):e2245&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7357295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suo C, et al. Therapeutically relevant structural and functional mechanisms triggered by physical and cognitive exercise. Mol Psychiatry. 2016;21(11):1633&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5078857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27001615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffei L, et al. Randomized trial on the effects of a combined physical/cognitive training in aged MCI subjects: the train the brain study. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):39471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28045051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne PM, et al. Effect of Tai Chi on cognitive performance in older adults: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62(1):25&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4055508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24383523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, et al. Comparative efficacy of various exercise interventions on cognitive function in patients with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11(2):212&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34004389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson J. The Montreal cognitive assessment (MoCA). Occup Med. 2015;65(9):764&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockrell JR, Folstein MF. Mini-Mental state examination (MMSE). Psychopharmacol Bull. 1988;24(4):689&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3249771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, et al. The Montreal cognitive Assessment, moca: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, et al. The Cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis JR, Koch GG. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. Biometrics. 1977;33(1):159&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">843571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y, et al. Effects of resistance training using elastic bands on muscle strength with or without a leucine supplement for 48 weeks in elderly patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocr J. 2021;68(3):291&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rondanelli M, et al. Improving rehabilitation in sarcopenia: a randomized-controlled trial utilizing a muscle-targeted food for special medical purposes. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2020;11(6):1535&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7749532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda H, et al. Effects of combining exercise with long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation on cognitive function in the elderly: a randomised controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):12906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki A, et al. Effects of two short-term aerobic exercises on cognitive function in healthy older adults during COVID-19 confinement in Japan: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(10):6202. 10.3390/ijerph19106202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9140575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35627740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang CK, et al. Efficacy of multidomain intervention against Physio-cognitive decline syndrome: A Cluster-randomized trial. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2021;95:104392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33765656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-J&#xfa;nior HJ, et al. Effects of combined resistance and power training on cognitive function in older women: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(10):3435. 10.3390/ijerph17103435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7277751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezola-Pardo C, et al. Comparison between multicomponent and simultaneous dual-task exercise interventions in long-term nursing home residents: the Ageing-ONDUAL-TASK randomized controlled study. Age Ageing. 2019;48(6):817&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarazona-Santabalbina FJ, et al. A multicomponent exercise intervention that reverses frailty and improves Cognition, Emotion, and social networking in the Community-Dwelling frail elderly: A randomized clinical trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2016;17(5):426&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26947059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansai JH, Rebelatto JR. Effect of two physical exercise protocols on cognition and depressive symptoms in oldest-old people: A randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2015;15(9):1127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bademli K, et al. Effects of physical activity program on cognitive function and sleep quality in elderly with mild cognitive impairment: A randomized controlled trial. Perspect Psychiatr Care. 2019;55(3):401&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30430592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancela Carral JM, Ay&#xe1;n P&#xe9;rez C. Effects of high-intensity combined training on women over 65. Gerontology. 2007;53(6):340&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17575465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorner T, et al. The effect of structured strength and balance training on cognitive function in frail, cognitive impaired elderly long-term care residents. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2007;19(5):400&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18007119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinha C, et al. Impact of different aquatic exercise programs on body composition, functional fitness and cognitive function of non-institutionalized elderly adults: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(17):8963. 10.3390/ijerph18178963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8430467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira CB, et al. Effects of a 12-Week exercise training program on physical function in institutionalized frail elderly. J Aging Res. 2018;2018:p7218102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5821996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xe4;ndin K, et al. Long-Term effects of individually tailored physical training and activity on physical Function, Well-Being and cognition in Scandinavian nursing home residents: A randomized controlled trial. Gerontology. 2016;62(6):571&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Htut TZC, et al. Effects of physical, virtual reality-based, and brain exercise on physical, cognition, and preference in older persons: a randomized controlled trial. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2018;15:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6169073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30305852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue T, et al. Effect of combined bifidobacteria supplementation and resistance training on cognitive function, body composition and bowel habits of healthy elderly subjects. Benef Microbes. 2018;9(6):843&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30198326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanthong P, et al. Traditional Thai exercise (Ruesi Dadton) for improving motor and cognitive functions in mild cognitive impairment: a randomized controlled trial. J Exerc Rehabil. 2021;17(5):331&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8566108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34805022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi M, et al. The effect of aerobic dance intervention on brain spontaneous activity in older adults with mild cognitive impairment: A resting-state functional MRI study. Exp Ther Med. 2019;17(1):715&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6307442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J, et al. Mind-body exercise improves cognitive function and modulates the function and structure of the hippocampus and anterior cingulate cortex in patients with mild cognitive impairment. Neuroimage Clin. 2019;23:101834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31128522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei XH, Ji LL. Effect of handball training on cognitive ability in elderly with mild cognitive impairment. Neurosci Lett. 2014;566:98&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amjad I, et al. Therapeutic effects of aerobic exercise on EEG parameters and higher cognitive functions in mild cognitive impairment patients. Int J Neurosci. 2019;129(6):551&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30929591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J, et al. Effect of square dance exercise on older women with mild mental disorders. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:699778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8357995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann K, et al. Moderate-to-High intensity physical exercise in patients with alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled trial. J Alzheimers Dis. 2016;50(2):443&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26682695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam LC, et al. A 1-year randomized controlled trial comparing Mind body exercise (Tai Chi) with stretching and toning exercise on cognitive function in older Chinese adults at risk of cognitive decline. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2012;13(6):e56815&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22579072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam LC, et al. Would older adults with mild cognitive impairment adhere to and benefit from A structured lifestyle activity intervention to enhance cognition? A cluster randomized controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(3):e0118173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4380493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25826620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarou I, et al. International ballroom dancing against neurodegeneration: A randomized controlled trial in Greek Community-Dwelling elders with mild cognitive impairment. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2017;32(8):489&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10852896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28840742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song D, Yu DSF. Effects of a moderate-intensity aerobic exercise programme on the cognitive function and quality of life of community-dwelling elderly people with mild cognitive impairment: A randomised controlled trial. Int J Nurs Stud. 2019;93:97&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi T, et al. Effects of cognitive leisure activity on cognition in mild cognitive impairment: results of a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2017;18(8):686&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varela S, et al. Effects of two different intensities of aerobic exercise on elderly people with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized pilot study. Clin Rehabil. 2012;26(5):442&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adcock M, et al. Effects of an In-home multicomponent exergame training on physical Functions, Cognition, and brain volume of older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Front Med (Lausanne). 2019;6:321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32047751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callisaya ML, et al. A novel cognitive-motor exercise program delivered via a tablet to improve mobility in older people with cognitive impairment - StandingTall cognition and mobility. Exp Gerontol. 2021;152:111434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34098009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-J&#xfa;nior HJ, Uchida MC. Effects of Low-Speed and High-Speed resistance training programs on frailty Status, physical Performance, cognitive Function, and blood pressure in prefrail and frail older adults. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:702436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8350041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Silva F, et al. Three months of multimodal training contributes to mobility and executive function in elderly individuals with mild cognitive impairment, but not in those with alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled trial. Maturitas. 2019;126:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SG, Kim JH, Jun TW. Effects of 12-Week resistance exercise on electroencephalogram patterns and cognitive function in the elderly with mild cognitive impairment: A randomized controlled trial. Clin J Sport Med. 2018;28(6):500&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28727639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CH, et al. Effect of various exercises on frailty among older adults with subjective cognitive concerns: a randomised controlled trial. Age Ageing. 2020;49(6):1011&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32520984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iuliano E, et al. Effects of different types of physical activity on the cognitive functions and attention in older people: A randomized controlled study. Exp Gerontol. 2015;70:105&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26183691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, et al. Combined intervention of physical activity, aerobic exercise, and cognitive exercise intervention to prevent cognitive decline for patients with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized controlled clinical study. J Clin Med. 2019;8(7):940. 10.3390/jcm8070940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31261796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual-Valdunciel A, et al. Peripheral electrical stimulation to reduce pathological tremor: a review. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2021;18(1):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz PC, Longo AB. The Fonthill dental surgery complication classification scale. Clin Exp Dent Res. 2019;5(6):725&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowik AJ. Betwixt, Between, besides: reflections on moving beyond the binary in reproductive health care. Creat Nurs. 2020;26(2):105&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, et al. Functional monomer impurity affects adhesive performance. Dent Mater. 2015;31(12):1493&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26518339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK. Physical activity and muscle-brain crosstalk. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2019;15(7):383&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein MF, Folstein SE, McHugh PR. <i>Mini-mental state. A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician.</i> J Psychiatr Res, 1975;12(3):189&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(4):601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6593317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31081853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart C, et al. Health outcomes of sarcopenia: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(1):e0169548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, et al. Effects of multi-domain cognitive-motor training in older adults with amnestic mild cognitive impairment: A randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Nurs. 2025;61:64&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39541634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colcombe S, Kramer AF. Fitness effects on the cognitive function of older adults: a meta-analytic study. Psychol Sci. 2003;14(2):125&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12661673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northey JM, et al. Exercise interventions for cognitive function in adults older than 50: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):154&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Ambrose T, et al. Resistance training and executive functions: a 12-month randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(2):170&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G. Indirect and mixed-treatment comparison, network, or multiple-treatments meta-analysis: many names, many benefits, many concerns for the next generation evidence synthesis tool. Res Synth Methods. 2012;3(2):80&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26062083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimani A, et al. Graphical tools for network meta-analysis in STATA. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(10):e76654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Guidelines Approved by the Guidelines Review Committee, in WHO Guidelines on Physical Activity and Sedentary Behaviour. 2020, World Health Organization &#xa9; World Health Organization 2020. Geneva.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandola A, et al. Physical activity and depression: towards Understanding the antidepressant mechanisms of physical activity. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2019;107:525&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31586447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth FW, Roberts CK, Laye MJ. Lack of exercise is a major cause of chronic diseases. Compr Physiol. 2012;2(2):1143&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngandu T, et al. A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2015;385(9984):2255&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10):pEd000142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>