<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41436976</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mapping the global public health intelligence landscape: a multiregional cross-sectional survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>210</StartPage><MedlinePgn>210</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">210</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-025-25406-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Public health intelligence (PHI) allows for timely detection of public health threats. Exchange and close cooperation between PHI teams are crucial for early threat detection and standards harmonization, yet a comprehensive overview documenting their activities is lacking. We aimed to enhance mutual awareness and collaboration possibilities by mapping and characterizing PHI teams.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We developed and distributed an online survey through network sampling (June-November 2023) via regional Centres for Disease Prevention and Control (Africa CDC, ECDC, US CDC), the International Association of National Public Health Institutes (IANPHI), the Robert Koch-Institute, and the World Health Organization (WHO). We identified and described PHI teams and their activities, including implementation of PHI processes, workforce, capacity building, priorities and perspectives on challenges and opportunities, by WHO regions and type of institution.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 132 PHI teams from 87 countries in all regions, primarily in public health institutions (40%, 53/132) and ministries (27%, 35/132). Potential public health threats are monitored at national (39%, 51/132), international (20%, 26/132), and both levels (42%, 55/132). Most teams (89%, 114/128) integrate indicator-based and event-based surveillance. Teams focus mainly on human communicable diseases (95%, 125/132), healthcare-associated infections/antimicrobial resistance (66%, 87/132) and health in natural disasters (64%, 85/132). Nearly half of the teams (43%, 50/117) are not part of early event detection networks. All teams based in regional public health institutions (7/7) and United Nations (UN) institutions (10/10) are able to scale up their activities if needed. More than half of the teams (59%, 71/120) provide training activities on early detection. There is a strong interest in capacity building and networking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">PHI teams worldwide perform partially overlapping tasks, suggesting benefits from broader exchange. The interest in trainings and networking underscores the need for platforms supporting exchange, peer-to-peer cooperation and capacity building. International partner institutions are key in fostering global development of PHI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12889-025-25406-0.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xe9;ndez-Brito</LastName><ForeName>Alba</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology, Robert Koch Institute, Nordufer 20, Berlin, 13353, Germany. Mendez-BritoA@rki.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training for Applied Epidemiology (PAE), Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology, Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, Germany. Mendez-BritoA@rki.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ECDC Fellowship Programme, Field Epidemiology path (EPIET), European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control (ECDC), Stockholm, Sweden. Mendez-BritoA@rki.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerber</LastName><ForeName>Romy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology, Robert Koch Institute, Nordufer 20, Berlin, 13353, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spiteri</LastName><ForeName>Gianfranco</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Functions Unit, European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tetuh</LastName><ForeName>Kyeng Mercy</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Surveillance and Disease Intelligence, Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fehr</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for International Health Protection, Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manthey</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EpiStack, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alinon</LastName><ForeName>Kokou Nouwame</ForeName><Initials>KN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Surveillance and Disease Intelligence, Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esquevin</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for International Health Protection, Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Squires</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Association of National Public Health Institutes (IANPHI), Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jansen</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for International Health Protection, Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Correa-Mart&#xed;nez</LastName><ForeName>Carlos L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for International Health Protection, Robert Koch Institute, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemic intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Event-based surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indicator-based surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public health intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public health threats</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surveillance systems</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was not required for this study, as it did not involve human participants, patient data, or any identifiable personal information as defined by the Declaration of Helsinki. Approval for data collection was obtained from the data protection officer at the Robert Koch Institute. All participants provided informed consent prior to completing the survey and were informed that they could withdraw at any time. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41436976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12805728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-25406-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-025-25406-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Early detection, assessment and response to acute public health events: implementation of early warning and response with a focus on event-based surveillance: interim version [https://iris.who.int/handle/10665/112667] </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemic intelligence. [https://unterm.un.org/unterm2/en/view/e97b9e62-b1f5-4e63-bb01-0cc8b51a6d64].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public health intelligence. [https://unterm.un.org/unterm2/en/view/2b406931-845d-4e66-a6fe-b464ee3d6573].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan OW, Abdelmalik P, Perez-Gutierrez E, Fall IS, Kato M, Hamblion E, Matsui T, Nabeth P, Pebody R, Pukkila J, et al. How better pandemic and epidemic intelligence will prepare the world for future threats. Nat Med. 2022;28(8):1526&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01900-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9243925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas H, Tahoun MM, Aboushady AT, Khalifa A, Corpuz A, Nabeth P. Usage of social media in epidemic intelligence activities in the WHO, regional office for the Eastern mediterranean. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7(Suppl 4). 10.1136/bmjgh-2022-008759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Togami E, Griffith B, Mahran M, Nezu IH, Mirembe BB, Kaasik-Aaslav K, et al. The world health organization&#x2019;s public health intelligence activities during the COVID-19 pandemic response, December 2019 to December 2021. Euro Surveill. 2022;27(49):2200142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2022.27.49.2200142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9732925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckathorn DD, Cameron CJ. Network sampling: from snowball and multiplicity to respondent-driven sampling. Annu Rev Sociol. 2017;43(1):101&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-soc-060116-053556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatri RB, Endalamaw A, Erku D, Wolka E, Nigatu F, Zewdie A, et al. Preparedness, impacts, and responses of public health emergencies towards health security: qualitative synthesis of evidence. Arch Public Health. 2023;81(1):208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-023-01223-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38037151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Health Regulations. In. Third Edition. Edited by World Health Organization: World Health Organization 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saad Duque NJ, Greene-Cramer B, Awofisayo-Okuyelu A, Minet DS, Almiron M, Swanson K, et al. Embedding public health intelligence into the global public health architecture. BMJ Public Health. 2024;2(2):e001011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2024-001011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12581011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41190234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lata H, Saad Duque NJ, Togami E, Miglietta A, Perkins D, Corpuz A, Kato M, Babu A, Dorji T, Matsui T et al. Disseminating information on acute public health events globally: experiences from the WHO&#x2019;s Disease Outbreak News. BMJ Glob Health. 2024;9(2). 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-012876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10900317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikejezie J, Miglietta A, Hammermeister Nezu I, Adele S, Higdon MM, Feikin D, Lata H, Mesfin S, Idoko F, Shimizu K, et al. Informing the pandemic response: the role of the WHO&#x2019;s COVID-19 Weekly Epidemiological Update. BMJ Glob Health. 2024;9(4). 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-014466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38580376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker M, Garzon Villalba X, Kiguli-Malwadde E. No pain, no shame: turning crisis into opportunity during US funding cuts. Lancet Glob Health. 2025;13(8):e1336-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(25)00197-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40712605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Defining collaborative surveillance: A core concept for strengthening the global architecture for health emergency preparedness, response, and resilience (HEPR). In. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2023.&#xa0;ISBN: 978-92-4-007406-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Africa CDC, Officially Launches Event-based Surveillance Revised Framework., EBS Training Manual and Health Information Exchange Guidelines and Standards [https://africacdc.org/news-item/africa-cdc-officially-launches-event-based-surveillance-revised-framework-ebs-training-manual-and-health-information-exchange-guidelines-and-standards/] </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ECDC hosts inaugural Epidemic Intelligence Network meeting. In Rome, editor [https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/news-events/ecdc-hosts-inaugural-epidemic-intelligence-network-meeting-rome].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EIOS Community of Practice. [https://www.who.int/initiatives/eios/eios-community-of-practice] </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IANPHI 2023 Progress Report. In.: International Association of National Public Health Institutes (IANPHI). 2024: pp. 12&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetuh KM, Salyer SJ, Aliddeki D, Tibebu B, Osman F, Amabo FC, Warren LK, Buba MI, Kebede Y. Evaluating event-based surveillance capacity in africa: use of the Africa CDC scorecard, 2022&#x2013;2023. Prev Med Rep. 2023;36:102398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmedr.2023.102398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10502352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37719793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimi Y, Wabacha J. Strengthening coordination and collaboration of one health approach for zoonotic diseases in Africa. One Health Outlook. 2023;5(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42522-023-00082-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10394936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otu A, Effa E, Meseko C, Cadmus S, Ochu C, Athingo R, et al. Africa needs to prioritize one health approaches that focus on the environment, animal health and human health. Nat Med. 2021;27(6):943&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01375-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34017135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouyer F, Thiongane O, Hobeika A, Arsevska E, Binot A, Correges D, et al. Epidemic intelligence in Europe: a user needs perspective to foster innovation in digital health surveillance. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-18466-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10999084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38582850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical contributors to the Pandemic and Epidemic Intelligence Innovation Forum February meeting and report: innovations in public health surveillance: updates from a forum convened by the WHO hub for pandemic and epidemic Intelligence, 2 and 3 February 2022. Eurosurveillance. 2022;27(15):2200302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9012096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercy K, Balajee A, Numbere TW, Ngere P, Simwaba D, Kebede Y. Africa cdc&#x2019;s blueprint to enhance early warning surveillance: accelerating implementation of event-based surveillance in Africa. J Public Health Afr. 2023;14(8):2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/jphia.2023.2827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10519113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37753431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawley AW, Mercy K, Shivji S, Lofgren H, Trowbridge D, Manthey C, Tebeje YK, Clara AW, Landry K, Salyer SJ. An indicator framework for the monitoring and evaluation of event-based surveillance systems. Lancet Glob Health. 2024;12(4):e707&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(24)00034-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11348395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38364834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-S&#xe1;nchez M, Esquevin S, Jansen A, Raiser SG. Identification and definition of attributes to evaluate international event-based surveillance using Epidemic Intelligence from Open Sources (EIOS) at the Robert Koch Institute, Germany. In: European Scientific Conference on Applied Infectious Disease Epidemiology. Barcelona; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotsche CI, Meierkord A, Baruch J, K&#xf6;rner-Nahodilov&#xe1; L, Weishaar H, Hanefeld J. Approaches, challenges, and opportunities to strengthen the epidemic intelligence workforce: a scoping review. Public Health. 2023;225:353&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2023.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37979312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What&#x2019;s new at the WHO Hub for Pandemic and Epidemic Intelligence? Issue 10. March 2024 [https://pandemicandepidemicintel.substack.com/p/whats-new-at-the-who-hub-for-pandemic] </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global arbovirus initiative. In: Preparing for the next pandemic by tackling mosquito-borne viruses with epidemic and pandemic potential. World Health Organization; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandemic Prevention, preparedness and response accord Q&amp;A. [https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/pandemic-prevention--preparedness-and-response-accord].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza JC, Paz S. Climate change and infectious disease in Europe: impact, projection and adaptation. Lancet Reg Health. 2021;9:100230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8513157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34664039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>