<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41441412</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2075-4663</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Applied Research on the Impact of a Neuromotor Development Program on the Lower Limb Strength of Junior Athletes in Greco-Roman Wrestling.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">428</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/sports13120428</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the effects of a structured motor intervention program on the development of lower limb strength in junior athletes practicing Greco-Roman wrestling. Recognizing the crucial role of explosive strength in performing technical and decisive actions during combat, the research introduces a progressive, applied training protocol tailored to the neuromotor development of children aged 10 to 12 years (control group: M = 11.14, SD = 1.10; experimental group: M = 11.07, SD = 0.83). Conducted over 17 months, the study involved two groups of 14 registered wrestlers each from School Sports Club No. 5 in Bucharest. The experimental group participated in a complementary motor training program emphasizing plyometric drills, bodyweight strength exercises, and wrestling-specific movements, while the control group continued with the standard training routine. The intervention's impact was evaluated using the OptoJump Next system, a biomechanical analysis tool measuring key indicators of explosive strength-jump height, ground contact time, flight time, and reactive strength index (RSI)-through the single-leg counter-movement jump (CMJ) test. Comparative analysis of pre- and post-intervention results showed significant improvements in neuromotor performance among athletes in the experimental group, confirming the effectiveness of the proposed methodology. This research thus provides a reproducible, evidence-based intervention model with direct applicability in optimizing the training of young Greco-Roman wrestlers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasilescu</LastName><ForeName>Florentin</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sportive Club No. 5, 010241 Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leonte</LastName><ForeName>Nicoleta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport-Physical Therapy, National University of Science and Technology Politehnica Bucharest, 060042 Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porfireanu</LastName><ForeName>Cristiana Maria</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Academy of Economic Studies Bucharest, 010374 Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tudor</LastName><ForeName>Virgil</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0893-1024</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, National University of Physical Education and Sport, 060057 Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101722684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2075-4663</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Greco-Roman wrestling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OptoJump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explosive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention program</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">juniors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Florentin Vasilescu collaborated with the Research and Innovation Center in Sport, Politehnica University of Bucharest. He participated in the design and implementation of the study, as well as in data collection and analysis. The role of the Center was to provide research infrastructure and institutional support. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41441412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12736863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports13120428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sports13120428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbes Z., Chamari K., Mujika I., Tabben M. Neuromuscular fitness and performance in young athletes: A scoping review. Biol. Sport. 2021;38:391&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemkov&#xe1; E., Kov&#xe1;&#x10d;ikov&#xe1; Z. Sport-specific training induced adaptations in postural control and their relationship with athletic performance. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2023;16:1007804. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2022.1007804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2022.1007804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36712149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forte R., De Vito G. Comparison of neuromotor and progressive resistance exercise training to improve mobility and fitness in community-dwelling older women. J. Sci. Sport Exerc. 2019;1:124&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1007/s42978-019-0017-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-019-0017-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pojskic H., Pagaduan J., Uzicanin E., Separovic V., Spasic M., Foretic N., Sekulic D. Reliability, Validity and Usefulness of a New Response Time Test for Agility-Based Sports: A Simple vs. Complex Motor Task. J. Sports Sci. Med. 2019;18:623&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6873124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R., Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A., Moran J., Chaabene H., Negra Y., Scanlan A.T. The effects of plyometric jump training on physical fitness attributes in basketball players: A meta-analysis. J. Sport Health Sci. 2022;11:656&#x2013;670. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2020.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2020.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9729929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa&#xf1;udo B., de Hoyo M., Carrasco L. The effectiveness of a neuromuscular training program on physical performance in youth athletes: A systematic review. J. Strength. Cond. Res. 2019;33:1367&#x2013;1373. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pojskic H., Pagaduan J., Babajic F., Asceric M. Effects of training on reaction time and agility in young male athletes. J. Hum. Kinet. 2022;82:179&#x2013;188. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2022-0040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reigal R.E., Barrero S., Mart&#xed;n I., Morales-S&#xe1;nchez V., Ju&#xe1;rez-Ruiz de Mier R., Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mendo A. Relationships between reaction time, selective attention, physical activity, and physical fitness in children. Front. Psychol. 2019;10:2278. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6803537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck D., Hossner E.J., Zahno S. Mechanisms for handling uncertainty in sensorimotor control in sports: A scoping review. Int. Rev. Sport Exerc. Psychol. 2025;18:723&#x2013;757. doi: 10.1080/1750984X.2023.2280899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750984X.2023.2280899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R., Sanchez-Sanchez J., Romero-Moraleda B., Yanci J., Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A., Manuel Clemente F. Effects of plyometric jump training in female soccer players&#x2019; vertical jump height: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J. Sports Sci. 2020;38:1475&#x2013;1487. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1745503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1745503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32255389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapotan A., Mih&#x103;ilescu L., Mihai I. The impact of OptoJump training on the power of lower limbs in female triple jumpers. J. Phys. Educ. Sport. 2023;23:555&#x2013;563. doi: 10.7752/jpes.2023.02069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7752/jpes.2023.02069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoro-Bomb&#xfa; R., de la Paz Arencibia L., Buzzichelli C., Miranda-Oliveira P., Fernandes O., Santos A., Rama L. The validity of the Push Band 2.0 on the Reactive Strength Index assessment in Drop Jump. Sensors. 2022;22:4724. doi: 10.3390/s22134724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22134724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9269219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35808221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravetter F.J., Wallnau L.B. Statistics for the Behavioral Sciences. 10th ed. Cengage Learning; Boston, MA, USA: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#x103;dinaru L., Merghe&#x219; P., Oravi&#x21b;an M. The contribution of plyometric exercises assisted by sensory technology on vertical jump parameters in U15 female volleyball players. Pedagog. Phys. Cult. Sports. 2024;28:156&#x2013;167. doi: 10.15561/26649837.2024.0210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/26649837.2024.0210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kittel A., Lindsay R., Le Noury P., Wilkins L. The use of extended reality technologies in sport perceptual-cognitive skill research: A systematic scoping review. Sports Med.-Open. 2024;10:128. doi: 10.1186/s40798-024-00794-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00794-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11607248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39612099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gierczuk D., Cie&#x15b;li&#x144;ski I., Bujak Z., Sadowski J. Relationship between selected strength and power variables and sports level in Greco-Roman wrestlers aged 14&#x2013;18 years. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2021;18:4813. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18094813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18094813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33946425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zugaj N., Karnincic H., Baic M. Differences in motor, functional, and sport-specific skills in gifted wrestlers with different acceleration of biological development. Sport. Mont. 2023;21:117&#x2013;121. doi: 10.26773/smj.230219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26773/smj.230219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashnazarov R., Karimov M., Nasimov M. The role of neuromuscular preparedness in tactical wrestling performance. World J. Wrestl. Res. 2022;1:33&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhmetov R., Khusainov R., Nurgaliev A. Neuromuscular coordination and reaction speed in young wrestlers. J. Phys. Educ. Sport. 2021;21:1485&#x2013;1491. doi: 10.7752/jpes.2021.03188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7752/jpes.2021.03188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrov M., Dimitrov T. Neuromotor training interventions in youth wrestling: Effects on explosive power. Eur. J. Wrestl. Sci. 2023;5:22&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C., Romero-Franco N., Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P. Performance assessment and monitoring using new technologies: A theoretical framework. Sports. 2021;9:66. doi: 10.3390/sports9050066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9050066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longakit J., Aque F.J., Toring-Aque L., Lobo J., Ayubi N., Mamon R., Coming L., Padilla D.K., Mondido C.A., Sinag J.M., et al. The effect of a 4-week plyometric training exercise on specific physical fitness components in U21 novice volleyball players. Pedagog. Phys. Cult. Sports. 2025;29:86&#x2013;95. doi: 10.15561/26649837.2025.0202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/26649837.2025.0202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mocanu G.D., Murariu G., Potop V. Differences in explosive strength values for students of the faculty of physical education and sports (male) according to body mass index levels. Pedagog. Phys. Cult. Sports. 2023;27:71&#x2013;83. doi: 10.15561/26649837.2023.0109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/26649837.2023.0109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bujalance-Moreno P., Fortes V., Gallardo L. Effects of combined plyometric and specific wrestling training on performance in youth Greco-Roman wrestlers. Int. J. Sports Sci. Coach. 2020;15:686&#x2013;694. doi: 10.1177/1747954120937376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954120937376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagovitsyn R.S., Koryagina I.A., Kharisova G.R. Adaptive models of training in combat sports for junior athletes. J. Phys. Educ. Sport. 2019;19:1534&#x2013;1540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez-Arrones L., S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E., Requena B. Integrative strength and tactical training in combat sports: A pathway to improve transferability. Strength Cond. J. 2022;44:44&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H., Negra Y., Capranica L., Bouguezzi R., Hachana Y., Granacher U. Specific physical training in young combat athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front. Physiol. 2020;11:1099. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2020.01099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.01099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7498679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33013468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani M., Miarka B., Briki W., Cheour F. Comparison of Mental Toughness and Power Test Performances in High-Level Kickboxers by Competitive Success. Asian J. Sports Med. 2016;7:e30840. doi: 10.5812/asjsm.30840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.30840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5003315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27625755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M., Drust B. The importance of high-intensity training and neuromuscular specificity in youth combat athletes: A practical framework. J. Funct. Morphol. Kinesiol. 2021;6:36. doi: 10.3390/jfmk6020036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk6020036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8167794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A.F., Ramirez-Campillo R., Sarmento H., Afonso J., Clemente F.M. Effects of training programs on decision-making in youth team sports players: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front. Psychol. 2021;12:663867. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2021.663867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.663867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34135822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R.A., Sousa NMFd Prestes J., Feito Y., Ernesto C., Voltarelli F.A. Monitoring Training Load, Well-Being, Heart Rate Variability, and Competitive Performance of a Functional-Fitness Female Athlete: A Case Study. Sports. 2019;7:35. doi: 10.3390/sports7020035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7020035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6409702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30744103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloui G., Dhahbi W., Ceylan H.&#x130;., Stefanica V., Alneama A., Mami M., Hayes L., Muntean R.I., Hermassi S. A Combined Balance and Plyometric Training Approach: Effects on Physical Performance Parameters in Youth Male Handball Players: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Rev. Psicol. Deporte (J. Sport Psychol.) 2025;34:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latyshev M., Sergeev N., Kudinov A. Individualization of physical training in youth wrestling based on motor characteristics. Teor. Prakt. Fiz. Kult. 2020;12:23&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo D.J., &#xc1;vila-Gand&#xed;a V., Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez A. Specific physical conditioning in combat sports: A practical update for trainers. Strength Cond. J. 2022;44:52&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreve A.A., Stoica M., Gheara C., Stoian O., Saftel A. Physical Effort Monitoring with the Catapult Gps System in the Context of an Aerobic Endurance Testing of Rugby Players. Elearning Softw. Educ. 2021;3:328&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aquino R., Carling C., Palucci Vieira L.H., Gon&#xe7;alves L.G.C., Puggina E.F. Tactical behavior and its relationship with physical and technical performance in youth combat sports. Int. J. Perform. Anal. Sport. 2023;23:215&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarrit B., Garnier Y.M., Birat A., Ruas C.V., Estevam E., Rance M., Morel C., Nottin S., Mattiello-Sverzut A.C., Nosaka K., et al. Can neuromuscular differences manifest by early adolescence in males between predominantly endurance and strength sports? Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2024;124:2651&#x2013;2663. doi: 10.1007/s00421-024-05480-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05480-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38630264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Aravena A., Herrera-Valenzuela T., Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla P., B&#xe1;ez-San Mart&#xed;n E., Thapa R.K., Ramirez-Campillo R. A systematic review with meta-analysis on the effects of plyometric-jump training on the physical fitness of combat sport athletes. Sports. 2023;11:33. doi: 10.3390/sports11020033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports11020033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9965890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullayev I.X. Improvement of the special physical training model of greco-roman junior wrestlers. Ment. Enlight. Sci.-Methodol. J. 2023;4:9&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrov A., Zimkin D. Standardization of physical performance in junior combat athletes: Methodological considerations. Phys. Educ. Theory Pract. 2020;26:87&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihaiu C., Stefanica V., Joksimovi&#x107; M., Ceylan H.&#x130;., Pirvu D. Impact of Specific Plyometric Training on Physiological and Performance Outcomes in U16 Performance Athletes Soccer Players. Rev. Rom. Pentru Educ. Multidimens. 2024;16:206&#x2013;223. doi: 10.18662/rrem/16.3/891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18662/rrem/16.3/891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>