<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41279114</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scaling Large Language Models for Next-Generation Single-Cell Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2025.04.14.648850</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2025.04.14.648850</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Single-cell RNA sequencing has transformed our understanding of cellular diversity, yet current single-cell foundation models (scFMs) remain limited in their scalability, flexibility across diverse tasks, and ability to natively integrate textual information. In this work, we build upon the Cell2Sentence (C2S) framework, which represents scRNA-seq profiles as textual "cell sentences," to train Large Language Models (LLMs) on a corpus comprising over one billion tokens of transcriptomic data, biological text, and metadata. Scaling the model to 27 billion parameters yields consistent improvements in predictive and generative capabilities and supports advanced downstream tasks that require synthesis of information across multi-cellular contexts. Targeted fine-tuning with modern reinforcement learning techniques produces strong performance in perturbation response prediction, natural language interpretation, and complex biological reasoning. This predictive strength enabled a dual-context virtual screen that nominated the kinase inhibitor silmitasertib (CX-4945) as a candidate for context-selective upregulation of antigen presentation. Experimental assessment in human cell models unseen during training supported this prediction, demonstrating that C2S-Scale can effectively guide the discovery of context-conditioned biology. C2S-Scale unifies transcriptomic and textual data at unprecedented scales, surpassing both specialized single-cell models and general-purpose LLMs to provide a platform for next-generation single-cell analysis and the development of "virtual cells."</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rizvi</LastName><ForeName>Syed Asad</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7932-9524</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University, Google Research.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levine</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Aakash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shiyang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Google DeepMind.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Curtis Jamison</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vrkic</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constante</LastName><ForeName>Nicole Mayerli</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Zirui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Sizhuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Cerise</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyu</LastName><ForeName>Zhuoyang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brown University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darji</LastName><ForeName>Rayyan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Lawrence</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwan</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hafler</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Hattie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8417-5606</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhodapkar</LastName><ForeName>Rahul M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2014-7515</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Southern California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaeger</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Google DeepMind.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perozzi</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Google Research.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishizuka</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4271-7312</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azizi</LastName><ForeName>Shekoofeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7447-6031</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Google DeepMind.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Dijk</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3911-9925</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM143072</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41279114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12632461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.04.14.648850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2025.04.14.648850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Angerer Philipp, Simon Lukas, Tritschler Sophie, Wolf F Alexander, Fischer David, and Theis Fabian J Single cells make big data: new challenges and opportunities in transcriptomics. Current opinion in systems biology, 4:85&#x2013;91, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CZI Cell Science Program, Abdulla Shibla, Aevermann Brian, Assis Pedro, Badajoz Seve, Bell Sidney M, Bezzi Emanuele, Cakir Batuhan, Chaffer Jim, Chambers Signe, et al. Cz cellxgene discover: A single-cell data platform for scalable exploration, analysis and modeling of aggregated data. Nucleic Acids Research, page gkae1142, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regev Aviv, Teichmann Sarah A, Lander Eric S, Amit Ido, Benoist Christophe, Birney Ewan, Bodenmiller Bernd, Campbell Peter, Carninci Piero, Clatworthy Menna, et al. The human cell atlas. elife, 6:e27041, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Haotian, Wang Chloe, Maan Hassaan, Pang Kuan, Luo Fengning, Duan Nan, and Wang Bo. scgpt: toward building a foundation model for single-cell multi-omics using generative ai. Nature Methods, pages 1&#x2013;11, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodoris Christina V, Xiao Ling, Chopra Anant, Chaffin Mark D, Al Sayed Zeina R, Hill Matthew C, Mantineo Helene, Brydon Elizabeth M, Zeng Zexian, Liu X Shirley, et al. Transfer learning enables predictions in network biology. Nature, 618(7965):616&#x2013;624, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37258680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Minsheng, Gong Jing, Zeng Xin, Liu Chiming, Guo Yucheng, Cheng Xingyi, Wang Taifeng, Ma Jianzhu, Zhang Xuegong, and Song Le. Large-scale foundation model on single-cell transcriptomics. Nature Methods, pages 1&#x2013;11, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Istrate Ana-Maria, Li Donghui, and Karaletsos Theofanis. scgenept: Is language all you need for modeling single-cell perturbations? bioRxiv, pages 2024&#x2013;10, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A Attention is all you need. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford Alec, Wu Jeffrey, Child Rewon, Luan David, Amodei Dario, Sutskever Ilya, et al. Language models are unsupervised multitask learners. OpenAI blog, 1(8):9, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown Tom, Mann Benjamin, Ryder Nick, Subbiah Melanie, Kaplan Jared D, Dhariwal Prafulla, Neelakantan Arvind, Shyam Pranav, Sastry Girish, Askell Amanda, et al. Language models are few-shot learners. Advances in neural information processing systems, 33:1877&#x2013;1901, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan Jared, McCandlish Sam, Henighan Tom, Brown Tom B, Chess Benjamin, Child Rewon, Gray Scott, Radford Alec, Wu Jeffrey, and Amodei Dario. Scaling laws for neural language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2001.08361, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Biao, Liu Zhongtao, Cherry Colin, and Firat Orhan. When scaling meets llm finetuning: The effect of data, model and finetuning method. arXiv preprint arXiv:2402.17193, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhodapkar Rahul M Representing cells as sentences enables natural-language processing for single-cell transcriptomics. bioRxiv, pages 2022&#x2013;09, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine Daniel, Rizvi Syed Asad, L&#xe9;vy Sacha, Pallikkavaliyaveetil Nazreen, Zhang David, Chen Xingyu, Ghadermarzi Sina, Wu Ruiming, Zheng Zihe, Vrkic Ivan, et al. Cell2sentence: Teaching large language models the language of biology. bioRxiv, pages 2023&#x2013;09, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team Gemma, Riviere Morgane, Pathak Shreya, Sessa Pier Giuseppe, Hardin Cassidy, Bhupatiraju Surya, Hussenot L&#xe9;onard, Mesnard Thomas, Shahriari Bobak, Ram&#xe9; Alexandre, et al. Gemma 2: Improving open language models at a practical size. arXiv preprint arXiv:2408.00118, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biderman Stella, Schoelkopf Hailey, Anthony Quentin Gregory, Bradley Herbie, O&#x2019;Brien Kyle, Hallahan Eric, Khan Mohammad Aflah, Purohit Shivanshu, Sai Prashanth USVSN, Raff Edward, et al. Pythia: A suite for analyzing large language models across training and scaling. In International Conference on Machine Learning, pages 2397&#x2013;2430. PMLR, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achiam Josh, Adler Steven, Agarwal Sandhini, Ahmad Lama, Akkaya Ilge, Aleman Florencia Leoni, Almeida Diogo, Altenschmidt Janko, Altman Sam, Anadkat Shyamal, et al. Gpt-4 technical report. arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.08774, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team Gemini, Anil Rohan, Borgeaud Sebastian, Alayrac Jean-Baptiste, Yu Jiahui, Soricut Radu, Schalkwyk Johan, Dai Andrew M, Hauth Anja, Millican Katie, et al. Gemini: a family of highly capable multimodal models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2312.11805, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez Romain, Regier Jeffrey, Cole Michael B, Jordan Michael I, and Yosef Nir Deep generative modeling for single-cell transcriptomics. Nature methods, 15(12):1053&#x2013;1058, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30504886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conde C Dom&#xed;nguez, Xu C, Jarvis LB, Rainbow DB, Wells SB, Gomes T, Howlett SK, Suchanek O, Polanski K, King HW, et al. Cross-tissue immune cell analysis reveals tissue-specific features in humans. Science, 376(6594):eabl5197, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells Steven B, Rainbow Daniel B, Mark Michal, Szabo Peter A, Ergen Can, Caron Daniel P, Maceiras Ana Raquel, Rahmani Elior, Benuck Eli, Amiri Valeh Valiollah Pour, et al. Multimodal profiling reveals tissue-directed signatures of human immune cells altered with age. Nature Immunology, 26(9):1612&#x2013;1625, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12396968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40804529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Qiuyu, Sharma Mehul, Glass Marla C, Kuan Emma L, Chander Aishwarya, Singh Mansi, Graybuck Lucas T, Thomson Zachary J, LaFrance Christian M, Zaim Samir Rachid, et al. Multi-omic profiling reveals age-related immune dynamics in healthy adults. Nature, pages 1&#x2013;11, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron Maayan, Veres Adrian, Wolock Samuel L, Faust Aubrey L, Gaujoux Renaud, Vetere Amedeo, Ryu Jennifer Hyoje, Wagner Bridget K, Shen-Orr Shai S, Klein Allon M, et al. A single-cell transcriptomic map of the human and mouse pancreas reveals inter-and intra-cell population structure. Cell systems, 3(4):346&#x2013;360, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5228327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27667365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Jieun, Eo Eun-Young, Kim Bokyong, Lee Heetak, Kim Jihoon, Koo Bon-Kyoung, Kim Hyung-Jun, Cho Sukki, Kim Jinho, and Cho Young-Jae. Transcriptomic analysis of air&#x2013;liquid interface culture in human lung organoids reveals regulators of epithelial differentiation. Cells, 13(23):1991, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11639892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39682739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Edward J, Shen Yelong, Wallis Phillip, Allen-Zhu Zeyuan, Li Yuanzhi, Wang Shean, Wang Lu, and Chen Weizhu. Lora: Low-rank adaptation of large language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2106.09685, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Yiqun and Zou James. Genept: a simple but effective foundation model for genes and cells built from chatgpt. bioRxiv, pages 2023&#x2013;10, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Tianyi, Kishore Varsha, Wu Felix, Weinberger Kilian Q, and Artzi Yoav. Bertscore: Evaluating text generation with bert. arXiv preprint arXiv:1904.09675, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touvron Hugo, Lavril Thibaut, Izacard Gautier, Martinet Xavier, Lachaux Marie-Anne, Lacroix Timoth&#xe9;e, Rozi&#xe8;re Baptiste, Goyal Naman, Hambro Eric, Azhar Faisal, et al. Llama: Open and efficient foundation language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2302.13971, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touvron Hugo, Martin Louis, Stone Kevin, Albert Peter, Almahairi Amjad, Babaei Yasmine, Bashlykov Nikolay, Batra Soumya, Bhargava Prajjwal, Bhosale Shruti, et al. Llama 2: Open foundation and fine-tuned chat models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2307.09288, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey Abhimanyu, Jauhri Abhinav, Pandey Abhinav, Kadian Abhishek, Al-Dahle Ahmad, Letman Aiesha, Mathur Akhil, Schelten Alan, Yang Amy, Fan Angela, et al. The llama 3 herd of models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.21783, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosselut Antoine, Chen Zeming, Romanou Angelika, Bonnet Antoine, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Cano Alejandro, Alkhamissi Badr, Matoba Kyle, Salvi Francesco, Pagliardini Matteo, Fan Simin, et al. Meditron: Open medical foundation models adapted for clinical practice. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrak Yanis, Bazoge Adrien, Morin Emmanuel, Gourraud Pierre-Antoine, Rouvier Mickael, and Dufour Richard. Biomistral: A collection of open-source pretrained large language models for medical domains. arXiv preprint arXiv:2402.10373, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora Rohit, Cao Christian, Kumar Mehul, Sinha Sarthak, Chanda Ayan, McNeil Reid, Samuel Divya, Arora Rahul K, Matthews T Wayne, Chandarana Shamir, et al. Spatial transcriptomics reveals distinct and conserved tumor core and edge architectures that predict survival and targeted therapy response. Nature Communications, 14(1):5029, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egeblad Mikala, Nakasone Elizabeth S, and Werb Zena Tumors as organs: complex tissues that interface with the entire organism. Developmental cell, 18(6):884&#x2013;901, 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2905377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20627072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannino Giuliana, Russo Cristina, Maugeri Grazia, Musumeci Giuseppe, Vicario Nunzio, Tibullo Daniele, Giuffrida Rosario, Parenti Rosalba, and Lo Furno Debora Adult stem cell niches for tissue homeostasis. Journal of Cellular Physiology, 237(1):239&#x2013;257, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9291197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34435361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cang Zixuan and Nie Qing. Inferring spatial and signaling relationships between cells from single cell transcriptomic data. Nature communications, 11(1):2084, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Suoqin, Guerrero-Juarez Christian F, Zhang Lihua, Chang Ivan, Ramos Raul, Kuan Chen-Hsiang, Myung Peggy, Plikus Maksim V, and Nie Qing Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using cellchat. Nature communications, 12(1):1088, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armingol Erick, Officer Adam, Harismendy Olivier, and Lewis Nathan E Deciphering cell&#x2013;cell interactions and communication from gene expression. Nature Reviews Genetics, 22(2):71&#x2013;88, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Shanshan, Bhatt Ruchir, Birditt Brian, Brown Carl, Brown Emily, Chantranuvatana Kan, Danaher Patrick, Dunaway Dwayne, Filanoski Brian, Garrison Ryan G, et al. High-plex multiomic analysis in ffpe tissue at single-cellular and subcellular resolution by spatial molecular imaging. BioRxiv, pages 2021&#x2013;11, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejada-Lapuerta Alejandro, Schaar Anna C, Gutgesell Robert, Palla Giovanni, Halle Lennard, Minaeva Mariia, Vornholz Larsen, Dony Leander, Drummer Francesca, Richter Till, et al. Nicheformer: a foundation model for single-cell and spatial omics. Nature methods, pages 1&#x2013;14, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39806059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troul&#xe9; Kevin, Petryszak Robert, Prete Martin, Cranley James, Harasty Alicia, Tuong Zewen Kelvin, Teichmann Sarah A, Garcia-Alonso Luz, and Vento-Tormo Roser. Cellphonedb v5: inferring cell-cell communication from single-cell multiomics data. arXiv preprint arXiv:2311.04567, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oughtred Rose, Rust Jennifer, Chang Christie, Breitkreutz Bobby-Joe, Stark Chris, Willems Andrew, Boucher Lorrie, Leung Genie, Kolas Nadine, Zhang Frederick, et al. The biogrid database: A comprehensive biomedical resource of curated protein, genetic, and chemical interactions. Protein Science, 30(1):187&#x2013;200, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33070389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpurkar P Squad: 100,000+ questions for machine comprehension of text. arXiv preprint arXiv:1606.05250, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrycks Dan, Burns Collin, Basart Steven, Zou Andy, Mazeika Mantas, Song Dawn, and Steinhardt Jacob. Measuring massive multitask language understanding. arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.03300, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Yubo, Ma Xueguang, Zhang Ge, Ni Yuansheng, Chandra Abhranil, Guo Shiguang, Ren Weiming, Arulraj Aaran, He Xuan, Jiang Ziyan, et al. Mmlu-pro: A more robust and challenging multi-task language understanding benchmark. arXiv preprint arXiv:2406.01574, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Wanjun, Cui Ruixiang, Guo Yiduo, Liang Yaobo, Lu Shuai, Wang Yanlin, Saied Amin, Chen Weizhu, and Duan Nan. Agieval: A human-centric benchmark for evaluating foundation models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2304.06364, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Abacha Asma and Demner-Fushman Dina. A question-entailment approach to question answering. BMC bioinformatics, 20:1&#x2013;23, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal Ankit, Umapathi Logesh Kumar, and Sankarasubbu Malaikannan Medmcqa: A large-scale multi-subject multi-choice dataset for medical domain question answering. In Conference on health, inference, and learning, pages 248&#x2013;260. PMLR, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Qiao, Dhingra Bhuwan, Liu Zhengping, Cohen William W, and Lu Xinghua Pubmedqa: A dataset for biomedical research question answering. arXiv preprint arXiv:1909.06146, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton Richard S and Barto Andrew G Reinforcement learning: An introduction. MIT press, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Zhihong, Wang Peiyi, Zhu Qihao, Xu Runxin, Song Junxiao, Bi Xiao, Zhang Haowei, Zhang Mingchuan, Li YK, Wu Y, et al. Deepseekmath: Pushing the limits of mathematical reasoning in open language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2402.03300, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian Aravind, Narayan Rajiv, Corsello Steven M, Peck David D, Natoli Ted E, Lu Xiaodong, Gould Joshua, Davis John F, Tubelli Andrew A, Asiedu Jacob K, et al. A next generation connectivity map: L1000 platform and the first 1,000,000 profiles. Cell, 171(6):1437&#x2013;1452, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29195078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Mingze, Wang Bao, Wei Jessica, de O. Fonseca Antonio H., Perry Curtis J., Frey Alexander, Ouerghi Feriel, Foxman Ellen F., Ishizuka Jeffrey J., Dhodapkar Rahul M., and van Dijk David Causal identification of single-cell experimental perturbation effects with cinema-ot. Nature Methods, 20(11):1769&#x2013;1779, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10630139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37919419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusel Martin, Ramsauer Hubert, Unterthiner Thomas, Nessler Bernhard, and Hochreiter Sepp. Gans trained by a two time-scale update rule converge to a local nash equilibrium. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, volume 30, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivatsan Sanjay R., McFaline-Figueroa Jos&#xe9; L., Ramani Vijay, Saunders Lauren, Cao Junyue, Packer Jonathan, Pliner Hannah A., Jackson Dana L., Daza Riza M., Christiansen Lena, Zhang Fan, Steemers Frank, Shendure Jay, and Trapnell Cole Massively multiplex chemical transcriptomics at single-cell resolution. Science, 367(6473):45&#x2013;51, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetzel Leon, Boehm Simon, Kilbertus Niki, G&#xfc;nnemann Stephan, lotfollahi mohammad, and Theis Fabian Predicting cellular responses to novel drug perturbations at a single-cell resolution. In Koyejo S., Mohamed S., Agarwal A., Belgrave D., Cho K., and Oh A., editors, Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, volume 35, pages 26711&#x2013;26722. Curran Associates, Inc., 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Huayang, Golji Javad, Brodeur Lauren K, Chung Franklin S, Chen Julie T, deBeaumont Rosalie S, Bullock Caroline P, Jones Michael D, Kerr Grainne, Li Li, et al. Tumor-derived ifn triggers chronic pathway agonism and sensitivity to adar loss. Nature medicine, 25(1):95&#x2013;102, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuertes Mercedes B, Kacha Aalok K, Kline Justin, Woo Seng-Ryong, Kranz David M, Murphy Kenneth M, and Gajewski Thomas F. Host type i ifn signals are required for antitumor cd8+ t cell responses through cd8&#x3b1;+ dendritic cells. Journal of Experimental Medicine, 208(10):2005&#x2013;2016, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21930765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stopfer Lauren E, Rettko Nicholas J, Leddy Owen, Mesfin Joshua M, Brown Eric, Winski Shannon, Bryson Bryan, Wells James A, and White Forest M. Mek inhibition enhances presentation of targetable mhc-i tumor antigens in mutant melanomas. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 119(49):e2208900119, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Li, Mayes Patrick A, Eastman Stephen, Shi Hong, Yadavilli Sapna, Zhang Tianqian, Yang Jingsong, Seestaller-Wehr Laura, Zhang Shu-Yun, Hopson Chris, et al. The braf and mek inhibitors dabrafenib and trametinib: effects on immune function and in combination with immunomodulatory antibodies targeting pd-1, pd-l1, and ctla-4. Clinical Cancer Research, 21(7):1639&#x2013;1651, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25589619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque Ashraful, Engel Jessica, Teichmann Sarah A, and L&#xf6;nnberg Tapio. A practical guide to single-cell rna-sequencing for biomedical research and clinical applications. Genome medicine, 9:1&#x2013;12, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5228100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahdanau Dzmitry. Neural machine translation by jointly learning to align and translate. arXiv preprint arXiv:1409.0473, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford Alec. Improving language understanding by generative pre-training. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf T Huggingface&#x2019;s transformers: State-of-the-art natural language processing. arXiv preprint arXiv:1910.03771, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paszke Adam, Gross Sam, Massa Francisco, Lerer Adam, Bradbury James, Chanan Gregory, Killeen Trevor, Lin Zeming, Gimelshein Natalia, Antiga Luca, et al. Pytorch: An imperative style, high-performance deep learning library. Advances in neural information processing systems, 32, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Zhi-Jie and Gao Ge. Multi-omics single-cell data integration and regulatory inference with graph-linked embedding. Nature Biotechnology, 40(10):1458&#x2013;1466, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer Moritz, Peneder Peter, Malzl Daniel, Lombardo Salvo Danilo, Peycheva Mihaela, Burton Jake, Hakobyan Anna, Sharma Varun, Krausgruber Thomas, Sin Celine, et al. Multimodal learning enables chat-based exploration of single-cell data. Nature Biotechnology, pages 1&#x2013;11, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Zhen, Cheng Xuesen, Ferdous Salma, Shao Jianming, Li Jin, Bao Yourong, Li Jean, Lu Jiaxiong, Lopez Antonio Jacobo, Wohlschlegel Juliette, et al. Single cell dual-omic atlas of the human developing retina. Nature Communications, 15(1):6792, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clerc Olivier, Deniaud Madeline, Vallet Sylvain D, Naba Alexandra, Rivet Alain, Perez Serge, Thierry-Mieg Nicolas, and Ricard-Blum Sylvie. Matrixdb: integration of new data with a focus on glycosaminoglycan interactions. Nucleic acids research, 47(D1):D376&#x2013;D381, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roohani Yusuf, Huang Kexin, and Leskovec Jure. Predicting transcriptional outcomes of novel multigene perturbations with gears. Nature Biotechnology, 42(6):927&#x2013;935, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piran Zoe, Cohen Niv, Hoshen Yedid, and Nitzan Mor. Disentanglement of single-cell data with biolord. Nature Biotechnology, 42(11):1678&#x2013;1683, 11 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfollahi Mohammad, Alexander F., and Theis Fabian J. scgen predicts single-cell perturbation responses. Nature Methods, 16(8):715&#x2013;721, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31363220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunne Charlotte, Stark Stefan G., Gut Gabriele, del Castillo Jacobo Sarabia, Levesque Mitch, Lehmann Kjong-Van, Pelkmans Lucas, Krause Andreas, and R&#xe4;tsch Gunnar Learning single-cell perturbation responses using neural optimal transport. Nature Methods, 20(11):1759&#x2013;1768, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10630137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian Aravind, Tamayo Pablo, Mootha Vamsi K, Mukherjee Sayan, Ebert Benjamin L, Gillette Michael A, Paulovich Amanda, Pomeroy Scott L, Golub Todd R, Lander Eric S, and Mesirov Jill P Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A., 102(43):15545&#x2013;15550, October 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1239896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heumos L, Ji Yuge, May Lilly, Green Tessa D, Zhang Xinyue, Wu Xichen, Ostner Johannes, Peidli Stefan, Schumacher Antonia, Hrovatin Karin, Mueller M F, Chong F, Sturm Gregor, Tejada Alejandro, Dann Emma, Dong Mingze, Bahrami Mojtaba, Gold Ilan, Rybakov Sergei, Namsaraeva Altana, Moinfar A, Zheng Zihe, Roellin Eljas, Mekki Isra, Sander C, Lotfollahi M, Schiller Herbert B, and Theis Fabian J Pertpy: an end-to-end framework for perturbation analysis. bioRxiv, August 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunne Charlotte, Krause Andreas, and Cuturi Marco. Supervised Training of Conditional Monge Maps. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrum Greg and others. RDKit: Open-source cheminformatics. https://www.rdkit.org. Accessed: 2025-12-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szegedy Christian, Vanhoucke Vincent, Ioffe Sergey, Shlens Jon, and Wojna Zbigniew. Rethinking the inception architecture for computer vision. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), June 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team Gemma, Kamath Aishwarya, Ferret Johan, Pathak Shreya, Vieillard Nino, Merhej Ramona, Perrin Sarah, Matejovicova Tatiana, Alexandre Ram&#xe9; Morgane Rivi&#xe8;re, et al. Gemma 3 technical report. arXiv preprint arXiv:2503.19786, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Jesse, Ubas Airol A, de Borja Richard, Svensson Valentine, Thomas Nicole, Thakar Neha, Lai Ian, Winters Aidan, Khan Umair, Jones Matthew G, et al. Tahoe-100m: A giga-scale single-cell perturbation atlas for context-dependent gene function and cellular modeling. BioRxiv, pages 2025&#x2013;02, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes Alexis J, Samad Bushra, Tsui Jessica, Chew Nayvin W, Yan Peter, Reeder Gabriella C, Kushnoor Divyashree, Shen Alan, Davidson Brittany, Barczak Andrea J, et al. Discovering dominant tumor immune archetypes in a pan-cancer census. Cell, 185(1):184&#x2013;203, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34963056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das Bhaba K, Kannan Aarthi, Velasco Graham J, Kunika Mikaela D, Lambrecht Nils, Nguyen Quy, Zhao Haibo, Wu Jie, and Gao Ling Single-cell dissection of merkel cell carcinoma heterogeneity unveils transcriptomic plasticity and therapeutic vulnerabilities. Cell Reports Medicine, 4(7), 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleber-Netto Frederico O, Rao Xiayu, Guo Theresa, Xi Yuanxin, Gao Meng, Shen Li, Erikson Kelly, Kalu Nene N, Ren Shuling, Xu Guorong, et al. Variations in hpv function are associated with survival in squamous cell carcinoma. JCI insight, 4(1):e124762, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan K., Becker J., and Gravemeyer J.. Waga single cell rna sequencing. Gene Expression Omnibus, NCBI, GEO Accession: GSE130346, 2019. Homo sapiens, Expression profiling by high throughput sequencing. BioProject: PRJNA535920. Accessed: 2025-08-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy Alexey. An image is worth 16&#xd7;16 words: Transformers for image recognition at scale. arXiv preprint arXiv:2010.11929, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Daya, Yang Dejian, Zhang Haowei, Song Junxiao, Zhang Ruoyu, Xu Runxin, Zhu Qihao, Ma Shirong, Wang Peiyi, Bi Xiao, et al. Deepseek-r1: Incentivizing reasoning capability in llms via reinforcement learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:2501.12948, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Xuezhi, Wei Jason, Schuurmans Dale, Le Quoc, Chi Ed, Narang Sharan, Chowdhery Aakanksha, and Zhou Denny. Self-consistency improves chain of thought reasoning in language models. arXiv preprint arXiv:2203.11171, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niels M&#xfc;ndler Jingxuan He, Jenko Slobodan, and Vechev Martin. Self-contradictory hallucinations of large language models: Evaluation, detection and mitigation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2305.15852, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su-Yi Leong Cara and Linzen Tal Language models can learn exceptions to syntactic rules. arXiv preprint arXiv:2306.05969, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson Michael, Petty Jackson, and Frank Robert. How abstract is linguistic generalization in large language models? experiments with argument structure. Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics, 11:1377&#x2013;1395, 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>