<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41124160</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of technological parameters on mechanical properties and microstructure of heat-assisted friction stir welded joints of 6061 aluminum alloy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0334979</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0334979</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0334979</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0334979</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the influence of key technological parameters on the mechanical characteristics and microstructure of heat-assisted friction stir welded (FSW) joints of AA6061 aluminum alloy pipes. Specifically, the effect of tool rotation speed, transverse speed, and tool shoulder diameter was evaluated. An experimental campaign was conducted using a three-level, three-factor composite design, with the primary objective of determining the optimal combination of these parameters to maximize the tensile strength of the weldments. AA6061 aluminum alloy pipes, with a thickness of 5&#x2009;mm and an outer diameter of 80&#x2009;mm, were joined using a resistance preheating FSW (RPFSW) process. The input parameters were varied at three distinct levels: rotation speed (1250, 1500, 1750&#x2009;rpm), transverse speed (75, 87.5, 100&#x2009;mm/min), and shoulder diameter (12, 15, 18&#x2009;mm). Tensile tests were conducted to evaluate mechanical strength, and optical microscopy together with scanning electron microscopy (SEM), was employed to examine the microstructure of the weldments. The results indicate that the weldments achieved a tensile strength ranging from 49.7% to 72.4% of the base material. The optimal processing parameters were identified to achieve the highest predicted tensile strength of 198.15&#x2009;MPa, corresponding to a transverse speed of 100&#x2009;mm/min, a rotation speed of 1629&#x2009;rpm, and a shoulder diameter of 13&#x2009;mm. Microstructural analysis revealed that appropriate RPFSW parameters lead to suitable temperature and material flow, which in turn reduces weld defects and enhances the overall mechanical properties of the joint.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Nguyen et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Hoang-Linh</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-4738-3688</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Danang, University of Science and Technology, Danang City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Pham Van Dong University, Quang Ngai Province, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Van-Trung</ForeName><Initials>VT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8327-5987</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Danang, University of Science and Technology, Danang City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luu</LastName><ForeName>Duc-Binh</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Danang, University of Science and Technology, Danang City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Thien-Phuc</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (HCMUT), Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City, Linh Trung Ward, Thu Duc City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000497">Alloys</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>CPD4NFA903</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000535">Aluminum</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000497" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alloys</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000535" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aluminum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013718" MajorTopicYN="N">Tensile Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006358" MajorTopicYN="N">Hot Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017276" MajorTopicYN="N">Friction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008422" MajorTopicYN="N">Materials Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014896" MajorTopicYN="Y">Welding</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008855" MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopy, Electron, Scanning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41124160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12543162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0334979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-26601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amini A, Asadi P, Zolghadr P. Friction stir welding applications in industry. Advances in Friction-Stir Welding and Processing. Elsevier; 2014. p. 671&#x2013;722. doi: 10.1533/9780857094551.671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1533/9780857094551.671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L, Thornton M, Shergold M. A comparison of the mechanical behaviour of self-piercing riveted and resistance spot welded aluminium sheets for the automotive industry. Materials &amp; Design. 2010;31(3):1457&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2009.08.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2009.08.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas WM, Nicholas ED, Needham JC, Murch MG, Temple-Smith P, Dawes CJ GB. Patent Application No.9125978.8. 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaji S, Dharani Kumar S, Magarajan U, RameshBabu S, Ganeshkumar S, Sharma S, et al. Comparative analysis of experimental and numerical investigation on multiple projectile impact of AA5083 friction stir welded targets. PLoS One. 2023;18(7):e0285254. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0285254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0285254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10374147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37498917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti S, Kumar S, Singh I, Kumar D, Bhurat SS, Abdullah MR, et al. A Review of Recent Developments in Friction Stir Welding for Various Industrial Applications. JMSE. 2023;12(1):71. doi: 10.3390/jmse12010071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse12010071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Khoshnaw F. Friction stir welding. Welding of Metallic Materials. Elsevier; 2023. p. 197&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1016/b978-0-323-90552-7.00006-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-90552-7.00006-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langari J, Kolahan F. The effect of friction stir welding parameters on the microstructure, defects, and mechanical properties of AA7075-T651 joints. Scientia Iranica. 2018;0(0):0&#x2013;0. doi: 10.24200/sci.2018.5700.1434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24200/sci.2018.5700.1434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shunmugasundaram M, Praveen Kumar A, Ponraj Sankar L, Sivasankar S. Optimization of process parameters of friction stir welded dissimilar AA6063 and AA5052 aluminum alloys by Taguchi technique. Materials Today: Proceedings. 2020;27:871&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.01.122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.01.122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaknesh S, Sampathkumar K, Sevvel P, John Solomon I. Generation of force and torque during joining of AZ91C plates by FSW under distinctive tool tilt angle and their impact on mechanical strength and micro-structure. Journal of Adhesion Science and Technology. 2022;37(6):1071&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1080/01694243.2022.2057763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01694243.2022.2057763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar BY, Sevvel P. Impact of traverse speed during joining of CDA101 plates using FSW process. Scientia Iranica. 2022;29(4):1817&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel V, Li W, Liu X, Wen Q, Su Y, Shen J, et al. Tailoring grain refinement through thickness in magnesium alloy via stationary shoulder friction stir processing and copper backing plate. Materials Science and Engineering: A. 2020;784:139322. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2020.139322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2020.139322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balamurugan S, Jayakumar K, Nandakumar C. Investigation of mechanical, metallurgical and corrosion characteristics of friction stir welded dissimilar AA 5052-H32 and AA 6061-T6 joints. Journal of the Chinese Institute of Engineers. 2023;46(6):601&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/02533839.2023.2227875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02533839.2023.2227875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K S, Jayakumar K. Effect of tool pin profile on the mechanical and microstructural properties of dissimilar friction stir welded AA5083-H111 and AA6061-T6 aluminium alloys. Journal of the Chinese Institute of Engineers. 2022;45(3):227&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1080/02533839.2022.2034054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02533839.2022.2034054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthamaraikannan B, Krishnamoorthy J. Material flow and mechanical properties of friction stir welded AA 5052-H32 and AA6061-T6 alloys with Sc interlayer. Materials Testing. 2023;65(7):1127&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1515/mt-2022-0352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/mt-2022-0352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naveen Kumar P, Jayakumar K, Senthur Vaishnavan S. FSW on AA5083 H-111 and AA5754 H-111 dissimilar plates with scandium intermetallic layer. Materials Today: Proceedings. 2023;72:2294&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2022.09.389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.09.389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar PN, Jayakumar K. Influence of tool pin profiles in the strength enhancement of friction stir welded AA5083 and AA5754 alloys. Mater Res Express. 2022;9(3):036505. doi: 10.1088/2053-1591/ac5956</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ac5956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muchhadiya A, Kumar A, Kumari S, Saxena KK, Bandhu D, Vora J, et al. Optimization of friction stir welding process parameters for HDPE sheets using satisfaction function approach. IJEMS. 2024;31(1):58&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muchhadiya A, Kumari S, Bandhu D, Abhishek K, Vora JJ. Elucidating the effect of friction stir welding variables on HDPE sheets using grey integrated with fuzzy: experimental investigation and parametric optimization. JOM: The Journal of The Minerals, Metals &amp; Materials Society. 2023;75(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuse K, Venkata P, Reddy RM, Bandhu D. Machine learning classification approach for predicting tensile strength in aluminium alloy during friction stir welding. Int J Interact Des Manuf. 2024;19(1):639&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1007/s12008-024-01999-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-024-01999-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari S, Bandhu D, Muchhadiya A, Abhishek K. Recent trends in parametric influence and microstructural analysis of friction stir welding for polymer composites. Advances in Materials and Processing Technologies. 2023:1&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1080/2374068x.2023.2193447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2374068x.2023.2193447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abnar B, Gashtiazar S, Javidani M. Friction Stir Welding of Non-Heat Treatable Al Alloys: Challenges and Improvements Opportunities. Crystals. 2023;13(4):576. doi: 10.3390/cryst13040576</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst13040576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandel KD, Menghani JV. Fabrication of Aluminum 5083/SiC Surface Composite on Tungsten Inert Gas Weld Joint by Novel Direct Friction Stir Processing Technique. IJE. 2023;36(3):523&#x2013;31. doi: 10.5829/ije.2023.36.03c.12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5829/ije.2023.36.03c.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uday KN, Rajamurugan G. Influence of process parameters and its effects on friction stir welding of dissimilar aluminium alloy and its composites &#x2013; a review. Journal of Adhesion Science and Technology. 2022;37(5):767&#x2013;800. doi: 10.1080/01694243.2022.2053348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01694243.2022.2053348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalvani H, Mandal P. Cold forming of Al-5251 and Al-6082 tailored welded blanks manufactured by laser and electron beam welding. Journal of Manufacturing Processes. 2021;68:1615&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.06.070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.06.070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaduwanshi DK, Bag S, Pal S. Effect of Preheating in Hybrid Friction Stir Welding of Aluminum Alloy. J of Materi Eng and Perform. 2014;23(10):3794&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1007/s11665-014-1170-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-014-1170-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cota BS, Bracarense AQ. Hybrid friction stir welding process with plasma-assisted of 5052 H34 aluminum alloy and SAE 1020 steel: analysis of mechanical strength, tool wear and welding stresses. Soldagem &amp; Inspe&#xe7;&#xe3;o. 2020;25:e2509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad NA, Wu C, Padhy GK. Progress and trends in ultrasonic vibration assisted friction stir welding. Journal of Harbin Institute of Technology (New Series). 2018;25(3):16&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta K, Mondal AK, Bose D, Singh DK. Fundamentals of Electric Resistance Friction Stir Welding of Metals: A Review. In: 2020 IEEE 1st International Conference for Convergence in Engineering (ICCE. 2020. 32&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthil SM, Bhuvanesh Kumar M, Dennison MS. A Contemporary Review on Friction Stir Welding of Circular Pipe Joints and the Influence of Fixtures on This Process. Advances in Materials Science and Engineering. 2022;2022:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1155/2022/1311292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/1311292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangil N, Siddiquee AN, Yadav J, Yadav S, Khare V, Mittal N, et al. Friction stir welding and processing of pipes: a status report on joining, materials, and industry applications. WJE. 2024;22(3):540&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1108/wje-01-2024-0013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/wje-01-2024-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabry I, Hewidy AM, Alkhedher M, Mourad A-HI. Analysis of variance and grey relational analysis application methods for the selection and optimization problem in 6061-T6 flange friction stir welding process parameters. International Journal of Lightweight Materials and Manufacture. 2024;7(6):773&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.ijlmm.2024.06.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijlmm.2024.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh VP, Kumar A, Kumar R, Modi A, Kumar D, Mahesh V, et al. Effect of Rotational Speed on Mechanical, Microstructure, and Residual Stress Behaviour of AA6061-T6 Alloy Joints through Friction Stir Welding. J of Materi Eng and Perform. 2023;33(8):3706&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1007/s11665-023-08527-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-023-08527-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary S, Choudhary S, Vaish S, Upadhyay AK, Singla A, Singh Y. Effect of welding parameters on microstructure and mechanical properties of friction stir welded Al 6061 aluminum alloy joints. Materials Today: Proceedings. 2020;25:563&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2019.05.466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2019.05.466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinenko A, Kim K, Vysotskiy I, Zuiko I, Malopheyev S, Mironov S, et al. Microstructure-strength relationship in friction-stir welded 6061-T6 aluminum alloy. Materials Science and Engineering: A. 2020;793:139858. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2020.139858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2020.139858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu L, Ma N, Xiao X, Zhang K, Li H. Microstructure and Properties of Nonlinear Lap Joint of 6061 Aluminum Alloy by Friction Stir Welding. Metals. 2023;13(8):1494. doi: 10.3390/met13081494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met13081494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajakumar S, Muralidharan C, Balasubramanian V. Establishing empirical relationships to predict grain size and tensile strength of friction stir welded AA 6061-T6 aluminium alloy joints. Transactions of Nonferrous Metals Society of China. 2010;20(10):1863&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/s1003-6326(09)60387-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1003-6326(09)60387-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafi HK, Ram GDJ, Phanikumar G, Rao KP. Microstructural evolution during friction surfacing of tool steel H13. Materials &amp; Design. 2011;32(1):82&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2010.06.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2010.06.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Threadgill PL, Leonard AJ, Shercliff HR, Withers PJ. Friction stir welding of aluminium alloys. International Materials Reviews. 2009;54(2):49&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1179/174328009x411136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/174328009x411136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Abbas O, A. Ayoub A, A. Saleh F. Effect of pre-heating on the mechanical properties of friction stir welding for 6061 aluminum alloy. JEASD. 2021;25(Special):2-124-2&#x2013;134. doi: 10.31272/jeasd.conf.2.2.17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31272/jeasd.conf.2.2.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong S, Li N, Zhu Z, Wu LH, Xue P, Wang ZW, et al. A comparative study of conventional, dynamic rotation and heat-assisted friction stir welding of Ti-6Al-4V plates to reduce welding defects. Journal of Materials Processing Technology. 2024;323:118217. doi: 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2023.118217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2023.118217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih OS, Ou H, Sun W. Heat generation, plastic deformation and residual stresses in friction stir welding of aluminium alloy. International Journal of Mechanical Sciences. 2023;238:107827. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2022.107827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2022.107827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BSI C. BS EN ISO 6892-1: 2019 Metallic materials - Tensile testing Part 1: Methods of test at room temperature. British Standards; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alin A. Minitab. Wiley interdisciplinary reviews: computational statistics. 2010;2(6):723&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon J, Sevvel P, Gunasekaran J, Rajarajan SJ. Establishment of empirical relations amidst mechanical attributes of friction stir welded distinctive alloys of Mg and optimized process parameters. Mater Res Express. 2023;10(6):066502. doi: 10.1088/2053-1591/acd5ae</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/acd5ae</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satheesh C, Sevvel P, Kumar RS. Experimental identification of optimized process parameters for FSW of AZ91C Mg alloy using quadratic regression models. Journal of Mechanical Engineering/Strojni&#x161;ki Vestnik. 2020;66(12).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>