<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41579176</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of anesthesia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Anesth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of standardized diaphragm ultrasound measurement and conventional methods for predicting weaning failure: a prospective observational study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00540-026-03655-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Weaning from invasive mechanical ventilation (IMV) is challenging and has multiple causes. The diaphragm is the main respiratory muscle for inspiration. This prospective study aimed to determine the value of standardized diaphragm ultrasound (DUS) measurements [diaphragm excursion (DE), diaphragm thickness fraction (DTF), diaphragmatic rapid shallow breathing index (D-RSBI), rapid shallow diaphragmatic index (RSDI)] in predicting extubation success in intensive care patients, both individually and in combination with conventional indices [rapid shallow breathing index (RSBI), dynamic compliance (Cdyn), airway occlusion pressure, semi-quantitative cough strength score]. To isolate diaphragm contribution, only neurologically intact patients (Glasgow Coma Scale&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;14) with adequate airway protection reflexes were included. The second aim was to examine the relationship between IMV and DUS measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">151 patients on IMV for&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;24&#xa0;h and eligible for spontaneous breathing trial (SBT) were evaluated. Following exclusion criteria, patients underwent SBT in pressure support ventilation mode (positive end-expiratory pressure 5 cmH<sub>2</sub>O, pressure support 8 cmH<sub>2</sub>O). During SBT, mechanical ventilation parameters and diaphragm ultrasound measurements were recorded. Extubation failure was defined as need for reintubation or non-invasive ventilation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">DE and DTF were significantly higher, D-RSBI was lower in patients with successful extubation. There was no difference in RSDI. Multivariate logistic regression was statistically significant, odds ratios (10.018, 1.109, 1.094) were found for DE, DTF, Cdyn, respectively. The only significant correlation between IMV and DUS was DTF-tidal volume (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.500).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A standardized multiparametric model, combining DUS with conventional indices, provides moderate predictive accuracy for extubation success. Integrating DUS into weaning protocols can improve extubation readiness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aksoy</LastName><ForeName>Yener</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6212-7590</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Sancaktepe Sehit Prof.Dr. Ilhan Varank Training And Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Emek Neighborhood, Namik Kemal Street, Number:54, 34785, Istanbul, Turkey. yenerraksoyy@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozgultekin</LastName><ForeName>Asu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Sancaktepe Sehit Prof.Dr. Ilhan Varank Training And Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Emek Neighborhood, Namik Kemal Street, Number:54, 34785, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bal&#x131;k</LastName><ForeName>Yelda</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Haydarpasa Numune Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, 34674, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekinci</LastName><ForeName>Osman</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Haydarpasa Numune Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, 34674, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>J Anesth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8905667</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0913-8668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Anesth. 2026 Mar 31. doi: 10.1007/s00540-026-03724-w.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41915148</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diaphragm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Extubation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weaning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41579176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00540-026-03655-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00540-026-03655-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi V, Butturini A, Gioconda F, Gagliardi G. Diaphragm ultrasound: a valuable predictor of the outcome of extubation An observational pilot study in covid-19 related ARDS. Arch Clin Biomed Res. 2022;6(5):771&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26502/acbr.50170290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9835007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge H, Zhang A, Teng Y, Hu L. Evaluation of the combined predictive value of multiple indicators based on diaphragmatic ultrasound using logistic regression and ROC curve in weaning from mechanical ventilation in pediatric patients. Front Pediatr. 2024;12:1344709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2024.1344709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39026937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11254809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eksombatchai D, Sukkratok C, Sutherasan Y, Junhasavasdikul D, Theerawit P. The ratio of respiratory rate to diaphragm thickening fraction for predicting extubation success. BMC Pulm Med. 2023;23:109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-023-02392-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37016339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10071651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana PV, Cardenas LZ, de Albuquerque ALP. Diaphragm ultrasound in critically ill patients on mechanical ventilation-evolving concepts. Diagnostics (Basel). 2023;13(6):1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13061116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36980423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10046995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sferrazza Papa GF, Michela PG, Di Marco F, Imeri G, Laurent B, Goligher E, et al. A review of the ultrasound assessment of diaphragmatic function in clinical practice. Respiration. 2016;91:403&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000446518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambon M, Greco M, Speranza B, Cabrini L, Beccaria PF, Zangrillo A. Assessment of diaphragmatic dysfunction in the critically ill patient with ultrasound: a systematic review. Intensive Care Med. 2017;43:29&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-016-4524-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27620292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llamas-&#xc1;lvarez AM, Tenza-Lozano EM, Latour-P&#xe9;rez J. Diaphragm and lung ultrasound to predict weaning outcome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Chest. 2017;152:1140&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2017.08.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28864053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen D, Jonkman AH, Vries HJde, Wennen M, Elshof J, Hoofs MA, et al. Positive end-expiratory pressure affects geometry and function of the human diaphragm. J Appl Physiol. 2021;131:1328&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00184.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34473571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soilemezi E, Koco E, Tsimpos C, Tsagourias M, Savvidou S, Matamis D. Effects of continuous positive airway pressure on diaphragmatic kinetics and breathing pattern in healthy individuals: respiratory mechanics during CPAP. Respirology. 2016;21:1262&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.12823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27253912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen ML, Jonkman AH, Wennen M, Wils E-J, Endeman H, Heunks L. Diaphragm excursions as proxy for tidal volume during spontaneous breathing in invasively ventilated ICU patients. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2023;11:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40635-023-00553-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37891413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10611662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parada-Gereda HM, Tibaduiza AL, Rico-Mendoza A, Molano-Franco D, Nieto VH, Arias-Ortiz WA, et al. Effectiveness of diaphragmatic ultrasound as a predictor of successful weaning from mechanical ventilation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-023-04430-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10161591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goligher EC, Laghi F, Detsky ME, Farias P, Murray A, Brace D, et al. Measuring diaphragm thickness with ultrasound in mechanically ventilated patients: feasibility, reproducibility and validity. Intensive Care Med. 2015;41:734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-015-3724-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25749574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farghaly S, Hasan AA. Diaphragm ultrasound as a new method to predict extubation outcome in mechanically ventilated patients. Aust Crit Care. 2017;30:37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aucc.2016.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumhof S, Wheeler D, Thomas K, McCool FD, Mora J. Change in diaphragmatic thickness during the respiratory cycle predicts extubation success at various levels of pressure support ventilation. Lung. 2016;194:519&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00408-016-9911-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27422706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J, Han X, Bai L, Zhou L, Huang S. Assessment of heart rate, acidosis, consciousness, oxygenation, and respiratory rate to predict noninvasive ventilation failure in hypoxemic patients. Intensive Care Med. 2017;43:192&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-016-4601-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27812731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoodpoor A, Fouladi S, Ramouz A, Shadvar K, Ostadi Z, Soleimanpour H. Diaphragm ultrasound to predict weaning outcome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Anaesthesiol Intensive Ther. 2022;54:164&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/ait.2022.117273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35792111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10156496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadaro S, Grasso S, Mauri T, Dalla Corte F, Alvisi V, Ragazzi R, et al. Can diaphragmatic ultrasonography performed during the T-tube trial predict weaning failure? The role of diaphragmatic rapid shallow breathing index. Crit Care. 2016;20:305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-016-1479-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5039882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterr F, Reintke M, Bauernfeind L, Senyol V, Rester C, Metzing S, et al. Predictors of weaning failure in ventilated intensive care patients: a systematic evidence map. Crit Care. 2024;28:366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-024-05135-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39533438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11556093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Qian Z, Zhang H, Minjia W, Yu Y, Ye C, et al. Diaphragmatic ultrasonography-based rapid shallow breathing index for predicting weaning outcome during a pressure support ventilation spontaneous breathing trial. BMC Pulm Med. 2022;22(1):337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-022-02133-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36071420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9450260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fossat G, Daillet B, Emmanuelle D, Boulain T. Does diaphragm ultrasound improve the rapid shallow breathing index accuracy for predicting the success of weaning from mechanical ventilation? Aust Crit Care. 2022;35:233&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aucc.2021.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34340902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbrello M, Formenti P, Longhi D, Galimberti A, Piva I, Pezzi A, et al. Diaphragm ultrasound as indicator of respiratory effort in critically ill patients undergoing assisted mechanical ventilation: a pilot clinical study. Crit Care. 2015;19:161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-015-0894-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4403842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz A, Erbuth A, Boyko M, Vonderbank S, G&#xfc;rleyen H, Gibis N, et al. Comparison of ultrasound measurements for diaphragmatic mobility, diaphragmatic thickness, and diaphragm thickening fraction with each other and with lung function in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2022;17:2217&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S375956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36118281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9480595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formenti P, Miori S, Galimberti A, Umbrello M. The effects of positive end expiratory pressure and lung volume on diaphragm thickness and thickening. Diagnostics (Basel). 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics13061157 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13061157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10217715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldabayan YS, Tolba AA, Alrajeh AM, Ahmed AT, Mahgoub AA, Glalah AAA, et al. Factors affecting mechanical ventilator weaning success and 28&#xa0;day survival among patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome secondary to COVID-19. SAGE Open Nurs. 2023;9:23779608231187250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Husinat L, Jouryyeh B, Rawashdeh A, Robba C, Silva PL, Rocco PRM, et al. The role of ultrasonography in the process of weaning from mechanical ventilation in critically ill patients. Diagnostics (Basel). 2024;14:398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics14040398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38396437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10888003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brahee DD, Ogedegbe C, Hassler C, Nyirenda T, Hazelwood V, Morchel H, et al. Body mass index and abdominal ultrasound image quality: a pilot survey of sonographers. J Diagn Med Sonogr. 2013;29:66&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1177/8756479313476919 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/8756479313476919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wozniak H, Dos Santos Rocha A, Beckmann TS, Larpin C, Buetti N, Quintard H, et al. Hypophosphatemia on ICU admission is associated with an increased length of stay in the ICU and time under mechanical ventilation. J Clin Med. 2022;11:581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm11030581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35160032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8836766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theerawit P, Eksombatchai D, Sutherasan Y, Suwatanapongched T, Kiatboonsri C, Kiatboonsri S. Diaphragmatic parameters by ultrasonography for predicting weaning outcomes. BMC Pulm Med. 2018;18:175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-018-0739-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30470204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6251135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J, Zhang X, Song J. Predictive power of extubation failure diagnosed by cough strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2021;25:357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-021-03781-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34641973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8513306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Liu Y, Xu D, Dong R, Song Y. Diaphragmatic dynamics assessed by bedside ultrasound predict extubation in the intensive care unit: a prospective observational study. Int J Gen Med. 2024;17:5373&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.2147/IJGM.S487999 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S487999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39582920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11584334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>