<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41514340</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of concurrent training order on cardiorespiratory fitness, glucose tolerance, and obesity indices in type 2 diabetic patients: randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>69</StartPage><MedlinePgn>69</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">69</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01528-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Type 2 diabetes (T2DM) is linked to impaired metabolic and cardiovascular health, and concurrent exercise is a key intervention to enhance these outcomes. However, the effect of exercise sequence on these outcomes remains unclear. This study aimed to examine the effects of 12 weeks of concurrent training, performed in different sequences of aerobic and resistance exercise, on VO&#x2082; Peak, glucose tolerance area under the curve (GT AUC), waist-to-hip ratio (WHR), and body mass index (BMI) in patients with T2DM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomized controlled trial, participants were allocated to Concurrent Aerobic-Resistance Training (CART&#x2009;=&#x2009;13), Concurrent Resistance-Aerobic Training (CRAT&#x2009;=&#x2009;13), or a control group (COG&#x2009;=&#x2009;13). Training was conducted three times per week for 12 weeks. VO&#x2082; Peak, GT AUC, WHR, and BMI were measured pre- and post-intervention. Data were analyzed using a mixed-model ANOVA to assess Group &#xd7; Time interactions, followed, when significant, by Bonferroni-adjusted post hoc pairwise comparisons across groups to identify differences in intervention-related changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both CART and CRAT significantly improved VO&#x2082; Peak, GT AUC, WHR, and BMI compared to the control group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). VO&#x2082; Peak increased by 2.999 mL/kg/min in CART and 2.147 mL/kg/min in CRAT, while GT AUC decreased by 23.01 and 24.22 units, respectively, reflecting enhanced cardiovascular fitness and glucose tolerance. WHR decreased by 0.106 in CART and 0.095 in CRAT, whereas BMI reduction was greater in CART (2.76&#xa0;kg/m&#xb2;) than in CRAT (1.48&#xa0;kg/m&#xb2;), suggesting a potential effect of exercise sequence on obesity indices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Twelve weeks of concurrent training effectively enhanced cardiovascular fitness, glycemic control, and obesity indices in T2DM patients. While both exercise sequences provided benefits, performing aerobic exercise before resistance training may maximize BMI reduction, whereas improvements in VO&#x2082; Peak, reduction in WHR, and glucose tolerance occur regardless of exercise order. These findings support adopting flexible, evidence-based concurrent training programs for metabolic and cardiovascular health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">02 September 2025, Registration no: PACTR202509591505325.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amare</LastName><ForeName>Friew</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Physical Education, College of Education and Language Studies, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. firewa6070@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiflu</LastName><ForeName>Alemmebrat</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Physical Education, College of Education and Language Studies, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taddese</LastName><ForeName>Aschenaki</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Physical Education, College of Education and Language Studies, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise sequence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose tolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VO&#x2082; peak</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The protocol was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Addis Ababa University, College of Natural and Computational Sciences, and by the Institutional Review Board of Debre Markos University, Sport Science Academy (Reference No. SpScAc.IRC/03/2025). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants before study enrolment. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41514340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01528-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01528-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hameed I, et al. Type 2 diabetes mellitus: from a metabolic disorder to an inflammatory condition. World J Diabetes. 2015;6(4):598&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v6.i4.598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4434080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25987957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite SAO, et al. Low cardiorespiratory fitness in people at risk for type 2 diabetes: early marker for insulin resistance. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2009;1(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-5996-1-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19825145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaccardi F, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness and risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: A 23-year cohort study and a meta-analysis of prospective studies. Atherosclerosis. 2015;243(1):131&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2015.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26386209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtanen KA, et al. Increased fat mass compensates for insulin resistance in abdominal obesity and type 2 diabetes: A Positron-Emitting tomography study. Diabetes. 2005;54(9):2720&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.54.9.2720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucha-L&#xf3;pez MO et al. Anthropometric Measurements, metabolic profile, and physical fitness in a sample of Spanish women with type 2 diabetes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(22).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi JH, Shin MS, Lee BJ. Association of type 2 diabetes with anthropometrics, bone mineral density, and body composition in a large-scale screening study of Korean adults. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(7):e0220077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6656355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31339947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadasseril JC, Joseph T. Diabetes &#x2013; A Silent Killer: A Threat for Cardiorespiratory Fitness, in Cardiorespiratory Fitness - New Topics, H. S&#xf6;zen, Editor. IntechOpen: London; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iaccarino G, et al. Modulation of insulin sensitivity by exercise training: implications for cardiovascular prevention. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2021;14(2):256&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12265-020-10057-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8043859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kwon O. Nutrition and exercise: cornerstones of health with emphasis on obesity and type 2 diabetes management-A narrative review. Obes Rev. 2024;25(8):e13762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38715378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartee GD. Mechanisms for greater insulin-stimulated glucose uptake in normal and insulin-resistant skeletal muscle after acute exercise. Am J Physiology-Endocrinology Metabolism. 2015;309(12):E949&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00416.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4816200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talanian JL, et al. Two weeks of high-intensity aerobic interval training increases the capacity for fat oxidation during exercise in women. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102(4):1439&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01098.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17170203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuiman P, Hopman MTE, Mensink M. Glycogen availability and skeletal muscle adaptations with endurance and resistance exercise. Nutr Metabolism. 2015;12(1):59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-015-0055-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4687103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26697098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Heijden GJ, et al. Strength exercise improves muscle mass and hepatic insulin sensitivity in obese youth. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(11):1973&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181df16d9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Loenneke JP. Interpreting adaptation to concurrent compared with Single-Mode exercise training: some methodological considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48(2):289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0812-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, et al. Concurrent exercise incorporating high-intensity interval or continuous training modulates mTORC1 signaling and MicroRNA expression in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiology-Regulatory Integr Comp Physiol. 2016;310(11):R1297&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00479.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27101297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apr&#xf3; W, et al. Resistance exercise-induced S6K1 kinase activity is not inhibited in human skeletal muscle despite prior activation of AMPK by high-intensity interval cycling. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;308(6):E470&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00486.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25605643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Kneffel Z, Thalib L. The physiological effects of concurrent strength and endurance training sequence: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(11):1212&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1364405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28783467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikestad V, Dalen T. Effect of strength and endurance training sequence on endurance performance. Sports (Basel). 2024;12(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11359207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39195602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Deakin GB, Bentley DJ. Implications of impaired endurance performance following single bouts of resistance training: an alternate concurrent training perspective. Sports Med. 2017;47(11):2187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0758-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldhoon-Hainerov&#xe1; I, Hainer V, Zamrazilov&#xe1; H. Impact of dietary intake, lifestyle and biochemical factors on metabolic health in obese adolescents. Nutr Metabolism Cardiovasc Dis. 2017;27(8):703&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2017.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28693964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki S et al. Impact of Concurrent Exercise Training on Cardiac Autonomic Modulation, Metabolic Profile, Body Composition, Cardiorespiratory Fitness, and Quality of Life in Type 2 Diabetes with Cardiac Autonomic Neuropathy: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Clin Med. 2024;13(13).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11242881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38999476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, et al. ACSM&#x2019;s new preparticipation health screening recommendations from acsm&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription, ninth edition. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013;12(4):215&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31829a68cf</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verg&#xe8;s B, et al. Effects of cardiac rehabilitation on exercise capacity in type 2 diabetic patients with coronary artery disease. Diabet Med. 2004;21(8):889&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-5491.2004.01262.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15270793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, et al. Exercise standards for testing and training: a scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation. 2013;128(8):873&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0b013e31829b5b44</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabe H, et al. Predicting a target exercise heart rate that reflects the anaerobic threshold in nonbeta-blocked Hemodialysis patients: the Karvonen and heart rate reserve formulas. Ther Apher Dial. 2021;25(6):884&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1744-9987.13628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33511760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyth E, Basit H, Swift CJ. Glucose tolerance test. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassine HN, et al. Effects of exercise and caloric restriction on insulin resistance and cardiometabolic risk factors in older obese adults&#x2014;a randomized clinical trial. Journals Gerontol Ser A: Biomedical Sci Med Sci. 2009;64(1):90&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gln032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2691195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MS, et al. Malnutrition, anthropometric, and biochemical abnormalities in patients with diabetic nephropathy. J Ren Nutr. 2009;19(4):275&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jrn.2009.01.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, et al. Joint effects of physical Activity, body mass Index, waist Circumference, and waist-to-Hip ratio on the risk of heart failure. Circulation. 2010;121(2):237&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.887893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredella MA, et al. Anthropometry, CT, and DXA as predictors of GH deficiency in premenopausal women: ROC curve analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2009;106(2):418&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90998.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2644238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield DC, et al. Limits of body mass index to detect obesity and predict body composition. Nutrition. 2001;17(1):26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0899-9007(00)00471-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11165884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson RS, Ferguson EL. An interactive 24-hour recall for assessing the adequacy of iron and zinc intakes in developing countries. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanton CA, et al. The USDA automated Multiple-Pass method accurately estimates group total energy and nutrient intake. J Nutr. 2006;136(10):2594&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/136.10.2594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttriss JL, et al. Public health nutrition. Wiley; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baranowski T. 24-hour recall and diet record methods. Nutritional Epidemiol. 2012;40:49&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199754038.003.0004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EHNRI F. Food composition table for use in Ethiopia part IV. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: Ethiopian Health and Nutrition Research Institute; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EHNRI. Food composition table for use in Ethiopia part III.1968&#x2013;1997. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: Ethiopian nutrition Institute EHNRI; 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feyesa I, et al. Development and validation of food frequency questionnaire for food and nutrient intake of adults in Butajira. Southern Ethiopia: Research Square; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8635871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength Testing&#x2014;Predicting a One-Rep max from Reps-to-Fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreation Dance. 1993;64:88&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdul-Hameed U, et al. Reliability of 1-repetition maximum Estimation for upper and lower body muscular strength measurement in untrained middle aged type 2 diabetic patients. Asian J Sports Med. 2012;3(4):267&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.34549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3525823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23342225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara JM, Stearne DJ. Effect of concurrent Training, flexible nonlinear Periodization, and Maximal-Effort cycling on strength and power. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2013;27:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318274f343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23037617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM&#x2019;s. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Lippincott williams &amp; wilkins; 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Vicente A et al. Validity of the Polar H7 heart rate sensor for heart rate variability analysis during exercise in different Age, body composition and fitness level groups. Sens (Basel). 2021;21(3).1165&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopewell S, et al. CONSORT 2025 statement: updated guideline for reporting randomized trials. Nat Med. 2025;31(6):1776&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-025-03635-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40229553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on hemoglobin A1c levels in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2010;304(20):2253&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, et al. Aerobic and resistance exercise sequence affects excess postexercise oxygen consumption. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(2):332&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nystoriak MA, Bhatnagar A. Cardiovascular effects and benefits of exercise. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2018;5:135. 10.3389/fcvm.2018.00135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2018.00135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6172294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30324108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to endurance and strength training. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Yu L. Effects of concurrent training sequence on VO2max and lower limb strength performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2023;14&#x2013;2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9908959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36776981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Hargreaves M. Exercise, GLUT4, and skeletal muscle glucose uptake. Physiol Rev. 2013;93(3):993&#x2013;1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00038.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajpeyi S, et al. Effect of an acute long-duration exercise bout on skeletal muscle lipid droplet morphology, GLUT 4 protein, and perilipin protein expression. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123(12):2771&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05266-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11801175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37368137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBrasseur NK, Walsh K, Arany Z. Metabolic benefits of resistance training and fast glycolytic skeletal muscle. Am J Physiology-Endocrinology Metabolism. 2010;300(1):E3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00512.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stotzer US, et al. Benefits of resistance training on body composition and glucose clearance are inhibited by long-term low carbohydrate diet in rats. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(12):e0207951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0207951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6286018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30532163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, et al. Comprehensive assessment of the effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on lipid profile, glycemic control, and insulin resistance in type 2 diabetes: A meta-analysis. Med (Baltim). 2024;103(12):e37494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000037494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10957025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38517995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amare F, et al. Effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise training on body fat and glucolipid metabolism in inactive middle-aged adults with overweight or obesity: a randomized trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabilitation. 2024;16(1):189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00982-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11389517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39261968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ et al. Effect of a 12-Week concurrent training intervention on cardiometabolic health in obese men: A pilot study. Front Physiol. 2021;12&#x2013;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Neubeck L, Gallagher R. Measurement matters: A systematic review of waist measurement sites for determining central adiposity. Collegian. 2017;24(5):513&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colegn.2016.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki S, et al. Impact of concurrent training sequence on heart rate variability, glycemic control, body composition, lipid profile, and cardiorespiratory fitness in type 2 diabetes patients with cardiac autonomic neuropathy: A randomized controlled trial. Clin Epidemiol Global Health. 2024;29:101747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cegh.2024.101747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorakis N et al. Beyond calories: individual metabolic and hormonal adaptations driving variability in weight Management-A State-of-the-Art narrative review. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(24).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11676201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39769203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Ratamess N. Which comes first? Resistance before aerobic exercise or vice versa? ACSM&#x2019;s Health Fit J. 2014;18(1):9&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, et al. Effects of intra-session exercise sequence during water-based concurrent training. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(01):41&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohm TV, et al. Inflammation in obesity, diabetes, and related disorders. Immunity. 2022;55(1):31&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2021.12.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35021057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>