<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41837742</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Informing Fitness Testing Data Reporting and Visualization in Elite Soccer: A Survey Into Practitioner Preferences and Needs.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005355</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Asimakidis, ND, Beato, M, Parmar, N, Weldon, A, Bishop, C, and Turner, AN. Informing fitness testing data reporting and visualization in elite soccer: A survey into practitioner preferences and needs. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-This cross-sectional survey explored elite soccer practitioners' fitness testing reporting and visualization preferences. Overall, 145 soccer practitioners completed an online survey comprising 27 questions, with 3 sections: (a) background information, (b) preferences for fitness testing report content and insights, and (c) preferences and interpretation of data visualization formats. Fixed-response questions were analyzed using frequency analysis, while thematic analysis was applied to open-ended questions to generate key themes. Subjects predominantly valued tracking changes (91%) in performance over benchmark (61%) or position-specific (58%) comparisons. Although 44.8% prioritized individual performance, 42.1% emphasized both individual and team-level insights. Concerning the presentation of data, raw scores were the preferred format (62.1%), followed by standardized (37.2%) and composite scores (23.5%), depending on the context. Subjects highly valued interactive dashboards (91%), quadrant charts (87.6%), and traffic light systems (77.2%). Bar charts (77.2%) were the preferred visual format for interplayer comparisons, valued for their clarity, and reduced cognitive load, while line charts (51.7%) were favored for tracking performance over time, due to their simplicity and user familiarity. Radar charts (59.3%) were the preferred format for comparing individual performances to the wider team, valued for their ability to provide a holistic overview of strengths and weaknesses. Uncertainty indicators were endorsed by 52.3%, primarily for enhancing data interpretation and decision making, although concerns were raised about their ease of understanding and visual clutter. Practitioners can use this study's findings to inform user-friendly reporting strategies and meet diverse audience needs. Findings should also support practitioner training and the adoption of evolving industry practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asimakidis</LastName><ForeName>Nikolaos D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance Department, Ipswich Town Football Club, Ipswich, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beato</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Sports Sciences, University of Suffolk, Ipswich, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Biomedicine and Movement, University of Verona, Verona, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parmar</LastName><ForeName>Nimai</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weldon</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Life and Sport Sciences, Birmingham City University, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aston Villa Foundation, Aston Villa Football Club, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Anthony N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">data analytics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survey study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visual analytics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41837742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Armitage M, McErlain-Naylor SA, Devereux G, et al. On-field rehabilitation in football: Current practice and perceptions. A survey of the English Premier League and Football League. Sci Med Footb 9: 130&#x2013;139, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asimakidis ND, Bishop CJ, Beato M, et al. A survey into the current fitness testing practices of elite male soccer practitioners: From assessment to communicating results. Front Physiol 15: 1376047, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Madsen EE, Clubb J, Emmonds S, Krustrup P. Monitoring readiness to train and perform in female football: Current evidence and recommendations for practitioners. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 19: 223&#x2013;231, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birch J. Worldwide prevalence of red-green color deficiency. J Opt Soc Am A 29: 313&#x2013;320, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley PS. Setting the Benchmark&#x2019; part 1: The contextualised physical demands of positional roles in the FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022. Biol Sport 41: 261&#x2013;270, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol 3: 77&#x2013;101, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Reflecting on reflexive thematic analysis. Qual Res Sport Exerc Health 11: 589&#x2013;597, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Want to see my report, coach? Aspetar Sports Med J 6: 36&#x2013;42, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo L, Christel I, Terrado M, Cucchietti F, P&#xe9;rez-Montoro M. Users' cognitive load: A key aspect to successfully communicate visual climate information. Bull Am Meteorol Soc 103: 1&#x2013;16, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson L, Beato M, Devereux G, McErlain-Naylor SA. A review of the validity and reliability of accelerometer-based metrics from upper back&#x2013;mounted GNSS player tracking systems for athlete training load monitoring. J Strength Cond Res 38: 459&#x2013;474, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dello Iacono A, Datson N, Clubb J, Lacome M, Sullivan A, Shushan T. Data analytics practices and reporting strategies in senior football: Insights into athlete health and performance from over 200 practitioners worldwide. Sci Med Footb 1&#x2013;16: 1&#x2013;16, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exel J, Dabnichki P. Precision sports science: What is next for data analytics for athlete performance and well-being optimization?. Appl Sci 14: 3361, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franconeri SL, Padilla LM, Shah P, Zacks JM, Hullman J. The science of visual data communication: What works. Psychol Sci Public Interest 22: 110&#x2013;161, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall ECR, John G, Ahmetov II. Testing in football: A narrative review. Sports 12: 307, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harry JR, Hurwitz J, Agnew C, Bishop C. Statistical tests for sports science practitioners: Identifying performance gains in individual athletes. J Strength Cond Res 38: 264&#x2013;272, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leduc C, Weaving D. Invisible monitoring for athlete health and performance: A call for a better conceptualization and practical recommendations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 20: 880&#x2013;884, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lolli L, Bauer P, Irving C, et al. Data analytics in the football industry: A survey investigating operational frameworks and practices in professional clubs and national federations from around the world. Sci Med Footb 9: 189&#x2013;198, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco IT, Freitas TT, Alcaraz P, et al. Practices of strength and conditioning coaches in Brazilian elite soccer. Biol Sport 39: 779&#x2013;791, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan M. Administration, scoring, and interpretation of selected tests. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. (G. Gregory Haff, N. Travis Triplett, editors;&#xa0; 4th eds9). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2016. pp. 259&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Lake JP, Comfort P. Identifying and reporting position-specific countermovement jump outcome and phase characteristics within rugby league. PLoS One 17: e0265999, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson S, Bartlett JD, Gastin PB. Red, amber, or green? Athlete monitoring in team sport: The need for decision-support systems. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: S273&#x2013;S279, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson S, Kremer P, Aisbett B, Tran J, Cerin E. Consensus on measurement properties and feasibility of performance tests for the exercise and sport sciences: A Delphi study. Sports Med Open 3: 2, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwabish J. The practice of visual data communication: What works. Psychol Sci Public Interest 22: 97&#x2013;109, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Norris D, McLaren SJ, et al. A worldwide survey on the practices and perceptions of submaximal fitness tests in team sports. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 18: 765&#x2013;779, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Buchheit M, Hader K, Sarmento H, Afonso J. Building bridges instead of putting up walls: Connecting the &#x201c;Teams&#x201d; to improve soccer players' support. Sports Med 53: 2309&#x2013;2320, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JM, Madden JL, Cunningham LP, Wright M. Fitness testing in soccer revisited: Developing a contemporary testing battery. Strength Cond J 44: 10&#x2013;21, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Delaney JA, Duthie GM, Dascombe BJ. Developing athlete monitoring systems in team sports: Data analysis and visualization. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 698&#x2013;705, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Curtis RM. Building the foundations for information communication in sports science and its use in decision making. Strength Cond J 46: 74&#x2013;81, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner A. But did my athlete improve? Assessing performance changes when N = 1. Prof Strength Cond: 27&#x2013;31, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AN, Jones B, Stewart P, et al. Total score of athleticism: Holistic athlete profiling to enhance decision-making. Strength Cond J 41: 91&#x2013;101, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AN, Parmar N, Jovanovski A, Hearne G. Assessing group-based changes in high-performance sport. Part 2: Effect sizes and embracing uncertainty through confidence intervals. Strength Cond J 43: 68&#x2013;77, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward P, Coutts AJ, Pruna R, McCall A. Putting the &#x201c;I&#x201d; back in team. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 1107&#x2013;1111, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Black G, McLaren S, et al. Testing and profiling athletes: Recommendations for test selection, implementation, and maximizing information. Strength Cond J 46: 159&#x2013;179, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissgerber TL, Milic NM, Winham SJ, Garovic VD. Beyond bar and line graphs: Time for a new data presentation paradigm. PLoS Biol 13: e1002128, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldon A, Duncan MJ, Turner A, et al. Contemporary practices of strength and conditioning coaches in professional soccer. Biol Sport 38: 377&#x2013;390, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windt J, Taylor D, Little D, Sporer BC. Making everyone's job easier. How do data scientists fit as a critical member of integrated support teams?. Br J Sports Med 55: 73&#x2013;75, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>