<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41733058</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative effectiveness of neuromuscular, virtual reality, proprioceptive, blood flow restriction and conventional training after ACL reconstruction: A network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70345</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Quadriceps atrophy and post-operative pain are common following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) and can hinder functional recovery. This study aimed to systematically compare the effectiveness of neuromuscular training (NMT), virtual reality training (VRT), proprioceptive training (PT), blood flow restriction training (BFRT) and conventional rehabilitation training (CRT) in individuals undergoing rehabilitation after ACLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review and network meta-analysis (NMA) were conducted in accordance with PRISMA-NMA guidelines. Six databases (PubMed, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, Web of Science, CNKI and Wanfang) were searched for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) published up to 1 May 2025. Risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2.0 tool. A frequentist NMA was performed in Stata 17.0MP to estimate standardized mean differences (SMDs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs). Interventions were ranked using surface under the cumulative ranking curve (SUCRA) values. The certainty of evidence was appraised using the CINeMA framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-two RCTs involving 972 participants (mean age 23-39 years) were included. Compared with CRT, VRT showed favourable outcomes in visual analogue scale for pain (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.72, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[-1.22 to -0.22], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;86.5%), functional hop tests (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.26, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.46-2.05], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;97.5%) and isokinetic muscle strength (60&#xb0;/s) (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.24, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[1.28-3.20], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;99.6%). BFRT also outperformed CRT in several outcomes, including the International Knee Documentation Committee Subjective Knee Evaluation Form (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.37, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.77-1.96], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;81.8%), Lysholm Score (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.07, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.16-1.97], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;74.7%) and knee range of motion (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.42, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.80-2.04], SUCRA&#x2009;=&#x2009;99.1%), with relatively high SUCRA values. Compared with CRT, NMT demonstrated modest improvements in the Functional Hop Tests (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.29) and the Lysholm Score (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.00). Certainty of evidence ranged from moderate to low, primarily due to imprecision and risk of bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">VRT and BFRT may offer benefits across several domains of post-operative rehabilitation following ACLR, with NMT also showing potential. However, given the limitations in evidence certainty, further high-quality RCTs are warranted to confirm these findings and inform clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level I.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Binshan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-9278-7297</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1727-7667</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lianxu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Beijing Tsinghua Changgung Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Baosen</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Anqi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Shaojie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NWNU-SKON2023-17</GrantID><Agency>Northwest Normal University Young Faculty Research Capacity Enhancement Key Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virtual reality training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41733058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Andernord D, Desai N, Bj&#xf6;rnsson H, Ylander M, Karlsson J, Samuelsson K. Patient predictors of early revision surgery after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cohort study of 16,930 patients with 2&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:121&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bade MJ, Kohrt WM, Stevens&#x2010;Lapsley JE. Outcomes before and after total knee arthroplasty compared to healthy adults. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40:559&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard DJ, Davies L, Cook JA, Stokes J, Leal J, Fletcher H, et al. Rehabilitation versus surgical reconstruction for non&#x2010;acute anterior cruciate ligament injury (ACL SNNAP): a pragmatic randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2022;400:605&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard DJ, Dodd CA, Trundle HR, Simpson AH. Proprioception enhancement for anterior cruciate ligament deficiency. A prospective randomised trial of two physiotherapy regimes. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1994;76:654&#x2013;659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49:95&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cognetti DJ, Sheean AJ, Owens JG. Blood flow restriction therapy and its use for rehabilitation and return to sport: physiology, application, and guidelines for implementation. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:e71&#x2013;e76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cort&#xe9;s&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez I, Desdentado&#x2010;Guillem JM, Camacho&#x2010;Delgado MS, del Roc&#xed;o Ibancos&#x2010;Losada M, Obrero&#x2010;Gait&#xe1;n E, Lomas&#x2010;Vega R. Virtual reality&#x2010;based therapy after anterior cruciate ligament injury effectively reduces pain and improves knee function, movement patterns, and dynamic balance: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1736&#x2013;1753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran MT, Bedi A, Mendias CL, Wojtys EM, Kujawa MV, Palmieri&#x2010;Smith RM. Blood flow restriction training applied with high&#x2010;intensity exercise does not improve quadriceps muscle function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:825&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrosi R, Hewett TE. Validity of material related to the anterior cruciate ligament on TikTok. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12:23259671241228543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'ambrosi R, Milinkovic DD, Abermann E, Herbort M, Fink C. Quality of YouTube videos regarding anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using quadriceps tendon autograft is unsatisfactory. Arthroscopy. 2024;40:2236&#x2013;2243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Melo RFV, Komatsu WR, De Freitas MS, De Melo MEV, Cohen M. Comparison of quadriceps and hamstring muscle strength after exercises with and without blood flow restriction following anterior cruciate ligament surgery: a randomized controlled trial. J Rehabil Med. 2022;54:2550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePhillipo NN, Kennedy MI, Aman ZS, Bernhardson AS, O'Brien LT, LaPrade RF. The role of blood flow restriction therapy following knee surgery: expert opinion. Arthroscopy. 2018;34:2506&#x2013;2510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diermeier TA, Rothrauff BB, Engebretsen L, Lynch A, Svantesson E, Senorski EAH, et al. Treatment after ACL injury: panther symposium ACL treatment consensus group. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:14&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldridge S, Campbell M, Campbell M, Dahota A, Giraudeau B, Higgins J, et al. Revised Cochrane risk of bias tool for randomized trials (RoB 2.0): additional considerations for cluster&#x2010;randomized trials [Internet]. 2016 Oct 20 [cited 2025 Jun 28]. Available from: http://sites.google.com/site/riskofbiastool/welcome/rob-2-0-tool</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz RB, Gualano B, Rodrigues R, Kurimori CO, Fuller R, Lima FR, et al. Benefits of resistance training with blood flow restriction in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:897&#x2013;905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frobell RB, Roos EM, Roos HP, Ranstam J, Lohmander LS. A randomized trial of treatment for acute anterior cruciate ligament tears. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:331&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frobell RB, Roos HP, Roos EM, Roemer FW, Ranstam J, Lohmander LS. Treatment for acute anterior cruciate ligament tear: five year outcome of randomised trial. BMJ. 2013;346:f232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galimberti C, Ignazi S, Vercesi P, Riva G. Characteristics of interaction and cooperation in immersive and non&#x2010;immersive virtual environments. In: Riva G, Galimberti C, editors. Towards cyberpsychology: mind, cognition and society in the Internet age. Amsterdam: IOS Press; 2001. p. 129&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber JP, Marcus RL, Dibble LE, LaStayo PC. The use of eccentrically biased resistance exercise to mitigate muscle impairments following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a short review. Sports Health. 2009;1:31&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles L, Webster KE, McClelland J, Cook JL. Quadriceps strengthening with and without blood flow restriction in the treatment of patellofemoral pain: a double&#x2010;blind randomised trial. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1688&#x2013;1694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordano L, Maffulli N, Carimati G, Morenghi E, Volpi P. Increased time to surgery after anterior cruciate ligament tear in female patients results in greater risk of medial meniscus tear: a study of 489 female patients. Arthroscopy. 2023;39:613&#x2013;622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Bisschop M, Myer GD, Benjaminse A, Dijkstra PU, Van Keeken HG, et al. Immersive virtual reality improves movement patterns in patients after ACL reconstruction: implications for enhanced criteria&#x2010;based return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport rehabilitation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24:2280&#x2013;2286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinatth V, Garcia JR, Reid IK, Knapik DM, Verma NN, Chahla J. Blood flow restriction enhances recovery after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthroscopy. 2025;41:1048&#x2013;1060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gsangaya MR, Htwe O, Naicker AS, Yusoff BAHM, Mohammad N, Soh EZF, et al. Comparison between the effect of immersive virtual reality training versus conventional rehabilitation on limb loading and functional outcomes in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective randomized controlled trial. Asia Pac J Sports Med Arthrosc Rehabil Technol. 2023;34:28&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JD, Abrams GD, Bach BR, Williams D, Heidloff D, Bush&#x2010;Joseph CA, et al. Return to sport after ACL reconstruction. Orthopedics. 2014;37:e103&#x2013;e108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson A, Korner&#x2010;Bitensky N, Levin M. Virtual reality in stroke rehabilitation: a systematic review of its effectiveness for upper limb motor recovery. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2007;14:52&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Rosenblatt B, Haddad F, Gissane C, McCarthy D, Clarke T, et al. Comparing the effectiveness of blood flow restriction and traditional heavy load resistance training in the post&#x2010;surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: a UK national health service randomised controlled trial. Sports Med. 2019;49:1787&#x2013;1805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta&#x2010;analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:777&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack RA, Lambert BS, Hedt CA, Delgado D, Goble H, McCulloch PC. Blood flow restriction therapy preserves lower extremity bone and muscle mass after ACL reconstruction. Sports Health. 2023;15:361&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin T, Li Y. The effect of combined virtual reality balance training and movement training on patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. J Pract Orthop. 2022;28:659&#x2013;663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung W&#x2010;S, Kim S&#x2010;H, Nam S&#x2010;S, Kim J&#x2010;W, Moon H&#x2010;W. Effects of rehabilitation exercise with blood flow restriction after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Appl Sci. 2022;12:12058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Drobni&#x10d; M, Mar&#x161; T, Mi&#x161; K, Petri&#x10d; M, Weber D, et al. Functional and molecular adaptations of quadriceps and hamstring muscles to blood flow restricted training in patients with ACL rupture. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1636&#x2013;1646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimijashni M, Sarvestani FK, Yoosefinejad AK. The effect of contralateral knee neuromuscular exercises on static and dynamic balance, knee function, and pain in athletes who underwent anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a single&#x2010;blind randomized controlled trial. J Sport Rehabil. 2023;32:524&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya D, Guney&#x2010;Deniz H, Sayaca C, Calik M, Doral MN. Effects on lower extremity neuromuscular control exercises on knee proprioception, muscle strength, and functional level in patients with ACL reconstruction. BioMed Res Int. 2019;2019:1694695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil A, Fayaz N, Fawzy E, Mohamed N, Waly A, Mohammed M. Influence of blood flow restriction training on knee pain after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a double blinded randomized controlled trial. J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol. 2023;30:e30&#x2013;e38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani S, Rezaei I, Abasi S, Zakerabasali S, Yazdani A. Technical aspects of virtual augmented reality&#x2010;based rehabilitation systems for musculoskeletal disorders of the lower limbs: a systematic review. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023;24:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, Barbosa O, Maree D, Pantouveris M, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:500&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal AF, da Silva TD, Lopes PB, Bahadori S, de Ara&#xfa;jo LV, da Costa MVB, et al. The use of a task through virtual reality in cerebral palsy using two different interaction devices (concrete and abstract)&#x2014;a cross&#x2010;sectional randomized study. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2020;17:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Li J, Wang C, Fan Z, Xie S. The effect of virtual reality balance training on knee joint function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. J Pract Clin Med. 2022;26:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Li J, Qing L, Wang H, Ma H, Huang P. Effect of quadriceps training at different levels of blood flow restriction on quadriceps strength and thickness in the mid&#x2010;term postoperative period after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled external pilot study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023;24:360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Xiao F, Ren H, Peng Y, Feng F, Dong Q. The effects of blood flow restriction training on early muscle strength and mid&#x2010;term knee function following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2025;20:273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Peng J, Cao J, Ou Y, Wu J, Ma W, et al. Effectiveness of virtual reality technology in rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. PLoS One. 2025;20:e0314766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi C, Chacon&#x2010;Mikahil M, Cavaglieri C, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Vechin F, et al. Effect of concurrent training with blood flow restriction in the elderly. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36:395&#x2013;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Gu X, Fu J, Yao Y, Wu H, Li H, et al. The effect of lower limb rehabilitation robots combined with virtual reality training on walking ability after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. West China Med. 2022;37:717&#x2013;721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu&#x2010;Ambrose T, Taunton J, MacIntyre D, McConkey P, Khan K. The effects of proprioceptive or strength training on the neuromuscular function of the ACL reconstructed knee: a randomized clinical trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13:115&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobb R, Tumilty S, Claydon LS. A review of systematic reviews on anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13:270&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Zhang D, Zhao T, Liu X, Wang J, Zheng H, et al. The effects of proprioceptive training on anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2021;35:506&#x2013;521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N, King J. Anterior cruciate ligament injury. Br J Sports Med. 1998;32:266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mall NA, Chalmers PN, Moric M, Tanaka MJ, Cole BJ, Bach Jr, BR, et al. Incidence and trends of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the United States. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2363&#x2013;2370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Mouser JG, Dankel SJ, Buckner SL, Bell ZW, et al. The application of blood flow restriction: lessons from the laboratory. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2018;17:129&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meredith SJ, Rauer T, Chmielewski TL, Fink C, Diermeier T, Rothrauff BB, et al. Return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament injury: Panther Symposium ACL Injury Return to Sport Consensus Group. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8:2325967120930829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouarbes D, Menetrey J, Marot V, Courtot L, Berard E, Cavaignac E. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of outcomes for quadriceps tendon autograft versus bone&#x2013;patellar tendon&#x2013;bone and hamstring&#x2010;tendon autografts. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47:3531&#x2013;3540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederer D, Keller M, Sch&#xfc;ttler K&#x2010;F, Schoepp C, Petersen W, Best R, et al. Late&#x2010;stage rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a multicentre randomised controlled trial (PReP). Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2024;67:101827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, Nygaard T, Hvid LG, Wernbom M, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low&#x2010;load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol. 2012;590:4351&#x2013;4361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta H, Kurosawa H, Ikeda H, Iwase Y, Satou N, Nakamura S. Low&#x2010;load resistance muscular training with moderate restriction of blood flow after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Acta Orthop Scand. 2003;74:62&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;iestad BE, Holm I, Aune AK, Gunderson R, Myklebust G, Engebretsen L, et al. Knee function and prevalence of knee osteoarthritis after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective study with 10 to 15 years of follow&#x2010;up. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:2201&#x2013;2210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onate J, Herman D, Grooms D, Sutton Z, Wilkerson G. Neuroscience principles for ACL rehabilitation and reinjury risk reduction. In: Noyes FR, Barber&#x2010;Westin S, editors. Return to sport after ACL reconstruction and other knee operations: limiting the risk of reinjury and maximizing athletic performance. Cham: Springer; 2019. p. 359&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios&#x2010;Navarro G, Hogan N. Head&#x2010;mounted display&#x2010;based therapies for adults post&#x2010;stroke: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sensors. 2021;21:1111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, Burr J, Scott BR, Owens J, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10:533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, H&#xe4;ner M, Guenther D, Lutz P, Imhoff A, Herbort M, et al. Management after acute injury of the anterior cruciate ligament (ACL), part 2: management of the ACL&#x2010;injured patient. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:1675&#x2013;1689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan I, Carrion&#x2010;Plaza A, Furness PJ, Dimitri P. Home&#x2010;based immersive virtual reality physical rehabilitation in paediatric patients for upper limb motor impairment: a feasibility study. Virtual Real. 2023;27:3505&#x2013;3520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piedade SR, Arruda BPL, de Vasconcelos RA, Parker DA, Maffulli N. Rehabilitation following surgical reconstruction for anterior cruciate ligament insufficiency: what has changed since the 1960s?&#x2014;state of the art. J ISAKOS. 2023;8:153&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Karlsson J, Ayeni OR, Becker R. Author guidelines for conducting systematic reviews and meta&#x2010;analyses. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29:2739&#x2013;2744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Krolikowska A, de Girolamo L, Becker R, Karlsson J. Checklists, risk of bias tools, and reporting guidelines for research in orthopedics, sports medicine, and rehabilitation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:3029&#x2013;3033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renstr&#xf6;m PA. Eight clinical conundrums relating to anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury in sport: recent evidence and a personal reflection. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47:367&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risberg MA, Holm I, Myklebust G, Engebretsen L. Neuromuscular training versus strength training during first 6 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized clinical trial. Phys Ther. 2007;87:737&#x2013;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph KS, Axe MJ, Buchanan TS, Scholz JP, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L. Dynamic stability in the anterior cruciate ligament deficient knee. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2001;9:62&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt S, Krahl D, Podszun J, Knecht S, Zimmerer A, Sobau C, et al. Combining a digital health application with standard care significantly enhances rehabilitation outcomes for ACL surgery patients. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1241&#x2013;1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Pan W, Li L, Zeng M, Chen Y. Observation on the effect of immersive virtual reality training on lower limb motor function rehabilitation in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Zhejiang Med. 2021;43:1208&#x2013;1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiyu S, Zhixia L. Application of virtual reality technology in postoperative rehabilitation following total knee arthroplasty: a scoping review. Int J Orthop Trauma Nurs. 2024;54:101124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: a systematic review &amp; meta&#x2010;analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19:669&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, Senorski EH, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Prill R. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: decades of change. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1178&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Melick N, van Cingel RE, Brooijmans F, Neeter C, van Tienen T, Hullegie W, et al. Evidence&#x2010;based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1506&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Ji Z, Wang L, Zhang Q, Wang H, Qie S. The efficacy of 5 rehabilitation treatments after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a network meta&#x2010;analysis. Medicine. 2021;100:e27835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, Stanfield D, Webster KE, Myer GD. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:1861&#x2013;1876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda N, Glover EI, Phillips SM, Isfort RJ, Tarnopolsky MA. Sex&#x2010;based differences in skeletal muscle function and morphology with short&#x2010;term limb immobilization. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:1085&#x2013;1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y. The effect of neuromuscular training on the rehabilitation of athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Chin For Med. 2017;36:96&#x2013;97+100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JH, Lim BO, Ha M, Lee SW, Oh SJ, Lee YS, et al. A meta&#x2010;analysis of the effect of neuromuscular training on the prevention of the anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2010;18:824&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liao B, Chen S. Effect of neuromuscular rehabilitation training on motor function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Chin J Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;37:456&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liao B, Chen S, Liu C. The effect of neuromuscular training on the rehabilitation of athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Chin J Sports Med. 2014;33:772&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Rothrauff B, Chen L, Jin S, He S, He J. Comparison of blood flow restriction training rehabilitation and general rehabilitation exercise after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:2713&#x2013;2728.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>