<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41717199</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Practice of Integrated Volitional Control Electrical Stimulation in a Patient With Post-stroke Upper Limb Paresis and Difficulty in Thumb Opposition: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101830</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101830</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101830</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101830</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Upper limb paresis after stroke often limits functional grasp and fine manipulation, particularly owing to impaired palmar abduction and opposition of the thumb. Integrated volitional control electrical stimulation (IVES) synchronizes voluntary muscle activity with electrical stimulation and may promote motor learning and cortical reorganization. However, most applications have focused on facilitating finger extension, and approaches specifically targeting active thumb movement remain limited. This case report describes an IVES-based intervention designed to promote thumb palmar abduction during voluntary finger extension. A 40-year-old right-handed man presenting with left hemiplegia underwent outpatient occupational therapy using IVES in power-assist mode. Electrodes were placed over the extensor digitorum communis and thenar muscles to induce synchronized finger extension and thumb palmar abduction. Task-oriented training simulating motorcycle maintenance tasks was performed for 60 min, three times per week, for 10 weeks. After the intervention, upper limb motor function and activity level outcomes improved. The Fugl Meyer Assessment Upper Extremity score increased from 37 to 47 points, the Simple Test for Evaluating Hand Function score increased from 11 to 30 points, and the grip strength of the affected hand increased from 0.5 to 6.0 kg. Additionally, Motor Activity Log scores improved, and the patient reported clinically meaningful gains in bimanual motorcycle maintenance performance on the Canadian Occupational Performance Measure. This case suggests that synchronizing thumb palmar abduction with voluntary finger extension using IVES may facilitate active motor learning and functional recovery of grasp patterns requiring thumb opposition, offering an active alternative to passive assistance approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Nakamori et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamori</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Kansai University of Health Sciences, Osaka, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fugl&#x2013;meyer assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thumb opposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper-limb paresis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41717199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12914744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Recommendations for upper limb motor recovery: an overview of the UK and European rehabilitation after stroke guidelines (2023) O'Flaherty D, Ali K. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11276617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39057576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recovery of upper extremity function in stroke patients: the Copenhagen stroke study. Nakayama H, J&#xf8;rgensen HS, Raaschou HO, Olsen TS. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1994;75:394&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8172497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurorehabilitation with new functional electrical stimulation for hemiparetic upper extremity in stroke patients. Hara Y. J Nippon Med Sch. 2008;75:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18360073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortical effect and functional recovery by the electromyography-triggered neuromuscular stimulation in chronic stroke patients. Shin HK, Cho SH, Jeon HS, et al. Neurosci Lett. 2008;442:174&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18644424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of integrated volitional control electrical stimulation (IVES) on upper extremity function in chronic stroke. Yamaguchi T, Tanabe S, Muraoka Y, et al. Keio J Med. 2011;60:90&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21964036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motor improvement and corticospinal modulation induced by hybrid assistive neuromuscular dynamic stimulation (HANDS) therapy in patients with chronic stroke. Fujiwara T, Kasashima Y, Honaga K, et al. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2009;23:125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19060131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anatomy, physiology, and functional restoration of the thumb. Emerson ET, Krizek TJ, Greenwald DP. Ann Plast Surg. 1996;36:180&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8919384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constraint-induced movement therapy after injection of botulinum toxin type A for a patient with chronic stroke: one-year follow-up case report. Amano S, Takebayashi T, Hanada K, Umeji A, Marumoto K, Furukawa K, Domen K. Phys Ther. 2015;95:1039&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25592185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of a thumb web spacer splint on hand function in children with hemiplegic cerebral palsy. Ali IB, Elshazly FA, Ali MS. J Taibah Univ Med Sci. 2022;18:429&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36818181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The post-stroke hemiplegic patient. 1. A method for evaluation of physical performance. Fugl-Meyer AR, J&#xe4;&#xe4;sk&#xf6; L, Leyman I, Olsson S, Steglind S. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1135616/ Scand J Rehabil Med. 1975;7:13&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1135616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development and standardization of the hand function test. Kaneko T, Muraki T. https://da.lib.kobe-u.ac.jp/da/kernel/80070332/80070332.pdf BAMS (Kobe) 1990;6:49&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interrater reliability of a modified Ashworth scale of muscle spasticity. Bohannon RW, Smith MB. Phys Ther. 1987;67:206&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reliability and validity of the upper-extremity motor activity log-14 for measuring real-world arm use. Uswatte G, Taub E, Morris D, Vignolo M, McCulloch K. Stroke. 2005;36:2493&#x2013;2496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16224078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law MC, Carswell A, Baptiste S, McColl MA, Polatajko H, Pollock N. Canadian Occupational Performance Measure: COPM. Ottawa, Ontario: CAOT Publications ACE; 2019. Canadian Occupational Performance Measure (COPM), 5th Edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Functional evaluation: the Barthel index. Mahoney FI, Barthel D. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14258950/ Md State Med J. 1965;14:61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14258950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasch analysis staging methodology to classify upper extremity movement impairment after stroke. Woodbury ML, Velozo CA, Richards LG, Duncan PW. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94:1527&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23529144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A home-based rehabilitation program for the hemiplegic upper extremity by power-assisted functional electrical stimulation. Hara Y, Ogawa S, Tsujiuchi K, Muraoka Y. Disabil Rehabil. 2008;30:296&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of a task-oriented rehabilitation program on upper extremity recovery following motor stroke: the ICARE randomized clinical trial. Winstein CJ, Wolf SL, Dromerick AW, et al. JAMA. 2016;315:571&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26864411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of electromyography-controlled functional electrical stimulation on upper extremity function and cortical perfusion in stroke patients. Hara Y, Obayashi S, Tsujiuchi K, Muraoka Y. Clin Neurophysiol. 2013;124:2008&#x2013;2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23706813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation with functional electrical stimulation in stroke patients. Hara Y. Int J Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;1:147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of functional electrical stimulation applied to the wrist and finger muscles of hemiparetic subjects: a systematic review of the literature. Arantes NF, Vaz DV, Mancini MC, Pereira MS, Pinto FP, Pinto TP. Braz J Phys Ther. 2007;11:419&#x2013;427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of hand configuration on the grasping, holding, and placement of an instrumented object in patients with hemiparesis. Parry R, Macias Soria S, Pradat-Diehl P, Marchand-Pauvert V, Jarrass&#xe9; N, Roby-Brami A. Front Neurol. 2019;10:240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6433942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Examining minimal important change of the Canadian occupational performance measure for subacute rehabilitation hospital inpatients. Ohno K, Tomori K, Sawada T, Kobayashi R. J Patient Rep Outcomes. 2021;5:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8688664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34928482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>