<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41269443</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cross-Education of Strength: From Theory to Practice in Contemporary Sports Rehabilitation-A Narrative Review and Clinical Implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129</StartPage><MedlinePgn>129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">129</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00931-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cross-education (CE) of strength refers to strength gains in the untrained limb after unilateral resistance training. Despite the long-standing recognition of this phenomenon, its potential implications in clinical and rehabilitation settings have only been studied extensively in recent decades.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN BODY" NlmCategory="METHODS">The implementation of unilateral resistance training in early-stage sports rehabilitation remains underrated, likely due to the lack of consensus on evidence-based guidelines. Thus, this narrative review provides a current overview of the CE of strength, analyzes its practical implications for sports rehabilitation, and examines the training modalities and parameters that should be modulated to optimize CE adaptations, thereby supporting early intervention against post-injury neuromuscular decline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Unilateral resistance training in the healthy limb appears to represent a cost-effective and accessible rehabilitation strategy for athletes who are unable to work on their injured limb from the early stages of rehabilitation. This strategy may ensure the maintenance of muscle strength levels in the trained limb while minimizing neuromuscular decline in the injured and immobilized limb. CE of strength may be implemented as an addition to traditional early-stage rehabilitation strategies, such as pain, swelling, and inflammation reduction, the progressive restoration of joint range of motion, and the progressive strength training in sports injury rehabilitation. Further research is required to make definitive recommendations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirto</LastName><ForeName>Mauro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9187-6150</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esposito</LastName><ForeName>Fabio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4420-2611</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iaia</LastName><ForeName>F Marcello</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0981-6471</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Codella</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1608-1899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy. roberto.codella@unimi.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: As the information of this study are publicly accessible, no ethics approval was required. Data included in this study were extracted from prior studies that obtained written prior consent for publication. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: Mauro Mirto, Fabio Esposito, F. Marcello Iaia and Roberto Codella declare that they have no financial, personal, or professional conflicts of interest related to this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41269443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12638512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00931-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00931-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ruddy KL, Carson RG. Neural pathways mediating cross education of motor function. Front Hum Neurosci. 2013;7:397. 10.3389/fnhum.2013.00397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23908616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus CR, Arnold CM, Johnston G, et al. Cross-education for improving strength and mobility after distal radius fractures: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(7):1247&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.apmr.2013.03.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2013.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23529145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Zehr EP. Restoring symmetry: clinical applications of cross-education. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42(2):70&#x2013;5. 10.1249/JES.0000000000000009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Dragone D, Dvir Z, Deriu F. Cross-education of muscular strength following unilateral resistance training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(11):2335&#x2013;54. 10.1007/s00421-017-3720-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3720-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28936703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scripture EW, Smith TL, Brown EM. On the education of muscular control and power. Stud Yale Psycological Lab. 1894;2:114&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fimland MS, Helgerud J, Solstad GM, Iversen VM, Leivseth G, Hoff J. Neural adaptations underlying cross-education after unilateral strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(6):723&#x2013;30. 10.1007/s00421-009-1190-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1190-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19756705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S. Chronic neural adaptations to unilateral exercise: mechanisms of cross education. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2000;28(4):177&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11064852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortezanejad M, Roostayi MM, Daryabor A, Salemi P. The effect of contraction type and training volume in unilateral exercises on Cross-Education: A narrative review study. Muscle Ligaments Tendons J. 2023;13(02):320&#x2013;34. 10.32098/mltj.01.2019.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32098/mltj.01.2019.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2006;101(5):1514&#x2013;22. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00531.2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00531.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Rothwell J, Deriu F. Neurophysiological adaptations in the untrained side in conjunction with cross-education of muscle strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2018;124(6):1502&#x2013;18. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01016.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01016.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29446711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirer-Sastre R, Beltr&#xe1;n-Garrido JV, Corbi F. Contralateral effects after unilateral strength training: A Meta-Analysis comparing training loads. J Sports Sci Med. 2017;16(2):180&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5465979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green LA, Gabriel DA. The effect of unilateral training on contralateral limb strength in young, older, and patient populations: a meta-analysis of cross education. Phys Ther Rev. 2018;23:238&#x2013;49. 10.1080/10833196.2018.1499272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10833196.2018.1499272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haggert M, Pearce AJ, Frazer AK, Rahman S, Kidgell DJ, Siddique U. (2020). Determining the effects of Cross-Education on muscle Strength, thickness and cortical activation following limb immobilization: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. 10.37714/josam.v2i4.54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altheyab A, Alqurashi H, England TJ, Phillips BE, Piasecki M. Cross-education of lower limb muscle strength following resistance exercise training in males and females: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Physiol. 2024 Sep;5. 10.1113/EP091881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy KL, Rudolf AK, Kalkman B, et al. Neural adaptations associated with interlimb transfer in a ballistic wrist flexion task. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10:204. 10.3389/fnhum.2016.00204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2016.00204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4853797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27199722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe GS, Blazevich AJ, Taylor JL, Pulverenti T, Haff GG. Can the cross-education of strength attenuate the impact of detraining after a period of strength training? A quasi-randomized trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024. 10.1007/s00421-024-05509-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05509-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38809477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papandreou M, Billis E, Papathanasiou G, Spyropoulos P, Papaioannou N. Cross-exercise on quadriceps deficit after ACL reconstruction. J Knee Surg. 2013;26(1):51&#x2013;8. 10.1055/s-0032-1313744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0032-1313744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrushko JW, Gould LA, Farthing JP. Contralateral effects of unilateral training: sparing of muscle strength and size after immobilization. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(11):1131&#x2013;9. 10.1139/apnm-2018-0073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2018-0073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harput G, Ulusoy B, Yildiz TI, et al. Cross-education improves quadriceps strength recovery after ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(1):68&#x2013;75. 10.1007/s00167-018-5040-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-018-5040-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minshull C, Gallacher P, Roberts S, Barnett A, Kuiper JH, Bailey A. Contralateral strength training attenuates muscle performance loss following anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction: a randomised-controlled trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(12):3551&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00421-021-04812-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04812-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34542671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Krentz JR, Magnus CR. Strength training the free limb attenuates strength loss during unilateral immobilization. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2009;106(3):830&#x2013;6. 10.1152/japplphysiol.91331.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.91331.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus CR, Barss TS, Lanovaz JL, Farthing JP. Effects of cross-education on the muscle after a period of unilateral limb immobilization using a shoulder sling and swathe. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2010;109(6):1887&#x2013;94. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00597.2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00597.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Spittle M, Kidgell DJ. Cross education and immobilisation: mechanisms and implications for injury rehabilitation. J Sci Med Sport. 2012;15(2):94&#x2013;101. 10.1016/j.jsams.2011.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2011.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21924681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez F, Abi&#xe1;n P, Jim&#xe9;nez F, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J. Effects of Cross-Education after 6 weeks of eccentric Single-Leg decline squats performed with different execution times: A randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2021;13(6):594&#x2013;605. 10.1177/19417381211016353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381211016353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8559000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34075821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J, de Paz JA. Cross-education effects of unilateral accentuated eccentric isoinertial resistance training on lean mass and function. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(4):672&#x2013;84. 10.1111/sms.14108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34851533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onigbinde AT, Ajiboye RA, Bada AI, Isaac SO. Inter-limb effects of isometric quadriceps strengthening on untrained contra-lateral homologous muscle of patients with knee osteoarthritis. Technol Health Care. 2017;25(1):19&#x2013;27. 10.3233/THC-161239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/THC-161239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27447406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins BW, Lockyer EJ, Button DC. Prescribing cross-education of strength: is it time? Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(4):684&#x2013;5. 10.1002/mus.25665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28407340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Keller M, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, M&#xe1;rquez G. Effects of acute and chronic unilateral resistance training variables on ipsilateral motor cortical excitability and cross-education: A systematic review. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;40:143&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.09.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31546134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuyul-V&#xe1;squez I, &#xc1;lvarez E, Riquelme A, Zimmermann R, Araya-Quintanilla F. Effectiveness of unilateral training of the uninjured limb on muscle strength and knee function of patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis of Cross-Education. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31(5):605&#x2013;16. 10.1123/jsr.2021-0204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2021-0204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Siemionow V, Sahgal V, Xiong F, Yue GH. Greater movement-related cortical potential during human eccentric versus concentric muscle contractions. J Neurophysiol. 2001;86(4):1764&#x2013;72. 10.1152/jn.2001.86.4.1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.2001.86.4.1764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M, O&#x2019;Brien K, Kirk G, Murray R, McKinnon P, Shadgan B, Reid WD. The effects of eccentric versus concentric resistance training on muscle strength and mass in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(8):556&#x2013;68. 10.1136/bjsm.2008.051417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2008.051417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(11):1689&#x2013;97. 10.1007/s40279-016-0543-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0543-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between Low- vs. High-Load resistance training: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. Concentric loading: Morphological, Molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol. 2017;8:447. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, Grgic J, Delcastillo K, Belliard R, Alto A. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayatpour N. Acute and chronic neural adaptations to different types of muscle contractions. Sport Sci Health. 2025;21:1223&#x2013;32. 10.1007/s11332-024-01313-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-024-01313-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s O, Rehbein C, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez O, Chalchat E, Siracusa J, Garc&#xed;a-Vicencio S, Thomas-Junius C, Chennaoui M, Martin V, Pe&#xf1;ailillo L. Acute cross-education effect on force production and central/peripheral responses to unilateral eccentric and concentric resistance exercise in elbow flexors. J Neurophysiol. 2025;133(6):1844&#x2013;58. 10.1152/jn.00028.2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00028.2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40388208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazer AK, Williams J, Spittle M, Kidgell DJ. Cross-education of muscular strength is facilitated by homeostatic plasticity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(4):665&#x2013;77. 10.1007/s00421-017-3538-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3538-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Lamon S. The Cross-Education phenomenon: brain and beyond. Front Physiol. 2017;8:297. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28539892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazer AK, Pearce AJ, Howatson G, Thomas K, Goodall S, Kidgell DJ. Determining the potential sites of neural adaptation to cross-education: implications for the cross-education of muscle strength. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(9):1751&#x2013;72. 10.1007/s00421-018-3937-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-018-3937-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29995227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Milanese C, Schena F. Cross-education effect after unilateral eccentric-only isokinetic vs. dynamic constant external resistance training. Sport Sci Health. 2015;11:329&#x2013;35. 10.1007/s11332-015-0244-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-015-0244-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoeller RF, Angelopoulos TJ, Thompson BC, et al. Vascular remodeling in response to 12 Wk of upper arm unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(11):2003&#x2013;8. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a70707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a70707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Zult T, Farthing JP, Zijdewind I, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T. Mirror training to augment cross-education during resistance training: a hypothesis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2013;7:396. 10.3389/fnhum.2013.00396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zult T, Howatson G, K&#xe1;d&#xe1;r EE, Farthing JP, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T. Role of the mirror-neuron system in cross-education. Sports Med. 2014;44(2):159&#x2013;78. 10.1007/s40279-013-0105-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0105-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24122078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zult T, Goodall S, Thomas K, Solnik S, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Howatson G. Mirror training augments the Cross-education of strength and affects inhibitory paths. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(6):1001&#x2013;13. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26765630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrone M, Martinez G, Achene A, Scaglione M, Masala S, Manca A, Deriu F. Size and site matter: the influence of corpus callosum subregional lesions on the magnitude of cross-education of strength. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1554742. 10.3389/fphys.2025.1554742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1554742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11891228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40066282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy KL, Leemans A, Woolley DG, Wenderoth N, Carson RG. Structural and functional cortical connectivity mediating cross education of motor function. J Neurosci. 2017;37(10):2555&#x2013;64. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2536-16.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2536-16.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5354316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28154150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Borowsky R, Chilibeck PD, Binsted G, Sarty GE. Neuro-physiological adaptations associated with cross-education of strength. Brain Topogr. 2007 Winter;20(2):77&#x2013;88. 10.1007/s10548-007-0033-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez MA, Cohen LG. Mechanisms underlying functional changes in the primary motor cortex ipsilateral to an active hand. J Neurosci. 2008;28(22):5631&#x2013;40. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0093-08.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0093-08.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2440822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18509024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Chye L, Teo WP. Cross-Activation of the motor cortex during unilateral contractions of the quadriceps. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017;11:397. 10.3389/fnhum.2017.00397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2017.00397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28824401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Fari&#xf1;as J, Iglesias-Soler E, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, M&#xe1;rquez G. Training load but not fatigue affects cross-education of maximal voluntary force. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(2):313&#x2013;24. 10.1111/sms.13844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn J, Herbert RD, Hancock MJ, Gandevia SC. Training with unilateral resistance exercise increases contralateral strength. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2005;99(5):1880&#x2013;4. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00559.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00559.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Richardson SP, Lomarev M, et al. Interhemispheric plasticity in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1188&#x2013;99. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820a94b8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820a94b8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21200340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Gandevia SC, Carroll TJ. Unilateral strength training increases voluntary activation of the opposite untrained limb. Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;120(4):802&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.clinph.2009.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2009.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19230754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minetto MA, Botter A, Gamerro G, Varvello I, Massazza G, Bellomo RG, Maffiuletti NA, Saggini R. Contralateral effect of short-duration unilateral neuromuscular electrical stimulation and focal vibration in healthy subjects. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54(6):911&#x2013;20. 10.23736/S1973-9087.18.05004-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.18.05004-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Zhang SS, Crowley-McHattan ZJ. A scoping review of the contralateral effects of unilateral peripheral stimulation on neuromuscular function. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(2):e0263662. 10.1371/journal.pone.0263662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0263662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8827438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Merni F. Effect of Lower-Body resistance training on Upper-Body strength adaptation in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(1):13&#x2013;8. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29257792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Othman A, Behm DG, Chaouachi A. Evidence of homologous and heterologous effects after unilateral leg training in youth. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(3):282&#x2013;91. 10.1139/apnm-2017-0338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29069548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdi HR, Maroto-Izquierdo S, de Paz JA. Ipsilateral Lower-to-Upper limb Cross-Transfer effect on muscle Strength, mechanical Power, and lean tissue mass after accentuated eccentric loading. Med (Kaunas). 2021;57(5):445. 10.3390/medicina57050445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina57050445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capozio A, Chakrabarty S, Astill S. Acute effects of strength and skill training on the cortical and spinal circuits of contralateral limb. J Mot Behav. 2024;56(2):119&#x2013;31. 10.1080/00222895.2023.2265316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00222895.2023.2265316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green LA, Gabriel DA. The cross education of strength and skill following unilateral strength training in the upper and lower limbs. J Neurophysiol. 2018;120(2):468&#x2013;79. 10.1152/jn.00116.2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00116.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29668382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaouachi A, Ben Othman A, Makhlouf I, Young JD, Granacher U, Behm DG. Global training effects of trained and untrained muscles with youth can be maintained during 4 weeks of detraining. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(10):2788&#x2013;800. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29794891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Galas A, Campa F, Pedrinolla A, Schena F, Venturelli M. The eccentric phase in unilateral resistance training enhances and preserves the contralateral knee extensors strength gains after detraining in women: A randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2022;13:788473. 10.3389/fphys.2022.788473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.788473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8928196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen W, Frazer AK, Tallent J, Pearce AJ, Kidgell DJ. Unilateral strength training imparts a Cross-Education effect in unilateral knee osteoarthritis patients. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2022;7(4):77. 10.3390/jfmk7040077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk7040077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36278738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidgell DJ, Stokes MA, Pearce AJ. Strength training of one limb increases corticomotor excitability projecting to the contralateral homologous limb. Motor Control. 2011;15(2):247&#x2013;66. 10.1123/mcj.15.2.247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/mcj.15.2.247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21628728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus CR, Boychuk K, Kim SY, Farthing JP. At-home resistance tubing strength training increases shoulder strength in the trained and untrained limb. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(3):586&#x2013;93. 10.1111/sms.12037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23293845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombs TA, Frazer AK, Horvath DM, Pearce AJ, Howatson G, Kidgell DJ. Cross-education of wrist extensor strength is not influenced by non-dominant training in right-handers. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(9):1757&#x2013;69. 10.1007/s00421-016-3436-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3436-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagerquist O, Zehr EP, Docherty D. Increased spinal reflex excitability is not associated with neural plasticity underlying the cross-education effect. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2006;100(1):83&#x2013;90. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00533.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00533.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16357081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Kidgell DJ, Pearce AJ. Reduction in corticospinal Inhibition in the trained and untrained limb following unilateral leg strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(8):3097&#x2013;107. 10.1007/s00421-011-2289-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2289-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22200796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwill AM, Pearce AJ, Kidgell DJ. Corticomotor plasticity following unilateral strength training. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46(3):384&#x2013;93. 10.1002/mus.23316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.23316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22907229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abazovic E, Kova&#x10d;evic E, Kovac S, Bradic J. The effect of training of the non-dominant knee muscles on ipsi- and contralateral strength gains. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2015;23(3):177&#x2013;82. 10.3233/IES-150579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-150579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Pisanu F, Ortu E, et al. A comprehensive assessment of the cross-training effect in ankle dorsiflexors of healthy subjects: A randomized controlled study. Gait Posture. 2015;42(1):1&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25922111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Wong LZ, Simmons ND, Mirallais A, Ronca F, Kumar B. Bilateral improvements following unilateral Home-Based training in plantar flexors: A potential for Cross-Education in rehabilitation. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;32(1):14&#x2013;23. 10.1123/jsr.2021-0383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2021-0383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietz V. Do human bipeds use quadrupedal coordination? Trends Neurosci. 2002;25(9):462&#x2013;7. 10.1016/s0166-2236(02)02229-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0166-2236(02)02229-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Kidgell DJ. Anodal-tDCS applied during unilateral strength training increases strength and corticospinal excitability in the untrained homologous muscle. Exp Brain Res. 2014;232(10):3243&#x2013;52. 10.1007/s00221-014-4016-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-014-4016-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24942703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Teo WP, Kidgell DJ. Anodal transcranial direct current stimulation prolongs the Cross-education of strength and corticomotor plasticity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(9):1788&#x2013;97. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25551405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei LC, Chan CH. Exploring the potential of noninvasive brain stimulation in sports performance enhancement: ethical considerations and future directions. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(9):e14723. 10.1111/sms.14723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39238212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason J, Frazer AK, Horvath DM, et al. Ipsilateral corticomotor responses are confined to the homologous muscle following cross-education of muscular strength. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(1):11&#x2013;22. 10.1139/apnm-2017-0457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28829918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD, Binsted G. Cross-education of arm muscular strength is unidirectional in right-handed individuals. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(9):1594&#x2013;600. 10.1249/01.mss.0000177588.74448.75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000177588.74448.75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16177613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ZW, Wong V, Spitz RW, Yamada Y, Song JS, Kataoka R, Chatakondi RN, Abe T, Loenneke JP. Unilateral high-load resistance training influences strength changes in the contralateral arm undergoing low-load training. J Sci Med Sport. 2023;26(8):440&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.jsams.2023.06.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2023.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37423835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JS, Yamada Y, Kataoka R, Hammert WB, Kang A, Spitz RW, Wong V, Seffrin A, Kassiano W, Loenneke JP. Does unilateral High-Load resistance training influence strength change in the contralateral arm also undergoing High-Load training? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(12):e14772. 10.1111/sms.14772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39582380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinder MR, Schmidt MW, Garry MI, Carroll TJ, Summers JJ. Absence of cross-limb transfer of performance gains following ballistic motor practice in older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2011;110(1):166&#x2013;75. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00958.2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00958.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21088207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hester GM, Magrini MA, Colquhoun RJ, et al. Cross-education: effects of age on rapid and maximal voluntary contractile characteristics in males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(6):1313&#x2013;22. 10.1007/s00421-019-04123-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04123-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hester GM, Pope ZK, Magrini MA, et al. Age does not attenuate maximal velocity adaptations in the ipsilateral and contralateral limbs during unilateral resistance training. J Aging Phys Act. 2019;27(1):1&#x2013;8. 10.1123/japa.2017-0297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.2017-0297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29485309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park DW, Park YS, Koh K, Kwon HJ, Lee SH, Park J, Shim JK. Enhancing prehension strength and dexterity through cross-education effects in the elderly. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):9819. 10.1038/s41598-025-94182-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-94182-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11928469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40118923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part II: long term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med. 2000;30(3):145&#x2013;54. 10.2165/00007256-200030030-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200030030-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10999420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestroni L, Read P, Bishop C, Turner A. Strength and power training in rehabilitation: underpinning principles and practical strategies to return athletes to high performance. Sports Med. 2020;50(2):239&#x2013;52. 10.1007/s40279-019-01195-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01195-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31559567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papandreou MG, Papaioannou N, Antonogiannakis E, Zeeris H. The effect of cross exercise on quadriceps strength in different knee angles after the anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Braz J Biomotricity. 2007;1(4):123&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barss TS, Pearcey GE, Zehr EP. Cross-education of strength and skill: an old Idea with applications in the aging nervous system. Yale J Biol Med. 2016;89(1):81&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4797840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27505019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yoshida R, Kiyono R, et al. Cross-education and detraining effects of eccentric vs. concentric resistance training of the elbow flexors. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2021;13(1):105. 10.1186/s13102-021-00298-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-021-00298-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz TI, Turhan E, Huri G, Ocguder DA, Duzgun I. Cross-education effects on shoulder rotator muscle strength and function after shoulder stabilization surgery: a randomized controlled trial. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2024;33(4):804&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.jse.2023.10.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2023.10.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori S, Moretti A, Toro G, Arienti C, Patrini M, Kiekens C, Negrini S, Iolascon G, Gimigliano F. Overview of Cochrane systematic reviews for rehabilitation interventions in individuals with upper limb fractures: A mapping synthesis. Med (Kaunas). 2024;60(3):469. 10.3390/medicina60030469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina60030469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks NE, Myburgh KH. Skeletal muscle wasting with disuse atrophy is multi-dimensional: the response and interaction of myonuclei, satellite cells and signaling pathways. Front Physiol. 2014;5:99. 10.3389/fphys.2014.00099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2014.00099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24672488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall BT, Morton JP, van Loon LJ. Strategies to maintain skeletal muscle mass in the injured athlete: nutritional considerations and exercise mimetics. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15(1):53&#x2013;62. 10.1080/17461391.2014.936326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.936326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25027662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall BT, Dirks ML, Snijders T, et al. Short-term muscle disuse lowers myofibrillar protein synthesis rates and induces anabolic resistance to protein ingestion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2016;310(2):E137&#x2013;47. 10.1152/ajpendo.00227.2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00227.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26578714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crossland H, Skirrow S, Puthucheary ZA, Constantin-Teodosiu D, Greenhaff PL. The impact of immobilisation and inflammation on the regulation of muscle mass and insulin resistance: different routes to similar end-points. J Physiol. 2019;597(5):1259&#x2013;70. 10.1113/JP275444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP275444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6395472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29968251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appell HJ. Muscular atrophy following immobilisation. A review. Sports Med. 1990;10(1):42&#x2013;58. 10.2165/00007256-199010010-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199010010-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2197699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Issac LC, Lane JL, Damron LA, Hoffman RL. Neuromuscular plasticity during and following 3 Wk of human forearm cast immobilization. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2008;105(3):868&#x2013;78. 10.1152/japplphysiol.90530.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90530.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18635877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer N, H&#xe4;nggi J, M&#xfc;ller NA, Simmen HP, J&#xe4;ncke L. Effects of limb immobilization on brain plasticity. Neurology. 2012;78(3):182&#x2013;8. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823fcd9c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823fcd9c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22249495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burianov&#xe1; H, Sowman PF, Marstaller L, et al. Adaptive motor imagery: A multimodal study of Immobilization-Induced brain plasticity. Cereb Cortex. 2016;26(3):1072&#x2013;80. 10.1093/cercor/bhu287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhu287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25477368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opie GM, Evans A, Ridding MC, Semmler JG. Short-term immobilization influences use-dependent cortical plasticity and fine motor performance. Neuroscience. 2016;330:247&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2016.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2016.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avanzino L, Bassolino M, Pozzo T, Bove M. Use-dependent hemispheric balance. J Neurosci. 2011;31(9):3423&#x2013;8. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4893-10.2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4893-10.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6623942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21368053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenkranz K, Seibel J, Kacar A, Rothwell J. Sensorimotor deprivation induces interdependent changes in excitability and plasticity of the human hand motor cortex. J Neurosci. 2014;34(21):7375&#x2013;82. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5139-13.2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5139-13.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6608189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24849369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500&#x2013;14. 10.1136/bjsports-2022-106158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Su&#xe1;rez-Arrones L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on performance in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):512&#x2013;9. 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as J, et al. Velocity loss as a critical variable determining the adaptations to strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(8):1752&#x2013;62. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, Cornejo-Daza PJ, et al. Effects of velocity loss in the bench press exercise on strength gains, neuromuscular adaptations, and muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(11):2154&#x2013;66. 10.1111/sms.13775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson D, Vu V, Ness BM, Wellsandt E, Morrison S. A Multi-Systems approach to human movement after ACL reconstruction: the musculoskeletal system. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;17(1):27&#x2013;46. 10.26603/001c.29456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.29456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35237463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrushko JW, Carr JC, Farthing JP, et al. Potential role of cross-education in early-stage rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(23):1474&#x2013;5. 10.1136/bjsports-2023-107456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-107456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37821207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung KS, Ha JK, Yeom CH, et al. Are muscle strength and function of the uninjured lower limb weakened after anterior cruciate ligament injury? Two-Year Follow-up after reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(12):3013&#x2013;21. 10.1177/0363546515606126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515606126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26460100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes M, Young A. The contribution of reflex Inhibition to arthrogenous muscle weakness. Clin Sci (Lond). 1984;67(1):7&#x2013;14. 10.1042/cs0670007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0670007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6375939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart JM, Pietrosimone B, Hertel J, Ingersoll CD. Quadriceps activation following knee injuries: a systematic review. J Athl Train 2010 Jan-;45(1):87&#x2013;97. 10.4085/1062-6050-45.1.87</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarzycki R, Morton SM, Charalambous CC, Pietrosimone B, Williams GN, Snyder-Mackler L. Examination of corticospinal and spinal reflexive excitability during the course of postoperative rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2020;50(9):516&#x2013;22. 10.2519/jospt.2020.9329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2020.9329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9361008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez KM, Palmieri-Smith RM, Krishnan C. How does anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction affect the functioning of the brain and spinal cord? A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10(2):172&#x2013;81. 10.1016/j.jshs.2020.07.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2020.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas AC, Wojtys EM, Brandon C, Palmieri-Smith RM. Muscle atrophy contributes to quadriceps weakness after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(1):7&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.jsams.2014.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2014.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges PW. Pain and motor control: from the laboratory to rehabilitation. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2011;21(2):220&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.jelekin.2011.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2011.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce AJ, Hendy A, Bowen WA, Kidgell DJ. Corticospinal adaptations and strength maintenance in the immobilized arm following 3 weeks unilateral strength training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23(6):740&#x2013;8. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01453.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01453.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22429184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdes O, Ramirez C, Perez F, Garcia-Vicencio S, Nosaka K, Penailillo L. Contralateral effects of eccentric resistance training on immobilized arm. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(1):76&#x2013;90. 10.1111/sms.13821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32897568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr JC, Voskuil CC, Andrushko JW, MacLennan RJ, DeFreitas JM, Stock MS, Farthing JP. Cross-education attenuates muscle weakness and facilitates strength recovery after orthopedic immobilization in females: A pilot study. Physiol Rep. 2025;13(8):e70329. 10.14814/phy2.70329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.70329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12032444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40285446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt LC, Paterno MV, Hewett TE. The impact of quadriceps femoris strength asymmetry on functional performance at return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(9):750&#x2013;9. 10.2519/jospt.2012.4194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.4194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4157226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22813542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zult T, Gokeler A, van Raay JJAM, et al. Cross-education does not accelerate the rehabilitation of neuromuscular functions after ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(8):1609&#x2013;23. 10.1007/s00421-018-3892-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-018-3892-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6060748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29796857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zult T, Gokeler A, van Raay JJAM, et al. Cross-education does not improve early and late-phase rehabilitation outcomes after ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(2):478&#x2013;90. 10.1007/s00167-018-5116-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-018-5116-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30182287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading recommendations for muscle Strength, Hypertrophy, and local endurance: A Re-Examination of the repetition continuum. Sports (Basel). 2021;9(2):32. 10.3390/sports9020032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9020032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Gokeler A, Herrington L, Hughes M, Grassi A, Wadey R, Patterson S, Compagnin A, La Rosa G, Della Villa F. Optimising the Early-Stage rehabilitation process Post-ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2024;54(1):49&#x2013;72. 10.1007/s40279-023-01934-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01934-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37787846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Carroll TJ, et al. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength and skill training: modified Delphi consensus to Establish key aspects of Cross-Education. Sports Med. 2021;51(1):11&#x2013;20. 10.1007/s40279-020-01377-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01377-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neltner TJ, Addie CD, Cosio-Lima LM, Dake CC, Brown LE. No effect of short term cross-education training on concentric contralateral shoulder strength. Isokin Ex Sci. 2019;27(4):261&#x2013;6. 10.3233/IES-192172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-192172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer KS, Fukuda DH, Boone CH, et al. Short-Term unilateral resistance training results in cross education of strength without changes in muscle Size, Activation, or endocrine response. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(5):1213&#x2013;23. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26466136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barss TS, Klarner T, Pearcey GEP, Sun Y, Zehr EP. Time course of interlimb strength transfer after unilateral handgrip training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2018;125(5):1594&#x2013;608. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00390.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00390.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr JC, Ye X, Stock MS, Bemben MG, DeFreitas JM. The time course of cross-education during short-term isometric strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(6):1395&#x2013;407. 10.1007/s00421-019-04130-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04130-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;karabot J, Brownstein CG, Casolo A, Del Vecchio A, Ansdell P. The knowns and unknowns of neural adaptations to resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(3):675&#x2013;85. 10.1007/s00421-020-04567-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04567-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med. 1979;58(3):115&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyes NG, Yee P, Lanovaz JL, Farthing JP. Cross-education after high-frequency versus low-frequency volume-matched handgrip training. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(4):689&#x2013;95. 10.1002/mus.25637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28249351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NDM, Miramonti AA, Hill EC, et al. Greater neural adaptations following High- vs. Low-Load resistance training. Front Physiol. 2017;8:331. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda Y, Miyamura M. Cross transfer effects of muscular training on blood flow in the ipsilateral and contralateral forearms. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1983;51(3):321&#x2013;9. 10.1007/BF00429068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00429068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6685030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields RK, Leo KC, Messaros AJ, Somers VK. Effects of repetitive handgrip training on endurance, specificity, and cross-education. Phys Ther. 1999;79(5):467&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/79.5.467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10331750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss BM, Refsnes PE, Abildgaard A, Nicolaysen K, Jensen J. Effects of maximal effort strength training with different loads on dynamic strength, cross-sectional area, load-power and load-velocity relationships. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1997;75(3):193&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s004210050147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9088836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelet DCS, Orsatti FL. Effects of resistance training at different intensities of load on cross-education of muscle strength. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021;46(10):1279&#x2013;89. 10.1139/apnm-2021-0088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JZ, Shan ZY, Zhang LD, Sahgal V, Brown RW, Yue GH. Human brain activation during sustained and intermittent submaximal fatigue muscle contractions: an FMRI study. J Neurophysiol. 2003;90(1):300&#x2013;12. 10.1152/jn.00821.2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00821.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12634278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fari&#xf1;as J, Mayo X, Giraldez-Garc&#xed;a MA, et al. Set configuration in strength training programs modulates the cross education phenomenon. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(9):2414&#x2013;20. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fari&#xf1;as J, Rial-V&#xe1;zquez J, Carballeira E, et al. Cross education is modulated by set configuration in knee extension exercise. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2023;23(1):43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9976175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36856099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akima H, Saito A. Activation of quadriceps femoris including Vastus intermedius during fatiguing dynamic knee extensions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(11):2829&#x2013;40. 10.1007/s00421-013-2721-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-013-2721-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24037137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, Pyne DB, Hunt PH, McKenna MJ. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(2):382&#x2013;8. 10.1519/R-15224.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-15224.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Libardi CA. Is resistance training to muscular failure necessary? Front Physiol. 2016;7:10. 10.3389/fphys.2016.00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2016.00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. The application of training to failure in periodized multiple-set resistance exercise programs. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):628&#x2013;31. 10.1519/R-20426.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-20426.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE. 2010;5(8):e12033. 10.1371/journal.pone.0012033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, De Luca R, Marcora SM. May a nonlocalized postactivation performance enhancement exist between the upper and lower body in trained men? J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(1):68&#x2013;73. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35900802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voskuil CC, Andrushko JW, Huddleston BS, Farthing JP, Carr JC. Exercise prescription and strategies to promote the cross-education of strength: a scoping review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2023;48(8):569&#x2013;82. 10.1139/apnm-2023-0041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2023-0041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37156010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Carroll TJ. Cross education: possible mechanisms for the contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training. Sports Med. 2007;37(1):1&#x2013;14. 10.2165/00007256-200737010-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737010-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17190532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn J, Herbert RD, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2004;96(5):1861&#x2013;6. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00541.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00541.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Lambert NJ, Hill JP. Greater cross education following training with muscle lengthening than shortening. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29(1):107&#x2013;12. 10.1097/00005768-199701000-00015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199701000-00015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9000162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD. The effect of eccentric training at different velocities on cross-education. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(6):570&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s00421-003-0841-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-003-0841-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12756570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley LK, Palmieri-Smith RM. Cross-education strength and activation after eccentric exercise. J Athl Train. 2014;49(5):582&#x2013;9. 10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidgell DJ, Frazer AK, Daly RM, et al. Increased cross-education of muscle strength and reduced corticospinal Inhibition following eccentric strength training. Neuroscience. 2015;300:566&#x2013;75. 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2015.05.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2015.05.057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26037804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng WC, Nosaka K, Tseng KW, Chou TY, Chen TC. Contralateral effects by unilateral eccentric versus concentric resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(2):474&#x2013;83. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12376810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(13):1003&#x2013;11. 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC. Eccentric, but not concentric blood flow restriction resistance training increases muscle strength in the untrained limb. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;43:1&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.01.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong V, Spitz RW, Song JS, et al. Blood flow restriction augments the cross-education effect of isometric handgrip training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124(5):1575&#x2013;85. 10.1007/s00421-023-05386-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05386-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38168713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Taylor MB, Rider P, et al. Ipsilateral motor cortical responses to TMS during lengthening and shortening of the contralateral wrist flexors. Eur J Neurosci. 2011;33(5):978&#x2013;90. 10.1111/j.1460-9568.2010.07567.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-9568.2010.07567.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP. Recent advances in the Understanding of the repeated bout effect: the protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13(2):88&#x2013;97. 10.1034/j.1600-0838.2003.02477.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0838.2003.02477.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12641640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon S, Kang M, Ye X. Contralateral protective effect against repeated bout of damaging exercise: A meta-analysis. Res Sports Med. 2023 Mar-;31(2):137&#x2013;56. 10.1080/15438627.2021.1954512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Chen HL, Tseng WC, et al. Contralateral versus ipsilateral protective effect against muscle damage of the elbow flexors and knee extensors induced by maximal eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(12):2548&#x2013;60. 10.1111/sms.14482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37642310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Wagle JP, Douglas J, Taber CB, Harden M, Haff GG, Stone MH. Implementing eccentric resistance Training-Part 2: practical recommendations. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2019;4(3):55. 10.3390/jfmk4030055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk4030055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne MN, Timmins RG, Opar DA, et al. An Evidence-Based framework for strengthening exercises to prevent hamstring injury. Sports Med. 2018;48(2):251&#x2013;67. 10.1007/s40279-017-0796-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0796-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29116573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power D, Haddad F, Wallis S, Barr K. Ramping isometrics for accelerated return to play following hamstring tendon repair: A case study. J Elite Sport Perform. 2023;1:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnason SM, Birnir B, Gu&#xf0;mundsson TE, Gu&#xf0;nason G, Briem K. Medial hamstring muscle activation patterns are affected 1&#x2013;6 years after ACL reconstruction using hamstring autograft. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22(5):1024&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00167-013-2696-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-013-2696-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24067994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Turner A, Gonzalo-skok O, Read P. Inter-limb asymmetry during rehabilitation. Understanding formulas and monitoring the magnitude and direction. Aspetar Sports Med J. 2021;9:19&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Bourne MN, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Lorenzen C, Opar DA. Short biceps femoris fascicles and eccentric knee flexor weakness increase the risk of hamstring injury in elite football (soccer): a prospective cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1524&#x2013;35. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay AD, Blazevich AJ, Tysoe JC, Baxter BA. Cross-Education effects of isokinetic eccentric plantarflexor training on Flexibility, Strength, and Muscle-Tendon mechanics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56(7):1242&#x2013;55. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000003418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38451696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Othman A, Chaouachi A, Chaouachi M, et al. Dominant and nondominant leg press training induce similar contralateral and ipsilateral limb training adaptations with children. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44(9):973&#x2013;84. 10.1139/apnm-2018-0766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2018-0766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30664382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JS, Hammert WB, Kataoka R, et al. Unilateral high-load resistance training induced a similar cross-education of strength between the dominant and non-dominant arm. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(14):1308&#x2013;12. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2388997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2388997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39115420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razian M, Hosseinzadeh M, Behm DG, Sardroodian M. Effect of leg dominance on ipsilateral and contralateral limb training adaptation in middle-aged women after unilateral sensorimotor and resistance exercise training. Res Sports Med. 2024;32(3):345&#x2013;62. 10.1080/15438627.2022.2113878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2022.2113878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca A, Ginatempo F, Cabboi MP, et al. No evidence of neural adaptations following chronic unilateral isometric training of the intrinsic muscles of the hand: a randomized controlled study. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(10):1993&#x2013;2005. 10.1007/s00421-016-3451-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3451-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27485469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krisnan L, Yusof A, Marathamuthu S, Selvanayagam VS. Cross-limb transfer during isometric plantar flexion familiarization. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):8620. 10.1038/s41598-025-93626-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-93626-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11903993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40075151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong V, Song JS, Yamada Y, et al. Is there evidence for the asymmetrical transfer of strength to an untrained limb? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024. 10.1007/s00421-024-05472-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05472-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11322193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38568258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>