<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41923121</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-6410</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sex differences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sex Differ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex differences in response to a short-term training program intervention in obese adolescents: a plasma metabolomics study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13293-026-00896-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study aims to investigate sex differences in the response to short-term Training Program intervention and the underlying metabolomic mechanisms among obese adolescents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 98 obese adolescents underwent a 4-week, strictly controlled short-term Training Program intervention. Pre- and post-intervention measurements included body morphometry, body composition, lipid metabolism, and glucose homeostasis indicators. Plasma samples were analyzed using targeted metabolomics. Linear mixed-effects models (LMM) were employed to identify Sex-differential Responsive Metabolites, with volcano plots utilized to visualize metabolic regulation preferences between sexes. Hierarchical clustering analysis identified co-regulated metabolic modules within the Sex-differential Responsive Metabolites for pathway analysis. Partial least squares (PLS) regression models were constructed separately for males and females to identify metabolic biomarkers capable of predicting changes in clinical indicators.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Post-intervention, both males and females showed significant decreases in weight, body mass index (BMI), chest circumference, waist circumference, hip circumference, waist-to-hip ratio, body water, Body fat mass, fat free mass, skeletal muscle mass, body fat percentage, total cholesterol (TC), triglycerides (TG), and low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Additionally, HOMA-&#x3b2; levels significantly decreased only in females (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). After adjusting for developmental maturity and baseline metabolic risk, the improvements in body fat mass and body fat percentage in males were significantly greater than those in females (both P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), whereas no statistical differences were found in weight and BMI improvements (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). The change in HOMA-&#x3b2; differed significantly between sexes (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.031), with females exhibiting a more pronounced downregulation following the intervention. LMM identified 65 Sex-differential Responsive Metabolites. Hierarchical clustering revealed two co-regulated modules: Module 1 showed a strong upward trend in males but a weak response in females, significantly enriched in the linoleic acid metabolism pathway; Module 2 showed a downward trend in both sexes, but the magnitude of downregulation was more pronounced in males, significantly enriched in pathways related to amino acid catabolism and energy metabolism. PLS model analysis indicated that Sex-differential Responsive Metabolites had predictive capacity for male Fasting Blood Glucose (FBG, R<sup>2</sup>Y&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.2653,Q<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0091), female FBG (R<sup>2</sup>Y&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.3552,Q<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1321), and female LDL-c (R<sup>2</sup>Y&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.3895,Q<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1853).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Obese adolescents exhibit significant sexual dimorphism in their response to short-term Training Program. Under the same standardized training program, males achieve greater fat reduction and appear to leverage a synergistic strategy of fatty acid oxidation and protein sparing, whereas females prioritize amino-acid network fine-tuning. Predictive modeling indicates that sex-differential metabolites can predict glucolipid improvements in females. These findings provide a scientific basis for developing sex-differential exercise prescriptions for metabolic health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China. 11251@gzsport.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Innovative Research Center for Sports Science in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China. 11251@gzsport.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Xianyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Innovative Development of Sports and Healthcare Integration, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Huiguo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China. 11450@gzsport.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Innovative Development of Sports and Healthcare Integration, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China. 11450@gzsport.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zekai</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Innovative Research Center for Sports Science in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, 510500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024TSZK017</GrantID><Agency>the New Type of Regular Higher Education Institutions Think Tanks in Guangdong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23ATY007</GrantID><Agency>The National Social Science Fund of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sex Differ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548963</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-6410</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obese adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sex differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Short-term training program intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by the Ethics Committee (EC) of Guangzhou Sport University (protocol code 2018LCLL-008,approved date: 2018-06-25). Consent for publication: Informed consent was obtained from all subjects involved in the study.Written informed consent was obtained from the parents of the patients. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Related publications: The cohort and intervention protocol described in the present study have been previously reported in related publications focusing on different research objectives, including overall metabolomic changes following the intervention, insulin resistance phenotypes, proteomic remodeling, and inter-individual variability in weight loss response. The current manuscript addresses a distinct scientific question, specifically sex-differential metabolic responsiveness to short-term exercise intervention, employing linear mixed-effects models and predictive metabolomic modeling approaches that were not applied in the previous studies.There is no duplication of primary results, statistical models, or interpretations between the present manuscript and prior publications.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41923121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13293-026-00896-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13293-026-00896-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pinhas-Hamiel O, Hamiel U, Bendor CD, et al. The Global Spread of Severe Obesity in Toddlers, Children, and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis [J]. Obes Facts. 2022;15(2):118&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization W H. Tenfold increase in childhood and adolescent obesity in four decades: new study by Imperial College London and WHO [J/OL] 2017, https://www.who.int/news/item/11-10-2017-tenfold-increase-in-childhood-and-adolescent-obesity-in-four-decades-new-study-by-imperial-college-london-and-who?utm_source=chatgpt.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global. regional, and national prevalence of child and adolescent overweight and obesity, 1990&#x2013;2021, with forecasts to 2050: a forecasting study for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021 [J]. Lancet. 2025;405(10481):785&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaghoubpour K, Tasdighi E, Abdi H, et al. Association of obesity phenotypes in adolescents and incidence of early adulthood type 2 diabetes mellitus: Tehran lipid and glucose study [J]. Pediatr Diabetes. 2021;22(7):937&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao YY, Wang D, Chu C, et al. Long-term burden and increasing trends of body mass index are linked with adult hypertension through triglyceride-glucose index: a 30-year prospective cohort study. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;34(9):2134&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tragomalou A, Paltoglou G, Manou M, et al. Non-Traditional Cardiovascular Risk Factors in Adolescents with Obesity and Metabolic Syndrome May Predict Future Cardiovascular Disease [J]. Nutrients. 2023;15(20):4342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Song Y, Ying J, et al. Effects of lifestyle interventions on mental health in children and adolescents with overweight or obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis [J]. EClinicalMedicine. 2025;81: 103121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasi D, Volkow ND. Childhood obesity&#x2019;s effect on cognition and brain connectivity worsens with low family income. JCI Insight. 2024;9(16):e181690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Li J, Liu Y, Zhou Y. Effects of different exercise modalities and intensities on body composition in overweight and obese children and adolescents: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1193223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kido K, KJ&#xf8;BSTED R. Editorial: exercise and its role in regulating energy metabolism-insight from intramuscular mechanisms and cellular signaling. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1169923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheggen R, Konstanti P, Smidt H, et al. Eight-week exercise training in humans with obesity: Marked improvements in insulin sensitivity and modest changes in gut microbiome [J]. Obes (Silver Spring). 2021;29(10):1615&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koceva A, Herman R, Janez A, et al. Sex- and Gender-Related Differences in Obesity: From Pathophysiological Mechanisms to Clinical Implications [J]. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(13):7342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauvais-Jarvis F. Sex differences in energy metabolism: natural selection, mechanisms and consequences. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2024;20(1):56&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Zhou Z, Wang Y, et al. Exercise-induced metabolomics and its association with metabolic health in adolescents [J]. Nutr Metab (Lond). 2025;22(1):48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrino JK, Anthony TG, Gillies P, Arent SM. The exercise metabolome: acute aerobic and anaerobic signatures. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2022;19(1):603&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization W H. Obesity and overweight [J/OL] 2025, https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/obesity-and-overweight</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour [J]. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gately PJ, Cooke CB, Barth JH, et al. Children&#x2019;s residential weight-loss programs can work: a prospective cohort study of short-term outcomes for overweight and obese children [J]. Pediatrics. 2005;116(1):73&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie X, Yang G, Qin Y, et al. Metabolic Characteristics of Obese Adolescents with Different Degrees of Weight Loss After Identical Exercise Training Intervention [J]. Metabolites. 2025;15(5):313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Chen P. Validation of the self-administered rating scale for pubertal development (Chinese version). Chin J Sports Med. 2012;31(6):512&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, et al. Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and beta-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man [J]. Diabetologia. 1985;28(7):412&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenmann JC. On the use of a continuous metabolic syndrome score in pediatric research. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2008;7:17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn WB, Broadhurst D, Begley P, et al. Procedures for large-scale metabolic profiling of serum and plasma using gas chromatography and liquid chromatography coupled to mass spectrometry [J]. Nat Protoc. 2011;6(7):1060&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage EG, Godzien J, Alonso-Herranz V, et al. Missing value imputation strategies for metabolomics data [J]. Electrophoresis. 2015;36(24):3050&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia J, Wishart DS. Web-based inference of biological patterns, functions and pathways from metabolomic data using MetaboAnalyst. Nat Protoc. 2011;6(6):743&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo D, Stol K-J. PLS-SEM for software engineering research: an introduction and survey. ACM Comput Surv. 2021;54(4):1&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoermann R, Fui MNT, Krakauer JC, et al. A body shape index (ABSI) reflects body composition changes in response to testosterone treatment in obese men [J]. Int J Obes (Lond). 2019;43(11):2210&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong M, Xu M, Zhou Y, et al. Assessing visceral obesity and abdominal adipose tissue distribution in healthy populations based on computed tomography: a large multicenter cross-sectional study. Front Nutr. 2022;9:871697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Dong G, Zhao X, et al. Post-exercise Effects and Long-Term Training Adaptations of Hormone Sensitive Lipase Lipolysis Induced by High-Intensity Interval Training in Adipose Tissue of Mice [J]. Front Physiol. 2020;11: 535722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karastergiou K, Smith SR, Greenberg AS, Fried SK. Sex differences in human adipose tissues - the biology of pear shape. Biol Sex Differ. 2012;3(1):13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjune JI, Str&#xf8;mland PP, Jersin R, et al. Metabolic and Epigenetic Regulation by Estrogen in Adipocytes [J]. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2022;13: 828780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kant R, Verma V, Patel S, et al. Effect of serum zinc and copper levels on insulin secretion, insulin resistance and pancreatic &#x3b2; cell dysfunction in US adults: findings from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) 2011&#x2013;2012. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2021;172:108627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merino B, GARC&#xed;A-AR&#xe9;VALO M. Sexual hormones and diabetes: the impact of estradiol in pancreatic &#x3b2; cell. Int Rev Cell Mol Biol. 2021;359:81&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korac A, Srdic-Galic B, Kalezic A, et al. Adipokine signatures of subcutaneous and visceral abdominal fat in normal-weight and obese women with different metabolic profiles. Arch Med Sci. 2021;17(2):323&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa DN, Santosa S, Jensen MD. Sex differences in the metabolism of glucose and fatty acids by adipose tissue and skeletal muscle in humans. Physiol Rev. 2025;105(3):897&#x2013;934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Many GM, Sanford JA, Sagendorf TJ, et al. Sexual dimorphism and the multi-omic response to exercise training in rat subcutaneous white adipose tissue [J]. Nat Metab. 2024;6(5):963&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzo L T, Trefely S, Demetriadou C, et al. Acetylcarnitine shuttling links mitochondrial metabolism to histone acetylation and lipogenesis [J]. Sci Adv. 2023;9(18):eadf0115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo N, Frigeni M, Pasquali M. Carnitine transport and fatty acid oxidation [J]. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2016;1863(10):2422&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuura TR, Puchalska P, Crawford PA, Kelly DP. Ketones and the heart: metabolic principles and therapeutic implications [J]. Circ Res. 2023;132(7):882&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randle PJ, Garland PB, Hales CN, Newsholme EA. The glucose fatty-acid cycle. Its role in insulin sensitivity and the metabolic disturbances of diabetes mellitus [J]. Lancet. 1963;1(7285):785&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoio DM. Metabolic inflexibility: when mitochondrial indecision leads to metabolic gridlock [J]. Cell. 2014;159(6):1253&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonen W, Schwaberger G, Lamprecht M, Hofmann P. Whole body substrate metabolism during different exercise intensities with special emphasis on blood protein changes in trained subjects-a pilot study [J]. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2023;8(3):102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreher SI, Goj T, VON Toerne C, et al. Sex differences in resting skeletal muscle and the acute and long-term response to endurance exercise in individuals with overweight and obesity [J]. Mol Metab. 2025;98:102185.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>