<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41416873</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tissue Flossing: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Its Effects on Range of Motion, Pain, Muscle Strength, and Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>225</StartPage><EndPage>237</EndPage><MedlinePgn>225-237</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005340</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Yao, L, Gan, J, Romagnoli, M, Liu, D, and Staiano, W. Tissue flossing: a systematic review and meta-analysis of its effects on range of motion, pain, muscle strength, and performance. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): 225-237, 2026-This systematic review and meta-analysis evaluated the acute effects of tissue flossing (TF) on joint range of motion (ROM), pain, muscle strength, and exercise performance in healthy individuals, also examining how subjects and intervention factors modify its efficacy. Databases (PubMed, Web of Science, EBSCO, Cochrane Library) were searched through September 2025 for randomized controlled and crossover trials involving TF in healthy subjects. Two independent reviewers handled screening, extraction, methodological quality assessment (Physiotherapy Evidence Database [PEDro] scale), and evidence grading (Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation). We conducted meta-analyses, meta-regressions, and subgroup analyses by gender, training status, application site, and band pressure. Twenty studies ( n = 480) were included. Tissue flossing produced a trivial but significant ROM increase (Hedges' g = 0.19; 95% CI 0.05-0.33; p = 0.01). No significant effects appeared for muscle strength, muscle function, pain, sprint, or jump outcomes. Effectiveness varied by individual and intervention characteristics. The quality of evidence was moderate. Tissue flossing may acutely enhance joint ROM but does not significantly affect performance, and its benefits depend on individual and protocol variables. However, these conclusions are limited by the moderate quality of the available evidence, underscoring the need for more rigorous studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The School of Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Jianyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Coaching College, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romagnoli</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Dongsen</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The School of Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staiano</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1269-0016</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Biological and Cognitive Psychology, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="Y">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064746" MajorTopicYN="Y">Therapy, Soft Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myofascial compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy modalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41416873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrews J, Guyatt G, Oxman AD, et al. GRADE guidelines: 14. Going from evidence to recommendations: The significance and presentation of recommendations. J Clin Epidemiol 66: 719&#x2013;725, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelopoulos P, Mylonas K, Tsepis E, et al. The effects of instrument-assisted soft tissue mobilization, tissue flossing, and kinesiology taping on shoulder functional capacities in amateur athletes. J Sport Rehabil 30: 1028&#x2013;1037, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshem H, Helfand M, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, et al. GRADE guidelines: 3. Rating the quality of evidence. J Clin Epidemiol 64: 401&#x2013;406, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Effect Sizes Based on Means. Introduction to Meta-Analysis. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2021. pp. 21&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: Physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale. J Physiother 66: 59, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheatham SW, Nadeau J, Jackson W, Baker R. Effects of tissue flossing on athletic performance measures: A systematic review. Sports (Basel) 12: 312&#x2013;336, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Cheng F, Yang J, et al. Effect of tissue flossing on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage: A randomized controlled trial. Biol Sport 42: 177&#x2013;184, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The Concepts of Power Analysis. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. (2nd ed.). New York: Routledge, 2013. p. 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colonna S, Casacci F. Myofascial system and physical exercise: A narrative review on stretching (part I). Cureus 16: e75077, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: A new edition of the cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 10: ED000142, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JA, Stecco C, Stecco A. Application of fascial manipulation technique in chronic shoulder pain&#x2014;Anatomical basis and clinical implications. J Bodyw Mov Ther 13: 128&#x2013;135, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Queiros VS, de Fran&#xe7;a IM, Trybulski R, et al. Myoelectric activity and fatigue in low-load resistance exercise with different pressure of blood flow restriction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 12: 786752, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Overmayer RG. The effects of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion and jump performance. Phys Ther Sport 25: 20&#x2013;24, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, Mackay K, Mills B, Tavares F. Tissue flossing on ankle range of motion, jump and sprint performance: A follow-up study. Phys Ther Sport 28: 29&#x2013;33, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: A simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics 56: 455&#x2013;463, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R. Association between elastography-assessed muscle mechanical properties and high-speed dynamic performance. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 1233&#x2013;1239, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Q, Aiken CA, Fang C, Pan Z. Effects of exergaming on physical and cognitive functions in individuals with autism spectrum disorder: A systematic review. Games Health J 8: 74&#x2013;84, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz CO, Morris PE, Richler JJ. Effect size estimates: Current use, calculations, and interpretation. J Exp Psychol Gen 141: 2&#x2013;18, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galis J, Cooper DJ. Application of a floss band at differing pressure levels: Effects at the ankle joint. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2454&#x2013;2460, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godfrey RJ, Madgwick Z, Whyte GP. The exercise-induced growth hormone response in athletes. Sports Med 33: 599&#x2013;613, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ. Testosterone and male ageing: Spinning the wheels. Med J Aust 193: 379&#x2013;380, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 327: 557&#x2013;560, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holsgaard Larsen A, Caserotti P, Puggaard L, Aagaard P. Reproducibility and relationship of single-joint strength vs multi-joint strength and power in aging individuals. Scand J Med Sci Sports 17: 43&#x2013;53, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MT. A comparison of traditional blood flow restriction versus band tissue flossing for induction of muscular fatigue. University of Alabama Libraries, 2021. Available at: http://ir.ua.edu/handle/123456789/8210 . Accessed September 5, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung KB, Kim S, Lee Y Effects on mechanical properties, joint range of motion, and grip strength of forearm muscles depending on wrapping direction of the floss band. Phys Ther Rehabil Sci 13: 95&#x2013;105, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalc M, Mikl S, &#x17d;&#xf6;k&#x161; F, Vogrin M, St&#xf6;ggl T. Effects of different tissue flossing applications on range of motion, maximum voluntary contraction, and H-reflex in young martial arts fighters. Front Physiol 12: 752641, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneda H, Takahira N, Tsuda K, et al. Effects of tissue flossing and dynamic stretching on hamstring muscles function. J Sports Sci Med 19: 681&#x2013;689, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataura S, Suzuki S, Matsuo S, et al. Acute effects of the different intensity of static stretching on flexibility and isometric muscle force. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3403&#x2013;3410, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz B, Zaguri R, Edvardson S, et al. Nociception and pain in humans lacking a functional TRPV1 channel. J Clin Invest 133: e153558, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy MS, Nicholson HD, Woodley SJ. The morphology of the subacromial and related shoulder bursae. An anatomical and histological study. J Anat 240: 941&#x2013;958, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kielur DS, Powden CJ. Changes of ankle dorsiflexion using compression tissue flossing: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Rehabil 30: 306&#x2013;314, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitsuksan T. The application of tissue flossing during plyometric exercise for the prevention of delayed onset muscle soreness. Sci Technol Asia 26: 145154, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingler W, Velders M, Hoppe K, Pedro M, Schleip R. Clinical relevance of fascial tissue and dysfunctions. Curr Pain Headache Rep 18: 439, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama Y, Masuda S, Ohmori T, et al. Response to mechanical properties and physiological challenges of fascia: Diagnosis and rehabilitative therapeutic intervention for myofascial system disorders. Bioeng (Basel) 10: 474, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig H, Goldstone A, Lu CY. Polyamines regulate calcium fluxes in a rapid plasma membrane response. Nature 305: 530&#x2013;534, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Bernsteiner D, Budini F, et al. Tissue flossing of the thigh increases isometric strength acutely but has no effects on flexibility or jump height. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1648&#x2013;1658, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Mo&#x10d;nik R, Nakamura M. Effects of tissue flossing on the healthy and impaired musculoskeletal system: A scoping review. Front Physiol 12: 666129, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 35: 339&#x2013;361, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Li R, Wong SHS, Sum RKW, Sit CHP. The impact of exercise interventions concerning executive functions of children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactive disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 18: 68, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Li R, Wong SHS, et al. The effects of exercise interventions on executive functions in children and adolescents with autism spectrum disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 52: 75&#x2013;88, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald GZ, Penney MDH, Mullaley ME, et al. An acute bout of self-myofascial release increases range of motion without a subsequent decrease in muscle activation or force. J Strength Cond Res 27: 812&#x2013;821, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maemichi T, Ogawa Y, Wakamiya K, et al. Elucidation of the effect of flossing on improving joint range of motion. J Sports Sci Med 24: 75&#x2013;83, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maust Z, Bradney D, Collins SM, Wesley C, Bowman TG. The effects of soft tissue flossing on hamstring range of motion and lower extremity power. Int J Sports Phys Ther 16: 689&#x2013;694, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. The role of rate of force development on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res 25: 379&#x2013;385, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meader N, King K, Llewellyn A, et al. A checklist designed to aid consistency and reproducibility of GRADE assessments: Development and pilot validation. Syst Rev 3: 82, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills B, Mayo B, Tavares F, Driller M. The effect of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion, jump, and sprint performance in elite rugby union athletes. J Sport Rehabil 29: 282&#x2013;286, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372: n71, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paravlic AH, Segula J, Drole K, et al. Tissue flossing around the thigh does not provide acute enhancement of neuromuscular function. Front Physiol 13: 870498, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins RK, Lavin KM, Raue U, et al. Effects of aging and lifelong aerobic exercise on expression of innate immune components in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 129: 1483&#x2013;1492, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Schulz R, Michel S. Tissue flossing: A new short-term compression therapy for reducing exercise-induced delayed-onset muscle soreness. A randomized, controlled and double-blind pilot crossover trial. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 59: 861&#x2013;867, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves GV, Kraemer RR, Hollander DB, et al. Comparison of hormone responses following light resistance exercise with partial vascular occlusion and moderately difficult resistance exercise without occlusion. J Appl Physiol (1985) 101: 1616&#x2013;1622, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano Y, Kawabata M, Nakatani K, et al. Immediate effects of calf tissue flossing on ankle joint torque and dorsiflexion range of motion in healthy individuals: A randomized controlled crossover trial. J Sports Sci Med 23: 778&#x2013;786, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CK, Bonezi A, Alzamendi F, Silva F, Luisa Bona R. Acute effects of tissue flossing on the thigh. J Bodyw Mov Ther 42: 493&#x2013;499, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherrington C, Moseley AM, Herbert RD, Elkins MR, Maher CG. Ten years of evidence to guide physiotherapy interventions: Physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro). Br J Sports Med 44: 836&#x2013;837, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiotani H, Takahashi K, Honma Y, et al. Mechanical linkage between achilles tendon and plantar fascia accounts for range of motion of human ankle-foot complex. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 66&#x2013;73, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starrett K, Cordoza G. Becoming a Supple Leopard 2nd Edition: The Ultimate Guide to Resolving Pain, Preventing Injury, and Optimizing Athletic Performance. Las Vegas: Victory Belt Publishing, 2015. pp. 283&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson PJ, Stevenson RK, Duarte KW. Acute effects of the voodoo flossing band on ankle range of motion. J Med Biomed Appl Sci 7: 244&#x2013;253, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo DA, Neagu N, Ily&#xe9;s P, et al. Range of motion (ROM) and dynamic balance testing through kinetic prophylaxis means (applying tissue flossing) to football players. RREM 15: 154&#x2013;170, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira EL, Barroso R, Silva-Batista C, et al. Blood flow restriction increases metabolic stress but decreases muscle activation during high-load resistance exercise. Muscle Nerve 57: 107&#x2013;111, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veroniki AA, Jackson D, Viechtbauer W, et al. Methods to estimate the between-study variance and its uncertainty in meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods 7: 55&#x2013;79, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidoni A, Gillett M, Botchu R, James S. Lower limb muscle injuries: The good, the bad and the ugly. Eur J Radiol 104: 101&#x2013;107, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogrin M, Kalc M, Li&#x10d;en T. Acute effects of tissue flossing around the upper thigh on neuromuscular performance: A study using different degrees of wrapping pressure. J Sport Rehabil 30: 601&#x2013;608, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogrin M, Novak F, Licen T, et al. Acute effects of tissue flossing on ankle range of motion and tensiomyography parameters. J Sport Rehabil 30: 129&#x2013;135, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wdowski MM, Rosicka K, Hill M. Influence of lower-limb muscular and tendon mechanical properties and strength on countermovement jump performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 63: 16&#x2013;22, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss K, Kalichman L Deep fascia as a potential source of pain: A narrative review. J Bodyw Mov Ther 28: 82&#x2013;86, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke J, Vleeming A, Wearing S. Overuse injury: The result of pathologically altered myofascial force transmission? Exerc Sport Sci Rev 47: 230&#x2013;236, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester LJ, Blake MT, Fleming AR, et al. Hemodynamic responses to resistance exercise with blood flow restriction using a practical method versus a traditional cuff-inflation system. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 11548, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>