<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41150469</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2075-4663</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mental Resilience and Mindfulness in Athletes: A Preliminary Study Across Sports and Experience Levels.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">334</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/sports13100334</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is important to study if and how athletes' mental resilience and mindfulness are connected, because both could promote mental health, as well as facilitate coping with stress and successful athletic performance. It was hypothesized that mental resilience and mindfulness would correlate, and also that mental resilience and mindfulness would differ in both means and correlation strength according to the type of sport. The possible nexus of mental resilience and mindfulness with the longevity of sports practice was also examined. The sample consisted of 177 athletes whose mean age was 21 years old and whose average sports practice lasted 8.7 years. Most of them were professional athletes (<i>N</i> = 121, 68.4%). They practiced individual sports (<i>N</i> = 85, 48.0%), combat sports (<i>N</i> = 47, 26.6%), and team sports (<i>N</i> = 45, 25.4%). The Bulgarian adaptations of the Mindful Attention Awareness Scale and the Brief Resilience Scale were used. The athletes' mental resilience and mindfulness correlated significantly and positively. The athletes' mental resilience correlated positively with the years of sports practice among the amateur athletes and among the athletes practicing team sports. The athletes' mindfulness increased with age for the athletes practicing combat sports and team sports. Mindfulness diminished with more years of sports practice for the amateur athletes and for those practicing individual sports. The athletes practicing combat sports had higher mental resilience than those practicing individual sports and those practicing team sports. The male athletes had higher mental resilience than the female athletes. The established positive nexus between the athletes' mental resilience and mindfulness means that training mindfulness could be a mechanism for strengthening mental resilience, as well as higher mental resilience could facilitate mindful awareness of the present moment and focus attention on what is happening now. The athletes practicing individual sports are those who need more training for enhancing mindfulness and mental resilience. Physical activity and sports participation may contribute to mental health improvement by strengthening mindfulness and mental resilience.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stoyanova</LastName><ForeName>Stanislava</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8873-9285</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, South-West University "Neofit Rilski", 2700 Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ivantchev</LastName><ForeName>Nikolay</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, South-West University "Neofit Rilski", 2700 Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gergov</LastName><ForeName>Teodor</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, South-West University "Neofit Rilski", 2700 Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yordanova</LastName><ForeName>Bilyana</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, South-West University "Neofit Rilski", 2700 Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101722684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2075-4663</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental resilience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mindfulness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41150469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12568208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports13100334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sports13100334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hadzhieva T. Psihosotsialni Aspekti na Hranento i Hranitelnite Razstroistva [Psychosocial Aspects of Eating and Eating Disorders] South-West University &#x201c;Neofit Rilski&#x201d;; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexandrova B., Bogdanova E. Lichnost I aktivnost prez prizmata na nevropsihologiata [Personality and activity through the prism of neuropsychology] In: Nikolov P., Madolev V., Popova R., Krastev L., Rusinova V., Nikolov B., Gaidarov K., Bozhinova D., Mavrodiev S., Mancheva R., editors. Lichnost, Sotsialna Sreda, Aktivnost, 3 Natsionalna Konferentsia s Mezhdunaroddno Uchastie 2006 [Personality, Social Environment, Activity: 3rd National Conference with International Participation 2006] South-West University &#x201c;Neofit Rilski&#x201d; Press; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2008. pp. 353&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naydenova V., Ilieva S. Zdravoslovni praktiki, fizicheska aktivnost i psihosomatichni oplakvania pri studenti [Health practices, physical activity and psychosomatic complaints in students] In: Mutafova-Zaberska Y., editor. Lichnost, Motivatsia, Sport [Personality, Motivation, Sport] Volume 14. University Press of the National Sports Academy; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2009. pp. 188&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penedo F.J., Dahn J.R. Exercise and well-being: A review of mental and physical health benefits associated with physical activity. Curr. Opin. Psychiatry. 2025;18:189&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1097/00001504-200503000-00013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001504-200503000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16639173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozhkova S. Bachelor Thesis. South-West Univerity &#x201c;Neofit Rilski&#x201d;; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2017. Dinamika na Samochuvstvito, Aktivnostta i Nastronieto pri Sportuvashti Fitness [Dynamics of Self-Esteem, Activity and Mood in Fitness Athletes]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochschild J., Stroud E., Marczak M. Physical activity and mental health: A critical review. J. Health Psychol. 2019;24:317&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal J.A., Smith P.J., Hoffman B.M. Exercise and depression: A review of reviews. J. Clin. Psychol. 2007;63:969&#x2013;977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loginova I. Psihologicheskoe Zdorove Cheloveka: Zhiznenii Resurs i Zhiznenii Portentsial [Psychological Health of a Person: Life Resource and Life Potential] Verso Publishing House; Krasnoyarsk, Russia: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikiforova G. Psihologia Zdorovia [Psychology of Health] Peter Publishing House; St. Petersburg, Russia: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman R.S., Aghajanian G.K. Synaptic plasticity and depression: New insights from stress and rapid-acting antidepressants. Nat. Med. 2012;18:1820&#x2013;1829. doi: 10.1038/nm.4050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.4050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5405628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26937618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen K., Stojanovic J., Berg S. The effects of physical exercise on mental health: The role of endorphins. J. Ment. Health. 2017;26:171&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  Constitution of the World Health Organization. 1946.  [(accessed on 17 February 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.who.int/about/governance/constitution.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M. Izsledvane na nyakoi lichnostni harakteristiki pri sportuvashti i nesportuvashti studenti [Study of some personal peculiarities in students practicing and non-practicing sport] In: Popov N., editor. Lichnost. Motivatsiya. Sport [Personality. Motivation. Sport] Volume 11. National Sports Academy Press; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2006. pp. 173&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiev M. Psihologicheski trening za izgrazhdane na aktivna psihicheska protivostresova zashtita [Psychological training for building active mental stress protection] In: Popov N., editor. Lichnost, Motivatsiya, Sport [Personality, Motivation, Sport] Volume 2. National Sports Academy PRES; Sofia, Bulgaria: 1996. pp. 35&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denny K.G., Steiner H. External and internal factors influencing happiness in elite collegiate athletes. Child Psychiatry Hum. Dev. 2008;40:55&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1007/s10578-008-0111-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10578-008-0111-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avci Taskiran T., Gurbuz B. The investigation of the relationship between perceived freedom and brief resilience: The role of participation in physical activity. Balt. J. Health Phys. Act. 2021;13((Suppl. S1)):19&#x2013;28. doi: 10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.1.03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.1.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisyov K. Researching of the joint angles on the legs, during the support period of the move step in classic mountain running. Trakia J. Sci. 2023;21((Suppl. S1)):577&#x2013;582. doi: 10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.1.03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.1.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihaylova T.S. Trevozhnost i Psihichna Ustoychivost [Anxiety and Mental Resilience] Avangard Prima; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kareva R. Kratka skala za rezilentnost (BRS) na balgarski: Otsenyavane na sposobnostta za vazstanovyavane ot neblagopriyatni sabitiya [The Brief Resilience Scale (BRS) in Bulgarian: Assessing the ability to bounce back from adverse events] Psychol. Res. 2021;24:23&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoyanova S., Miteva S., Ivantchev N. Perceived threat of COVID-19, self-assessment of physical health and mental resilience. Philos. Psychol. 2022;37:428&#x2013;454. doi: 10.1080/09515089.2022.2086456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09515089.2022.2086456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balcombe L., De Leo D., Turner M.J. Athlete psychological resilience and digital mental health implementation. Front. Psychol. 2022;13:1082998. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1082998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1082998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36532980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barik P., Kar R. Comparison of sports specific personality traits among invasion, target, striking/fielding and net/wall games. Int. J. Physiol. Nutr. Phys. Educ. 2019;4:2016&#x2013;2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobasa S.C., Maddi S.R., Kahn S. Hardiness and health: A prospective study. J. Personal. Social Psychol. 1982;42:168&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.42.1.168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.42.1.168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7057354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobasa S.C., Maddi S.R., Puccetti M.C. Personality and exercise as buffers in the stress-illness relationship. J. Behav. Med. 1982;5:391&#x2013;404. doi: 10.1007/BF00845369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00845369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus R.S., Folkman S. Stress, Appraisal, and Coping. Springer; New York, NY, USA: 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihaylova T.S. Ph.D. Thesis. South-West University &#x201c;Neofit Rilski&#x201d;; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2020. Blagopoluchie v Trudni Zhiteyski Situatsii [Well-Being in Difficult Life Situations]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong P.T.P. Toward a dual-systems model of what makes life worth living. In: Wong P.T.P., editor. The Human Quest for Meaning: Theories, Research and Applications. 2nd ed. Routledge, Taylor &amp; Francis Group; New York, NY, USA: 2012. pp. 3&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodopyanova N.E., Starchenkova E.S. Rol resursno-investitsionnogo kopinga v emotsionalnom perezhivanii ekstremalnykh situatsiy i razvitii individualnoy stress-rezistentnosti [The role of resource-investment coping in the emotional experience of extreme situations and the development of individual stress-resistance] Vestn. St. Peterbg. Univ. 2009;12:13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsenova B. Lichnostni korelati na barnaut-sindroma [Personality correlates of burnout syndrome] In: Nikolov P., editor. III Natsionalen Kongres po Psihologiya: Sbornik Nauchni Dokladi, Sofiya, 28&#x2013;23 oktomvri 2005 g. [III National Congress of Psychology: Collection of Scientific Papers, Sofia, 28&#x2013;23 October 2005] Sofi-R; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2005. pp. 360&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecherkina A.A., Ershova I.A., Novikova O.V. Issledovaniye ustanovok suprugov s raznoy stepen&#x2019;yu udovletvorennosti brakom [A study of the attitudes of spouses with different degrees of marital satisfaction] Pedagog. Obraz. V Ross. 2019;9:163&#x2013;168. doi: 10.26170/po19-09-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26170/po19-09-22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gergov T. Zhizneustoichivost i Samootsenka Prez Zrelostta [Resilience and Self-Esteem in Maturity] South-West University Press; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green K.T., Hayward L.C., Williams A.M., Dennis P.A., Bryan B.C., Taber K.H., Mid-Atlantic Mental Illness Research, Education and Clinical Center Workgroup. Davidson J.R., Beckham J.C., Calhoun P.S. Examining the factor structure of the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC) in a post-9/11 U.S. military veteran sample. Assessment. 2014;21:443&#x2013;451. doi: 10.1177/1073191114524014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1073191114524014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4147024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24586090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaishnavi S., Connor K., Davidson J.R. An abbreviated version of the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC), the CD-RISC2: Psychometric properties and applications in psychopharmacological trials. Psychiatry Res. 2007;152:293&#x2013;297. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2007.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2007.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2041449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17459488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagnild G.M., Young H.M. Development and psychometric evaluation of the resilience scale. J. Nurs. Meas. 1993;1:165&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7850498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith B.W., Dalen J., Wiggins K., Tooley E., Christopher P., Bernard J. The brief resilience scale: Assessing the ability to bounce back. Int. J. Behav. Med. 2008;15:194&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1080/10705500802222972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705500802222972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18696313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuetzel B. Coping strategies for handling stress and providing mental health in elite athletes: A systematic review. Front. Sports Act. Living. 2023;5:1265783. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2023.1265783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1265783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38033656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor K.M., Davidson J.R.T. Development of a new resilience scale: The Connor-Davidson Resilience scale (CD-RISC) Depress. Anxiety. 2003;18:76&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1002/da.10113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.10113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12964174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero C.P., Jejurikar N., Carter C.W. The psychology of the female athlete: How mental health and wellness mediate sports performance, injury and recovery. Ann. Jt. 2021;6:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.21037/aoj-20-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/aoj-20-53</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbova B.P. Ph.D. Thesis. Sofia Univrsity &#x201c;St. Kliment Ohridski&#x201d;; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2019. Stres i Blagopoluchie vav Visokoriskova Sreda [Stress and Well-Being in a High-Risk Environment]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alispahic S., Hasanbegovic-Anic E. Mindfulness: Age and gender differences on a Bosnian Sample. Psychol. Thought. 2017;10:155&#x2013;166. doi: 10.5964/psyct.v10i1.224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5964/psyct.v10i1.224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorozhevets A.N. Kognitivnyye mekhanizmy adaptatsii k krizisnym sobytiyam [Cognitive mechanisms of adaptation to crisis events] Zhurnal Prakt. Psikhologa. 1998;4:3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lake A.E., III Headache as a stressor: Dysfunctional versus adaptive coping styles. Headache. 2009;49:1369&#x2013;1377. doi: 10.1111/j.1526-4610.2009.01516.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1526-4610.2009.01516.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J.D., Pacilio L.E., Lindsay E.K., Brown K.W. Brief mindfulness meditation training alters psychological and neuroendocrine responses to social evaluative stress. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;44:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.02.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24767614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuman-Olivier Z., Trombka M., Lovas D.A., Brewer J.A., Vago D.R., Gawande R., Dunne J.P., Lazar S.W., Loucks E.B., Fulwiler C. Mindfulness and behavior change. Harv. Rev. Psychiatry. 2020;28:371&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1097/HRP.0000000000000277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HRP.0000000000000277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7647439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33156156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tugade M.M., Fredrickson B.L. Resilient individuals use positive emotions to bounce back from negative emotional experiences. J. Personal. Soc. Psychol. 2004;86:320&#x2013;333. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.86.2.320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.86.2.320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3132556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y.H., Chiu W., Hwang J., Noh S. Mobile-based mindfulness meditation intervention&#x2019;s impact on mental health among young male judo athletes in South Korea: A quasi-experimental study. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:12691. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-63637-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-63637-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11148055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D., Lawlor P. Analysis of effective mindfulness training in east asian dominant sports: A comparative study. J. Stud. Res. 2023;12:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.47611/jsrhs.v12i4.5758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47611/jsrhs.v12i4.5758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidic Z. Sharpening the mental edge in ice-hockey: Impact of a season-long psychological skills training and mindfulness intervention on athletic coping skills, resilience, stress and mindfulness. J. Sport Behav. 2021;44:468&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F., Zhang Z., Liu S., Zhang N., Siu P.M. Examining the effects of brief mindfulness training on athletes&#x2019; flow: The mediating role of resilience. Evid. Based Complement. Altern. Med. 2021;2021:8. doi: 10.1155/2021/6633658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6633658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8166472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34122602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Jing L., Liu Y., Wang H. Association of mindfulness on state-trait anxiety in choking-susceptible athletes: Mediating roles of resilience and perceived stress. Front. Psychol. 2023;14:1232929. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1232929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1232929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37711325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholls A.R., Polman R.C.J. Coping in sport: A systematic review. J. Sports Sci. 2007;25:11&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/02640410600630654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410600630654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Z., Jiang H., Wang H., Liu Y. The association between mindfulness and athletes&#x2019; distress tolerance: The mediating roles of cognitive reappraisal and mental toughness. Behav. Sci. 2025;15:298. doi: 10.3390/bs15030298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs15030298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11939238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40150193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuellar N.G. Resiliency recovery post COVID-19. J. Transcult. Nurs. 2020;31:433. doi: 10.1177/1043659620939652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1043659620939652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32794437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguntuase S.B., Sun Y. Effects of mindfulness training on resilience, self-confidence and emotion regulation of elite football players: The mediating role of locus of control. Asian J. Sport Exerc. Psychol. 2022;2:198&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.ajsep.2022.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajsep.2022.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee A., Biswas R.A. A comparative study on mindfulness among different sports persons. Int. J. Phys. Educ. Sports Health. 2021;8:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebar A.L., Stanton R., Geard D., Short C.E. The role of social support in the relationship between physical activity and mental health. Ment. Health Phys. Act. 2015;9:45&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guszkowska M., Wojcik K. Effect of mental toughness on sporting performance: Review of studies. Balt. J. Health Phys. Act. 2021;13((Suppl. S2)):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.2.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29359/BJHPA.2021.Suppl.2.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Sun J., Zhou Y., Gong L., Huang S. The effect of mindfulness training on the psychological state of high-level athletes: Meta analysis and system evaluation research. J. Sports Sci. 2025;43:600&#x2013;622. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2025.2468997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2025.2468997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajilchi B., Amini H.R., Ardakani Z.P., Zadeh M.M., Kisely S. Applying mindfulness training to enhance the mental toughness and emotional intelligence of amateur basketball players. Australas. Psychiatry Bull. R. Aust. N. Z. Coll. Psychiatr. 2019;27:291&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1177/1039856219828119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1039856219828119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30763131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batey J., Symes R. Ahead of the competition: Anxiety control in archery. In: Cotterill S., Weston N., Breslin G., editors. Sport and Exercise Psychology: Practitioner Case Studies. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2017. pp. 125&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holder T. The use of team strengths at a major championship. In: Cotterill S., Weston N., Breslin G., editors. Sport and Exercise Psychology: Practitioner Case Studies. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2017. pp. 21&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piermatt&#xe9;o A., Lo Monaco G., Reymond G., Eyraud M., Dany L. The meaning of sport and performance among amateur and professional athletes. Int. J. Sport Exerc. Psychol. 2018;18:472&#x2013;484. doi: 10.1080/1612197X.2018.1536160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1612197X.2018.1536160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kov&#xe1;cs K.E. Factors influencing sport persistence along the socio-ecological model-a presentation of sport persistence models based on the findings of a representative Hungarian sample. Sports. 2025;13:97. doi: 10.3390/sports13040097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports13040097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12030790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40278723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai C., Mei Z., Yang Y., Luo S. From adversity to adaptation: The struggle between resilience and athlete burnout in stressful situations. Front. Psychol. 2025;16:1578198. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1578198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1578198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12162697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40519831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli N., Vealey R.S. &#x201c;Bouncing back&#x201d; from adversity: Athletes&#x2019; experiences of resilience. Sport Psychol. 2008;22:316&#x2013;335. doi: 10.1123/tsp.22.3.316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/tsp.22.3.316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association  WMA Declaration of Helsinki&#x2014;Ethical Principles for Medical Research Involving Human Subjects.  [(accessed on 13 August 2024)].  Available online:  https://www.wma.net/policies-post/wma-declaration-of-helsinki-ethical-principles-for-medical-research-involving-human-subjects/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; New Jersey, NJ, USA: 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Garc&#xed;a C., Acebes-S&#xe1;nchez J., Rodriguez-Romo G., Mon-L&#xf3;pez D. Resilience in sports: Sport type, gender, age and sport level differences. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2021;18:8196. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18158196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18158196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grim C. Triathlon&#x2014;An individual multidiscipline sport with a multidisciplinary approach for the athletes&#x2019; health. Ger. J. Sports Med. 2020;71:227&#x2013;228. doi: 10.5960/dzsm.2020.464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5960/dzsm.2020.464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhelyazkova&#x2013;Koynova Z., Chervenkova L., Yordanov V. Balgarska adaptatsiya na test za izsledvane na osaznatostta (mindfulness) [Bulgarian adaptation of a test measuring mindfulness] In: Georgiev M., editor. Lichnost. Motivatsiya. Sport [Person. Motivation. Sport] Volume 15. National Sports Academy Press; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2010. pp. 121&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K.W., Ryan R.M. The benefits of being present: Mindfulness and its role in psychological well-being. J. Personal. Social Psychol. 2003;84:822&#x2013;848. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakracheva M. Proaktiven Mayndfulnes&#x2014;Patishta kam Psihichno Blagopoluchie i Protsaftyavane [Proactive Mindfulness&#x2014;Pathways to Psychological Well-Being and Flourishing] Sofia University &#x201c;St. Kliment Ohridski&#x201d; Press; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farewell C.V., Jewell J., Walls J., Leiferman J.A. A mixed-methods pilot study of perinatal risk and resilience during COVID-19. J. Prim. Care Community Health. 2020;11:2150132720944074. doi: 10.1177/2150132720944074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2150132720944074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzhambov A., Tilov B., Makakova D., Dimitrova D. Psychometric properties and contribution to mental health of the Bulgarian version of the 4-factor Ruminative Thought Style Questionnaire. Folia Medica. 2019;61:529&#x2013;539. doi: 10.3897/folmed.61.e47726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3897/folmed.61.e47726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soper D. Calculator: Significance of the Difference Between Two Correlations. Free Statistics Calculators Version 4.0. 2025.  [(accessed on 2 March 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.danielsoper.com/statcalc/calculator.aspx?id=104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johanson G.A., Brooks G.P. Initial scale development: Sample size for pilot studies. Educ. Psychol. Meas. 2010;70:394&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1177/0013164409355692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0013164409355692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics How to Holm-Bonferroni Method: Step by Step. 2025.  [(accessed on 3 June 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.statisticshowto.com/holm-bonferroni-method/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes W. Benjamini&#x2013;Hochberg Method. In: Dubitzky W., Wolkenhauer O., Cho K.H., Yokota H., editors. Encyclopedia of Systems Biology. Springer; New York, NY, USA: 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4419-9863-7_1215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermaier L. Controlling Your Type I Errors: Bonferroni and Benjamini-Hochberg. 2024.  [(accessed on 2 June 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.statsig.com/blog/controlling-type-i-errors-bonferroni-benjamini-hochberg.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenhard W., Lenhard A. Computation of Effect Sizes. Psychometrica. 2022.  [(accessed on 16 March 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.psychometrica.de/effect_size.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouder J.N., Speckman P.L., Sun D., Morey R.D., Iverson G. Bayesian t-tests for accepting and rejecting the null hypothesis. Psychon. Bull. Rev. 2009;16:225&#x2013;237. doi: 10.3758/PBR.16.2.225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/PBR.16.2.225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19293088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelter R. Analysis of Bayesian posterior significance and effect size indices for the two-sample t-test to support reproducible medical research. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 2020;20:88. doi: 10.1186/s12874-020-00968-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-020-00968-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7178740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelova N., Mavrodiev S. Scoping review of psychological research and publications related to the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic and the measures taken. Psychol. Thought. 2024;17:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.37708/psyct.v17i1.956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37708/psyct.v17i1.956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shook N.J., Ford C., Strough J., Delaney R., Barker D. In the moment and feeling good: Age differences in mindfulness and positive affect. Transl. Issues Psychol. Sci. 2017;3:338&#x2013;347. doi: 10.1037/tps0000139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/tps0000139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman K.A., Glass C.R., Arnkoff D.B. Evaluation of mindful sport performance enhancement (MSPE): A new approach to promote flow in athletes. J. Clin. Sport Psychol. 2009;3:334&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1123/jcsp.3.4.334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jcsp.3.4.334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadzhieva T. Ph.D. Thesis. South-West University &#x201c;Neofit Rilski&#x201d;; Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria: 2019. Potrebnosti i Samootsenka pri Sportuvashti i Nesportuvashti Student [Needs and Self-Esteem in Students Practicing and Non-Practicing Sport]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiel A., Diehl K., Giel K.E., Schnell A., Schubring A.M., Mayer J., Zipfel S., Schneider S. The German young Olympic athletes&#x2019; lifestyle and health management study (GOAL study): Design of a mixed-method study. BMC Public Health. 2011;11:410&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-11-410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-11-410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3141443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21627777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannouli V. Are sex differences in self-estimated intelligence an elusive phenomenon? Exploring the role of working memory, creativity, and other psychological correlates in young and older adults. Brain Behav. 2022;13:e2857. doi: 10.1002/brb3.2857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.2857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9927843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36704836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner H., Weijters B., Pieters R. The biasing effect of common method variance: Some clarifications. J. Acad. Mark. Sci. 2021;49:221&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1007/s11747-020-00766-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11747-020-00766-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper B., Eva N., Zarea Fazlelahi F., Newman A., Lee A., Obschonka M. Addressing common method variance and endogeneity in vocational behavior research: A review of the literature and suggestions for future research. J. Vocat. Behav. 2020;121:103472. doi: 10.1016/j.jvb.2020.103472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvb.2020.103472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kock F., Berbekova A., Assaf A.G. Understanding and managing the threat of common method bias: Detection, prevention and control. Tour. Manag. 2021;86:104330. doi: 10.1016/j.tourman.2021.104330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tourman.2021.104330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner H., Weijters B. Dealing with Common Method Variance in international marketing Research. J. Int. Mark. 2021;29:7&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1177/1069031X21995871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1069031X21995871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>