<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41928364</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2049-3002</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cancer &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>PER2 knockdown drives immunotherapy resistance in gastric cancer via metabolic reprogramming of myeloid-derived suppressor cells.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40170-026-00424-7</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Shenggang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Shenzhen People's Hospital, The Second Clinical Medical College, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital, Southern University of Science and Technology, No. 3046 Shennan East Road, Luohu District, Shenzhen, Guangdong, 518020, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Shixi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Class Ward 2 of The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, 510632, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Shenzhen People's Hospital, The Second Clinical Medical College, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital, Southern University of Science and Technology, No. 3046 Shennan East Road, Luohu District, Shenzhen, Guangdong, 518020, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Haitao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital, Southern University of Science and Technology, No. 3046 Shennan East Road, Luohu District, Shenzhen, Guangdong, 518020, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Medical Research Center, Shenzhen People's Hospital, The Second Clinical Medical College, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Wenbiao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Shenzhen People's Hospital, The Second Clinical Medical College, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China. chanwenbiao@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital, Southern University of Science and Technology, No. 3046 Shennan East Road, Luohu District, Shenzhen, Guangdong, 518020, China. chanwenbiao@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SYWGSJCYJ202406</GrantID><Agency>Shenzhen People's Hospital Clinical Scientist Training "Five Three" Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JCYJ20240813104108012</GrantID><Agency>Shenzhen Basic Research Project (Natural Science Foundation)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cancer Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607582</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-3002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PER2 knockdown</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune checkpoint inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lactate metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myeloid-derived suppressor cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STAT3 signaling pathway</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All animal experiments were conducted in accordance with the guidelines for the care and use of laboratory animals and were approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC) of Shenzhen People&#x2019;s Hospital, The Second Clinical Medical College of Jinan University, and The First Affiliated Hospital of Southern University of Science and Technology. All procedures complied with relevant institutional and national regulations and were performed in accordance with the ARRIVE guidelines to minimize animal suffering. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41928364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40170-026-00424-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40170-026-00424-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Morgan E, Arnold M, Camargo MC, et al. The current and future incidence and mortality of gastric cancer in 185 countries, 2020&#x2013;40: A population-based modelling study. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;47:101404. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang WJ, Zhao HP, Yu Y, et al. Updates on global epidemiology, risk and prognostic factors of gastric cancer. World J Gastroenterol. 2023;29(16):2452&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v29.i16.2452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kono K, Nakajima S, Mimura K. Current status of immune checkpoint inhibitors for gastric cancer. Gastric Cancer. 2020;23(4):565&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10120-020-01090-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Xie T, Zhang X, Qi C, Shen L, Peng Z. Immune checkpoint inhibitors for treatment of advanced gastric or gastroesophageal junction cancer: current evidence and future perspectives. Chin J Cancer Res. 2020;32(3):287&#x2013;302. https://doi.org/10.21147/j.issn.1000-9604.2020.03.02.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng D, Li M, Zhou R, et al. Tumor microenvironment characterization in gastric cancer identifies prognostic and immunotherapeutically relevant gene signatures. Cancer Immunol Res. 2019;7(5):737&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1158/2326-6066.cir-18-0436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang F, Zhang T, Li Q, Chen X, Jiang F, Shen X. The tumor immune-microenvironment in gastric cancer. Tumori. 2022;108(6):541&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1177/03008916211070051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Renz BW, Ilmer M, et al. Myeloid-Derived suppressor cells in solid tumors. Cells. 2022;11(2):310. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11020310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Luo Y, Rao D, et al. Myeloid-derived suppressor cells in cancer: therapeutic targets to overcome tumor immune evasion. Exp Hematol Oncol. 2024;13(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s40164-024-00505-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu HP, Wang CY, Hsieh PY, Fang JH, Chen YL. Knockdown of serine/threonine-protein kinase 24 promotes tumorigenesis and myeloid-derived suppressor cell expansion in an orthotopic immunocompetent gastric cancer animal model. J Cancer. 2020;11(1):213&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.7150/jca.35821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Chen X, Zheng S, et al. The expansion of MDSCs induced by exosomal PD-L1 promotes the progression of gastric cancer. J Transl Med. 2024;22(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-024-05611-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Chen Z, Sui W, Han W. Recent advances in the mechanisms of PD-L1 expression in gastric cancer: a review. Biol Res. 2025;58(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s40659-025-00597-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren R, Xiong C, Ma R, et al. The recent progress of myeloid-derived suppressor cell and its targeted therapies in cancers. MedComm. 2023;4(4). https://doi.org/10.1002/mco2.323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C, Lan P, Fu L. The role of myeloid-derived suppressor cells in Gastrointestinal cancer. Cancer Commun. 2021;41(6):442&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1002/cac2.12156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Chen J, Wen Z, et al. The role of circadian clock genes in colorectal carcinoma: novel insights into regulatory mechanism and implications in clinical therapy. Life Sci. 2023;333:122145. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2023.122145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cal-Kayitmazbatir S, Francey LJ, Lee Y, Liu AC, Hogenesch JB. PSMD11 modulates circadian clock function through PER and CRY nuclear translocation. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(3):e0283463. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0283463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L, Cen H, Weng J, et al. PER2 integrates circadian disruption and pituitary tumorigenesis. Theranostics. 2023;13(8):2657&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.7150/thno.82995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, de la Pe&#xf1;a JB, Cheong JH, Kim HJ. Neurobiological functions of the period circadian clock 2 Gene, Per2. Biomolecules Ther. 2018;26(4):358&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.4062/biomolther.2017.131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang-Verslues WW, Chang PH, Jeng YM, et al. Loss of corepressor PER2 under hypoxia up-regulates OCT1-mediated EMT gene expression and enhances tumor malignancy. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110(30):12331&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1222684110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Wood PA, Oh EY, Du-Quiton J, Ansell CM, Hrushesky WJM. Down regulation of circadian clock gene period 2 accelerates breast cancer growth by altering its daily growth rhythm. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2008;117(2):423&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-008-0133-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang R, Cui Y, Wang Y, et al. Circadian clock gene Per2 downregulation in non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer is associated with tumour progression and metastasis. Oncol Rep Published Online September. 2018;13. https://doi.org/10.3892/or.2018.6704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xian H, Li Y, Zou B, et al. Identification of TIMELESS and RORA as key clock molecules of non-small cell lung cancer and the comprehensive analysis. BMC Cancer. 2022;22(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s12885-022-09203-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Zhuang Y, Zhong M, et al. Period 2 suppresses the malignant cellular behaviors of colorectal cancer through the epithelial-mesenchymal transformation process. Cancer Control. 2022;29. https://doi.org/10.1177/10732748221081369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Ji Y, Chen X, et al. KDM6A phosphorylation suppresses PER2 to confer a glycolytic vulnerability in HNSCC. Cell Death Dis. 2025;16(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-025-08130-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiello I, Fedele MLM, Rom&#xe1;n F, et al. Circadian disruption promotes tumor-immune microenvironment remodeling favoring tumor cell proliferation. Sci Adv. 2020;6(42). https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aaz4530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Ao Y, Yang K, Tang H, Chen D. Circadian clock gene Per2 plays an important role in cell proliferation, apoptosis and cell cycle progression in human oral squamous cell carcinoma. Oncol Rep. 2016;35(6):3387&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.3892/or.2016.4724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Wang Q, Huang X, et al. Lactate in the tumor microenvironment: a rising star for targeted tumor therapy. Front Nutr. 2023;10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2023.1113739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jia A, Bi Y, Wang Y, Liu G. Metabolic regulation of Myeloid-Derived suppressor cell function in cancer. Cells. 2020;9(4):1011. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells9041011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x41a; T, Dong JH, Wang D, Li F, Zhang ZT. MIR-147B regulated proliferation and apoptosis of gastric cancer cells by targeting CPEB2 via the PTEN pathway. Balkan J Med Genet. 2022;25(1):61&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.2478/bjmg-2022-0007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wilt E, Lu X. Human isogenic cell line models for neutrophils and myeloid-derived suppressor cells. IJMS. 2020;21(20):7709. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21207709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M, Qi B, Xiaoxiang W, Xu J, Liu X. Baicalein increases cisplatin sensitivity of A549 lung adenocarcinoma cells via PI3K/Akt/NF-&#x3ba;B pathway. Biomed Pharmacother. 2017;90:677&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2017.04.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng CQ, Fan HX, Li XX, Li JJ, Sheng S, Zhang F. Resveratrol alleviates levodopa-induced dyskinesia in rats. Front Immunol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.683577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong H, Koh J, Kim S, et al. Cell-intrinsic PD-L1 signaling drives immunosuppression by myeloid-derived suppressor cells through IL-6/Jak/Stat3 in PD-L1-high lung cancer. J Immunother Cancer. 2025;13(3):e010612. https://doi.org/10.1136/jitc-2024-010612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng Y, Chen Y, Xia X, et al. PAD2-mediated citrullination of STAT3 enhances immunosuppressive function of PMN-MDSCs in tumor-bearing hosts. Int Immunopharmacol. 2025;164:115303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intimp.2025.115303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortin BM, Pfeiffer SM, Insua-Rodr&#xed;guez J, et al. Circadian control of tumor immunosuppression affects efficacy of immune checkpoint Blockade. Nat Immunol. 2024;25(7):1257&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41590-024-01859-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W, Chu TH, Nienh&#xfc;ser H, et al. PD-1 signaling promotes Tumor-Infiltrating Myeloid-Derived suppressor cells and gastric tumorigenesis in mice. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(3):781&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2020.10.036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsumi C, Ohuchida K, Katayama N, et al. Tumor-infiltrating monocytic myeloid-derived suppressor cells contribute to the development of an immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment in gastric cancer. Gastric Cancer. 2024;27(2):248&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10120-023-01456-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su YL, Banerjee S, White SV, Kortylewski M. STAT3 in Tumor-Associated myeloid cells: multitasking to disrupt immunity. IJMS. 2018;19(6):1803. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms19061803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillmer EJ, Zhang H, Li HS, Watowich SS. STAT3 signaling in immunity. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2016;31:1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cytogfr.2016.05.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Zakeri A, Alban T, et al. VISTA promotes the metabolism and differentiation of myeloid-derived suppressor cells by STAT3 and polyamine-dependent mechanisms. Cell Rep. 2024;43(1):113661. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2023.113661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Pan M, Liu M, et al. Lactate: a rising star in tumors and inflammation. Front Immunol. 2024;15. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1496390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu XY, Yang JL, Lai R, et al. Impact of lactate on immune cell function in the tumor microenvironment: mechanisms and therapeutic perspectives. Front Immunol. 2025;16. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2025.1563303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotoh T, Kim JK, Liu J, et al. Model-driven experimental approach reveals the complex regulatory distribution of p53 by the circadian factor period 2. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113(47):13516&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1607984113.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>