<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851593</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Return-to-Play Criteria Following Lower Limb Muscle Injuries in Soccer: A Systematic Review with Evidence Synthesis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02404-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective was to systematically identify and categorize return-to-play (RTP) domains and criteria used following muscle injuries in male soccer players, and to describe the certainty of the evidence according to the number, design and methodological quality of the studies implementing RTP criteria within each domain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In total, six databases were searched up to 10 March 2024. Studies reporting RTP criteria for hamstring, adductor, quadriceps, and calf injuries, as well as general criteria for all muscle injuries, were included. The certainty of evidence for RTP criteria was assessed on the basis of the studies citing each criterion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Out of 58,057 records, 135 studies met the inclusion criteria. Strength and pain criteria are the most cited tests for determining RTP clearance following hamstring injuries, particularly criteria related to between-limb knee flexors/extensors strength symmetry and no pain during soccer-specific actions. Range of motion criteria (active knee extension, passive and active straight leg raise, and Askling-H tests) and subjective readiness demonstrated the highest certainty of evidence in RTP decision making after hamstring injuries. RTP criteria following adductor injuries showed a moderate-to-very-low certainty of evidence across domains. Criteria for quadriceps and calf injuries ranged from low to very low evidence, while general lower limb muscle injury criteria had only very low evidence. Following adductor injuries, the highest evidence (moderate) was shown by pain assessments and completing at least one full team training session.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Symmetry between limbs in knee flexor and extensor strength combined with no pain during soccer-specific actions were the most frequently implemented RTP criteria for hamstring injuries. In addition, range of motion evaluation (i.e., active knee extension, passive and active straight leg raise, and Askling-H tests) and subjective readiness assessments have been more consistently employed in higher-quality intervention studies than other domains following hamstring injuries in soccer players. Pain assessments, completing at least one full team training session and restoring strength levels are the most cited criteria for RTP following adductor injuries. The evidence base describing RTP criteria for quadriceps and calf injuries is limited and is not implemented in randomized controlled trials with high methodological quality, highlighting the need for further robust research in these domains.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO CRD42022363836.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pecci</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2842-3067</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, University of Seville, Seville, Spain. jpecci@us.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Dyk</LastName><ForeName>Nicol</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0724-5997</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section Sports Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Physiotherapy and Sport Sciences, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myer</LastName><ForeName>Gregory D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9983-8422</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance And Research Center (SPARC), Emory University School of Medicine, Flowery Branch, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wallace H. Coulter Department of Biomedical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology and Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sa&#xf1;udo</LastName><ForeName>Borja</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9969-9573</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, University of Seville, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FPU22/01315</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Universidades</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: The authors declare no conflict of interests. Financial disclosures Gregory D. Myer consults with commercial entities to support commercialization strategies and applications to the US Food and Drug Administration but has no direct financial interest in the commercialization of the products. Dr. Myer&#x2019;s institution receives current and ongoing grant funding from National Institutes of Health/NIAMS (U01AR067997, R01AR070474, R01AR055563, R01AR076153, R01AR077248, R61AT012421), Department of Defense (W81XWH22C0062), and Arthritis Foundation (OACTN). Dr. Myer has received industry-sponsored research funding to his institutions related to injury prevention and sport performance and has current ongoing funding from Arthrex Inc. to evaluate ACL surgical treatment optimization strategies. Dr. Myer receives author royalties from Human Kinetics and Wolters Kluwer. Dr. Myer is an inventor of biofeedback technologies (patent no. US11350854B2, Augmented and Virtual Reality for Sport Performance and Injury Prevention Application, approval date: 6 July 2022, software copyrighted), designed to enhance rehabilitation and prevent injuries. Dr. Myer receives inventor-related royalties from biofeedback technologies (Include Health: LIC1907082014-0706). Patient Involvement: Not applicable. Ethical Approval: Not applicable. Data Sharing: All data relevant to the study are included in the article or are available as supplementary files. Author Contributions: J.P., N.V.D., G.D.M. and B.S. conceptualized the study; J.P. and B.S. were involved in the data curation and investigation process; J.P., N.V.D., G.D.M. and B.S. contributed to the methodology and the project administration of the study, as well as to the resources; J.P. and B.S. were involved in the software part for the present study; B.S. supervised the study; N.V.D. and G.D.M. were responsible for the validation of the study; J.P. was responsible for the visualization part of the study, creating figures and visual material and also wrote the original draft; N.V.D., G.D.M. and B.S. reviewed and edited the final draft.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02404-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02404-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, Spreco A, Bengtsson H, Bahr R. Injury rates decreased in men&#x2019;s professional football: an 18-year prospective cohort study of almost 12 000 injuries sustained during 1.8 million hours of play. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:1084&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8458074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulici L, Certa D, Zago M, Volpi P, Esposito F. Injury burden in professional European football (soccer): systematic review, meta-analysis, and economic considerations. Clin J Sport Med. 2023;33:450&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M, Ekstrand J. Injuries among male and female elite football players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19:819&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18980604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2008.00861.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, Hagglund M, Walden M. Injury incidence and injury patterns in professional football: the UEFA injury study. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:553&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19553225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2009.060582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M. Epidemiology of muscle injuries in professional football (soccer). Am J Sports Med. 2011;39:1226&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21335353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510395879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Villa F, Massa B, Bortolami A, Nanni G, Olmo J, Buckthorpe M. Injury mechanisms and situational patterns of severe lower limb muscle injuries in male professional football (soccer) players: a systematic video analysis study on 103 cases. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:1550&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37898508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Pulido JJ, Beato M, Ponce-Bord&#xf3;n JC, L&#xf3;pez del Campo R, Resta R, et al. Analysis of the effect of injuries on match performance variables in professional soccer players: a retrospective, experimental longitudinal design. Sports Med Open. 2022;8:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8894514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00427-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Calvo T, Rojas-Valverde D, del L&#xf3;pez Campo R, Resta R, Diaz-Garc&#xed;a J, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Understanding the impact of hamstring injuries on match performance in Spanish professional soccer players. Kinesiology. 2023;55:375&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26582/k.55.2.18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgans R, Rhodes D, Bezuglov E, Etemad O, Di Michele R, Teixeira JE, et al. The impact of injury on match running performance following the return to competitive match-play over two consecutive seasons in elite European soccer players. J Phys Educ Sport. 2023;23:1142&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley R, Massey A, Gabbett T, Blanch P, Cameron M, Conlan G, et al. Match high-speed running distances are often suppressed after return from hamstring strain injury in professional footballers. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2021;13:290&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120964456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valera-Garrido F, Jim&#xe9;nez-Rubio S, Minaya-Mu&#xf1;oz F, Est&#xe9;vez-Rodr&#xed;guez JL, Navandar A. Ultrasound-guided percutaneous needle electrolysis and rehab and reconditioning program for rectus femoris muscle injuries: a cohort study with professional soccer players and a 20-week follow-up. Appl Sci. 2020;10:7912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10217912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, van de Hoef S, Reurink G, Huisstede B, Backx F. Return to play after hamstring injuries: a qualitative systematic review of definitions and criteria. Sports Med. 2016;46:899&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26767837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4887544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0468-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, Backx F, Goedhart EA, Huisstede BM. Return to play after hamstring injuries in football (soccer): a worldwide Delphi procedure regarding definition, medical criteria and decision-making. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1583&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28360143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green B, McClelland JA, Semciw AI, Schache AG, McCall A, Pizzari T. The assessment, management and prevention of calf muscle strain injuries: a qualitative study of the practices and perspectives of 20 expert sports clinicians. Sports Med Open. 2022;8:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8761182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-021-00364-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Martinez-Ruiz E, Edouard P, Morin J-B, Martinez-Martinez F, Idoate F, et al. A multifactorial, criteria-based progressive algorithm for hamstring injury treatment. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:1482&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28277402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Brughelli M. A return-to-sport algorithm for acute hamstring injuries. Phys Ther Sport. 2011;12:2&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21256444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2010.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serner A, H&#xf6;lmich P, Tol JL, Thorborg K, Lanzinger S, Otten R, et al. Progression of strength, flexibility, and palpation pain during rehabilitation of athletes with acute adductor injuries: a prospective cohort study. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2021;51:126&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33115342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2021.9951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedret C, Rodas G, Balius R, Capdevila L, Bossy M, Vernooij RWM, et al. Return to play after soleus muscle injuries. Orthop J Sports Med. 2015;3:232596711559580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967115595802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creighton DW, Shrier I, Shultz R, Meeuwisse WH, Matheson GO. Return-to-play in sport: a decision-based model. Clin J Sport Med. 2010;20:379&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20818198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0b013e3181f3c0fe</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisciotti GN, Volpi P, Alberti G, Aprato A, Artina M, Auci A, et al. Italian consensus statement (2020) on return to play after lower limb muscle injury in football (soccer). BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2019;5:e000505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31673400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6797382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2018-000505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambaldi M, Beasley I, Rushton A. Return to play criteria after hamstring muscle injury in professional football: a Delphi consensus study. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28246078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton BM, Read P, van Dyk N, Wilson MG, Pollock N, Court N, et al. London International Consensus and Delphi study on hamstring injuries part 3: rehabilitation, running and return to sport. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:278&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36650032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-105384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop G, Ardern CL, Andersen TE, Lewin C, Dupont G, Ashworth B, et al. Return-to-play practices following hamstring injury: a worldwide survey of 131 premier league football teams. Sports Med. 2020;50:829&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7069905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01199-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delvaux F, Rochcongar P, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Bourlet G, Daniel C, Diverse P, et al. Return-to-play criteria after hamstring injury: actual medicine practice in professional soccer teams. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13:721&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25177206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4126316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Int J Surg. 2021;88:105906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2021.105906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, B&#xfc;ttner F, Andrade R, Weir A, Ashe MC, Holden S, et al. Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 Statement items for systematic reviews in the sport and exercise medicine, musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports science fields: the PERSiST (implementing prisma in exercise, rehabilitation, sport medicine and sports science) guidance. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:175&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34625401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-103987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal R, Ranganathan P. Study designs: part 4&#x2014;interventional studies. Perspect Clin Res. 2019;10:137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31404185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6647894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/picr.PICR_91_19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock N, James SLJ, Lee JC, Chakraverty R. British athletics muscle injury classification: a new grading system. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1347&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller-Wohlfahrt H-W, Haensel L, Mithoefer K, Ekstrand J, English B, McNally S, et al. Terminology and classification of muscle injuries in sport: the Munich consensus statement. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47:342&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23080315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock N, Patel A, Chakraverty J, Suokas A, James SLJ, Chakraverty R. Time to return to full training is delayed and recurrence rate is higher in intratendinous (&#x2018;c&#x2019;) acute hamstring injury in elite track and field athletes: clinical application of the British Athletics Muscle Injury Classification. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:305&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macdonald B, McAleer S, Kelly S, Chakraverty R, Johnston M, Pollock N. Hamstring rehabilitation in elite track and field athletes: applying the British Athletics Muscle Injury Classification in clinical practice. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1464&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir A, Brukner P, Delahunt E, Ekstrand J, Griffin D, Khan KM, et al. Doha agreement meeting on terminology and definitions in groin pain in athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:768&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26031643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4484366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Bro&#x17c;ek J, Guyatt G, Oxman A. Handbook for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations using the GRADE approach. Updated October. 2013;2013:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murad MH, Mustafa RA, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Sultan S, Santesso N. Rating the certainty in evidence in the absence of a single estimate of effect. Evid Based Med. 2017;22:85&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28320705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5502230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebmed-2017-110668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ish&#xf8;i L, Krommes K, Husted RS, Juhl CB, Thorborg K. Diagnosis, prevention and treatment of common lower extremity muscle injuries in sport&#x2014;grading the evidence: a statement paper commissioned by the Danish Society of Sports Physical Therapy (DSSF). Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:528&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31937579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7212929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Olivares-Jabalera J, Fernandes RJ, Clemente FM, Rocha-Rodrigues S, Claudino JG, et al. Effectiveness of conservative interventions after acute hamstrings injuries in athletes: a living systematic review. Sports Med. 2023;53:615&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01783-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.l4898 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31533922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6749182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Checklist. [cited 2023 Dec 10]; Scottish intercollegiate guidelines network (SIGN).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Brozek J, Alonso-Coello P, Rind D, et al. Corrigendum to GRADE guidelines 6. Rating the quality of evidence-imprecision. J Clin Epidemiol 2011;64:1283&#x2013;1293. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;137:265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34174652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.04.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Hamid MS, Mohamed Ali MR, Yusof A, George J, Lee LPC. Platelet-rich plasma injections for the treatment of hamstring injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2410&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546514541540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silder A, Sherry MA, Sanfilippo J, Tuite MJ, Hetzel SJ, Heiderscheit BC. Clinical and morphological changes following 2 rehabilitation programs for acute hamstring strain injuries: a randomized clinical trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2013;43:284&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23485730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3751188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2013.4452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Aimi M, Vaz MA, Baroni BM. Effects of low-level laser therapy on hamstring strain injury rehabilitation: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;42:124&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31991284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey JT, Timmins RG, Maniar N, Rio E, Hickey PF, Pitcher CA, et al. Pain-free versus pain-threshold rehabilitation following acute hamstring strain injury: a randomized controlled trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2020;50:91&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2020.8895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherry MA, Best TM. A comparison of 2 rehabilitation programs in the treatment of acute hamstring strains. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2004;34:116&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15089024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2004.34.3.116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer ML, Hoegberget&#x2010;Kalisz M, Jensen MH, Olesen JL, Svensson RB, Coupp&#xe9; C, et al. Role of tissue perfusion, muscle strength recovery, and pain in rehabilitation after acute muscle strain injury: a randomized controlled trial comparing early and delayed rehabilitation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28:2579&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen R, Whiteley R, van der Made AD, van Dyk N, Almusa E, Geertsema C, et al. Early versus delayed lengthening exercises for acute hamstring injury in male athletes: a randomised controlled clinical trial. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:792&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35338036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9252858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Walden M, Ekstrand J. Lower reinjury rate with a coach-controlled rehabilitation program in amateur male soccer. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:1433&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17369558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546507300063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton B, Tol JL, Almusa E, Boukarroum S, Eirale C, Farooq A, et al. Platelet-rich plasma does not enhance return to play in hamstring injuries: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:943&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezuglov E, Maffulli N, Tokareva A, Achkasov E. Platelet-rich plasma in hamstring muscle injuries in professional soccer players. A pilot study. Muscle Ligaments Tendons J. 2019;09:112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32098/mltj.01.2019.20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askling CM, Tengvar M, Thorstensson A. Acute hamstring injuries in Swedish elite football: a prospective randomised controlled clinical trial comparing two rehabilitation protocols. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47:953&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23536466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Iglesias J, Lekue JA, Larruskain J, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Burgos-Alonso N, Andia I. Platelet-rich plasma injections for acute hamstring muscle injuries: a randomized controlled trial in soccer players. Sports Orthop Traumatol. 2023;39:292&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orthtr.2023.03.082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey JT, Rio E, Best TM, Timmins RG, Maniar N, Hickey PF, et al. Early introduction of high-intensity eccentric loading into hamstring strain injury rehabilitation. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25:732&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2022.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen P, Witvrouw E, Muxart P, Tol JL, Whiteley R. A combination of initial and follow-up physiotherapist examination predicts physician-determined time to return to play after hamstring injury, with no added value of MRI. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:431&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26843538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reurink G, Goudswaard GJ, Moen MH, Tol JL, Verhaar JAN, Weir A. Strength measurements in acute hamstring injuries: intertester reliability and prognostic value of handheld dynamometry. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2016;46:689&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2016.6363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Rubio S, Navandar A, Rivilla-Garc&#xed;a J, Paredes-Hern&#xe1;ndez V, G&#xf3;mez-Ruano M-&#xc1;. Improvements in match-related physical performance of professional soccer players after the application of an on-field training program for hamstring injury rehabilitation. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;29:1145&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2019-0033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reurink G, Goudswaard GJ, Tol JL, Almusa E, Moen MH, Weir A, et al. MRI observations at return to play of clinically recovered hamstring injuries. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1370&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24255767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reurink G, Almusa E, Goudswaard GJ, Tol JL, Hamilton B, Moen MH, et al. No association between fibrosis on magnetic resonance imaging at return to play and hamstring reinjury risk. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:1228&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25748473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515572603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt BM, Tyler TF, Kwiecien SY, Fox MB, McHugh MP. Mapping tenderness to palpation predicts return to play following acute hamstring strain. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15:421&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32566378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7297001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayuob A, Kayani B, Haddad FS. Musculotendinous junction injuries of the proximal biceps femoris: a prospective study of 64 patients treated surgically. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:1974&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520926999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler TF, Schmitt BM, Nicholas SJ, McHugh MP. Rehabilitation after hamstring-strain injury emphasizing eccentric strengthening at long muscle lengths: results of long-term follow-up. J Sport Rehabil. 2017;26:131&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27632842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2015-0099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagamoto H. Magnetic resonance imaging parameters relate with recovery time from muscle strain among professional football players. Transl Sports Med. 2020;3:309&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moen MH, Reurink G, Weir A, Tol JL, Maas M, Goudswaard GJ. Predicting return to play after hamstring injuries. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1358&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25037199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croisier J-L, Forthomme B, Namurois M-H, Vanderthommen M, Crielaard J-M. Hamstring muscle strain recurrence and strength performance disorders. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30:199&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11912088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465020300020901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melegati G, Tornese D, Gevi M, Trabattoni A, Pozzi G, Schonhuber H, et al. Reducing muscle injuries and reinjuries in one Italian professional male soccer team. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2013;3:324&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32098/mltj.04.2013.14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanon G, Combi F, Combi A, Perticarini L, Sammarchi L, Benazzo F. Platelet-rich plasma in the treatment of acute hamstring injuries in professional football players. Joints. 2016;04:017&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11138/jts/2016.4.1.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Made AD, Almusa E, Whiteley R, Hamilton B, Eirale C, van Hellemondt F, et al. Intramuscular tendon involvement on MRI has limited value for predicting time to return to play following acute hamstring injury. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:83&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28903949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versteeg JPM, Thijs KM, Zuithoff NPA, Backx FJG, Huisstede BMA. Hamstring&#x2010;and&#x2010;lower&#x2010;back flexibility is not related to hamstring&#x2010;and&#x2010;lower&#x2010;back injuries in elite female soccer players. Transl Sports Med. 2021;4:726&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuermans J, Van Tiggelen D, Danneels L, Witvrouw E. Susceptibility to hamstring injuries in soccer. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:1276&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26912281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515626538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangensteen A, Guermazi A, Tol JL, Roemer FW, Hamilton B, Alonso J-M, et al. New MRI muscle classification systems and associations with return to sport after acute hamstring injuries: a prospective study. Eur Radiol. 2018;28:3532&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29460072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-017-5125-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S-M, Lee J-H. Effect of balance taping using kinesiology tape for a hamstring muscle injury and traumatic knee pain in an amateur university football player: a case report. Medicine. 2018;97:e10973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5999489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000010973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas Fuentes A, Urkiza Ibaibarriaga I, Gil Orozko SM. Incorporation of a high-level soccer player into the team after a muscle injury: a case study (Incorporaci&#xf3;n de un jugador de f&#xfa;tbol de alto nivel en el equipo despu&#xe9;s de una lesi&#xf3;n muscular: Un estudio de caso). Retos. 2015;26:168&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v0i26.34460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brukner P, Nealon A, Morgan C, Burgess D, Dunn A. Recurrent hamstring muscle injury: applying the limited evidence in the professional football setting with a seven-point programme. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:929&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23322894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldock J, Wright S, McNally E, Wedatilake T. Intratendinous hamstring injuries: sequential MRIs as a tool to reduce the risk of reinjury in elite sport. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e241365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34799386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8606769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bcr-2020-241365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setuain I, Lecumberri P, Izquierdo M. Sprint mechanics return to competition follow-up after hamstring injury on a professional soccer player: a case study with an inertial sensor unit based methodological approach. J Biomech. 2017;63:186&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28844725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2017.08.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Edouard P, Samozino P, Brughelli M, Cross M, Ross A, et al. Field monitoring of sprinting power&#x2013;force&#x2013;velocity profile before, during and after hamstring injury: two case reports. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:535&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1122207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taberner M, O&#x2019;keefe J, Dunn A, Cohen DD. Return to sport and beyond following intramuscular tendon hamstring injury: a case report of an English Premier League football player. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;56:38&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35752044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.05.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vos R-J, Reurink G, Goudswaard G-J, Moen MH, Weir A, Tol JL. Clinical findings just after return to play predict hamstring re-injury, but baseline MRI findings do not. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25037201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilcoyne KG, Dickens JF, Keblish D, Rue J-P, Chronister R. Outcome of grade I and II hamstring injuries in intercollegiate athletes. Sports Health. 2011;3:528&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3445226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738111422044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyk N, Wangesteen A, Vermeulen R, Whiteley R, Bahr R, Tol JL, et al. Similar isokinetic strength preinjury and at return to sport after hamstring injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1091&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley R, van Dyk N, Wangensteen A, Hansen C. Clinical implications from daily physiotherapy examination of 131 acute hamstring injuries and their association with running speed and rehabilitation progression. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:303&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton B, Wangensteen A, Whiteley R, Almusa E, Geertsema L, Targett S, et al. Cohen&#x2019;s MRI scoring system has limited value in predicting return to play. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;26(4):1288&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28161749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5876264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Mendes B, Firmino T, Correia JP, Witvrouw EEMC, Oliveira R, et al. Semitendinosus and biceps femoris long head active stiffness response until failure in professional footballers with vs. without previous hamstring injury. Eur J Sport Sci. 2022;22:1132&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2021.1910347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley R, Gregson W, Bahr R, Tabben M, Chamari K, Lolli L, et al. High-speed running during match-play before and after return from hamstring injury in professional footballers. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32:1502&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross KM, Saliba SA, Conaway M, Gurka KK, Hertel J. Days to return to participation after a hamstrings strain among American collegiate soccer players. J Athl Train. 2015;50:733&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25978100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4532185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1052-6050-50.2.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collings TJ, Diamond LE, Barrett RS, Timmins RG, Hickey JT, du Moulin WS, et al. Impact of prior anterior cruciate ligament, hamstring or groin injury on lower limb strength and jump kinetics in elite female footballers. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;52:297&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34742028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areia C, Barreira P, Montanha T, Oliveira J, Ribeiro F. Neuromuscular changes in football players with previous hamstring injury. Clin Biomech. 2019;69:115&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2019.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Attene G, Ardig&#xf2; LP, Bragazzi NL, Maffulli N, Zagatto AM, et al. Can a repeated sprint ability test help clear a previously injured soccer player for fully functional return to activity? A pilot study. Clin J Sport Med. 2017;27:361&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27428681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieters D, Witvrouw E, Wezenbeek E, Schuermans J. Value of isokinetic strength testing for hamstring injury risk assessment: should the &#x2018;strongest&#x2019; mates stay ashore? Eur J Sport Sci. 2022;22:257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2020.1851774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Lorenzen C, Opar DA. Biceps femoris long head architecture. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:905&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25207929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicens-Bordas J, Esteve E, Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A, Clausen MB, Bandholm T, Opar D, et al. Eccentric hamstring strength is associated with age and duration of previous season hamstring injury in male soccer players. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15:246&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7134347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley S, Dobbin N, Morgan C, Goodwin PC. Predictors of time to return to play and re-injury following hamstring injury with and without intramuscular tendon involvement in adult professional footballers: a retrospective cohort study. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25:216&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34740516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corazza A, Orlandi D, Baldari A, Gatto P, Stellatelli M, Mazzola C, et al. Thigh muscles injuries in professional soccer players: a one year longitudinal study. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2013;3:331&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32098/mltj.04.2013.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tol JL, Hamilton B, Eirale C, Muxart P, Jacobsen P, Whiteley R. At return to play following hamstring injury the majority of professional football players have residual isokinetic deficits. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1364&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4174121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima-E-Silva FX, Oliveira GS, Medeiros TM, Dornelles MP, Ribeiro-Alvares JBA, Baroni BM. Flexibility, strength, and fascicle length of football players with and without history of hamstring strain injury in the prior season. Sci Med Footb. 2020;4:322&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2020.1751871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar DA, Williams MD, Timmins RG, Dear NM, Shield AJ. Knee flexor strength and bicep femoris electromyographical activity is lower in previously strained hamstrings. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2013;23:696&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23290179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2012.11.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia P, Santos P, Mil-Homens P, Gomes M, Dias A, Valamatos MJ. Rapid hamstrings to quadriceps ratio at long muscle lengths in professional football players with previous hamstring strain injury. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20:1405&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31917646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2020.1714741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dauty M, Potiron-Josse M, Rochcongar P. Identification of previous hamstring muscle injury by isokinetic concentric and eccentric torque measurement in elite soccer player. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2003;11:139&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-2003-0140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuermans J, Van Tiggelen D, Danneels L, Witvrouw E. Biceps femoris and semitendinosus&#x2014;teammates or competitors? New insights into hamstring injury mechanisms in male football players: a muscle functional MRI study. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1599&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4267196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-094017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navandar A, Veiga S, Torres G, Chorro D, Navarro E. A previous hamstring injury affects kicking mechanics in soccer players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2018;58:1815&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29327823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.18.07852-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MJC, Reid SL, Elliott BC, Lloyd DG. Running biomechanics and lower limb strength associated with prior hamstring injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1942&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a55200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sole G, Milosavljevic S, Nicholson H, Sullivan SJ. Altered muscle activation following hamstring injuries. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46:118&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21393256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.079343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami M, Arab AM, Ghamkhar L. The activity pattern of the lumbo-pelvic muscles during prone hip extension in athletes with and without hamstring strain injury. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2014;9:312&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4060308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuermans J, Danneels L, Van Tiggelen D, Palmans T, Witvrouw E. Proximal neuromuscular control protects against hamstring injuries in male soccer players: a prospective study with electromyography time-series analysis during maximal sprinting. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45:1315&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28263670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516687750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entwisle T, Ling Y, Splatt A, Brukner P, Connell D. Distal musculotendinous T junction injuries of the biceps femoris: an MRI case review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2017;5:232596711771499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967117714998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangensteen A, Tol JL, Witvrouw E, Van Linschoten R, Almusa E, Hamilton B, et al. Hamstring reinjuries occur at the same location and early after return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2112&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27184543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516646086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Samozino P, Martinez-Ruiz E, Brughelli M, Schmikli S, Morin J-B, et al. Progression of mechanical properties during on-field sprint running after returning to sports from a hamstring muscle injury in soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35:690&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24424959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1363192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;ksund OD, Kristoffersen M, Bogen BE, Wisnes A, Engeseth MS, Nilsen A-K, et al. Higher drop in speed during a repeated sprint test in soccer players reporting former hamstring strain injury. Front Physiol. 2017. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2017.00025 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28751866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5508024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai T, Takamoto K, Bito I. Previous hamstring muscle strain injury alters passive tissue stiffness and vibration sense. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2021;27:573&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34391289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2021.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh S, Sarvestan J, Svoboda Z, Alaei F, Lindu&#x161;ka P, Ataabadi PA. Hamstring and ACL injuries impacts on hamstring-to-quadriceps ratio of the elite soccer players: a retrospective study. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;53:97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34894617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankaew A, Jan Y-K, Hwang I-S, Kuo L-C, Lin C-F. Hamstring activation deficits in different jumping directions in athletes with a history of hamstring strain injuries: a cross-sectional laboratory study. Sports Biomech. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2023.2236074 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2023.2236074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37458569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimenta R, Antunes H, Lopes T, Veloso A. Do repeated sprints affect the biceps femoris long head architecture in football players with and without an injury History?&#x2014;A retrospective study. Biology Basel. 2023;12:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36671788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9855802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology12010096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritzmann R, Str&#xfc;tt S, Torreno I, Riesterer J, Centner C, Suarez-Arrones L. Neuromuscular characteristics of agonists and antagonists during maximal eccentric knee flexion in soccer players with a history of hamstring muscle injuries. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0277949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9714924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0277949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Vel&#xe1;zquez M, Wille CM, Hurley SA, Kijowski R, Heiderscheit BC, McMillan AB. MRI radiomics for hamstring strain injury identification and return to sport classification: a pilot study. Skeletal Radiol. 2024;53:637&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-023-04449-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valente HG, Oliveira RRde, Baroni BM. How are hamstring strain injuries managed in elite men&#x2019;s football clubs? A survey with 62 Brazilian physical therapists. Phys Ther Sport. 2023;61:73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36940549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2023.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvinen-Barrow M, Massey WV, Hemmings B. Role of sport medicine professionals in addressing psychosocial aspects of sport-injury rehabilitation: professional athletes&#x2019; views. J Athl Train. 2014;49:764&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25243737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4264648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.44</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruna R, Yanguas J, van der Made AD, Capdevila L, Balius R, Alomar X, et al. Length of the free tendon is not associated with return to play time in biceps femoris muscle injuries. Apunts Med Esport. 2019;54:37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apunts.2018.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Made AD, Almusa E, Reurink G, Whiteley R, Weir A, Hamilton B, et al. Intramuscular tendon injury is not associated with an increased hamstring reinjury rate within 12 months after return to play. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1261&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29654058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Rubio S, Navandar A, Rivilla-Garc&#xed;a J, Paredes-Hern&#xe1;ndez V. Validity of an on-field readaptation program following a hamstring injury in professional soccer. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;28:jsr.2018-0203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Kimmenade RJLL, van Bergen CJA, van Deurzen PJE, Verhagen RAW. A rare case of adductor longus muscle rupture. Case Rep Orthop. 2015;2015:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Goeverden W, Langhout RFH, Barendrecht M, Tak IJR. Active pelvic tilt is reduced in athletes with groin injury; a case-controlled study. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;36:14&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30611026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.12.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serner A, Weir A, Tol JL, Thorborg K, Lanzinger S, Otten R, et al. Return to sport after criteria-based rehabilitation of acute adductor injuries in male athletes: a prospective cohort study. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8:232596711989724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967119897247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serner A, Weir A, Tol JL, Thorborg K, Yamashiro E, Guermazi A, et al. Associations between initial clinical examination and imaging findings and return-to-sport in male athletes with acute adductor injuries: a prospective cohort study. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:1151&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32182099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520908610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Petersen J, Nielsen MB, H&#xf6;lmich P. Clinical recovery of two hip adductor longus ruptures: a case-report of a soccer player. BMC Res Notes. 2013;6:205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23693119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3665545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-6-205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Branci S, Nielsen MP, Tang L, Nielsen MB, H&#xf6;lmich P. Eccentric and isometric hip adduction strength in male soccer players with and without adductor-related groin pain. Orthop J Sports Med. 2014;2:232596711452177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967114521778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;lmich P, Uhrskou P, Ulnits L, Kanstrup I-L, Nielsen MB, Bjerg AM, et al. Effectiveness of active physical training as treatment for long-standing adductor-related groin pain in athletes: randomised trial. Lancet. 1999;353:439&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9989713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)03340-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delahaye H, Laffargue P, Voisin P, Weissland T, Letombe A, Dupont L, et al. Evaluation of athletes with longstanding groin pain. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2003;11:45&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-2003-0125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Serner A, Petersen J, Madsen TM, Magnusson P, H&#xf6;lmich P. Hip adduction and abduction strength profiles in elite soccer players. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39:121&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510378081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light N, Smith N, Delahunt E, Thorborg K. Hip and groin injury management in English youth football: a survey of 64 professional academies. Sci Med Footb. 2018;2:133&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2018.1441536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mech&#xf3; S, Balius R, Bossy M, Valle X, Pedret C, Ruiz-Cotorro &#xc1;, et al. Isolated adductor magnus injuries in athletes: a case series. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11:232596712211388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671221138806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak I, Langhout R, Bertrand B, Barendrecht M, Stubbe J, Kerkhoffs G, et al. Manual therapy and early return to sport in football players with adductor-related groin pain: a prospective case series. Physiother Theory Pract. 2020;36:1009&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30307775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593985.2018.1531096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzotta G, Pecorelli A, Querques G, Biancardi S, Morzenti C, Sironi S. MRI characteristics of adductor longus lesions in professional football players and prognostic factors for return to play. Eur J Radiol. 2018;108:52&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30396671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrad.2018.09.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur S, Maurya UK, Shenoy S. Recovery of two elite footballers from adductor strain with dry needling and eccentric strengthening: two case studies. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2023;35:332&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37330790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.04.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergani L, Cuniberti M, Zanovello M, Maffei D, Farooq A, Eirale C. Return to play in long-standing adductor-related groin pain: a Delphi study among experts. Sports Med. 2022;8:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Rubio S, Est&#xe9;vez Rodr&#xed;guez JL, Navandar A. Validity of a rehab and reconditioning program following an adductor longus injury in professional soccer. J Sport Rehabil. 2021;30:1224&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2020-0360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balius R, Maestro A, Pedret C, Estruch A, Mota J, Rodriguez L, et al. Central aponeurosis tears of the rectus femoris: practical sonographic prognosis. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43:818&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19174412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2008.052332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo Y, Watanabe K, Nakazato K, Koyama K, Hiranuma K. Central tendon injury impairs regional neuromuscular activation of the rectus femoris muscle. Sports. 2021;9:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34822350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8620181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9110150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurovich AN. Controlled re-injury of a thigh muscle tear in a soccer player: a case study. J Phys Ther Sci. 2012;24:295&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.24.295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser S, Jantz D, Hurdle MF, Taylor W. Proximal rectus femoris avulsion: ultrasonic diagnosis and nonoperative management. J Athl Train. 2015;50:778&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25978099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4532190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1052-6050-50.2.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogliacomi F, Visigalli A, Valenti PG, Pedrazzini A, Bernuzzi G, Concari G, et al. Rectus femoris myotendinous lesion treated with PRP: a case report. Acta Bio Medica: Atenei Parmensis. 2019;90:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31821305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7233700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimozaki K, Nakase J, Asai K, Yoshimizu R, Kimura M, Kanayama T, et al. Relationship between anatomical injury site of rectus femoris muscle strain and time taken to return to play in Japanese professional soccer players. J Orthop Surg. 2022;30:102255362211417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10225536221141786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo Y, Watanabe K, Nakazato K, Koyama K, Hakkaku T, Kemuriyama S, et al. The effect of a previous strain injury on regional neuromuscular activation within the rectus femoris. J Hum Kinet. 2019;66:89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6458589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak H-S, Han Y-M, Lee S-Y, Kim K-N, Chung GH. Diagnosis and follow-up US evaluation of ruptures of the medial head of the gastrocnemius (&#x201c;tennis leg&#x201d;). Korean J Radiol. 2006;7:193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16969049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2667601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3348/kjr.2006.7.3.193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreira P, Kassarjian A, Ara&#xfa;jo JP, Ferreira R, Espregueira Mendes J. Calf injuries in professional football: treat the patient or the scan?&#x2014;a case study. Phys Ther Sport. 2016;21:63&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27428536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2016.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash A, Entwisle T, Schneider M, Brukner P, Connell D. Connective tissue injury in calf muscle tears and return to play: MRI correlation. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:929&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29074478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida K, Itoigawa Y, Maruyama Y, Kaneko K. Healing process of gastrocnemius muscle injury on ultrasonography using B&#x2010;mode imaging, power doppler imaging, and shear wave elastography. J Ultrasound Med. 2019;38:3239&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31165497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.15035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Piqueras P, Gonz&#xe1;lez-V&#xed;llora S, Grassi A, Gojanovic B, H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M. Are we making SMART decisions regarding return to training of injured football players? Preliminary results from a pilot study. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2018;26:115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-172201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Nakamura FY, Castillo D, Yanci J, Fanchini M. Determining the relationship between internal load markers and noncontact injuries in young elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:421&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30204512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley R, Farooq A, Johnson A. Development of a data-based interval kicking program for preparation and rehabilitation purposes in professional football. Sci Med Footb. 2017;1:107&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2017.1288919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portillo J, Abi&#xe1;n P, Calvo B, Paredes V, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J. Effects of muscular injuries on the technical and physical performance of professional soccer players. Phys Sportsmed. 2020;48:437&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00913847.2020.1744485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengtsson H, Ekstrand J, Wald&#xe9;n M, H&#xe4;gglund M. Few training sessions between return to play and first match appearance are associated with an increased propensity for injury: a prospective cohort study of male professional football players during 16 consecutive seasons. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:427&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31466941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isern-Kebschull J, Pedret C, Mech&#xf3; S, Pruna R, Alomar X, Yanguas X, et al. MRI findings prior to return to play as predictors of reinjury in professional athletes: a novel decision-making tool. Insights Imaging. 2022;13:203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36575363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9794673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-022-01341-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvi M, Curti M, Mazzoni S, Genesio L, Tavana R, Callegari L, et al. Paramagnetic contrast medium in high-level athletes with lower limb muscle injuries: can it make the return to sport safer reducing the recurrence rate? Radiol Med. 2022;127:507&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35286540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9098586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11547-022-01472-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart LM, Cohen DD, Patterson SD, Springham M, Reynolds J, Read P. Previous injury is associated with heightened countermovement jump force&#x2010;time asymmetries in professional soccer players. Transl Sports Med. 2019;2:256&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.92</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ja&#xe9;n TF, Rey G&#xc1;, Cuesta JA, Loureda RA, Espa&#xf1;a F&#xc1;, Matas RB, et al. Spanish consensus statement: the treatment of muscle tears in sport. Orthop J Sports Med. 2015;3:2325967115622434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27213161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967115622434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezuglov E, Khaitin V, Shoshorina M, Butovskiy M, Karlitskiy N, Mashkovskiy E, et al. Sport-specific rehabilitation, but not PRP injections, might reduce the re-injury rate of muscle injuries in professional soccer players: a retrospective cohort study. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2022;7:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36278733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9589983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk7040072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller CW. Quantifying the functional rehabilitation of injured football players * commentary. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40:151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2492043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2005.021048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar DA, Williams MD, Timmins RG, Dear NM, Shield AJ. Rate of torque and electromyographic development during anticipated eccentric contraction is lower in previously strained hamstrings. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41:116&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23108640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512462809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey JT, Timmins RG, Maniar N, Williams MD, Opar DA. Criteria for progressing rehabilitation and determining return-to-play clearance following hamstring strain injury: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2017;47:1375&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28035586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0667-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia L, Taylor D, Pappas E, Hegedus EJ, Michener LA. Beginning with the end in mind: implementing backward design to improve sports injury rehabilitation practices. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52:770&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36453072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2022.11440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Alentorn-Geli E, Brughelli M. Hamstring strain injuries: are we heading in the right direction? Br J Sports Med. 2012;46:81&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.081695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freckleton G, Cook J, Pizzari T. The predictive validity of a single leg bridge test for hamstring injuries in Australian Rules Football Players. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:713&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23918443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramah C, Mendiguchia J, Dos&#x2019;Santos T, Morin J-B. Exploring the role of sprint biomechanics in hamstring strain injuries: a current opinion on existing concepts and evidence. Sports Med. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-023-01925-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01925-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11052868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Villa F, Buckthorpe M, Pellegrini A, Ranzini A, Esposito F, Crescenzo C, et al. A comparative video analysis of hamstring injuries mechanism and situational pattern in men&#x2019;s and women&#x2019;s football (soccer). Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1002/ksa.12313 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.12313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38881374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen R, van Dyk N, Whiteley R, Chamari K, Gregson W, Lolli L, et al. Injury-inciting circumstances of sudden-onset hamstring injuries: video analyses of 63 match injuries in male professional football players in the Qatar Stars League (2013&#x2013;2020). Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:1196&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39242176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero-Calder&#xf3;n B, Alfonso Morcillo J, Chena M, Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez A. Comparison of training and match load between metabolic and running speed metrics of professional Spanish soccer players by playing position. Biol Sport. 2022;39:933&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2022.110884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huygaerts S, Cos F, Cohen DD, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Guitart M, Blazevich AJ, et al. Mechanisms of hamstring strain injury: interactions between fatigue, muscle activation and function. Sports. 2020;8:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32443515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7281534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports8050065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zein MI, Mokkenstorm MJK, Cardinale M, Holtzhausen L, Whiteley R, Moen MH, et al. Baseline clinical and MRI risk factors for hamstring reinjury showing the value of performing baseline MRI and delaying return to play: a multicentre, prospective cohort of 330 acute hamstring injuries. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:766&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38729628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11228232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-107878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Attar WSA, Husain MA. Effectiveness of injury prevention programs with core muscle strengthening exercises to reduce the incidence of hamstring injury among soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2023;15:805&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381231170815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall A, Davison M, Andersen TE, Beasley I, Bizzini M, Dupont G, et al. Injury prevention strategies at the FIFA 2014 World Cup: perceptions and practices of the physicians from the 32 participating national teams. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:603&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4413740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall A, Carling C, Davison M, Nedelec M, Le Gall F, Berthoin S, et al. Injury risk factors, screening tests and preventative strategies: a systematic review of the evidence that underpins the perceptions and practices of 44 football (soccer) teams from various premier leagues. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:583&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25576530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4413799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-094104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kloskowska P, Morrissey D, Small C, Malliaras P, Barton C. Movement patterns and muscular function before and after onset of sports-related groin pain: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46:1847&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27142535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5097097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0523-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhari AMW, Jamison ST, McNally MP, Pan X, Schmitt LC. Hip adductor activations during run-to-cut manoeuvres in compression shorts: implications for return to sport after groin injury. J Sports Sci. 2014;32:1333&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24669858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4134387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2014.889849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serner A, Mosler AB, Tol JL, Bahr R, Weir A. Mechanisms of acute adductor longus injuries in male football players: a systematic visual video analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:158&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30006458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F, Della Villa S, Roi GS. On-field rehabilitation part 2: a 5-stage program for the soccer player focused on linear movements, multidirectional movements, soccer-specific skills, soccer-specific movements, and modified practice. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49:570&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2019.8952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage M, McErlain-Naylor SA, Devereux G, Beato M, Buckthorpe M. On-field rehabilitation in football: current knowledge, applications and future directions. Front Sports Act Living. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2022.970152 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.970152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9760760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Alentorn-Geli E, Idoate F, Myer GD. Rectus femoris muscle injuries in football: a clinically relevant review of mechanisms of injury, risk factors and preventive strategies. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47:359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22864009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orchard JW. Intrinsic and extrinsic risk factors for muscle strains in Australian football. Am J Sports Med. 2001;29:300&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11394599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465010290030801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fousekis K, Tsepis E, Poulmedis P, Athanasopoulos S, Vagenas G. Intrinsic risk factors of non-contact quadriceps and hamstring strains in soccer: a prospective study of 100 professional players. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:709&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.077560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witvrouw E, Danneels L, Asselman P, D&#x2019;Have T, Cambier D. Muscle flexibility as a risk factor for developing muscle injuries in male professional soccer players. Am J Sports Med. 2003;31:41&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465030310011801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis CL, Sahrmann SA, Moran DW. Anterior hip joint force increases with hip extension, decreased gluteal force, or decreased iliopsoas force. J Biomech. 2007;40:3725&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17707385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2580726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2007.06.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietsch S, Pizzari T. Risk factors for quadriceps muscle strain injuries in sport: a systematic review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52:389&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2022.10870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio E, Kidgell D, Moseley GL, Gaida J, Docking S, Purdam C, et al. Tendon neuroplastic training: changing the way we think about tendon rehabilitation: a narrative review. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:209&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26407586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew N, Gabbe BJ, Cook J, Lloyd DG, Donnelly CJ, Nash C, et al. Could targeted exercise programmes prevent lower limb injury in community Australian football? Sports Med. 2013;43:751&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23681448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0056-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Flanagan EP. The role of elastic energy in activities with high force and power requirements: a brief review. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1705&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31817ae4a7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Kanehisa H, Takeshita D, Kawakami Y, Fukashiro S, Fukunaga T. In vivo dynamics of human medial gastrocnemius muscle&#x2010;tendon complex during stretch&#x2010;shortening cycle exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 2000;170:127&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11114950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201x.2000.00768.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green B, Lin M, Schache AG, McClelland JA, Semciw AI, Rotstein A, et al. Calf muscle strain injuries in elite Australian football players: a descriptive epidemiological evaluation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30:174&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31494970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielsson A, Horvath A, Senorski C, Alentorn-Geli E, Garrett WE, Cugat R, et al. The mechanism of hamstring injuries&#x2014;a systematic review. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21:641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7526261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-020-03658-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards WB. Modeling overuse injuries in sport as a mechanical fatigue phenomenon. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2018;46:224&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, Witvrouw E, Clarsen B, Cools A, et al. 2016 Consensus statement on return to sport from the First World Congress in Sports Physical Therapy. Bern Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:853&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecci J, S&#xe1;nchez-Trigo H, Mancha-Triguero D, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Reverte-Pagola G, del Ojo-L&#xf3;pez JJ, et al. Return to performance: machine learning insights into how absence time following muscle injuries affects match running performance in LaLiga soccer players. Biol Sport. 2025;42:275&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12490316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.151651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon B, Alexander J, Harper D. &#x2018;Post-rehabilitation phase&#x2019; in professional football: are we optimising player support after return to play? Br J Sports Med. 2025;59:625&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39880605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2024-109458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cejudo A, Centenera-Centenera JM, Santonja-Medina F. The potential role of hamstring extensibility on sagittal pelvic tilt, sagittal spinal curves and recurrent low back pain in team sports players: a gender perspective analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:8654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8393976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18168654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto-Acevedo R, Romero-Moraleda B, Montalvo-P&#xe9;rez A, Vald&#xe9;s-&#xc1;lvarez A, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez C, Mon-L&#xf3;pez D. Should we use the men load&#x2013;velocity profile for women in deadlift and hip thrust? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:4888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10048953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20064888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perna P, Kerin F, Greig N, Beato M. Return-to-play criteria following a hamstring injury in professional football: a scoping review. Res Sports Med. 2024;33:175&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39666593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2024.2439274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>