<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41606747</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-511X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lipids in health and disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lipids Health Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>TyHGB combined with diagonal earlobe crease and traditional risk factors for constructing a diagnostic model of coronary heart disease.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">66</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12944-026-02880-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">TyHGB is a novel insulin resistance (IR)-related indicator, and its association with coronary heart disease (CHD) remains unclear. Additionally, studies have shown a close correlation between the diagonal earlobe crease (DELC) and CHD, yet it has not been fully applied in clinical practice to date. Therefore, this study constructed and validated a diagnostic model for CHD by combining TyHGB and DELC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 1664 patients suspected of CHD who underwent coronary angiography (CAG) in the Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital from September 2021 to April 2025 were recruited for this study. Participants were categorized into a CHD group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1,316) and a non-CHD group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;348). Univariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were employed to assess the associations of TyHGB, DELC, and other relevant factors with CHD. Restricted cubic spline (RCS) analysis was employed to assess the dose-response correlation between TyHGB and the risk of CHD, and TyHGB levels were compared across quartiles. A nomogram incorporating TyHGB and DELC was developed, and its diagnostic performance was assessed using decision curve analysis (DCA) and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Age, sex, hypertension, diabetes, CR, Lp(a), TyHGB, and DELC were identified as independent risk factors for CHD through multivariate logistic regression analysis (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). RCS curve analysis demonstrated a linear relationship between TyHGB and CHD risk (P for nonlinear&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.477). Further quartile grouping of TyHGB revealed a progressive increase in CHD risk with rising TyHGB levels. Compared to the first quartile group, patients in the fourth quartile group exhibited a 2.087-fold higher risk of CHD (95% CI: 1.374&#x2013;3.170). Optimal predictive variables were selected in the training set using Lasso regression and multivariate logistic regression. ROC curves were utilized to validate diagnostic performance, with the training set yielding an area under the curve (AUC) of 0.706 (95% CI: 0.669&#x2013;0.743) and the validation set an AUC of 0.716 (95% CI: 0.657&#x2013;0.775).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Both TyHGB and DELC have been identified as independent risk factors for CHD, with a linear relationship observed between TyHGB levels and CHD risk. A diagnostic model for CHD, developed by integrating TyHGB, DELC, and traditional risk factors, demonstrates strong diagnostic efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12944-026-02880-y.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Mingliang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 06700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Wenxin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 06700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 06700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ruoling</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 06700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Yuhua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yanchun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shasha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Tiezhu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China. 44797453@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Donglei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chengde Central Hospital/Second Clinical College of Chengde Medical University, Chengde , 067000, China. dongleiluocn@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 20200348</GrantID><Agency>the Medical Science Research Project of Hebei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 202109A019</GrantID><Agency>the S&amp;T Program of Chengde</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. CYCXZZ202508</GrantID><Agency>the Funding Project for Cultivating Innovative Ability of Postgraduates at Chengde Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lipids Health Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101147696</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1476-511X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary heart disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagonal earlobe crease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TyHGB</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Every patient participating in the study were informed about it and then signed the informed consent form. The Chinese clinical registration identifier for this trial is ChiCTR2000041499, which is accessible online at http://www.chictr.org.cn . All methods in this study were performed in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations and the Declaration of Helsinki. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-026-02880-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12944-026-02880-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Martin SS, Aday AW, Almarzooq ZI, Anderson CAM, Arora P, Avery CL, et al. 2024 heart disease and stroke statistics: A report of US and global data from the American heart association. Circulation. 2024;149(8):e347&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12146881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38264914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global regional. National age-sex-specific mortality for 282 causes of death in 195 countries and territories, 1980&#x2013;2017: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2017. Lancet. 2018;392(10159):1736&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Leyte DJ, Zepeda-Garc&#xed;a O, Dom&#xed;nguez-P&#xe9;rez M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garrido A, Villarreal-Molina T, Jacobo-Albavera L. Endothelial Dysfunction, inflammation and coronary artery disease: potential biomarkers and promising therapeutical approaches. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(8):3850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulati M, Levy PD, Mukherjee D, Amsterdam E, Bhatt DL, Birtcher KK, et al. 2021 AHA/ACC/ASE/CHEST/SAEM/SCCT/SCMR Guideline for the Evaluation and Diagnosis of Chest Pain: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2021;144(22):e368-e454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34709879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida K, Tanabe Y, Hosokawa T, Morikawa T, Fukuyama N, Kobayashi Y, et al. Coronary computed tomography angiography for clinical practice. Jpn J Radiol. 2024;42(6):555&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11139719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38453814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava P, Kashikar S, Parihar PH, Kasat P, Bhangale P, Shrivastava P. A systematic review on deep learning-enabled coronary CT angiography for plaque and stenosis quantification and cardiac risk prediction. Eur J Radiol Open. 2025;14:100652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12123344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40453037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Dou J, Yang HH, Guo RL, Jiang C, Tse G, et al. Clinical value of the diagonal earlobe crease in patients with chest pain for diagnosing coronary heart disease. Int J Gen Med. 2024;17:1557&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11055521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38680192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank ST. Aural sign of coronary-artery disease. N Engl J Med. 1973;289(6):327&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4718047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galassi FM, Borghi C, Ballestriero R, Habicht ME, Henneberg M, R&#xfc;hli FJ. Palaeopathology of the earlobe crease (Frank&#x2019;s sign): new insights from renaissance Art. Int J Cardiol. 2017;236:82&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28284502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott WJ. Ear lobe crease and coronary artery disease. 1,000 patients and review of the literature. Am J Med. 1983;75(6):1024&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6359874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agouridis AP, Elisaf MS, Nair DR, Mikhailidis DP. Ear lobe crease: a marker of coronary artery disease? Arch Med Sci. 2015;11(6):1145&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4697048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26788075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babes EE, Bustea C, Behl T, Abdel-Daim MM, Nechifor AC, Stoicescu M, et al. Acute coronary syndromes in diabetic patients, outcome, revascularization, and antithrombotic therapy. Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;148:112772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35245735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi AK, Dubey P, Reddy SY, Clegg DJ. Associations of glycemic index and glycemic load with cardiovascular disease: updated evidence from Meta-analysis and cohort studies. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2022;24(3):141&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35119682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H, Ma Y, Zhou Z, Li X, Ding K, Wu Y, et al. Disease patterns of coronary heart disease and type 2 diabetes harbored distinct and shared genetic architecture. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9738029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36494812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Shin SJ, Kim YS, Kang HT. Positive association between the ratio of triglycerides to high-density lipoprotein cholesterol and diabetes incidence in Korean adults. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8431895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34503545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Liu Y, Li L, Zheng Y, Wang Y, Su J, et al. Correlation between the triglyceride-to-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio and other unconventional lipid parameters with the risk of prediabetes and type 2 diabetes in patients with coronary heart disease: a RCSCD-TCM study in China. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9166647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Gui J, Liu H, Guo LL, Li J, Lei Y, et al. Predicting metabolic syndrome by obesity- and lipid-related indices in mid-aged and elderly chinese: a population-based cross-sectional study. Front Endocrinol. 2023;14:1201132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10419183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S, Zhang Y, Qiao X, Duo Y, Xu J, Peng Z, et al. HOMA-IR as a risk factor of gestational diabetes mellitus and a novel simple surrogate index in early pregnancy. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2022;157(3):694&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Li C, Wang N, Song G. Association between the new TyG indicator-TyHGB and gestational diabetes mellitus: results from the case-control and prospective cohort studies. J Transl Med. 2025;23(1):190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11831843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39956901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo R, Yang H, Dou J, Gao J, Yin Y, Gu Y, et al. Diagnostic value of the diagonal earlobe crease in combination with lipoprotein(a) in coronary heart disease. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):21047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12215279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40594446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuuti J, Wijns W, Saraste A, Capodanno D, Barbato E, Funck-Brentano C, et al. 2019 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(3):407&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-L&#xf3;pez P, Ares-Carral C, L&#xf3;pez-Pastor AR, Infante-Men&#xe9;ndez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez Illaness T, Vega de Ceniga M, et al. Implication of miR-155-5p and miR-143-3p in the vascular insulin resistance and instability of human and experimental atherosclerotic plaque. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(18):10253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9499612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36142173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pliszka M, Szablewski L. Severe insulin resistance syndromes: clinical spectrum and management. Int J Mol Sci. 2025;26(12):5669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12192740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40565151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Ji H, Sun W, An X, Lian F. Triglyceride glucose (TyG) index: A promising biomarker for diagnosis and treatment of different diseases. Eur J Intern Med. 2025;131:3&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39510865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suren Garg S, Kushwaha K, Dubey R, Gupta J. Association between obesity, inflammation and insulin resistance: insights into signaling pathways and therapeutic interventions. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2023;200:110691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37150407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao E, Wang R, Chen Y, Xie H, Gao Y, Dong B, et al. Evaluation of a new TyG indicator, TyHGB, in predicting non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: evidence from two independent populations. Lipids Health Dis. 2025;24(1):342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12551267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41131568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello BT, Silverman ER, Doukky R, Braun LT, Aggarwal NT, Deng Y, et al. Lipoprotein(a) and increased cardiovascular risk in women. Clin Cardiol. 2016;39(2):96&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6490748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26880352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennet A, Di Angelantonio E, Erqou S, Eiriksdottir G, Sigurdsson G, Woodward M, et al. Lipoprotein(a) levels and risk of future coronary heart disease: large-scale prospective data. Arch Intern Med. 2008;168(6):598&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18362252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danesh J, Collins R, Peto R. Lipoprotein(a) and coronary heart disease. Meta-analysis of prospective studies. Circulation. 2000;102(10):1082&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffing G. Images in clinical medicine. Frank&#x2019;s sign. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(10):e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24597888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baboujian A, Bezwada P, Ayala-Rodriguez C. Diagonal earlobe Crease, a marker of coronary artery disease: A case report on frank&#x2019;s sign. Cureus. 2019;11(3):e4219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6506272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31106102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Culebras A. Bilateral earlobe creases and subsequent malignant cerebral infarction: A patient with diffuse endothelial dysfunction. Cureus. 2020;12(7):e9329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7444846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32850206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoyanov GS, Dzhenkov D, Petkova L, Sapundzhiev N, Georgiev S. The histological basis of frank&#x2019;s sign. Head Neck Pathol. 2021;15(2):402&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8134579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32712879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlander AH, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez J, Velasco-Ortega E. Diagonal ear lobe crease and atherosclerosis: a review of the medical literature and dental implications. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2012;17(1):e153&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21743392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Nor B, Wan Razali WMH, Mohd Nor F. Relationship between frank&#x2019;s sign and cardiovascular disease: an Autopsy-Based study. Cureus. 2025;17(9):e91756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12501647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41063902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Qiu C, Xu J, Zhang Y, Cui Q, Guan G, et al. Ear crease features are associated with complexity of coronary lesions. Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e923343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7171428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32281613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan JCN, Lim LL, Wareham NJ, Shaw JE, Orchard TJ, Zhang P, et al. The lancet commission on diabetes: using data to transform diabetes care and patient lives. Lancet. 2021;396(10267):2019&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33189186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen FS, Wei JC, Chiu LT, Hsu CC, Hwu CM. Diabetes, hypertension, and cardiovascular disease development. J Transl Med. 2022;20(1):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8722333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34980154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannel WB. Hypertension: reflections on risks and prognostication. Med Clin North Am. 2009;93(3):541&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19427490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholls SJ, Tuzcu EM, Kalidindi S, Wolski K, Moon KW, Sipahi I, et al. Effect of diabetes on progression of coronary atherosclerosis and arterial remodeling: a pooled analysis of 5 intravascular ultrasound trials. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2008;52(4):255&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18634979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Sr., Pencina MJ, Massaro JM, Coady S. Cardiovascular disease risk assessment: insights from Framingham. Glob Heart. 2013;8(1):11&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3673738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Angelantonio E, Chowdhury R, Sarwar N, Aspelund T, Danesh J, Gudnason V. Chronic kidney disease and risk of major cardiovascular disease and non-vascular mortality: prospective population based cohort study. BMJ. 2010;341:c4986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2948649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20884698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim A, Tai ES, Tan VY, Welsh AH, Liew R, Naidoo N, et al. C-reactive protein and serum creatinine, but not haemoglobin A1c, are independent predictors of coronary heart disease risk in non-diabetic Chinese. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2016;23(12):1339&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza A, Pessina AC, Tikhonoff V, Montemurro D, Casiglia E. Serum creatinine and coronary mortality in the elderly with normal renal function: the cardiovascular study in the elderly (CASTEL). J Nephrol. 2005;18(5):606&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16299689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>