<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41126058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prospects of training system and deficit irrigation for increasing yield and water use efficiency of pitaya (Hylocereus spp.) in the Mediterranean region.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1431</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1431</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1431</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-025-07442-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is well known that the water consumption of some tropical fruits is high. However, in the world and especially in agricultural areas, where the Mediterranean climate prevails, drought is defined as one of the most important abiotic stress factors that affect product patterns. For this reason, this research chose the pitaya (Hylocereus spp.) plant, which has relatively low water consumption among tropical fruit species. Three different training (Control [Pole], T and Inverted U) systems with different deficit irrigation (combined with FULL&#x2009;=&#x2009;100%; DI75&#x2009;=&#x2009;75%, DI50&#x2009;=&#x2009;50% and DI25&#x2009;=&#x2009;25%) treatments in the cultivation of pitaya under greenhouse conditions; their effects on the yield, evapotranspiration, water use efficiency, irrigation water use efficiency, yield response factor and some quality parameters (fruit weight, length and width, fruit flesh hardness and water-soluble dry matter) were examined. The research was carried out in Antalya province, Turkey between 2018 and 2021 and 'Vietnamese Jaina' was used as a cultivar. Irrigation applications were carried out using drip irrigation method and the amount of irrigation water to be used in the control (FULL) treatment was calculated based on measurement values taken from the A-Class evaporation pan. The research findings revealed that the amount of irrigation water varied between 27.63&#xa0;mm and 83.80&#xa0;mm, and the fruit flesh value ranged between 79.36&#xa0;kg cm<sup>-2</sup> and 105.53&#xa0;kg cm<sup>-2</sup>. In general, as the irrigation water level decreases, a decrease in fruit flesh values is also recorded. In addition, it was found that different irrigation water levels affect yield. The average yield values were found as DI75 (7169.60&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;FULL (5783.90&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;DI50 (4737.00&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;DI25 (4376.30&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>) ranking from high to low. Yield varied according to the training system, with the highest value recorded in the Pole (Control) System (5625.30&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>) followed by Inverted U System (5594.90&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>) and T System (5330.00&#xa0;kg ha<sup>-1</sup>). As an important finding for yield values, it was found that the treatment DI75 irrigation has a general superiority over the other irrigation treatments. Based on the research findings, considering the yield and quality parameters, a Pole (Control) System and an Inverted U System were recommended as a training system, respectively, along with the irrigation treatment (DI75), in which 75% of the water needed by the plant is given in greenhouse conditions considering the evaporation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaman</LastName><ForeName>Harun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Structures and Irrigation, Faculty of Agriculture, Akdeniz University, Antalya, 07058, Turkey. hkaman@akdeniz.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;bb&#xfc;k</LastName><ForeName>Hamide</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Akdeniz University, Antalya, 07058, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altinkaya</LastName><ForeName>Lokman</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Crop and Animal Production, Horticulture Program, Kumluca Vocational School, Akdeniz University, Antalya, 07350, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balki&#xe7;</LastName><ForeName>Recep</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Crop and Animal Production, Elmal&#x131; Vocational School, Akdeniz University, Antalya, 07700, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xdc;nl&#xfc;</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Republic of T&#xfc;rkiye Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry, Alata Horticultural Research Institute, Alparslan Turkes Bulvari, Erdemli-Mersin, 33740, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>TUBITAK-118O672</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technical Research Council of Turkey</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TUBITAK-118O672</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technical Research Council of Turkey</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TUBITAK-118O672</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technical Research Council of Turkey</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TUBITAK-118O672</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technical Research Council of Turkey</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057914" MajorTopicYN="Y">Agricultural Irrigation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029421" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cactaceae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005638" MajorTopicYN="N">Fruit</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019083" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Mediterranean Region</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055864" MajorTopicYN="N">Droughts</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014421" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Turkey</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018556" MajorTopicYN="N">Crops, Agricultural</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drought resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fruit yield</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water use efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water-yield relations</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41126058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12542249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-07442-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-025-07442-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Trivellini A, Lucchesini M, Ferrante A, Massa D, Orlando M, Incrocci L, Mensuali-Sodi A. Pitaya, an attractive alternative crop for mediterranean region. Agronomy. 2020;10(8):1065. 10.3390/agronomy10081065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy10081065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi Y. Thirty-One Years of Research and Development in The Vine Cacti Pitaya in Israel. In: Jiang, Y.L., P.C. Liu and P.H. Huang, editors, Improving Pitaya Production and Marketing: International Workshop Proceedings, September 7&#x2013;9, Kaoshiung, Taiwan, organized by FFTC, TARI and SOFRI. Taipei, Taiwan, ROC, FFTC, 2015. pp. 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerd A, Tel-Zur N, Mizrahi Y. Fruit of vine and columnar cacti. In: Nobel PS, editor. Cacti: biology and uses. Los Angeles: UCLA Press; 2002. pp. 185&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi Y, Nerd A. Climbing and columnar cacti: new arid land fruit crops. In: Janick J, editor. Perspectives in new crops and new crops uses. Alexandria, VA: ASHS; 1999. pp. 358&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbek &#xd6;, Kaman H. Effects of different irrigation regimes on eggplant yield in greenhouse conditions. Bangladesh J Bot. 2018;47(2):173&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, Demir H, S&#xf6;nmez &#x130;, Polat E, Mohamoud SS, &#xdc;&#xe7;ok Z. Salinity accumulation in the root area of the Curly lettuce grown in deficit irrigation conditions. J Tekirdag Agricultural Fac. 2021;18(3):508&#x2013;20. 10.33462/jotaf.846652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33462/jotaf.846652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;, Polat E. Response of greenhouse grown cucumber to partial root zone drying and conventional deficit irrigation. Kahramanmara&#x15f; S&#xfc;t&#xe7;&#xfc; &#x130;mam university journal of agriculture and nature. (Journal Agricultural Natural). 2022;25(2):337&#x2013;47. 10.18016/ksutarimdoga.vi.883294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18016/ksutarimdoga.vi.883294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luders L, McMahon G. The Pitaya or Dragon Fruit. Department of Primary Industries and Fisheries Northern Territory, Australia, No. D42.2006. pp. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi Y, Nerd A, Nobel PS. Cacti as crops. Hortic Reviews. 1997;18:291&#x2013;319. 10.1002/9780470650608.ch6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9780470650608.ch6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie Q, Gao GL, Fan QJ, Qiao G, Wen XP, Liu T, Peng ZJ, Cai YQ. Isolation and characterization of a catalase gene HuCAT3 from Pitaya (<i>Hylocereus undatus</i>) and its expression under abiotic stress. Gene. 2015;563(1):63&#x2013;71. 10.1016/j.gene.2015.03.007.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2015.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25752288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi Y, Raveh E, Yossov E, Nerd A, Ben-Asher J. New fruit crops with high water use efficiency. In: Janick J, Whipkey A, editors. Creating markets for economic development of new crops and new uses. Alexandria, VA: ASHS; 2007. pp. 216&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerd A, Neumann PM. Phloem water transport maintains stem growth in a drought-stressed crop cactus (<i>Hylocereus undatus</i>). J Am Soc Hortic Sci. 2004;129(4):486&#x2013;90. 10.21273/JASHS.129.4.0486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21273/JASHS.129.4.0486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante IHL, Beckmann MZ, Martins ABG, Galbiatti JA, Cavalcante LF. Water salinity and initial development of Pitaya. Int J Fruit Sci. 2007;7(3):81&#x2013;92. 10.1300/J492v07n03_08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J492v07n03_08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques VB, Moreira RA, Ramos JD, Araujo NA, Cruz MDM. Depth of planting and apical dominance on cuttings of red Pitaya. Semina Ciencias Agrarias. 2012;33(6):2091&#x2013;8. 10.5433/1679-0359.2012v33n6p2091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5433/1679-0359.2012v33n6p2091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirda C, Cetin M, Dasgan Y, Topcu S, Kaman H, Ekici B, Derici MR, Ozguven AI. Yield response of greenhouse grown tomato to partial root drying and conventional deficit irrigation. Agric Water Manage. 2004;69(3):191&#x2013;201. 10.1016/j.agwat.2004.04.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2004.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakma SP, Rashid ASMH, Roy S, Islam M. Effect of NPK doses on the yield of Dragon fruit (<i>Hylocereus Costaricensis</i> [F.A.C. Weber] Britton &amp; Rose) in Chittagong hill tracts. American-Eurasian J Agricultural Environ Sci (AEJAES). 2014;14(6):521&#x2013;6. 10.5829/idosi.aejaes.2014.14.06.12346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5829/idosi.aejaes.2014.14.06.12346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crane JH, Balerdi CF. Pitaya Growing in the Florida Home Landscape. UF-IFAS-Extension #HS1068. 2009. p.9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;ksal ES, Cemek B, Art&#x131;k C, Temizel KE, Ta&#x15f;an M. A new approach for neutron moisture meter calibration: artificial neural network. Irrig Sci. 2011;29:369&#x2013;77. 10.1007/s00271-010-0246-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00271-010-0246-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;. Performance evaluation of PR2 in determination of soil water content. Yuzuncu Yil Univ J Agricultural Sci. 2021;31(3):543&#x2013;50. 10.29133/yyutbd.878567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29133/yyutbd.878567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart JI, Cuenca RH, Pruitt WO, Hagan RM,Tosso J. Determination and Utilization of Water Production Functions for Principal CaliforniaCrops. W-67 CA Contributing Project Report, University of California, Davis, USA. 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doorenbos J, Kassam AH. Yield Response to Water. FAO Irrigation and Drainage Paper No: 33, Rome. 1979. p.193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas ST, Mitcham EJ. Quality of pitaya fruit (Hylocereus undatus) as influenced by storage temperature and packaging. Scienta Agricola, 2013;70(4):257-262 10.1590/S0103-90162013000400006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balkic R, Balc&#x131;-Torun F, Gungor KK, Guler G, Gubbuk H. Physical and chemical characterization of guava (Psidium guajava L.) genotypes grown in subtropical condition. Notulae Botanicae Horti Agrobotanici Cluj-Napoca, 2024;52(2):13353.10.15835/nbha52213353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves MM, Maroco JP, Pereira JS. Understanding plant responses to drought-from genes to the whole plant. Functional Plant Biology, 2003;30(3):239-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32689007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fereres E, Soriano MA. Deficit irrigation for reducing agricultural water use. Journal of Experimental Botany, 2007;58(2):147-159.10.1093/jxb/erl165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17088360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MF, Numan SM, Akhtar S. Cultivation, nutritional value and health benefits of dragon fruit (Hylocereus spp.): A review. International Journal of Horticultural Science and Technology, 2021;8(3):259-269.10.22059/ijhst.2021.311550.400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Bellec F, Vaillant F, Imbert E. Pitahaya (Hylocereus spp.): A new fruit crop, a market with a future. Fruits, 2006;61(4):237-250.10.1051/fruits:2006021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizrahi Y. Vine-cacti pitayas: the new crops of the world. Revista Brasileira de Fruticultura 2014;36(1):124-13810.1590/0100-2945-452/13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElObeidy A.A. Mass propagation of pitaya (Dragon Fruit). Fruits, 2006;61(5):313-319.10.1051/fruits:2006030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang YL, Chen LY, Lee TC, Chang PT. Improving postharvest storage of fresh red-fleshed pitaya (Hylocereus polyrhizus sp.) fruit by pre-harvest application of CPPU. Scientia Horticulturae, 2020;273:10964610.1016/j.scienta.2020.109646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panigrahi P, Raychaudhuri S, Thakur AK, Nayak AK, Sahu P, Ambast SK. Automatic drip irrigation scheduling effects on yield and water productivity of banana. Scientia Horticulturae, 2019;257:10867710.1016/j.scienta.2019.108677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavuz D, Seymen M, S&#xfc;heri S, Yavuz N, T&#xfc;rkmen &#xd6;, Kurtar ES. How do rootstocks of citron watermelon (Citrullus lanatus var. citroides) affect the yield and quality of watermelon under deficit irrigation? Agricultural Water Management, 2020;241:10635110.1016/j.agwat.2020.106351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Xing Y. Evaluation of the effects of irrigation and fertilization on tomato fruit yield and quality: a principal component analysis. Scientific Reports. 2017;7(1):350. 10.1038/s41598-017-00373-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-00373-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28336916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>