<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41177914</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-4758</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hemodialysis international. International Symposium on Home Hemodialysis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hemodial Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Aerobic Combined Resistance Exercise in Dialysis on Restless Legs Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>258</StartPage><EndPage>266</EndPage><MedlinePgn>258-266</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hdi.70031</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To analyze the effects of aerobic combined resistance exercise in dialysis on restless legs syndrome (RLS), sleep quality, anxiety, depression, and quality of life of maintenance dialysis patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">59 patients who underwent maintenance hemodialysis combined with RLS in the blood purification center of Taihe County People's Hospital of Anhui Province from September to December 2024 were selected as the study subjects. The study subjects were divided into 30 cases of the control group and 29 cases of the intervention group using a randomized numerical table. The control group received routine dialysis and health education. In contrast, the intervention group received aerobic combined resistance exercise in dialysis, similar to the control group, with the time controlled at about 40&#x2009;min, three times a week for 12&#x2009;weeks. We observed the severity of RLS (IRLS), Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), self-rating anxiety scale (SAS), self-rating depression scale (SDS), and quality of life (the Kidney Disease Questionnaire, KDQ) in the two groups before and after 12&#x2009;weeks of intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There was no statistical difference in IRLS, PSQI, SAS, SDS, and KDQ scores between the two groups before the intervention (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). After 12&#x2009;weeks of intervention, IRLS, SAS, and SDS scores of the intervention group were lower than those of the control group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Notably, the intervention group showed significantly improved PSQI scores (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The KDQ scores were higher than those of the control group, and the differences were all statistically significant (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Aerobic combined resistance exercise in dialysis can improve the symptoms of RLS in maintenance hemodialysis patients, enhance sleep quality, reduce negative emotions such as anxiety and depression, and improve quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 International Society for Hemodialysis.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Amin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Affiliated Taihe Hospital of Wannan Medical College (Taihe County People's Hospital), Fuyang, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Liqin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8328-8406</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Nursing, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Affiliated Taihe Hospital of Wannan Medical College (Taihe County People's Hospital), Fuyang, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Liheng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Affiliated Taihe Hospital of Wannan Medical College (Taihe County People's Hospital), Fuyang, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Wenwen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Affiliated Taihe Hospital of Wannan Medical College (Taihe County People's Hospital), Fuyang, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>School of Nursing, Wannan Medical College</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>Hemodial Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101093910</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1492-7535</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012148" MajorTopicYN="Y">Restless Legs Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006435" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Dialysis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combined exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemodialysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">restless legs syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41177914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hdi.70031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>R. P. Allen, D. L. Picchietti, D. Garcia&#x2010;Borreguero, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Restless Legs Syndrome/Willis&#x2010;Ekbom Disease Diagnostic Criteria: Updated International Restless Legs Syndrome Study Group (IRLSSG) Consensus Criteria &#x2013; History, Rationale, Description, and Significance,&#x201d; Sleep Medicine 15, no. 8 (2024): 860&#x2013;873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Zhou, Y. Liu, X. R. Zhang, C. Wang, S. S. Liu, and Y. Jiang, &#x201c;Global Prevalence of Restless Legs Syndrome Among Hemodialysis Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Brain and Behavior: A Cognitive Neuroscience Perspective 14, no. 1 (2024): 1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liu, Q. Du, and Y. Jiang, &#x201c;Prevalence of Restless Legs Syndrome in Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sleep Medicine 114, no. 1 (2024): 15&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Hariharan, L. Chkhikvadze, A. Mateshvili, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association of Sleep Problems With Dialysis Shifts in Patients Undergoing Hemodialysis in Tbilisi, Georgia,&#x201d; Cureus 16, no. 7 (2024): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, S. C. Liu, Y. Q. Ji, N. Mao, and W. Lv, &#x201c;Survey on the Influencing Factors and Quality of Life of Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients With Combined Restless Legs Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Xuzhou Medical University 44, no. 10 (2024): 753&#x2013;759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Du, H. Gan, Z. J. Chen, and Y. F. Xia, &#x201c;Clinical Characteristics and Associated Factors of Restless Legs Syndrome in Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Nephrology 33, no. 3 (2017): 198&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Y. Song, R. J. Hu, Y. S. Diao, L. Chen, and X. L. Jiang, &#x201c;Effects of Exercise Training on Restless Legs Syndrome, Depression, Sleep Quality, and Fatigue Among Hemodialysis Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Pain and Symptom Management 55, no. 4 (2018): 1184&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Winkelman, M. J. Armstrong, R. P. Allen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Practice Guideline Summary: Treatment of Restless Legs Syndrome in Adults: Report of the Guideline Development, Dissemination, and Implementation Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology,&#x201d; Neurology 87, no. 24 (2016): 2585&#x2013;2593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. K. Sakkas, G. M. Hadjigeorgiou, C. Karatzaferi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Intradialytic Aerobic Exercise Training Ameliorates Symptoms of Restless Legs Syndrome and Improves Functional Capacity in Patients on Hemodialysis: a Pilot Study,&#x201d; ASAIO Journal 54, no. 2 (2008): 185&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Mortazavi, B. Vahdatpour, A. Ghasempour, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Aerobic Exercise Improves Signs of Restless Leg Syndrome in End Stage Renal Disease Patients Suffering Chronic Hemodialysis,&#x201d; Scientific World Journal 2013, no. 1 (2013): 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. D. Giannaki, G. K. Sakkas, C. Karatzaferi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Exercise Training and Dopamine Agonists in Patients With Uremic Restless Legs Syndrome: a Six&#x2010;Month Randomized, Partially Double&#x2010;Blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Comparative Study,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology 14, no. 1 (2013): 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. D. Giannaki, G. K. Sakkas, C. Karatzaferi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Evidence of Increased Muscle Atrophy and Impaired Quality of Life Parameters in Patients With Uremic Restless Legs Syndrome,&#x201d; PLoS One 10, no. 6 (2011): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhang, A. M. Li, Y. J. Liu, and T. T. Yu, &#x201c;Study on the Intervention Effect of Aerobic Exercise in Dialysis on Restless Legs Syndrome and Psychological Condition of Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Nephrology 20, no. 7 (2020): 586&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Xia and F. X. Chen, &#x201c;Application Value of Pedicab Exercise Therapy With Gabapentin in Treating Hemodialysis Patients With Restless Leg Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Family Medicine 20, no. 5 (2022): 793&#x2013;795 807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Altayb Ismail, I. Daffalla, T. Singh, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Efficacy of Aerobic and Stretching Exercises in Managing Willis&#x2010;Ekbom Disease (Restless Leg Syndrome) Among Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Cureus 16, no. 10 (2024): 71470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. F. Ma and S. D. Chen, &#x201c;Diagnosis and Treatment of Restless Legs Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Neuroimmunology and Neurology 17, no. 5 (2010): 379&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Chen, T. H. Lee, Y. K. Tu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Pharmacological and Non&#x2010;Pharmacological Treatments for Restless Legs Syndrome in End&#x2010;Stage Kidney Disease: a Systematic Review and Component Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Nephrology, Dialysis, Transplantation 37, no. 10 (2022): 1982&#x2013;1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. M. Chen, Standard Operating Procedures for Blood Purification (People's Health Publishing House, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Ashby, N. Borman, J. Burton, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Renal Association Clinical Practice Guideline on Haemodialysis,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology 20, no. 1 (2019): 1&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal Rehabilitation Committee of the Rehabilitation Physicians Branch of the Chinese Physicians Association and Y. C. Ma, &#x201c;Expert Consensus on Exercise Rehabilitation for Adult Chronic Kidney Disease Patients in China,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Nephrology 35, no. 7 (2019): 537&#x2013;543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Society of Rehabilitation Medicine, Renal Rehabilitation Professional Committee of Kidney Winning Disease, Zhongguancun Kidney Disease and Blood Purification Union, Renal Rehabilitation Professional Committee of Rehabilitation Physicians Branch of Chinese Physicians' Association, &#x201c;Expert Consensus on the Rehabilitation of Adult Hemodialysis Beneficiaries in China,&#x201d; China Blood Purification 20, no. 11 (2021): 721&#x2013;727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Sun, Q. Gu, D. Q. Xue, X. X. Shen, S. Chen, and X. Y. Yu, &#x201c;A Summary of the Best Evidence for Exercise Workouts in Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients on Dialysis,&#x201d; Journal of Nursing 37, no. 13 (2022): 9&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Compagnat, J. Y. Salle, S. Mandigout, J. Lacroix, N. Vuillerme, and J. C. Daviet, &#x201c;Rating of Perceived Exertion With Borg Scale in Stroke Over Two Common Activities of the Daily Living,&#x201d; Topics in Stroke Rehabilitation 25, no. 2 (2018): 145&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. C. Liu, M. Q. Tang, L. Hu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Study on the Reliability and Validity of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Psychiatry 29, no. 2 (1996): 103&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. D. Wang, X. L. Wang, and H. Ma, Handbook of Mental Health Rating Scales, 1st ed. (Chinese Mental Health Journal Press, 1999), 194&#x2013;196. 235&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. M. Huang, Y. Zhang, L. M. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Quality of Life and Influencing Factors of Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients in Wuhan,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Nephrology 21, no. 2 (2005): 88&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. X. Liu, S. Y. Dang, X. J. Lu, H. G. Hu, and J. H. Liu, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of the Effect of Aerobic Combined Resistance Exercise on the Intervention of Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Chongqing Medicine 53, no. 12 (2024): 1856&#x2013;1863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Safarpour, N. D. Vaziri, and B. Jabbari, &#x201c;Restless Legs Syndrome in Chronic Kidney Disease &#x2013; A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Tremor and Other Hyperkinetic Movements (New York, N.Y.) 13, no. 1 (2023): 1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. J. Ren and X. Q. Wang, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of the Effectiveness of Exercise Therapy in the Treatment of Restless Legs Syndrome in Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Anhui Medicine 21, no. 1 (2017): 82&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. D. Giannaki, G. K. Sakkas, G. M. Hadjigeorgiou, M. Manconi, and P. Bargiotas, &#x201c;Unfolding the Role of Exercise in the Management of Sleep Disorders,&#x201d; European Journal of Applied Physiology 124, no. 9 (2024): 2547&#x2013;2560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. H. Li, L. Z. Huang, X. H. Ren, J. Zhao, and M. M. Tang, &#x201c;Research on the Effect of Chinese Medicine Foot Bath on Sleep Quality and Symptom Distress in Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Chinese General Medicine 19, no. 10 (2016): 1207&#x2013;1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. P. Xu, Q. Hu, X. Z. Zhu, and C. X. Zhang, &#x201c;Effects of Resistance Training Combined With Aerobic Exercise on Sleep Quality and Fatigue in Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Nursing Research 32, no. 2 (2018): 317&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. D. Giannaki, G. M. Hadjigeorgiou, C. Karatzaferi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Single&#x2010;Blind Randomized Controlled Trial to Evaluate the Effect of 6 Months of Progressive Aerobic Exercise Training in Patients With Uraemic Restless Legs Syndrome,&#x201d; Nephrology, Dialysis, Transplantation 28, no. 11 (2013): 2834&#x2013;2840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Tentori, S. J. Elder, J. Thumma, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Physical Exercise Among Participants in the Dialysis Outcomes and Practice Patterns Study (DOPPS): Correlates and Associated Outcomes,&#x201d; Nephrology, Dialysis, Transplantation 25, no. 9 (2010): 3050&#x2013;3062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. S. Grigoriou, A. A. Krase, C. Karatzaferi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Intradialytic Hybrid Exercise Training on Fatigue Symptoms in Patients Receiving Hemodialysis Therapy,&#x201d; International Urology and Nephrology 53, no. 4 (2021): 771&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. T. Sahli, J. Jo, S. A. Mousa, and F. I. Tarazi, &#x201c;Clinical Management of Restless Legs Syndrome in End&#x2010;Stage Renal Disease Patients,&#x201d; CNS Spectrums 22, no. 1 (2017): 14&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>