<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41914234</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2282-4197</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>98</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archivio italiano di urologia, andrologia : organo ufficiale [di] Societa italiana di ecografia urologica e nefrologica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Ital Urol Androl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of the need for realistic circumcision manikin design as a learning resource for medical students in the clinical skills laboratory: mixed methods study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>14848</StartPage><MedlinePgn>14848</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/aiua.2026.14848</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Circumcision is a Level 4A clinical skill in the Indonesian Medical Doctor Competency Standards (Standar Kompetensi Dokter Indonesia [SKDI]) that every medical graduate must master. However, learning is currently hampered by the limited availability of manikins with adequate anatomical and functional realism, resulting in procedural training that is not fully safe, standardized, or meaningful. This study aims to analyse the need for a realistic circumcision manikin design as an effective learning resource by exploring the perspectives of students, lecturers, instructors, experts, and laboratory staff.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study employed a convergent parallel mixedmethods approach. Quantitative data were collected using Likert-scale questionnaires from 214 third- and fourth-year medical students (total sampling) and analysed descriptively. Qualitative data were obtained through in-depth semi-structured interviews with four lecturers/experts and two laboratory staff members (purposive sampling), along with non-participatory observations and document reviews, and were analysed thematically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Quantitative findings showed that while students found the current manikins helpful, there was a high demand for improvements in anatomical realism (skin elasticity, prepuce variation, mucosal layers, and vascular representation), functional realism (tissue resistance, bleeding simulation, and complication management), and interactive features (objective feedback). Qualitative analysis further emphasized the need for accurate anatomy, functional simulation to support repetitive practice, integration with standardized patients, and considerations related to durability, portability, and cost efficiency.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There is a strong need for the development of high-fidelity circumcision manikins that integrate anatomical, functional, and communication-scenario realism. The design blueprint generated from this study provides a foundation for next-generation prototypes aimed at improving the quality of clinical skills training in medical education.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jauhari</LastName><ForeName>Pebrian</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Public Health and Nursing, Gadjah Mada University, Yogyakarta.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hidayah</LastName><ForeName>Rachmadya Nur</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Health Education, Faculty of Medicine, Public Health and Nursing, Gadjah Mada University, Yogyakarta.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suhoyo</LastName><ForeName>Yoyo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Health Education, Faculty of Medicine, Public Health and Nursing, Gadjah Mada University, Yogyakarta.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faruk</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Hasanuddin University, Makassar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Ital Urol Androl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9308247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1124-3562</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002944" MajorTopicYN="Y">Circumcision, Male</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008348" MajorTopicYN="Y">Manikins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013337" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007214" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Indonesia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066908" MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circumcision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">realistic manikins</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41914234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/aiua.2026.14848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Mata &#xc1;N de S, de Azevedo KPM, Braga LP, et al. Training in communication skills for self-efficacy of health professionals: a systematic review. Hum Resour Health. 2021; 19:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. Brigo MJK, Garbelini MCDL, Coelho ICMM. Confidence degree and skill development in undergraduate medical students using male urogenital training simulators. Rev Col Bras Cir. 2024;51:e20243593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>3. Musharyanti L, Haryanti F, Claramita M. Improving Nursing Students&#x2019; Medication Safety Knowledge and Skills on Using the 4C/ID Learning Model. J Multidiscip Healthc (Internet). 2021 (dikutip 2 Januari 2026); 14:287-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>4. Palinrungi MA, Faruk M, Marewa MR, et al. Comparison of novel dorsal buttonhole slit versus conventional dorsal slit circumcision: efficacy, safety, and parents&#x2019; satisfaction. Arch Ital Urol Androl 2025;97:13999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>5. Konsil Kedokteran Indonesia. Standar Kompetensi Dokter Indonesia. 2 ed. Jakarta: Konsil Kedokteran Indonesia; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>6. Daryanto B, Seputra KP, Amorga R, Naim HY. Circumcision of male children in the community service project: the characteristics and prospective follow up study. Cancer Sci Res 2021; 4:1-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>7. Ahmed F, Al-Wageeh S, Ghabisha S, et al. Catastrophic complications of circumcision by traditional circumcisers. Open Access Emerg Med OAEM. 2021;13:425-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>8. Campain NJ, Parnham AS, Spasojevic N, et al. Use of a simulated model to teach male adult circumcision in Sub-Saharan Africa. World J Surg. 2017; 41:10-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>9. Demak IPK, Sari P, Tanra AAM, et al. Developing and validating low cost male catheterization mannequin as learning media in clinical skills learning. Indian J Public Health Res Dev 2018;9:1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>10. Maison POM, Yahaya I, Mensah S, et al. An assessment of the training and practice of circumcision by medical circumcisers in Ghana. Afr J Urol 2020; 26:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>11. Al Khatami R. Pengembangan Desain Preputium Pada Alat Peraga Sirkumsisi Universitas Islam Indonesia. https://dspace.uii.ac.id/bitstream/handle/123456789/44341/18525086.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. Cecilio-Fernandes D, Patel R, Sandars J. Using insights from cognitive science for the teaching of clinical skills: AMEE Guide No. 155. Med Teach. 2023; 45:1214-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>13. Sugiyono S. Metode Penelitian Pendidikan Pendekatan Kuantitatif, Kualitatif dan R&amp;D. Bandung: Alfabeta; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>14. El Sersi MH, Zaki MSM, Elnaggar SS, Mahrose R. Low-dose caudal versus dorsal penile nerve block for postoperative analgesia after circumcision: a randomized comparative study. Anaesthesiol Intensive Ther. 2023; 55:297-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Kigozi G, Nkale J, Wawer M, et al. Designing and usage of a lowcost penile model for male medical circumcision skills training in Rakai, Uganda. Urology. 2011; 77:1495-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>16. Sindu IGP, Kertiasih NK, Dinata IGS, Sugiartawan P. Development and validation of a virtual reality circumcision training simulator: simulator sickness, user experience, and clinical performance in Bali, Indonesia. Indones J Comput Cybern Syst. Indonesian Computer, Electronics and Instrumentation Support Society; 2025; 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>17. Maulana MS, Winarto H, Amalia G. Augmented reality application for surgery simulation: circumcision augmented reality simulation (CARS). Med Tek J Tek Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>18. Dos Santos J, Alsabban A, Maizels M, et al. CIRCumcision learning experience using simulation: A pilot learning platform for safe neonatal circumcision training offered either virtually or in person. Front Urol 2023; 3:1199194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>19. Vardhani A, Findyartini A, Wahid M. Needs analysis for competence of information and communication technology for medical graduates. Educ Med J 2024;16:119-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>20. McGaghie WC, Kristopaitis T. Deliberate practice and mastery learning: origins of expert medical performance. Cleland J, Durning SJ, editors. Researching Medical Education 1 ed. Wiley; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>21. Wolterinck C, Poortman C, Schildkamp K, Visscher A. Assessment for Learning: Devel-oping the required teacher competencies. Eur J Teach Educ 2024;47:711-29.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>