<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41419821</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2180</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genomic analysis of a clinical Mycolicibacterium houstonense isolate reveals dual escalation in adaptability and virulence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>86</StartPage><MedlinePgn>86</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">86</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12866-025-04637-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND"><i>Mycolicibacterium houstonense</i> is prone to being misidentified as other mycobacteria, particularly <i>M. fortuitum</i>. This study characterized the genome of a clinical <i>M. houstonense</i> isolate and delineated its phylogenetic relationship with <i>M. fortuitum</i> to provide a basis for accurate diagnosis and management of infections caused by this species.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Genome sequencing was used to determine the taxonomic status, virulence profile, and resistance traits of the clinical isolate, while comparative genomics was employed to delineate its evolutionary relationship with <i>M. fortuitum</i>.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The clinical isolate was definitively identified as <i>M. houstonense</i>. Genomic analysis revealed a unique repertoire of virulence and resistance genes. Its genome harbors 590 virulence genes, many of which encode T7SS effectors. In addition to resistance genes commonly found in nontuberculous mycobacteria, it also carries <i>M. tuberculosis</i>-related resistance determinants, enhancing its resilience to disinfectants, antiseptics, and antimicrobials commonly used in clinical settings. Phylogenomic analysis indicates that <i>M. houstonense</i> and <i>M. fortuitum</i> drive reciprocal divergence, reinforcing their environmental adaptability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Genomic analysis is poised to serve as a robust tool for the identification of <i>M. houstonense</i>. The clinical isolate in our study suggests a potential dual escalation of <i>M. houstonense</i> in adaptability and virulence, underscoring the need for stricter clinical monitoring and environmental surveillance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12866-025-04637-6.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ailing</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Science, MOE Key Laboratory of Geriatric Diseases and Immunology, Suzhou Key Laboratory of Pathogen Bioscience and Anti-infective Medicine, Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University, Suzhou, Jiangsu Province, 215123, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Nifang</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University (Changshu NO.1 People's Hospital), Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bibo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University (Changshu NO.1 People's Hospital), Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China. zbb116@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University (Changshu NO.1 People's Hospital), Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheng</LastName><ForeName>Yuefeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University (Changshu NO.1 People's Hospital), Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yimai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Changshu Medicine Examination Institute, Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Zhenghao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Changshu Medicine Examination Institute, Changshu, Jiangsu Province, 215500, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shuyan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Science, MOE Key Laboratory of Geriatric Diseases and Immunology, Suzhou Key Laboratory of Pathogen Bioscience and Anti-infective Medicine, Suzhou Medical College of Soochow University, Suzhou, Jiangsu Province, 215123, PR China. wushuyan@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SKY2023086</GrantID><Agency>Medical Innovation Application Research Project of Soochow Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Qngg2023036</GrantID><Agency>"National Mentoring System" Training Program for Young Talents in the Soochow Healthcare Field</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>32270187</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100966981</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycolicibacterium fortuitum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycolicibacterium houstonense</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comparative genome analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval for the collection of Mycolicibacterium houstonense hospital isolates and background clinical data was obtained from the Medical Ethics Committee of Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University, Changshu NO.1 People&#x2019;s Hospital, Jiangsu, China, with approval number L2025037. This study was conducted in accordance with Helsinki Declaration. According to the Changshu Hospital Affiliated to Soochow University Medical Ethics Committee, informed consent was deemed unnecessary because the isolate was obtained from residual pus specimens remaining after the completion of clinical microbiological testing of hospitalized patients. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41419821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12874952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12866-025-04637-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12866-025-04637-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pavlik I, Ulmann V, Hubelova D, Weston RT. Nontuberculous mycobacteria as sapronoses: A review. Microorganisms. 2022;10(7).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9315685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35889064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daley CL, Iaccarino JM, Lange C, Cambau E, Wallace RJ Jr., Andrejak C, Bottger EC, Brozek J, Griffith DE, Guglielmetti L et al. Treatment of nontuberculous mycobacterial pulmonary disease: an official ATS/ERS/ESCMID/IDSA clinical practice guideline. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(1):2000535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8375621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32636299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuuchi K, Morimoto K, Yoshiyama T, Tanaka Y, Fujiwara K, Okumura M, Izumi K, Shiraishi Y, Mitarai S, Ogata H, et al. Interrelational changes in the epidemiology and clinical features of nontuberculous mycobacterial pulmonary disease and tuberculosis in a referral hospital in Japan. Respir Med. 2019;152:74&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2019.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31128614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevots DR, Marras TK. Epidemiology of human pulmonary infection with nontuberculous mycobacteria: a review. Clin Chest Med. 2015;36(1):13&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccm.2014.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25676516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GS, Ghio AJ, Stout JE, Messier KP, Hudgens EE, Murphy MS, Pfaller SL, Maillard JM, Hilborn ED. Epidemiology of nontuberculous mycobacteria isolations among central North Carolina residents, 2006&#x2013;2010. J Infect. 2016;72(6):678&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2016.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26997636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groote MA, Huitt G. Infections due to rapidly growing mycobacteria. Clin Infect Diseases: Official Publication Infect Dis Soc Am. 2006;42(12):1756&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/504381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16705584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith DE, Aksamit T, Brown-Elliott BA, Catanzaro A, Daley C, Gordin F, Holland SM, Horsburgh R, Huitt G, Iademarco MF, et al. An official ATS/IDSA statement: diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of nontuberculous mycobacterial diseases. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2007;175(4):367&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200604-571ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Hsueh PR. Diseases caused by nontuberculous mycobacteria in Asia. Future Microbiol. 2014;9(1):93&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fmb.13.138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24328383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schinsky MF, Morey RE, Steigerwalt AG, Douglas MP, Wilson RW, Floyd MM, Butler WR, Daneshvar MI, Brown-Elliott BA, Wallace RJ, et al. Taxonomic variation in the Mycobacterium fortuitum third biovariant complex: description of Mycobacterium boenickei sp. nov., Mycobacterium Houstonense sp. nov., Mycobacterium neworleansense sp. nov. And Mycobacterium Brisbanense sp. nov. And recognition of Mycobacterium porcinum from human clinical isolates. Int J Syst Evol Microbiol. 2004;54(Pt 5):1653&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02743-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15388725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash KA, Andini N, Zhang Y, Brown-Elliott BA, Wallace RJ Jr. Intrinsic macrolide resistance in rapidly growing mycobacteria. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2006;50(10):3476&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00402-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1610084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17005837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Temporal D, Zvezdanova ME, Benedi P, Marin M, Blazquez-Sanchez M, Ruiz-Serrano MJ, Munoz P, Rodriguez-Sanchez B. Identification of nocardia and non-tuberculous Mycobacterium species by MALDI-TOF MS using the VITEK MS coupled to IVD and RUO databases. Microb Biotechnol. 2023;16(4):778&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1751-7915.14146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36541026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seemann T. Prokka: rapid prokaryotic genome annotation. Bioinformatics. 2014;30(14):2068&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btu153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24642063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain C, Rodriguez RL, Phillippy AM, Konstantinidis KT, Aluru S. High throughput ANI analysis of 90K prokaryotic genomes reveals clear species boundaries. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):5114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-07641-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6269478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30504855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitto F, Battistuzzi FU. Estimating pangenomes with Roary. Mol Biol Evol. 2019;37(3):933&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msz284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7038658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31848603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danecek P, Auton A, Abecasis G, Albers CA, Banks E, DePristo MA, Handsaker RE, Lunter G, Marth GT, Sherry ST, et al. The variant call format and vcftools. Bioinformatics. 2011;27(15):2156&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btr330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21653522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LT, Schmidt HA, von Haeseler A, Minh BQ. IQ-TREE: a fast and effective stochastic algorithm for estimating maximum-likelihood phylogenies. Mol Biol Evol. 2015;32(1):268&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msu300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25371430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyaanamoorthy S, Minh BQ, Wong TKF, von Haeseler A, Jermiin LS. ModelFinder: fast model selection for accurate phylogenetic estimates. Nat Methods. 2017;14(6):587&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.4285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5453245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28481363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letunic I, Bork P. Interactive tree of life (iTOL) v5: an online tool for phylogenetic tree display and annotation. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(W1):W293&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33885785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M, Eisen JA. A simple, fast, and accurate method of phylogenomic inference. Genome Biol. 2008;9(10):R151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/gb-2008-9-10-r151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18851752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngan GJ, Ng LM, Jureen R, Lin RT, Teo JW. Development of multiplex PCR assays based on the 16S-23S rRNA internal transcribed spacer for the detection of clinically relevant nontuberculous mycobacteria. Lett Appl Microbiol. 2011;52(5):546&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1472-765X.2011.03045.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Zheng D, Zhou S, Chen L, Yang J. VFDB 2022: a general classification scheme for bacterial virulence factors. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50(D1):D912&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab1107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8728188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34850947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groschel MI, Sayes F, Simeone R, Majlessi L, Brosch R. ESX secretion systems: mycobacterial evolution to counter host immunity. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2016;14(11):677&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrmicro.2016.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27665717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy S, Ghatak D, Das P, BoseDasgupta S. ESX secretion system: the gatekeepers of mycobacterial survivability and pathogenesis. Eur J Microbiol Immunol. 2020;10(4):202&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/1886.2020.00028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33174865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap A, Singh PK, Silakari O. Chemical classes targeting energy supplying GyrB domain of Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Tuberc (Edinb Scotl). 2018;113:43&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tube.2018.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30514513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kim HJ, Heo R, Kim HS, Song JM, Kim CT, Kim HJ, Kim SH, Gwon JH, Bae G, et al. Mutations in GyrA and GyrB among drug-resistant Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolates in South Korea. Infect Genet Evolution: J Mol Epidemiol Evolutionary Genet Infect Dis. 2025;136:105849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2025.105849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41173129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baran&#x10d;okov&#xe1; M, Kikelj D, Ila&#x161; J. Recent progress in the discovery and development of DNA gyrase B inhibitors. Future Med Chem. 2018;10(10):1207&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4155/fmc-2017-0257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi AD, Etemad N, Hashemzadeh M, Khandan Dezfuli S, Goodarzi H. Frequency of Rrs and RpsL mutations in streptomycin-resistant Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolates from Iranian patients. J Global Antimicrob Resist. 2017;9:51&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgar.2017.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28404234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Molin M, Gut M, Rominski A, Haldimann K, Becker K, Sander P. Molecular mechanisms of intrinsic streptomycin resistance in Mycobacterium abscessus. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2018;62(1):e01427&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5740355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde SS, Javid-Majd F, Blanchard JS. Overexpression and mechanistic analysis of chromosomally encoded aminoglycoside 2&#x2019;-N-acetyltransferase (AAC(2&#x2019;)-Ic) from Mycobacterium tuberculosis. J Biol Chem. 2001;276(49):45876&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M108810200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11590162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xf3;n-Garc&#xed;a S, Otal I, Mart&#xed;n C, G&#xf3;mez-Lus R, A&#xed;nsa JA. Novel streptomycin resistance gene from Mycobacterium fortuitum. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2006;50(11):3920&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00223-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1635185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16954315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georghiou SB, Magana M, Garfein RS, Catanzaro DG, Catanzaro A, Rodwell TC. Evaluation of genetic mutations associated with Mycobacterium tuberculosis resistance to amikacin, Kanamycin and capreomycin: a systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(3):e33275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0033275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22479378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint L, Korkegian A, Parish T. InhA inhibitors have activity against non-replicating Mycobacterium tuberculosis. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(11):e0239354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0239354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7671525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33201882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivi&#xe8;re E, Whitfield MG, Nelen J, Heupink TH, Van Rie A. Identifying Isoniazid resistance markers to guide inclusion of high-dose Isoniazid in tuberculosis treatment regimens. Clin Microbiol Infection: Official Publication Eur Soc Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020;26(10):1332&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2020.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32653663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unissa AN, Subbian S, Hanna LE, Selvakumar N. Overview on mechanisms of Isoniazid action and resistance in Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Infect Genet Evolution: J Mol Epidemiol Evolutionary Genet Infect Dis. 2016;45:474&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2016.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27612406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen MH, Vilch&#xe8;ze C, Kremer L, Besra GS, Parsons L, Salfinger M, Heifets L, Hazbon MH, Alland D, Sacchettini JC, et al. Overexpression of inhA, but not kasA, confers resistance to Isoniazid and ethionamide in Mycobacterium smegmatis, M. bovis BCG and M. tuberculosis. Mol Microbiol. 2002;46(2):453&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2958.2002.03162.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12406221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Zhu Y, Yan Y, Wang W, Wang Y. Deciphering extracellular antibiotic resistance genes (eARGs) in activated sludge by metagenome. Water Res. 2019;161:610&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2019.06.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31254887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prezioso SM, Brown NE, Goldberg JB. Elfamycins: inhibitors of elongation factor-Tu. Mol Microbiol. 2017;106(1):22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/mmi.13750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5701666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buroni S, Manina G, Guglierame P, Pasca MR, Riccardi G, De Rossi E. LfrR is a repressor that regulates expression of the efflux pump LfrA in Mycobacterium smegmatis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2006;50(12):4044&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00656-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1694004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novotna GB, Kwun MJ, Hong HJ. In vivo characterization of the activation and interaction of the VanR-VanS two-Component regulatory system controlling glycopeptide antibiotic resistance in two related streptomyces species. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2015;60(3):1627&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01367-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4775988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26711760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilch&#xe8;ze C, Weisbrod TR, Chen B, Kremer L, Hazb&#xf3;n MH, Wang F, Alland D, Sacchettini JC, Jacobs WR Jr. Altered NADH/NAD&#x2009;+&#x2009;ratio mediates coresistance to Isoniazid and ethionamide in mycobacteria. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2005;49(2):708&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.49.2.708-720.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC547332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15673755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilch&#xe8;ze C, Av-Gay Y, Attarian R, Liu Z, Hazb&#xf3;n MH, Colangeli R, Chen B, Liu W, Alland D, Sacchettini JC, et al. Mycothiol biosynthesis is essential for ethionamide susceptibility in Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Mol Microbiol. 2008;69(5):1316&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.2008.06365.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2628429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18651841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts AH, Moon CW, Faulkner V, Kendall SL, Waddell SJ, Bacon J. EfpA is required for regrowth of Mycobacterium tuberculosis following Isoniazid exposure. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2024;68(8):e0026124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.00261-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11304720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39037241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng TL, Shang YY, Huang HR, Chu NH, Chen ST. [Effects of four efflux pump inhibitors on the activities of clarithromycin against Mycobacterium abscessus]. Zhonghua Jie He He Hu Xi Za zhi = Zhonghua Jiehe He Huxi Zazhi = Chin J Tuberculosis Respiratory Dis. 2022;45(5):468&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Li GL, Pang H, Liu HC, Xiao TY, Li SJ, Luo Q, Jiang Y, Wang RB, Wan KL. Preliminary study on drug susceptibility profile and resistance mechanisms to macrolides of clinical isolates of Non-tuberculous mycobacteria from China. Biomed Environ Sci: BES. 2018;31(4):290&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29773092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timm J, Perilli MG, Duez C, Trias J, Orefici G, Fattorini L, Amicosante G, Oratore A, Joris B, Fr&#xe8;re JM, et al. Transcription and expression analysis, using LacZ and PhoA gene fusions, of Mycobacterium fortuitum beta-lactamase genes cloned from a natural isolate and a high-level beta-lactamase producer. Mol Microbiol. 1994;12(3):491&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.1994.tb01037.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8065266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobba S, Howard NC, Das S, Ahmed M, Tang L, Thirunavukkarasu S, Larsen MH, Mathema B, Divangahi M, Khader SA. Mycobacterium tuberculosis carrying the rifampicin drug-resistance-conferring RpoB mutation H445Y is associated with suppressed immunity through type I interferons. mBio. 2023;14(5):e0094623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mbio.00946-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37682004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Smet KAL, Kempsell KE, Gallagher A, Duncan K, Young DB. Alteration of a single amino acid residue reverses fosfomycin resistance of Recombinant MurA from Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Microbiology. 1999;145(Pt 11):3177&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/00221287-145-11-3177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10589726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colangeli R, Helb D, Sridharan S, Sun J, Varma-Basil M, Hazb&#xf3;n MH, Harbacheuski R, Megjugorac NJ, Jacobs WR Jr., Holzenburg A, et al. The Mycobacterium tuberculosis IniA gene is essential for activity of an efflux pump that confers drug tolerance to both Isoniazid and ethambutol. Mol Microbiol. 2005;55(6):1829&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.2005.04510.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15752203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Gao Y, Wang J, Hameed HMA, Wang S, Fang C, Tian X, Zhang J, Han X, Ju Y, et al. EmbB and EmbC regulate the sensitivity of Mycobacterium abscessus to echinomycin. mLife. 2024;3(3):459&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mlf2.12139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11442130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39359678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallejos-S&#xe1;nchez K, Lopez JM, Antiparra R, Toscano E, Saavedra H, Kirwan DE, Amzel LM, Gilman RH, Maruenda H, Sheen P, et al. Mycobacterium tuberculosis ribosomal protein S1 (RpsA) and variants with truncated C-terminal end show absence of interaction with Pyrazinoic acid. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):8356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-65173-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7239899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32433489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Cui P, Niu H, Zhang S, T&#xf8;njum T, Zhu B, Zhang Y. Introducing RpsA point mutations &#x2206;438A and D123A into the chromosome of Mycobacterium tuberculosis confirms their role in causing resistance to Pyrazinamide. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2019;63(6):e02681&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30858213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Morichaud Z, Chen S, Leonetti JP, Brodolin K. Mycobacterium tuberculosis RbpA protein is a new type of transcriptional activator that stabilizes the &#x3c3; A-containing RNA polymerase holoenzyme. Nucleic Acids Res. 2012;40(14):6547&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gks346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3413145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22570422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan S, Venter H, Dabbs ER. Ribosylative inactivation of Rifampin by Mycobacterium smegmatis is a principal contributor to its low susceptibility to this antibiotic. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1997;41(11):2456&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.41.11.2456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koteva K, Cox G, Kelso JK, Surette MD, Zubyk HL, Ejim L, Stogios P, Savchenko A, S&#xf8;rensen D, Wright GD. Rox, a rifamycin resistance enzyme with an unprecedented mechanism of action. Cell Chem Biology. 2018;25(4):403&#x2013;e412405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chembiol.2018.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29398560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Li S, Ge Q, Guo H, Shang Y, Ren W, Wang Y, Xue Z, Lu J, Pang Y. Determination of critical concentration for drug susceptibility testing of Mycobacterium tuberculosis against para-aminosalicylic acid with clinical isolates with thyA, FolC and DfrA mutations. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2022;21(1):48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12941-022-00537-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9637297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36335391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buwembo W, Aery S, Rwenyonyi CM, Swedberg G, Kironde F. Point mutations in the folp gene partly explain sulfonamide resistance of Streptococcus mutans. Int J Microbiol. 2013;2013:367021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/367021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3596926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23533419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xf3;n-Garc&#xed;a S, Mart&#xed;n C, A&#xed;nsa JA, De Rossi E. Characterization of Tetracycline resistance mediated by the efflux pump tap from Mycobacterium fortuitum. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2006;57(2):252&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dki436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Rossi E, Blokpoel MC, Cantoni R, Branzoni M, Riccardi G, Young DB, De Smet KA, Ciferri O. Molecular cloning and functional analysis of a novel Tetracycline resistance determinant, tet(V), from Mycobacterium smegmatis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1998;42(8):1931&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.42.8.1931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9687386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maitra A, Nukala S, Dickman R, Martin LT, Munshi T, Gupta A, Shepherd AJ, Arnvig KB, Tabor AB, Keep NH, et al. Characterization of the MurT/GatD complex in Mycobacterium tuberculosis towards validating a novel anti-tubercular drug target. JAC-antimicrobial Resist. 2021;3(1):dlab028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jacamr/dlab028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8210147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harth G, Maslesa-Galic S, Tullius MV, Horwitz MA. All four Mycobacterium tuberculosis GlnA genes encode glutamine synthetase activities but only GlnA1 is abundantly expressed and essential for bacterial homeostasis. Mol Microbiol. 2005;58(4):1157&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.2005.04899.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16262797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safi H, Gopal P, Lingaraju S, Ma S, Levine C, Dartois V, Yee M, Li L, Blanc L, Ho Liang HP, et al. Phase variation in Mycobacterium tuberculosis GlpK produces transiently heritable drug tolerance. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2019;116(39):19665&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1907631116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6765255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31488707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazioglu O, Kareem BO, Afzal M, Shafeeq S, Kuipers OP, Ulijasz AT, Andrew PW, Yesilkaya H. Glutamate dehydrogenase (GdhA) of Streptococcus pneumoniae is required for high temperature adaptation. Infect Immun. 2021;89(12):e0040021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.00400-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8594611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winthrop KL, Marras TK, Adjemian J, Zhang H, Wang P, Zhang Q. Incidence and prevalence of nontuberculous mycobacterial lung disease in a large U.S. Managed care health Plan, 2008&#x2013;2015. Annals Am Thorac Soc. 2020;17(2):178&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201804-236OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31830805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santin M, Barrabeig I, Malchair P, Gonzalez-Luquero L, Benitez MA, Sabria J, Palau-Benavent M, Canete C, Lloret-Queralto JA, Grijota-Camino MD, et al. Pulmonary infections with nontuberculous Mycobacteria, Catalonia, Spain, 1994&#x2013;2014. Emerg Infect Dis. 2018;24(6):1091&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2406.172095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh P, Kumar A, Biswas R, Vijayakumar D, Thulasidharan S, Anjaneyan G, Kunoor A, Biswas L. Epidemiology of nontuberculous mycobacterial infection in tuberculosis suspects. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2021;105(5):1335&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.21-0095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8592207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34424857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zweijpfenning SMH, Ingen JV, Hoefsloot W. Geographic distribution of nontuberculous mycobacteria isolated from clinical specimens: A systematic review. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;39(3):336&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0038-1660864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30071548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasch P, Beyer W, Bosch A, Borriss R, Drevinek M, Dupke S, Ehling-Schulz M, Gao X, Grunow R, Jacob D, et al. A MALDI-ToF mass spectrometry database for identification and classification of highly pathogenic bacteria. Sci Data. 2025;12(1):187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-025-04504-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39890826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagmoti MB, Kulgod SY, Narang R, Mulla RG. Diagnosis and management of postlaparotomy wound infection caused by Mycobacterium fortuitum. Int J Mycobacteriology. 2019;8(4):400&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijmy.ijmy_93_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31793513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Yang Q, Pan J, Shi H, Jin B, Chen Q. Cardiac resynchronization therapy-defibrillator pocket infection caused by Mycobacterium fortuitum: a case report and review of the literature. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2019;19(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-019-1028-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6402086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30836955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q, Chen R, Yang E, Yuan Y, Tian Y, Han Y, Wang S, Wang B, Yan W, Zhang Q, et al. Non-tuberculous mycobacterial infection of the musculoskeletal system detected at two tertiary medical centres in Henan, China, 2016&#x2013;2020. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:791918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.791918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maillard JY, Pascoe M. Disinfectants and antiseptics: mechanisms of action and resistance. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2024;22(1):4&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-023-00958-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37648789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>