<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41804444</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Performance of Triglyceride/High-Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol (TG/HDL-C) Ratio in Detecting Insulin Resistance Among Obese Children and Adolescents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103072</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103072</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103072</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background We evaluated the diagnostic performance of the triglyceride/high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (TG/HDL-C) ratio for detecting insulin resistance (IR) in obese children and adolescents using sex- and puberty-specific homeostasis model assessment for insulin resistance (HOMA-IR) cutoffs. Methods This retrospective cross-sectional study included 207 obese patients (5-18 years old; 127 girls and 80 boys) assessed at a tertiary pediatric endocrinology clinic. IR was defined using sex-specific and pubertal stage-specific HOMA-IR thresholds. Anthropometric data and fasting glucose, insulin, lipid profile, glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c), and thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) were recorded. Receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis evaluated the TG/HDL-C ratio for IR discrimination. Results Compared with the IR-negative group, IR-positive participants had higher weight, body mass index (BMI) (and standard deviation score {SDS}), TG/HDL-C ratio, fasting insulin, HOMA-IR, HbA1c, fasting glucose, triglycerides,&#xa0;and TSH (all p&lt;0.05).&#xa0;The best threshold for TG/HDL-C to identify IR was around 1.7 (area under the curve {AUC}=0.601; p=0.019), with sensitivity and specificity of 71.2% and 55.1%, respectively. Diagnostic accuracy was consistent across sex and pubertal groups. Conclusions The TG/HDL-C ratio demonstrates moderate diagnostic performance in detecting insulin resistance in obese children and adolescents, and this performance is independent of pubertal status or sex. In clinical settings, such as primary care, where insulin measurement and HOMA-IR calculation are not feasible, the TG/HDL-C ratio can be used as an independent marker. However, when insulin measurements are possible, this ratio should be considered a supportive marker alongside HOMA-IR. Additional investigations should assess the potential of this ratio to enhance diagnostic accuracy in multivariate analysis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Bahar Akin et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahar Akin</LastName><ForeName>Semra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Endocrinology, Derince Training and Research Hospital, Kocaeli, TUR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">child</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">triglycerides</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. The Derince Training and Research Hospital Clinical Research Ethics Committee issued approval 2025-16. Ethical approval was obtained from the Clinical Research Ethics Committee of the tertiary hospital (Derince Training and Research Hospital) (decision number: 2025-16), and the requirement for informed consent was waived because of the retrospective, anonymized nature of the study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41804444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12967794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Worldwide trends in underweight and obesity from 1990 to 2022: a pooled analysis of 3663 population-representative studies with 222 million children, adolescents, and adults. NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC) Lancet. 2024;403:1027&#x2013;1050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38432237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of childhood obesity and related parental factors across socioeconomic strata in Ankara, Turkey. Yardim MS, &#xd6;zcebe LH, Araz OM, et al. East Mediterr Health J. 2019;25:374&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31469157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perceptions of obesity prevention policies: socioeconomic assessment in the Turkish capital. Haley SJ, Li S, Uner S, et al. J Pediatr Nurs. 2019;44:0&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30413328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childhood obesity: causes and consequences. Sahoo K, Sahoo B, Choudhury AK, Sofi NY, Kumar R, Bhadoria AS. J Family Med Prim Care. 2015;4:187&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25949965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adipose tissue and insulin resistance in obese. Ahmed B, Sultana R, Greene MW. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;137:111315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33561645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homeostasis model assessment is more reliable than the fasting glucose/insulin ratio and quantitative insulin sensitivity check index for assessing insulin resistance among obese children and adolescents. Keskin M, Kurtoglu S, Kendirci M, Atabek ME, Yazici C. Pediatrics. 2005;115:0&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insulin resistance in obese children and adolescents: HOMA-IR cut-off levels in the prepubertal and pubertal periods. Kurto&#x11f;lu S, Hatipo&#x11f;lu N, Maz&#x131;c&#x131;o&#x11f;lu M, Kendirici M, Keskin M, Kondolot M. J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2010;2:100&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21274322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triglyceride to HDL-C ratio is associated with insulin resistance in overweight and obese children. Iwani NA, Jalaludin MY, Zin RM, et al. Sci Rep. 2017;7:40055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5216403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28059134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Should triglycerides and the triglycerides to high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio be used as surrogates for insulin resistance? Kim-Dorner SJ, Deuster PA, Zeno SA, Remaley AT, Poth M. Metabolism. 2010;59:299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19796777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TG: HDL-C ratio as insulin resistance marker for metabolic syndrome in children with obesity. Nur Zati Iwani AK, Jalaludin MY, Yahya A, et al. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022;13:852290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8965646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TG/HDL-C ratio for predicting insulin resistance in obese children from Beijing, China. Zhang T, Duan F, Qian Y, Zhang J, Sun H, Wan N. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2024;24:1101&#x2013;1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11337239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37937558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of TG-HDL ratio instead of HOMA ratio as insulin resistance marker in overweight and children with obesity. Behiry EG, El Nady NM, AbdEl Haie OM, Mattar MK, Magdy A. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2019;19:676&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The triglyceride/HDL ratio as a surrogate biomarker for insulin resistance. Baneu P, V&#x103;c&#x103;rescu C, Dr&#x103;gan SR, et al. Biomedicines. 2024;12:1493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11274455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39062066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization 2006 child growth standards and 2007 growth reference charts: a discussion paper by the Committee on Nutrition of the European Society for Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Nutrition. Turck D, Michaelsen KF, Shamir R, et al. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2013;57:258&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23880630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical longitudinal standards for height, weight, height velocity, weight velocity, and stages of puberty. Tanner JM, Whitehouse RH. Arch Dis Child. 1976;51:170&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1545912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">952550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice guideline for screening and management of high blood pressure in children and adolescents. Flynn JT, Kaelber DC, Baker-Smith CM, et al. Pediatrics. 2017;140:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28827377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and beta-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man. Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, Naylor BA, Treacher DF, Turner RC. Diabetologia. 1985;28:412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3899825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Index for rating diagnostic tests. Youden WJ. Cancer. 1950;3:32&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15405679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TriGlycerides and high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio compared with homeostasis model assessment insulin resistance indexes in screening for metabolic syndrome in the chinese obese children: a cross section study. Liang J, Fu J, Jiang Y, Dong G, Wang X, Wu W. BMC Pediatr. 2015;15:138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4587405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26416207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis of lipid disorders in insulin resistance: a brief review. Bjornstad P, Eckel RH. Curr Diab Rep. 2018;18:127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6428207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30328521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regulation of plasma triglycerides in insulin resistance and diabetes. Ginsberg HN, Zhang YL, Hernandez-Ono A. Arch Med Res. 2005;36:232&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15925013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liver insulinization as a driver of triglyceride dysmetabolism. Cook JR, Hawkins MA, Pajvani UB. Nat Metab. 2023;5:1101&#x2013;1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12206343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37460842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The triglyceride-to-HDL cholesterol ratio: association with insulin resistance in obese youths of different ethnic backgrounds. Giannini C, Santoro N, Caprio S, et al. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:1869&#x2013;1874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21730284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usefulness of the triglycerides to high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio (TG/HDL-C) in prediction of metabolic syndrome in Polish obese children and adolescents. Krawczyk M, Rumi&#x144;ska M, Witkowska-S&#x119;dek E, Majcher A, Pyr&#x17c;ak B. Acta Biochim Pol. 2018;65:605&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30451245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TG: HDL-C ratio is a good marker to identify children affected by obesity with increased cardiometabolic risk and insulin resistance. Nur Zati Iwani AK, Jalaludin MY, Wan Mohd Zin RM, et al. Int J Endocrinol. 2019;2019:8586167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6914959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31885562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel diagnostic tool in determining insulin resistance in obese children: triglyceride / HDL ratio. Demiral M. J Surg Med. 2021;5:1144&#x2013;1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>To use of triglyceride/hdl cholesterol ratio to predict insulin resistance and dysglycemia in overweight and obese children. Ciftci N, Kayas L. Ann Med Res. 2023;30:920&#x2013;923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk assessment of metabolic syndrome in adolescents using the triglyceride/high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio and the total cholesterol/high-density lipoprotein cholesterol ratio. Chu SY, Jung JH, Park MJ, Kim SH. Ann Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2019;24:41&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6449623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altered metal homeostasis associates with inflammation, oxidative stress, impaired glucose metabolism, and dyslipidemia in the crosstalk between childhood obesity and insulin resistance. Gonz&#xe1;lez-Dom&#xed;nguez &#xc1;, Mill&#xe1;n-Mart&#xed;nez M, Dom&#xed;nguez-Riscart J, Mateos RM, Lechuga-Sancho AM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Dom&#xed;nguez R. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11:2439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9774623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36552647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>