<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41415137</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0976-7800</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of mid-life health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Midlife Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sarcopenia in Menopausal Women: Prevalence, Risk Factors, Hormonal Mechanisms, and Management Strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>367</StartPage><EndPage>370</EndPage><MedlinePgn>367-370</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jmh.jmh_134_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sarcopenia, an age-related loss of muscle mass and function, represents a significant musculoskeletal condition in menopausal women, affecting up to 80% of those with musculoskeletal complaints, and poses a growing public health concern in India where 71% of the population lives in rural areas with high prevalence of risk factors like poor nutrition and physical inactivity. This systematic review aimed to examine the prevalence, risk factors, hormonal mechanisms, and management strategies for sarcopenia in menopausal women, with emphasis on implications for maternal health and preventive interventions. A literature search from 2015 to 2025 was conducted via PubMed and Google Scholar using terms such as sarcopenia, menopausal complaints, and preventive measures, including only original, peer-reviewed, English-language full-text articles relevant to menopause and sarcopenia. From 92 identified articles, 12 met the criteria, revealing sarcopenia prevalence in India ranging from 10% to 43.6%, higher in rural settings and among diabetics. Hormonal declines in estrogen, testosterone, dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA), progesterone, and growth hormone (GH)/insulin-like growth factor 1 (IGF-1), coupled with increased cortisol, contribute to muscle loss. Effective interventions include protein intake of 0.8-1.2 g/kg/day, vitamin D supplementation of 800-1000 IU/day, physical activity comprising 150 min/week of aerobic exercise plus resistance training, and hormone therapy. Maternal complications encompass elevated fall risk and physical disability, which indirectly impact fetal health in perimenopausal pregnancies. Overall, sarcopenia in menopausal women demands heightened awareness and targeted interventions, especially in rural India, with future research needed on biomarkers and optimized protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Mid-life Health.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrikhande</LastName><ForeName>Laxmi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shrikhande Hospital and Research Centre Pvt Ltd., Nagpur, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kedar</LastName><ForeName>Khsama</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynaecology, SVNGMC, Yavatmal, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mounisa</LastName><ForeName>Dondapati Chandra</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynaecology, SVNGMC, Yavatmal, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garg</LastName><ForeName>Ruchika</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, SN Medical College, Agra, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Prabhat</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, SN Medical College, Agra, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrikhande</LastName><ForeName>Aditya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Internal Medicine, Parkland Hospital, Farmington, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Midlife Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101552746</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0976-7800</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormonal changes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preventive interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41415137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12711168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jmh.jmh_134_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JMH-16-367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Malla VG, Tuteja A. Menopausal spectrum of urban Indian women. J Midlife Health. 2014;5:99&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4071654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24970991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung TW, Chou MY, Iijima K, et al. Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia:2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:300&#x2013;7.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh N, Harshitha R, Bhargava M. Prevalence of sarcopenia in an elderly population in rural South India: A cross-sectional study. F1000Res. 2020;9:175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman R, Wilson BP, Paul TV, Yadav B, Kango Gopal G, Viggeswarpu S. Prevalence and factors contributing to primary sarcopenia in relatively healthy older Indians attending the outpatient department in a tertiary care hospital: A cross-sectional study. Aging Med (Milton) 2021;4:257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8711223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yogesh M, Patel MG, Makwana HH, Kalariya H. Unraveling the enigma of sarcopenia and sarcopenic obesity in Indian adults with type 2 diabetes &#x2013;A comparative cross-sectional study. Clin Diabetes Endocrinol. 2024;10:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11181647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38880930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao AR, Bhagwasia M, Singh V, Bajpai S, Singhal S, Chatterjee P, et al. Prevalence and determinants of sarcopenia among older adults in India: Insights from the longitudinal aging study in India. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2025;73:1429&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39887986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okayama A, Nakayama N, Kashiwa K, Horinouchi Y, Fukusaki H, Nakamura H, et al. Prevalence of sarcopenia and its association with quality of life, postural stability, and past incidence of falls in postmenopausal women with osteoporosis: A cross-sectional study. Healthcare (Basel) 2022;10:192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoine S, Granier P, Tiffoche C, Rannou-Bekono F, Thieulant ML, Delamarche P. Estrogen receptor alpha mRNA in human skeletal muscles. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:439&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyagi V, Scordo M, Yoon RS, Liporace FA, Greene LW. Revisiting the role of testosterone: Are we missing something? Rev Urol. 2017;19:16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst KL, Bhasin S. Testosterone action on skeletal muscle. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2004;7:271&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaras N, Samaras D, Frangos E, Forster A, Philippe J. A review of age-related dehydroepiandrosterone decline and its association with well-known geriatric syndromes: Is treatment beneficial? Rejuvenation Res. 2013;16:285&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23647054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrie F, Luu-The V, Labrie C, Simard J. DHEA and its transformation into androgens and estrogens in peripheral target tissues: Intracrinology. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2001;22:185&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11456468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cable JK, Grider MH. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Physiology, progesterone.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkman JE, Tariq MA, Leavitt L, Sharma S.  StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025.  [[Last updated 2023 May 01]]. Physiology, Growth Hormone. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK482141/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanciulli G, Delitala A, Delitala G. Growth hormone, menopause and ageing: No definite evidence for 'rejuvenation'with growth hormone. Hum Reprod Update. 2009;15:341&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thau L, Gandhi J, Sharma S. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Physiology, cortisol.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho EJ, Choi Y, Jung SJ, Kwak HB. Role of exercise in estrogen deficiency-induced sarcopenia. J Exerc Rehabil. 2022;18:2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35356136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzoli R, Boonen S, Brandi ML, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Cooper C, Kanis JA, et al. Vitamin D supplementation in elderly or postmenopausal women: A 2013 update of the 2008 recommendations from the European Society for Clinical and Economic Aspects of Osteoporosis and Osteoarthritis (ESCEO) Curr Med Res Opin. 2013;29:305&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23320612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintziori G, Lambrinoudaki I, Goulis DG, Ceausu I, Depypere H, Erel CT, et al. EMAS position statement: Non-hormonal management of menopausal vasomotor symptoms. Maturitas. 2015;81:410&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25982505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock K, Ketvertis KM. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2021. Menopause.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik R, Goel H. Clinical validation of calf circumference with DEXA scans as a measure of muscle mass to assess sarcopenia in community settings in Indian postmenopausal women. J Midlife Health. 2024;15:99&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11321518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39145269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>