<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41652340</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence gaps in the effects of exercise on SASP-Related biomarkers in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">322</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-026-07025-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Cellular senescence is a hallmark of aging, characterized by the secretion of proinflammatory factors known as the senescence-associated secretory phenotype (SASP). While physical exercise is proposed as a potential modulator of cellular aging, its effect on specific senescence biomarkers in older adults remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis following PRISMA guidelines (PROSPERO: CRD42024623676). Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) involving participants aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;60 years were included if they compared structured exercise interventions with control conditions and reported biomarkers of cellular senescence. A Bayesian meta-analysis was performed, and the risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2.0 tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Three RCTs (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1447; age range 66&#x2013;79; 64.2% female) met the inclusion criteria. Two were eligible for meta-analysis, focusing on SASP-related cytokines (CCL2, IL-6, IL-8, TNF-&#x3b1;). No statistically significant differences were observed between the exercise and control groups. One excluded study reported increased SIRT levels following resistance training, but these are not standard senescence markers. Notably, none of the included RCTs evaluated key upstream markers such as p16^INK4a^ or p21, highlighting a critical gap in current research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This review found no conclusive evidence that exercise training affects canonical markers of cellular senescence in older adults. The biomarkers analyzed were limited to SASP-related cytokines, which reflect downstream inflammation rather than primary senescence regulation. Future studies should use standardized protocols to evaluate upstream markers such as p16^INK4a^ and p21 to better understand the impact of physical activity on cellular aging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12877-026-07025-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Romero</LastName><ForeName>Eleuterio A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0254-6501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Nursing and Health Care, Puerta de Hierro Health Research Institute-Segovia de Arana (IDIPHISA), Majadahonda, 28222, Spain. esanchezromero@fgcu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Florida Gulf Coast University, Fort Myers, FL, 33965, USA. esanchezromero@fgcu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Madrid, 28014, Spain. esanchezromero@fgcu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Orofacial Pain Working Group, Sociedad Espa&#xf1;ola de Disfunci&#xf3;n Craneomandibular y Dolor Orofacial (SEDCYDO), Madrid, 28009, Spain. esanchezromero@fgcu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Pozas</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4804-550X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Madrid, 28014, Spain. oliver.martp@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Orofacial Pain Working Group, Sociedad Espa&#xf1;ola de Disfunci&#xf3;n Craneomandibular y Dolor Orofacial (SEDCYDO), Madrid, 28009, Spain. oliver.martp@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2893-1627</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Madrid, 28014, Spain. samuel.fernandezc@uah.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Fisioterapia, Universidad de Alcal&#xe1;, Facultad de Enfermer&#xed;a y Fisioterapia, Alcal&#xe1; de Henares, 28801, Spain. samuel.fernandezc@uah.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romero-Rosado</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;lvaro</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-8054-2465</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Madrid, 28014, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Fisioterapia, Universidad de Alcal&#xe1;, Facultad de Enfermer&#xed;a y Fisioterapia, Alcal&#xe1; de Henares, 28801, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sillevis</LastName><ForeName>Rob</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2245-0996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Florida Gulf Coast University, Fort Myers, FL, 33965, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuenca-Zald&#xed;var</LastName><ForeName>Juan Nicol&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6787-3944</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Nursing and Health Care, Puerta de Hierro Health Research Institute-Segovia de Arana (IDIPHISA), Majadahonda, 28222, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Group on Musculoskeletal Disorders, Madrid, 28014, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Unit, Primary Health Care Center "El Abaj&#xf3;n", Las Rozas de Madrid, 28231, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cellular senescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Senescence markers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Senescence-Associated secretory phenotype (SASP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">p16^INK4a^</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">p21</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. This study is a systematic review and meta-analysis based entirely on previously published data. No new data were collected from human participants, and all included randomized controlled trials had obtained prior ethics approval and participant consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41652340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12977871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-026-07025-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-026-07025-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Englund DA, Sakamoto AE, Fritsche CM, Heeren AA, Zhang X, Kotajarvi BR, Lecy DR, Yousefzadeh MJ, Schafer MJ, White TA, Atkinson EJ, LeBrasseur NK. Exercise reduces Circulating biomarkers of cellular senescence in humans. Aging Cell. 2021;20(7):e13415. 10.1111/acel.13415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acel.13415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8282238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34101960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T, Tsang C, Huang J. Can hypoxic exercise retard cellular senescence? A narrative review. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2024;21:31. 10.1186/s11556-024-00352-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-024-00352-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11559150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39533169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Han J, Elisseeff JH, Demaria M. The senescence-associated secretory phenotype and its physiological and pathological implications. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2024;25(12):958&#x2013;78. 10.1038/s41580-024-00727-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41580-024-00727-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38654098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautmans I, Salimans L, Njemini R, Beyer I, Lieten S, Liberman K. The effects of exercise interventions on the inflammatory profile of older adults: A systematic review of the recent literature. Exp Gerontol. 2021;146:111236. 10.1016/j.exger.2021.111236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2021.111236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberman K, Forti LN, Beyer I, Bautmans I. The effects of exercise on muscle strength, body composition, physical functioning and the inflammatory profile of older adults: a systematic review. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2017;20(1):30&#x2013;53. 10.1097/MCO.0000000000000335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27755209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohtani N. The roles and mechanisms of senescence-associated secretory phenotype (SASP): can it be controlled by senolysis? Inflamm Regeneration. 2022;42(1):11. 10.1186/s41232-022-00197-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41232-022-00197-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple BA, Mattingly ML, Godwin JS, McIntosh MC, Kontos NJ, Agyin-Birikorang A, Michel JM, Plotkin DL, Chen SY, Ziegenfuss TN, Fruge AD, Gladden LB, Robinson AT, Mobley CB, Mackey AL, Roberts MD. The effects of resistance training on denervated myofibers, senescent cells, and associated protein markers in middle-aged adults. FASEB Journal: Official Publication Federation Am Soc Experimental Biology. 2024;38(8):e23621. 10.1096/fj.202302103RRR.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202302103RRR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, de Souto Barreto P, Arai H, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Cadore EL, Cesari M, Chen LK, Coen PM, Courneya KS, Duque G, Ferrucci L, Fielding RA, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Robledo LM, Harridge SDR, Kirk B, Kritchevsky S, Landi F, Lazarus N, Liu-Ambrose T, Fiatarone Singh MA. Global consensus on optimal exercise recommendations for enhancing healthy longevity in older adults (ICFSR). J Nutr Health Aging. 2025;29(1):100401. 10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39743381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaquin N, Tu V, Rodier F. Assessing functional roles of the Senescence-Associated secretory phenotype (SASP). <i>Methods in molecular biology</i>. (Clifton N J). 2019;1896:45&#x2013;55. 10.1007/978-1-4939-8931-7_6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4939-8931-7_6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30474839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, Shekelle P, Stewart LA, PRISMA-P Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4:148&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagendrababu V, Duncan HF, Dummer PMH. Research that matters: systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Int Endod J. 2020;53(4):437&#x2013;9. 10.1111/iej.13272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.13272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32170984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa Santos CM, de Mattos Pimenta CA, Nobre MR. The PICO strategy for the research question construction and evidence search. Rev Latinoam Enferm. 2007;15(3):508&#x2013;11. 10.1590/s0104-11692007000300023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s0104-11692007000300023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17653438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, Thomas J. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10):ED000142. PMID: 31643080; PMCID: PMC10284251. 10.1002/14651858.ED000142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, Cates CJ, Cheng HY, Corbett MS, Eldridge SM, Emberson JR, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Hopewell S, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Junqueira DR, J&#xfc;ni P, Kirkham JJ, Lasserson T, Li T, McAleenan A, Reeves BC, Shepperd S, Shrier I, Stewart LA, Tilling K, White IR, Whiting PF, Higgins JPT. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898. PMID: 31462531 10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh ML. Interrater reliability: the kappa statistic. Biochem Med. 2012;22:276&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11613/BM.2012.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23092060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ver C. Bayesian random-effects meta-analysis using the Bayesmeta R&#x2009;~&#x2009;package. J Stat Softw. 2020;93(6):1&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v093.i06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Atkinson EJ, Aversa Z, White TA, Heeren AA, Mielke MM, Cummings SR, Pahor M, Leeuwenburgh C, LeBrasseur NK. Biomarkers of cellular senescence predict the onset of mobility disability and are reduced by physical activity in older adults. J Gerontol Biol Sci Med Sci. 2024;79(3):1&#x2013;9. 10.1093/gerona/glad257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glad257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10851672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37948612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseeuw PJ, Croux C. Alternatives to the median absolute deviation. J Am Stat Assoc. 1993;88(424):1273&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01621459.1993.10476408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leys C. Detecting outliers: do not use standard deviation around the mean, use absolute deviation around the median. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2013;49(4):764&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesp.2013.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ver C, Bender R, Dias S, Schmid CH, Schmidli H, Sturtz S, Webe S, Friede T. On weakly informative prior distributions for the heterogeneity parameter in bayesian random-effects meta-analysis. Res Syn Methods. 2021;12:448&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33486828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seide SE, R&#xf6;ver C, Friede T. Likelihood-based random-effects meta-analysis with few studies: empirical and simulation studies. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-018-0618-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6330405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30634920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [updated March 2011]. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlim MT, McGirr A, dos Santos NR, Tremblay S, Martins R. Efficacy of theta burst stimulation (TBS) for major depression: an exploratory meta-analysis of randomized and sham-controlled trials. J Psychiatr Res. 2017;90:102&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2017.02.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallapiran K, Koo S, Kirubakaran R, Hancock K, Review. Effectiveness of mindfulness in improving mental health symptoms of children and adolescents: A meta-analysis. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2015;20:182&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/camh.12113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGirr A, Berlim MT, Bond DJ, Neufeld NH, Chan PY, Yatham LN, Lam RW. A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of adjunctive ketamine in electroconvulsive therapy: efficacy and tolerability. J Psychiatr Res. 2015;62:23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2015.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25684151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos V, Filippou D. Nocturia in CPAP-Treated obstructive sleep apnea patients: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. SN Compr Clin Med. 2020;2:2799&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42399-020-00584-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagiz G, Akaras E, Kubis H-P, Owen JA. The effects of resistance training on architecture and volume of the upper extremity muscles: A systematic review of randomised controlled trials and Meta-Analyses. Appl Sci. 2022;12(3):1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12031593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott M, Plummer M, Roos M. How vague is vague? How informative is informative? Reference analysis for bayesian meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2021;40(20):4505&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.9076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8453582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34041768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai R, Lin L, Boland MR, Chen Y. A robust bayesian Copas selection model for quantifying and correcting publication bias. ArXiv: Methodol. 2020:2005.02930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despeghel M, Reichel T, Zander J, Kr&#xfc;ger K, Weyh C. Effects of a 6-week low-dose combined resistance and endurance training on T cells and systemic inflammation in the elderly. Cells. 2021;10(4):843.10.3390/cells10040843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10040843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand-Moghadam B, Eskandari M, Golestani F, Rezae S, Mahmoudi N, Gaeini AA. The effect of 12-week resistance exercise training on serum levels of cellular aging process parameters in elderly men. Exp Gerontol. 2020;141:111090. 10.1016/j.exger.2020.111090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2020.111090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32919015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Atkinson EJ, Aversa Z, White TA, Heeren AA, Achenbach SJ, Mielke MM, Cummings SR, Pahor M, Leeuwenburgh C, LeBrasseur NK. Associations between biomarkers of cellular senescence and physical function in humans: observations from the lifestyle interventions for elders (LIFE) study. GeroScience. 2022;44(6):2757&#x2013;70. 10.1007/s11357-022-00685-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-022-00685-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9768064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36367600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Hickson LJ, Eirin A, Kirkland JL, Lerman LO. Cellular senescence: the good, the bad, and the unknown. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2022;18(10):611&#x2013;26. 10.1038/s41581-022-00601-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41581-022-00601-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9362342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35922662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St. Sauver JL, Weston SA, Atkinson EJ, McGree ME, Mielke MM, White TA, Heeren AA, Olson JE, Rocca WA, Palmer AK, Cummings SR, Fielding RA, Bielinski SJ, LeBrasseur NK. Biomarkers of cellular senescence and risk of death in humans. Aging Cell. 2023;22:e14006. 10.1111/acel.14006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acel.14006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10726868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37803875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falvino A, Gasperini B, Cariati I, Bonanni R, Chiavoghilefu A, Gasbarra E, Botta A, Tancredi V, Tarantino U. (2024). Cellular senescence: The driving force of musculoskeletal diseases. <i>Biomedicines, 12</i>(9), 1948. 10.3390/biomedicines12091948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11429507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39335461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong GCL, Ng TKS, Lee JL, Lim PY, Chua SKJ, Tan C, Chua M, Tan J, Lee S, Sia A, Ng MKW, Mahendran R, Kua EH, Ho RCM, Larbi A. Horticultural therapy reduces biomarkers of Immunosenescence and inflammaging in community-dwelling older adults: A feasibility pilot randomized controlled trial. Journals Gerontology: Med Sci. 2021;76(2):307&#x2013;17. 10.1093/gerona/glaa271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glaa271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7812436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33070170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>