<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41369578</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Individualized Training Based on Change of Direction Deficit on Speed Performance in Basketball Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>468</StartPage><EndPage>475</EndPage><MedlinePgn>468-475</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005343</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Barrera-Dom&#xed;nguez, FJ, Scott Talpey, Almagro, BJ, and Molina-L&#xf3;pez, J. Effect of individualized training based on change of direction deficit on speed performance in basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 468-475, 2026-Linear and changes of direction (COD) speed are considered key performance determinants in basketball. The aim of this study was to analyze the effect of an individualized COD deficit-based training program on linear speed and COD efficiency, and performance in basketball players. In addition, the differences in linear speed and COD performance between 2 time periods (4 and 8 weeks) with this training were analyzed. Thirty-six male basketball players (age, 21.4 &#xb1; 3.23 years; height, 1.87 &#xb1; 0.07 m; body mass, 83.6 &#xb1; 7.83 kg) were divided into an intervention group (INT, n = 18), who performed an individualized COD deficit-based training, and a control group (CON, n = 18), who underwent a nonindividualized multidirectional repeated sprint training program. Both groups performed the intervention 2 days per week. Baseline, 4-week, and 8-week assessments included 10 meters linear speed and COD (5 + 5 meters at 45&#xb0;, 90&#xb0;, and 180&#xb0; cut) tests. An improvement in multidirectional speed efficiency was observed from 4 weeks in the INT group (effect size [ES] &#x2265; 1.61, p &lt; 0.01), with no change in the CON group. After 8 weeks, significant improvements were observed in the INT players' mean speed performance (mean difference [MD] -0.09, ES = 0.34, p &lt; 0.01), with COD180&#xb0; showing the greatest changes (MD &#x2264; -0.18, ES &#x2265; 0.44, p &lt; 0.01). In conclusion, an individualized COD deficit-based training program improved speed performance after 8 weeks, with changes in multidirectional speed efficiency after first 4 weeks. Given basketball's unpredictable and multidirectional nature, strength and conditioning coaches should seek the optimal trade-off between the linear and multidirectional speed demands on their players.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrera-Dom&#xed;nguez</LastName><ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5387-1788</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Psychology and Sport Sciences, COIDESO, University of Huelva, Huelva, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talpey</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0791-8570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almagro</LastName><ForeName>Bartolom&#xe9; J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0807-5694</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Psychology and Sport Sciences, COIDESO, University of Huelva, Huelva, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molina-L&#xf3;pez</LastName><ForeName>Jorge</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2516-5226</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Psychology and Sport Sciences, COIDESO, University of Huelva, Huelva, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FPU22/01057</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Ciencia, Innovaci&#xf3;n y Universidades</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001490" MajorTopicYN="Y">Basketball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acceleration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deceleration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resisted sprint</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asadi A, Arazi H, Young WB, S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E. The effects of plyometric training on change-of-direction ability: A meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 563&#x2013;573, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Nevill AM. Statistical methods for assessing measurement error (reliability) in variables relevant to sports medicine. Sports Med 26: 217&#x2013;238, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aztarain-Cardiel K, L&#xf3;pez-Laval I, Marco-Contreras LA, et al. Effects of plyometric training direction on physical performance in basketball players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 18: 135&#x2013;141, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baena-Raya A, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Romea E, Soriano-Maldonado A, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez M. Gender-specific association of the sprint mechanical properties with change of direction performance in basketball. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2868&#x2013;2874, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baena-Raya A, Robles-Ruiz J, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez MA. Effects of light versus very heavy resisted sprint training on multidirectional speed in semi-professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 39: e155&#x2013;e161, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera-Dom&#xed;nguez FJ, Almagro BJ, S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E, Molina-L&#xf3;pez J. Effect of individualised strength and plyometric training on the physical performance of basketball players. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 2379&#x2013;2388, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera-Dom&#xed;nguez FJ, Jones PA, Almagro BJ, Molina-L&#xf3;pez J. Determination of change of direction deficit thresholds across a spectrum of angles in basketball players. J Sports Sci 42: 621&#x2013;628, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera-Dom&#xed;nguez FJ, Mart&#xed;nez-Garc&#xed;a D, Jerez-Mayorga D, et al. Vertical versus horizontal training for improving the change of direction speed in adult basketball players: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38: 791&#x2013;803, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgeois F, McGuigan M, Gill N, Gamble G. Physical characteristics and performance in change of direction tasks: A brief review and training considerations. J Aust Strength 25: 104&#x2013;117, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brini S, Boullosa D, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, et al. Impact of combined versus single-mode training programs based on drop jump and specific multidirectional repeated sprint on bio-motor ability adaptations: A parallel study design in professional basketball players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 14: 160, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Carrasco L, et al. Effects of 10-week eccentric overload training on kinetic parameters during change of direction in football players. J Sports Sci 34: 1380&#x2013;1387, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A, Badiella A, Saavedra V, et al. Match activity demands of elite Spanish female basketball players by playing position. Int J Perform Anal Sport 15: 687&#x2013;703, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos'Santos T, Thomas C, Comfort P, Jones PA. The effect of angle and velocity on change of direction biomechanics: An angle-velocity trade-off. Sports Med 48: 2235&#x2013;2253, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos'Santos T, Thomas C, Jones PA. How early should you brake during a 180&#xb0; turn? A kinetic comparison of the antepenultimate, penultimate, and final foot contacts during a 505 change of direction speed test. J Sports Sci 39: 395&#x2013;405, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos'Santos T, Thomas C, McBurnie A, Comfort P, Jones PA. Change of direction speed and technique modification training improves 180&#xb0; turning performance, kinetics, and kinematics. Sports (Basel) 9: 73, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falch HN, Guldteig R&#xe6;derg&#xe5;rd H, van den Tillaar R. Effect of different physical training forms on change of direction ability: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open 5: 53, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods 39: 175&#x2013;191, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas TT, Pereira LA, Alcaraz PE, et al. Influence of strength and power capacity on change of direction speed and deficit in elite team-sport athletes. J Hum Kinet 68: 167&#x2013;176, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas TT, Alcaraz PE, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, et al. Differences in change of direction speed and deficit between male and female national rugby sevens players. J Strength Cond Res 35: 3170&#x2013;3176, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas TT, Pereira LA, Alcaraz PE, et al. Percentage-based change of direction deficit: A new approach to standardize time- and velocity-derived calculations. J Strength Cond Res 36: 3521&#x2013;3526, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a F, V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Castellano J, Casals M, Schelling X. Differences in physical demands between game quarters and playing positions on professional basketball players during official competition. J Sports Sci Med 19: 256&#x2013;263, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalo-Skok O, Bishop C. Change of direction speed and deficit over single and multiple changes of direction: Influence of biological age in youth basketball players. J Sports Sci 41: 1490&#x2013;1497, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handford MJ, Bright TE, Mundy P, et al. The need for eccentric speed: A narrative review of the effects of accelerated eccentric actions during resistance-based training. Sports Med 52: 2061&#x2013;2083, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Samozino P, Morin J-B. Optimized training for jumping performance using the force-velocity imbalance: Individual adaptation kinetics. PLoS One 14(5): e0216681, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller S, Koob A, Corak D, von Sch&#xf6;ning V, Born DP. How to improve change-of-direction speed in junior team sport athletes-horizontal, vertical, maximal, or explosive strength training? J Strength Cond Res 34: 473&#x2013;482, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenhard W, Lenhard A. Computation of effect sizes. Psychometrica, 2016. Available at https://www.psychometrica.de/effect_size.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez D. Flywheel eccentric training: How to effectively generate eccentric overload. Strength Cond J 46: 234&#x2013;250, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBurnie AJ, Dos'Santos T. Multidirectional speed in youth soccer players: Theoretical underpinnings. Strength Cond J 44: 15&#x2013;33, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimphius S, Geib G, Spiteri T, Carlisle D. &#x201c;Change of direction deficit&#x201d; measurement in Division I American football players. J Aust Strength Cond 21: 115&#x2013;117, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimphius S, Callaghan SJ, Spiteri T, Lockie RG. Change of direction deficit: A more isolated measure of change of direction performance than total 505 time. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3024&#x2013;3032, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimphius S, Callaghan SJ, Bezodis NE, Lockie RG. Change of direction and agility tests: Challenging our current measures of performance. Strength Cond J 40: 26&#x2013;38, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxendine JB. Generality and specificity in the learning of fine and gross motor skills. Res Quarterly 38: 86&#x2013;94, 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ple&#x161;a J, Ujakovi&#x107; F, Ribi&#x10d; A, et al. Effectiveness of an individualized training based on dynamic strength index on sprinting, jumping and change of direction performance in basketball players: A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci Med 23: 504&#x2013;514, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power CJ, Fox JL, Dalbo VJ, Scanlan AT. External and internal load variables encountered during training and games in female basketball players according to playing level and playing position: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 8(1): 107, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Sabat&#xe9; J, Guti&#xe9;rrez H, Marco-Contreras LA, et al. Influence of vertical-oriented vs. horizontal-oriented combined strength training in young basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1280&#x2013;1287, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solleiro-Duran D, Cidre-Fuentes P, Rey E, et al. Effects of linear versus curvilinear sprint training on multidirectional speed in young soccer players: A randomized parallel-group trial. Biol Sport 42: 89&#x2013;97, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama T, Maeo S, Kurihara T, Kanehisa H, Isaka T. Change of direction speed tests in basketball players: A brief review of test varieties and recent trends. Front Sports Active Living 3: 645350, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaloy S, Freitas TT, Pareja-Blanco F, Alcaraz PE, Loturco I. Narrative review on the use of sled training to improve sprint performance in team sport athletes. Strength Cond J 45: 13&#x2013;28, 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>