<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41495932</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is There a Correlation Between Knee Extension Peak Torque Quadriceps Maximal Force and Biomechanical Determinants in Hop Tests of the MERItest, 6 months After ACL Reconstruction?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>133</StartPage><EndPage>138</EndPage><MedlinePgn>133-138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001413</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the relationship between isokinetic knee extension peak torque and specific biomechanical variables during hop tests in patients 6 months postanterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Prospective, cross-sectional study analyzing the correlations between isokinetic knee extension torque and biomechanical outcomes across various functional tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sports clinic with a specialized biomechanics laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sixty-one patients (47 males, 14 females), aged 16 to 55 years, who had undergone ACLR, participated. All met the inclusion criteria and completed the follow-up testing at 6 months postsurgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ASSESSMENT OF RISK FACTORS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Key independent variables included isokinetic knee extension peak torque. Participants completed standardized functional tests: single-leg and double-leg drop jumps, single-leg hop tests, and double-leg countermovement jumps.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Outcome measures included biomechanical parameters related to dynamic knee stability, including peak knee extensor moments, knee joint power during push-off, peak knee flexion and valgus, and vertical ground reaction force and braking forces.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Moderate correlations were observed between knee extension peak torque and select biomechanical variables, including peak knee extensor moments during single-leg drop jumps, knee joint power during push-off phases in both single and double-leg drop jumps, and peak braking forces in single-leg hop tests. However, these relationships suggest that additional factors play essential roles in dynamic stability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although quadriceps strength is moderately linked to key biomechanical markers, our findings indicate that a more comprehensive assessment, integrating both strength and biomechanical evaluation, could enhance ACLR rehabilitation strategies. This combined approach may better support recovery and minimize reinjury risk.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dodelin</LastName><ForeName>Damien</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0668-5616</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomechanical Laboratory of Medical Stadium, M&#xe9;rignac, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laurent</LastName><ForeName>Xavier</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Restart, Medical Stadium, M&#xe9;rignac, France; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graveleau</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique du Sport, M&#xe9;rignac, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogas-Droy</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;loise</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique du Sport, M&#xe9;rignac, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouguennec</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique du Sport, M&#xe9;rignac, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059549" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007719" MajorTopicYN="Y">Knee Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070598" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hop tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>King E, Richter C, Daniels KAJ, et al. Biomechanical but not strength or performance measures differentiate Male athletes who experience ACL reinjury on return to level 1 sports. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:918&#x2013;927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber-Westin S, Noyes FR. One in 5 athletes sustain reinjury upon return to high-risk sports after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review in 1239 athletes younger than 20 years. Sports Health. 2020;12:587&#x2013;597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, et al. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:1861&#x2013;1876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgi CR, Peters S, Ardern CL, et al. Which criteria are used to clear patients to return to sport after primary ACL reconstruction? A scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1154&#x2013;1161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marigi EM, Hale RF, Bernard CD, et al. Are 6-Month functional and isokinetic testing measures risk factors for second anterior cruciate ligament injuries at Long-T follow-up?. J knee Surg. 2023;36:1060&#x2013;1068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crotty NMN, Daniels KAJ, McFadden C, et al. Relationship between isokinetic knee strength and single-leg drop jump performance 9 months after ACL reconstruction. Orthopaedic J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671211063800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutsiadis A, Brossard P, Panisset JC, et al. Minimally invasive combined anterior and anterolateral stabilization of the knee using hamstring tendons and adjustable-loop suspensory fixation device: surgical technique. Arthrosc Tech. 2017;6:e419&#x2013;e425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Korakakis V, Graham-Smith P, et al. Vertical and horizontal hop performance: contributions of the hip, knee, and ankle. Sports health. 2021;13:128&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA, Lambros C. Development and preliminary validation of a scale to measure the psychological impact of returning to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Phys Ther Sport. 2008;9:9&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobian DG, Knurr KA, Joachim MR, et al. Does it matter? Isometric or isokinetic assessment of quadriceps strength symmetry 9 months after ACLR in collegiate athletes. Sports Health. 2024;14:19417381241247819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan KD, Donnelly CJ, Reinbolt JA. Empirical based modeling for the assessment of dynamic knee stability: implications for anterior cruciate ligament injury risk. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc Annu Int Conf. 2018;2018:1676&#x2013;1679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper DJ, McBurnie AJ, Santos TD, et al. Biomechanical and neuromuscular performance requirements of horizontal deceleration: a review with implications for random intermittent multi-directional sports. Sports Med (Auckland, N.Z.). 2022;52:2321&#x2013;2354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Villa F, Buckthorpe M, Grassi A, et al. Systematic video analysis of ACL injuries in professional male football (soccer): injury mechanisms, situational patterns and biomechanics study on 134 consecutive cases. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:1423&#x2013;1432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Sideris V, King E, et al. Performance and symmetry measures during vertical jump testing at return to sport after ACL reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:1304&#x2013;1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Recommendations for movement Re-training after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med (Auckland, N.Z.). 2021;51:1601&#x2013;1618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilanthananond M, Tharawadeepimuk K, Saengsirisuwan V, et al. Muscle activation and ground reaction force between single-leg drop landing and jump landing among young females during weight-acceptance phase. Sports (Basel, Switzerland). 2023;11:185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang YL, Mulligan CMS, Johnson ST, et al. Explosive quadriceps strength symmetry and landing mechanics limb symmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in females. J athletic Train. 2021;56:912&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wade L, Lichtwark GA, Farris DJ. Joint and muscle-tendon coordination strategies during submaximal jumping. J Appl Physiol. 2020;128:596&#x2013;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandiyeh P, Parola LR, Costa MQ, et al. Long-term bilateral neuromuscular function and knee osteoarthritis after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Bioengineering. 2023;10:812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham MC, Reeves KA, Johnson DL, et al. Relationship between quadriceps strength and knee joint power during jumping after ACLR. Orthopaedic J Sports Med. 2023;11:23259671231150938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones HSR, Moore IS, King E, et al. Movement strategy correspondence across jumping and cutting tasks after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32:612&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>