<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41231399</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7339</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Supportive care in cancer : official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Support Care Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers and facilitators to implementing pelvic floor muscle training after radical prostatectomy in China: a qualitative study using the consolidated framework for implementation research.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1058</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1058</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00520-025-10161-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Urinary incontinence is the most common adverse outcome following radical prostatectomy (RP) for prostate cancer, and pelvic floor muscle training (PFMT) is among the most effective interventions. However, implementation of PFMT after RP in China remains limited. This study aimed to explore the barriers and facilitators influencing the implementation of evidence-based PFMT in this context.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative study recruited 35 stakeholders comprising physical therapists, medical staff, and post-prostatectomy patients from a tertiary hospital in China during the period from December 2022 to March 2023. Participants were selected through purposive and convenience sampling. Semi-structured interviews were conducted using a guide based on the Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR), refined through expert consultation and pre-interviews. Data were collected through audio-recorded, in-person interviews and analyzed using directed content analysis. NVivo software facilitated coding, and COREQ guidelines were followed. Triangulation and independent double coding ensured rigor and reliability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Barriers in the innovation domain included evidence skepticism, implementation challenges, lack of standardization, and resource constraints; facilitators included strong support for PFMT and ease of implementation. In the outer setting, barriers included attitudinal resistance, resource inadequacy, coordination gaps, and financial constraints, while patient engagement served as a facilitator. Inner setting barriers included post-discharge support gaps, equipment limitations, and knowledge gaps; reform motivation was a facilitator. At the individual level, awareness gaps were a key barrier, while expert facilitation was beneficial. In the implementation process domain, follow-up challenges were noted, alongside adaptive implementation and data-informed decision-making as facilitators.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Targeted strategies and improved resource allocation are needed to support PFMT implementation and enhance recovery and quality of life in Chinese prostate cancer patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shandong Second Medical University, Weifang, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Weifang People's Hospital, Shandong Second Medical University, Weifang, Shandong Province, China. xiaotaogeng@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Support Care Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9302957</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0941-4355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011468" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prostatectomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017773" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pelvic Floor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prostatic Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014549" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Incontinence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive implementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostate cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radical prostatectomy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: The ethics of this study are in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and were approved by the Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine (Approval No. IIT20220264B-R1). Consent to participate: Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Consent for publication: Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41231399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-025-10161-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00520-025-10161-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Mottet N, van den Bergh RCN, Briers E, Van den Broeck T, Cumberbatch MG, De Santis M, Fanti S, Fossati N, Gandaglia G, Gillessen S, Grivas N, Grummet J, Henry AM, van der Kwast TH, Lam TB, Lardas M, Liew M, Mason MD, Moris L, Oprea-Lager DE, van der Poel HG, Rouvi&#xe8;re O, Schoots IG, Tilki D, Wiegel T, Willemse PM, Cornford P (2021) EAU-EANM-ESTRO-ESUR-SIOG guidelines on prostate cancer-2020 update. Part 1: Screening, diagnosis, and local treatment with curative intent Eur Urol 79: 243&#x2013;262. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2020.09.042 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Jiang X, Shi Y, Lv Z (2024) A review of enhanced recovery after surgery concept in perioperative radical prostatectomy for prostate cancer J Robot Surg 19: 9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11701-024-02170-8 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskin A, Cowan JE, Braun A, Lonergan PE, Mohamad O, Washington SL, 3rd, Zhao S, Broering JM, Cooperberg MR, Breyer BN, Carroll PR (2023) Long-term complications and health-related quality of life outcomes after radical prostatectomy with or without subsequent radiation treatment for prostate cancer Urol Oncol 41: 429.e429&#x2013;429.e414. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.urolonc.2023.06.003 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungovan SF, Carlsson SV, Gass GC, Graham PL, Sandhu JS, Akin O, Scardino PT, Eastham JA, Patel MI (2021) Preoperative exercise interventions to optimize continence outcomes following radical prostatectomy Nat Rev Urol 18: 259&#x2013;281. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41585-021-00445-5 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman DK, Guzzo T, Lee D, Jayadevappa R (2014) An evidence-based strategy for the conservative management of the male patient with incontinence Curr Opin Urol 24: 553&#x2013;559. https://doi.org/10.1097/mou.0000000000000115 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandhu JS, Breyer B, Comiter C, Eastham JA, Gomez C, Kirages DJ, Kittle C, Lucioni A, Nitti VW, Stoffel JT, Westney OL, Murad MH, McCammon K (2019) Incontinence after prostate treatment: AUA/SUFU guideline J Urol 202: 369&#x2013;378. https://doi.org/10.1097/ju.0000000000000314 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos J, Brasil VV, Azevedo C, Izidoro LCR, Batista AJG, Ferreira ACS, Mata L (2024) Pelvic floor muscle training in men with post-prostatectomy urinary incontinence: a scoping review Rev Lat Am Enfermagem 32: e4386. https://doi.org/10.1590/1518-8345.7335.4386 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Li Y, Qi Z, Wang W (2023) Barriers and facilitators of the implementation of the application of pelvic floor muscle training in patients with prostate cancer: a scoping review Front Public Health 11: 1191508. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2023.1191508 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges PW, Stafford RE, Hall L, Neumann P, Morrison S, Frawley H, Doorbar-Baptist S, Nahon I, Crow J, Thompson J, Cameron AP (2020) Reconsideration of pelvic floor muscle training to prevent and treat incontinence after radical prostatectomy Urol Oncol 38: 354&#x2013;371. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.urolonc.2019.12.007 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Reardon CM, Widerquist MAO, Lowery J (2022) The updated consolidated framework for implementation research based on user feedback. Implement Sci 17:75. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012-022-01245-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-022-01245-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36309746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9617234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennink MM, Kaiser BN, Marconi VC (2017) Code saturation versus meaning saturation: how many interviews are enough? Qual Health Res 27: 591&#x2013;608. https://doi.org/10.1177/1049732316665344 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallio H, Pietil&#xe4; AM, Johnson M, Kangasniemi M (2016) Systematic methodological review: developing a framework for a qualitative semi-structured interview guide J Adv Nurs 72: 2954&#x2013;2965. https://doi.org/10.1111/jan.13031 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengtsson M (2016) How to plan and perform a qualitative study using content analysis NursingPlus Open 2: 8&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.npls.2016.01.001 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J (2007) Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups Int J Qual Health Care 19: 349&#x2013;357. https://doi.org/10.1093/intqhc/mzm042 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parekh AR, Feng MI, Kirages D, Bremner H, Kaswick J, Aboseif S (2003) The role of pelvic floor exercises on post-prostatectomy incontinence J Urol 170: 130&#x2013;133. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.ju.0000072900.82131.6f .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Str&#x105;czy&#x144;ska A, Weber-Rajek M, Strojek K, Piekorz Z, Styczy&#x144;ska H, Goch A, Radzimi&#x144;ska A (2019) The impact of pelvic floor muscle training on urinary incontinence in men after radical prostatectomy (RP) - a systematic review Clin Interv Aging 14: 1997&#x2013;2005. https://doi.org/10.2147/cia.S228222 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson CA, Omar MI, Campbell SE, Hunter KF, Cody JD, Glazener CM (2015) Conservative management for postprostatectomy urinary incontinence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001843.pub5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001843.pub5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26597166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8612699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gacci M, Sakalis VI, Karavitakis M, Cornu JN, Gratzke C, Herrmann TRW, Kyriazis I, Malde S, Mamoulakis C, Rieken M, Schouten N, Smith EJ, Speakman MJ, Tikkinen KAO, Gravas S (2022) European Association of Urology guidelines on male urinary incontinence Eur Urol 82: 387&#x2013;398. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2022.05.012 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gifford W, Zhang Q, Chen S, Davies B, Xie R, Wen SW, Harvey G (2018) When east meets west: a qualitative study of barriers and facilitators to evidence-based practice in Hunan China BMC Nurs 17: 26. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12912-018-0295-x .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa VC, Lugo-Agudelo LH, Aguirre-Acevedo DC, Contreras JAP, Borrero AMP, Pati&#xf1;o-Lugo DF, Valencia DAC (2020) Individual, health system, and contextual barriers and facilitators for the implementation of clinical practice guidelines: a systematic metareview. Health Res Policy Syst 18:74. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12961-020-00588-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12961-020-00588-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7322919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore KN, Griffiths D, Hughton A (1999) Urinary incontinence after radical prostatectomy: a randomized controlled trial comparing pelvic muscle exercises with or without electrical stimulation BJU Int 83: 57&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1464-410x.1999.00894.x .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soundararajan K, Dilruksha Chandrasiri M, Balchandra P (2022) Staff awareness of pelvic floor muscle training (PFMT) in tertiary care - a qualitative cross-sectional study J Obstet Gynaecol 42: 2282&#x2013;2286. https://doi.org/10.1080/01443615.2022.2040966 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschhorn AD, Kolt GS, Brooks AJ (2014) A multicomponent theory-based intervention improves uptake of pelvic floor muscle training before radical prostatectomy: a &#x2018;before and after&#x2019; cohort study BJU Int 113: 383&#x2013;392. https://doi.org/10.1111/bju.12385 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed P, Osborne LA, Whittall CM, Emery S (2021) Impact of patient motivation on compliance and outcomes for incontinence Physiotherapy 113: 100&#x2013;106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physio.2020.10.003 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Da Cu&#xf1;a Carrera I, Guti&#xe9;rrez Nieto M, L&#xf3;pez Garc&#xed;a S, Ojea Calvo A, Lantar&#xf3;n Caeiro EM (2020) Early 3-month treatment with comprehensive physical therapy program restores continence in urinary incontinence patients after radical prostatectomy: a&#xa0;randomized controlled trial Neurourol Urodyn 39: 1529&#x2013;1537. https://doi.org/10.1002/nau.24389 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalalinia SF, Raei M, Naseri-Salahshour V, Varaei S (2020) The effect of pelvic floor muscle strengthening exercise on urinary incontinence and quality of life in patients after prostatectomy: a randomized clinical trial. J Caring Sci 9:33&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.34172/jcs.2020.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/jcs.2020.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32296657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7146723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suso-Mart&#xed; L, La Touche R, Herranz-G&#xf3;mez A, Angulo-D&#xed;az-Parre&#xf1;o S, Paris-Alemany A, Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez F (2021) Effectiveness of telerehabilitation in physical therapist practice: an umbrella and mapping review with meta-meta-analysis. Phys Ther. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzab075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzab075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33611598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao J, Yao Z, Remis A, Huang B, Li Y, Yu X (2024) Pelvic floor muscle training in telerehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis Arch Gynecol Obstet 309: 1753&#x2013;1764. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00404-024-07380-x .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson C, Roberts C, Toohey K, McKie A (2020) Prostate cancer prehabilitation and the importance of multimodal interventions for person-centred care and recovery Semin Oncol Nurs 36: 151048. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soncn.2020.151048 .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>