<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41701315</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A 12-Week Strength and Conditioning Intervention: An Individualized Case Series Approach for 3 Amateur and 3 Professional Female Golfers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e373</StartPage><EndPage>e384</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e373-e384</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005342</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Robinson, L, Murray, A, Coughlan, D, Ehlert, A, Heeney, C, Turner, A, and Bishop, C. A 12-week strength and conditioning intervention: An individualized case series approach for 3 amateur and 3 professional female golfers. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): e373-e384, 2026-This study used an individualized, case series approach to 12 weeks of strength and conditioning (S&amp;C) training, for 3 high-level amateur and 3 professional female golfers. Each player took part in a 90-minute testing session both pre- and postintervention, and 2 structured S&amp;C sessions per week for 12 weeks. Movement competency assessments were used to help guide exercise selection in each intervention and test measures included golf shot data, the isometric mid-thigh pull, isometric bench press, and countermovement jump, with a total of 12 metrics across the 4 assessment protocols. Analyses of individual performance changes were done by using the SD for each test metric, relative to preintervention scores. Collectively, for the 3 amateur players, 32 out of a possible 36 metrics showed changes &gt; the baseline SD , while for the 3 professional players, 23 metrics elicited changes &gt; the baseline SD . Of note, this collective difference was largely attributable to professional 1, who showed only 4 "true" improvements in test scores, out of a possible 12. This study has shown that taking an individualized approach to S&amp;C training predominantly elicits meaningful changes in both golf shot data and physical performance-a concept that is essential to understand for an individual sport, such as golf.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Faculty of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professional Golfers' Association, The Belfry, Sutton Coldfield, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>England Golf, The National Golf Centre, Woodhall Spa, Lincolnshire, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Group, Virginia Water, Surrey, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coughlan</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>England Golf, The National Golf Centre, Woodhall Spa, Lincolnshire, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Group, Virginia Water, Surrey, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehlert</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, NC; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heeney</LastName><ForeName>Conor</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance Sport, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Faculty of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Faculty of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The R&amp;A, St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Group, Virginia Water, Surrey, England.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Golf</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">golf</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance science</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41701315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beckham G, Lamont H, Sato K, Ramsey M, Stone M. Isometric strength of powerlifters in key positions of the conventional deadlift. J Trainology 1: 32&#x2013;35, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckham G, Sato K, Santana P, Mizuguchi S, Haff GG, Stone H. Effect of body position on force production during the isometric midthigh pull. J Strength Cond Res 32: 48&#x2013;56, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Ehlert A, Wells J, Brearley S, Brennan A, Coughlan D. Strength and conditioning for golf athletes: Biomechanics, injury risk, physical requirements, and recommendations for testing and training. Prof Strength Cond J 64: 7&#x2013;18, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Wells J, Ehlert A, et al. Trackman 4: Within and between-session reliability and inter-relationships of launch monitor metrics during indoor testing in high-level golfers. J Sports Sci 41: 2138&#x2013;2143, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliss A, Langdown B. Integrating strength and conditioning training and golf practice during the golf season: Approaches and perceptions of highly skilled golfers. Int J Sports Sci Coach 18: 1605&#x2013;1614, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brearley S, Coughlan D, Wells J. Strength and conditioning in golf: Probability of performance impact. Sport Perform Scientific Rep 1: 1&#x2013;3, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brearley S, Buckthorpe M, Xu J, Bishop C. The dynamic strength index: Is it a useful tool to guide programming decisions? Prof Strength Cond J 71: 13&#x2013;22, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Validity and reliability of the FlightScope mevo+ launch monitor for assessing golf performance. J Strength Cond Res 38: e174&#x2013;e181, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Associations and within-group differences in physical characteristics and golf performance data in high-level amateur players. Appl Sci 14: 1854&#x2013;1859, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Mountjoy M, et al. Associations between physical characteristics and golf clubhead speed: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 54: 1553&#x2013;1577, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Dos'Santos T, Beckham G, Stone M, Guppy S, Haff GG. Standardization and methodological considerations for the isometric midthigh pull. Strength Cond J 41: 57&#x2013;79, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormack S, Newton R, McGuigan M, Doyle T. Reliability of measures obtained during single and repeated countermovement jumps. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 3: 131&#x2013;144, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan D, Taylor M, Jackson J, Ward N, Beardsley C. Physical characteristics of youth elite golfers and their relationship with driver clubhead speed. J Strength Cond Res 34: 212&#x2013;217, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlert A. The correlations between physical attributes and golf clubhead speed: A systematic review with quantitative analyses. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1351&#x2013;1363, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlert A. The effects of strength and conditioning interventions on golf performance: A systematic review. J Sports Sci 38: 2720&#x2013;2731, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlert A, Wilson P. A systematic review of golf warm-ups: Behaviors, injury, and performance. J Strength Cond Res 33: 3444&#x2013;3462, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furness J, Schram B, Cox A, Anderson S, Keogh J. Reliability and concurrent validity of the iPhone&#xae; compass application to measure thoracic rotation range of motion (ROM) in healthy participants. PeerJ 6: e4431, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Ruben R, Lider J, Twine C, Cormie P. A comparison of methods for determining the rate of force development during isometric midthigh clean pulls. J Strength Cond Res 29: 386&#x2013;395, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harry J, Hurwitz J, Agnew C, Bishop C. Statistical tests for sports science practitioners: Identifying performance gains in individual athletes. J Strength Cond Res 38: e264&#x2013;e272, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus E, Hardesty K, Sunderland K, Hegedus R, Smoliga J. A randomized trial of traditional and golf-specific resistance training in amateur female golfers: Benefits beyond golf performance. Phys Ther Sport 22: 41&#x2013;53, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K. Effects of core muscle strengthening training on flexibility, muscular strength and driver shot performance in female professional golfers. Int J Appl Sports Sci 22: 111&#x2013;127, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk D, Mannerberg J, Robinson T, Nelson M. Eight weeks of strength and power training improves club head speed in collegiate golfers. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2205&#x2013;2213, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen N, Watkins J, Kilduff L, Bevan H, Bennett M. Development of a criterion method to determine peak mechanical power output in a countermovement jump. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1552&#x2013;1558, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson L, Murray A, Coughlan D, et al. Relationships and within-group differences in physical attributes and golf performance in elite amateur female players. Life 14: 674&#x2013;679, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson L, Murray A, Ehlert A, et al. Effects of physical training and associations between physical performance characteristics and golf performance in female players: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38: 374&#x2013;383, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson L, Murray A, Glover D, et al. Associations between physical performance and golf shot data: A pilot study of touring professional female players. J Strength Cond Res 39: 687&#x2013;694, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Delextrat A, Gonzalez-Badillo J. The relationship between golf performance, anthropometrics, muscular strength and power characteristics in young elite players. Int J Sports Med 15: 156&#x2013;164, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner A. But did my athlete improve? Assessing performance changes when N = 1. Prof Strength Cond J 63: 27&#x2013;31, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells J, Mitchell A, Charalambous L, Fletcher I. Relationships between highly skilled golfers' clubhead velocity and kinetic variables during a countermovement jump. Sports Biomech 23: 2598&#x2013;2610, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells J, Mitchell A, Charalambous L, Fletcher I. Relationships between highly skilled golfers' clubhead velocity and force producing capabilities during vertical jumps and an isometric mid-thigh pull. J Sports Sci 36: 1847&#x2013;1851, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>