<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41880198</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1827-1928</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of sports medicine and physical fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychological resistance of athletes: focus on moral standards, sports values and prosocial behavior.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.23736/S0022-4707.26.17756-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Currently, the issue of an athlete psychological resistance, the focus on moral standards (such as justice, loyalty, respect, honesty) and prosocial sport behavior is becoming increasingly important. However, empirical research is lacking to analyze the characteristics of prosocial sport behavior among Russian athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="THE AIM OF THE STUDY" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">to identify relation between athletes' focus on moral standards, social values of sport and prosocial behavior and their psychological resistance and psychological well-being.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The research studied 174 athletes, including team (game-based) sports (volleyball, basketball, football: 53.5%), and individual (cyclic) sports (track-and-field athletics, skiing, swimming: 46.5%); age from 17 to 28 years (mean: 20); 42% are men, 58% are women; sports experience from 1 to 19 years (mean: 8.5); 18% are Masters of Sports and Candidates Master of Sports, 16% have athletic titles, 66% do not have athletic titles. The following methods were used to conduct the study: Psychological Competence of Athletes, Subjective Well-Being Scale (Russian-language version by M.V. Sokolova), Moral Foundations Questionnaire (MFQ-32), Spirit of Sport (SOS) (Russian-language version by K.A. Bochaver), Prosocial and Antisocial Behavior in Sports Scale (PABSS - Prosocial and Antisocial Behavior in Sports Scale; Russian-language version by P.A. Kislyakov et al.).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In general, all sports values at an above-average level are important to the test-takers, however, the values of teamwork and solidarity are less in demand. Athletes are more likely to point to the examples of how they demonstrate help and support to others during competitive activities and workout training than examples of unsportsmanlike and aggressive behavior. At the same time, prosocial sports behavior is more often observed with respect to the teammates or the national team. The study results made it possible to establish correlations between the prosociality of athletes, the importance of moral standards, social sport values (respect for sports ethics, adherence to rules, teamwork, respect for oneself and for other participants of competitions, good manners and education, a sense of community and solidarity, health), psychological sport resistance and subjective well-being. At the same time, prosociality in sports is a predictor of psychological resistance and subjective well-being. Cluster analysis made it possible to identify four types of athletes according to the severity of the studied characteristics: "Athlete-Aggressor," "Athlete-Individualist," "Athlete-idealist," "Athlete-Moralist."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Such criteria of the development of an athlete's personality as moral standards, social values, and prosocial sports behavior can be considered as a kind of internal resource that helps an athlete to gain sports identity and referent significance, to maintain psychological resistance during the competitive activities and workout training, and to ensure psychological well-being. The study contributes to a better understanding of the moral and psychological development of athletes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kislyakov</LastName><ForeName>Pavel A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Russian State Social University, Moscow, Russia - kisliakovpav@yandex.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krasnova</LastName><ForeName>Ekaterina A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Russian State Social University, Moscow, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belov</LastName><ForeName>Michael S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Department of Physical Culture and Sports, Ivanovo State Power Engineering University, Ivanovo, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tyurina</LastName><ForeName>Svetlana Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Department of Physical Culture and Sports, Ivanovo State Power Engineering University, Ivanovo, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376337</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-4707</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41880198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.26.17756-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0022-4707.26.17756-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>