<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41807491</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preparation of motion sensor using AgNWs material and performance analysis in sports activities.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42806-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High-performance motion sensors are crucial for scientific training and health management. However, existing flexible strain sensors often face limitations in signal stability, response speed, and signal-to-noise ratio during dynamic monitoring, which hinders reliable high-precision data acquisition. To address these challenges, this study aimed to develop a novel strain sensor by focusing on optimizing the composite process of conductive materials and flexible substrates, thereby enhancing performance for practical human motion monitoring applications. This study fabricated a resistive flexible strain sensor using Silver Nanowires (AgNWs) as the conductive material and Polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) as the flexible substrate. The sensor operates on the principle that strain induces changes in the conductive network's connectivity. A key innovation in fabrication lies in using dimethyl silicone oil as a pre-dispersion medium, combined with an ultrasonic-assisted process to construct a uniform and robust three-dimensional AgNWs network within the PDMS matrix, ensuring strong interfacial adhesion and structural integrity. The experimental results demonstrated superior performance of the PDMS-based sensor. Compared to sensors based on Cellulose Nanofiber (CNF) and Polyethylene Terephthalate (PET) substrates, it exhibited a resistance fluctuation of less than 5% over 3,000 tensile cycles. At 60% strain, its response time was only 5,000 ms, approximately 50% faster than that of the CNF-based sensor. Furthermore, in the 0.5-1.5&#xa0;Hz frequency range typical of human motion, the sensor achieved an excellent average signal-to-noise ratio of up to 26.27 dB. This research successfully developed an AgNWs/PDMS flexible strain sensor with outstanding dynamic stability, fast response, and high signal quality, providing a reliable sensing solution for high-precision data collection in sports training and health monitoring. The main innovation points include: (1) Adopting the interface engineering strategy of dimethyl silicone oil pre dispersion to construct a uniform and stable 3D AgNWs network; (2) Integrating spin coating and screen printing to achieve integrated manufacturing of sensors; (3) Achieving breakthroughs in comprehensive performance by linking sensor design and performance, and integrating signal processing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Huayi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animation and Esports, Shanghai Publishing and Printing College, Shanghai, 200093, China. wanghuayi2022@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AgNWs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle electrical signal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PDMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sensors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41807491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42806-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42806-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. Preparation of silver nanoparticles modified SnO2 humidity sensor for tobacco storage environment detection. Sens. Actuators B Chem. 409, 135612&#x2013;135612. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.135612 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, Q. et al. Preparation and properties of polyvinyl alcohol/chitosan-based hydrogel with dual pH/NH3 sensor for naked-eye monitoring of seafood freshness. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 263, 130440&#x2013;130441. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.130440 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed Ameen, S. S. &amp; Omer, K. M. Recent advances of bimetallic-metal organic frameworks: Preparation, properties, and fluorescence-based biochemical sensing applications. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 16(25), 31895&#x2013;31921. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06931 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayankojo, A. G., Reut, J. &amp; Syritski, V. Electrochemically synthesized MIP sensors: Applications in healthcare diagnostics. Biosens. Bioelectron. 14(2), 71&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.3390/bios14020071 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. et al. Flexible strain sensor based on AgNWs/MXene/SEBS with high sensitivity and wide strain range. Electron. Mater. Lett. 20(6), 684&#x2013;693. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13391-024-00514-y (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R., Li, X. &amp; Chen, T. Resistive flexible strain sensor based on AgNWs&#x2013;Gr&#x2013;PDMS for wearable electronics. AIP Adv. 14(5), 5&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211831 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo-L&#xf3;pez, D. N. et al. Flexible force sensor based on a PVA/AgNWs nanocomposite and cellulose acetate. Sensors 24(9), 2819. https://doi.org/10.3390/s24092819 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D., Lu, W. &amp; Qu, J. Rapid preparation of high strength, high stretchability, transparent, self-healing conductive elastomers for strain sensors by photo-initiated copolymerization of two novel polymerizable deep eutectic solvents. Eur. Polym. J. 210, 112999&#x2013;113000. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eurpolymj.2024.112999 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, K. et al. Temperature-and pressure-sensitive ionic conductive elastomer for respiratory monitoring and human motion sensing. J. Mater. Chem. C 12(8), 2824&#x2013;2835. https://doi.org/10.1039/D3TC04143C (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustosa, G. M. M. M. et al. Nanoengineered PDMS/Pd/ZnO-based sensor to improve detection of H<sub>2</sub> dissolved gas in oil at room temperature. ACS Sens. 10(4), 2554&#x2013;2568. https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.4c02896 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Z. et al. Research progress of flexible pressure sensor based on MXene materials. RSC Adv. 14(14), 9547&#x2013;9558. https://doi.org/10.1039/D3RA07772A (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H. et al. Design, preparation, and application of molecularly imprinted nanomaterials for food safety analysis with electrochemistry. Coord. Chem. Rev. 500, 215523&#x2013;215524. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2023.215523 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. &amp; Yuan, T. Remarks of optical fibers and devices for microfluidic sensing: Preparation and processing. Photonic Sens. 15(2), 250208&#x2013;250209. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13320-025-0722-z (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, R. et al. Recent advances in flexible pressure sensors based on MXene materials. Adv. Mater. 36(24), 2312761&#x2013;2312762. https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202312761 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. et al. Skin preparation-free, stretchable microneedle adhesive patches for reliable electrophysiological sensing and exoskeleton robot control. Sci. Adv. 10(3), 5260&#x2013;5261. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adi5260 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, X. et al. Amorphous carbon derived from daily carbon ink for wide detection range, low-cost, eco-friendly and flexible pressure sensor. Mater. Chem. Phys. 321, 129489&#x2013;129490. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129489 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, A. et al. Dynamic simulation and experimental studies of molecularly imprinted label-free sensor for determination of milk quality marker. Food Chem. 449, 139238&#x2013;139239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.139238 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao, Y. et al. Facile and fast preparation of stretchable, self-adhesive, moisturizing, antifreezing and conductive tough hydrogel for wearable strain sensors. J. Mater. Chem. C 12(12), 4406&#x2013;4416. https://doi.org/10.1039/D3TC04113A (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, J. et al. Sandpaper-assisted preparation of microstructured multifunctional PANI/PVA composite hydrogel film for high-sensitivity pressure sensors with accurate pressure identification and motion monitoring. Mater. Today Commun. 38, 107783&#x2013;107784. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.107783 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, J. et al. Preparation of ultralong AgNWs/PU composite foam for outstanding electromagnetic interference shielding, joule heating, and human motion detection. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 7(9), 10312&#x2013;10324. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00800 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghannam, F. et al. Recent progress in PDMS-based microfluidics toward integrated organ-on-a-chip biosensors and personalized medicine. Biosens. Bioelectron. 15(2), 76&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.3390/bios15020076 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. Z. et al. Jan., MXene hybridized polymer with enhanced electromagnetic energy harvest for sensitized microwave actuation and self-powered motion sensing,Nano-Micro Lett., 17, 1, pp. 65&#x2013;67, (2025). https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01578-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellendorf, A., Tichelmann, P. &amp; Uhl, J. Performance analysis of a dynamic test bench based on a linear direct drive,Arch. Adv. Eng. Sci. 1 (1), 55&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.47852/bonviewAAES3202902 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C. et al. A cross-scale honeycomb architecture-based flexible piezoresistive sensor for multiscale pressure perception and fine-grained identification. Mater. Horiz. 11(2), 510&#x2013;518. https://doi.org/10.1039/D3MH01387A (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Q., Liu, Z., Xu, Z., Li, B. &amp; Yang, S. rGO/In<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> heterostructures based gas sensor for efficient ppb-level n-butanol detection. J. Alloys Compd. 986, 174154&#x2013;174156. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174154 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, M. L. et al. Non-contact humidity monitoring: Boosting the performance of all-printed humidity sensor using PDDA-modified Ti3C2Tx nanoribbons. Chem. Eng. J. 485, 149633&#x2013;149634. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149633 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, W. et al. Dual bionic-inspired stretchable strain sensor based on graphene/multi-walled carbon nanotubes/polymer composites for electronic skin. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 179, 108043&#x2013;108044. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108043 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, S. et al. CuO/TiO2/MXene-based sensor and SMS-TENG array integrated inspection robots for self-powered ethanol detection and alarm at room temperature,ACS Sens., 9, 3, pp. 1188&#x2013;1198, (2024). https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.3c01963</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. A high-sensitive rubber-based sensor with integrated strain and humidity responses enabled by bionic gradient structure. Adv. Funct. Mater. 34(34), 2400789&#x2013;2400790. https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400789 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z. et al. Electrospun thermoplastic polyurethane membrane decorated with carbon nanotubes: a platform of flexible strain sensors for human motion monitoring,Polymer, 303, pp. 127120&#x2013;127121, (2024). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polymer.2024.127120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y., Li, Z., Wang, J. &amp; Zhang, K. Highly conductive and stretchable strain sensors based on silver nanowire-silicone modified polyurethane composites. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 16 (15), 19234&#x2013;19245. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00896 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M., Wang, S., Zhao, G., Liu, C. &amp; Zhang, W. A high-sensitivity, self-healable MXene/silver nanowire strain sensor for full-range human motion monitoring. Nano Res. 17 (5), 4231&#x2013;4242. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6566-8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, F., Sun, H., Li, X. &amp; Chen, Y. Ultrafast-response and flexible pressure sensor based on silver nanowire/Ti3C2Tx MXene aerogel. Chem. Eng. J. 471, pp. (144523). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.144523 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, P., Du, H., Cao, L. &amp; Liu, Y. Ordered silver nanowire/PDMS array for transparent, high-sensitivity strain sensing. Chem. Eng. J. 465, 142876. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.142876 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S., Wang, Y., Yang, J. &amp; Li, F. Microstructured silver nanowire/PDMS strain sensors with ultrahigh sensitivity fabricated by a templating method. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 6 (9), 7891&#x2013;7900. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c01158 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Wang, Q., Hu, J. &amp; Yang, B. A dual-functional sensor based on AgNW@ZnO nanorods for UV light and strain monitoring with excellent durability, Sens. Actuators B Chem. 417, pp. (135712). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.135712 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Liu, H., Zhang, T. &amp; Wu, X. Wide-range and high-sensitivity strain sensors based on a sandwiched CNTs/AgNWs/CNTs/TPU structure. Adv. Mater. Technol. 9 (4, pp. 2301235, ). https://doi.org/10.1002/admt.202301235 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>