<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41416199</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2643-6515</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Plant phenomics (Washington, D.C.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plant Phenomics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Generation of labeled leaf point clouds for plants trait estimation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100071</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100071</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100071</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.plaphe.2025.100071</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Today, leaf trait estimation remains a labor-intensive process. The effort to obtain ground truth measurements limits how accurately this task can be performed automatically. Traditionally, plant scientists manually measure the traits of harvested leaves and associate them with sensor data, which is key for training machine learning approaches and to automate the processes. In this paper, we propose a neural network-based method to generate synthetic 3D point clouds of leaves with their associated traits to support approaches for phenotyping. We use real-world leaf point clouds to learn how to generate realistic leaves from a leaf skeleton, which is automatically extracted. We use the generated leaves to fine-tune different leaf trait estimation methods. We evaluate our generated data using different trait estimation methods and compare the results to using real-world data or other synthetic datasets from agricultural simulation software. Experiments show that our approach generates leaf point clouds with high similarity to real-world leaves. Tuning trait estimation methods on our generated data improves their performance in the estimation of real-world leaves' traits, making our data crucial for developing and testing data-driven trait estimation methods. Accurate trait estimation is key to understanding crop growth, productivity, and pest resistance, as leaf size directly influences photosynthesis, yield potential, and vulnerability to insects and fungal growth.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roggiolani</LastName><ForeName>Gianmarco</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Robotics, University of Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Brian N</ForeName><Initials>BN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Science, University of Davis, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behley</LastName><ForeName>Jens</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Robotics, University of Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stachniss</LastName><ForeName>Cyrill</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Robotics, University of Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lamarr Institute for Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Plant Phenomics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769942</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2643-6515</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">3D plant phenotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning for agriculture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leaf trait estimation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41416199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12710001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.plaphe.2025.100071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2643-6515(25)00077-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tabe-Ojong M.P.J., Lokossou J.C., Gebrekidan B., Affognon H.D. Adoption of climate-resilient groundnut varieties increases agricultural production, consumption, and smallholder commercialization in West Africa. Nat. Commun. 2023;14:5175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10449883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37620315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Guo Y., Sirault X., Stefanova K., Saradadevi R., Turner N.C., Nelson M.N., Furbank R.T., Siddique K.H., Cowling W.A. Nondestructive phenomic tools for the prediction of heat and drought tolerance at anthesis in Brassica species. Plant Phenomics. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonetti P., Hanafy M.S., Tayade R., Ramakrishnan M., Sonah H., Jacobsen H.J. Leveraging genomics, phenomics, and plant biotechnology approaches for improving abiotic and biotic stress tolerance in cereals and legumes. Front. Plant Sci. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10660271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38023923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migicovsky Z., Li M., Chitwood D.H., Myles S. Morphometrics reveals complex and heritable apple leaf shapes. Front. Plant Sci. 2018;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29354142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamang B.G., Zhang Y., Zambrano M.A., Ainsworth E.A. Anatomical determinants of gas exchange and hydraulics vary with leaf shape in soybean. Ann. Bot. 2022;131:909&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10332398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B., Kumar S., Elangovan A., Vasht D., Arya S., Duc N.T., Swami P., Pawar G.S., Raju D., Krishna H., et al. Phenomics based prediction of plant biomass and leaf area in wheat using machine learning approaches. Front. Plant Sci. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10337996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37448870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W., Feng H., Zhang X., Zhang J., Doonan J.H., Batchelor W.D., Xiong L., Yan J. Crop phenomics and high-throughput phenotyping: past decades, current challenges, and future perspectives. Mol. Plant. 2020;13:187&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31981735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood R., Lucas J., Acuna D., Li D., Philion J., Alvarez J.M., Yu Z., Fidler S., Law M.T. 2022. How Much More Data Do I Need? Estimating Requirements for Downstream Tasks; pp. 275&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubbens J., Cieslak M., Prusinkiewicz P., Stavness I. The use of plant models in deep learning: an application to leaf counting in rosette plants. Plant Method. 2018;14:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5773030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29375647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weyler J., Milioto A., Falck T., Behley J., Stachniss C. Joint plant instance detection and leaf count estimation for in-field plant phenotyping. IEEE Rob. Autom. Lett. 2021;6:3599&#x2013;3606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L., Jiang X., Yang Y., Samy E.R.A., Lefsrud M., Hoyos-Villegas V., Sun S. Eff-3DPSeg: 3D organ-level plant shoot segmentation using annotation-efficient deep learning. Plant Phenomics. 2023;5:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10395505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37539075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das Choudhury S., Maturu S., Samal A., Stoerger V., Awada T. Leveraging image analysis to compute 3D plant phenotypes based on voxel-grid plant reconstruction. Front. Plant Sci. 2020;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33362806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Zheng S., Gui L. Automatic measurement of morphological traits of typical leaf samples. Sensors. 2021;21:2247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myronenko A., Song X. Point set registration: Coherent point drift. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2010;32:2262&#x2013;2275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20975122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks E., Magistri F., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE Intl. Conf. on Robotics &amp; Automation (ICRA) 2022. Precise 3D reconstruction of plants from UAV imagery combining bundle adjustment and template matching.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks E., Sodano M., Magistri F., Wiesmann L., Desai D., Marcuzzi R., Behley J., Stachniss C. High precision leaf instance segmentation for phenotyping in point clouds obtained under real field conditions. IEEE Rob. Autom. Lett. 2023;8:4791&#x2013;4798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F., Tsaftaris S.A., Giuffrida M.V. 2024. GMT: Guided Mask Transformer for Leaf Instance Segmentation. arXiv:2406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W., Carroll M.E., Singh A., Swetnam T.L., Merchant N., Sarkar S., Singh A.K., Ganapathysubramanian B. UAS-based plant phenotyping for research and breeding applications. Plant Phenomics. 2021;2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34195621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser F., Rosu R.A., Corneli&#xdf;en A., Klingbeil L., Kuhlmann H., Behnke S. Field robot for high-throughput and high-resolution 3D plant phenotyping: towards efficient and sustainable crop production. IEEE Robot. Autom. Mag. 2023;30:20&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolhar S., Jagtap J. Plant trait estimation and classification studies in plant phenotyping using machine vision&#x2013;A review. Informat. Proc. Agricult. 2023;10:114&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pape J.M., Klukas C. Proc. Of the Europ. Conf. on Computer Vision Workshops. 2015. 3-D histogram-based segmentation and leaf detection for rosette plants; pp. 61&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai G., Ge Y., Hussain W., Baenziger P.S., Graef G. A multi-sensor system for high throughput field phenotyping in soybean and wheat breeding. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2016;128:181&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Wang K., Yang F., Pan S., Han H. Image segmentation of overlapping leaves based on chan&#x2013;vese model and Sobel operator. Informat. Proc. Agricult. 2017;5:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggiolani G., Sodano M., Guadagnino T., Magistri F., Behley J., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE Intl. Conf. on Robotics &amp; Automation (ICRA) 2023. Hierarchical approach for joint semantic, plant instance, and leaf instance segmentation in the agricultural domain.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y., Bai G., Stoerger V., Schnable J.C. Temporal dynamics of maize plant growth, water use, and leaf water content using automated high throughput RGB and hyperspectral imaging. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2016;127:625&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magistri F., Marcuzzi R., Marks E., Sodano M., Behley J., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE Intl. Conf. on Robotics &amp; Automation (ICRA) 2024. Efficient and accurate transformer-based 3D shape completion and reconstruction of fruits for agricultural robots.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue W., Ding H., Jin T., Meng J., Wang S., Liu Z., Ma X., Li J. CucumberAI: cucumber fruit morphology identification system based on artificial intelligence. Plant Phenomics. 2024;6:193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39144674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone C., Potena C., Nardi D. Proc. Of the Intl. Conf. on Simulation and Modeling Methodologies, Technologies and Applications. 2020. Simulation of near infrared sensor in unity for plant-weed segmentation classification.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Burridge J., Blok P.M., Guo W. A patch-level data synthesis pipeline enhances species-level crop and weed segmentation in natural agricultural scenes. Agriculture. 2025;15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmrich D.N., Bauer F.M., Giraud M., Schnepf A., G&#xf6;bbert J.H., Scharr H., Hvannberg E.T., Riedel M. A scalable pipeline to create synthetic datasets from functional&#x2013;structural plant models for deep learning. in silico Plants. 2024;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey BN. Helios. A scalable 3D plant and environmental biophysical modeling framework. Front. Plant Sci. 2019;10:1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6813926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi T., Guevara D., Cheng Z., Bandodkar G., Wang C., Bailey B.N., Earles M., Liu X. Proc. Of the Intl. Conf. on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE) 2024. DAVIS-Ag: a synthetic plant dataset for prototyping domain-inspired active vision in agricultural robots.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triggs B., McLauchlan P.F., Hartley R.I., Fitzgibbon A.W. Proc. Of the Intl. Workshop on Vision Algorithms: Theory and Practice. 1999. Bundle adjustment - a modern synthesis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magistri F., Chebrolu N., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE/RSJ Intl. Conf. on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2020. Segmentation-based 4D registration of plants point clouds for phenotyping.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronneberger O., Fischer P., Brox T. Proc. Of the Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention (MICCAI) 2015. U-net: convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas H., Qi C., Deschaud J., Marcotegui B., Goulette F., Guibas L. Proc. Of the IEEE/CVF Intl. Conf. on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019. KPConv: flexible and deformable convolution for point clouds.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds D.A. Encyclopedia of Biometrics. 2018. Gaussian mixture models.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon R., Zaenker T., Dengler N., Bennewitz M. Proc. Of the IEEE/RSJ Intl. Conf. on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2023. NBV-SC: next best view planning based on shape completion for fruit mapping and reconstruction.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde D., Valanarasu J.M.J., Patel V. Proc. Of the IEEE/CVF Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023. Clip goes 3d: leveraging prompt tuning for language grounded 3d recognition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayasumana S., Ramalingam S., Veit A., Glasner D., Chakrabarti A., Kumar S. Proc. Of the IEEE/CVF Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2024. Rethinking fid: towards a better evaluation metric for image generation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kynk&#xe4;&#xe4;nniemi T., Karras T., Laine S., Lehtinen J., Aila T. Proc. Of the Conf. on Neural Information Processing Systems. NeurIPS); 2019. Improved precision and recall metric for assessing generative models.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks E., B&#xf6;mer J., Magistri F., Sah A., Behley J., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE/RSJ Intl. Conf. on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2024. BonnBeetClouds3D: a dataset towards point cloud-based organ-level phenotyping of sugar beet plants under real field conditions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunck D., Magistri F., Rosu R., et al. Pheno4D: a spatio-temporal dataset of maize and tomato plant point clouds for phenotyping and advanced plant analysis. PLoS One. 2021;16:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8372960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggiolani G., Magistri F., Guadagnino T., Behley J., Stachniss C. Unsupervised pre-training for 3D leaf instance segmentation. IEEE Rob. Autom. Lett. 2023;11:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes L., Marcuzzi R., Mersch B., Behley J., Stachniss C. Proc. Of the IEEE/CVF Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2024. Scaling diffusion models to real-world 3D LiDAR scene completion.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma D., Ba J. Proc. Of the Intl. Conf. on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2015. Adam: a method for stochastic optimization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusel M., Ramsauer H., Unterthiner T., Nessler B., Hochreiter S. Proc. Of the Conf. Neural Information Processing Systems. NIPS); 2017. GANs trained by a two time-scale update rule converge to a local nash equilibrium.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi S.S., Wang Y., Del Bue A. Proc. Of the IEEE Intl. Conf. on Image Processing (ICIP) 2021. Pointview-GCN: 3D shape classification with multi-view point clouds.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusel M., Ramsauer H., Unterthiner T., Nessler B., Hochreiter S. Gans trained by a two time-scale update rule converge to a local nash equilibrium. Proc. Conf. Neural Inform. Proc. Syst. (NeurIPS) 2017;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajjadi M.S., Bachem O., Lucic M., Bousquet O., Gelly S. Assessing generative models via precision and recall. Proc. Conf. Neural Inform. Proc. Syst. (NeurIPS) 2018;31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi&#x144;kowski M., Sutherland D.J., Arbel M., Gretton A. Proc. Of the Intl. Conf. on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2018. Demystifying MMD GANs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyato T., Kataoka T., Koyama M., Yoshida Y. Proc. Of the Intl. Conf. on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2018. Spectral normalization for generative adversarial networks.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart P.E., Nilsson N.J., Raphael B. A formal basis for the heuristic determination of minimum cost paths. IEEE Trans. Syst. Sci. Cybern. 1968;4:100&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardini F., Mittleman J., Rushmeier H., Silva C., Taubin G. The ball-pivoting algorithm for surface reconstruction. tvcg. 1999;5:349&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang A., Funkhouser T., Guibas L., et al. Stanford University &#x2014; Princeton University &#x2014; Toyota Technological Institute at; Chicago: 2015. ShapeNet: an Information-Rich 3D Model Repository. Tech. Rep. arXiv:1512.03012 [cs.GR]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deitke M., Schwenk D., Salvador J., Weihs L., Michel O., VanderBilt E., Schmidt L., Ehsani K., Kembhavi A., Farhadi A. Proc. Of the IEEE/CVF Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023. Objaverse: a universe of annotated 3d objects.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>