<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41540367</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Objective measures of physical activity and physical capacities in lipedema - a scooping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>50</StartPage><MedlinePgn>50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">50</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-026-04271-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Lipedema is a chronic condition characterized by abnormal subcutaneous fat accumulation, predominantly affecting women. It is associated with pain, swelling, reduced mobility, and psychological distress, all of which may limit physical activity (PA) and impair physical function. While PA is increasingly recognized as a key component in conservative management, most existing studies rely on self-reported data, which are prone to bias. Objective assessments of PA and physical capacity are essential to better understand functional limitations and guide tailored interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This scoping review aimed to map and summarize existing studies that have used objective methods to assess physical activity levels and physical function in women with lipedema.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The review is reported following the PRISMA-ScR guidelines. A systematic search was conducted in five databases (Scopus, Web of Science, MEDLINE, CINAHL, and AMED) from inception to August 13, 2025. Studies were included if they investigated lipedema and used objective measures of PA or physical capacity. After screening 5,147 records and assessing 46 full-text articles, six studies met the inclusion criteria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The included studies employed various objective tools, such as accelerometry, six-minute walk tests, sit-to-stand tests, and handheld dynamometry. Sample sizes ranged from 31 to 96 participants with lipedema, with a predominance of female subjects. Findings indicated that individuals with lipedema generally exhibit lower walking capacity and muscle strength compared to healthy or BMI-matched controls. Structured exercise interventions, particularly multimodal programs combining aerobic and resistance training, were associated with improvements in walking distance, muscle strength, and pain reduction. However, methodological heterogeneity and small sample sizes limit the generalizability of findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Objective assessments reveal that individuals with lipedema have reduced physical capacity, but structured physical activity interventions may yield functional benefits. Despite promising results, the evidence base remains limited. Future research should prioritize standardized, objective measurement protocols and larger, well-designed trials to inform evidence-based guidelines for physical activity in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-026-04271-y.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc5;str&#xf6;m Malm</LastName><ForeName>Ida</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnostics, School of Health and Welfare, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping University, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping, Sweden. Ida.astrom-malm@ju.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Violasdotter Nilsson</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of University Library, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping University, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurtig-Wennl&#xf6;f</LastName><ForeName>Anita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnostics, School of Health and Welfare, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping University, J&#xf6;nk&#xf6;ping, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>BMC Womens Health. 2026 Mar 7;26(1):148. doi: 10.1186/s12905-026-04345-x.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41794729</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lipedema</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Objective physical activity assessment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41540367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12838409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-026-04271-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-026-04271-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nicol&#xe1;s PC, Lipedema. More than a problem of fat legs. Update in the pathophysiology, diagnosis and surgical treatment. Revista de Cir. 2021;73(3):370&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buck DW, Herbst KL, Lipedema. A relatively common disease with extremely common misconceptions. Plast Reconstr Surg - Global Open. 2016;4(9).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu&#x11f;ral A, Bakar Y. An approach to lipedema: a literature review of current knowledge of an underestimated health problem. Eur J Plast Surg. 2019;42(6):549&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00238-019-01519-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forner-Cordero I, Forner-Cordero A, Szolnoky G. Update in the management of lipedema. Int Angiol. 2021;40(4):345&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0392-9590.21.04604-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33870676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollina U, Heinig B. Differential diagnostics of lipedema and lymphedema: A practical guideline. Hautarzt. 2018;69(12):1039&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00105-018-4304-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30402687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke C, Kirby JN, Smidt T, Best T. Stages of lipoedema: experiences of physical and mental health and health care. Qual Life Res. 2023;32(1):127&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-022-03216-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35972618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aitzetm&#xfc;ller-Klietz ML, Busch L, Hamatschek M, Paul M, Schriek C, Wiebringhaus P et al. Understanding the vicious circle of Pain, physical Activity, and mental health in lipedema Patients&#x2014;A response surface analysis. J Clin Med. 2023;12(16).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy D, Williams A. Best practice guidelines for the management of lipoedema. Br J Community Nurs. 2017;22(Sup10):S44&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/bjcn.2017.22.Sup10.S44</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28961048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. WHO guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2020. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240015128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World health organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annunziata G, Paoli A, Manzi V, Camajani E, Laterza F, Verde L, et al. The role of physical exercise as a therapeutic tool to improve lipedema: A consensus statement from the Italian society of motor and sports sciences (Societ&#xe0; Italiana Di scienze motorie e Sportive, SISMeS) and the Italian society of phlebology (Societ&#xe0; Italiana Di Flebologia, SIF). Curr Obes Rep. 2024;13(4):667&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13679-024-00579-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38958868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erden E, Turk AC, Erden E, Yetim S, Borman P. The &#x131;ncidence of neuropathic pain and &#x131;ts &#x131;mpact on quality of life in patients with lipedema. Ir J Med Sci. 2025;194(5):1829&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11845-025-04024-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40788448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prince SA, Cardilli L, Reed JL, Saunders TJ, Kite C, Douillette K, et al. A comparison of self-reported and device measured sedentary behaviour in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2020;17(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-020-00938-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7055033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32131845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton DM, Haennel RG. Validity and reliability of the 6-minute walk test in a cardiac rehabilitation population. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2000;20(3):156&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008483-200005000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10860197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson J, Pearce PF, Ferguson LA, Langford CA. Understanding scoping reviews: Definition, purpose, and process. J Am Assoc Nurse Pract. 2017;29(1):12&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2327-6924.12380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27245885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg C, Wengstr&#xf6;m Y. Att g&#xf6;ra systematiska litteraturstudier: v&#xe4;rdering, analys och presentation av omv&#xe5;rdnadsforskning. 3. uppl. ed. Stockholm: Natur &amp; Kultur; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angst F, Lehmann S, Aeschlimann A, Sand&#xf2;r PS, Wagner S. Cross-sectional validity and specificity of comprehensive measurement in lymphedema and lipedema of the lower extremity: a comparison of five outcome instruments. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2020;18(1):245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-020-01488-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Esch-Smeenge J, Damstra RJ, Hendrickx AA. Muscle strength and functional exercise capacity in patients with lipoedema and obesity: a comparative study. J Lymphoedema. 2017;12(1):27&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakizli Erdal E, Ergin C, Haspolat M, Erturk B, Keser I. Effects of multimodal exercise program on edema, pain, exercise capacity, lower extremity muscle strength and function in patients with lipedema. Phlebology. 2025:2683555251343148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atan T, Bahar-Ozdemir Y. The effects of complete decongestive therapy or intermittent pneumatic compression therapy or exercise only in the treatment of severe lipedema: A randomized controlled trial. Lymphatic Res Biology. 2021;19(1):86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/lrb.2020.0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benz T, Lehmann S, Sandor PS, Angst F. Relationship between subjectively-rated and objectively-tested physical function across six different medical diagnoses. J Rehabil Med. 2023;55:jrm9383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/jrm.v55.9383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10711800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38050460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortimer PS, Pearson M, Gawrysiak P, Riches K, Keeley V, Tew KF, et al. LymphActiv: A digital physical activity behavior intervention for the treatment of lymphedema and lipedema. Lymphatic Res Biology. 2024;22(2):112&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karas M, Bai J, Str&#x105;czkiewicz M, Harezlak J, Glynn NW, Harris T, et al. Accelerometry data in health research: challenges and opportunities. Stat Biosci. 2019;11(2):210&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12561-018-9227-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6874221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31762829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du H, Newton PJ, Salamonson Y, Carrieri-Kohlman VL, Davidson PM. A review of the Six-Minute walk test: its implication as a Self-Administered assessment tool. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2009;8(1):2&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejcnurse.2008.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18694656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzoletti L, Zanolin ME, Dorelli G, Ferrari P, Dalle Carbonare LG, Crisafulli E, et al. Six-minute walk distance in healthy subjects: reference standards from a general population sample. Respir Res. 2022;23(1):83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-022-02003-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8985335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATS statement. Guidelines for the six-minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166(1):111&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm.166.1.at1102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>