<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41174782</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of football training on patients with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>314</StartPage><MedlinePgn>314</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">314</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01361-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hypertension and metabolic disorders remain major global health burdens, yet the specific benefits of football training for adults with these conditions are not fully characterized. This study aimed to systematically evaluate the effects of recreational football on cardiovascular, metabolic, and fitness outcomes, addressing current gaps in evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We systematically reviewed randomized and matched controlled trials published in English and Chinese, including 20 studies and 1,225 adult participants. Primary outcomes were blood pressure, heart rate, body composition, peak oxygen uptake (VO&#x2082;max), muscle strength, and cardiometabolic biomarkers. Random-effects models were used for pooled analyses, with subgroup and sensitivity analyses. This systematic review and meta-analysis were registered in the PROSPERO international prospective register of systematic reviews (CRD420251143230).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Football training significantly reduced systolic blood pressure (MD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;6.67&#xa0;mmHg, 95% CI:&#x2009;-&#x2009;8.95 to&#x2009;-&#x2009;4.39; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.00001), resting heart rate (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;2.26, 95% CI:&#x2009;-&#x2009;3.71 to&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.81; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002), and diastolic pressure in both normotensive (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;2.44, 95% CI:&#x2009;-&#x2009;3.41 to&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.47) and hypertensive groups (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;0.92, 95% CI:&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.40 to&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.43). VO&#x2082;max improved (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.96, 95% CI: 1.62 to 6.31; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0009), as did ejection fraction, E/A ratio, and LV mass. Benefits were observed for LDL (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;1.64), triglycerides (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;3.42), total cholesterol (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;2.44), and HDL (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.91). Body fat mass declined in males (SMD&#x2009;= -&#x2009;0.74), muscle strength increased (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.14), and insulin, HbA1c, and FGF-21 improved significantly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Recreational football is an effective intervention for improving cardiovascular and metabolic health in adults, particularly those with hypertension. These findings highlight football training as a practical adjunct to conventional exercise therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wangyang</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Hanjiang Normal University, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fangfang</LastName><ForeName>Jiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, China West Normal University, Nanchong, 637000, Sichuan, China. jiangfang34@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024B02</GrantID><Agency>Hanjiang Normal University Teaching Research Project "Construction and Practice of Big Data System for College Students' Physical Education Course Learning Process under the Background of Education Digitalization"</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023515</GrantID><Agency>Hubei Provincial Teaching Research Project "Research on the Construction of Ideological and Political Teaching Evaluation System for Public Physical Education Courses in Colleges and Universities"</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VO&#x2082;max</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: As this study is a systematic review and meta-analysis of previously published data, it did not involve new human or animal participants. Therefore, ethical approval and informed consent were not required. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41174782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12577365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01361-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01361-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdel Fattah M, Gaber H, Elgamil A, Abo Elanin F. Effect of aerobic regular exercise training on blood pressure control for patients with hypertension. J High Instit Public Health. 2007;37(3):542&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/jhiph.2007.22539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LJ, Hansen PR, Sogaard P, Madsen JK, Bech J, Krustrup P. Improvement of systolic and diastolic heart function after physical training in sedentary women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):50&#x2013;7. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01088.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01088.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20136765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LJ, Randers MB, Hansen PR, Hornstrup T, Schmidt JF, Dvorak J, et al. Structural and functional cardiac adaptations to 6 months of football training in untrained hypertensive men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):27&#x2013;35. 10.1111/sms.12237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LJ, Randers MB, Westh K, Martone D, Hansen PR, Junge A, et al. Football as a treatment for hypertension in untrained 30&#x2013;55-year-old men: a prospective randomised study. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):98&#x2013;102. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01109.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01109.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20210907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen TR, Schmidt JF, Nielsen JJ, Randers MB, Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, et al. Effect of football or strength training on functional ability and physical performance in untrained old men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):76&#x2013;85. 10.1111/sms.12245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen TR, Schmidt JF, Thomassen M, Hornstrup T, Frandsen U, Randers MB, et al. A preliminary study: effects of football training on glucose control, body composition, and performance in men with type 2 diabetes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):43&#x2013;56. 10.1111/sms.12259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacon L, Windmeier S, Smith L. Comprehensive data extraction for meta-analysis: Handling missing standard deviations.&#xa0;Res Synth Methods. 2013;4(2):123-35. 10.1002/jrsm.1078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barene S, Krustrup P, Brekke OL, Holtermann A. Soccer and Zumba as health-promoting activities among female hospital employees: a 40-weeks cluster randomised intervention study. J Sports Sci. 2014;32(16):1539&#x2013;49. 10.1080/02640414.2014.906043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2014.906043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24720526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barene S, Krustrup P, Jackman S, Brekke O, Holtermann A. Do soccer and Zumba exercise improve fitness and indicators of health among female hospital employees? A 12-week RCT. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(6):990&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24151956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charchar FJ, Prestes PR, Mills C, Ching SM, Neupane D, Marques FZ, et al. Lifestyle management of hypertension: International Society of Hypertension position paper endorsed by the World Hypertension League and European Society of Hypertension. J Hypertens. 2024;42(1):23&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37712135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SMJ, Lee H, Koyama S, Zou RS, Schuermans A, Ganesh S, et al. Cumulative diastolic blood pressure burden in normal systolic blood pressure and cardiovascular disease. Hypertension. 2024;81(2):273&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.123.22160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10841692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38084606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Ramirez-Campillo R, Sarmento H. Effects of the small-sided soccer games on blood pressure in untrained hypertensive adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Healthcare. 2021;9(3):345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8003134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly LJ, Scott S, Mohr M, Ermidis G, Julian R, Bangsbo J, et al. Effects of small-volume soccer and vibration training on body composition, aerobic fitness, and muscular PCr kinetics for inactive women aged 20&#x2013;45. J Sport Health Sci. 2014;3(4):284&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2014.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Barcelos GT, Heberle I, Coneglian JC, Vieira BA, Delevatti RS, Gerage AM. Effects of aerobic training progression on blood pressure in individuals with hypertension: a systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:719063. 10.3389/fspor.2022.719063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.719063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35252853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y, Zeng X, Tang C, Hou X, Zhang Y, Shi L. The effect of exercise training on heart rate variability in patients with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(13):1272&#x2013;87. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2388984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2388984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39115012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genovesi S, Vania A, Caroli M, Orlando A, Lieti G, Parati G, et al. Non-pharmacological treatment for cardiovascular risk prevention in children and adolescents with obesity. Nutrients. 2024;16(15):2497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16152497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11314452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39125377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grashow R, Eagle SR, Terry DP, DiGregorio H, Baggish AL, Weisskopf MG, et al. Medical conditions in former professional American-style football players are associated with self-reported clinical features of traumatic encephalopathy syndrome. Neurotrauma Rep. 2024;5(1):376&#x2013;86. 10.1089/neur.2024.0008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neur.2024.0008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11035840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38655114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammami A, Kasmi S, Razgallah M, Tabka Z, Shephard RJ, Bouhlel E. Recreational soccer training improves heart-rate variability indices and physical performance in untrained healthy adolescent. Sport Sci Health. 2017;13:507&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-016-0343-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Y. Effect of sports training on the rehabilitation of hypertensive patients. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2022;28(3):183&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-8692202228032021_0460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodzic A, Gendron P, Baron E, &#xc9;thier A, Bonnefous O, Saloux E, et al. Inter-season training effects on cardiovascular health in American-style football players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16(1):108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00888-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11092187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38741116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt K, Gray CM, Maclean A, Smillie S, Bunn C, Wyke S. Do weight management programmes delivered at professional football clubs attract and engage high risk men? A mixed-methods study. BMC Public Health. 2014;14:50. 10.1186/1471-2458-14-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-14-50</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24443845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen MD, Sundstrup E, Randers MB, Kjaer M, Andersen LL, Krustrup P, et al. The effect of strength training, recreational soccer and running exercise on stretch-shortening cycle muscle performance during countermovement jumping. Hum Mov Sci. 2012;31(4):970&#x2013;86. 10.1016/j.humov.2011.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2011.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22397814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoepfli-Lenzin C, Sennhauser C, Toigo M, Boutellier U, Bangsbo J, Krustrup P, et al. Effects of a 12-week intervention period with football and running for habitually active men with mild hypertension. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):72&#x2013;9. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01089.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01089.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20136764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Hansen PR, Andersen LJ, Jakobsen MD, Sundstrup E, Randers MB, et al. Long-term musculoskeletal and cardiac health effects of recreational football and running for premenopausal women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):58&#x2013;71. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01111.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01111.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20546545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Hansen PR, Randers MB, Nybo L, Martone D, Andersen LJ, et al. Beneficial effects of recreational football on the cardiovascular risk profile in untrained premenopausal women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):40&#x2013;9. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01110.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01110.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20210906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Nielsen JJ, Krustrup BR, Christensen JF, Pedersen H, Randers MB, et al. Recreational soccer is an effective health-promoting activity for untrained men. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(11):825&#x2013;31. 10.1136/bjsm.2008.053124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2008.053124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19098116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Randers MB, Andersen LJ, Jackman SR, Bangsbo J, Hansen PR. Soccer improves fitness and attenuates cardiovascular risk factors in hypertensive men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(3):553&#x2013;60. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182777051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182777051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Skoradal MB, Randers MB, Weihe P, Uth J, Mortensen J, et al. Broad-spectrum health improvements with one year of soccer training in inactive mildly hypertensive middle-aged women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(12):1893&#x2013;901. 10.1111/sms.12829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28124381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenze C, Pietrosimone B, Currie KD, Walton SR, Kerr ZY, Brett BL, et al. Joint injury, osteoarthritis, and cardiovascular disease risk factors in former National Football League athletes: an NFL-LONG study. J Athl Train. 2023;58(6):528&#x2013;35. 10.4085/1062-6050-0437.22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-0437.22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10496448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36645831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Liu X, Shen F, Xu N, Li Y, Xu K, et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on blood pressure in patients with hypertension: a meta-analysis. Med (Baltimore). 2022;101(50):e32246. 10.1097/MD.0000000000032246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000032246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9771301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36550888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z, Qian H, Zhang X, Wang Y, Wang J, Yu P. Effectiveness and safety of inspiratory muscle training in patients with pulmonary hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:999422. 10.3389/fcvm.2022.999422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.999422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36523361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanovi&#x107; Z, Panteli&#x107; S, &#x10c;ovi&#x107; N, Spori&#x161; G, Mohr M, Krustrup P. Broad-spectrum physical fitness benefits of recreational football: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(15):926&#x2013;39. 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29371223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Fatouros IG, Asghar M, Buono P, Nassis GP, Krustrup P. Football training as a non-pharmacological treatment of the global aging population-a topical review. Front Aging. 2023;4:1146058. 10.3389/fragi.2023.1146058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fragi.2023.1146058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9947510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Helge EW, Petersen LF, Lindenskov A, Weihe P, Mortensen J, et al. Effects of soccer vs swim training on bone formation in sedentary middle-aged women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(12):2671&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00421-015-3231-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3231-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26255288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Lindenskov A, Holm PM, Nielsen HP, Mortensen J, Weihe P, et al. Football training improves cardiovascular health profile in sedentary, premenopausal hypertensive women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):36&#x2013;42. 10.1111/sms.12278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Nordsborg NB, Lindenskov A, Steinholm H, Nielsen HP, Mortensen J, Krustrup P. High-intensity recreational football training improves blood pressure control and cardiovascular health in hypertensive women: A 5-year follow-up study.&#xa0;Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26(10):1157&#x2013;67. 10.1111/sms.12588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Sj&#xfa;r&#xf0;arson T, Skoradal MB, Nordsborg NB, Krustrup P. Long-term continuous exercise training counteracts the negative impact of the menopause transition on cardiometabolic health in hypertensive women - a 9-year RCT follow-up. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;85:54&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.pcad.2023.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2023.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38070694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawi WMIW, Seman MHA, Akmal N, Jamaludin RAAR, Shaharudin MI, Shipah NAM. Exercise and hypertension: a review on exercise recommendation, mechanism of action, exercise-related risk and innovative exercise approach. Asian J Med Health Sci. 2024;7(2):70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedralli ML, Eibel B, Waclawovsky G, Schaun MI, Nisa-Castro-Neto W, Umpierre D, et al. Effects of exercise training on endothelial function in individuals with hypertension: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Am Soc Hypertens. 2018;12(12):e65&#x2013;75. 10.1016/j.jash.2018.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jash.2018.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randers MB, Andersen TR, Mohr M, Ottesen L, Krustrup P. Football as broadspectrum fitness training. In Football as Prevention and Treatment: A White Paper Focusing on 10 Non-Communicable Diseases and Risk Factors. Dansk Boldspil-Union; 2024. pp. 6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randers MB, Nielsen JJ, Krustrup BR, Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Nybo L, et al. Positive performance and health effects of a football training program over 12 weeks can be maintained over a 1-year period with reduced training frequency. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 1):80&#x2013;9. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01091.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01091.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20210904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randers MB, Petersen J, Andersen LJ, Krustrup BR, Hornstrup T, Nielsen JJ, et al. Short-term street soccer improves fitness and cardiovascular health status of homeless men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(6):2097&#x2013;106. 10.1007/s00421-011-2171-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2171-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scar&#xe0; A, Palam&#xe0; Z, Robles AG, Dei L-L, Borrelli A, Zanin F, et al. Non-pharmacological treatment of heart failure from physical activity to electrical therapies: a literature review. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2024;11(4):122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11050051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38667740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt JF, Hansen PR, Andersen TR, Andersen LJ, Hornstrup T, Krustrup P, et al. Cardiovascular adaptations to 4 and 12 months of football or strength training in 65- to 75-year-old untrained men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):86&#x2013;97. 10.1111/sms.12217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24902992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrader B, Conradi C, L&#xfc;ders S, Vaske B, Koziolek M, Gehlenborg E, et al. Health football beats them all: subgroup analysis of the 3F (Fit&amp;Fun with Football) study on white-coat hypertension, sustained hypertension, dippers, nondippers, and on pharmacologically un(treated) arterial hypertension. J Hypertens. 2023;41(4):564&#x2013;71. 10.1097/hjh.0000000000003360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/hjh.0000000000003360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9994839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36729435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seabra A, Katzmarzyk P, Carvalho MJ, Seabra A, Coelho ESM, Abreu S, et al. Effects of 6-month soccer and traditional physical activity programmes on body composition, cardiometabolic risk factors, inflammatory, oxidative stress markers and cardiorespiratory fitness in obese boys. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(19):1822&#x2013;9. 10.1080/02640414.2016.1140219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1140219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique U, Amin F, Shams F, Ali I, Nouman M, Mahmood HF, et al. Epidemiology; risk factors and prevention strategies for cardiovascular disease and obesity in Pakistan. The American Journal of Medical Sciences and Pharmaceutical Research. 2025;7(03):21&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37547/tajmspr/Volume07Issue03-04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xfa;r&#xf0;arson T, Nordsborg NB, Kristiansen J, Andersen LJ, Krustrup P, Kyhl K, et al. The impact of exercise intensity and duration for swim training-induced adaptations in cardiac structure and function in women with mild hypertension. Physiol Rep. 2024;12(21):e70116. 10.14814/phy2.70116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.70116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11530408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39487596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, Cates CJ, Cheng HY, Corbett MS, Eldridge SM, Emberson JR, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Hopewell S, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Junqueira DR, J&#xfc;ni P, Kirkham JJ, Lasserson T, Li T, McAleenan A, &#x2026; Higgins JPT. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials.&#xa0;BMJ (Clinical research ed.). 2019;&#xa0;366:l4898. 10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen LL, Andersen TR, Randers MB, Helge JW, et al. Positive effects of 1-year football and strength training on mechanical muscle function and functional capacity in elderly men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(6):1127&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s00421-016-3368-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3368-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27068158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JMM, Roever L, Ramasamy A, Pereira R, Carneiro I, Krustrup P, et al. Statistical heterogeneity in meta-analysis of hypertension and exercise training: a meta-review. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(22):2033&#x2013;44. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2309055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2309055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38341865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uth J, Hornstrup T, Christensen JF, Christensen KB, Jorgensen NR, Schmidt JF, et al. Efficacy of recreational football on bone health, body composition, and physical functioning in men with prostate cancer undergoing androgen deprivation therapy: 32-week follow-up of the FC prostate randomised controlled trial. Osteoporos Int. 2016;27(4):1507&#x2013;18. 10.1007/s00198-015-3399-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-015-3399-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26572756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uth J, Hornstrup T, Schmidt JF, Christensen JF, Frandsen C, Christensen KB, et al. Football training improves lean body mass in men with prostate cancer undergoing androgen deprivation therapy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(Suppl 1):105&#x2013;12. 10.1111/sms.12260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Li Y, Tian L, Feng Z, Yun C, Zhang S, et al. In-hospital systolic blood pressure lowering patterns and risk of rehospitalization for angina in patients with hypertension and coronary artery disease. Hypertens Res. 2025;48(2):662&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41440-024-01942-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39396071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Yan W, Yu Q, Wu P, Bigambo FM, Chen J. Association between Exercise and Blood Pressure in Hypertensive Residents: A Meta-Analysis. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2022;2022(1):2453805. 10.1155/2022/2453805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/2453805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>