<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41290343</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1319-6138</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurosciences (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurosciences (Riyadh)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A narrative review of clinical practice guidelines for the application of physical therapy and rehabilitation procedures in the management of multiple sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>262</StartPage><EndPage>270</EndPage><MedlinePgn>262-270</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17712/nsj.2025.4.20250054</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic autoimmune disorder characterized by neuroinflammation and progressive neurodegeneration, leading to significant physical and cognitive impairments. Rehabilitation, particularly physical therapy, has emerged as a crucial component in managing MS-related disability by improving mobility, reducing fatigue, and enhancing overall quality of life. This narrative review investigates current international guidelines on physical therapy and rehabilitation for MS. Literature search in databases (January 2010 until August 2025) resulted in three guidelines that met the inclusion criteria. Evidence suggests that structured aerobic and resistance training programmes, combined with balance and flexibility exercises, contribute significantly to maintaining functional independence. Additionally, assistive technologies offer promising advances in patient-centred care. However, challenges such as limited accessibility, variability in disease presentation, and adherence to rehabilitation programmes pose significant barriers. This narrative review highlights the need for comprehensive and multidisciplinary clinical guidelines to optimize physical therapy interventions and improve the long-term well-being of MS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Neurosciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alhusayni</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1807-4015</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Health Rehabilitation, College of Applied Medical Sciences at Shaqra, Shaqra University, Shaqra, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Saudi Arabia</Country><MedlineTA>Neurosciences (Riyadh)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101252453</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1319-6138</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017410" MajorTopicYN="Y">Practice Guidelines as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41290343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12676939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17712/nsj.2025.4.20250054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">30/4/262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Woo MS, Engler JB, Friese MA. The neuropathobiology of multiple sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurosci 2024; 25: 493-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38789516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kister I, Bacon TE, Chamot E, Salter AR, Cutter GR, Kalina JT, et al. Natural history of multiple sclerosis symptoms. Int J MS Care 2013; 15: 146-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3883021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24453777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk A, Maver A, Juvan P, Drulovi&#x107; J, Mesaro&#x161; &#x160;, Novakovi&#x107; I, et al. Increased burden of rare variants in GWAS associated genes in familial multiple sclerosis. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 21200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12219419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40592943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarghami A, Li Y, Claflin SB, van der Mei I, Taylor BV. Role of environmental factors in multiple sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 2021; 21: 1389-1408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34494502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi H, Khoshdooz S, Alem E, Bakhshimoghaddam F, Doaei S, Goodarzi MO. Vitamin D in Multiple Sclerosis: A Comprehensive Umbrella Review. J Nutr 2024; 154: 3505-3520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39374790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Kockum I, Stridh P. Trends in the environmental risks associated with earlier onset in multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2022; 68: 104250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Turner-Stokes L, Ng L, Kilpatrick T. Multidisciplinary rehabilitation for adults with multiple sclerosis. Postgrad Med J 2008; 84: 385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18716020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soler B, Raats J, Abasiyanik Z, Lamers I, Makshakov G, Feys P. Systematic evaluation of the guidelines for rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis patients: an overview according to ICF functioning domains. Int J Rehabil Res 2021; 44: 289-297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlayson M, Plow M, Cho C. Use of physical therapy services among middle-aged and older adults with multiple sclerosis. Phys Ther 2010; 90: 1607-1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Amatya B, Turner-Stokes L. Symptomatic therapy and rehabilitation in primary progressive multiple sclerosis. Neurol Res Int 2011; 2011: 740505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W. Advancing biomechanics: enhancing sports performance, mitigating injury risks, and optimizing athlete rehabilitation. Frontiers Media (SA); 2025. p. 1556024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39968189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalb R, Brown TR, Coote S, Costello K, Dalgas U, Garmon E, et al. Exercise and lifestyle physical activity recommendations for people with multiple sclerosis throughout the disease course. Mult Scler 2020; 26: 1459-1469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32323606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimigliano F, Negrini S. The World Health Organization&#x201d; rehabilitation 2030: a call for action. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2017; 53: 155-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28382807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soelberg Sorensen P, Giovannoni G, Montalban X, Thalheim C, Zaratin P, Comi G. The multiple sclerosis care unit. Mult Scler 2019; 25: 627-636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30351211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasova K, Freeman J, Martinkova P, Pavlikova M, Cattaneo D, Jonsdottir J, et al. The organisation of physiotherapy for people with multiple sclerosis across Europe: a multicentre questionnaire survey. BMC Health Serv Res 2016; 16: 552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27716390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinkov&#xe1; P, Freeman J, Drabinov&#xe1; A, Erosheva E, Cattaneo D, Jonsdottir J, et al. Physiotherapeutic interventions in multiple sclerosis across Europe: regions and other factors that matter. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2018; 22: 59-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29579644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters LM, van Munster CE, Van Wijmeersch B, Bruyndonckx R, Lamers I, Hellings N, et al. Multidisciplinary data infrastructures in multiple sclerosis: why they are needed and can be done! Mult Scler 2019; 25: 500-509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30381984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supper I, Gratadour J, Fran&#xe7;ois M, Jaafari N, Boussageon R. A critical appraisal of acute sore throat guidelines using the AGREE II instrument: a scoping review. Fam Pract 2024; 41: 223-233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Development Division MoHM, editor. Management of Multiple Sclerosis. In: Malaysia Health Technology Assessment Section (MaHTAS). 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>guideline NG220&#xa0;N. Multiple sclerosis in adults: management. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts F, Hobbs H, Jessop H, Bozzolini C, Burman J, Greco R, et al. Rehabilitation before and after autologous haematopoietic stem cell transplantation (AHSCT) for patients with multiple sclerosis (MS): consensus guidelines and recommendations for best clinical practice on behalf of the Autoimmune Diseases Working Party, Nurses Group, and Patient Advocacy Committee of the European Society for Blood and Marrow Transplantation (EBMT). Front Neurol 2020; 11: 556141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7759663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33362684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Amatya B. Rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis: a systematic review of systematic reviews. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2017; 98: 353-367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peresedova A, Chernikova L, Zavalishin I. Physical rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis: general principles and high-tech approaches. Annals of the Russian academy of medical sciences. 2013; 68: 14-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24640715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Saad HB. Revolutionizing &#x201c;text neck syndrome&#x201d; management: paradigm shifting from &#x201c;posture correction&#x201d; to &#x201c;posture change&#x201d;. Acta Kinesiol 2024; 18: 37-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donz&#xe9; C, Massot C. Rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis in 2021. Presse Med 2021; 50: 104066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33989721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Briki W, Heissel A, Schega L, Dergaa I, Guelmami N, et al. Physical Activity to Counter Age-Related Cognitive Decline: Benefits of Aerobic, Resistance, and Combined Training-A Narrative Review. Sports Med Open 2025; 11: 56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12085549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40381170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahantigh-Akbari N, Tahan N, Sadat-Naimi S, Daryabor A, Danesh-Shahreki B, Rastgar-Koutenaei F, et al. Effect of aerobic exercises on fatigue in patients with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review. Phys Ther Rev 2025; 30: 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahantigh-Akbari N, Tahan N, Sadat-Naimi S, Daryabor A, Danesh-Shahreki B, Rastgar-Koutenaei F, et al. Effect of aerobic exercises on fatigue in patients with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review. Phys Ther Rev 2025; 30: 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosnoff JJ, Gappmaier E, Frame A, Motl RW. Influence of spasticity on mobility and balance in persons with multiple sclerosis. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2011; 35: 129-132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21934374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xee;rbu CA, Thompson DC, Plesa FC, Vasile TM, Jianu DC, Mitrica M, et al. Neurorehabilitation in multiple sclerosis&#x2014;A review of present approaches and future considerations. J Clin Med 2022; 11: 7003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9739865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baird JF, Sandroff BM, Motl RW. Therapies for mobility disability in persons with multiple sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 2018; 18: 493-502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6291756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29772185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemenschneider M, Hvid LG, Stenager E, Dalgas U. Is there an overlooked &#x201c;window of opportunity&#x201d; in MS exercise therapy? Perspectives for early MS rehabilitation. Mult Scler 2018; 24: 886-894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavazzi E, Bergsland N, Cattaneo D, Gervasoni E, Lagan&#xe0; MM, Dipasquale O, et al. Effects of motor rehabilitation on mobility and brain plasticity in multiple sclerosis: a structural and functional MRI study. J Neurol 2018; 265: 1393-1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29627940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joisten N, Rademacher A, Bloch W, Schenk A, Oberste M, Dalgas U, et al. Influence of different rehabilitative aerobic exercise programs on (anti-) inflammatory immune signalling, cognitive and functional capacity in persons with MS&#x2013;study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. BMC Neurol 2019; 19: 1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6407211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30849952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Padulo J, Be&#x161;lija T, Cheze L. Revolutionizing Low Back Pain Management: A Paradigm Shift from &#x201c;Posture Correction&#x201d; to &#x201c;Posture Change&#x201d;. New Asian Journal of Medicine 2024; 2: 17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beer S, Aschbacher B, Manoglou D, Gamper E, Kool J, Kesselring J. Robot-assisted gait training in multiple sclerosis: a pilot randomized trial. Mult Scler 2008; 14: 231-236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17942510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato MP, Langdon D, Montalban X, Benedict RH, DeLuca J, Krupp LB, et al. Treatment of cognitive impairment in multiple sclerosis: position paper. J Neurol 2013; 260: 1452-1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23180174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martino Cinnera A, Bisirri A, Leone E, Morone G, Gaeta A. Effect of dual-task training on balance in patients with multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil 2021; 35: 1399-1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza A, Kelleher A, Cooper R, Cooper RA, Iezzoni LI, Collins DM. Multiple sclerosis and mobility-related assistive technology: systematic review of literature. J Rehabil Res Dev 2010; 47: 213-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20665347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pike J, Jones E, Rajagopalan K, Piercy J, Anderson P. Social and economic burden of walking and mobility problems in multiple sclerosis. BMC Neurol 2012; 12: 94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3517776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22989365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kister I, Chamot E, Salter AR, Cutter GR, Bacon TE, Herbert J. Disability in multiple sclerosis: a reference for patients and clinicians. Neurology 2013; 80: 1018-1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3653203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23427319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ascherio A, Munch M. Epstein-Barr virus and multiple sclerosis. Epidemiology 2000; 11: 220-224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11021623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciampi E, Uribe-San-Martin R, Soler B, Molnar K, Reyes D, Keller K, et al. Prevalence of comorbidities in Multiple Sclerosis and impact on physical disability according to disease phenotypes. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2020; 46: 102565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubsik-Gidlewska AM, Klimkiewicz P, Klimkiewicz R, Janczewska K, Wolda&#x144;ska-Oko&#x144;ska MZ. Rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis. Adv Clin Exp Med 2017; 26: 709-715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28691412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florindo M. Inflammatory cytokines and physical activity in multiple sclerosis. Int Sch Res Notices 2014; 2014: 151572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3921944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24592334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xf6;ring A, Pfueller CF, Paul F, D&#xf6;rr J. Exercise in multiple sclerosis&#x2014;an integral component of disease management. EPMA J 2012; 3: 1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22738091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shobeiri P, Karimi A, Momtazmanesh S, Teixeira AL, Teunissen CE, van Wegen EE, et al. Exercise-induced increase in blood-based brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) in people with multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise intervention trials. PLoS One 2022; 17: e0264557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokhtarzade M, Motl R, Negaresh R, Zimmer P, Khodadoost M, Baker JS, et al. Exercise-induced changes in neurotrophic factors and markers of blood-brain barrier permeability are moderated by weight status in multiple sclerosis. Neuropeptides 2018; 70: 93-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zackowski KM, Freeman J, Brichetto G, Centonze D, Dalgas U, DeLuca J, et al. Prioritizing progressive MS rehabilitation research: A call from the International Progressive MS Alliance. Mult Scler 2021; 27: 989-1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33720795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalgas U, Hvid LG, Kwakkel G, Motl RW, De Groot V, Feys P, et al. Moving exercise research in multiple sclerosis forward (the MoXFo initiative): developing consensus statements for research. Mult Scler 2020; 26: 1303-1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManaman C, Novak B, Paul L, Rooney S. Changes in walking speed following resistance training in people with multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PM R 2025; 17: 222-237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11826970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39311403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Materne O, Chamari K. Rethinking knee injury prevention strategies: joint-by-joint training approach paradigm versus traditional focused knee strengthening. Biol Sport 2025; 42: 59-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12490306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grange E, Ferriero G, Dileo L, Solaro C. Constraint-induced movement therapy for upper limb rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2022; 58: 497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9980516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34985238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers I, Feys P, Swinnen E. Robot-assisted rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis: Overview of approaches, clinical outcomes, and perspectives. Rehabilitation robotics 2018:253-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabr&#xf2; RS, Russo M, Naro A, De Luca R, Leo A, Tomasello P, et al. Robotic gait training in multiple sclerosis rehabilitation: can virtual reality make the difference? Findings from a randomized controlled trial. J Neurol Sci 2017; 377: 25-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gervasoni E, Parelli R, Uszynski M, Crippa A, Marzegan A, Montesano A, et al. Effects of functional electrical stimulation on reducing falls and improving gait parameters in multiple sclerosis and stroke. PM&amp;R 2017; 9: 339-347. e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27825837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiaravalloti ND, DeLuca J. Cognitive impairment in multiple sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2008; 7: 1139-1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19007738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes C, Howard IM. Spasticity management in multiple sclerosis. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 2013; 24: 593-604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24314678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>