<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41166634</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2162-2388</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IEEE transactions on neural networks and learning systems</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Noise-Tolerant CIM-DNNs Explained.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1005</StartPage><EndPage>1017</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1005-1017</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/TNNLS.2025.3621473</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Compute-in-memory (CIM) systems implemented with resistive random access memory (RRAM) crossbars are a promising approach for accelerating deep neural network (DNN) computations. However, it is noteworthy that RRAM-based CIM systems are susceptible to computational errors. Unlike digital computation, the nature of analog computing introduces the risk of error accumulation throughout the computation process. Various techniques have been proposed to help deal with the errors in CIM systems, among which, training methods to create noise-tolerant CIM-based DNNs (CIM-DNNs) models that are insensitive to weight variations are the most promising due to their simplicity and low implementation cost. Although promising empirical results of variation-aware training (VAT) showcasing DNN models with high tolerance to device nonidealities have been demonstrated, there remains a significant gap in the understanding of noise tolerance properties in VAT-trained CIM-DNNs and how to improve VAT based on these understandings. The exploration of these theoretical aspects represents an area requiring further investigation and research. This work endeavors to explore the fundamental properties of noise tolerance in DNNs for CIM systems. We encapsulate our contributions into three key points. First, we identify factors that influence DNNs' performance when subjected to noise through a series of training experiments. Second, we offer both theoretical insights and practical demonstrations illustrating how VAT operates to yield solutions with heightened resistance to noise during the training process. Finally, leveraging these insights, we provide guidelines for implementing VAT to obtain optimal noise tolerance in CIM-DNNs. Our objective is to establish a theoretical foundation for VAT, and building on these insights, we aim to offer general and straightforward guidelines for DNN training, experimenting with factors such as hyperparameter choices for optimizers and weight clamping. Ultimately, our aim is to contribute to general and practical solutions for the development of reliable CIM systems. Our studies focus on analyzing how noise injection and different optimizers affect the convergence dynamics during training to reach a more noise-tolerant solution through VAT. Future studies could incorporate advanced regularizers reflecting the flatness of the solution into the cost function, which may be necessary for models beyond DNNs studied here. Combined together, these techniques can potentially lead to practical solutions for the development of reliable CIM systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Fan-Hsuan</ForeName><Initials>FH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeu-Jer Lee</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yuting</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ziyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Wei D</ForeName><Initials>WD</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616214</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2162-237X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41166634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2025.3621473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>