<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41269252</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-5241</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Aesthetic plastic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Aesthetic Plast Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Abdominoplasty Specimens as a Practical Training Model for Ultrasound-Guided Gluteal Lipofilling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1890</StartPage><EndPage>1898</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1890-1898</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00266-025-05446-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Gluteal fat grafting (commonly known as the Brazilian Butt Lift, BBL) has surged in popularity over the past decade, but this rise has been marred by safety concerns. Inadvertent intramuscular fat injection during BBL can lead to fat embolism, contributing to a reported mortality rate as high as 1 in 2,351-6,241-making it the deadliest cosmetic procedure. In response, there is growing advocacy for ultrasound guidance during gluteal lipofilling to ensure injections remain in the safer subcutaneous plane. However, practical training models to teach ultrasound-guided gluteal fat grafting are lacking or cost-prohibitive.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We present a practical, cost-free training model for ultrasound-guided gluteal lipofilling using abdominoplasty specimens. This model is designed to simulate the superficial and deep subcutaneous gluteal compartments in an anatomically realistic way, while providing immediate tactile feedback to prevent excessive cannula depth. We compare this abdominoplasty-based training setup to previously described models and highlight its advantages in simplicity, realism, and accessibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Resected abdominal skin-fat specimens from routine abdominoplasty surgeries were repurposed as training phantoms. Each specimen was placed skin-side up on a rigid surface to mimic the underlying gluteal muscle/fascial support. A small skin incision served as the entry point for a blunt cannula, and a wireless ultrasound probe was used externally to visualize cannula placement in real time. No synthetic or animal tissues were added. Trainees practiced advancing the cannula within the specimen's subcutaneous layer under ultrasound guidance, with the rigid base providing an endpoint "stop" if the cannula ventured too deep.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The abdominoplasty tissue model closely replicated the ultrasonic appearance and tactile feel of the gluteal subcutaneous region. Distinct superficial and deep fatty layers were observed on ultrasound, analogous to the gluteal fat compartments. Trainees could readily identify the cannula as a bright echo and steer it within the tissue. When the cannula approached the base (simulating the gluteal fascia plane), a firm resistance was felt upon contact with the rigid surface. This immediate feedback effectively alerted users to excessive depth, reinforcing proper technique. The model required minimal preparation and no additional cost, as tissues were obtained from surgical discard. Participants in trial sessions reported improved coordination between probe and cannula and increased confidence in maintaining a safe injection plane.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The abdominoplasty-based ultrasound training model offers an ethical, accessible platform to develop the skills necessary for safe gluteal fat grafting. It eliminates the costs and logistical barriers associated with cadaver or synthetic models, yet provides realistic anatomy and a built-in safety mechanism. This model can be implemented easily in any body-contouring practice and holds promise for widespread adoption in training programs. By lowering the barrier to hands-on ultrasound practice, it may help accelerate the uptake of ultrasound-guided techniques and ultimately improve the safety profile of gluteal fat grafting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE IV" NlmCategory="METHODS">This journal requires that authors assign a level of evidence to each article. For a full description of these Evidence-Based Medicine ratings, please refer to the Table of Contents or the online Instructions to Authors &#xa0; www.springer.com/00266 .</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature and International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruno</LastName><ForeName>Agostino</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Private practice, Santa Maria di Leuca Clinic, Via Tiberina, 178, 00188, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foti</LastName><ForeName>Riccardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9549-7952</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Rome "Tor Vergata", 00133, Rome, Italy. riccardofoti.md@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Aesthetic Plast Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7701756</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-216X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002081" MajorTopicYN="N">Buttocks</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061645" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abdominoplasty</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018084" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ultrasonography, Interventional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015187" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lipectomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000637" MajorTopicYN="N">transplantation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008953" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Anatomic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominoplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BBL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brazilian Butt Lift</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fat embolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gluteal fat grafting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest to disclose Human Participant or Animal Rights: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals performed by any of the authors. Informed consent: For this type of study informed consent is not required</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41269252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00266-025-05446-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00266-025-05446-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rios L, Gupta V. Improvement in Brazilian butt lift (BBL) safety with the current recommendations from ASERF, ASAPS, and ISAPS. Aesthet Surg J. 2020;40(8):864&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaa098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mofid MM, Teitelbaum S, Suissa D, Ramirez-Monta&#xf1;ana A, Astarita DC, Mendieta C, et al. Report on mortality from gluteal fat grafting: recommendations from the ASERF task force. Aesthet Surg J. 2017;37(7):796&#x2013;806. https://doi.org/10.1093/asj/sjx004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjx004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28369293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5846701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio D, Kenkel JM. Practice advisory on gluteal fat grafting. Aesthet Surg J. 2022;42(9):1019&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1093/asj/sjac082 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjac082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin JP, Walden JL, Lee BT, Van Natta BW, Piccolo N, Blunk T, et al. Statement on patient safety during gluteal fat grafting endorsed by the International Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery (ISAPS), American Society of Plastic Surgeons (ASPS), the Aesthetic Society, the Plastic Surgery Foundation (PSF), the Aesthetic Surgery Education and Research Foundation (ASERF), the International Society of Plastic Regenerative Surgeons (ISPRES), the International Federation for Adipose Therapeutics and Science (IFATS) and. Aesthet Plast Surg. 2023;47(2):894&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00266-023-03282-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00266-023-03282-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidal-Laureano N, Huerta CT, Perez EA, Earle SA. Augmented safety profile of ultrasound-guided gluteal fat transfer: retrospective study with 1815 patients. Aesthet Surg J. 2024;44(4):NP263&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1093/asj/sjad377 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjad377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38124368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein ER, Pazmi&#xf1;o P, Garcia O Jr. A clinically relevant model for hands-on training in ultrasound-guided gluteal fat grafting: the Miami butt model. Aesthet Surg J. 2025;45(8):821&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1093/asj/sjaf065 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjaf065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40337909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12260375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazmi&#xf1;o P. Ultrasound-guided gluteal fat grafting: a to Z. Clin Plast Surg. 2023;50(4):587&#x2013;601. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cps.2023.07.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cps.2023.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37704326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>