<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41322937</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Physical Therapy on Empowering Neurological Aging: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95640</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e95640</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e95640</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.95640</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aging is an inevitable biological process that is frequently accompanied by neurological decline, which profoundly impacts gait, balance, and the ability to perform activities of daily living. Physical therapy (PT) plays a pivotal role in mitigating these deficits by enhancing mobility, strength, and independence through evidence-based interventions like resistance training, balance exercises, and functional mobility programs. This narrative review synthesizes current evidence on PT's effectiveness in managing age-related neurological changes, emphasizing its integration within interdisciplinary teams and the use of innovative technologies such as exoskeletons, telerehabilitation, and brain-computer interfaces. A combination of specific keywords and Boolean operators was utilized to identify peer-reviewed studies on the databases PubMed, Google Scholar, and ScienceDirect, focusing on the impact of PT in empowering neurological aging. PT encourages active engagement and enhances the quality of life for elderly people with neurological disorders. With an aging population, the demand for PT services is expected to continue rising, underscoring the importance of adequate resources and specialized training programs in this profession. Despite robust evidence supporting the benefits of PT, gaps persist in understanding its long-term efficacy, optimal intervention dosing, and the integration of emerging technologies into routine practice. Challenges such as limited access to specialized services and insufficient data on cost-effectiveness and patient adherence further complicate the delivery of care. This review advocates for future research to refine PT strategies, enhance interdisciplinary collaboration, and leverage technological advancements to optimize outcomes for older adults with neurological conditions, ultimately promoting successful aging and sustained independence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Baladaniya et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baladaniya</LastName><ForeName>Maheshkumar</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Neighborhood Physical Therapy PC, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baldania</LastName><ForeName>Shraddha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Enjoy Rehab PT PC, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gandhi</LastName><ForeName>Nensi V</ForeName><Initials>NV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physiotherapy, Sumandeep Vidyapeeth Deemed to be University, Vadodara, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hait</LastName><ForeName>Anamitra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, KG Hospital, Chittaranjan, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">daily living activities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation telerehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41322937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12661250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.95640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The aging mind: vascular health in normal cognitive aging. Warsch JR, Wright CB. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:0&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of gait disorders in community-residing older adults. Verghese J, LeValley A, Hall CB, Katz MJ, Ambrose AF, Lipton RB. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2006;54:255&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1403740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16460376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise for sarcopenia in older people: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Shen Y, Shi Q, Nong K, et al. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2023;14:1199&#x2013;1211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10235889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37057640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global status report on neurology.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240116139 https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240116139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimizing exoskeleton assistance to improve walking speed and energy economy for older adults. Lakmazaheri A, Song S, Vuong BB, Biskner B, Kado DM, Collins SH. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2024;21:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38167151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic review of the effects of interactive telerehabilitation with remote monitoring and guidance on balance and gait performance in older adults and individuals with neurological conditions. Park C, Lee BC. Bioengineering (Basel) 2024;11:460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11117498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38790328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gait and cognitive impairments in multiple sclerosis: the specific contribution of falls and fear of falling. Kalron A, Allali G. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2017;124:1407&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early supported discharge services for people with acute stroke. Langhorne P, Baylan S. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28703869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. BMJ. 2021;372:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SANRA&#x2014;a scale for the quality assessment of narrative review articles. Baethge C, Goldbeck-Wood S, Mertens S. Res Integr Peer Rev. 2019;4:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6434870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30962953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Structure-function interactions in the hippocampus and prefrontal cortex are associated with episodic memory in healthy aging. Snytte J, Setton R, Mwilambwe-Tshilobo L, Natasha Rajah M, Sheldon S, Turner GR, Spreng RN. eNeuro. 2024;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10972739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38479810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Normal aging induces changes in the brain and neurodegeneration progress: review of the structural, biochemical, metabolic, cellular, and molecular changes. Lee J, Kim HJ. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:931536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35847660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and neuroplasticity in neurodegenerative disorders: a comprehensive review of exercise interventions, cognitive training, and AI applications. Ben Ezzdine L, Dhahbi W, Dergaa I, et al. Front Neurosci. 2025;19:1502417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11906675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40092068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurogenesis in aging and age-related neurodegenerative diseases. Culig L, Chu X, Bohr VA. Ageing Res Rev. 2022;78:101636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35490966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurodegenerative disorders: mechanisms of degeneration and therapeutic approaches with their clinical relevance. Gadhave DG, Sugandhi VV, Jha SK, et al. Ageing Res Rev. 2024;99:102357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heavy strength training in older adults: implications for health, disease and physical performance. T&#xf8;ien T, Berg OK, Modena R, Brobakken MF, Wang E. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2025;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40241440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson's disease: etiopathogenesis and treatment. Jankovic J, Tan EK. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:795&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical therapy for neurological conditions in geriatric populations. Carmeli E. Front Public Health. 2017;5:333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5725432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Sidhu J, Lui F, Tsao JW. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Alzheimer disease.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29763097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing the efficacy of physical therapy interventions in Alzheimer's disease: a network meta-analysis. Wu J, Teng Y, Xie Y, Xing S, Zhi S. Front Aging Neurosci. 2025;17:1541287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11919892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ischaemic stroke. Campbell BC, De Silva DA, Macleod MR, Coutts SB, Schwamm LH, Davis SM, Donnan GA. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2019;5:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31601801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing the impact of multidisciplinary collaboration on quality of life in older patients receiving primary care: cross sectional study. Albarqi MN. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11240966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38998793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The burden of spinal disorders in the elderly. Waldrop R, Cheng J, Devin C, McGirt M, Fehlings M, Berven S. Neurosurgery. 2015;77 Suppl 4:0&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of therapeutic aquatic exercise vs physical therapy modalities for patients with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. Peng MS, Wang R, Wang YZ, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34994794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Late-onset epilepsy and subsequent increased risk of dementia. Tsai ZR, Zhang HW, Tseng CH, et al. Aging (Albany NY) 2021;13:3573&#x2013;3587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33429365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Masrori P, Van Damme P. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:1918&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of respiratory muscle training in improving pulmonary function and survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Benzo-Iglesias MJ, Rocamora-P&#xe9;rez P, Valverde-Mart&#xed;nez ML&#xc1;, Garc&#xed;a-Luengo AV, Benzo-Iglesias PM, L&#xf3;pez-Liria R. Ther Adv Respir Dis. 2025;19:17534666251346095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12149620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40488544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafti D, Ehsan M, Xixis KL. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Multiple sclerosis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29763024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interdisciplinary teamworking in rehabilitation: experiences of change initiators in a national rehabilitation hospital. Christophers L, Torok Z, Trayer A, Hong GC, Carroll A. BMC Health Serv Res. 2025;25:651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12057162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40329284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peripheral neuropathy, an independent risk factor for falls in the elderly, impairs stepping as a postural control mechanism: a case-cohort study. Kohle F, Stark C, Kl&#xfc;nter HD, et al. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2024;29:453&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11625983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39219364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aging-related protein alterations in the brain. Syed RA, Hayat M, Qaiser H, et al. J Alzheimers Dis. 2024;99:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38339930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falls caused by balance disorders in the elderly with multiple systems involved: pathogenic mechanisms and treatment strategies. Xing L, Bao Y, Wang B, et al. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1128092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9996061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36908603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gait disturbances in old age: classification, diagnosis, and treatment from a neurological perspective. Jahn K, Zwergal A, Schniepp R. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2010;107:306&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2872829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20490346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postural control in elderly subjects. Pyykk&#xf6; I, J&#xe4;ntti P, Aalto H. Age Ageing. 1990;19:215&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2363386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray K, Aquino N, Nugent J. Acquired Brain Injury. Cham: Springer; 2019. The role of the physical therapist on the neuro-rehabilitation team.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gait disorders in adults and the elderly: a&#xa0;clinical guide. Pirker W, Katzenschlager R. Wien Klin Wochenschr. 2017;129:81&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5318488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27770207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balance and gait in the elderly: a contemporary review. Osoba MY, Rao AK, Agrawal SK, Lalwani AK. Laryngoscope Investig Otolaryngol. 2019;4:143&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6383322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of a gait and balance training program on an unstable mudflats surface in older adults: a randomized controlled pilot study. Lee J, Chun MH, Lee J. Medicine (Baltimore) 2023;102:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10036031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36961156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of balance training using a virtual-reality system in older fallers. Duque G, Boersma D, Loza-Diaz G, et al. Clin Interv Aging. 2013;8:257&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23467506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can resistance training improve mental health outcomes in older adults? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cunha PM, Werneck AO, Santos LD, Oliveira MD, Zou L, Schuch FB, Cyrino ES. Psychiatry Res. 2024;333:115746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38281452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integration of balance and strength training into daily life activity to reduce rate of falls in older people (the LiFE study): randomised parallel trial. Clemson L, Fiatarone Singh MA, Bundy A, Cumming RG, Manollaras K, O'Loughlin P, Black D. BMJ. 2012;345:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3413733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22872695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring the impact of physiotherapy on health outcomes in older adults with chronic diseases: a cross-sectional analysis. Reddy RS, Alahmari KA, Alshahrani MS, et al. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1415882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11416960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39314794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of resistance training in healthy older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Chen N, He X, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2021;18:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8588688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multicomponent physical exercise with simultaneous cognitive training to enhance dual-task walking of older adults: a secondary analysis of a 6-month randomized controlled trial with 1-year follow-up. Eggenberger P, Theill N, Holenstein S, Schumacher V, de Bruin ED. Clin Interv Aging. 2015;10:1711&#x2013;1732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4631411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resistance training for activity limitations in older adults with skeletal muscle function deficits: a systematic review. Papa EV, Dong X, Hassan M. Clin Interv Aging. 2017;12:955&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28670114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of rehabilitative exercises on swallowing function in elderly people: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Dehaghani SE, Bakhtiyari J, Salmani M, Shahabi S, Tahooneh A, Azkhosh M. Middle East J Rehabil Health Stud. 2023;10:130196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of balance training on postural control in people with multiple sclerosis using the CAREN virtual reality system: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Kalron A, Fonkatz I, Frid L, Baransi H, Achiron A. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2016;13:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26925955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and exercise recommendations for stroke survivors: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Billinger SA, Arena R, Bernhardt J, et al. Stroke. 2014;45:2532&#x2013;2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of sensor-based interventions in improving gait and balance performance in older adults: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Mao Q, Zhang J, Yu L, Zhao Y, Luximon Y, Wang H. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2024;21:85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11131332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38807117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strength gains after 12&#xa0;weeks of resistance training correlate with neurochemical markers of brain health in older adults: a randomized control 1H-MRS study. Sheoran S, Vints WA, Valatkevi&#x10d;ien&#x117; K, et al. Geroscience. 2023;45:1837&#x2013;1855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36701005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity intervention for the prevention of neurological diseases. Kantawala B, Ramadan N, Hassan Y, et al. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10442603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37614284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speech-language pathology approaches to neurorehabilitation in acute care during COVID-19: capitalizing on neuroplasticity. Langton-Frost N, Brodsky MB. PM R. 2022;14:217&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34595841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dysphagia after stroke: an overview. Gonz&#xe1;lez-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ottenstein L, Atanelov L, Christian AB. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2013;1:187&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4066736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24977109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dysphagia in Parkinson disease: part I - pathophysiology and diagnostic practices. Rudisch DM, Krasko MN, Burdick R, Broadfoot CK, Rogus-Pulia N, Ciucci MR. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2023;11:176&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10441627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37608845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: is there an association or a red flag? A case report and literature review. Aljthalin R, Albalawi R, Alyahya A, Alhathlool R, Alhashemi M. BMC Neurol. 2024;24:307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11365120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39217293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voice meets swallowing: a scoping review of therapeutic connections. Castillo-Allendes A, Searl J, Vergara J, Ballentine N, Ebdah S, Rameau A, Hunter EJ. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2025;34:877&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11903005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39772835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation of airway protection in individuals with movement disorders: a telehealth feasibility study. Sevitz JS, Borders JC, Dakin AE, Kiefer BR, Alcalay RN, Kuo SH, Troche MS. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2022;31:2741&#x2013;2758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9911128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36279509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interdisciplinary teamwork in the community rehabilitation of older adults: an example of flexible working in primary care. Griffiths J, Austin L, Luker K. Prim Health Care Res Dev. 2004;5:228&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for the prevention of stroke in patients with stroke and transient ischemic attack: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Kernan WN, Ovbiagele B, Black HR, et al. Stroke. 2014;45:2160&#x2013;2236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroke survivors' experiences of physical rehabilitation: a systematic review of qualitative studies. Luker J, Lynch E, Bernhardsson S, Bennett L, Bernhardt J. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;96:1698&#x2013;1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25847387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motivational strategies for stroke rehabilitation: a descriptive cross-sectional study. Oyake K, Suzuki M, Otaka Y, Tanaka S. Front Neurol. 2020;11:553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7297944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32587572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring client-centered care experiences in in-patient rehabilitation settings. Bamm EL, Rosenbaum P, Wilkins S, Stratford P, Mahlberg N. Glob Qual Nurs Res. 2015;2:2333393615582036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5342279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28462306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goal setting and strategies to enhance goal pursuit for adults with acquired disability participating in rehabilitation. Levack WM, Weatherall M, Hay-Smith EJ, Dean SG, McPherson K, Siegert RJ. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26189709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical therapists use different motivational strategies for stroke rehabilitation tailored to an individual's condition: a qualitative study. Oyake K, Sue K, Sumiya M, Tanaka S. Phys Ther. 2023;103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37017336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motivational strategies for stroke rehabilitation: a&#xa0;Delphi study. Oyake K, Suzuki M, Otaka Y, Momose K, Tanaka S. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2020;101:1929&#x2013;1936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The clinical use of quality-of-life scales in neurological disorders. Corallo F, De Luca R, Leonardi R, De Salvo S, Bramanti P, Marino S. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2013;25:193&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of neuropalliative care on quality of life and satisfaction with quality of care in patients with progressive neurological disease and their family caregivers: an interventional control study. Bu&#x17e;gov&#xe1; R, Koz&#xe1;kov&#xe1; R, Bar M. BMC Palliat Care. 2020;19:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7495890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fostering well-being in the elderly: translating theories on positive aging to practical approaches. Bar-Tur L. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:517226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8062922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A literature review of high-tech physiotherapy interventions in the elderly with neurological disorders. Spanakis M, Xylouri I, Patelarou E, Patelarou A. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:9233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Challenges and opportunities for the future of brain-computer interface in neurorehabilitation. Simon C, Bolton DA, Kennedy NC, Soekadar SR, Ruddy KL. Front Neurosci. 2021;15:699428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8282929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34276299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain-actuated functional electrical stimulation elicits lasting arm motor recovery after stroke. Biasiucci A, Leeb R, Iturrate I, et al. Nat Commun. 2018;9:2421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robotic gait training in multiple sclerosis rehabilitation: can virtual reality make the difference? Findings from a randomized controlled trial. Calabr&#xf2; RS, Russo M, Naro A, et al. J Neurol Sci. 2017;377:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digital technology enablers of tele-neurorehabilitation in pre- and post-COVID-19 pandemic era - a scoping review. Uddin M, Ganapathy K, Syed-Abdul S. Int J Telerehabil. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11250154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39022438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>