<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917019</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Wastewater surveillance reveals patterns of antibiotic resistance across the United States.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-71195-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antibiotic resistance is a growing public health threat, with over 2.8 million antibiotic-resistant infections and 35,000 attributable deaths annually in the U.S. Here, we sought to use wastewater monitoring to assess community-level burden of antibiotic resistance. This study quantifies concentrations of antibiotic resistance genes (ARGs) by digital droplet PCR in wastewater solids obtained from 163 wastewater treatment plants in 40 states in the United States. We measure 11 ARGs that confer resistance to beta-lactams (bla<sub>CMY</sub>, bla<sub>CTX-M</sub>, bla<sub>KPC</sub>, bla<sub>NDM</sub>, bla<sub>OXA-48</sub>, bla<sub>TEM</sub>, bla<sub>VIM</sub>), colistin (mcr-1), methicillin (mecA),&#xa0;tetracycline (tetW), and vancomycin (vanA). The South has higher overall ARG concentrations compared to the Midwest. We pair these data with national data sets including antibiotic use, social vulnerability, size of animal agriculture operations, location of healthcare facilities, and presence of airports to investigate potential drivers of resistance. We also generate predictive maps of ARG concentrations for counties with data within the range of our training set in the United States. We show social vulnerability indicators (housing burden and access to health insurance) and indicators of international travel are associated with increased ARG concentrations in wastewater, while antibiotic usage is only weakly positively associated. Our results provide a national baseline of ARG concentrations and highlight the complexity of factors driving spread of antibiotic resistance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sooyeol</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3321-7241</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of California, Berkeley, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulli</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Elana M G</ForeName><Initials>EMG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7238-6833</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duong</LastName><ForeName>Dorothea</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Verily Life Sciences, South San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Linfield</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca Y</ForeName><Initials>RY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8079-700X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases and Geographic Medicine, Department of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCormack</LastName><ForeName>Caroline E M</ForeName><Initials>CEM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-4917-8836</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of California, Berkeley, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>Bradley J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6444-4159</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Verily Life Sciences, South San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Google LLC, Mountain View, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolfe</LastName><ForeName>Marlene K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gangarosa Department of Environmental Health, Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boehm</LastName><ForeName>Alexandria B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8162-5090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pickering</LastName><ForeName>Amy J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6193-2221</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of California, Berkeley, CA, USA. pickering@berkeley.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biohub, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA. pickering@berkeley.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blum Center for Developing Economies, University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA, USA. pickering@berkeley.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-71195-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-71195-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>U. S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Antimicrobial Resistance Threats in the United States, 2021-2022. https://www.cdc.gov/antimicrobial-resistance/data-research/threats/update-2022.html (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (U.S.). Antibiotic Resistance Threats in the United States, 2019. https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/82532, https://doi.org/10.15620/cdc:82532 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes, A. H. et al. Understanding the mechanisms and drivers of antimicrobial resistance. Lancet 387, 176&#x2013;187 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriksen, R. S. et al. Global monitoring of antimicrobial resistance based on metagenomics analyses of urban sewage. Nat. Commun. 10, 1124 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collignon, P., Beggs, J. J., Walsh, T. R., Gandra, S. &amp; Laxminarayan, R. Anthropological and socioeconomic factors contributing to global antimicrobial resistance: a univariate and multivariable analysis. Lancet Planet Health 2, E398&#x2013;E405 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, S., Wu, X., Pruden, A., Zhang, L. &amp; Vikesland, P. Global scale exploration of human faecal and sewage resistomes as a function of socio-economic status. Nat. Water 2, 975&#x2013;987 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. et al. Longitudinal monitoring of sewershed resistomes in socioeconomically diverse urban neighborhoods. Commun. Med. 5, 7 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar, S., Turbett, S. E., Harris, J. B. &amp; LaRocque, R. C. Antimicrobial-resistant bacteria in international travelers. Curr. Opin. Infect. Dis. 34, 423&#x2013;431 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost, I., Van Boeckel, T. P., Pires, J., Craig, J. &amp; Laxminarayan, R. Global geographic trends in antimicrobial resistance: the role of international travel. J. Travel Med. 26, taz036 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conforti, S. et al. Strengthening policy relevance of wastewater-based surveillance for antimicrobial resistance. Environ. Sci. Technol. 59, 2339&#x2013;2343 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munk, P. et al. Genomic analysis of sewage from 101 countries reveals global landscape of antimicrobial resistance. Nat. Commun. 13, 7251 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto Riquelme, M. V. et al. Demonstrating a comprehensive wastewater-based surveillance approach that differentiates globally sourced resistomes. Environ. Sci. Technol. 56, 14982&#x2013;14993 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington, A. et al. Urban monitoring of antimicrobial resistance during a COVID-19 surge through wastewater surveillance. Sci. Total Environ. 853, 158577 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, A. et al. &#x3b2;-lactam resistance genes in bacteriophage and bacterial DNA from wastewater, river water, and irrigation water in Washington State. Water Res. 161, 335&#x2013;340 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph, S. M., Battaglia, T., Maritz, J. M., Carlton, J. M. &amp; Blaser, M. J. Longitudinal comparison of bacterial diversity and antibiotic resistance genes in New York City sewage. mSystems. 4, e00327&#x2013;19 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestre-Carballa, L., Navarro-L&#xf3;pez, V. &amp; Martinez-Garcia, M. City-scale monitoring of antibiotic resistance genes by digital PCR and metagenomics. Environ. Microbiome. 19, 16 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight, M. E. et al. National-scale antimicrobial resistance surveillance in wastewater: A comparative analysis of HT qPCR and metagenomic approaches. Water Res. 262, 121989 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, B. C., Vikesland, P. J. &amp; Pruden, A. Evaluating quantitative metagenomics for environmental monitoring of antibiotic resistance and establishing detection limits. Environ. Sci. Technol. acs.est.4c08284 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c08284 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, L. N. et al. Socioeconomic disparities and the prevalence of antimicrobial resistance. Clin. Infect. Dis. 79, 1346&#x2013;1353 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See, I. et al. Socioeconomic factors explain racial disparities in invasive community-associated methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus disease rates. Clin. Infect. Dis. 64, 597&#x2013;604 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreatos, N., Shehadeh, F., Pliakos, E. E. &amp; Mylonakis, E. The impact of antibiotic prescription rates on the incidence of MRSA bloodstream infections: a county-level, US-wide analysis. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents 52, 195&#x2013;200 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetgeluck, C. et al. Using wastewater surveillance to investigate community-level differences in antibacterial resistance in a major urban center, USA. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 91, e01684-25 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadimpalli, M. L., Chan, C. W. &amp; Doron, S. Antibiotic resistance: a call to action to prevent the next epidemic of inequality. Nat. Med. 27, 187&#x2013;188 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcilla, M. S. et al. Import and spread of extended-spectrum &#x3b2;-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae by international travellers (COMBAT study): a prospective, multicentre cohort study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 17, 78&#x2013;85 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar, S. et al. Insights into global antimicrobial resistance dynamics through the sequencing of enteric bacteria from U.S. international travelers. J. Infect. Dis. 33, e164&#x2013;e173 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macias, E. P. &amp; Morales, L. S. Crossing the border for health care. J. Health Care Poor Underserved 12, 77&#x2013;87 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbett, K. et al. Appropriate antibiotic use: variation in knowledge and awareness by Hispanic ethnicity and language. Prev. Med. 40, 162&#x2013;169 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkes, B. A. et al. Healthcare system distrust and non-prescription antibiotic use: a cross-sectional survey of adult antibiotic users. Antibiotics. 12, 79 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoorob, R., Grigoryan, L., Nash, S. &amp; Trautner, B. W. Nonprescription antimicrobial use in a primary care population in the United States. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 60, 5527&#x2013;5532 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caneschi, A., Bardhi, A., Barbarossa, A. &amp; Zaghini, A. The use of antibiotics and antimicrobial resistance in veterinary medicine, a complex phenomenon: a narrative review. Antibiotics. 12, 487 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mundkur, M. L. et al. Changes in outpatient use of antibiotics by adults in the United States, 2006&#x2013;2015. Drug Saf. 41, 1333&#x2013;1342 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grigoryan, L. et al. Use of antibiotics without a prescription in the U.S. population: a scoping review. Ann. Intern. Med. 171, 257&#x2013;263 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Han, Y., Li, L., Liu, J. &amp; Yan, X. Distribution, sources, and potential risks of antibiotic resistance genes in wastewater treatment plant: a review. Environ. Pollut. 310, 119870 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Chu, L., Wojn&#xe1;rovits, L. &amp; Tak&#xe1;cs, E. Occurrence and fate of antibiotics, antibiotic resistant genes (ARGs) and antibiotic resistant bacteria (ARB) in municipal wastewater treatment plant: An overview. Sci. Total Environ. 744, 140997 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner, E. et al. Metagenomic profiling of internationally sourced sewage influents and effluents yields insight into selecting targets for antibiotic resistance monitoring. Environ. Sci. Technol. 58, 16547&#x2013;16559 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda, R. et al. Transition of antimicrobial resistome in wastewater treatment plants: impact of process configuration, geographical location and season. Npj Clean. Water 6, 46 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares, R. D. S., Fidalgo, C., Rodrigues, E. T., Tac&#xe3;o, M. &amp; Henriques, I. Integron-associated genes are reliable indicators of antibiotic resistance in wastewater despite treatment- and seasonality-driven fluctuations. Water Res. 258, 121784 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao, Y.-N. et al. Biomarkers of antibiotic resistance genes during seasonal changes in wastewater treatment systems. Environ. Pollut. 234, 79&#x2013;87 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caucci, S. et al. Seasonality of antibiotic prescriptions for outpatients and resistance genes in sewers and wastewater treatment plant outflow. FEMS Microbiol. Ecol. 92, fiw060 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, C. L. et al. Metagenomics disentangles epidemiological and microbial ecological associations between community antibiotic use and antibiotic resistance indicators measured in sewage. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.11.24318846 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikesland, P. et al. Can wastewater-based surveillance relate antimicrobial use to resistance patterns? Metagenomic analysis of two neighboring treatment plants. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4420801/v1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. et al. Solid evidence and liquid gold: trade-offs of processing settled solids, whole influent, or centrifuged influent for codetecting viral, bacterial, and eukaryotic pathogens in wastewater. Environ. Sci. Technol. 59, 16240&#x2013;16249 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm, A. B. et al. Human viral nucleic acids concentrations in wastewater solids from Central and Coastal California USA. Sci. Data 10, 396 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman, J. S. et al. Wastewater-based estimation of the effective reproductive number of SARS-CoV-2. Environ. Health Perspect. 130, 057011 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topol, A. et al. High Throughput RNA Extraction and PCR Inhibitor Removal of Settled Solids for Wastewater Surveillance of SARS-CoV-2 RNA V.2. protocols.io https://doi.org/10.17504/protocols.io.b2mkqc4w (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchardt, M. A. et al. The environmental microbiology minimum information (EMMI) guidelines: qPCR and dPCR quality and reporting for environmental microbiology. Environ. Sci. Technol. 55, 10210&#x2013;10223 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esri Data and Maps. USA ZIP Code Boundaries. https://www.arcgis.com/home/item.html?id=d6f7ee6129e241cc9b6f75978e47128b (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Social Vulnerability Index 2022. https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/place-health/php/svi/svi-data-documentation-download.html?CDC_AAref_Val=https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/placeandhealth/svi/data_documentation_download.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. 2022 5-Year American Community Survey (ACS). https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/acs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. 2020 Census Urban-Rural Classification. https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/geography/guidance/geo-areas/urban-rural.html (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Homeland Security. Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data. https://hifld-geoplatform.hub.arcgis.com/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esri Data and Maps. USA Airports 1,000,000 or more. https://hub.arcgis.com/datasets/esri::usa-airports/about?layer=1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Agriculture. 2022 National Agricultural Statistics Service Quick Stats. https://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epic Systems Corporation. About Epic Cosmos. https://cosmos.epic.com/about/ (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarabichi, Y. et al. The cosmos collaborative: a vendor-facilitated electronic health record data aggregation platform. ACI Open 05, e36&#x2013;e46 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mankowski, M. A. et al. Generalizability of kidney transplant data in electronic health records&#x2014;the Epic Cosmos Database vs the Scientific Registry of Transplant Recipients. Am. J. Transplant. 25, 744&#x2013;755 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantor, R. S. et al. Operationalizing a routine wastewater monitoring laboratory for SARS-CoV-2. PLoS Water. 1, e0000007 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenum, I. et al. A framework for standardized qPCR-targets and protocols for quantifying antibiotic resistance in surface water, recycled water and wastewater. Crit. Rev. Environ. Sci. Technol. 52, 4395&#x2013;4419 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, X. et al. Toward a universal unit for quantification of antibiotic resistance genes in environmental samples. Environ. Sci. Technol. 57, 9713&#x2013;9721 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biau, G. Analysis of a random forests model. J. Mach. Learn. Res. 13, 1063&#x2013;1095 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genuer, R., Poggi, J.-M. &amp; Tuleau, C. Random Forests: some methodological insights. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.48550/ARXIV.0811.3619 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhn, M. Building Predictive Models in R Using the caret Package. J. Stat. Softw. 28, (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S., Chan, E. M. G. &amp; Zulli, A. Wastewater surveillance reveals patterns of antibiotic resistance across the United States. Zenodo https://doi.org/10.5281/ZENODO.18749049 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. Cartographic Boundary Files. https://www.census.gov/geographies/mapping-files/time-series/geo/cartographic-boundary.html (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>