<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41328271</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2352-8273</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SSM - population health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SSM Popul Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mapping war trauma: A machine learning approach to predict mental health impacts in Ukraine.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101879</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101879</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101879</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ssmph.2025.101879</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper presents a predictive modeling system based on the use of GeoAI to estimate mental health outcomes of wartime in Ukrainian cities, utilizing spatially linked data on the environment, infrastructure, and conflict. Six self-reported psychological outcomes, symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder, or PSD, anxiety, depression, insomnia, loneliness, and sleep duration, were collected in surveys throughout the war and analyzed in the context of more than 30 spatial predictors: cold exposure, access to heating, power outages, housing insulation, and city-level frequency of drone, missile, artillery, and shelling attacks. Predictor datasets that are derived from incident tracking, World Health Organization, and humanitarian reporting systems, and environmental indicators derived from surveys, which are harmonized using a spatial data integration protocol. In realizing the GeoAI concept, we developed a machine learning pipeline utilizing Ordinary Least Squares, Lasso, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, and Extreme Gradient Boosting. All models were trained and tested on spatially independent training and testing splits in order to preserve the generalization properties of the models. XG Boost is also shown to be effective, with R2 values often exceeding 0.74 and MAPE values typically less than 7.2&#xa0;%. Feature importance analysis revealed that key drivers of being exposed to prolonged cold, inadequate insulation, and exposure to drones or artillery were found to be dominant drivers of psychological distress. This GeoAI framework combines the strength of geospatial analytics with artificial intelligence to give precise and high-resolution location-based forecasting of mental health burdens in conflict settings. The method offers a flexible tool for a proactive humanitarian response that can target mental health services spatially based on predictions of mental health vulnerability, in contrast to retrospective clinical information, for relief agencies and public health planners. This work is a step towards incorporating GeoAI in the field of crisis epidemiology, demonstrating the ability to use GeoAI in real-time, place-based mental health planning in war-affected areas.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tayebi</LastName><ForeName>Safiyeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, 54 Joyce Kilmer, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sert Oti</LastName><ForeName>Ayse</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Informatics, Rutgers Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy, Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey, 33 Livingston Ave, New Brunswick, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathollahian</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electronic Visualization Laboratory (EVL), Department of Computer Science, University of Illinois Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haque</LastName><ForeName>Ubydul</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rutgers Global Health Institute, New Brunswick, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Epidemiology, School of Public Health, Rutgers University, Piscataway, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SSM Popul Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101678841</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2352-8273</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental stressors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GeoAI (geospatial artificial intelligence)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wartime mental health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41328271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12664983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmph.2025.101879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2352-8273(25)00133-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abay K.A., Abay M.H., Berhane G., Chamberlin J., Croke K., Tafere K. Access to health services, food, and water during an active conflict: Evidence from Ethiopia. PLOS Global Public Health. 2022;2(11) doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0001015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0001015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Juboori R. Violence and child mental health outcomes in Iraq: Mapping vulnerable areas. Psychiatry International. 2024;5(1):39&#x2013;52. doi: 10.3390/psychiatryint5010004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/psychiatryint5010004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemi Q., Panter-Brick C., Oriya S., Ahmady M., Alimi A.Q., Faiz H., Hakim N., Sami Hashemi S.A., Manaly M.A., Naseri R., Parwiz K., Sadat S.J., Sharifi M.Z., Shinwari Z., Ahmadi S.J., Amin R., Azimi S., Hewad A., Musavi Z.&#x2026;Ventevogel P. Afghan mental health and psychosocial well-being: Thematic review of four decades of research and interventions. BJPsych Open. 2023;9(4) doi: 10.1192/bjo.2023.502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjo.2023.502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10375890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37424447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhariri W., Mcnally A., Knuckey S. 2021. J U N E 2 0 2 1 the right to Mental Health in Yemen: A distressed and Ignored Foundation for peace.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34194200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audi M.N., Mwenda K.M., Wei G., Lurie M.N. Healthcare accessibility in preconflict Syria: A comparative spatial analysis. BMJ Open. 2022;12(5) doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9073410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35508340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin Z.E., Ozturk Z.K. Performance analysis of XGBoost classifier with missing data. 2021. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/350135431</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya J. LASSO Regression-A procedural improvement. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13140/RG.2.2.17732.13444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigabo F., Biracyaza E., Kanazayire C., Kangabe J., Gishoma D. Reconciliation villages in post-genocide Rwanda, beyond rhetoric to practical reconciliation and psychosocial reintegration. Discover Social Science and Health. 2025;5(1) doi: 10.1007/s44155-025-00201-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44155-025-00201-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnell L.N. 2017. Nonlinear relationships between the environment and health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulesteix A.L., Janitza S., Kruppa J., K&#xf6;nig I.R. Overview of random forest methodology and practical guidance with emphasis on computational biology and bioinformatics. Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery. 2012;2(6):493&#x2013;507. doi: 10.1002/widm.1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/widm.1072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantelmi R., Di Gravio G., Patriarca R. Reviewing qualitative research approaches in the context of critical infrastructure resilience. Environment Systems and Decisions. 2021;41(3):341&#x2013;376. doi: 10.1007/s10669-020-09795-8. Springer.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10669-020-09795-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpiniello B. The mental health costs of armed Conflicts&#x2014;A review of systematic reviews conducted on refugees, asylum-seekers and people living in War zones. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2023;20(4) doi: 10.3390/ijerph20042840. MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20042840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9957523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlson F., Van Ommeren M., Flaxman A., Cornett J., Whiteford H., Saxena S. New WHO prevalence estimates of mental disorders in conflict settings: A systematic review and meta-analysis. The Lance. 2019 doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30934-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30934-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Guestrin C. Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining. 2016. XGBoost: A scalable tree boosting system; pp. 785&#x2013;794. 13-17-August-2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/2939672.2939785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosic K., Kopilas V., Jovanovic T. War, emotions, mental health, and artificial intelligence. Frontiers in Psychology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1394045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1394045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11327060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39156807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan De Perez E., Van Den Hurk B., Van Aalst M.K., Jongman B., Klose T., Suarez P. Forecast-based financing: An approach for catalyzing humanitarian action based on extreme weather and climate forecasts. Natural Hazards and Earth System Sciences. 2015;15(4):895&#x2013;904. doi: 10.5194/nhess-15-895-2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/nhess-15-895-2015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirdelen T., Tekin P., Aksu I.O., Ekinci F. The prediction model of characteristics for wind turbines based on meteorological properties using neural network swarm intelligence. Sustainability. 2019;11(17) doi: 10.3390/su11174803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su11174803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exenberger S., Steidl A., Kamara A., Huber A. Exploring posttraumatic growth in Sierra Leone using mixed methods. Journal of Happiness Studies. 2022;23(2):689&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1007/s10902-021-00419-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10902-021-00419-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber K., Fox C., Abdalla M., Tatem A., Qirbi N., Lloyd-Braff L., Al-Shabi K., Ongwae K., Dyson M., Hassen K. Estimating access to health care in Yemen, a complex humanitarian emergency setting: A descriptive applied geospatial analysis. Lancet Global Health. 2020;8(11):e1435&#x2013;e1443. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(20)30359-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(20)30359-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregg Greenough P., Nelson E.L. Beyond mapping: A case for geospatial analytics in humanitarian health. Conflict and Health. 2019;13(1) doi: 10.1186/s13031-019-0234-9. BioMed Central Ltd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13031-019-0234-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31719842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haar R., Sirkin S. 2022. Strengthening data to protect healthcare in conflict zones.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan G., Ventevogel P., Jefee-Bahloul H., Barkil-Oteo A., Kirmayer L.J. Mental health and psychosocial wellbeing of Syrians affected by armed conflict. Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences. 2016;25(2):129&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1017/S2045796016000044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796016000044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6998596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q., Jin G., Xiong X., Ye H., Xie Y. Monitoring urban change in conflict from the perspective of optical and SAR satellites: The case of mariupol, a City in the conflict between RUS and UKR. Remote Sensing. 2023;15(12) doi: 10.3390/rs15123096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15123096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim M. Evolution of random Forest from decision tree and bagging: A bias-variance perspective. Dhaka University Journal of Applied Science and Engineering. 2023;7(1):66&#x2013;71. doi: 10.3329/dujase.v7i1.62888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/dujase.v7i1.62888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayasinghe S. The 12 dimensions of health impacts of war (the 12-D framework): A novel framework to conceptualise impacts of war on social and environmental determinants of health and public health. BMJ Global Health. 2024;9(5) doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-014749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2023-014749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38777392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakaje A., Al Zohbi R., Hosam Aldeen O., Makki L., Alyousbashi A., Alhaffar M.B.A. Mental disorder and PTSD in Syria during wartime: A nationwide crisis. BMC Psychiatry. 2021;21(1) doi: 10.1186/s12888-020-03002-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-020-03002-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElroy E., Hyland P., Shevlin M., Karatzias T., Valli&#xe8;res F., Ben-Ezra M., Vang M.L., Lorberg B., Martsenkovskyi D. Change in child mental health during the Ukraine war: Evidence from a large sample of parents. European Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. 2024;33(5):1495&#x2013;1502. doi: 10.1007/s00787-023-02255-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-023-02255-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11098962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37421462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller H., Groeger A., Hersh J., Matranga A., Serrat J., Designed J.S., Performed J.S. Monitoring war destruction from space using machine learning. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2025400118/-/DCSupplemental.y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8201876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munezero E., Manoukian S. The social determinants of health and health seeking behaviour in populations affected by armed conflict: A qualitative systematic review. Medicine, Conflict and Survival. 2021;37(4):293&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1080/13623699.2021.1971824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13623699.2021.1971824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34544291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munyaka J.C.B., Chenal J., Mabaso S., Tfwala S.S., Mandal A.K. Geospatial tools and remote sensing strategies for timely humanitarian response: A case Study on drought monitoring in Eswatini. Sustainability. 2024;16(1) doi: 10.3390/su16010409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16010409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordstrand A.E., Gjerstad C.L., Hjemdal O., Holen A., Tveitstul T., Reichelt J.G., Kennair L.E.O., Bakker L.-P., Kristoffersen R., B&#xf8;e H.J. Killing in combat; the diverging mental health impact on distinct veteran populations &#x2013; A two-sample Study. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31234/osf.io/4g9fb</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasrawi R., Vicuna Polo S., Abu Khader R., Abu Al-Halawa D., Hallaq S., Abu Halaweh N., Abdeen Z. Machine learning techniques for identifying mental health risk factor associated with schoolchildren cognitive ability living in politically violent environments. Frontiers in Psychiatry. 2023;14 doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1071622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1071622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10250653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savige T., Kamstra P., McCosker A., Farmer J. Using data bricolage and mixed-methods GIS to uncover mental health service gaps in rural Australia. The Professional Geographer. 2024;76(3):289&#x2013;302. doi: 10.1080/00330124.2024.2308610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00330124.2024.2308610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shevlin M., Hyland P., Karatzias T. The psychological consequences of the Ukraine war: What we know, and what we have to learn. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica. 2022;146(2):105&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1111/acps.13466. John Wiley and Sons Inc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slewa-Younan S., Uribe Guajardo M.G., Heriseanu A., Hasan T. A systematic review of post-traumatic stress disorder and depression amongst Iraqi refugees located in Western countries. Journal of Immigrant and Minority Health. 2015;17(4):1231&#x2013;1239. doi: 10.1007/s10903-014-0046-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10903-014-0046-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>State Statistics Service of Ukraine . Vol. 2023. 2023. (Population statistics).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibshiranit R. Regression shrinkage and selection via the lasso. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society B. 1996;58(Issue 1) https://academic.oup.com/jrsssb/article/58/1/267/7027929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torkamani-Azar F., Imani H., Fathollahian H. Video quality measurement based on 3-D. Singular value decomposition. Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation. 2015;27:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jvcir.2014.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvcir.2014.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNHCR . 2023. Ukraine refugee situation. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations . 2024. World Population Prospects 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner M., Jaime C. 2020. Philipp rotmann (GPPi)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Wu Y., Jacobson M.H., Lee M., Jin P., Trasande L., Liu M. A family of partial-linear single-index models for analyzing complex environmental exposures with continuous, categorical, time-to-event, and longitudinal health outcomes. Environmental Health: A Global Access Science Source. 2020;19(1) doi: 10.1186/s12940-020-00644-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12940-020-00644-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang X., Zhang H., Xia S.T. ACM international conference proceeding series. 2020. Label aggregation of gradient boosting decision trees; pp. 140&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3421558.3421581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>