<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41422255</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-511X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lipids in health and disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lipids Health Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risk prediction of multiple cardiometabolic diseases in middle-aged and older adults using lipid metabolism biomarkers and derived composite measures based on machine learning: a prospective cohort study of CHARLS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">22</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12944-025-02820-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Cardiometabolic multimorbidity (CMM) has become an increasing global public health challenge. In China, the prevalence of CMM is rising rapidly among middle-aged and older adults, with estimates ranging from 11.6% to 16.9%, posing a substantial burden on both individuals and healthcare systems. However, effective tools for predicting individual risk of CMM remain limited, hindering timely prevention and intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study used data from the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study (CHARLS) between 2011 and 2015, including 7,913 participants aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;45 years without CMM at baseline. Incident CMM events were identified during the 2015 follow-up based on self-reported diagnoses of cardiometabolic diseases. Ten lipid metabolism biomarkers and derived composite indices (TC, TG, LDL-C, HDL-C, TyG, TyG-BMI, LAP, CTI, non-HDL-C, and RC) were evaluated. Predictive models were estimated using logistic regression, random forest, gradient boosting machine, eXtreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost), support vector machine, na&#xef;ve Bayes, deep learning (DL), and an ensemble model. The dataset was randomly split into training (75%) and validation (25%) subsets. Model discrimination was assessed using ROC curves and Area Under the Curve (AUC); calibration was evaluated with calibration plots and Brier scores; classification performance was examined using confusion matrices. Decision curve analysis (DCA) and clinical impact curves (CIC) were applied to assess clinical utility across risk thresholds. Feature importance ranking and SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) were used to quantify variable contributions, marginal effects, and feature interactions. In addition, regional variations in CMM incidence were illustrated using choropleth maps, and correlations between lipid markers and CMM prevalence were analyzed with Pearson coefficients and heatmaps.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Over the four-year follow-up, 1,355 participants (17.1%) developed CMM. Compared with controls, incident cases were older, had a higher proportion of women and urban residents, and showed higher BMI. They also had significantly elevated triglycerides (126.6 vs. 101.8&#xa0;mg/dL), reduced HDL-C (45.2 vs. 50.3&#xa0;mg/dL, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and increased TyG-BMI and LAP (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Geographical analysis revealed markedly higher CMM incidence in northern cold regions (&gt;&#x2009;40%) than in southern regions (&lt;&#x2009;20%). The ensemble model achieved robust predictive performance (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.715), followed closely by the DL model (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.716) and GBM (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.714). These non-linear models consistently outperformed GLM (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.696), SVM (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.696), and XGBoost (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.683). Ensemble, DL, and RF models also demonstrated the best calibration (lowest Brier score, 0.125) and provided the greatest net benefit across risk thresholds. SHAP analysis indicated that composite indices, particularly TyG-BMI, LAP, and TyG, contributed most to risk prediction, whereas HDL-C exerted a protective effect. In contrast, traditional single lipid markers such as LDL-C and TC ranked lower in predictive importance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates that machine learning models incorporating lipid metabolism biomarkers and derived indices can predict the risk of CMM. Composite indicators such as TyG and LAP, which capture insulin resistance and visceral adiposity, showed superior predictive value. DL and ensemble models provided higher discrimination and clinical utility compared with traditional approaches. These models may enable early identification of high-risk individuals, underscoring the importance of lipid and metabolic management in CMM prevention, with potential implications for clinical decision-making and public health strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12944-025-02820-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Sports, Macao Polytechnic University, Macao, SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Peijie</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Health, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Binghong</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Sports, Macao Polytechnic University, Macao, SAR, China. gaobinghong@mpu.edu.mo.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Athletic Performance, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China. gaobinghong@mpu.edu.mo.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RP/FCSD-02/2025</GrantID><Agency>Macao Polytechnic University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lipids Health Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101147696</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1476-511X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CHARLS cohort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiometabolic multimorbidity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Derived composite indices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lipid metabolism biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk prediction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the institutional review board of Peking University and conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical approval for household questionnaires and physical measurements was granted under IRB00001052-11015, and for biomarker collection under IRB00001052-11014. All procedures were performed in accordance with local legislation and institutional requirements. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their involvement in the study. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that the study was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41422255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12825255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-025-02820-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12944-025-02820-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Di Angelantonio E. Association of cardiometabolic Multimorbidity with mortality in 1 million people. JAMA. 2015;314(1):52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.7008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26151266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivim&#xe4;ki M. Overweight, obesity, and risk of cardiometabolic multimorbidity: pooled analysis of individual-level data. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2017;5(10):715&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canoy D. Cardiometabolic disease multimorbidity and mortality: a population-based cohort study. BMC Med. 2021;19(1):258&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-021-02126-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8555122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34706724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen RK. Effect on life expectancy of temporal sequence in a cardiometabolic multimorbidity pathway. Lancet Public Health. 2023;8(7):e632-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37393092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X. Healthy lifestyle and life expectancy among individuals with cardiometabolic Multimorbidity. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:830319&#x2013;830319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.830319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9218816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35757322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J. Multimorbidity patterns and association with mortality in Chinese adults. Chin Med J. 2022;135(20):230&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9276333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35191418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y. Prevalence and patterns of multimorbidity in china: a systematic review. Maturitas. 2024;188:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38096988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y. Cardiometabolic Multimorbidity among Chinese women: prevalence and associated factors. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1048348&#x2013;1048348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9947472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D. Trends of cardiometabolic multimorbidity and mortality in 1,038,704 Chinese adults. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;29(9):1040&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y. Lifestyle, cardiometabolic disease, and Multimorbidity in 0.5 million Chinese adults. Eur Heart J. 2021;42(34):3374&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehab413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8423468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y. Composite healthy lifestyle and risk of cardiometabolic multimorbidity: a prospective study. BMC Med. 2023;21(1):46&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong J. Multimorbidity and out-of-pocket expenditures among middle-aged and older adults in china: evidence from CHARLS. Lancet Public Health. 2022;7(2):e95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JG. Non&#x2013;HDL cholesterol and coronary heart disease risk prediction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53(4):316&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2008.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19161879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekholdt SM. Non-HDL cholesterol vs LDL cholesterol for risk prediction: meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2012;60(3):263&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parish S. Blood lipids and vascular disease: emerging risk factors collaboration. JAMA. 2009;302(18):1993&#x2013;2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2009.1619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3284229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19903920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE. The triglyceride&#x2013;glucose index as a surrogate marker of insulin resistance. Metab Syndr Relat Disord. 2008;6(4):299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/met.2008.0034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19067533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasques ACJ. TyG index and HOMA-IR performance comparison. Arch Endocrinol Metab. 2011;55(1):32&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Er LK. Triglyceride glucose&#x2013;body mass index (TyG&#x2013;BMI) and incident diabetes. Med (Baltim). 2016;95(17):e3647&#x2013;3647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-&#xcd;&#xf1;igo L. TyG-related indices and cardiovascular risk in a prospective cohort. Sci Rep. 2017;7:3423&#x2013;3423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn HS. The lipid accumulation product as a measure of visceral adiposity. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(1):151&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.29.01.06.dc05-1805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato MC. Visceral adiposity index: a reliable indicator of visceral fat function. Diabetes Care. 2010;33(4):920&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc09-1825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20067971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motamed N. Lipid accumulation product and metabolic syndrome. Endocrinol Metab. 2016;31(1):64&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26319991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai H. Atherogenic index of plasma and cardiovascular risk. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2018;28(10):1007&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S. Triglyceride-glucose index and incident diabetes: a meta-analysis. Prim Care Diabetes. 2022;16(5):700&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M. Triglyceride-glucose index and cardiovascular disease risk: systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:903372&#x2013;903372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. Lipid accumulation product (LAP) and cardiovascular risk: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2022;14(16):3254&#x2013;3254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu J. Visceral adiposity index and cardiometabolic outcomes: a systematic review. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2022;32(6):1230&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordestgaard BG. Triglycerides and remnant cholesterol: causal or not? Clin Chem. 2014;60(1):129&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C. METS-IR and cardiometabolic Multimorbidity in Chinese adults: a nationwide longitudinal study. Front Nutr. 2025;12:1518840&#x2013;1518840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1518840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11860098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40013162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen-Telders C, Schlaich M, Schutte A, Stergiou G, Poulter N, Beaney T. Risk factors for cardiometabolic multimorbidity: an analysis of 4 million participants from May measurement month 2017&#x2013;2019. Eur Heart J. 2024;45(Supplement1):ehae666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong T, Lin W, Zhou Q, Yang Y, Liu X, Chen J, et al. Association of adiposity indicators with cardiometabolic multimorbidity risk in hypertensive patients: a large cross-sectional study. Front Endocrinol. 2024;15:1302296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2024.1302296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10991765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38577567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW. Clinical prediction models: A practical approach to development, validation, and updating (evaluation concepts). BMJ. 2010;341:c4671&#x2013;4671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteva A. A guide to deep learning in healthcare. Nat Med. 2019;25(1):24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-018-0316-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajkomar A. Scalable and accurate deep learning with electronic health records. NPJ Digit Med. 2018;1:18&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-018-0029-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng SF. Can machine-learning improve cardiovascular risk prediction using routine clinical data? PLoS One. 2017;12(4):e0174944-0174944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0174944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y. Cohort profile: the China health and retirement longitudinal study (CHARLS). Int J Epidemiol. 2014;43(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dys203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Fu C, Yang F, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of hypertension for the middle-aged population in China&#x2014;results from the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study (CHARLS)[J]. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2019;41(1):80&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10641963.2018.1445751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29553846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Hu Y, Smith JP, et al. Cohort profile: the China health and retirement longitudinal study (CHARLS)[J]. Int J Epidemiol. 2014;43(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dys203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg S M, Lee S I. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions[J]. Advances in neural information processing systems, 2017, 30.Lundberg SM. A Unified Approach to Interpreting Model Predictions. In: Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS): 2017;2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM. Consistent individualized feature attribution for tree ensembles. In: Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS): 2018;2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM. From local explanations to global understanding with explainable AI. Nat Mach Intell. 2020;2(1):252&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-019-0138-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Strauss J, Yang G, Giles J, Hu P, Hu Y, et al. China health and retirement longitudinal study&#x2013;2011&#x2013;2012 national baseline users&#x2019; guide. Beijing: Natl School Dev Peking Univ. 2013;2:1&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Hu Y, Smith JP, Strauss J, Yang G. Cohort profile: the China health and retirement longitudinal study (CHARLS). Int J Epidemiol. 2014;43(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dys203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Crimmins E, Hu P, Kim JK, Meng Q, Strauss J, Wang Y, Zeng J, Zhang Y, Zhao Y. Venous blood-based biomarkers in the China health and retirement longitudinal study: rationale, design, and results from the 2015 wave. Am J Epidemiol. 2019;188(11):1871&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwz170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31364691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H. TyG-BMI and arterial stiffness/metabolic phenotypes. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22:96&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. Non&#x2013;HDL cholesterol and coronary heart disease risk in Chinese populations. Int J Cardiol. 2006;110(1):111&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varbo A. Remnant cholesterol and ischemic heart disease. Atherosclerosis. 2014;234(1):145&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24977981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varbo A. Remnant cholesterol as a causal risk factor for ischemic heart disease. Eur Heart J. 2013;34(24):1826&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23265341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langsted A. Remnant cholesterol and cardiovascular risk: clinical chemistry perspective. Clin Chem. 2016;62(4):594&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathiyakumar V. Fasting vs nonfasting lipid profiles and remnant cholesterol. Circulation. 2018;137(1):10&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.117.030677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29038168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HH. Remnant cholesterol and atherosclerotic risk: a meta-analysis. Atherosclerosis. 2021;329:11&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpert DH. Stacked generalization. Neural Netw. 1992;5(2):241&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0893-6080(05)80023-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topol EJ. High-performance medicine: the convergence of human and artificial intelligence. Nat Med. 2019;25(1):44&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-018-0300-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong ER. Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves. Biometrics. 1988;44(3):837&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2531595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Calster B. Calibration: the achilles&#x2019; heel of predictive analytics. BMC Med. 2019;17:230&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-019-1466-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6912996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31842878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liou L. Calibration and bias of deployed machine learning models in health care. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2024;31(10):2239&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ. Decision curve analysis: a novel method for evaluating prediction models. Med Decis Making. 2006;26(6):565&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X06295361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2577036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ. Net benefit approaches to evaluating the clinical utility of predictive models. BMJ. 2016;352:i6&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26810254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Calster B. Calibration and decision-analytic performance of risk prediction models. Med Decis Making. 2015;35(2):162&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X14547233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robin X. pROC: an open-source package for R and S&#x2009;+&#x2009;to analyze and compare ROC curves. BMC Bioinformatics. 2011;12:77&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2105-12-77</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3068975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21414208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susmaga R. Confusion matrix visualization. In: Intelligent Information Processing and Web Mining: Proceedings of the International IIS: IIPWM &#x2018;04 Conference held in Zakopane, Poland, May 17&#x2013;20, 2004: 2004: Springer; 2004: 107&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visa S, Ramsay B, Ralescu AL, Van Der Knaap E. Confusion matrix-based feature selection. Maics. 2011;710(1):120&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brier GW. Verification of forecasts expressed in terms of probability. Mon Weather Rev. 1950;78(1):1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1175/1520-0493(1950)078&lt;0001:VOFEIT&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hoorde K. A flexible tool for constructing calibration plots. J Biomed Inform. 2015;54:283&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25579635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Broeck G, Lykov A, Schleich M, Suciu D. On the tractability of SHAP explanations. J Artif Intell Res. 2022;74:851&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1613/jair.1.13283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nohara Y, Matsumoto K, Soejima H, Nakashima N. Explanation of machine learning models using Shapley additive explanation and application for real data in hospital. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2022;214:106584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34942412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundararajan M, Najmi A. The many Shapley values for model explanation. In: International conference on machine learning: 2020: PMLR; 2020: 9269&#x2013;9278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inglis A, Parnell A, Hurley CB. Visualizing variable importance and variable interaction effects in machine learning models. J Comput Graph Stat. 2022;31(3):766&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10618600.2021.2007935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson BD, Gilbert PB, Carone M, Simon N. Nonparametric variable importance assessment using machine learning techniques. Biometrics. 2021;77(1):9&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/biom.13392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7946807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33043428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc; G, Batty M, Strobl J, Lin H, Zhu A-X, Chen M. Reflections and speculations on the progress in geographic information systems (GIS): a geographic perspective. Int J Geogr Inf Sci. 2019;33(2):346&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13658816.2018.1533136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedgwick P Pearson&#x2019;s correlation coefficient. BMJ. 2012;345:e4483. 10.1136/bmj.e4483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.e4483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaahmadi&#x2010;Rezaei H, Raeisizadeh M, Zarezade V, et al. Comparison of atherogenic indices for predicting the risk of metabolic syndrome in Southwest Iran: results from the Hoveyzeh Cohort Study (HCS)[J]. Diabetol Metabol Syndr. 2024;16(1):112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38783371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang H, Wang L, et al. Predicting metabolic syndrome by obesity- and lipid-related indices: a cross-sectional and longitudinal study. BMC Endocr Disorders. 2023;23(1):15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon J-H, et al. Triglyceride-Glucose index predicts future atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in the general population. Endocrinol Metabolism. 2023;38(2):230&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10475965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzadeh M, Kizel R, Sakib MN et al. Atherogenic index of plasma as a predictor of coronary artery disease. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Agostino RB. Cardiovascular disease risk assessment: insights from Framingham. Glob Heart. 2013;8(1):11&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gheart.2013.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3673738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church E, Poppe K, Wells S. Scoping review of the use of multimorbidity variables in cardiovascular disease risk prediction. BMC Public Health. 2025. 10.1186/s12889-025-22169-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-22169-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11912685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40097958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng C, Liang B, Kong Z, et al. Metabolomic profiling reveals biomarkers in coronary heart disease comorbidity[J]. J Diabetes Res. 2024;2024(1):8559677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/jdr/8559677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11671664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39735415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moe &#xc5;M, Ytterstad E, Hopstock LA, et al. Associations and predictive power of dietary patterns on metabolic syndrome and its components[J]. Nutr Metabol Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;34(3):681&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2023.10.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotamisligil GS. Inflammation, metaflammation and immunometabolic disorders. Nature. 2017;542(7640):177&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature21363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau B, et al. Adipose tissue inflammation and metabolic dysfunction: a clinical perspective. Diabetologia. 2022;65(8):1213&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Rodr&#xed;guez-Mor&#xe1;n M, Guerrero-Romero F. The product of fasting glucose and triglycerides as surrogate for identifying insulin resistance: an epidemiological analysis. Metab Syndr Relat Disord. 2008;6(4):299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/met.2008.0034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19067533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tall AR, Rader DJ. The trials and tribulations of CETP inhibitors. Circ Res. 2018;122(1):106&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.117.311978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5756107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29018035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L, et al. Associations of cardiometabolic index, lipid accumulation product and visceral adiposity index with cardiometabolic Multimorbidity in hypertensive patients. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2023;23(1):189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y, Bengio Y, Hinton G. Deep learning. Nature. 2015;521:436&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature14539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietterich TG. Ensemble methods in machine learning. Multiple Classifier Syst 2000:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Lee S-I. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2017;30:4765&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Pan W, Chen R. Machine learning-based stroke risk prediction in an elderly UK cohort: incorporating composite metabolic indices. J Am Heart Association. 2020;9(23):e018876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sniderman AD, Thanassoulis G, Glavinovic T, Navar AM, Pencina M, Catapano AL. Apolipoprotein B particles and cardiovascular disease: a narrative review. JAMA Cardiol. 2019;4(12):1287&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2019.3780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31642874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varbo A, Nordestgaard BG. Remnant cholesterol and triglyceride-rich lipoproteins in atherosclerosis progression and cardiovascular disease. Curr Opin Lipidol. 2019;30(5):385&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero-Romero F, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ortiz M, Mart&#xed;nez-Abundis E, Ramos-Zavala MG, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez SO, et al. The product of triglycerides and glucose, a simple measure of insulin sensitivity. Comparison with the euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010;95(7):3347&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2010-0288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, Rodr&#xed;guez-Mor&#xe1;n M, Guerrero-Romero F. The product of fasting glucose and triglycerides as surrogate for identifying insulin resistance: an update. Lipids Health Dis. 2008;7(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19067533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Han K, Yang HS, Kim HB, Cho JH, Kwon H-S, et al. Identifying subgroups of obesity using the product of triglycerides and glucose: the Korea National health and nutrition examination Survey, 2008&#x2013;2010. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2016;85(5):699&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24841432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Wang D, Yang H, Chen S, Xu W, Wang F. Triglyceride-glucose index and the risk of cardiovascular events in patients with coronary artery disease: a prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn HS. The lipid accumulation product performs better than the body mass index for recognizing cardiovascular risk: a population-based comparison. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2005;5(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2261-5-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1236917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16150143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchesini G, Bugianesi E, Forlani G, Cerrelli F, Lenzi M, Manini R, Natale S, Vanni E, Villanova N, Melchionda N. Nonalcoholic fatty liver, steatohepatitis, and the metabolic syndrome. Hepatology. 2003;37(4):917&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/jhep.2003.50161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12668987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Jaramillo P, Lahera V, L&#xf3;pez-Lopez J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Salda&#xf1;a J, Camacho PA, Cohen DD. The lipid accumulation product and obesity phenotypes: relationship with insulin resistance in adults with normal weight, overweight and obesity. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;24(10):1002&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Chen L, Zhao M. Cold exposure and cardiometabolic health: evidence from Northern China. J Cardiovasc Metabolism. 2023;15(4):210&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Sun H, Wang R. Regional disparities in cardiometabolic disease burden in China: a nationwide epidemiological analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):134&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li Q, Zhang H. Quantifying the contribution of dietary and environmental factors to north-south cardiovascular mortality differences in China. Lancet Reg Health - Western Pac. 2021;12:100178&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Zhou X, Hu B. Air pollution, metabolic disorders, and cardiovascular risk: A population-based study in Northern China. Environ Health Perspect. 2023;131(2):27001&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>