<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41591267</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1132</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical orthopaedics and related research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Orthop Relat Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>What Substitution and Prediction Strategies Address the Challenge of an Unmeasurable C2-7 Cobb Angle?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003812</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The C2-7 Cobb angle is an important parameter in evaluating cervical sagittal alignment, which is widely used for preoperative planning, identifying surgical indications, and postoperative assessment. However, this angle becomes unmeasurable in 28% to 49% of clinical radiographs because of poor visualization of the C7 inferior endplate, limiting treatment planning and radiographic follow-up in cervical alignment assessment. The C2-6 Cobb angle has been proposed as a substitute in previous research, but these studies were limited by small symptomatic cohorts from a single center and lacked both subgroup-specific and external validation. Furthermore, there is currently a lack of reference standards for the clinical use of the C2-6 Cobb angle, and no established machine-learning models are available to accurately predict the C2-7 Cobb angle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="QUESTIONS/PURPOSES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">(1) Can the C2-6 Cobb angle serve as a reliable substitute for the C2-7 angle? (2) Can machine-learning models accurately predict the C2-7 Cobb angle?</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a retrospective, multicountry imaging study from January 2020 to January 2025, utilizing standing lateral cervical spine radiographs from a large hospital data set in China and public data sets from Vietnam and India. In China, 11,800 radiographs were initially screened. The inclusion criterion was cervical radiographs of sufficient clarity. The exclusion criterion was cervical radiographs with incomplete visualization of anatomic structures. Following these exclusions, 10,571 radiographs from China were included, comprising 10,000 standard standing lateral radiographs plus 284 implant and 287 flexion-extension radiographs. From the public data sets, 470 radiographs from Vietnam and 62 from India were reviewed, with no radiographs excluded. A total of 11,103 radiographs were available for final analysis. Key variables included demographics (age, sex), symptomatic status, implant status, and radiographic sagittal parameters derived from standing lateral views. Four orthopaedic specialists labeled keypoints on the original radiographs, including the corner points of C2 to C7 and the centroid of C2. An algorithm was employed for precise measurement of the C2-6 and C2-7 Cobb angles. The Pearson correlation coefficient was calculated to assess the strength of the correlation between the C2-6 and C2-7 Cobb angles, and a linear regression analysis was applied to derive a predictive equation for the C2-7 Cobb angle based on the C2-6 Cobb angle. Subsequently, the 10,000 standard Chinese standing lateral radiographs were randomly assigned to the training set (80%) and the testing set (20%). An independent validation set (n = 1103) was established to assess robustness, comprising 284 implant radiographs and 287 flexion-extension radiographs from China, together with 470 from Vietnam and 62 from India.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Correlation analysis demonstrated a strong positive correlation between the C2-6 and C2-7 Cobb angles in the overall population (r = 0.92; p &lt; 0.001). Machine-learning models incorporating the C2-6 Cobb angle and other sagittal parameters achieved high predictive accuracy for estimating the C2-7 Cobb angle, with Lasso regression performing best (R2 = 0.93, mean absolute error [MAE] = 2.57). Additionally, strong performance was observed in the validation set (R2 = 0.95, MAE = 3.21). In the subgroup analysis for the extension in males group, the linear model achieved the best validation results, with R2 = 0.94 and MAE = 2.52.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A strong correlation and high interpretable linear regression results between the C2-6 and C2-7 Cobb angles were observed across different countries, body positions, and implants, suggesting that the C2-6 Cobb angle can serve as a reliable substitute for the C2-7 Cobb angle in radiographic imaging. Further analysis revealed that the C2-6 Cobb angle is approximately 6&#xb0; smaller than the C2-7 Cobb angle at the population level, which may serve as an important reference for standardized interpretation in clinical evaluation. Machine-learning models achieved high predictive accuracy for estimating the C2-7 Cobb angle, with the best performing model (Lasso regression) achieving an MAE of 2.57, offering an alternative clinical application option. To facilitate clinical use, we provide a freely available online tool (http://c2-7cobbanglepredictionsystem.online) that will be maintained for at least 15 years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level III, diagnostic study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the Association of Bone and Joint Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Zerui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dongzhimen Hospital, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ran</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sha</LastName><ForeName>Zongshuo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9396-3302</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Lingmin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Haodong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-2621-4722</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Qianzi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhongze</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-5230-8644</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dongzhimen Hospital, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jinsong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dongzhimen Hospital, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Dongran</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yixing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jinyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dongzhimen Hospital, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dongzhimen Hospital, Beijing University of Chinese Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Orthop Relat Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0075674</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-921X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Each author certifies that there are no funding or commercial associations (consultancies, stock ownership, equity interest, patent/licensing arrangements, etc.) that might pose a conflict of interest in connection with the submitted article related to the author or any immediate family members. All ICMJE Conflict of Interest Forms for authors and Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research&#xae; editors and board members are on file with the publication and can be viewed on request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41591267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003086-990000000-02304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aldahamsheh O, Alhammoud A, Halayqeh S, et al. Stand-alone anchored spacer vs anterior plate construct in the management of adjacent segment disease after anterior cervical discectomy and fusion: a systematic review and meta-analysis of comparative studies. Global Spine J. 2024;14:1038-1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles YP, Prost S, Pesenti S, et al. Variation of cervical sagittal alignment parameters according to gender, pelvic incidence and age. Eur Spine J. 2022;31:1228-1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Wang J, Wei X, et al. The importance of preoperative T1 slope for determining proper postoperative C2-7 Cobb&#x2019;s angle in patients undergoing cervical reconstruction. J Orthop Surg Res. 2020;15:507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Luo J, Pan Z, et al. The change of cervical spine alignment along with aging in asymptomatic population: a preliminary analysis. Eur Spine J. 2017;26:2363-2371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ct K, Levin LS, Ondra SL, Shaffrey CI, Morgan CJ. Neutral upright sagittal spinal alignment from the occiput to the pelvis in asymptomatic adults: a review and resynthesis of the literature. J Neurosurg Spine. 2007;6:104-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du W, Wang HX, Lv J, et al. Cervical alignment and clinical outcome of anterior cervical discectomy and fusion vs. anterior cervical corpectomy and fusion in local kyphotic cervical spondylotic myelopathy. Heliyon. 2023;9:e19106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunias ZS, Van Calster B, Timmerman D, Boulesteix AL, van Smeden M. A comparison of hyperparameter tuning procedures for clinical prediction models: a simulation study. Stat Med. 2024;43:1119-1134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Wang J, Cai M, Xia L. Can C7 slope substitute the t1 slope in idiopathic scoliosis patients? A radiographic study. J Pediatr Orthop. 2021;41:e374-e379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelb DR, Lenke LG, Bridwell KH, Blanke K, McEnery KW. An analysis of sagittal spinal alignment in 100 asymptomatic middle and older aged volunteers. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1995;20:1351-1358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue T, Ito K, Ando K, et al. Age-related changes in upper and lower cervical alignment and range of motion: normative data of 600 asymptomatic individuals. Eur Spine J. 2020;29:2378-2383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Huec JC, Demezon H, Aunoble S. Sagittal parameters of global cervical balance using EOS imaging: normative values from a prospective cohort of asymptomatic volunteers. Eur Spine J. 2015;24:63-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Huec JC, Thompson W, Mohsinaly Y, Barrey C, Faundez A. Sagittal balance of the spine. Eur Spine J. 2019;28:1889-1905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BS, Walsh KM, Lubelski D, et al. The effect of C2-3 disc angle on postoperative adverse events in cervical spondylotic myelopathy. J Neurosurg Spine. 2018;30:38-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Kim KT, Seo EM, Suk KS, Kwack YH, Son ES. The influence of thoracic inlet alignment on the craniocervical sagittal balance in asymptomatic adults. J Spinal Disord Tech. 2012;25:E41-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Wang Q, Zhao Q, et al. Unveiling and validating a modified method to assess cervical sagittal alignment as an effective substitute for conventional C2-7 Cobb angle. Clin Orthop Surg. 2025;17:130-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T, Lu J, Zhang Y, et al. Does spinal sagittal imbalance lead to future vertebral compression fractures in osteoporosis patients? Spine J. 2021;21:1362-1375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T, Wang Z, Chen G, Liu W. Predictive effect of cervical sagittal parameters on conservative treatment of single-segment cervical spondylotic radiculopathy. World Neurosurg. 2020;134:e1028-e1036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musoro JZ, Zwinderman AH, Puhan MA, ter Riet G, Geskus RB. Validation of prediction models based on lasso regression with multiply imputed data. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama Y, Yata K, Aoshima M. Support vector machine and its bias correction in high-dimension, low-sample-size settings. J Stat Plann Inference. 2017;191:88-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen HT, Pham HH, Nguyen NT, et al. VinDr-SpineXR: a deep learning framework for spinal lesions detection and classification from radiographs. In: de Bruijne M, Cattin PC, Cotin S, eds. Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention &#x2013; MICCAI 2021. Springer, Cham; 2021:291-301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez-Pereira S, Hitzl W, Bullmann V, Meier O, Koller H. Sagittal balance of the cervical spine: an analysis of occipitocervical and spinopelvic interdependence, with C-7 slope as a marker of cervical and spinopelvic alignment. J Neurosurg Spine. 2015;23:16-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passias PG, Vasquez-Montes D, Poorman GW, et al. Predictive model for distal junctional kyphosis after cervical deformity surgery. Spine J. 2018;18:2187-2194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyanka (2024). F1000 data of cervical spine. figshare. Dataset. Available at: https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.28080251.v1. Accessed September 15, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6084/m9.figshare.28080251.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probst P, Boulesteix AL, Bischl B. Tunability: importance of hyperparameters of machine learning algorithms. J Mach Learn Res. 2019;20:1-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran Y, Qin W, Qin C, et al. A high-quality dataset featuring classified and annotated cervical spine x-ray atlas. Sci Data. 2024;11:625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley LH III, Skolasky RL, Albert TJ, Vaccaro AR, Heller JG. Dysphagia after anterior cervical decompression and fusion: prevalence and risk factors from a longitudinal cohort study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2005;30:2564-2569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo J, Suk KS, Kwon JW, et al. Cervical foraminal stenosis as a risk factor for cervical kyphosis following cervical laminoplasty. Spine J. 2022;22:1271-1280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha Z, Yang X, Ran Y, et al. The correlation between gender, age, curvature, and symptom-related changes in C6 and C7 slope in 10,000 subjects. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2025;50:1658-1666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen X, Wu H, Shi C, et al. Preoperative and intraoperative skull traction combined with anterior-only cervical operation in the treatment of severe cervical kyphosis (&gt;50 degrees). World Neurosurg. 2019;130:e915-e925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JS, Ben-Israel D, Kelly MP, et al. The gap between surgeon goal and achieved sagittal alignment in adult cervical spine deformity surgery. J Neurosurg Spine. 2025;42:309-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamai K, Buser Z, Paholpak P, Sessumpun K, Nakamura H, Wang JC. Can C7 slope substitute the T1 slope?: an analysis using cervical radiographs and kinematic MRIs. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2018;43:520-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamai K, Suzuki A, Yabu A, et al. Clinical impact of cervical imbalance on surgical outcomes of laminoplasty: a propensity score-matching analysis. Clin Spine Surg. 2020;3:E1-E7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Santbrink E, Schuermans V, van de Goor A, et al. The influence of body posture on cervical alignment measured in the sagittal plane on conventional radiographs: a systematic review. Spine J. 2025;25:1751-1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veeravagu A, Cole T, Jiang B, Ratliff JK. Revision rates and complication incidence in single- and multilevel anterior cervical discectomy and fusion procedures: an administrative database study. Spine J. 2014;14:1125-1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Guo R, Yang C, et al. The difference of sagittal correction of adult subaxial cervical spine surgery according to age: a retrospective study. Orthop Surg. 2022;14:1790-1798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Wang R, Li J, et al. Intervertebral-spreader-assisted anterior cervical discectomy and fusion prevents postoperative axial pain by alleviating facet joint pressure. J Orthop Surg Res. 17:91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerramilli S, Apley DW. Fractional cross-validation for optimizing hyperparameters of supervised learning algorithms. Technometrics. Published online June 9, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You J, Tang X, Gao W, Shen Y, Ding WY, Ren B. Factors predicting adjacent segment disease after anterior cervical discectomy and fusion treating cervical spondylotic myelopathy: a retrospective study with 5-year follow-up. Medicine (Baltimore). 2018;97:e12893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yukawa Y, Kato F, Suda K, Yamagata M, Ueta T. Age-related changes in osseous anatomy, alignment, and range of motion of the cervical spine. Part I: radiographic data from over 1,200 asymptomatic subjects. Eur Spine J. 2012;21:1492-1498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Buser Z, Abedi A, Dong X, Wang JC. Can C2-6 Cobb angle replace C2-7 Cobb angle? An analysis of cervical kinetic magnetic resonance images and x-rays. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2019;44:240-245.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>