<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41930820</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2534</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>296</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary immunology and immunopathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Immunol Immunopathol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lactiplantibacillus plantarum-fermented shallot (Allium cepa L.) bulb in drinking water as a potential antibiotic alternative against Salmonella pullorum infection in broilers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111112</StartPage><MedlinePgn>111112</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.vetimm.2026.111112</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0165-2427(26)00051-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Salmonella pullorum infection causes severe economic losses in the poultry industry, while the rising threat of antimicrobial resistance necessitates sustainable alternatives to antibiotics. This study evaluated the protective efficacy of Lactiplantibacillus plantarum 1582-fermented shallot (Allium cepa L.) extract (FS) administered via drinking water in broilers challenged with S. pullorum NCTC10705. A total of 300 one-day-old male chickens were randomly allocated to six groups: negative control (NC), positive control (PC), antibiotic (AB), and three FS inclusion levels (1%, 2%, and 3%). While S. pullorum significantly impaired growth performance in the PC group (p&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05), FS supplementation, particularly at 2-3%, restored body weight gain and survival rates (90.0-91.8%) to levels comparable to the NC and AB groups. Mechanistically, FS modulated immune responses by restoring serum IgA and IgM levels, downregulating pro-inflammatory cytokines (TNF-&#x3b1;, IFN-&#x3b3;), and upregulating IL-4. Furthermore, FS enhanced intestinal barrier integrity by increasing villus height and upregulating tight junction protein ZO-1 (with Claudin-2 restored to control levels). Microbiological analysis revealed that FS significantly reduced cecal Salmonella and E. coli loads while promoting beneficial Lactiplantibacillus spp. (p&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05). These findings demonstrate that water-based supplementation of fermented shallot extract effectively mitigates S. pullorum infection by reinforcing gut health and immunity, positioning it as a promising antibiotic alternative in poultry production.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoang</LastName><ForeName>Thi Anh Phuong</ForeName><Initials>TAP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, Tay Nguyen University, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Xuan Hoa</ForeName><Initials>XH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine, University of Agriculture and Forestry, Hue University, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phan</LastName><ForeName>Vu Hai</ForeName><Initials>VH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine, University of Agriculture and Forestry, Hue University, Viet Nam. Electronic address: phanvuhai@hueuni.edu.vn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Immunol Immunopathol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8002006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0165-2427</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotic alternative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Broilers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fermented shallot extract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lactiplantibacillus plantarum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella pullorum</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Phan Vu Hai reports financial support was provided by Ministry of Education and Training, Vietnam (B2024-DHH-24). The authors declare no conflicts of interest. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41930820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetimm.2026.111112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0165-2427(26)00051-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>