<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41334627</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-7670</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Veterinary record</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Rec</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>'Knowledge, attitudes and practices' survey of Austrian veterinarians' antibiotic use in clinical practice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/vetr.6121</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is a critical global health issue, with antimicrobial use (AMU) in veterinary medicine playing a relevant role in its emergence. This study aimed to evaluate the knowledge, attitudes and practices of Austrian veterinarians regarding AMU and AMR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An online survey was conducted in 2022. Veterinary respondents were grouped according to their type of practice (companion animals, i.e., pets and horses; farm; mixed practice).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Knowledge gaps were identified, particularly among companion animal veterinarians, with only 31% correctly recognising cefovecin as a critically important antimicrobial and 16% incorrectly stating it was a first-choice drug. However, treating groups of animals with orally administered antibiotics was correctly classed as having the highest influence on AMR by 75% of 165 respondents. With respect to deciding to use antibiotics, all practitioners considered a clinical examination to be important or very important, while cost considerations and owner expectations were classed by companion animal practitioners as being significantly less important than among farm and mixed practitioners. Of all 180 veterinarians, 47% reported using antimicrobial susceptibility testing always or regularly (approximately 20%&#x2012;50% of antibiotic treatments).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The small sample size may have introduced confirmation bias, as practitioners with a particular interest in AMU and AMR may have been more likely to respond to the survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings confirm the need for additional training to improve prudent AMU and awareness of antimicrobial stewardship in clinical practice across all veterinary sectors in Austria. Future efforts should prioritise the knowledge gaps among companion animal practitioners, in particular.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Veterinary Record published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Veterinary Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Firth</LastName><ForeName>Clair L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4919-7786</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Food Science and Veterinary Public Health, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayer</LastName><ForeName>Patricia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Food Science and Veterinary Public Health, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xe4;sbohrer</LastName><ForeName>Annemarie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Food Science and Veterinary Public Health, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Safety, German Federal Institute for Risk Assessment, Unit Epidemiology, Zoonoses and Antimicrobial Resistance, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripolt</LastName><ForeName>Tanja</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Data, Statistics and Risk Assessment, Austrian Agency for Health and Food Safety, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuchs</LastName><ForeName>Klemens</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Data, Statistics and Risk Assessment, Austrian Agency for Health and Food Safety, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>VetAustria</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Rec</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0031164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0042-4900</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41334627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vetr.6121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Naghavi M, Vollset SE, Ikuta KS, Swetschinski LR, Gray AP, Wool EE, et&#xa0;al. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis with forecasts to 2050. Lancet. 2024;404(10459):1199&#x2012;1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endtz HP, Ruijs GJ, van Klingeren B, Jansen WH, van der Reyden T, Mouton RP. Quinolone resistance in campylobacter isolated from man and poultry following the introduction of fluoroquinolones in veterinary medicine. J Antimicrob Chemother. 1991;27(2):199&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, FAO, OIE, UNEP. Strategic framework for collaboration on antimicrobial resistance&#x2014;together for One Health [Internet]. 2022 [cited 2023 Oct 7]. Available from: https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/352625/9789240045408&#x2010;eng.pdf?sequence=1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. European surveillance of veterinary antimicrobial consumption (ESVAC): 2009&#x2012;2023 [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 2]. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/veterinary&#x2010;regulatory&#x2010;overview/antimicrobial&#x2010;resistance&#x2010;veterinary&#x2010;medicine/european&#x2010;surveillance&#x2010;veterinary&#x2010;antimicrobial&#x2010;consumption&#x2010;esvac&#x2010;2009&#x2010;2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. European sales and use of antimicrobials for veterinary medicine: annual surveillance report for 2023. EMA/CVMP/ESUAVET/80289/2025 [Internet]. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union; 2025 [cited 2025 May 4]. Available from: https://data.europa.eu/doi/10.2809/4487470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BMG. Verordnung des Bundesministers f&#xfc;r Gesundheit, mit der ein System zur &#xdc;berwachung des Vertriebs und Verbrauchs von Antibiotika im Veterin&#xe4;rbereich eingerichtet wird. Veterin&#xe4;r&#x2010;Antibiotika&#x2010;Mengenstr. 2014. https://www.ris.bka.gv.at/GeltendeFassung.wxe?Abfrage=Bundesnormen&amp;Gesetzesnummer=20008823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BMSGPK. Bundesgesetz &#xfc;ber Tierarzneimittel (Tierarzneimittelgesetz&#x2014;TAMG) (Austrian Federal Law on Veterinary Medicinal Products) [Internet]. 2024. Available from: https://www.ris.bka.gv.at/eli/bgbl/I/2023/186/20231230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Union. Regulation (EU) 2019/6 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 11 December 2018 on veterinary medicinal products and repealing Directive 2001/82/EC. Off J Eur Union. 2019;4:43&#x2013;167. Available from: http://data.europa.eu/eli/reg/2019/6/2022&#x2010;01&#x2010;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade C, Menon V, Ameen S, Praharaj SK. Designing and conducting knowledge, attitude, and practice surveys in psychiatry: practical guidance. Ind J Psychol Med. 2020;42(5):478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: a language and environment for statistical computing. [Internet]. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2023. Available from: https://www.R&#x2010;project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Categorisation of antibiotics for use in animals for prudent and responsible use [Internet]. 2019 [cited 2020 Feb 12]. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/news/categorisation&#x2010;antibiotics&#x2010;used&#x2010;animals&#x2010;promotes&#x2010;responsible&#x2010;use&#x2010;protect&#x2010;public&#x2010;animal&#x2010;health</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Briyne N, Atkinson J, Pokludov&#xe1; L, Borriello SP, Price S. Factors influencing antibiotic prescribing habits and use of sensitivity testing amongst veterinarians in Europe. Vet Rec. 2013;173(19):475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarillion M, Hertzsch R, Richter A. Off&#x2010;label&#x2010;use von Antibiotika in der Pferdemedizin&#x2014;eine anonyme deutschlandweite Online&#x2010;Umfrage. Tier&#xe4;rztliche Praxis Ausgabe G: Gro&#xdf;tiere /Nutztiere. 2025;53:155&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarillion M, Hertzsch R, Richter A. Off&#x2010;label use of antibiotics in small animal medicine&#x2014;a Germany&#x2010;wide anonymous online survey. Antibiotics. 2025;14(4):419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKernan C, Benson T, Farrell S, Dean M. Antimicrobial use in agriculture: critical review of the factors influencing behaviour. JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2021;3(4):dlab178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf6;ndal H, Fall N, Blanco&#x2010;Penedo I, Sternberg&#x2010;Lewerin S. Restrictive but not restricted: perspectives on antimicrobial use and antimicrobial resistance among Swedish dairy veterinarians. Vet Rec Open. 2021;8(1):e25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visschers VHM, Backhans A, Collineau L, Loesken S, Nielsen EO, Postma M, et&#xa0;al. A comparison of pig farmers&#x2019; and veterinarians&#x2019; perceptions and intentions to reduce antimicrobial usage in six European countries. Zoonoses Public Health. 2016;63(7):534&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AGES. Risikobarometer 2023 Antibiotikaresistenzen [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Aug 30]. Available from: https://www.ages.at/forschung/wissen&#x2010;aktuell/detail/risikobarometer&#x2010;2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weese JS, Battersby I, Morrison J, Spofford N, Soltero&#x2010;Rivera M. Antimicrobial use practices in canine and feline dental procedures performed in primary care veterinary practices in the United States. PLoS One. 2023;18(12):e0295070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Union. Ban on antibiotics as growth promoters in animal feed enters into effect [Internet]. 2005 . p. 1. Available from: http://europa.eu/rapid/press&#x2010;release_IP&#x2010;05&#x2010;1687_en.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell A, Bard AM, Rees GM. Assessing veterinarians&#x2019; opinions of antimicrobial stewardship initiative acceptability for farm practice in Wales. Vet Rec. 2024;195(10):e4799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan OSK, Wu P, Cowling B, Lee E, Yeung M, St&#x2010;Hilaire S, et&#xa0;al. Prescribing antibiotics prudently&#x2014;a survey of policy implementation drivers among physicians and veterinarians. One Health. 2024;18:100752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias MC, Alpizar&#x2010;Jara R, Lavrador C, Marques C, Broens EM, Duarte EL. Companion animal owners&#x2019; knowledge, attitudes and perceptions regarding antibiotic use in Portugal. Antibiotics. 2024;13(6):533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KW, Bard AM, Adam KE, Rees GM, Morgans L, Cresswell L, et&#xa0;al. Diagnostics and the challenge of antimicrobial resistance: a survey of UK livestock veterinarians&#x2019; perceptions and practices. Vet Rec. 2020;187(12):e125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxinou DT, Lamnisos D, Filippou C, Spernovasilis N, Tsioutis C. Antimicrobial use and antimicrobial resistance in food&#x2010;producing animals: cross&#x2010;sectional study on knowledge, attitudes, and practices among veterinarians and operators of establishments in the Republic of Cyprus. Antibiotics. 2025;14(3):251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busani L, Graziani C, Binkin N, Franco A, Di Egidio A, Battisti A. Survey of the knowledge, attitudes and practice of Italian beef and dairy cattle veterinarians concerning the use of antibiotics. Vet Rec. 2004;155(23):733&#x2013;738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavigne SH, Louis S, Rankin SC, Zaoutis TE, Szymczak JE. How companion animal veterinarians in the United States perceive financial constraints on antibiotic decision&#x2010;making. Vet Rec. 2021;188(12):e62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svensson C, Lomander H, Kokko S. Veterinary herd health management&#x2014;experiences and perceptions among Swedish dairy cattle veterinarians. J Dairy Sci. 2022;105(8):6820&#x2013;6832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey E, Kedrowicz A, Hedgpeth MW. Veterinary students underestimate cat and dog owner adherence and knowledge regarding antimicrobial use and resistance. J Vet Med Educ. 2024;51(6):844&#x2013;854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currie K, King C, Nuttall T, Smith M, Flowers P. Expert consensus regarding drivers of antimicrobial stewardship in companion animal veterinary practice: a Delphi study. Vet Rec. 2018;182(24):691.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>