<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41474180</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The implementation gap in anterior cruciate ligament prevention programs-From evidence to everyday practice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70258</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury remains one of the most impactful injuries in pivoting sports, with non-contact mechanisms accounting for the majority of cases and offering a clear target for prevention. Robust evidence-including multiple Level 1 meta-analyses-demonstrates that structured neuromuscular training (NMT) programs can reduce ACL injury rates by approximately 50%, particularly among youth and female athletes. Effective programs are multicomponent, integrate strength, plyometrics, agility, balance and movement-quality feedback, and require adequate training dose and in-season continuity. Despite this well-established evidence base, real-world implementation remains limited. Coaches and sports organisations frequently report barriers such as time constraints, competing performance priorities and low confidence in delivering prevention exercises. This disconnect reflects a broader implementation gap: while we know what works, we are not consistently doing it. Insights from implementation science, including JBI's phased models, facilitation strategies and context-driven frameworks, provide a roadmap for translating evidence into sustained practice. Reframing prevention as performance-enhancing movement training and embedding programs such as the ESSKA 'Prevention for All' initiative into coaching pathways and club standards are essential system-level strategies. The priority is no longer proving efficacy, but achieving widespread, high-fidelity implementation so that ACL prevention becomes a routine component of athlete preparation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prill</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4916-1206</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg/Havel, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Brandenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kr&#xf3;likowska</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2939-7370</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Research Laboratory, Faculty of Physiotherapy, Wroclaw Medical University, University Centre of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostoijc</LastName><ForeName>Marko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0108-5750</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Traumatology Division, Traumatology Department "Dra&#x161;kovi&#x107;eva", University Hospital "Sisters of Mercy", Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Osteon Orthopaedics and Sports Medicine Clinic, Mostar, Bosnia and Herzegovina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enes Kayaalp</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9545-7454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patt</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bergman Clinics, Capelle aan den IJssel, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janosky</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9018-1955</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Science, Lasell University, Newton, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lockwood</LastName><ForeName>Craig</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3722-676X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, The University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1833-7608</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg/Havel, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Brandenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESMA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41474180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Al Attar WSA, Bakhsh JM, Khaledi EH, Ghulam H, Sanders RH. Injury prevention programs that include plyometric exercises reduce the incidence of anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review of cluster randomised trials. J Physiother. 2022;68:255&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allu S, Beaucage M, Donald M, Escoto M, Kappel J, Morrin L, et al. Collaborative implementation science: a Can&#x2010;SOLVE CKD case example. JBI Evid Implement. 2024;22:418&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia L, De Oliveira Silva D, Whalan M, McKay MJ, Sullivan J, Fuller CW, et al. Non&#x2010;contact anterior cruciate ligament injury epidemiology in team&#x2010;ball sports: a systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis by sex, age, sport, participation level, and exposure type. Sports Med. 2022;52:2447&#x2013;2467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clar C, Fischerauer SF, Leithner A, Rasic L, Ruckenstuhl P, Sadoghi P. Reducing ACL injury risk: a meta&#x2010;analysis of prevention programme effectiveness. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:2815&#x2013;2824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnell&#x2010;Fink LA, Klara K, Collins JE, Yang HY, Goczalk MG, Katz JN, et al. Effectiveness of knee injury and anterior cruciate ligament tear prevention programs: a meta&#x2010;analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0144063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi A, Pizza N, Al&#x2010;Zu'bi BBH, Fabbro GD, Lucidi GA, Zaffagnini S. Clinical outcomes and osteoarthritis at very long&#x2010;term follow&#x2010;up after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671211062238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin LY, Agel J, Albohm MJ, Arendt EA, Dick RW, Garrett WE, et al. Noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries: risk factors and prevention strategies. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2000;8:141&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg J, Sundberg A, Della Villa F, Hamrin Senorski E. Anterior cruciate ligament injury mechanism in athletes across various sports: a scoping review. Ann Jt. 2025;10:35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvist J, Pettersson M. Knee&#x2010;related quality of life compared between 20 and 35 years after an anterior cruciate ligament injury treated surgically with primary repair or reconstruction, or nonsurgically. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52:311&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizarondo L, McArthur A, Porche D, Corremans M, Perrenoud B, Rodrigues R, et al Facilitation in evidence implementation &#x2010; experiences, challenges, and determinants of perceived effectiveness: a qualitative systematic review. JBI Evid Implement. 2023;21:409&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, McArthur A, Klugar M, Stannard D, Cooper AS, Enuameh Y, et al. Providing a scaffold for considering theoretical frameworks in evidence implementation projects: the JBI approach to evidence implementation. JBI Evid Implement. 2023;21:386&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petushek EJ, Sugimoto D, Stoolmiller M, Smith G, Myer GD. Evidence&#x2010;based best&#x2010;practice guidelines for preventing anterior cruciate ligament injuries in young female athletes: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47:1744&#x2013;1753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porritt K, McArthur A, Lockwood C, Munn Z. JBI's approach to evidence implementation: a 7&#x2010;phase process model to support and guide getting evidence into practice. JBI Evid Implement. 2023;21:3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Briem K, Karlsson J, Hirschmann MT, Nyland J. Teamwork is needed now: time to focus on collaboration, rehabilitation and patients&#x2019; needs! Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32:1641&#x2013;1644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Janosky J, Bode L, van Melick N, Villa FD, Becker R, et al. Prevention of ACL injury is better than repair or reconstruction&#x2010;Implementing the ESSKA&#x2010;ESMA &#x2018;Prevention for All&#x2019; ACL programme. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1954&#x2013;1958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Ma CB, Wong SE, Beaufils P, Monllau JC, Arhos EK, et al. The formal EU&#x2010;US meniscus rehabilitation 2024 consensus: an ESSKA&#x2010;AOSSM&#x2010;AASPT initiative. Part II&#x2010;prevention, non&#x2010;operative treatment and return to sport. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:3014&#x2013;3024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi VG, Prill R, Jahnke S, Zaffagnini S, Becker R. The influence of gluteal muscle strength deficits on dynamic knee valgus: a scoping review. J Exp Orthop. 2022;9:81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins L, Farrey T, Janosky J, Minjares V, Mandelbaum BR, Pearle A. Preventing anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries in high school sports participants: an executive summary of the inaugural meeting of the national ACL injury coalition. HSS J Musculoskel J Hosp Special Surg. 2024;20:333&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers&#x2010;Granelli HJ, Bizzini M, Arundale A, Mandelbaum BR, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L. Does the FIFA 11+ injury prevention program reduce the incidence of ACL injury in male soccer players? Clin Orthop Rel Res. 2017;475:2447&#x2013;2455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto D, Myer GD, Barber Foss KD, Hewett TE. Dosage effects of neuromuscular training intervention to reduce anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes: meta&#x2010; and sub&#x2010;group analyses. Sports Med. 2014;44:551&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tischer T, Martens G, Cabri J, Thoreux P, Tscholl P, Edouard P, et al. The awareness of injury prevention programmes is insufficient among French&#x2010; and German&#x2010;speaking sports medicine communities in Europe. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:2563&#x2013;2571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Hewett TE. Anterior cruciate ligament injury and knee osteoarthritis: an umbrella systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin J Sport Med. 2021;32:145&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Hewett TE. Meta&#x2010;analysis of meta&#x2010;analyses of anterior cruciate ligament injury reduction training programs. J Orthop Res. 2018;36:2696&#x2013;2708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JH, Lim BO, Ha M, Lee SW, Oh SJ, Lee YS, et al. A meta&#x2010;analysis of the effect of neuromuscular training on the prevention of the anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2010;18:824&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>