<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41359935</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of Sport Representation and Attitudes Toward Strength Training on Neuromuscular Performance Profiles in University Athletes: Part I Female Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>311</StartPage><EndPage>323</EndPage><MedlinePgn>311-323</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005309</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>McClean, ZJ, da Silva Torres, R, Herzog, W, Pasanen, K, Lun, V, Nimphius, S, and Jordan, MJ. The influence of sport representation and attitudes toward strength training on neuromuscular performance profiles in university athletes: part I female athletes. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): 311-323, 2026-Neuromuscular performance is often assessed across strength, power, and plyometric tasks in athlete populations with an increasing emphasis on biomechanical testing that yields multifaceted data sets with several outcome measures per task. This leads to specific challenges in determining relevant neuromuscular performance benchmarks especially when considering contextual factors related to the sport environment. Thus, characterizing athlete neuromuscular performance subpopulations (or profiles) while accounting for the influence of contextual factors such as those related to the sport environment, and psychosocial factors such as the athlete's attitudes toward strength training could provide a framework for more specific neuromuscular benchmarks. Therefore, neuromuscular performance profiles were explored in female university athletes while accounting for sport influences and attitudes toward strength training. Female university athletes ( n = 192) from 5 sports completed a comprehensive lower body neuromuscular performance testing battery and surveys assessing attitudes toward strength training. Clustering was done to define neuromuscular performance profiles and Fisher's Exact Tests were used to examine differences in attitudes toward strength training across clusters. A high-strength/high-power/high-stiffness cluster, low-strength/low-power/low-stiffness cluster, and low-strength/low-power/high-stiffness cluster were identified with no difference in sport representation but differences in attitudes toward strength training ( p &lt; 0.047; alpha = 0.05). These findings may help to quantify the characteristics of different female university athlete neuromuscular performance profiles while accounting for potential sport and psychosocial influences. One potential application of these results is to inform neuromuscular performance benchmarks that can be used in conjunction with preseason evaluations or in the context of restoring performance readiness after injury.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClean</LastName><ForeName>Zachary J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7219-9448</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva Torres</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Group, Wageningen University &amp; Research, Wageningen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herzog</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasanen</LastName><ForeName>Kati</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lun</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Medicine Center, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nimphius</LastName><ForeName>Sophia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medial and Health Science, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Medicine Center, University of Calgary, Calgary, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete profiling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">countermovement jump testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unsupervised machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41359935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abernethy P, Wilson G, Logan P. Strength and power assessment. Issues, controversies and challenges. Sports Med 19: 401&#x2013;417, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton C, Crossley K, Culvenor A, et al. Should we rely on the limb symmetry index to evaluate functional performance after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction? J Sci Med Sport 24: S1&#x2013;S2, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: Comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance profiling, neuromuscular fatigue monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Cond J 45: 545&#x2013;553, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittencourt NFN, Meeuwisse WH, Mendon&#xe7;a LD, et al. Complex systems approach for sports injuries: Moving from risk factor identification to injury pattern recognition&#x2014;Narrative review and new concept. Br J Sports Med 50: 1309&#x2013;1314, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Magnusson SP, Rasmussen LR, Kjaer M, Aagaard P. Muscle performance during maximal isometric and dynamic contractions is influenced by the stiffness of the tendinous structures. J Appl Physiol 99: 986&#x2013;994, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Bishop C, Simons C, et al. Lower extremity stiffness: Effects on performance and injury and implications for training. Strength Cond J 36: 103&#x2013;112, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Maloney S, Bishop C, Read PJ, Turner AN. Lower extremity stiffness: Considerations for testing, performance enhancement, and injury risk. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1156&#x2013;1166, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucher Sandbakk S, T&#xf8;nnessen E, Haugen T, Sandbakk &#xd8;. Training and coaching of female vs. male endurance athletes on their road to gold. Perceptions among successful elite athlete coaches. Dtsch Z F&#xfc;r Sportmed J Sports Med 73: 251&#x2013;258, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui M. Introduction to the K-Means clustering algorithm based on the elbow method. Account Audit Finance 1: 5&#x2013;8, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B, Layer J, Vertz C, et al. Baseline assessments of strength and balance performance and bilateral asymmetries in collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res 33: 3015&#x2013;3029, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworkin SL. &#x201c;Holding back&#x201d;: Negotiating a glass ceiling on women's muscular strength. Sociol Perspect 44: 333&#x2013;350, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu H, Li Z, Zhou X, et al. The profiles of single leg countermovement jump kinetics and sprinting in female soccer athletes. Heliyon 9(e19159): 1&#x2013;8, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao J, Ho TK. Machine learning made easy: A review of scikit-learn package in python programming language. J Educ Behav Stat 44: 348&#x2013;361, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden S, Boreham C, Doherty C, Wang D, Delahunt E. Clinical assessment of countermovement jump landing kinematics in early adolescence: Sex differences and normative values. Clin Biomech 30: 469&#x2013;474, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvat M, Ramsey V, Franklin C, et al. A method for predicting maximal strength in collegiate women athletes. J Strength Cond Res 17: 324&#x2013;328, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauhiainen S, Pohl AJ, &#xc4;yr&#xe4;m&#xf6; S, Kauppi J-P, Ferber R. A hierarchical cluster analysis to determine whether injured runners exhibit similar kinematic gait patterns. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 732&#x2013;740, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan M, Bishop C. Testing limb symmetry and asymmetry after ACL injury: Four considerations to increase its utility. Strength Cond J 46(4): 1533&#x2013;4295, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Bishop C, et al. Explosive strength and stretch-shortening-cycle capacity during ACL rehabilitation. Aspetar Sports Med J 12: 324&#x2013;331, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. Lower limb asymmetry in mechanical muscle function: A comparison between ski racers with and without ACL reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: e301&#x2013;e309, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. A comparison of lower limb stiffness and mechanical muscle function in ACL-reconstructed, elite, and adolescent alpine ski racers/ski cross athletes. J Sport Health Sci 7: 416&#x2013;424, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Morris N, Lane M, et al. Monitoring the return to sport transition after ACL injury: An alpine ski racing case study. Front Sports Act Living 2: 1&#x2013;16, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kauffmann J, Esders M, Ruff L, et al. From clustering to cluster explanations via neural networks. IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst 35: 1926&#x2013;1940, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauersen JB, Andersen TE, Andersen LB. Strength training as superior, dose-dependent and safe prevention of acute and overuse sports injuries: A systematic review, qualitative analysis and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 52: 1557&#x2013;1563, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepp&#xe4;nen M, Pasanen K, Kujala UM, et al. Stiff landings are associated with increased ACL injury risk in young female basketball and floorball players. Am J Sports Med 45: 386&#x2013;393, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RK, Wastvedt S, Pareek A, et al. Unsupervised machine learning of the combined Danish and Norwegian knee ligament registers: Identification of 5 distinct patient groups with differing ACL revision rates. Am J Sports Med 52: 881&#x2013;891, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean Z, Mossel Nbv, McKenzie M, et al. Lower extremity asymmetry values derived from multiple strength testing modes are associated with perceived functional capabilities among university athletes. Transl Sports Med 2024(5589056): 1&#x2013;11, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean ZJ, McKenzie M, Zukowski M, et al. Predicting multijoint maximal eccentric and concentric strength with force-velocity jump mechanics in collegiate athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 20: 399&#x2013;410, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean ZJ, Pasanen K, Lun V, et al. A biopsychosocial model for understanding training load, fatigue, and musculoskeletal sport injury in university athletes: A scoping review. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1177&#x2013;1188, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ, Gill ND. Strength and power profiling of athletes: Selecting tests and how to use the information for program design. Strength Cond J 35: 7&#x2013;14, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Ripley NJ, Comfort P. Force plate-derived countermovement jump normative data and benchmarks for professional rugby league players. Sensors 22: 1&#x2013;10, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Gill N, Cronin J, McGuigan M. A brief review of strength and ballistic assessment methodologies in sport. Sports Med 44: 603&#x2013;623, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf8;ller M, Zebis MK, Myklebust G, et al. &#x201c;Is it fun and does it enhance my performance?&#x201d;&#x2014;Key implementation considerations for injury prevention programs in youth handball. J Sci Med Sport 24: 1136&#x2013;1142, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Kushner AM, Brent JL, et al. The back squat: A proposed assessment of functional deficits and technical factors that limit performance. Strength Cond J 36: 4&#x2013;27, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons JL, Coen SE, Bekker S. Anterior cruciate ligament injury: Towards a gendered environmental approach. Br J Sports Med 55: 984&#x2013;990, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasanen K. Testing Training Programs for the Prevention of Running-Related Injuries. ISRCTN, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasanen K, Sepp&#xe4;nen A, Lepp&#xe4;nen M, et al. Knee laxity, joint hypermobility, femoral anteversion, hamstring extensibility and navicular drop as risk factors for non-contact ACL injury in female athletes: A 4.5-year prospective cohort study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 33(2 ksa.12625): 1&#x2013;8, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, et al. Scikit-learn: Machine learning in python. J Mach Learn Res 12: 2825&#x2013;2830, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson PA, Lovalekar M, Cruz DE, et al. Unsupervised machine learning in countermovement jump and isometric mid-thigh pull performance produces distinct combat and physical fitness clusters in male and female U.S. marine corps recruits. Mil Med 189: 38&#x2013;46, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruyn EC, Watsford ML, Murphy AJ, et al. Relationship between leg stiffness and lower body injuries in professional Australian football. J Sports Sci 30: 71&#x2013;78, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivi&#xe8;re JR, Rossi J, Jimenez-Reyes P, Morin J-B, Samozino P. Where does the one-repetition maximum exist on the force-velocity relationship in squat? Int J Sports Med 38: 1035&#x2013;1043, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secomb JL, Nimphius S, Farley ORL, et al. Relationships between lower-body muscle structure and, lower-body strength, explosiveness and eccentric leg stiffness in adolescent athletes. J Sports Sci Med 14: 691&#x2013;697, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson R, Sundberg A, Piussi R, et al. Questioning the rules of engagement: A critical analysis of the use of limb symmetry index for safe return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med 59: 376&#x2013;384, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DJ. A framework for understanding the training process leading to elite performance. Sports Med 33: 1103&#x2013;1126, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens TM, Lawson BR, DeVoe DE, Reiser RF. Gender and bilateral differences in single-leg countermovement jump performance with comparison to a double-leg jump. J Appl Biomech 23: 190&#x2013;202, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyanskaya O, Cantor M, Sherlock G, et al. Missing value estimation methods for DNA microarrays. Bioinformatics 17: 520&#x2013;525, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasudevan A, Ford E. Motivational factors and barriers towards initiating and maintaining strength training in women: A systematic review and meta-synthesis. Prev Sci 23: 674&#x2013;695, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk R, Fidos-Czuba O, Rutkowski L, et al. Predicting competitive swimming performance. Cent Eur J Sport Sci Med 9: 105&#x2013;112, 2015. Accessed November 15, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkerson GB, Colston MA, Baker CS. A sport fitness index for assessment of sport-related injury risk. Clin J Sport Med 26: 423&#x2013;428, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>