<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41553529</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-3023</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International urogynecology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Urogynecol J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Constipation as a Hidden Barrier to Pelvic Floor Tele-Rehabilitation: A Randomized Controlled Trial in Women with Stress Urinary Incontinence.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00192-025-06511-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate whether integrating constipation management into tele-supervised pelvic floor muscle training (PFMT) improves continence outcomes compared with PFMT alone, and to determine whether constipation, pelvic floor self-efficacy, body awareness, and adherence predict treatment response.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomized controlled trial, 200 women aged 18-60&#xa0;years with stress urinary incontinence (SUI) were randomized to group A (tele-supervised PFMT only) or group B (PFMT plus constipation management). All participants completed a 12-week live Zoom&#xae;-based PFMT program. In addition, group B received dietary fiber regulation, hydration guidance, bowel habit training, optimal defecation posture instruction, and osmotic laxatives when clinically indicated according to Rome IV and Wexner criteria. Outcomes-ICIQ-UI SF, 1-h pad test, Oxford pelvic floor strength, self-efficacy, body awareness, constipation severity (Wexner), bowel frequency, and quality of life (ICIQ-LUTSqol)-were assessed at baseline, week 12 and 3-month follow-up. Analyses were performed under an intention-to-treat framework with multiple imputation; longitudinal changes were examined using repeated-measures ANOVA (or Friedman tests for non-normal variables), and baseline-adjusted between-group comparisons were evaluated using ANCOVA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both groups improved significantly in urinary symptoms, leakage, muscle strength, self-efficacy, and body awareness (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). However, group B showed greater improvement in ICIQ-UI SF scores (-7.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.6 vs&#x2009;-6.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.8; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.021), pad-test leakage (-6.6&#xa0;g vs&#x2009;-5.4&#xa0;g; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.034) and quality of life (-12.0 vs&#x2009;-9.3; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.026). Constipation severity decreased only in group B (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Functional constipation reduces responsiveness to PFMT-based tele-rehabilitation in women with SUI. Integrating bowel management, self-efficacy strengthening, and body awareness into PFMT supports a multidisciplinary, gut-informed continence rehabilitation approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive license to International Urogynecological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baykan &#xc7;opuro&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;zge</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1014-8845</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Program, Department of Therapy and Rehabilitation, Incesu Ay&#x15f;e and Saffet Arslan Vocational School of Health Services, Kayseri University, Kayseri, Turkey. ozgebaykancopuroglu@kayseri.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;opuro&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-2375-6253</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Kayseri City Hospital, Kayseri, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teki&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>Dilek</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-0971-1606</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Kayseri City Hospital, Kayseri, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int Urogynecol J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567041</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0937-3462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bowel dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Constipation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress urinary incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tele-rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical Approval and Consent to Participate: This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Kayseri City Hospital (Approval No: 238) and conducted in accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to enrollment. Consent for Publication: All participants provided written consent for the anonymized publication of their data. No identifiable personal or clinical information is disclosed in this manuscript. Conflicts of interest: None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41553529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-025-06511-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00192-025-06511-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Trapani S, Villa G, Marcomini I, Bagnato E, Rinaldi S, Caglioni M, et al. Prevalence, risk factors and costs of female urinary incontinence: a multicentre cross-sectional study. Int J Urol Nurs. 2025;19(3):e70027. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijun.70027 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijun.70027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasnopolsky N, Ben Ami N, Dar G. Ultrasound assessment and self-perception of pelvic floor muscle function in women with stress urinary incontinence in different positions. Diagnostics. 2024;14(19):2230. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics14192230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics14192230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39410634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11475027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayner AM, Tang CY, Toohey K, Mendoza C, Nahon I. Opportunities and capabilities to perform pelvic floor muscle training are critical for participation: a systematic review and qualitative meta-synthesis. Phys Ther. 2022;102(10):pzac106. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzac106 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzac106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35913726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Er-Rabiai Y, Torres-Lacomba M, Casa&#xf1;a J, et al. Correlation of self-efficacy for pelvic floor muscle exercise with symptoms of stress urinary incontinence in women. Int Urogynecol J. 2024;35:1487&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-024-05818-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-024-05818-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38861006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittelbrunn CC, de Fraga R, Martins C, et al. Pelvic floor physical therapy and mindfulness: approaches for chronic pelvic pain in women&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023;307:663&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00404-022-06514-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-022-06514-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razavi SZE, Amirak A, Rahimi N, et al. The effect of biofeedback on constipation, sleep, depression, anxiety and quality of life in patients with dyssynergic defecation: a quasi-experimental study. Appl Psychophysiol Biofeedback. 2025;50:71&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10484-024-09680-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10484-024-09680-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39789199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desprez C, Bridoux V, Leroi AM. Disorders of anorectal motility: functional defecation disorders and fecal incontinence. J Visc Surg. 2022;159(1):S40-50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jviscsurg.2021.12.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jviscsurg.2021.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hage-Fransen MA, Wiezer M, Otto A, et al. Pregnancy- and obstetric-related risk factors for urinary incontinence, fecal incontinence, or pelvic organ prolapse later in life: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2021;100(3):373&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1111/aogs.14027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aogs.14027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kijmanawat A, Saraluck A, Manonai J, et al. Mobile application-based pelvic floor muscle training for treatment of stress urinary incontinence: an assessor-blind, randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2023;12(22):7003. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12227003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12227003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38002618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10672388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Mata KRU, Costa RCM, Carbone &#xc9;DSM, et al. Telehealth in the rehabilitation of female pelvic floor dysfunction: a systematic literature review. Int Urogynecol J. 2021;32(2):249&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-020-04588-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-020-04588-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLancey JO, Pipitone F. Pathophysiology and effects of pregnancy on the pelvic floor. In: Pelvic Floor, Perineal, and Anal Sphincter Trauma During Childbirth: Diagnosis, Management and Prevention. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2024. p. 17&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-43095-4_2 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhu C, Drake M. Applied anatomy and physiology. In: Abrams&#x2019; Urodynamics. 4th ed. Cham: Springer; 2021. p. 24&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119245957.ch2 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles CH, Dinning P, Scott SM, Swash M, de Wachter S. New concepts in the pathophysiology of fecal incontinence. Ann Laparosc Endosc Surg. 2022;7:1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.21037/ALES-2022-02 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/ALES-2022-02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederauer S, Hunt G, Foreman KB, Merryweather A, Hitchcock R. Intrinsic factors contributing to elevated intra-abdominal pressure. Comput Methods Biomech Biomed Eng. 2023;26(8):941&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1080/10255842.2022.2100220 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10255842.2022.2100220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roch M, Gaudreault N, Cyr MP, Venne G, Bureau NJ, Morin M. The female pelvic floor fascia anatomy: a systematic search and review. Life. 2021;11(9):900. https://doi.org/10.3390/life11090900 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life11090900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34575049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8467746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi A, Akbarpour E, Majidirad F, et al. Dyssynergic defecation: a comprehensive review on diagnosis and management. Turk J Gastroenterol. 2023;34(3):182&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.5152/tjg.2023.22148 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/tjg.2023.22148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36919830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10152153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heitmann PT, Vollebregt PF, Knowles CH, et al. Understanding the physiology of human defaecation and disorders of continence and evacuation. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18(11):751&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41575-021-00487-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41575-021-00487-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peinado-Molina RA, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez A, Mart&#xed;nez-V&#xe1;zquez S, et al. Pelvic floor dysfunction: prevalence and associated factors. BMC Public Health. 2023;23:2005. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-023-16901-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-16901-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37838661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10576367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuronen M, Hantunen S, Alanne L, et al. Pregnancy, puerperium and perinatal constipation: an observational hybrid survey on pregnant and postpartum women and age-matched non-pregnant controls. BJOG. 2021;128(6):1057&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1111/1471-0528.16559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1471-0528.16559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N, Mohamadi S, Hemmati M, et al. Global prevalence of constipation during pregnancy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2024;24:836. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12884-024-07057-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-024-07057-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11660625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzotti A, Fumagalli S, Zanini S, et al. What is known about changes in pelvic floor muscle strength and tone in women during the childbirth pathway? A scoping review. Eur J Midwifery. 2024;8:10.18332/ejm/189955. https://doi.org/10.18332/ejm/189955 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/ejm/189955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11295251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Wang B, Gao H, He C, Hua R, Liang C, et al. Vagus nerve and underlying impact on the gut microbiota&#x2013;brain axis in behavior and neurodegenerative diseases. J Inflamm Res. 2022;15:6213&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.2147/JIR.S384949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JIR.S384949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36386584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9656367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perelmuter S, Soogoor A, Maliszewski K, Grimshaw A. Investigating the overlapping presentation of irritable bowel syndrome and vulvodynia: a scoping review of the evidence and mechanisms. Sex Med Rev. 2024;12(4):559&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1093/sxmrev/qeae053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sxmrev/qeae053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39084679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neshatian L, Karmonik C, Khavari R, Shi Z, Elias S, Boone T, et al. Alterations in brain activation patterns in women with functional defecatory disorder: a novel fMRI rectal balloon expulsion study. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2022;34(12):e14389. https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14389 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35478218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti DA, Vedaei F, Tobia A, Navarreto E, Hriso C, Ross R, et al. Brain functional connectivity changes on fMRI in patients with chronic pelvic pain treated with the neuro emotional technique: a randomised controlled trial. J Obstet Gynaecol. 2025;45(1):2472767. https://doi.org/10.1080/01443615.2025.2472767 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01443615.2025.2472767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40083279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal&#x131; S, &#xd6;zengin N, Top&#xe7;uo&#x11f;lu MA. The effect of e-pelvic floor muscle training on symptoms in women with stress urinary incontinence: a randomized controlled trial. Womens Health. 2023;63(6):473&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1080/03630242.2023.2223729 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03630242.2023.2223729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y, Feng S, Tong B, Lu S, Jin Y. Effect of pelvic floor muscle training using mobile health applications for stress urinary incontinence in women: a systematic review. BMC Womens Health. 2022;22(1):400. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-022-01985-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-022-01985-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9531466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu P, Wang X, Guo P, Li Y, Zhang L, Chen Y. The effectiveness of eHealth interventions on female pelvic floor dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int Urogynecol J. 2022;33(12):3325&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-022-05222-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-022-05222-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35616695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9135393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alesha M, Sayner AM, Tang CY, Toohey K, Mendoza C, Nahon I. Opportunities and capabilities to perform pelvic floor muscle training are critical for participation: a systematic review and qualitative meta-synthesis. Phys Ther. 2022;102(10):pzac106. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzac106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzac106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittelbrunn CC, de Fraga R, Martins C, Romano R, Massaneiro T, Mello GVP, et al. Pelvic floor physical therapy and mindfulness: approaches for chronic pelvic pain in women&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023;307(3):663&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00404-022-06514-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-022-06514-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#xe7;yi&#x11f;it K, Ortanc&#x131;l &#xd6;, Tezel N, &#x15e;efik S&#xd6;, Sar&#x131;kaya F, Gayretli TK. The effect of pelvic floor health education on knowledge and awareness levels in patients with urinary incontinence. Int Urogynecol J. 2025:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-025-06350-4</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>