<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41622763</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1464-5165</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disability and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Disabil Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A foundational framework for high-intensity interval training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>20</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/09638288.2026.2617083</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to evaluate the effects of high-intensity interval training on patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and to synthesize the evidence into a Frequency, Intensity, Time, and Type framework for clinical application.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials from PubMed, EMBASE, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL) within the Cochrane Library through 14 July 2025. Trials evaluating structured high-intensity interval training programs in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease were included. Two reviewers independently extracted data and assessed methodological quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sixteen trials were included, with data from 11 pooled for meta-analysis. Compared to moderate-intensity continuous training, high-intensity interval training significantly improved walking distance, peak workload, and quality of life. High-intensity interval training combined with resistance training also yielded greater improvements in exercise capacity than usual care. No serious adverse events were directly attributed to the training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">High-intensity interval training is a safe and superior strategy compared to continuous training for enhancing outcomes in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. This review successfully translates these findings into a practical Frequency, Intensity, Time, and Type framework, providing a scientific model to standardize clinical practice and guide future research.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Fu-An</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7281-0729</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Far Eastern Memorial Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Hsuei-Chen</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-9177-8282</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Assistive Technology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Master's Program in Long-Term Care and Management, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi</LastName><ForeName>Ting-Wei</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Far Eastern Memorial Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Di</ForeName><Initials>WD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-0912-3688</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Assistive Technology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Asia Eastern University of Science and Technology, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Ching</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1472-3870</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Far Eastern Memorial Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Chao-Chun</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8242-3626</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Far Eastern Memorial Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Assistive Technology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Disabil Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207179</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0963-8288</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>High-intensity interval training is a safe and more effective rehabilitation strategy than traditional continuous training for improving exercise capacity and quality of life in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.This research translates evidence into a practical Frequency, Intensity, Time, and Type framework, offering clinicians a clear, evidence-based guide for prescribing high-intensity interval training and standardizing care.High-intensity interval training is a targeted intervention for the peripheral muscle dysfunction common in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, providing a potent stimulus that may be more effective at reversing muscle atrophy and improving physical function than moderate-intensity exercise.The intermittent structure of high-intensity interval training, with its built-in recovery periods, presents a valuable and potentially more tolerable alternative for patients with significant dyspnea who find sustained, continuous exercise difficult to maintain.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41622763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2026.2617083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>