<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41735830</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1865-1372</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of emergency medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Emerg Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Extensive thoracic spontaneous epidural hematoma presenting with position-induced transient paraplegia: successful conservative management in the resource limited settings.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">81</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12245-026-01151-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma (SSEH) is a rare condition with an estimated incidence of 0.1 per 100,000 individuals. It is usually characterized by sudden spinal pain followed by rapidly progressive neurological deficits. Surgical treatment is generally indicated if a patient presents with neurological deficits. We report a case of SSEH presenting with neurological deficits relieved after position change, recovering without surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION">The patient was a 73-year-old woman developed sudden, severe pain in the neck, back, lumbar region, and abdomen while sitting after meals. Upon arrival at the emergency department, her vital signs were stable except for hypertension. The patient was placed supine on a stretcher and became agitated because of back pain, but no motor or sensory symptoms were noted in the extremities. Pain initially improved with acetaminophen but recurred, requiring diclofenac. When attempting to sit again, complete motor and sensory deficits were noted in both lower limbs extending from the femur to the soles of the feet (the trunk was not assessed). Lower limbs muscle strength was 1/1 by Manual Muscle Test. Perineal sensory deficits and incontinence were present, leading to a diagnosis of bladder and bowel dysfunction (ASIA Grade A). Imaging revealed an extensive posterior epidural hematoma from C6 to Th12 with maximal cord compression at Th10&#x2013;12. No coagulopathy or vascular malformations were observed. The hospital was unable to provide emergency surgical decompression because of limited medical resources, including the unavailability of an on-call spine surgeon and refusal of the transfer request. The patient was managed conservatively with analgesia, blood pressure control, and hemostatic agents. Motor function recovered fully, and she was discharged independently on day 13 with only mild residual sensory impairment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">This case demonstrates a unique position-induced course; symptoms improved when supine and worsened while sitting. Treatment of SSEH is generally initiated once neurological symptoms appear. A case report described lumbar SSEH with position-induced symptoms; however, it was the opposite of the present case. This discrepancy reflects differences in position related spinal alignment. Lumbar lordosis decreases while sitting, expanding the canal, whereas thoracic kyphosis flattens when supine and increases while seated, narrowing the canal. In this patient, maximal compression at Th10&#x2013;12 was relieved when supine but exacerbated when sitting. In this case, conservative treatment was selected due to resource limitations, including the lack of an on-call spine surgeon and refusal of the transfer request. This approach ultimately resulted in the most favorable therapeutic outcome. When rapid improvement in position-induced symptoms is observed, conservative treatment may be a better option. These findings emphasize that SSEH presentation depends not only on hematoma size but also on lesion location and posture-related mechanics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murakami</LastName><ForeName>Kotaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ohda City Hospital, 1428-3 Yoshinaga, Ohda, Shimane, 694-0063, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Noriaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Matsunami General Hospital, 185-1 Dendai, Kasamatsu, Hashima, Gifu, 501-6062, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kodani</LastName><ForeName>Nobuhiro</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yasugi Daiichi Hospital, 899-1 Yasugi, Yasugi, Shimane, 692-0011, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Suzuki Internal Medicine and Ophthalmology Clinic, 532-12 Waki, Gotsu, Shimane, 695-0017, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwashita</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiaki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shimane University Hospital, 89-1 Enya-Cho, Izumo, Shimane, 693-8501, Japan. iwaci1ta@med.shimane-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency and Critical Care Medicine, Shimane University, Ennyacho 89-1, Izumo, Shimane, 693-8501, Japan. iwaci1ta@med.shimane-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Emerg Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101469435</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1865-1372</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Conservative management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lower extremity paralysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posture-dependent neurological symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thoracolumbar junction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: The patient has signed the consent. Competing interests: Yoshiaki Iwashita declares non-financial support from POSH WELLNESS LABORATORY Inc.-funded Department of Joint Research in Advanced Medicine for Electromagnetic Engineering, Shimane University.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41735830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13040710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12245-026-01151-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12245-026-01151-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Holt&#xe5;s S, Heiling M, L&#xf6;nntoft M. Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma: findings at MR imaging and clinical correlation. Radiology. 1996;199(2):409&#x2013;13. 10.1148/radiology.199.2.8668786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiology.199.2.8668786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8668786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raasck K, Habis AA, Aoude A, Sim&#xf5;es L, Barros F, Reindl R, et al. Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma management: a case series and literature review. Spinal Cord Ser Cases. 2017;3:16043. 10.1038/scsandc.2016.43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/scsandc.2016.43</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5289268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28382214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa J, DeVine JG. Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma: literature review. J Spine Surg. 2017;3(1):58&#x2013;63. 10.21037/jss.2017.02.04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jss.2017.02.04</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5386890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28435919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson A, Ong AGJ, Zhang YH. Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma - an uncommon cause of acute neurologic deficit in the emergency department: a case report. Int J Emerg Med. 2025;18(1):236. 10.1186/s12245-025-01031-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12245-025-01031-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12604215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang D, Iken S, Elbadri S, Falgiani M, Ganti L. Spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma: a case of a benign presentation and emergency department management. Cureus. 2022;14(3):e23532. 10.7759/cureus.23532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee WT, Fun JRS, Yeo YWM. Cervical epidural hematoma: a case series highlighting uncommon causes. Int J Emerg Med. 2024;17(1):115. 10.1186/s12245-024-00693-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12245-024-00693-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11378571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39242513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatlo B, Panciani PP, Bijlenga P, Schaller K. Cyclic alternation of paraplegia and leg pain as symptoms of a giant spontaneous spinal epidural haematoma. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2014;156(11):2155&#x2013;57. 10.1007/s00701-014-2245-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00701-014-2245-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25260927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na XBM, Khoo SMK. Stroke-like manifestation of a spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma with spontaneous resolution: a case report. Int J Emerg Med. 2023;16(1):10. 10.1186/s12245-023-00478-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12245-023-00478-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9940068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36803212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao S, Hirata H, Yoshihara T, Kobayashi T, Tsukamoto M, Egashira Y, et al. Conservative management of spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma: a case report with favorable prognosis. Clin Case Rep. 2024;12(5):e8760. 10.1002/ccr3.8760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11056786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38686020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitta K, Imamura H, Kamijo H, Maeda Y, Uchida M, Akita M, et al. Outcomes of conservative management of spontaneous spinal epidural hematomas: a retrospective study. Cureus. 2025;17(6):e85430. 10.7759/cureus.85430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12233866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40625464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J, Li B, Liu S, Liu Y, Zhao Y. Case report: a patient with spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma recovered after conservative treatment. Front Med (Lausanne). 2025;12:1509903. 10.3389/fmed.2025.1509903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1509903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11832481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39967594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg N, Cutsforth-Gregory J, Oushy S, Huynh T, Savastano LE, Cloft HJ, et al. Anatomy of spinal venous drainage for the neurointerventionalist: from puncture site to intervertebral foramen. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2022;43(4):517&#x2013;25. 10.3174/ajnr.A7409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A7409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8993202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35086801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevillotte T, Coudert P, Cawley D, Bouloussa H, Mazas S, Boissi&#xe8;re L, et al. Influence of posture on relationships between pelvic parameters and lumbar lordosis: comparison of the standing, seated, and supine positions. A preliminary study. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2018;104(5):565&#x2013;68. 10.1016/j.otsr.2018.06.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.otsr.2018.06.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirasawa Y, Bashir WA, Smith FW, Magnusson ML, Pope MH, Takahashi K. Postural changes of the dural sac in the lumbar spines of asymptomatic individuals using positional stand-up magnetic resonance imaging. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2007;32(4):E136&#x2013;40. 10.1097/01.brs.0000255202.94153.ca.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17304123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovecchio F, Lafage R, Elysee JC, Huang A, Ang B, Bannwarth M, et al. The utility of supine radiographs in the assessment of thoracic flexibility and risk of proximal junctional kyphosis. J Neurosurg Spine. 2021;35(1):110&#x2013;16. 10.3171/2020.11.Spine201565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2020.11.Spine201565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hey HW, Wong CG, Lau ET, Tan KA, Lau LL, Liu KG, et al. Differences in erect sitting and natural sitting spinal alignment-insights into a new paradigm and implications in deformity correction. Spine J. 2017;17(2):183&#x2013;89. 10.1016/j.spinee.2016.08.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2016.08.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27562103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker NA, Veeger NJ, Vergeer RA, Groen RJ. Prognosis after spinal cord and cauda compression in spontaneous spinal epidural hematomas. Neurology. 2015;84(18):1894&#x2013;903. 10.1212/wnl.0000000000001545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000001545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25862799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JJ, Kuh SU, Cho YE. Surgical management of spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma. Eur Spine J. 2006;15(6):998&#x2013;1004. 10.1007/s00586-005-0965-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00586-005-0965-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16758110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domenicucci M, Mancarella C, Santoro G, Dugoni DE, Ramieri A, Arezzo MF, et al. Spinal epidural hematomas: personal experience and literature review of more than 1000 cases. J Neurosurg Spine. 2017;27(2):198&#x2013;208. 10.3171/2016.12.Spine15475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2016.12.Spine15475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28574329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>