<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41876712</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5527</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scientific advances in post-exercise hypotension: a bibliometric review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41371-026-01129-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to perform a bibliometric review to map scientific advances and research trends related to post-exercise hypotension (PEH), a transient blood pressure reduction following physical exercise, increasingly recognized as a non-pharmacological strategy for hypertension management. A comprehensive search was conducted on Scopusdatabase to identify publications on PEH from 1985 to 2024. Metadata from 440 selected articles were analyzed using VOSviewer&#x2122; and Gephi&#x2122; software to construct keyword co-occurrence networks and identify emerging research topics, influential authors, and leading institutions. Bibliometric analysis revealed an increasing trend in PEH publications over the past decade, with Brazil and the United States leading in research output. High-intensity interval training, isometric resistance exercise and nutritional interventions emerged as key topics. Findings emphasized exercise intensity, recovery posture, and dietary strategies modulate PEH magnitude and duration. Complex autonomic and vascular factors were consistently implicated as physiological mechanisms of PEH, supporting the importance of individualized exercise prescriptions. This review highlights the growing clinical and scientific importance of PEH research. Notable gaps include the need for standardized assessment methodologies, greater biomarker utilization, and further evaluation of multimodal exercise-nutrition strategies to improve clinical translation. Future studies should expand PEH research in clinically high-risk and underrepresented groups (e.g., older adults and individuals with cardiometabolic or renal comorbidities), using harmonized protocols to enhance comparability and applicability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sezana-Costa</LastName><ForeName>Samara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-1048-5173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Moresi</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo Amadeu Dutra</ForeName><Initials>EAD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project Manager - Apple Developer Academy/Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Rosa</LastName><ForeName>Thiago Dos Santos</ForeName><Initials>TDS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0418-0945</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Graduate Program in Human Movement Sciences, State University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Jacarezinho, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Genomic Science and Biotechnology, Catholic University of Bras&#xed;lia, Brasilia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santos</LastName><ForeName>Clarcson Placido Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o</ForeName><Initials>CPC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group on Metabolic Diseases, Physical Exercise and Health Technologies, Bahiana School of Medicine and Public Health, Salvador, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9094-1493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (iBiMED), School of Health Sciences, University of Aveiro, Aveiro, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Alexandre Sergio</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Laboratory of Physical Training Studies Applied to Performance and Health, Federal University of Para&#xed;ba, Jo&#xe3;o Pessoa, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sim&#xf5;es</LastName><ForeName>Herbert Gustavo</ForeName><Initials>HG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polito</LastName><ForeName>Marcos Doederlein</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6720-007X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group of Cardiovascular Response and Exercise, Londrina State University, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farinatti</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Physical Activity and Health Promotion, Institute of Physical Education and Sports, University of Rio de Janeiro State, Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Brazil;, University of Rio de Janeiro State, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pescatello</LastName><ForeName>Linda S</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5841-798X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Correa</LastName><ForeName>Hugo de Luca</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3080-9391</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Physical Education Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Brazil. hugo.efucb@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moraes</LastName><ForeName>Milton Rocha</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Laboratory of Physical Training Studies Applied to Performance and Health, Federal University of Para&#xed;ba, Jo&#xe3;o Pessoa, Brazil. mrmoraes70@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, College of Education and Technology Phorte, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. mrmoraes70@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8811625</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0950-9240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no conflict of interest. The results of the study are presented clearly, honestly, and without fabrication, falsification, or inappropriate data manipulation. LSP is owner of P3-EX LLC, a software company that prioritizes, prescribes, and personalizes exercise (P3-EX) for individuals with cardiovascular diseaserisk factors, and inventor of the intellectual property of P3-EX which could benefit from this research.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41876712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41371-026-01129-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41371-026-01129-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>De Brito LC, Fecchio RY, Pe&#xe7;anha T, Lima A, Halliwill J, de Moraes Forjaz CL. Recommendations in post-exercise hypotension: concerns, best practices and interpretation. International journal of sports medicine. 2019;40:487&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0938-4415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes MR, Bacurau RFP, Sim&#xf5;es HG, Campbell CSG, Pudo MA, Wasinski F, et al. Effect of 12 weeks of resistance exercise on post-exercise hypotension in stage 1 hypertensive individuals. Journal of human hypertension. 2012;26:533&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jhh.2011.67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21734721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Fargo AE, Leach CN Jr, Scherzer HH. Short-term effect of dynamic exercise on arterial blood pressure. Circulation. 1991;83:1557&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.83.5.1557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2022015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brasil IA, Silva JCP, Pescatello LS, Farinatti P. Central and peripheral mechanisms underlying postexercise hypotension: A scoping review. Journal of Hypertension. 2024;42:751&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38525904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpio-Rivera E, Moncada-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Salazar-Rojas W, Solera-Herrera A. Acute effects of exercise on blood pressure: a meta-analytic investigation. Arquivos brasileiros de cardiologia. 2016;106:422&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4914008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti P, Polito MD, Massaferri R, Monteiro WD, Vasconcelos D, Johnson BT, et al. Postexercise hypotension due to resistance exercise is not mediated by autonomic control: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Autonomic Neuroscience. 2021;234:102825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2021.102825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34118764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Franklin BA, Fagard R, Farquhar WB, Kelley GA, Ray CA. Exercise and hypertension. Medicine &amp; science in sports &amp; exercise. 2004;36:533&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000115224.88514.3A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly K, Yeung PK. Post-Exercise hypotension: An alternative management strategy for hypertension and cardiovascular disease? In: MDPI. 2023;12:4456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iellamo F, Caminiti G, Montano M, Manzi V, Franchini A, Mancuso A, et al. Prolonged post-exercise hypotension: effects of different exercise modalities and training statuses in elderly patients with hypertension. International journal of environmental research and public health. 2021;18:3229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18063229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8003987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti P, Pescatello LS, Crisafulli A, Taiar R, Fernandez AB. Post-exercise hypotension: clinical applications and potential mechanisms. Front Physiol. 2022;13:899497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.899497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9039323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliwill JR, Buck TM, Lacewell AN, Romero SA. Postexercise hypotension and sustained postexercise vasodilatation: what happens after we exercise? Experimental physiology. 2013;98:7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2011.058065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22872658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day C, Wu Y, Pescatello LS. Evaluating the methodological quality of postexercise hypotension aerobic exercise interventions. Frontiers in Physiology. 2022;13:851950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.851950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8960741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards JJ, Deenmamode AH, Griffiths M, Arnold O, Cooper NJ, Wiles JD, et al. Exercise training and resting blood pressure: a large-scale pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. British journal of sports medicine. 2023;57:1317&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanssen H, Pescatello LS. Is isometric exercise training the best FIT for exercise prescription in the prevention and treatment of arterial hypertension? British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2024;58:231&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-107743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38123947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen CH, Thomas SH, Bentley DC. A brief experimental examination of post-exercise hypotension and the impact of calculation method. Blood Pressure Monitoring. 2021;26:279&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBP.0000000000000533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza LR, Vicente JB, Melo GR, Moraes VC, Olher RR, Sousa IC, et al. Acute hypotension after moderate-intensity handgrip exercise in hypertensive elderly people. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2018;32:2971&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamim CJR, da Silva LSL, Valenti VE, Gon&#xe7;alves LS, Porto AA, J&#xfa;nior MFT, et al. Effects of dietary inorganic nitrate on blood pressure during and post exercise: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized placebo-controlled trials. Free Radical Biology and Medicine. 2024;215:36&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2024.02.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Goulding RP, M&#xfc;ndel T, Schlader ZJ, Cotter JD, Koga S, et al. Interactive effects of exercise intensity and recovery posture on postexercise hypotension. American Journal of Physiology-Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology. 2024;326:R567&#x2013;R577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00036.2024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38646812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11381012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casonatto J, Cavalari JV. A single dosage of L-arginine oral supplementation induced post-aerobic exercise hypotension in hypertensive patients. Journal of Dietary Supplements. 2023;20:735&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19390211.2022.2106006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35903950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalves MDCR, Miranda Neto M, Cavalcante IG, Sebadelhe VR, Souza MF, Neves JP, et al. 200.000 IU of vitamin D does not reduce resting Blood Pressure and Inhibit Post-Exercise Hypotension in elderly women: a pilot study. Anais da Academia Brasileira de Ci&#xea;ncias. 2020;92:e20190227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0001-3765202020190227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32187256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpes LO, Domingues LB, Bertoletti O, Fuchs SC, Ferrari R. Inter-individual responses of post-exercise hypotension in older adults with hypertension: An exploratory analysis of different exercise modalities. Frontiers in Physiology. 2022;13:1050609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.1050609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36505064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9727289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters MC, Schmetzer J, M&#xf6;ser CV, Hahnefeld L, Angioni C, Thomas D, et al. Exercise-induced changes in bioactive lipids might serve as potential predictors of post-exercise hypotension. A pilot study in healthy volunteers. Cells. 2020;9:2111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells9092111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7563406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung PK, Kolathuru SS, Mohammadizadeh S, Akhoundi F, Linderfield B. Adenosine 5&#x2032;-triphosphate metabolism in red blood cells as a potential biomarker for post-exercise hypotension and a drug target for cardiovascular protection. Metabolites. 2018;8:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/metabo8020030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29724022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6027528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan PA, Day CA, Berkowsky RS, Zaleski AL, Gao S, Taylor BA, et al. Reliability and time course of postexercise hypotension during exercise training among adults with hypertension. Journal of Cardiovascular Development and Disease. 2024;11:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcdd11020042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38392256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10889392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou Y, Sun N, Zhang M, Qiu Y, Wang J, Chen J. Trends in exercise for hypertension: a bibliometric analysis. Frontiers in Cardiovascular Medicine. 2023;10:1260569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2023.1260569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37937288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10627159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aria M, Cuccurullo C. bibliometrix: An R-tool for comprehensive science mapping analysis. Journal of informetrics. 2017;11:959&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joi.2017.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gephi: an open source software for exploring and manipulating networks. Proceedings of the international AAAI conference on web and social media, 2009;3:361&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moresi E, Pinho I, Costa A An&#xe1;lise bibliom&#xe9;trica: uma abordagem quantitativa e qualitativa. 18th CONTECSI 2021-Proceedings. 2021; 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Eck N, Waltman L. Software survey: VOSviewer, a computer program for bibliometric mapping. scientometrics. 2009;84:523&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20585380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2883932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>