<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41869237</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers to Buprenorphine Prescribing for Opioid Use Disorder Among Louisiana Family Physicians: A Pilot Survey Study With Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103848</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103848</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103848</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103848</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Opioid use disorder is a prevalent and complex condition encountered in primary care. Buprenorphine is widely recognized as an effective pharmacologic treatment, yet it is not routinely incorporated into family medicine practices. This study aimed to assess perceived barriers to buprenorphine prescribing among Louisiana family physicians and to contextualize these barriers through a narrative review focused on practical implementation strategies. Methods This pilot, cross-sectional survey study was conducted among practicing family physicians in Louisiana and approved by the Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center-Shreveport Institutional Review Board (IRB). The anonymous, electronic survey was distributed to non-resident members of the Louisiana Academy of Family Physicians (LAFP) in September 2023 using a web-based platform. The survey assessed current buprenorphine prescribing practices and perceived barriers among non-prescribing respondents. Descriptive statistics were used to summarize results. Results A total of 65 family physicians completed the survey. Seventeen respondents (26%) reported actively prescribing buprenorphine for opioid use disorder, while 48 (74%) did not. Barrier-related items were completed only by non-prescribers (n = 48). The most frequently reported barriers included concern about attracting disruptive patients (54%), insufficient time to initiate and manage treatment (50%), lack of access to substance use disorder specialists (50%), insufficient education or training in opioid use disorder management (48%), concerns about diversion or misuse (37.5%), and limited availability of mental health services (37.5%). Regulatory concerns, including fear of Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) intrusion, were reported by 27% of respondents, while fewer expressed concerns regarding safety, effectiveness, reimbursement, or practice partner resistance. Conclusions In this pilot survey of Louisiana family physicians, most respondents did not prescribe buprenorphine despite recognizing the ongoing need for opioid use disorder treatment in their communities. Barriers to prescribing were multifactorial and primarily related to time constraints, educational gaps, perceived clinic disruption, and limited support resources rather than doubts about medication safety or efficacy. These findings highlight opportunities for targeted educational, structural, and workflow-focused interventions to expand medication for opioid use disorder (MOUD) delivery in family medicine and improve access to evidence-based opioid use disorder treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Pippin et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pippin</LastName><ForeName>Micah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center, Alexandria, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Rapides Regional Medical Center, Alexandria, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">buprenorphine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication for opioid use disorder (moud)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication-assisted treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid use disorder (oud)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">substance use disorder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center in Shreveport issued approval STUDY00002474. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41869237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13003184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS). U.S. Overdose Deaths Decrease in 2023, First Time Since 2018.  [
Dec;
2025 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/releases/20240515.html https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/releases/20240515.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of opioid use disorder: 2024 update to the national clinical practice guideline. Yakovenko I, Mukaneza Y, Germ&#xe9; K, et al. CMAJ. 2024;196:0&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11573384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39532476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance misuse in adults: a primary care approach. Kowalchuk A, Gonzalez SJ, Zoorob RJ. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38804757/ Am Fam Physician. 2024;109:430&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38804757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine therapy for opioid use disorder. Zoorob R, Kowalchuk A, Mejia de Grubb M. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29671504/ Am Fam Physician. 2018;97:313&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrating buprenorphine treatment for opioid use with primary care is associated with greater retention in treatment. Mirer AG, Tiemstra JD, Hammes NE, Cloum HM, LaFavor KJ. J Am Board Fam Med. 2022;35:206&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medication-assisted treatment for opioid use disorder in a rural family medicine practice. Deyo-Svendsen M, Cabrera Svendsen M, Walker J, Hodges A, Oldfather R, Mansukhani MP. J Prim Care Community Health. 2020;11:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7278292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32507023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geographic and specialty distribution of US physicians trained to treat opioid use disorder. Rosenblatt RA, Andrilla CH, Catlin M, Larson EH. Ann Fam Med. 2015;13:23&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4291261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25583888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A survey of barriers and facilitators to the adoption of buprenorphine prescribing after implementation of a New Jersey-wide incentivized DATA-2000 waiver training program. Nyaku AN, Zerbo EA, Chen C, et al. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24:179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10851589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Expanding buprenorphine use in primary care: changing the culture. Leiser A, Robles M. Perm J. 2022;26:177&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9662249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35933665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary care professionals' perspectives on tailoring buprenorphine training for rural practice. Fenstemaker C, Abrams EA, Obringer B, King K, Dhanani LY, Franz B. J Rural Health. 2024;40:671&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11399318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38486066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increasing capacity for treatment of opioid use disorder in rural primary care practices. Zittleman L, Curcija K, Nease DE Jr, et al. Ann Fam Med. 2022;20:18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35074763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facilitators of and barriers to buprenorphine initiation in the emergency department: a scoping review. Bozinoff N, Grennell E, Soobiah C, et al. Lancet Reg Health Am. 2024;38:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11459582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attitudes of primary care physicians toward prescribing buprenorphine: a narrative review. Louie DL, Assefa MT, McGovern MP. BMC Fam Pract. 2019;20:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6857230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31729957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers to primary care physicians prescribing buprenorphine. Hutchinson E, Catlin M, Andrilla CH, Baldwin LM, Rosenblatt RA. Ann Fam Med. 2014;12:128&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3948759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers rural physicians face prescribing buprenorphine for opioid use disorder. Andrilla CH, Coulthard C, Larson EH. Ann Fam Med. 2017;15:359&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5505456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28694273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analysis of barriers to adoption of buprenorphine maintenance therapy by family physicians. DeFlavio JR, Rolin SA, Nordstrom BR, Kazal LA Jr. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25651434/ Rural Remote Health. 2015;15:3019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25651434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predicting aberrant behaviors in opioid-treated patients: preliminary validation of the opioid risk tool. Webster LR, Webster RM. Pain Med. 2005;6:432&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16336480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development and validation of the current opioid misuse measure. Butler SF, Budman SH, Fernandez KC, Houle B, Benoit C, Katz N, Jamison RN. Pain. 2007;130:144&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17493754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) Wesson DR, Ling W. J Psychoactive Drugs. 2003;35:253&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12924748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opioid use disorder assessment tools and drug screening. Ducharme J, Moore S. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6699803/ Mo Med. 2019;116:318&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6699803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Home- versus office-based buprenorphine inductions for opioid-dependent patients. Sohler NL, Li X, Kunins HV, Sacajiu G, Giovanniello A, Whitley S, Cunningham CO. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2010;38:153&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2849656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19801178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measurement-based care using DSM-5 for opioid use disorder: can we make opioid medication treatment more effective? Marsden J, Tai B, Ali R, Hu L, Rush AJ, Volkow N. Addiction. 2019;114:1346&#x2013;1353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louisiana Department of Health. Louisiana Opioid Data Surveillance System.  [
Dec;
2025 
]. 2025. https://lodss.ldh.la.gov/ https://lodss.ldh.la.gov/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobilizing primary care against the opioid crisis in the post X-waiver era. Incze MA, Garland EL. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38:3618&#x2013;3620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The end of the X-waiver: excitement, apprehension, and opportunity. LeFevre N, St Louis J, Worringer E, Younkin M, Stahl N, Sorcinelli M. J Am Board Fam Med. 2023;36:867&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37704389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>After the MATE act: integrating buprenorphine prescribing into mainstream family medicine education and practice. Sokol R. Fam Med. 2024;56:74&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10932557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38055851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family physicians play key role in bridging the gap in access to opioid use disorder treatment. Abraham R, Wilkinson E, Jabbarpour Y, Bazemore A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32603069/ Am Fam Physician. 2020;102:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for disease control and prevention. buprenorphine dispensing data and maps.  [
Dec;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.cdc.gov/overdose-prevention/data-research/facts-stats/buprenorphine-dispensing-maps.html https://www.cdc.gov/overdose-prevention/data-research/facts-stats/buprenorphine-dispensing-maps.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Screening for unhealthy drug use: US preventive services task force recommendation statement. Krist AH, Davidson KW, Mangione CM, et al. JAMA. 2020;323:2301&#x2013;2309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32515821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence lacking to support universal unhealthy drug use screening. Coles S, Vosooney A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33448770/ Am Fam Physician. 2021;103:72&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Common questions about buprenorphine treatment for opioid use disorder. Tiemstra JD. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40238975/ Am Fam Physician. 2025;111:330&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40238975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reconsidering the usefulness of adding naloxone to buprenorphine. Blazes CK, Morrow JD. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:549272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7517938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine treatment in pregnancy and maternal-infant outcomes. Krishnapura SR, McNeer E, Loch SF, et al. JAMA Health Forum. 2025;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12035657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40287986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative safety of in utero exposure to buprenorphine combined with naloxone vs buprenorphine alone. Straub L, Bateman BT, Hern&#xe1;ndez-D&#xed;az S, et al. JAMA. 2024;332:805&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11320336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39133511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of buprenorphine-naloxone in pregnancy: a systematic review of the literature. Ordean A, Tubman-Broeren M. Pathophysiology. 2023;30:27&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9944489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36810423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine treatment for adolescents and young adults with opioid use disorders: a narrative review. Borodovsky JT, Levy S, Fishman M, Marsch LA. J Addict Med. 2018;12:170&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5970018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29432333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of buprenorphine induction strategies: patient-centered home-based inductions versus standard-of-care office-based inductions. Cunningham CO, Giovanniello A, Li X, Kunins HV, Roose RJ, Sohler NL. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2011;40:349&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21310583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine maintenance vs. placebo for opioid dependence. Raleigh MF. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28290640/ Am Fam Physician. 2017;95:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28290640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine maintenance versus placebo or methadone maintenance for opioid dependence. Mattick RP, Kimber J, Breen C, Davoli M. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;3:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of daily doses of buprenorphine with urgent health care utilization. Axeen S, Pacula RL, Merlin JS, Gordon AJ, Stein BD. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11425142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39320889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence on buprenorphine dose limits: a review. Grande LA, Cundiff D, Greenwald MK, Murray M, Wright TE, Martin SA. J Addict Med. 2023;17:509&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10547105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. food and drug administration. FDA recommends changes to labeling for transmucosal buprenorphine products indicated to treat opioid use disorder.  [
Dec;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-safety-and-availability/fda-recommends-changes-labeling-transmucosal-buprenorphine-products-indicated-treat-opioid-use https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-safety-and-availability/fda-recommends-changes-labeling-transmucosal-buprenorphine-products-indicated-treat-opioid-use</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine after nonfatal opioid overdose: reduced mortality risk in medicare disability beneficiaries. Samples H, Nowels MA, Williams AR, Olfson M, Crystal S. Am J Prev Med. 2023;65:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10293066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36906496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between buprenorphine treatment duration and mortality: a multi-site cohort study of people who discontinued treatment. Glanz JM, Binswanger IA, Clarke CL, et al. Addiction. 2023;118:97&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9722535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute care, prescription opioid use, and overdose following discontinuation of long-term buprenorphine treatment for opioid use disorder. Williams AR, Samples H, Crystal S, Olfson M. Am J Psychiatry. 2020;177:117&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does buprenorphine reduce mortality in adults with opioid use disorder compared with methadone? Wu R, Whiteley M, VanGompel E. Evid-Based Pract. 2024;27:10&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of buprenorphine and methadone on mortality: a primary care cohort study in the United Kingdom. Hickman M, Steer C, Tilling K, et al. Addiction. 2018;113:1461&#x2013;1476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6282737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29672985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases. Bethesda, MD: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases; [ Dec; 2025 ]. 2020. LiverTox: Clinical and Research Information on Drug-Induced Liver Injury.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine/Naloxone and methadone effects on laboratory indices of liver health: a randomized trial. Saxon AJ, Ling W, Hillhouse M, et al. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2013;128:71&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and medication treatment of opioid use disorder among primary care patients with hepatitis C and HIV. Tsui JI, Akosile MA, Lapham GT, et al. J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36:930&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobile low-threshold buprenorphine integrated with infectious disease services. Rosecrans A, Harris R, Saxton RE, et al. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2022;133:108553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8702567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appropriate use of drug testing in clinical addiction medicine. Jarvis M, Williams J, Hurford M, et al. J Addict Med. 2017;11:163&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28557958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of adherence monitoring in buprenorphine treatment: a pilot study using timed drug assays to determine accuracy of testing. Jamshidi N, Athavale A, Tremonti C, et al. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2023;89:1938&#x2013;1947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10952243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of buprenorphine diversion and misuse: the current evidence base and experiences from around the world. Lofwall MR, Walsh SL. J Addict Med. 2014;8:315&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4177012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25221984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing motivations for nonprescribed buprenorphine use among rural Appalachian substance users. McDonald MJ, DeVeaugh-Geiss AM, Chilcoat HD, Havens JR. J Addict Med. 2023;17:95&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36044288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Examining buprenorphine diversion through a harm reduction lens: an agent-based modeling study. Adams JW, Duprey M, Khan S, Cance J, Rice DP, Bobashev G. Harm Reduct J. 2023;20:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictive factors for relapse in patients on buprenorphine maintenance. Ferri M, Finlayson AJ, Wang L, Martin PR. Am J Addict. 2014;23:62&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3922612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24313243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine treatment for opioid use disorder: an overview. Shulman M, Wai JM, Nunes EV. CNS Drugs. 2019;33:567&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6585403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31062259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary care providers and specialists deliver comparable buprenorphine treatment quality. Gertner AK, Robertson AG, Powell BJ, Jones H, Silberman P, Domino ME. Health Aff (Millwood) 2020;39:1395&#x2013;1404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7895292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32744950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary care-based models for the treatment of opioid use disorder: a scoping review. Korthuis PT, McCarty D, Weimer M, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2017;166:268&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient satisfaction with primary care office-based buprenorphine/naloxone treatment. Barry DT, Moore BA, Pantalon MV, et al. J Gen Intern Med. 2007;22:242&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1824745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17356993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The value of treating opioid use disorder in family medicine: from the patient perspective. Kane C, Leiner C, Harless C, Foley KA, Fagan EB, Wilson CG. J Am Board Fam Med. 2020;33:611&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychosocial combined with agonist maintenance treatments versus agonist maintenance treatments alone for treatment of opioid dependence. Amato L, Minozzi S, Davoli M, Vecchi S. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counseling plus buprenorphine-naloxone maintenance therapy for opioid dependence. Fiellin DA, Pantalon MV, Chawarski MC, Moore BA, Sullivan LE, O'Connor PG, Schottenfeld RS. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:365&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16870915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimizing psychosocial support during office-based buprenorphine treatment in primary care: Patients' experiences and preferences. Fox AD, Masyukova M, Cunningham CO. Subst Abus. 2016;37:70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4801741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26566712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emergency department-initiated buprenorphine/naloxone treatment for opioid dependence: a randomized clinical trial. D'Onofrio G, O'Connor PG, Pantalon MV, et al. JAMA. 2015;313:1636&#x2013;1644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25919527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Improving transitions of care for patients initiated on buprenorphine for opioid use disorder from the emergency departments in King County, Washington. Fockele CE, Duber HC, Finegood B, Morse SC, Whiteside LK. J Am Coll Emerg Physicians Open. 2021;2:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identification, management, and transition of care for patients with opioid use disorder in the emergency department. Duber HC, Barata IA, Cio&#xe8;-Pe&#xf1;a E, et al. Ann Emerg Med. 2018;72:420&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-hospitalization care transition strategies for patients with substance use disorders: a narrative review and taxonomy. Incze MA, Kelley AT, James H, Nolan S, Stofko A, Fordham C, Gordon AJ. J Gen Intern Med. 2024;39:837&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11043281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early-career and graduating physicians more likely to prescribe buprenorphine. Peterson LE, Morgan ZJ, Eden AR. J Am Board Fam Med. 2020;33:7&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrating buprenorphine treatment into family medicine resident clinic. Tiemstra JD, Walsh LH. Fam Med. 2020;52:653&#x2013;655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buprenorphine waiver attitudes among primary care providers. Lai B, Croghan I, Ebbert JO. J Prim Care Community Health. 2022;13:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35822763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teaching residents to prescribe buprenorphine for opioid use disorder: insights from a community-based residency program. Cavitt L, St Louis J, Barr WB, Dono R, Weida N, Sorcinelli M. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2022;132:108621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34538691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of office-based buprenorphine prescribers for medicare patients. Abraham R, Wilkinson E, Jabbarpour Y, Petterson S, Bazemore A. J Am Board Fam Med. 2020;33:9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American society of addiction medicine: national practice guideline for the treatment of opioid use disorder.  [
Jan;
2026 
]. 2025. https://www.asam.org/quality-care/clinical-guidelines/national-practice-guideline https://www.asam.org/quality-care/clinical-guidelines/national-practice-guideline</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Providers slinical support system: PCSS training and mentoring for opioid use disorder&#xD;
.  [
Jan;
2026 
]. 2025. https://pcssnow.org https://pcssnow.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance abuse and mental health services administration: tip 63: medications for opioid use disorder.  [
Jan;
2026 
]. 2025. https://library.samhsa.gov/product/tip-63-medications-opioid-use-disorder/pep21-02-01-002 https://library.samhsa.gov/product/tip-63-medications-opioid-use-disorder/pep21-02-01-002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AAFP online CME: substance use disorders edition 2.  [
Jan;
2026 
]. 2025. https://www.aafp.org/cme/all/substance-use-disorders.html#:~:text=March%2019%2C%202027,caring%20for%20patients%20and%20communities https://www.aafp.org/cme/all/substance-use-disorders.html#:~:text=March%2019%2C%202027,caring%20for%20patients%20and%20communities</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Providers Clinical Support System. Centers for disease control and prevention: overdose prevention: treatment of opioid use disorder.  [
Jan;
2026 
]. 2025. https://www.cdc.gov/overdose-prevention/treatment/opioid-use-disorder.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com https://www.cdc.gov/overdose-prevention/treatment/opioid-use-disorder.html?utm_source=chatgpt.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Removal of medicaid prior authorization requirements and buprenorphine treatment for opioid use disorder. Christine PJ, Larochelle MR, Lin LA, McBride J, Tipirneni R. JAMA Health Forum. 2023;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10589810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37862034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Financing buprenorphine treatment in primary care: a microsimulation model. Fried JE, Basu S, Phillips RS, Landon BE. Ann Fam Med. 2020;18:535&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7708288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33168682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payment-related barriers to medications for opioid use disorder: a critical review of the literature and real-world application. Bowser D, Bohler R, Davis MT, Hodgkin D, Horgan C. J Subst Use Addict Treat. 2024;165:209441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11463342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrating buprenorphine for opioid use disorder into rural, primary care settings. Wyse JJ, Eckhardt A, Newell S, et al. J Gen Intern Med. 2024;39:2142&#x2013;2149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11347530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38955895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waiting room ambience and provision of opioid substitution therapy in general practice. Holliday SM, Magin PJ, Dunbabin JS, et al. Med J Aust. 2012;196:391&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22471540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>