<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41178985</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of high vs. low volume of the nordic hamstring curl on hamstring muscle architecture and eccentric strength in soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1631205</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1631205</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1631205</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1631205</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hamstring strain injuries (HSI) remain a significant problem in professional soccer, as this injury is the most prevalent. Nordic hamstring exercise (NHE) is the most researched exercise regarding its effect on modifiable factors of HSI. However, there is still debate about the minimal effective dosage for this exercise. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed (1) to analyse the effects of low- and high-volume NHE on eccentric strength and hamstring muscle architecture in soccer players, and (2) identify gaps in the literature to guide future research. Three electronic databases (PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus) were searched, and 11 studies met the inclusion criteria. Pooled effect sizes (Hedges' g) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) were calculated using a random-effects model. High-volume NHE interventions significantly improved eccentric hamstring strength (g = 0.77, 95% CI 0.49-1.06, p &lt; 0.001, I<sup>2</sup> = 51%), fascicle length (g = 0.43, 95% CI 0.20-0.65, p &lt; 0.001, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), and muscle thickness (g = 0.48, 95% CI 0.28-0.68, p &lt; 0.001, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). Effects on pennation angle were non-significant (g = - 0.16, 95% CI -0.38-0.06, p = 0.16). Low-volume protocols significantly increased eccentric strength (g = 0.46, 95% CI 0.06-0.87, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%) but did not result in meaningful changes in fascicle length, pennation angle, or muscle thickness. For eccentric torque, neither high or low volume interventions produced significant effects (both g &#x2248; 0.04, p = 0.74, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). Control groups across all outcomes showed only trivial or negative changes. Results indicate that high volume of NHE (&#x223c;2-3 sets of 8-12 repetitions/2-3 times per week) significantly increases peak eccentric strength, fascicle length of biceps femoris long head, and muscle thickness, while pennation angle shows only trivial increase. Low volume of NHE (&#x223c;1-2 sets of 3-5 repetitions/1-2 times per week) shows a similar effect on peak eccentric hamstring strength, but there are no improvements in hamstring muscle architecture. Additionally, the effect of both types of volume on hamstring eccentric peak torque seems to be inconsistent. The variability of different testing methods on isokinetic strength and small correlations between other methods introduce challenges in comparisons with eccentric strength outcomes. A high volume of NHE seems to influence hamstring architecture adaptations better than low volume despite no differences in eccentric peak strength. Factors such as the player's different level (amateur, semi-professional or professional), previous experience with NHE, and compliance significantly influence the training outcomes. Future research is needed to better determine the effect of low volume of NHE on the hamstring architecture adaptations in soccer players regarding previous experience with NHE and playing level. Furthermore, standardization of assessment tools and outcome measures is critical for future comparisons with isokinetic dynamometry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Cholp and Zemkov&#xe1;.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cholp</LastName><ForeName>Jozef</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Medical Sciences, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports, Comenius University in Bratislava, Bratislava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zemkov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Erika</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Medical Sciences, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports, Comenius University in Bratislava, Bratislava, Slovakia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee flexors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle force production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle morphology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41178985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12572617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1631205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1631205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P., Andersen J. L., Dyhre&#x2010;Poulsen P., Leffers A.-M., Wagner A., Magnusson S. P., et al. (2001). A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J. Physiology 534 (2), 613&#x2013;623. 10.1111/j.14697793.2001.t01-1-00613.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.14697793.2001.t01-1-00613.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11454977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amundsen R., Heimland J. S., Thorarinsdottir S., M&#xf8;ller M., Bahr R. (2022). Effects of high and low training volume with the nordic hamstring exercise on hamstring strength, jump height, and sprint performance in female football players: a randomised trial. Transl. Sports Med. 2022, 7133928. 10.1155/2022/7133928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/7133928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11022781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38655155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnason A., Andersen T. E., Holme I., Engebretsen L., Bahr R. (2008). Prevention of hamstring strains in elite soccer: an intervention study. Scand. J. Med. and Sci. Sports 18 (1), 40&#x2013;48. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2006.00634.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2006.00634.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17355322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizi E., Roberts T. J. (2014). Geared up to stretch: pennate muscle behavior during active lengthening. J. Exp. Biol. 217, 376&#x2013;381. 10.1242/jeb.094383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.094383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahr R., Thorborg K., Jan E. (2015). Evidence-based hamstring injury prevention is not adopted by the majority of champions league or Norwegian premier league football teams: the nordic hamstring survey. Br. J. Sports Med. 49 (22), 1466&#x2013;1471. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-094826</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25995308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biz C., Nicoletti P., Baldin G., Luigi Bragazzi N., Crim&#xec; A., Ruggieri P. (2021). Hamstring strain injury (HSI) prevention in professional and semi-professional football teams: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18 (16), 8272. 10.3390/ijerph18168272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18168272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Blazevich A. J., Gill N. D., Zhou S. (2006). Intra&#x2010; and intermuscular variation in human quadriceps femoris architecture assessed <i>in vivo</i>
. J. Anat.
209 (3), 289&#x2013;310. 10.1111/j.1469-7580.2006.00619.x

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7580.2006.00619.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2100333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16928199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourne M. N., Duhig S. J., Timmins R. G., Williams M. D., Opar D. A., Al Najjar A., et al. (2017). Impact of the nordic hamstring and hip extension exercises on hamstring architecture and morphology: implications for injury prevention. Br. J. Sports Med. 51 (5), 469&#x2013;477. 10.1136/bjsports-2016096130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016096130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27660368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brockett C. L., Morgan D. L., Proske U. (2001). Human hamstring muscles adapt to eccentric exercise by changing optimum length. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 5, 783&#x2013;790. 10.1097/00005768-200105000-00017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200105000-00017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M., Cholley Y., Nagel M., Poulos N. (2016). The effect of body mass on eccentric knee-flexor strength assessed with an instrumented nordic hamstring device (nordbord) in football players. Int. J. Sports Physiology Perform. 11 (6), 721&#x2013;726. 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26638728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadu J.-P., Goreau V., Lacourpaille L. (2022). A very low volume of nordic hamstring exercise increases maximal eccentric strength and reduces hamstring injury rate in professional soccer players. J. Sport Rehabilitation 31 (8), 1061&#x2013;1066. 10.1123/jsr.2021-0445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2021-0445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chebbi S., Karim C., Van Dyk N., Gabbett T., Tabben M. (2022). Hamstring injury prevention for elite soccer players: a real-world prevention program showing the effect of players&#x2019; compliance on the outcome. J. Strength Cond. Res. 36 (5), 1383&#x2013;1388. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33590986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesterton P., Craig T., Wright M., Portas M. (2021). Hamstring injury prevention practices and compliance of the nordic hamstring program in English professional football. Transl. Sports Med. 4 (2), 214&#x2013;222. 10.1002/tsm2.209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbert M., Ripley N., McMahon J. J., Evans M., Gregory Haff G., Comfort P. (2020). The effect of nordic hamstring exercise intervention volume on eccentric strength and muscle architecture adaptations: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sports Med. Auckl. N.Z. 50 (1), 83&#x2013;99. 10.1007/s40279-019-01178-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01178-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31502142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T. B., Tran D. L., Hogan C. M., Gregory Haff G., Latella C. (2021). Chronic effects of altering resistance training set configurations using cluster sets: a systematic review and metaanalysis. Sports Med. 51, 707&#x2013;736. 10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira N. T., Menezes Medeiros T., Vianna K. B., Gabriel Dos Santos, Baroni Oliveira B. M. J. (2020). A four-week training program with the nordic hamstring exercise during preseason increases eccentric strength of male soccer players. Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther. 15 (4), 571&#x2013;578. 10.26603/ijspt20200571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7735695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33354390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J., Pearson S., Ross A., McGuigan M. (2017). Chronic adaptations to eccentric training: a systematic review review. Sport Med. 47, 917&#x2013;941. 10.1007/s40279-016-0628-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0628-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclay J., Martin A., Robbe A., Pousson M. (2008). Spinal reflex plasticity during maximal dynamic contractions after eccentric training. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 40 (4), 722&#x2013;734. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31816184dc</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31816184dc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drury B., Green T., Ramirez-Campillo R., Moran J. (2020). Influence of maturation status on eccentric hamstring strength improvements in youth male soccer players after the Nordic hamstring exercise. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 15 (7), 990&#x2013;996. 10.1123/ijspp.2019-0184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J., H&#xe4;gglund M., Wald&#xe9;n M. (2011). Epidemiology of muscle injuries in professional football (soccer). Am. J. Sports Med. 39 (6), 1226&#x2013;1232. 10.1177/0363546510395879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510395879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21335353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J., Wald&#xe9;n M., H&#xe4;gglund M. (2016). Hamstring injuries have increased by 4% annually in men's professional football, since 2001: a 13-year longitudinal analysis of the UEFA elite club injury study UEFA elite club injury study. Br. J. Sports Med. 50 (12), 731&#x2013;737. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J., Werner K., Spreco A., Van Zoest W., Roberts C., Meyer T., et al. (2020). Time before return to play for the Most common injuries in professional football: a 16-Year Follow-up of the UEFA elite club injury study. Br. J. Sports Med. 54 (7), 421&#x2013;426. 10.1136/bjsports-2019-100666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J., Spreco A., Bengtsson H., Bahr R. (2021). Injury rates decreased in men&#x2019;s professional football: an 18-Year prospective cohort study of almost 12 000 injuries sustained during 1.8 million hours of play. Br. J. Sports Med. 55 (19), 1084&#x2013;1091. 10.1136/bjsports-2020-103159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8458074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J., Bengtsson H., Wald&#xe9;n M., Davison M., Khan K. M., H&#xe4;gglund M. (2023). Hamstring injury rates have increased during recent seasons and now constitute 24% of all injuries in men&#x2019;s professional football: the UEFA elite club injury study from 2001/02 to 2021/22. Br. J. Sports Med. 57 (5), 292&#x2013;298. 10.1136/bjsports-2021105407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021105407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36588400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi M. V., Atherton P. J., Reeves N. D., Fl&#xfc;ck M., Williams J., Mitchell W. K., et al. (2014). Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. 210 (3), 642&#x2013;654. 10.1111/apha.12225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24387247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi M. V., Reeves N. D., Narici M. V. (2017). Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. concentric loading: morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front. Physiology 8 (July), 447. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freckleton G., Pizzari T. (2013). Risk factors for hamstring muscle strain injury in sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br. J. Sports Med. 47 (6), 351&#x2013;358. 10.1136/bjsports-2011-090664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2011-090664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22763118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T. J. (2016). The training-injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br. J. Sports Med. 50 (5), 273&#x2013;280. 10.1136/bjsports2015-095788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports2015-095788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe9;rard R., Gojon L., Decleve P., Van Cant J. (2020). The effects of eccentric training on biceps femoris architecture and strength: a systematic review with meta-analysis training on biceps femoris architecture and strength: a systematic review with MetaAnalysis. J. Athl. Train. 55 (5), 501&#x2013;514. 10.4085/1062-6050-194-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-194-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32216654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goode A. P., Reiman M. P., Harris L., DeLisa L., Kauffman A., Beltramo D., et al. (2015). Eccentric training for prevention of hamstring injuries may depend on intervention compliance: a systematic review and MetaAnalysis. Br. J. Sports Med. 49 (6), 349&#x2013;356. 10.1136/bjsports-2014093466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014093466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25227125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guilhem G., Cornu C., Maffiuletti N. A., Gu&#xe9;vel A. (2013). Neuromuscular adaptations to isoload versus isokinetic eccentric resistance training. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 45 (2), 326&#x2013;335. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826e7066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826e7066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22903139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff G., Travis Triplett N. (2016). Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Fourth edition. Champaign, IL Windsor, ON Leeds: Human Kinetics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L. V., Ingram O. (1985). Statistical methods for meta-analysis. Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hopkins W. G. (2010). Linear models and effect magnitudes for research, clinical and practical applications. Sportscience
14, 49&#x2013;58. Available online at: https://www.sportsci.org/2010/wghlinmod.htm.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ish&#xf8;i L., H&#xf6;lmich P., Aagaard P., Thorborg K., Bandholm T., Serner A. (2018). Effects of the nordic hamstring exercise on sprint capacity in male football players: a randomized controlled trial randomized controlled trial. J. Sports Sci. 36 (14), 1663&#x2013;1672. 10.1080/02640414.2017.1409609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1409609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29192837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E., Baltzopoulos V. (1995). Isokinetic eccentric exercise. Sports Med. Auckl. N.Z. 19 (3), 202&#x2013;222. 10.2165/00007256-199519030-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199519030-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7784759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E., Blazevich A. J. (2022). Hamstrings force-length relationships and their implications for angle-specific joint torques: a narrative review. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabilitation 14 (1), 166. 10.1186/s13102-022-00555-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-022-00555-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9446565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E., Galanis N., Natsis K., George K. (2009). Validity of architectural properties of the hamstring muscles: correlation of ultrasound findings with cadaveric dissection. J. Biomechanics 42 (15), 2549&#x2013;2554. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2009.07.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2009.07.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19646698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong C. H., McDermott W. J., Elmer S. J., Martin J. C. (2014). Chronic eccentric cycling improves quadriceps muscle structure and maximum cycling power. Int. J. Sports Med. 35 (7), 559&#x2013;565. 10.1055/s-0033-1358471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1358471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24234011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber R. L., Jan F. (2000). Functional and clinical significance of skeletal muscle architecture architecture. Muscle Nerve 23 (11), 1647&#x2013;1666. 10.1002/10974598(200011)23:11&lt;1647::aid-mus1&gt;3.0.co;2-m</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/10974598(200011)23:11&lt;1647::aid-mus1&gt;3.0.co;2-m</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber R. L., Friden J. (2002). Morphologic and mechanical basis of delayed-onset muscle soreness. J. Am. Acad. Orthop. Surg. 10 (1), 67&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell R., Knox M., Weston M., Siegler J. C., Brennan S., Marshall P. W. M. (2018). Hamstring injury prevention in soccer: before or after training? Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 28 (2), 658&#x2013;666. 10.1111/sms.12925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28544170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L., Ren D., Huang S., Wu X., Ruan M. (2024). Fascicle behavior and muscle activity of the biceps femoris long head during running at increasing speeds. J. Sports Sci. Med. 23 (1), 603&#x2013;610. 10.52082/jssm.2024.603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11366839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39228786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh M. P. (2003). Recent advances in the understanding of the repeated bout effect: the protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand. J. Med. and Sci. Sports 13 (2), 88&#x2013;97. 10.1034/j.16000838.2003.02477.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.16000838.2003.02477.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12641640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros T. M., Ribeiro-Alvares J. B., Fritsch C. G., Oliveira G. S., SeveroSilveira L., Pappas E., et al. (2020). Effect of weekly training frequency with the nordic hamstring exercise on muscle-strain risk factors in football players: a randomized trial. Int. J. Sports Physiology Perform. 15 (7), 1026&#x2013;1033. 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32580161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros D. M., Marchiori C., Bruno M. B. (2021). Effect of nordic hamstring exercise training on knee flexors eccentric strength and fascicle length: a systematic review and meta-analysis review and meta-analysis. J. Sport Rehabilitation 30 (3), 482&#x2013;491. 10.1123/jsr.2019-0388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2019-0388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J., Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o F., Edouard P., Fonseca M., Pereira R., Lopes H., et al. (2020). Sprint versus isolated eccentric training: comparative effects on hamstring architecture and performance in soccer players. PloS One 15 (2), e0228283. 10.1371/journal.pone.0228283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7012429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32045411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mj&#xf8;lsnes R., Arnason A., &#xd8;sthagen T., Raastad T., Bahr R. (2004). A 10-week randomized trial comparing eccentric vs. concentric hamstring strength training in well-trained soccer players soccer players. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 14 (5), 311&#x2013;317. 10.1046/j.1600-0838.2003.367.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1600-0838.2003.367.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15387805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida S., Nakamura M., Kiyono R., Sato S., Yasaka K., Yoshida R., et al. (2022). Relationship between nordic hamstring strength and maximal voluntary eccentric, concentric and isometric knee flexion torque. PLOS ONE 17 (2), e0264465. 10.1371/journal.pone.0264465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0264465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8880649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar D. A., Williams M. D., Shield A. J. (2012). Hamstring strain injuries: factors that lead to injury and Re-Injury. Sports Med. 42 (3), 209&#x2013;226. 10.2165/11594800-000000000-00000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11594800-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22239734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar D. A., Piatkowski T., Williams M. D., Shield A. J. (2013). A novel device using the nordic hamstring exercise to assess eccentric knee flexor strength: a reliability and retrospective injury study. J. Orthop. Sports Phys. Ther. 43 (9), 636&#x2013;640. 10.2519/jospt.2013.4837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2013.4837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar D. A., Williams M. D., Timmins R. G., Hickey J., Duhig S. J., Shield A. J. (2015). Eccentric hamstring strength and hamstring injury risk in Australian footballers footballers. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 47 (4), 857&#x2013;865. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25137368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opar D. A., Timmins R. G., Behan F. P., Hickey J. T., van Dyk N., Price K., et al. (2021). Is pre-season eccentric strength testing during the nordic hamstring exercise associated with future hamstring strain injury? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 51 (9), 1935&#x2013;1945. 10.1007/s40279-021-01474-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01474-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33914283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M. J., McKenzie J. E., Bossuyt P. M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T. C., Mulrow C. D., et al. (2021). The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ Clin. Res. Ed. 372, n71. 10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potier T. G., Alexander C. M., Seynnes O. R. (2009). Effects of eccentric strength training on biceps femoris muscle architecture and knee joint range of movement. Eur. J. Appl. Physiology 105 (6), 939&#x2013;944. 10.1007/s00421-008-0980-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-008-0980-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presland J. D., Timmins R. G., Bourne M. N., Williams M. D., Opar D. A. (2018). The effect of nordic hamstring exercise training volume on biceps femoris long head architectural adaptation adaptation. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 28 (7), 1775&#x2013;1783. 10.1111/sms.13085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29572976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prilutsky B. I. (2000). &#x201c;Eccentric muscle action in sport and exercise,&#x201d; in Biomechanics in sport: performance enhancement and injury prevention. Editor Zatsiorsky V. M. (Malden, MA: Blackwell Science Ltd; ), 56&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles-Palaz&#xf3;n F. J., Ruiz-P&#xe9;rez I., Aparicio-Sarmiento A., Cejudo A., Ayala F., Sainz de Baranda P. (2022). Incidence, burden, and pattern of injuries in Spanish Male youth soccer players: a prospective cohort study. Phys. Ther. Sport 56 (July), 48&#x2013;59. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.06.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.06.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal R. (1979). The file drawer problem and tolerance for null results. Psychol. Bull. 86 (3), 638&#x2013;641. 10.1037/0033-2909.86.3.638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.86.3.638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudisill S. S., Varady N. H., Kucharik M. P., Eberlin C. T., Martin S. D. (2023). Evidence-based hamstring injury prevention and risk factor management: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Am. J. Sports Med. 51 (7), 1927&#x2013;1942. 10.1177/03635465221083998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465221083998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuermans J., Danneels L., Van Tiggelen D., Palmans T., Witvrouw E. (2017). Proximal neuromuscular control protects against hamstring injuries in Male soccer players: a prospective study with electromyography time-series analysis during maximal sprinting. Am. J. Sports Med. 45 (6), 1315&#x2013;1325. 10.1177/0363546516687750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516687750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28263670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebelien C., Stiller C. H., Maher S. F., Qu X. (2014). Effects of implementing Nordic hamstring exercises for semi-professional soccer players in Akershus, Norway. Orthopaedic Physical Therapy Practice 26 (2), 90&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severo-Silveira L., Dornelles M. P., Lima-E-Silva F. X., Marchiori C. L., Thales M., Medeiros E. P., et al. (2021). Progressive workload periodization maximizes effects of nordic hamstring exercise on muscle injury risk factors. J. Strength Cond. Res. 35 (4), 1006&#x2013;1013. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes O. R., de Boer M., Narici M. V. (2007). Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J. Appl. Physiology (Bethesda, Md. 1985) 102 (1), 368&#x2013;373. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00789.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00789.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17053104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddle J., Weaver K., Greig M., Harper D., Brogden C. M. (2024). A low-volume nordic hamstring curl programme improves change of direction ability, despite no architectural, strength or speed adaptations in elite youth soccer players. Res. Sports Med. 32 (1), 49&#x2013;60. 10.1080/15438627.2022.2079984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2022.2079984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35642790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart N. A., Waldron M., Ismail H., Giallauria F., Vigorito C., Cornelissen V., et al. (2015). Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. Int. J. Evidence-Based Healthc. 13 (1), 9&#x2013;18. 10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne J. A. C., Savovi&#x107; J., Page M. J., Elbers R. G., Blencowe N. S., Boutron I., et al. (2019). RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 28, l4898. 10.1136/bmj.l4898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Arrones L., Lara-Lopez P., Rodriguez-Sanchez P., Lazaro-Ramirez J. L., Di Salvo V., Guitart M., et al. (2019). Dissociation between changes in sprinting performance and nordic hamstring strength in professional Male football players. PLOS ONE 14 (3), e0213375. 10.1371/journal.pone.0213375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0213375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30870442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The Jamovi Project (2019). Jamovi (version 0.9) computer software. Available online at: https://www.jamovi.org.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thelen D. G., Chumanov E. S., Best T. M., Swanson S. C., Heiderscheit B. C. (2005). Simulation of biceps femoris musculotendon mechanics during the swing phase of sprinting. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 37 (11), 1931&#x2013;1938. 10.1249/01.mss.0000176674.42929.de</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000176674.42929.de</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins R. G., Bourne M. N., Shield A. J., Williams M. D., Lorenzen C., Opar D. A. (2016). Short biceps femoris fascicles and eccentric knee flexor weakness increase the risk of hamstring injury in elite football (soccer): a prospective cohort study. Br. J. Sports Med. 50 (24), 1524&#x2013;1535. 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M., Boutellier U. (2006). New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular muscle adaptations. Eur. J. Appl. Physiology 97 (6), 643&#x2013;663. 10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyk N., Witvrouw E., Bahr R. (2018). Interseason variability in isokinetic strength and poor correlation with nordic hamstring eccentric strength in football players. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 28 (8), 1878&#x2013;1887. 10.1111/sms.13201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29694677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianna K. B., Rodrigues L. G., Oliveira N. T., Ribeiro-Alvares J. B., Baroni B. M. (2021). A preseason training program with the nordic hamstring exercise increases eccentric knee flexor strength and fascicle length in professional female soccer players female soccer players. Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther. 16 (2), 459&#x2013;467. 10.26603/001c.19452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.19452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger H.-P., Gressenbauer C., K&#xf6;sters A., Scharinger M., M&#xfc;ller E. (2020). Device and method matter: a critical evaluation of eccentric hamstring muscle strength assessments. Scand. J. Med. and Sci. Sports 30 (2), 217&#x2013;226. 10.1111/sms.13569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31593621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods C., Hawkins R. D., Maltby S., Hulse M., Thomas A., Hodson A., et al. (2004). The football association medical research programme: an audit of injuries in professional football&#x2014;analysis of hamstring injuries. Br. J. Sports Med. 38 (1), 36&#x2013;41. 10.1136/bjsm.2002.002352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2002.002352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14751943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>