<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41850056</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-3171</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Poultry science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Poult Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>N-acetylated chito-oligosaccharides and xylanase improve intestinal health and production performance in laying hens.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106698</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106698</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106698</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.psj.2026.106698</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0032-5791(26)00324-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Synergistic feed additives that target the gut-immune axis offer a promising strategy to enhance health, nutrient utilization, and productivity. N-acetylated chito-oligosaccharides (NACOS) provide stimbiotic, antimicrobial, and immunomodulatory benefits, while xylanase improves non-starch polysaccharide degradation, nutrient availability, and microbial fermentation. This study evaluated a novel dual-action strategy combining NACOS, xylanase, or their combination (CXNRGY) on production performance, nutrient utilization, jejunal histomorphology, systemic immune status, and the cecal microbial community in laying hens. Forty HiSex White laying hens were randomly assigned to four dietary groups and fed either a control diet (CD) or the CD supplemented with NACOS (50 g/t), Xylanase (45,000 U/kg), or CXNRGY at the same respective doses. Dietary supplementation improved production metrics: egg weight was highest in the CXNRGY group compared with control and NACOS (P &lt; 0.001), while egg mass increased in Xylanase, NACOS and CXNRGY groups compared to control in the second phase (P &lt; 0.001). Xylanase and CXNRGY achieved the lowest FCR compared with NACOS and the control group. Haugh unit and albumen height were elevated in NACOS and Xylanase treatments (P &lt; 0.05), whereas CXNRGY maximized shell thickness and breaking strength (P &lt; 0.001). Nutrient utilization of crude fat, organic matter, and apparent metabolizable energy (AME) was significantly improved by NACOS, while Xylanase and CXNRGY further enhanced fiber and protein utilization. NACOS produced the greatest improvements in jejunal morphology (P &lt; 0.05) and, along with Xylanase and CXNRGY, reduced serum IL-1&#x3b1;, TNF-&#x3b1;, and IL-10 (P &lt; 0.05), while IL-1&#x3b2; and IL-6 were unaffected (P &gt; 0.05). Notably, CXNRGY altered the cecal microbiota by increasing the relative abundance of Lachnospiraceae, Ruminococcaceae, Subdoligranulum, Prevotellaceae and Clostridia, while decreasing Bacteroidaceae and Negativicutes, indicating a synergistic effect on microbial community structure. Xylanase enhances nutrient utilization and prebiotic availability, while NACOS strengthens gut barrier integrity and modulates immune responses. These results indicate that combining NACOS with xylanase provides a synergistic, antibiotic-free nutritional strategy that enhances gut health, immunity, egg quality, and overall performance in laying hens.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Hoeck</LastName><ForeName>Veerle</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kemin Europa NV, Herentals, Belgium. Electronic address: veerle.vanhoeck@kemin.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spaepen</LastName><ForeName>Riet</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kemin Europa NV, Herentals, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Somers</LastName><ForeName>Ingrid</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kemin Europa NV, Herentals, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelqader</LastName><ForeName>Anas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Production, School of Agriculture, The University of Jordan, Amman, 11942, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forier</LastName><ForeName>Bart</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kemin Europa NV, Herentals, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahasneh</LastName><ForeName>Zeinab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Production and Protection, Faculty of Agriculture, Jerash University, Jerash 26150, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Poult Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401150</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0032-5791</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intestinal Microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laying Hens</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N-Acetylated Chito-Oligosaccharides</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xylanase</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest in this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41850056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13011195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psj.2026.106698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0032-5791(26)00324-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdelqader A., Mahasneh Z., Van Hoeck V., Abuajamieh M., Abedal-Majed M., Al-Qaisi M., Al-Khaza&#x2019;leh J.F. Exogenous enzymes unlock prebiotic potential of Ulva lactuca: boosting gut health and growth performance in broilers. Poult. Sci. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12466226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40961780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdollahi A., Karimi A., Sadeghi A.A., Bedford M.R., Ashengroph M. The effects of the fiber source and xylanase supplementation on production, egg quality, digestibility, and intestinal morphology in the aged laying hen. Poult. Sci. 2021;100(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7936207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33518298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedford M., R. GB. CABI; 2022. Xylanases, &#x3b2;-glucanases and cellulases: their relevance in poultry nutrition; pp. 52&#x2013;69. (Enzymes in Farm Animal Nutrition).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryden W.L., Li X., Ruhnke I., Zhang D., Shini S. Nutrition, feeding and laying hen welfare. Anim. Prod. Sci. 2021;61(10):893&#x2013;914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caporaso J.G., Lauber C.L., Walters W.A., Berg-Lyons D., Huntley J., Fierer N., Owens S.M., Betley J., Fraser L., Bauer M., Gormley N. Ultra-high-throughput microbial community analysis on the Illumina HiSeq and MiSeq platforms. The ISME J. 2012;6(8):1621&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3400413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22402401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerrate S., Ekmay R., Engl J.A., Coon C. Predicting nutrient digestibility and energy value for broilers. Poult. Sci. 2019;98:3994&#x2013;4007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30968142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J., J L.i., Z.Q Mo., Z.Q Xu., S Mao., H H., Shi D., Luo X.C. Immunomodulatory effects of N-acetyl chitooligosaccharides on RAW264. 7 macrophages. Mar. Drugs. 2020;18(8):421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32806493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducatelle R., Goossens E., Eeckhaut V., Van Immerseel F. The Gordon Memorial Lecture: steering the gut microbiome for improved health and welfare in broilers. Br. Poult. Sci. 2025;66(4):419&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40476348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y.F., Chen Y.P., Jin R., Wang C., Wen C., Zhou Y.M. Dietary chitooligosaccharide supplementation alleviates intestinal barrier damage, and oxidative and immunological stress in lipopolysaccharide-challenged laying hens. Poult. Sci. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8844238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan G., Azad M., Kalam A., Lin Y., Kim S.W., Tian Y., Wang H. Biological effects and applications of chitosan and chito-oligosaccharides. Front. Physiol. 2019;10:516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6514239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31133871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao W., L.i K., G.e X., Yang H., Xu C., Liu S., Xing R. The effect of N-acetylation on the anti-inflammatory activity of chitooligosaccharides and its potential for relieving endotoxemia. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2022;23(15):8205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill F.W., Anderson D.L. Comparison of metabolizable energy and productive energy determinations with growing chicks. J. Nutr. 1958;64:587&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13549992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Je J.Y., Kim S., K. Chitooligosaccharides as potential nutraceuticals: production and bioactivities. Adv. Food Nutr. 2012;65:321&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22361197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha R., Fouhse J.M., Tiwari U.P., Li L., Willing B.P. Dietary fiber and intestinal health of monogastric animals. Front. Vet. Sci. 2019;6:48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6409295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaul J.Z, Hudson S.M., Creber KAM. Crosslinking of chitosan fibers with dialdehydes: proposal of a new reaction mechanism. J. Polym. Sci. Part B Polym. Phys. 1999;37:1079&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan R., Chang Q., Wei L., Zhao Z. The protective effects of chitosan oligosaccharides on intestinal integrity by regulating oxidative status and inflammation under oxidative stress. Marine Drugs. 2021;19(2):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7911331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33503912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.H., Lee B., Rousseau X., Gomes G.A., Oh H.J., Kim Y.J., Chang S.Y., An J.W., Go Y.B., Song D.C., Cho H.A. Stimbiotic supplementation modulated intestinal inflammatory response and improved broilers performance in an experimentally-induced necrotic enteritis infection model. J. Anim. Sci. Biotechnol. 2022;13(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9472449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36100948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodhi G., Kim Y.S., Hwang J.W., Kim S.K., Jeon Y.J., Je J.Y., Ahn C.B., Moon S.H., Jeon B.T., Park P.J. Chitooligosaccharide and its derivatives: preparation and biological applications. BioMed Res. Int. 2014;2014(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3958764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24724091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquardt R.R. A simple spectrophotometric method for the direct determination of uric acid in avian excreta. Poult. Sci. 1983;62(10):2106&#x2013;2108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6634586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q.W., Yan L., Ao X., Jang H.D., Cho J.H., Kim I.H. Effects of chito-oligosaccharide supplementation on egg production, nutrient digestibility, egg quality and blood profiles in laying hens. Asian-Australasian J. Anim. Sci. 2010;23(11):1476&#x2013;1481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal A., Singh A., Buatong J., Saetang J., Benjakul S. Chitooligosaccharide and its derivatives: potential candidates as food additives and bioactive components. Foods. 2023;12(20):3854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10606384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37893747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan N. In: Pre and Probiotics for Poultry Gut Health. O&#x2019;Neill H.M., Burton E., Scholey D., editors. 2023. Mechanisms of Prebiotic Xylo-Oligosaccharides on Improving Poultry Performance; pp. 128&#x2013;142. edited by. edited by.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers W.D., Ludden P.A., Nayigihugu V. Technical note: a procedure for the preparation and quantitative analysis of samples for titanium dioxide. J. Anim .Sci. 2004;82:79&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14753360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez A., Meng&#xed;bar M., Rivera&#x2011;Rodr&#xed;guez G., Moerchbacher B., Acosta N., Heras A. The effect of the degree of acetylation on the antimicrobial activity of chitosan. Internat. J. Food Microbiol. 1999;49:139&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short F.J, Gorton P., Wiseman J. Determination of titanium dioxide added as an inert marker in chicken digestibility studies. Anim. Feed. Sci. Technol. 1996;(59):215&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor A.E., Bedford M.R., Pace S.C., Miller H.M. The effects of phytase and xylanase supplementation on performance and egg quality in laying hens. Br. Poult. Sci. 2018;59(5):554&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29855193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hoeck V., Somers I., Abdelqader A., Wealleans A.L., Van de Craen S., Morisset D. Xylanase impact beyond performance: a microbiome approach in laying hens. Plos One. 2021;16(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8452031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34543338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Li D., Xu Y., Ding X., Liang S., Xie L., Wang Y., Zhan X. Xylanase supplement enhances the growth performance of broiler by modulating serum metabolism, intestinal health, short-chain fatty acid composition, and microbiota. Animals. 2024;14(8):1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38672330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widjaja H., Jayanegara A., Utomo D., Hazen K. The improvement of nutrient utilization and performance in laying hens fed by-product diets supplemented with xylanase and/or protease enzymes. Trop. Anim. Sci. J. 2025;48(5):412&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Cai K., Mishra R., Jha R. In ovo supplementation of chitooligosaccharide and chlorella polysaccharide affects cecal microbial community, metabolic pathways, and fermentation metabolites in broiler chickens. Poult. Sci. 2020;99(10):4776&#x2013;4785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32988512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Hao Z., Yang D., Ji W., Guo K., Sun X., Wang S., Yang S., Ma J., Wang T., Luo H. Alleviating clostridium perfringens-induced intestinal lesions in chickens using the xylanase CbXyn10C and its binary cocktail with a protease. Animals: An Open Access Journal from MDPI. 2025;15(2):123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11758347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>