<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41466934</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Penicillin Allergy Delabeling: Provider Knowledge, Practice Patterns, and Barriers Among Internal Medicine Residents in a Large Urban Community Teaching Hospital.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97928</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97928</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97928</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97928</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Penicillin allergy is the most frequently reported drug allergy, yet up to 90% of labels are inaccurate. These erroneous labels contribute to suboptimal antibiotic use, higher healthcare costs, and increased antimicrobial resistance. Despite growing evidence supporting delabeling, provider hesitancy and knowledge gaps persist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this study is to evaluate the awareness, confidence, and clinical decision-making of internal medicine residents regarding penicillin allergy delabeling within a large community hospital setting. Specifically, we seek to identify existing knowledge gaps, provider attitudes, and institutional barriers that may hinder appropriate delabeling efforts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional, anonymous electronic survey was administered to internal medicine residents at Ascension Saint Joseph Hospital in Chicago. The survey included questions on allergy knowledge, delabeling practices, confidence in risk stratification, and perceived barriers. Responses were analyzed using descriptive statistics and chi-square tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 66 residents invited, 42.4% (n = 28) responded. While 60.7% (n = 17) reported self-perceived knowledge on how to stratify beta-lactam allergy risk, only 12% (n = 2) felt confident in doing so. Familiarity with the PEN-FAST score increased with training level (postgraduate year (PGY)1: 0%; PGY3: 77%; p = 0.017). Half of the respondents had removed a penicillin allergy label, with significant differences by training level (p&#xa0;<i>=&#xa0;</i>0.048). Major barriers included lack of institutional protocols (n = 23, 82.14%), insufficient knowledge (n = 18, 64.3%), and time constraints (n = 12, 42.86%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Significant gaps exist in residents' knowledge and confidence regarding the delabeling of beta-lactam allergies. Lack of standardized training and protocols further hinders effective implementation. Structured educational interventions and institutional support are needed to promote safe and evidence-based delabeling practices as part of antimicrobial stewardship.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Aloyan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aloyan</LastName><ForeName>Tatevik</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ascension Saint Joseph Hospital, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salimova</LastName><ForeName>Dinara</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ascension Saint Joseph Hospital, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonov</LastName><ForeName>Evgenii</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Presbyterian Hospital, Albuquerque, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandra</LastName><ForeName>Gopika</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ascension Saint Joseph Hospital, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGrath</LastName><ForeName>Kris</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Immunology, Ascension Saint Joseph Hospital, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">allergy delabeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-lactam allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electronic health records</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pen-fast</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">penicillin allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality improvement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resident education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41466934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12744322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Feasibility of a centralized, pharmacy-led penicillin allergy delabeling program. Antoon JW, Grijalva CG, Grisso AG, et al. Hosp Pediatr. 2022;12:0&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35678128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric residents knowledge of penicillin allergy. Oseni LA, Tryfonos A, Basta C, Vastardi MA, Hammerschlag MR. Clin Pediatr (Phila) 2025;64:200&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38767311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penicillin allergy: a label that is not forever. Morales Mart&#xed;nez &#xc1;. Semergen. 2024;50:102280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38936101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of a proposed algorithm to assess and de-label false penicillin allergy labels in the community. Lim A, Khumra S, Mitri EA, et al. Infect Dis Health. 2025;30:316&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40340187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating the PEN-FAST clinical decision-making tool to enhance penicillin allergy delabeling. Su C, Belmont A, Liao J, Kuster JK, Trubiano JA, Kwah JH. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:883&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10282954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37338869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development and validation of a penicillin allergy clinical decision rule. Trubiano JA, Vogrin S, Chua KY, et al. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180:745&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7076536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32176248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penicillin allergy delabeling: a multidisciplinary opportunity. Staicu ML, Vyles D, Shenoy ES, Stone CA, Banks T, Alvarez KS, Blumenthal KG. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2020;8:2858&#x2013;2868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics review 8: Qualitative data-tests of association. Bewick V, Cheek L, Ball J. Crit Care. 2004;8:46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC420070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14975045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penicillin allergy. Castells M, Khan DA, Phillips EJ. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:2338&#x2013;2351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31826341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accuracy of penicillin allergy diagnostic tests: a&#xa0;systematic review and meta-analysis. Sousa-Pinto B, Tarrio I, Blumenthal KG, Ara&#xfa;jo L, Azevedo LF, Delgado L, Fonseca JA. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;147:296&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8019189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Consensus on drug allergy. Demoly P, Adkinson NF, Brockow K, et al. Allergy. 2014;69:420&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24697291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug allergy: a 2022 practice parameter update. Khan DA, Banerji A, Blumenthal KG, et al. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2022;150:1333&#x2013;1393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36122788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of a clinical decision rule to enable direct oral challenge in patients with low-risk penicillin allergy: the PALACE randomized clinical trial. Copaescu AM, Vogrin S, James F, et al. JAMA Intern Med. 2023;183:944&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37459086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penicillin allergy decision rule (PEN-FAST)  [
May;
2025 
]. https://www.mdcalc.com/calc/10422/penicillin-allergy-decision-rule-pen-fast https://www.mdcalc.com/calc/10422/penicillin-allergy-decision-rule-pen-fast</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PEN-FAST-ED: utilizing the PEN-FAST decision tool to guide antibiotic prescribing in the emergency department. Tran K, Lund J, Sealy C, Langley D, Kisgen J. Am J Emerg Med. 2025;90:124&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39864256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative performance of 4 penicillin-allergy prediction strategies in a large cohort. Ghiordanescu IM, Cioc&#x103;nea-Teodorescu I, Molinari N, et al. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2024;12:2985&#x2013;2993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39038539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An inpatient antimicrobial stewardship team driven penicillin allergy delabeling protocol for minimal and low-risk penicillin allergic patients. Shankaran S, Adochio E, Petrak R, et al. Antimicrob Steward Healthc Epidemiol. 2025;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11869059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40026768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of a pharmacist driven penicillin allergy de-labeling protocol on rates of reported allergy in the intensive care unit. Mahmud M, Kokoy SR, Stollings JL, et al. Hosp Pharm. 2025;60:480&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12055799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40342611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>