<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41342791</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-5487</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epidemiology (Cambridge, Mass.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epidemiology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bounds and E-values for Marginal Causal Effects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5</StartPage><EndPage>15</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5-15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/EDE.0000000000001919</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Unmeasured confounding is an important obstacle when estimating causal effects from observational data. Ding and VanderWeele (EPIDEMIOLOGY 2016;27:368) derived bounds for causal effects, based on sensitivity parameters that quantify the maximal strength of unmeasured confounding. These bounds translate to the popular E-value metric, which quantifies the magnitude of unmeasured confounding required to "explain away" an observed association. While Ding and VanderWeele mainly focused on conditional (on measured confounders) causal effects, they also outlined how their method might be used for marginal causal effects. However, this requires specification of the sensitivity parameters at each level of the measured confounders, which is impractical in high-dimensional settings, and it yields overly conservative bounds that lack a natural E-value analog. In this article, we propose novel bounds for marginal causal effects based on Ding and VanderWeele's sensitivity parameters. The proposed bounds only require the analyst to specify the maximal values of the sensitivity parameters across all levels of the measured confounders, thus substantially reducing dimensionality. Furthermore, the proposed bounds are often narrower than Ding and VanderWeele's bounds, and they translate naturally into an E-value for marginal causation. We show how the proposed bounds can be estimated using standard regression techniques, and we illustrate through an application to publicly available data, with accompanying R code provided.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sj&#xf6;lander</LastName><ForeName>Arvid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5226-6685</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cioc&#x103;nea-Teodorescu</LastName><ForeName>Iuliana</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Victor Babe&#x219; National Institute of Pathology, Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carol Davila University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabriel</LastName><ForeName>Erin E</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Section of Biostatistics, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Epidemiology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9009644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1044-3983</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015984" MajorTopicYN="Y">Causality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015986" MajorTopicYN="N">Confounding Factors, Epidemiologic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003627" MajorTopicYN="N">Data Interpretation, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bounds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Causality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Confounding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">E-value</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41342791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EDE.0000000000001919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001648-202601000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Robins JM. The analysis of randomized and non-randomized AIDS treatment trials using a new approach to causal inference in longitudinal studies. In: Sechrest L, Freeman H, Mulley A, eds. Health Service Research Methodology: A Focus on AIDS. U.S. Public Health Service, National Center for Health Services Research; 1989:113&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balke A, Pearl J. Bounds on treatment effects from studies with imperfect compliance. J Am Stat Assoc. 1997;92:1171&#x2013;1176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JL, Rubin DB. Estimation of causal effects via principal stratification when some outcomes are truncated by &#x201c;death&#x201d;. J Educ Behav Stat. 2003;28:353&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z, Kuroki M, Pearl J, Tian J. Bounds on direct effects in the presence of confounded intermediate variables. Biometrics. 2008;64:695&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;lander A. Bounds on natural direct effects in the presence of confounded intermediate variables. Stat Med. 2009;28:558&#x2013;571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding P, VanderWeele TJ. Sensitivity analysis without assumptions. Epidemiology. 2016;27:368&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderWeele TJ, Ding P. Sensitivity analysis in observational research: introducing the E-value. Ann Intern Med. 2016;167:268&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cioc&#x103;nea-Teodorescu I, Gabriel EE, Sj&#xf6;lander A. Sensitivity analysis for unmeasured confounding in the estimation of marginal causal effects. Biometrika. 2022;109:1101&#x2013;1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Estimating causal effects of treatments in randomized and nonrandomized studies. J Educ Psychol. 1974;66:688&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearl J. Causality: Models, Reasoning, and Inference. 2nd ed. Cambridge University Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;lander A. Sharp bounds for causal effects based on Ding and VanderWeele&#x2019;s sensitivity parameters. J Causal Inference. 2024;12:20230019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasza J, Wolfe R, Schuster T. Assessing the impact of unmeasured confounding for binary outcomes using confounding functions. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46:1303&#x2013;1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cioc&#x103;nea-Teodorescu I, Sj&#xf6;lander A. A cautionary note on a recently proposed sensitivity analysis for unmeasured confounding. Int J Epidemiol. 2021;50:711&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumback BA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Haneuse SJ, Robins JM. Sensitivity analyses for unmeasured confounding assuming a marginal structural model for repeated measures. Stat Med. 2004;23:749&#x2013;767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiba Y. Sensitivity analysis of unmeasured confounding for the causal risk ratio by applying marginal structural models. Commun Stat - Theory Methods. 2009;39:65&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franks A, D&#x2019;Amour A, Feller A. Flexible sensitivity analysis for observational studies without observable implications. J Am Stat Assoc. 2019;115:1730&#x2013;1746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;lander A, Gabriel EE, Cioc&#x103;nea-Teodorescu I. Sensitivity analysis for causal effects with generalized linear models. J Causal Inference. 2022;10:441&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M, Yao W. Sensitivity analysis of unmeasured confounding in causal inference based on exponential tilting and super learner. J Appl Stat. 2023;50:744&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabi R, Bonvini M, Kennedy EH, Huang MY, Smid M, Scharfstein DO. Semiparametric sensitivity analysis: unmeasured confounding in observational studies. Biometrics. 2024;80:ujae106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH, VanderWeele TJ. Bounding bias due to selection. Epidemiology. 2019;30:509&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zetterstrom S, Waernbaum I. Selection bias and multiple inclusion criteria in observational studies. Epidemiol Methods. 2022;11:20220108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur MB. The M-value: a simple sensitivity analysis for bias due to missing data in treatment effect estimates. Am J Epidemiol. 2023;192:612&#x2013;620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding P, VanderWeele TJ. Sharp sensitivity bounds for mediation under unmeasured mediator-outcome confounding. Biometrika. 2016;103:483&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;lander A, Waernbaum I. Improved sensitivity bounds for mediation under unmeasured mediator-outcome confounding. J Causal Inference. 2024;12:20230070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanski LA, Boos DD. The calculus of M-estimation. Am Stat. 2002;56:29&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>