<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41799615</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association Between Functional Muscle Assessment and Psychological Factors on Return to Sport and Graft Failure After ACL Reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251383072</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251383072</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251383072</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251383072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Few researchers have examined both psychological and physical factors simultaneously in return to sport (RTS) and reinjury.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To assess the role of psychological profiles and physical aspects in RTS and reinjury risk and to inform and develop innovative treatment strategies that may be beneficial after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cohort study; Level of evidence, 2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">During the rehabilitation process, patients (aged 18-45 years) with ACL reconstruction (using patellar tendon or hamstring autografts) were screened. A statistical analysis was conducted using the cluster method and ascending hierarchical cluster analysis (Ward method), which allowed us to highlight a 4-cluster solution (<i>P</i> &lt; .001). Muscle strength (maximal isokinetic strength of the quadriceps/hamstring, single-leg hop test between 3 and 6 months) and psychological factors were measured. A follow-up call was made to patients in the second year after surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study included a total of 162 athletes to determine psychological profiles. The prospective follow-up percentage for patients who responded was 75.9% regarding RTS and reinjury. Profile 1 (intermediate) was characterized by "moderate reinjury anxiety, no depression"; profile 2 (intermediate depressive) by "moderate reinjury anxiety and minor anxious-depressive reaction"; profile 3 (confident) by "no reinjury anxiety, no depression, high confidence"; and profile 4 (negative) by "high anxiety, high depression, low confidence." The percentage of female athletes was higher in profile 4 than in profile 3 (<i>P</i> &lt; .01). Profile 4 had the lowest RTS rate with 45.8% (profile 3: 77.8%; <i>P</i> = .01). Profile 3 had the least strength deficit (muscular quadriceps force at 90 and 240 deg/sec between profile 3 versus 1 (<i>P</i> = .01; <i>P</i> = .02), 3 versus 4 (<i>P</i> = .001; <i>P</i> = .004), and hamstring profile 3 versus 2 (<i>P</i> = .006). Profile 3 was associated with difference in timing to RTS between profile 3 versus 1 (<i>P</i> = .0004), 3 versus 4 (<i>P</i> = .007), and 3 versus 2 (<i>P</i> = .002). Profile 3, with a more quickly achieved RTS (mean = 222 days), had a higher reinjury rate at 13.9% (compared with profile 4: 0%; <i>P</i> = .047). Profile 3 reported all 5 cases of reinjury before return to competition. Profiles 1 and 2 with reinjuries (<i>P</i> = .003) suffered a strength deficit (12.9%-22.9%), primarily in the hamstrings (<i>P</i> = .049).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Profile 3, which was the most confident and least deficient, and recovered the fastest, had the most relapses. Reinjured athletes in profiles 1 and 2 had deficits in strength, particularly in their hamstrings. Individuals in profile 4, who rarely returned to sports, were the most anxious, the most deficient, and had the greatest difficulty returning to sports.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laboute</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2001-3186</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERS Capbreton, Groupe Ramsay Sant&#xe9;, Capbreton, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verhaeghe</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERS Capbreton, Groupe Ramsay Sant&#xe9;, Capbreton, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perez</LastName><ForeName>Sebastien</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERS Capbreton, Groupe Ramsay Sant&#xe9;, Capbreton, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Decamps</LastName><ForeName>Greg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bordeaux, Laboratory of Psychology, Bordeaux, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caumeil</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bordeaux, Laboratory of Psychology, Bordeaux, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reinjury anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared that there are no conflicts of interest in the authorship and publication of this contribution. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto. Ethical approval for this study was obtained from Comit&#xe9; de Protection des Personnes du Sud-Ouest et Outre-Mer 4, Limoges (CPP18-025a/2017-A03659-44).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41799615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12965705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251383072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251383072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aizawa J, Hirohata K, Ohji S, Ohmi T, Koga H, Yagishita K. Factors associated with psychological readiness to return to sports with cutting, pivoting, and jump-landings after primary ACL reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(11):232596712096448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson MN, Womble MN, Mohler SA, et al. Preliminary study of fear of re-injury following sport-related concussion in high school athletes. Dev Neuropsychol. 2019;44(6):443-451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appaneal RN, Levine BR, Perna FM, Roh JL. Measuring postinjury depression among male and female competitive athletes. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2009;31(1):60-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. A systematic review of the psychological factors associated with returning to sport following injury. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(17):1120-1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Whitehead TS, Webster KE. Sports participation 2 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in athletes who had not returned to sport at 1 year: a prospective follow-up of physical function and psychological factors in 122 athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(4):848-856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25583757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong KA, Khawaja NG. Gender differences in anxiety: an investigation of the symptoms, cognitions, and sensitivity towards anxiety in a nonclinical population. Behav Cogn Psychother. 2002;30(2):227-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: toward a unifying theory of behavioral change. Psychol Rev. 1977;84(2):191-215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber-Westin S, Noyes FR. One in 5 athletes sustain reinjury upon return to high-risk sports after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review in 1239 athletes younger than 20 years. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2020;12(6):587-597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beischer S, Senorski EH, Thome&#xe9; C, Samuelsson K, Thome&#xe9; R. Young athletes return too early to knee-strenuous sport, without acceptable knee function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(7):1966-1974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6061439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29032484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biau DJ, Tournoux C, Katsahian S, Schranz PJ, Nizard RS. Bone-patellar tendon-bone autografts versus hamstring autografts for reconstruction of anterior cruciate ligament: meta-analysis. BMJ. 2006;332(7548):995-1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1450040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16603564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohu Y, Klouche S, Lefevre N, Webster K, Herman S. Translation, cross-cultural adaptation and validation of the French version of the Anterior Cruciate Ligament-Return to Sport after Injury (ACL-RSI) scale. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2015;23(4):1192-1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgi CR, Peters S, Ardern CL, et al. Which criteria are used to clear patients to return to sport after primary ACL reconstruction? A scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(18):1154-1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caumeil B, Edouard P, D&#xe9;camps G. Adaptation et validation francophone du Re-Injury Anxiety Inventory&#x2009;: Le Questionnaire d&#x2019;Anxi&#xe9;t&#xe9; de Re-Blessure (RIAI-F). J Traumatol Sport. 2022;39(4):229-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caumeil B, Laboute E, Verhaeghe E, P&#xe9;rez S, D&#xe9;camps G. Reinjury anxiety and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cluster analysis and prospective study among 162 athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(5):1189-1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38520139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christino MA, Fleming BC, Machan JT, Shalvoy RM. Psychological factors associated with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction recovery. Orthop J Sports Med. 2016;4(3):232596711663834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4811017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27069948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Kamarck T, Mermelstein R. A global measure of perceived stress. J Health Soc Behav. 1983;24(4):385-396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6668417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousson-G&#xe9;lie F, Bruchon-Schweitzer M, Quintard B, Nuissier J. Analyse multidimensionnelle d&#x2019;une &#xe9;chelle de coping: validation fran&#xe7;aise de la W.C.C. (Ways of Coping Checklist). Multidimensional analysis of a coping scale: the French validation of the Ways of Coping Checklist. Psychol Fr. 1996;41(2):155-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFroda SF, ODonnell RM, Fadale PD, Owens BD, Fleming BC. The role of magnetic resonance imaging in evaluating postoperative ACL reconstruction healing and graft mechanical properties: a new criterion for return to play? Phys Sportsmed. 2021;49(2):123-129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32897799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everhart JS, Best TM, Flanigan DC. Psychological predictors of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction outcomes: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2015;23(3):752-762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faleide AGH, Magnussen LH, Strand T, et al. The role of psychological readiness in return to sport assessment after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(5):1236-1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay S, Kvist J. Fear of reinjury following surgical and nonsurgical management of anterior cruciate ligament injury: an exploratory analysis of the NACOX multicenter longitudinal cohort study. Phys Ther. 2022;102(2):PZAB273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8860188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34939109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanigan DC, Everhart JS, Pedroza A, Smith T, Kaeding CC. Fear of reinjury (kinesiophobia) and persistent knee symptoms are common factors for lack of return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy. 2013;29(8):1322-1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23906272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French DJ, France CR, Vigneau F, French JA, Evans RT. Fear of movement/(re)injury in chronic pain: a psychometric assessment of the original English version of the Tampa scale for kinesiophobia (TSK). Pain. 2007;127(1):42-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16962238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher BV, Gardner FL. An examination of the relationship between early maladaptive schemas, coping, and emotional response to athletic injury. J Clin Sport Psychol. 2007;1(1):47-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gana K, Caumeil B, Broc G. L&#x2019;analyse typologique en classes et profils latents en psychologie : principes de base et applications L&#x2019;Ann&#xe9;e Psychol. 2022;122(1):185-222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobbi A, Francisco R. Factors affecting return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with patellar tendon and hamstring graft: a prospective clinical investigation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2006;14(10):1021-1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16496124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder-Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):804-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4912389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M, Singh M, Karimi D, et al. ; BEAR Trial Team. LigaNET: a multi-modal deep learning approach to predict the risk of subsequent anterior cruciate ligament injury after surgery. medRxiv. Preprint posted online July 27, 2023. doi: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.07.25.23293102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins LD, Taylor MK, Park D, et al. ; International Knee Documentation Committee. Reliability and validity of the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) Subjective Knee Form. Joint Bone Spine. 2007;74(6):594-599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17888709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivarsson A, Johnson U. Psychological factors as predictors of injuries among senior soccer players. A prospective study. J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9(2):347-352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwame T, Matsuura T, Okahisa T, et al. Quadriceps strength to body weight ratio is a significant indicator for initiating jogging after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2021;28:240-246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33429149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauhiainen S, Pohl AJ, &#xc4;yr&#xe4;m&#xf6; S, Kauppi JP, Ferber R. A hierarchical cluster analysis to determine whether injured runners exhibit similar kinematic gait patterns. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(4):732-740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins SM, Guzman A, Gardner BB, et al. Rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament injury: review of current literature and recommendations. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2022;15(3):170-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9107547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35381974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, et al. Single leg vertical jump performance identifies knee function deficits at return to sport after ACL reconstruction in male athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(9):490-498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9016240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvist J, Ek A, Sporrstedt K, Good L. Fear of re-injury: a hindrance for returning to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2005;13(5):393-397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboute E, James-Belin E, Puig PL, Trouve P, Verhaeghe E. Graft failure is more frequent after hamstring than patellar tendon autograft. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(12):3537-3546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29767271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboute E, James-Belin E, Ucay O, Caubere A, Verhaeghe E. Prospective study of functional outcomes and return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the knee. Int Orthop. 2023;48(2):455-463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10799780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37700201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboute E, Savalli L, Puig P, et al. Analysis of return to competition and repeat rupture for 298 anterior cruciate ligament reconstructions with patellar or hamstring tendon autograft in sportspeople. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2010;53(10):598-614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboute E, Savalli L, Puig PL, Trouve P, Larbaigt M, Raffestin M. Validity and reproducibility of the PPLP scoring scale in the follow-up of athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2010;53(3):162-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20219437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laboute E, Vignerot V, Puig PL, Trouve T, Ferrand R, Verhaeghe E, Analyse vid&#xe9;ographique 2D d&#x2019;exercices fonctionnels avec d&#xe9;placements verticaux et mesure de la force musculaire isocin&#xe9;tique du genou apr&#xe8;s ligamentoplastie du ligament crois&#xe9; ant&#xe9;rieur, J Traumatol Sport. 2018;35(4):210-217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CCH, Ardern CL, Feller JA, Webster KE. Eighty-three per cent of elite athletes return to preinjury sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review with meta-analysis of return to sport rates, graft rupture rates and performance outcomes. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(2):128-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28223305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langford JL, Webster KE, Feller JA. A prospective longitudinal study to assess psychological changes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(5):377-378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19019910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesage FX, Berjot S, Deschamps F. Psychometric properties of the French versions of the Perceived Stress Scale. Int J Occup Med Environ Health. 2012;25(2):178-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22528542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lethem J, Slade PD, Troup JD, Bentley G. Outline of a fear-avoidance model of exaggerated pain perception&#x2013;I. Behav Res Ther. 1983;21(4):401-408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6626110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyckx K, Schwartz SJ, Berzonsky MD, et al. Capturing ruminative exploration: Extending the four-dimensional model of identity formation in late adolescence. J Res Personal. 2008;42(1):58-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch AD, Logerstedt DS, Grindem H, et al. Consensus criteria for defining &#x201c;successful outcome&#x201d; after ACL injury and reconstruction: a Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort investigation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(5):335-342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23881894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meredith SJ, Rauer T, Chmielewski TL, et al. ; Panther Symposium ACL Injury Return to Sport Consensus Group. Return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament injury: Panther Symposium ACL Injury Return to Sport Consensus Group. J ISAKOS. 2021;6(3):138-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34006577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray MM, Kiapour AM, Kalish LA, et al. Predictors of healing ligament size and magnetic resonance signal intensity at 6 months after bridge-enhanced anterior cruciate ligament repair. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(6):1361-1369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6497549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30986359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohji S, Aizawa J, Hirohata K, et al. Single-leg hop can result in higher limb symmetry index than isokinetic strength and single-leg vertical jump following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2021;29:160-166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos SD, Tishukov M, Stamou K, Totlis T, Natsis K. Fear of re-injury following ACL reconstruction: an overview. J Res Pract Musculoskelet Syst. 2018;2(4):124-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochcongar P, Laboute E, Jan J, Carling C. Ruptures of the anterior cruciate ligament in soccer. Int J Sports Med. 2009;30(5):372-378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19199222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery-Cottet B, Hopper GP, Gousopoulos L, et al. Incidence of and risk factors for arthrogenic muscle inhibition in acute anterior cruciate ligament injuries: a cross-sectional study and analysis of associated factors from the SANTI Study Group. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(1):60-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38164669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen WWES, van der Steen MC, Liu WY, Janssen RPA. Timing of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and preoperative pain are important predictors for postoperative kinesiophobia. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(8):2502-2510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31879792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trigsted SM, Cook DB, Pickett KA, Cadmus-Bertram L, Dunn WR, Bell DR. Greater fear of reinjury is related to stiffened jump-landing biomechanics and muscle activation in women after ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(12):3682-3689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29700560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trottier C, Mageau G, Trudel P, Halliwell WR. Validation de la version canadienne-fran&#xe7;aise du Life Orientation Test-Revised. Validation of the Canadian-French version of Life Orientation Test-Revised. Can J Behav Sci Rev Can Sci Comport. 2008;40:238-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda Y, Matsushita T, Shibata Y, et al. Association between meeting return-to-sport criteria and psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10(5):232596712210939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9096206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Untas A, Aguirrezabal M, Chauveau P, Leguen E, Combe C, Rascle N. Anxi&#xe9;t&#xe9; et d&#xe9;pression en h&#xe9;modialyse&#x2009;: validation de l&#x2019;Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). N&#xe9;phrologie Th&#xe9;rapeutique. 2009;5(3):193-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallieres EF, Vallerand RJ. Traduction et Validation Canadienne-Fran&#xe7;aise de L&#x2019;&#xe9;chelle de L&#x2019;estime de Soi de Rosenberg. Int J Psychol. 1990;25(2):305-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villa FD, H&#xe4;gglund M, Villa SD, Ekstrand J, Wald&#xe9;n M. High rate of second ACL injury following ACL reconstruction in male professional footballers: an updated longitudinal analysis from 118 players in the UEFA Elite Club Injury Study. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(23):1350-1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8606446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33846157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker N, Thatcher J, Lavallee D. A preliminary development of the Re-Injury Anxiety Inventory (RIAI). Phys Ther Sport. 2010;11(1):23-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20129120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Nagelli CV, Hewett TE, Feller JA. Factors associated with psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(7):1545-1550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6598700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29718684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Cai HM, Yang WT, et al. Effect of personality traits on rehabilitation effect after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: an observational study. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2022;65(4):101570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34536570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Tibbetts AS, Covassin T, Cheng G, Nayar S, Heiden E. Epidemiology of overuse and acute injuries among competitive collegiate athletes. J Athl Train. 2012;47(2):198-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3418132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67(6):361-370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuk EF, Kim S, Burland JP, Glaviano NR. The comparison of psychological barriers between individuals with a history of anterior knee pain, anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, and healthy individuals. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18(1):92-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9897036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>