<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41764301</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of different exercise modes on prostate cancer: a Bayesian network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41076-3</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports and Training, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China. liqiangmu815@tjus.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social and Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, 310600, China. liqiangmu815@tjus.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social and Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, 310600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostate cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41764301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41076-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41076-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schafer, E. J. et al. Recent Patterns and Trends in Global Prostate Cancer Incidence and Mortality. Update Eur. Urol. 87 (3), 302&#x2013;313 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Blarigan, E. L. et al. Trends in Prostate Cancer Incidence and Mortality Rates. JAMA Netw. Open. 8(1). (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Z. Q., Shi, A. M., Wang, K. X. &amp; Zhang, W. D. Epidemiology of prostate cancer: current status. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 19 (5), 805&#x2013;812 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberger, B. A., Zaorsky, N. G. &amp; Den, R. B. Comparison of Radical Prostatectomy Versus Radiation and Androgen Deprivation Therapy Strategies as Primary Treatment for High-risk Localized Prostate Cancer: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Eur. Urol. Focus. 6 (2), 404&#x2013;418 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, P. L. et al. Adverse Effects of Androgen Deprivation Therapy and Strategies to Mitigate Them. Eur. Urol. 67 (5), 825&#x2013;836 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houben, L. H. P. et al. Resistance Exercise Training Increases Muscle Mass and Strength in Prostate Cancer Patients on Androgen Deprivation Therapy. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 55 (4), 614&#x2013;624 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock, C. L. et al. Nutrition and physical activity guidelines for cancer survivors. CA. Cancer J. Clin. 62 (4), 242&#x2013;274 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skolarus, T. A. et al. American Cancer Society prostate cancer survivorship care guidelines. CA. Cancer J. Clin. 64 (4), 225&#x2013;249 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guida, J. L. et al. Strategies to Prevent or Remediate Cancer and Treatment-Related Aging. JNCI: J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 113 (2), 112&#x2013;122 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar, N. M. &amp; Jones, L. W. Development of Exercise as Interception Therapy for Cancer. JAMA Oncology. 5(11) 1620&#x2013;1627 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daum, C. W., Cochrane, S. K., Fitzgerald, J. D., Johnson, L. &amp; Buford, T. W. Exercise Interventions for Preserving Physical Function among Cancer Survivors in Middle to Late Life. Journal Frailty &amp; Aging :1&#x2013;11. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller, J. T., Hartland, M. C., Maloney, L. T. &amp; Davison, K. Therapeutic effects of aerobic and resistance exercises for cancer survivors: a systematic review of meta-analyses of clinical trials. Br. J. Sports Med. 52 (20), 1311 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, K. L. et al. Exercise Guidelines for Cancer Survivors: Consensus Statement from International Multidisciplinary Roundtable. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 51 (11), 2375&#x2013;2390 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, S. C., Newton, R. U., Spence, R. R. &amp; Galv&#xe3;o, D. A. The Exercise and Sports Science Australia position statement: Exercise medicine in cancer management. J. Sci. Med. Sport. 22 (11), 1175&#x2013;1199 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Blarigan, E. L. et al. Effect of a Home-based Walking Intervention on Cardiopulmonary Fitness and Quality of Life Among Men with Prostate Cancer on Active Surveillance: The Active Surveillance Exercise Randomized Controlled Trial. Eur. Urol. Oncol. 7 (3), 519&#x2013;526 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke, L. et al. Lifestyle Changes for Improving Disease-specific Quality of Life in Sedentary Men on Long-term Androgen-Deprivation Therapy for Advanced Prostate Cancer: A Randomised Controlled Trial. Eur. Urol. 65 (5), 865&#x2013;872 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o, D. A., Taaffe, D. R., Spry, N., Joseph, D. &amp; Newton, R. U. Combined Resistance and Aerobic Exercise Program Reverses Muscle Loss in Men Undergoing Androgen Suppression Therapy for Prostate Cancer Without Bone Metastases: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J. Clin. Oncol. 28 (2), 340&#x2013;347 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o, D. A. et al. A Multicentre Year-long Randomised Controlled Trial of Exercise Training Targeting Physical Functioning in Men with Prostate Cancer Previously Treated with Androgen Suppression and Radiation from TROG 03.04 RADAR. Eur. Urol. 65 (5), 856&#x2013;864 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuade, J. L. et al. Qigong/tai chi for sleep and fatigue in prostate cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Psycho-Oncology 26 (11), 1936&#x2013;1943 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushik, D. et al. Effects of yoga in men with prostate cancer on quality of life and immune response: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 25 (3), 531&#x2013;538 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wekesa, A., Harrison, M. &amp; Watson, R. W. Physical activity and its mechanistic effects on prostate cancer. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 18 (3), 197&#x2013;207 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedland, S. J. et al. A lifestyle intervention of weight loss via a low-carbohydrate diet plus walking to reduce metabolic disturbances caused by androgen deprivation therapy among prostate cancer patients: carbohydrate and prostate study 1 (CAPS1) randomized controlled trial. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 22 (3), 428&#x2013;437 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, K. et al. Comparing aerobic and resistance exercise emphasis during androgen deprivation and radiation therapy for prostate cancer: A randomised feasibility trial. Supportive Care Cancer 33(7), 601 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie, P. et al. Safety and efficacy of resistance exercise in prostate cancer patients with bone metastases. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 16 (4), 328&#x2013;335 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher, O. et al. Effects of Exercise During Radiation Therapy on Physical Function and Treatment-Related Side Effects in Men With Prostate Cancer: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int. J. Radiat. Oncol. Biol. Phys. 111 (3), 716&#x2013;731 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, M. F., Midtgaard, J. &amp; Bjerre, E. D. Do Patients with Prostate Cancer Benefit from Exercise Interventions? A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. International J. Environ. Res. Public. Health. 19(2), 972 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Valkenhoef, G. et al. Automating network meta-analysis. Res. Synthesis Methods. 3 (4), 285&#x2013;299 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim, S. R., Kim, S-J., Lee, J. &amp; R&#xfc;cker, G. Network meta-analysis: application and practice using R software. Epidemiol. Health 41 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraja, K. &amp; Braga-Neto, U. Bayesian Classification of Proteomics Biomarkers from Selected Reaction Monitoring Data using an Approximate Bayesian Computation-Markov Chain Monte Carlo Approach. Cancer Inform. 17 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavridis, D. &amp; Salanti, G. A practical introduction to multivariate meta-analysis. Stat. Methods Med. Res. 22 (2), 133&#x2013;158 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen, J. P., Crawford, B., Bergman, G. &amp; Stam, W. Bayesian meta-analysis of multiple treatment comparisons: an introduction to mixed treatment comparisons. Value Health. 11 (5), 956&#x2013;964 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatnagar, N., Lakshmi, P. V. M. &amp; Jeyashree, K. Multiple treatment and indirect treatment comparisons: An overview of network meta-analysis. Perspect. Clin. Res. 5(4) (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti, G., Ades, A. E. &amp; Ioannidis, J. P. A. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 64 (2), 163&#x2013;171 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinquart, L., Attiche, N., Bafeta, A., Porcher, R. &amp; Ravaud, P. Uncertainty in Treatment Rankings: Reanalysis of Network Meta-analyses of Randomized Trials. Ann. Intern. Med. 164 (10), 666&#x2013;673 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffart, L. M. et al. Mediators of the resistance and aerobic exercise intervention effect on physical and general health in men undergoing androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer. Cancer 120 (2), 294&#x2013;301 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capela, A. et al. Effects of walking football on adherence, safety, quality of life and physical fitness in patients with prostate cancer: Findings from the PROSTATA_MOVE randomized controlled trial. Front. Oncol. 13 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla Via, J. et al. Musculoskeletal Responses to Exercise Plus Nutrition in Men with Prostate Cancer on Androgen Deprivation: A 12-Month RCT. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 53 (10), 2054&#x2013;2065 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson, J. K. et al. Impact of resistance training on body composition and metabolic syndrome variables during androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer: a pilot randomized controlled trial. BMC Cancer 18(1) (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson, J. K. et al. Effect of Periodized Resistance Training on Skeletal Muscle During Androgen Deprivation Therapy for Prostate Cancer: A Pilot Randomized Trial. Integr. Cancer Ther. 20 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o, D. A. et al. Psychological distress in men with prostate cancer undertaking androgen deprivation therapy: modifying effects of exercise from a year-long randomized controlled trial. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 24 (3), 758&#x2013;766 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o, D. A. et al. Exercise and Psychosexual Education to Improve Sexual Function in Men With Prostate Cancer. JAMA Netw. Open. 8(3) (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskin, C. J. et al. Fitness outcomes from a randomised controlled trial of exercise training for men with prostate cancer: the ENGAGE study. J. Cancer Surviv. 10 (6), 972&#x2013;980 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazova, A. et al. Clinical Utility of miRNA-1, miRNA-29 g and miRNA-133s Plasma Levels in Prostate Cancer Patients With High-Intensity Training After Androgen-Deprivation Therapy. Physiol. Res. S139&#x2013;S47 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. H. et al. The Effect on Bone Outcomes of Home-based Exercise Intervention for Prostate Cancer Survivors Receiving Androgen Deprivation Therapy. Cancer Nurs. 41 (5), 379&#x2013;388 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun, L. J. Lifestyle Intervention for Promoting Physical Activity in Prostate Cancer Patients with Androgen Deprivation Therapy. Journal Men&#x2019;s Health (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndjavera, W. et al. Exercise-induced attenuation of treatment side&#x2010;effects in patients with newly diagnosed prostate cancer beginning androgen&#x2010;deprivation therapy: a randomised controlled trial. BJU Int. 125 (1), 28&#x2013;37 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen, T. S. et al. Effects of strength training on body composition, physical functioning, and quality of life in prostate cancer patients during androgen deprivation therapy. Acta Oncol. 54 (10), 1805&#x2013;1813 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos, E. et al. High-intensity interval training or resistance training versus usual care in men with prostate cancer on active surveillance: a 3-arm feasibility randomized controlled trial. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 46 (12), 1535&#x2013;1544 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S-W. et al. Recovery of Overall Exercise Ability, Quality of Life, and Continence After 12-Week Combined Exercise Intervention in Elderly Patients Who Underwent Radical Prostatectomy: A Randomized Controlled Study. Urology 80 (2), 299&#x2013;306 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santa Mina, D. et al. Exercise effects on adipokines and the IGF axis in men with prostate cancer treated with androgen deprivation: A randomized study. Can. Urol. Association J. 7, 11&#x2013;12 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe, D. R. et al. Effects of Different Exercise Modalities on Fatigue in Prostate Cancer Patients Undergoing Androgen Deprivation Therapy: A Year-long Randomised Controlled Trial. Eur. Urol. 72 (2), 293&#x2013;299 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uth, J. et al. Football training over 5 years is associated with preserved femoral bone mineral density in men with prostate cancer. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 28 (S1), 61&#x2013;73 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uth, J. et al. Efficacy of recreational football on bone health, body composition, and physical functioning in men with prostate cancer undergoing androgen deprivation therapy: 32-week follow-up of the FC prostate randomised controlled trial. Osteoporos. Int. 27 (4), 1507&#x2013;1518 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uth, J. et al. Football training improves lean body mass in men with prostate cancer undergoing androgen deprivation therapy. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 24 (S1), 105&#x2013;112 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters-Stone, K. M. et al. Resistance Training Reduces Disability in Prostate Cancer Survivors on Androgen Deprivation Therapy: Evidence From a Randomized Controlled Trial. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 96 (1), 7&#x2013;14 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters-Stone, K. M. et al. Benefits of partnered strength training for prostate cancer survivors and spouses: results from a randomized controlled trial of the Exercising Together project. J. Cancer Surviv. 10 (4), 633&#x2013;644 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjerre, E. D. et al. Football Compared with Usual Care in Men with Prostate Cancer (FC Prostate Community Trial): A Pragmatic Multicentre Randomized Controlled Trial. Sports Med. 49 (1), 145&#x2013;158 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen, A. K. et al. A lifestyle intervention among elderly men on active surveillance for non-aggressive prostate cancer: a randomised feasibility study with whole-grain rye and exercise. Trials. 18(1). (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houben, L. H. P. et al. Benefits of resistance training are not preserved after cessation of supervised training in prostate cancer patients on androgen deprivation therapy. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 24 (1), 116&#x2013;126 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid, T. et al. Effect of a 2-year home-based endurance training intervention on physiological function and PSA doubling time in prostate cancer patients. Cancer Causes Control. 27 (2), 165&#x2013;174 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J-S. et al. Exercise in advanced prostate cancer elevates myokine levels and suppresses in-vitro cell growth. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 25 (1), 86&#x2013;92 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill, R. F., Haseen, F., Murray, L. J., O&#x2019;Sullivan, J. M. &amp; Cantwell, M. M. A randomised controlled trial to evaluate the efficacy of a 6-month dietary and physical activity intervention for patients receiving androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer. J. Cancer Surviv. 9 (3), 431&#x2013;440 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rantaniemi, L. et al. Is Exercise During Androgen Deprivation Therapy Effective and Safe? A Randomized Controlled Trial. Scandinavian J. Med. &amp; Sci. Sports. 35(6). (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villumsen, B. R., Jorgensen, M. G., Frystyk, J., H&#xf8;rdam, B. &amp; Borre, M. Home-based &#x2018;exergaming&#x2019; was safe and significantly improved 6&#x2010;min walking distance in patients with prostate cancer: a single&#x2010;blinded randomised controlled trial. BJU Int. 124 (4), 600&#x2013;608 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall, B. A. et al. Exercise Improves V&#x2d9;O2max and Body Composition in Androgen Deprivation Therapy&#x2013;treated Prostate Cancer Patients. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 49 (8), 1503&#x2013;1510 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke, L. et al. Lifestyle Intervention in Men with Advanced Prostate Cancer Receiving Androgen Suppression Therapy: A Feasibility Study. Cancer Epidemiol. Biomarkers Prev. 20 (4), 647&#x2013;657 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo, R. A. et al. Levels of fatigue and distress in senior prostate cancer survivors enrolled in a 12-week randomized controlled trial of Qigong. J. Cancer Surviv. 8 (1), 60&#x2013;69 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojan, K. et al. Physical exercise for functional capacity, blood immune function, fatigue, and quality of life in high-risk prostate cancer patients during radiotherapy: a prospective, randomized clinical study. Eur. J. Phys. Rehabil Med. 52 (4), 489&#x2013;501 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojan, K., Kwiatkowska-Borowczyk, E., Leporowska, E. &amp; Milecki, P. Inflammation, cardiometabolic markers, and functional changes in men with prostate cancer. A randomized controlled trial of a 12-month exercise program. Pol. Arch. Intern. Med. 127 (1), 25&#x2013;35 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlais, C. S. et al. Quality of life for men with metastatic castrate-resistant prostate cancer participating in an aerobic and resistance exercise pilot intervention. Urologic Oncology: Seminars Original Investigations. 41 (3), 146. e1-.e11. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon, C. et al. Pilot Study on the Impact of a Home-Based Exercise Program on Inflammatory Cytokines and Quality of Life in Men with Prostate Cancer Under Active Surveillance. Cancer Control 29 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piraux, E. et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training compared with resistance training in prostate cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 24 (1), 156&#x2013;165 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles, L. A. et al. The Prostate cancer&#x2013;Exercise and Metformin randomised controlled feasibility Trial (Pre-EMpT) in men following active surveillance, radical prostatectomy and radiotherapy. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 11(1), 71 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal, R. J. et al. Resistance Exercise in Men Receiving Androgen Deprivation Therapy for Prostate Cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 21 (9), 1653&#x2013;1659 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal, R. J. et al. Randomized Controlled Trial of Resistance or Aerobic Exercise in Men Receiving Radiation Therapy for Prostate Cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 27 (3), 344&#x2013;351 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, C. L. C. et al. Active for LifeAfter Cancer: a randomized trial examining a lifestyle physical activity program for prostate cancer patients. Psycho-Oncology 15 (10), 847&#x2013;862 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culos-Reed, S. N. et al. Physical activity for men receiving androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer: benefits from a 16-week intervention. Support. Care Cancer. 18 (5), 591&#x2013;599 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg, B. L. et al. SleepNow &#x2013; A combined cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia and physical exercise intervention in men with metastatic prostate cancer: results from a feasibility randomized controlled trial. Acta Oncol. 64, 222&#x2013;228 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, D-W. et al. A Randomized Trial of the Effects of Exercise on Anxiety, Fear of Cancer Progression and Quality of Life in Prostate Cancer Patients on Active Surveillance. J. Urol. 207 (4), 814&#x2013;822 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston, P. M. et al. Effects of a clinician referral and exercise program for men who have completed active treatment for prostate cancer: A multicenter cluster randomized controlled trial (ENGAGE). Cancer 121 (15), 2646&#x2013;2654 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zopf, E. M. et al. Effects of a 15-Month Supervised Exercise Program on Physical and Psychological Outcomes in Prostate Cancer Patients Following Prostatectomy. Integr. Cancer Ther. 14 (5), 409&#x2013;418 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keilani, M. et al. Effects of resistance exercise in prostate cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Support. Care Cancer. 25 (9), 2953&#x2013;2968 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempin, S. et al. The Effect of Resistance and/or Aerobic Training on Quality of Life, Fitness, and Body Composition in Prostate Cancer Patients&#x2014;A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Cancers 16(24), 4286 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez, P. et al. Interventions for Improving Body Composition in Men with Prostate Cancer: A Systematic Review and Network Meta-analysis. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 54 (5), 728&#x2013;740 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale, D. G. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 20 (5 Suppl), S135&#x2013;S145 (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xc3;O, D. A. et al. Resistance Training and Reduction of Treatment Side Effects in Prostate Cancer Patients. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 38 (12), 2045&#x2013;2052 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigaran, A. et al. The effect of exercise training on cardiometabolic health in men with prostate cancer receiving androgen deprivation therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 24 (1), 35&#x2013;48 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid, T. et al. Endurance training improves insulin sensitivity and body composition in prostate cancer patients treated with androgen deprivation therapy. Endocr. Relat. Cancer. 20 (5), 621&#x2013;632 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader, S. et al. Impact of aerobic and resistance training on fatigue, quality of life, and physical activity in prostate cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Surg. 110 (10), 6170&#x2013;6181 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, X. et al. Which Type of Exercise During Radiation Therapy Is Optimal to Improve Fatigue and Quality of Life in Men with Prostate Cancer? A Bayesian Network Analysis. Eur. Urol. Open. Sci. 43, 74&#x2013;86 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams, S. C. et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training on fatigue and quality of life in testicular cancer survivors. Br. J. Cancer. 118 (10), 1313&#x2013;1321 (2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>