<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41549493</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing a Repetition-Based Inter-Set Rest Adjustment Method in Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19417381251398823</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19417381251398823</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381251398823</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381251398823</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study aimed to develop an objective, repetition-based method for inter-set rest adjustment in resistance training (RT), addressing limitations of fixed and self-selected intervals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The adjustable protocol would yield greater repetition volume, higher velocity, and lower fatigue than the fixed protocol, with reduced time cost compared with the self-selected protocol.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Crossover randomized trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 20 young adults completed 3 RT protocols in randomized order: fixed, self-selected, and adjustable. Each protocol involved 5 sets of bench press and bench pull at approximately 75% 1 repetition maximal, performed close to failure. The protocols differed in inter-set rest strategy: fixed (3-minute rest), self-selected (participant-determined), and adjustable (based on previous set repetition count).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our findings indicated that the self-selected and adjustable protocols resulted in significantly greater repetition volume compared with the fixed protocol (<i>F</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.0; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003). Although the self-selected and adjustable protocols exhibited significantly higher fastest set velocity than the fixed protocol (<i>F</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.5, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04), the practical difference was only 0.01&#x2009;m/s. In addition, no significant main effects of protocol were observed in mean set velocity, blood lactate concentration, or perceived exertion (<i>F</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.1-2.4; <i>P</i> = 0.10-0.58). In terms of time efficiency, the fixed protocol was the most efficient, followed by the adjustable protocol, with the self-selected protocol being the least efficient.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">People using the adjustable protocol achieved greater repetition volume without increased metabolic stress or perceived exertion compared with the fixed 3-minute rest. Although the adjustable protocol sacrifices some time efficiency compared with the fixed protocol, it remains more efficient than the self-selected approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The repetition-based inter-set rest adjustment approach can serve as a feasible alternative to both fixed and self-selected inter-set rest approaches in RT.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zongwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hansen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Sichuan Agricultural University, Ya'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weakley</LastName><ForeName>Jonathon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research (CARR) Centre, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds Beckett University, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoqian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shandong University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0608-8755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de la Sant&#xed;sima Concepci&#xf3;n, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery time</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">velocity monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no potential conflicts of interest in the development and publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41549493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12815620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381251398823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Francesco L, Latini D, Hoffman JR. Autoregulation does not provide additional benefits to a mixed session periodized resistance training program in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(9):1535-1542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11343444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38814694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Ari A, Silverman Y, Obolski U, Halperin I. On your mark, get set, choose! A randomized cross-over study comparing fixed and self-selected rest periods in interval running among professional female soccer players. Sports Med Open. 2025;11(1):2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11730044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39806263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Salles BF, Polito MD, Goessler KF, Mannarino P, Matta TT, Sim&#xe3;o R. Effects of fixed vs. self-suggested rest between sets in upper and lower body exercises performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16(8):927-931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27050709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>do Carmo EC, De Souza EO, Roschel H, et al. Self-selected rest interval improves vertical jump postactivation potentiation. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(1):91-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29481453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farah BQ, Lima AH, Lins-Filho OL, et al. Effects of rest interval length on rating of perceived exertion during a multiple-set resistance exercise. Percept Mot Skills. 2012;115(1):273-282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23033762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Falkel JE. Value of resistance training for the reduction of sports injuries. Sports Med. 1986;3(1):61-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3633121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes EW, K&#xfc;lkamp W, de Andrade Blanco RL, Knihs D, Dal Pupo J. Variations in mean propulsive velocity responses during bench press exercise across different inter-set rest intervals. Sport Sci Health. 2025:21:337-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Jimenez-Reyes P, Janicijevic D, Tufano JJ, Marquez G, Garcia-Ramos A. Effect of different interset rest intervals on mean velocity during the squat and bench press exercises. Sports Biomech. 2023;22(7):834-847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):137-151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Cobley SP, Davies TB, Michael SW, Halaki M. Accuracy in estimating repetitions to failure during resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(8):2162-2168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27787474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henselmans M, Schoenfeld BJ. The effect of inter-set rest intervals on resistance exercise-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2014;44(12):1635-1643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25047853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare E, Stavreski B, Jennings GL, Kingwell BA. Exploring motivation and barriers to physical activity among active and inactive Australian adults. Sports. 2017;5(3):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JC, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exerc Sci. 2018;11(5):226-238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jani&#x107;ijevi&#x107; D, Miras-Moreno S, Morenas-Aguilar MD, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Does the length of inter-set rest periods impact the volume of bench pull repetitions completed before surpassing various cut-off velocities? J Human Kinet. 2024;95:139-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jani&#x107;ijevi&#x107; D, Miras-Moreno S, Morenas-Aguilar MD, Moraga-Maureira E, Weakley J, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Optimizing mechanical performance in the bench press: the combined influence of inter-set rest periods and proximity to failure. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(24):2193-2200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38369845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Castilla AP, Ramos AG, et al. The acute and chronic effects of implementing velocity loss thresholds during resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and critical evaluation of the literature. Sports Med. 2023;53(1):177-214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesinski M, Prieske O, Granacher U. Effects and dose-response relationships of resistance training on physical performance in youth athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):781-795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes CR, Crisp AH, Schoenfeld B, et al. Effect of rest interval length between sets on total load lifted and blood lactate response during total-body resistance exercise session. Asian J Sports Med. 2018;9(2):e57500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Marcos-Frutos D, Leban &#x17d;, Li Z, et al. The impact of <i>Rhodiola rosea</i> extract on strength performance in alternative bench-press and bench-pull exercises under resting and mental fatigue conditions: a randomized, triple-blinded, placebo-controlled, crossover trial. Nutrients. 2025;17(6):940.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11944791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40289957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques DL, Ribeiro JN, Sousa AC, Travassos B, Marques MC. Strength and power performance changes during an in-season resistance training program in elite futsal players: a case study. J Hum Kinet. 2022;84:184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9679173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36457472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martos-Arregui A, Li Z, Miras-Moreno S, et al. Comparative effects of caffeine, beta-alanine, and their combination on mechanical, physiological, and perceptual responses to upper-body superset resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2025;125(3):837-850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39438314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio F, Faigenbaum AD, Larumbe-Zabala E, et al. Effects of different resistance training volumes on strength and power in team sport athletes. J Strength Condit Res. 2013;27(7):1832-1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23044934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Nosaka K, Steele J. Maximal number of repetitions at percentages of the one repetition maximum: a meta-regression and moderator analysis of sex, age, training status, and exercise. Sports Med. 2024;54(2):303-321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37792272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Mignogna P, Mignardi S, Tonni F, D&#x2019;Ottavio S. Effect of different pushing speeds on bench press. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(5):376-380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharhag-Rosenberger F, Meyer T, G&#xe4;&#xdf;ler N, Faude O, Kindermann W. Exercise at given percentages of VO2max: heterogeneous metabolic responses between individuals. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(1):74-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19230766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Condit Res. 2017;31(12):3508-3523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Polito M, Freitas de Salles B, et al. Acute and long-term comparison of fixed vs. self-selected rest interval between sets on upper-body strength. J Strength Condit Res. 2022;36(2):540-544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinney J, Millward H. Time and money: a new look at poverty and the barriers to physical activity in Canada. Social Indicators Res. 2010;99(2):341-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Cowley N, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. The effect of feedback on resistance training performance and adaptations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(9):1789-1803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37410360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Feng S, Peng R, Li H. The role of velocity-based training (VBT) in enhancing athletic performance in trained individuals: a meta-analysis of controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(15):9252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Bi S, Luo Y, Cao Y, Zhang G. Auto-regulation method vs. Fixed-loading method in maximum strength training for athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:651112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7994759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33776802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Feng S, Su S. The effect of various training variables on developing muscle strength in velocity-based training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Med. 2023;44(12):857-864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37196672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Weakley J, Li H, Li Z, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Superset versus traditional resistance training prescriptions: a systematic review and meta-analysis exploring acute and chronic effects on mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual variables. Sports Med. 2025;55(4):953-975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12011898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39903375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Dolan C, Quiles JM, et al. Efficacy of daily one-repetition maximum training in well-trained powerlifters and weightlifters: a case series. Nutr Hospital. 2016;33(2):437-443.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>