<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41918138</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2072-1315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of health, population, and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Health Popul Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of cumulative obesity- and insulin resistance-related indices with incident cardiovascular disease in Chinese middle-aged and elderly populations: a nationwide prospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41043-026-01306-w</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiarun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yixin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xinnan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Congai</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuanyuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Jiangyan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510641, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Beijing Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Acupuncture Neuromodulation, Beijing, 100010, China. lululalavictor1985@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>7232270</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82374575</GrantID><Agency>China National Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CFH2024-2-2235</GrantID><Agency>Capital's Funds for Health Improvement and Research</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>B2207</GrantID><Agency>Out-standing Young Talents Program of Capital Medial University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DFL20241001</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Hospital Management Center "peak" talent training plan team</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Bangladesh</Country><MedlineTA>J Health Popul Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959228</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1606-0997</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CHARLS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study protocol was reviewed and approved by the Ethical Review Committee of Peking University (IRB00001052-11015), and all participants provided written informed consent at the time of participation. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Clinical trial number: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41918138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-026-01306-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41043-026-01306-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Causes of Death Collaborators. Global burden of 288 causes of death and life expectancy decomposition in 204 countries and territories and 811 subnational locations, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403(10440):2100&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah GA, Fuster V, Murray CJL, Roth GA. Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risks Collaborators. Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risks, 1990&#x2013;2022. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;82(25):2350&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, Addolorato G, Ammirati E, Baddour LM, et al. Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risk Factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: Update From the GBD 2019 Study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(25):2982&#x2013;3021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill MA, Yang Y, Zhang L, Sun Z, Jia G, Parrish AR, et al. Insulin resistance, cardiovascular stiffening and cardiovascular disease. Metabolism. 2021;119:154766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluher M. Obesity: global epidemiology and pathogenesis. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2019;15(5):288&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Cai X, Mai W, Li M, Hu Y. Association between prediabetes and risk of cardiovascular disease and all cause mortality: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2016;355:i5953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MS, Kim WJ, Khera AV, Kim JY, Yon DK, Lee SW, et al. Association between adiposity and cardiovascular outcomes: an umbrella review and meta-analysis of observational and Mendelian randomization studies. Eur Heart J. 2021;42(34):3388&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piche ME, Tchernof A, Despres JP. Obesity Phenotypes, Diabetes, and Cardiovascular Diseases. Circ Res. 2020;126(11):1477&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Chen S, Xu Q, Xia X, Zhang Y, Wang P, et al. Magnitude and time course of insulin resistance accumulation with the risk of cardiovascular disease: an 11-years cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22(1):339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coral DE, Smit F, Farzaneh A, Gieswinkel A, Tajes JF, Sparso T, et al. Subclassification of obesity for precision prediction of cardiometabolic diseases. Nat Med. 2025;31(2):534&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Li M, Zeng T, Hu R, Xu Y, Xu M, et al. Association Between Insulin Resistance and Cardiovascular Disease Risk Varies According to Glucose Tolerance Status: A Nationwide Prospective Cohort Study. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(8):1863&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFronzo RA, Tobin JD, Andres R. Glucose clamp technique: a method for quantifying insulin secretion and resistance. Am J Physiol. 1979;237(3):E214&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka S, Matsuzawa Y, Tokunaga K, Tarui S. Contribution of intra-abdominal fat accumulation to the impairment of glucose and lipid metabolism in human obesity. Metabolism. 1987;36(1):54&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Jaramillo P, Gomez-Arbelaez D, Martinez-Bello D, Abat MEM, Alhabib KF, Avezum A, et al. Association of the triglyceride glucose index as a measure of insulin resistance with mortality and cardiovascular disease in populations from five continents (PURE study): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2023;4(1):e23&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D, Zhou J, Garstka MA, Xu Q, Li Q, Wang L, et al. Association of obesity- and insulin resistance-related indices with subclinical carotid atherosclerosis in type 1 diabetes: a cross-sectional study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Sun Z, Li Y, Yang Y, Liu W, Huang M, et al. Association between the cumulative estimated glucose disposal rate and incident cardiovascular disease in individuals over the age of 50 years and without diabetes: data from two large cohorts in China and the United States. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhao L, Lu Y, Xiao Y, Zhou X. Insulin resistance assessed by estimated glucose disposal rate and risk of incident cardiovascular diseases among individuals without diabetes: findings from a nationwide, population based, prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Hu Q, Li Z, Zhang X, Yang L, Kong L. Dose-response association between Chinese visceral adiposity index and cardiovascular disease: a national prospective cohort study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2024;15:1284144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Luo M, Sheng Z, Zhou R, Xiang W, Huang W, et al. Association of lipid accumulation product with all-cause and cardiovascular disease mortality: Result from NHANES database. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;34(6):1467&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Y, Wang B, Geng T, Chen J, Chen W, Li L. The association between TyG and all-cause/non-cardiovascular mortality in general patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus is modified by age: results from the cohort study of NHANES 1999&#x2013;2018. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao T, Luo T, Pei H, Yimingniyazi B, Aili D, Aimudula A, et al. Association between abdominal obesity indices and risk of cardiovascular events in Chinese populations with type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Y, Li Z, Sun M, Wu Q, Shi H, Ye L. Changes in remnant cholesterol and the incidence of diabetes: Results from two large prospective cohort studies. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27(7):3645&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Wu Q, Liu H, Hu W, Zhu J, Ji Z, et al. Predictive value of remnant cholesterol inflammatory index for stroke risk: Evidence from the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal study. J Adv Res. 2025;76:543&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Hu Y, Smith JP, Strauss J, Yang G. Cohort profile: the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study (CHARLS). Int J Epidemiol. 2014;43(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B, Mancia G, Spiering W, Agabiti Rosei E, Azizi M, Burnier M, et al. 2018 ESC/ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. Eur Heart J. 2018;39(33):3021&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addendum. 2. Classification and Diagnosis of Diabetes: Standards of Medical Care in Diabetes-2021. Diabetes Care 2021;44(Suppl. 1):S15-S33. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(9):2182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Li J, Chen J, Hu D, Li Y, Huang J, et al. Predicting lifetime risk for developing atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in Chinese population: the China-PAR project. Sci Bull (Beijing). 2018;63(12):779&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Li J, Hu D, Chen J, Li Y, Huang J, et al. Predicting the 10-Year Risks of Atherosclerotic Cardiovascular Disease in Chinese Population: The China-PAR Project (Prediction for ASCVD Risk in China). Circulation. 2016;134(19):1430&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SV, O&#x2019;Donoghue ML, Ruel M, Rab T, Tamis-Holland JE, Alexander JH, et al. 2025 ACC/AHA/ACEP/NAEMSP/SCAI Guideline for the Management of Patients With Acute Coronary Syndromes: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2025;151(13):e771&#x2013;862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visseren FLJ, Mach F, Smulders YM, Carballo D, Koskinas KC, Back M, et al. 2021 ESC Guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice. Eur Heart J. 2021;42(34):3227&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFronzo RA. Insulin resistance, lipotoxicity, type 2 diabetes and atherosclerosis: the missing links. The Claude Bernard Lecture 2009. Diabetologia. 2010;53(7):1270&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Li S, Ren Q, Qiu Y, Pan M, Liu G, et al. The interaction between triglyceride-glucose index and visceral adiposity in cardiovascular disease risk: findings from a nationwide Chinese cohort. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhao L, Lu Y, Meng X, Zhou X. Association between Chinese visceral adiposity index and risk of stroke incidence in middle-aged and elderly Chinese population: evidence from a large national cohort study. J Transl Med. 2023;21(1):518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li H, Chen X, Liang X. Association between various insulin resistance indices and cardiovascular disease in middle-aged and elderly individuals: evidence from two prospectives nationwide cohort surveys. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2024;15:1483468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Zhu T, Song W, Zhai Y, Tang Y, Ruan F, et al. Assessment of six insulin resistance surrogate indexes for predicting stroke incidence in Chinese middle-aged and elderly populations with abnormal glucose metabolism: a nationwide prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Liu J, Shen Q, Chen H, Liu Y, Wang N, et al. Body Roundness Index Trajectories and the Incidence of Cardiovascular Disease: Evidence From the China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2024;13(19):e034768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang D, Ma R, Zhong X, Jiang Y, Lu J, Li Y, et al. Positive association between different triglyceride glucose index-related indicators and psoriasis: evidence from NHANES. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1325557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn HS. The lipid accumulation product performs better than the body mass index for recognizing cardiovascular risk: a population-based comparison. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2005;5:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J, Zhang Y, Zhu Y, Chen W, Chen L, Ma F, et al. Estimated glucose disposal rate for predicting cardiovascular events and mortality in patients with non-diabetic chronic kidney disease: a prospective cohort study. BMC Med. 2024;22(1):411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domazet SL, Olesen TB, Stidsen JV, Svensson CK, Nielsen JS, Thomsen RW, et al. Low-grade inflammation in persons with recently diagnosed type 2 diabetes: The role of abdominal adiposity and putative mediators. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26(6):2092&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed MUD, Syed BA, Ong SA, Oreskovich FJ, Gunn SM. Characteristics of Abdominal Visceral Adipose Tissue, Metabolic Health and the Gut Microbiome in Adults. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2024;109(3):680&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein EJ, Osman JL, Cohen HW, Rajpathak SN, Lewis O, Crandall JP. Use of the estimated glucose disposal rate as a measure of insulin resistance in an urban multiethnic population with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(8):2280&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofolo M, Gualdani E, Scarale MG, Bianchi C, Aragona M, Campi F, et al. Insulin Resistance and Risk of Major Vascular Events and All-Cause Mortality in Type 1 Diabetes: A 10-Year Follow-up Study. Diabetes Care. 2020;43(10):e139&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao S, Yu L, Li J, Wu J, Huang X, Xie Z, et al. Insulin resistance quantified by estimated glucose disposal rate predicts cardiovascular disease incidence: a nationwide prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Zhou Z, Wu X, Qiu Y, Liu Z, Luo L, et al. Association between the changes in the estimated glucose disposal rate and new-onset cardiovascular disease in middle-aged and elderly individuals: A nationwide prospective cohort study in China. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27(4):1859&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju SH, Yi HS. Implication of Sex Differences in Visceral Fat for the Assessment of Incidence Risk of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. Diabetes Metab J. 2022;46(3):414&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchernof A, Despres JP. Pathophysiology of human visceral obesity: an update. Physiol Rev. 2013;93(1):359&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Singal PK, Ravandi A, Rabinovich-Nikitin I. Sex-Specific Differences in the Pathophysiology of Hypertension. Biomolecules. 2025;15(1):143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X, Wang W. Estimated glucose disposal rate and risk of cardiovascular disease and mortality in U.S. adults with prediabetes: a nationwide cross-sectional and prospective cohort study. Acta Diabetol. 2024;61(11):1413&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goff DC Jr., Lloyd-Jones DM, Bennett G, Coady S, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Gibbons R, et al. 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the assessment of cardiovascular risk: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2014;129(25 Suppl 2):S49&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PW, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Levy D, Belanger AM, Silbershatz H, Kannel WB. Prediction of coronary heart disease using risk factor categories. Circulation. 1998;97(18):1837&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Moons KGM, Dhiman P, Riley RD, Beam AL, Van Calster B, et al. TRIPOD&#x2009;+&#x2009;AI statement: updated guidance for reporting clinical prediction models that use regression or machine learning methods. BMJ. 2024;385:e078378.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>