<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41782801</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1177-9322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioinformatics and biology insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioinform Biol Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence to Advance Bioinformatics in Africa: Opportunities, Challenges, and Ethical Considerations in Combating Antimicrobial Resistance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11779322261427123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>11779322261427123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11779322261427123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/11779322261427123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Africa continues to bear a disproportionate burden of infectious diseases, particularly antimicrobial-resistant (AMR) infections, which significantly affect public health and socio-economic development. Addressing these complex health threats requires innovative approaches to data analysis, pathogen surveillance, and intervention design. The emergence of advanced computational tools especially artificial intelligence (AI) is expected to reduce turnaround times for AMR prediction from days to hours by leveraging whole-genome sequencing (WGS)-based models. This article explores the synergistic integration of AI and bioinformatics, focusing on their application in combating AMR in Africa. It details how AI techniques, particularly machine learning (ML) and deep learning (DL) algorithms, can enhance genomic research by automating the analysis of large-scale sequence datasets, predicting resistance patterns, and modeling infections transmission dynamics. In regions with limited laboratory capacity, AI models can detect resistance genes rapidly and assist clinicians in selecting appropriate antibiotics, offering a faster and more scalable alternative to traditional diagnostics. Tools such as convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and support vector machines (SVMs) are examples of models capable of classifying pathogen strains based on genetic data. Furthermore, the article highlights the emerging role of large language models (LLMs) in supporting bioinformatics workflows. These tools aid researchers by generating analysis scripts, interpreting complex outputs, troubleshooting code errors, summarizing literature, and preparing manuscripts or grant proposals particularly benefiting early-career scientists who may lack access to advanced training or mentorship. Despite notable progress, significant challenges remain, including limited infrastructure, barriers to data sharing, and the urgent need for ethical guidelines and policies to govern AI integration. Ultimately, this article underscores the transformative potential of AI in advancing bioinformatics across Africa and advocates for sustained investment in infrastructure, capacity-building, and responsible policy frameworks to harness AI for improved health research and disease control outcomes. We propose 3 priority actions: building African AMR genomic datasets, investing in AI-ready infrastructure, and developing responsible data-governance frameworks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyimo</LastName><ForeName>Beatus</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6743-4546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Bio-Engineering (LiSBE), Nelson Mandela African Institution of Science and Technology (NM-AIST), Arusha, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioinform Biol Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101467187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1177-9322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-enabled diagnostics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AMR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioinformatics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genomic AMR prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genomic surveillance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41782801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12953961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11779322261427123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_11779322261427123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO Strategic and Technical Advisory Group for Antimicrobial Resistance (STAG-AMR). WHO; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Bank. Drug-Resistant Infections a Threat to Our Economic Future. World Bank; 2017. www.worldbank.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antimicrobial Resistance Collaborators. The burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in the WHO African region in 2019: a cross-country systematic analysis. Lancet Glob Health. 2024;12:e201-e216. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(23)00539-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(23)00539-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10805005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38134946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SK, Hussein S, Qurbani K, et al. Antimicrobial resistance: impacts, challenges, and future prospects. J Med Surg Public Health. 2024;2:100081. doi: 10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chigozie VU, Aniokete CU, Ogbonna PI, Iroha RI. Transforming antimicrobial resistance mitigation: the genomic revolution in one health and public health. Discov Appl Sci. 2025;7:1187. doi: 10.1007/s42452-025-07053-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-025-07053-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherry NL, Lee JYH, Giulieri SG, et al. Genomics for antimicrobial resistance&#x2014;progress and future directions. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2025;69:e0108224. doi: 10.1128/aac.01082-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.01082-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12057382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40227048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deo RC. Machine learning in medicine. Circulation. 2015;132:1920-1930. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.001593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.001593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26572668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libbrecht MW, Noble WS. Machine learning applications in genetics and genomics. Nat Rev Genet. 2015;16:321-332. doi: 10.1038/nrg3920</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrg3920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5204302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25948244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyimo BM, Popkin-Hall ZR, Giesbrecht DJ, et al. Potential opportunities and challenges of deploying next generation sequencing and CRISPR-Cas systems to support diagnostics and surveillance towards malaria control and elimination in Africa. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:757844. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2022.757844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2022.757844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35909968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiosia A, Boylan S, Retford M, et al. Current data science capacity building initiatives for health researchers in LMICs: global &amp; regional efforts. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1418382. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1418382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1418382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11631614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39664549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangeda RZ, Mwakilili AD, Masamu U, et al. A Baseline evaluation of bioinformatics capacity in Tanzania reveals areas for training. Front Educ (Lausanne). 2021;6:665313. doi: 10.3389/feduc.2021.665313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2021.665313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochola R. The case for genomic surveillance in Africa. Trop Med Infect Dis. 2025;10:129. doi: 10.3390/tropicalmed10050129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/tropicalmed10050129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12115357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40423359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babirye SR, Nsubuga M, Mboowa G, Batte C, Galiwango R, Kateete DP. Machine learning-based prediction of antibiotic resistance in Mycobacterium tuberculosis clinical isolates from Uganda. BMC Infect Dis. 2024;24:1391. doi: 10.1186/s12879-024-10282-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-024-10282-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39639222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiffer-Smadja N, Rawson TM, Ahmad R, et al. Machine learning for clinical decision support in infectious diseases: a narrative review of current applications. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26:584-595. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2019.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2019.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31539636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Mao Y, Hua X, et al. Machine learning-based prediction of antimicrobial resistance and identification of AMR-related SNPs in Mycobacterium tuberculosis. BMC Genom Data. 2025;26:48. doi: 10.1186/s12863-025-01338-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12863-025-01338-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12255030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40646483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nsubuga M, Galiwango R, Jjingo D, Mboowa G. Generalizability of machine learning in predicting antimicrobial resistance in E. Coli: a multi-country case study in Africa. BMC Genomics. 2024;25:287. doi: 10.1186/s12864-024-10214-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12864-024-10214-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38500034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanui CK, Ndembi N, Kebede Y, Tessema SK. Artificial intelligence to transform public health in Africa. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024;24:e542. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(24)00435-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(24)00435-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39053483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasse GE, Cosh SM, Humphries J, Islam MS. Leveraging artificial intelligence for One Health: opportunities and challenges in tackling antimicrobial resistance&#x2014;scoping review. One Health Outlook. 2025;7:51. doi: 10.1186/s42522-025-00170-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42522-025-00170-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12532937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41102753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Smit D, Smuts H.
The impact of GitHub copilot on developer productivity from a software engineering body of knowledge perspective, 2024. https://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Fan L, Li L, et al. Large language models in biomedical and health informatics: a review with bibliometric analysis. J Healthc Inform Res. 2024;8:658-711. doi: 10.1007/s41666-024-00171-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41666-024-00171-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11499577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39463859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisong E. Building Machine Learning and Deep Learning Models on Google Cloud Platform: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners. Apress Media LLC; 2019. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4842-4470-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4842-4470-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelwanis M, Simsekler MCE, Gabor AF, Sleptchenko A, Omar M. Artificial intelligence adoption challenges from healthcare providers&#x2019; perspectives: a comprehensive review and future directions. Saf Sci. 2026;193:107028. doi: 10.1016/j.ssci.2025.107028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssci.2025.107028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Erickson N, Mueller J, Shirkov A, et al. AutoGluon-tabular: robust and accurate AutoML for structured data. Published Online March 13, 2020. http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.06505</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaillard M, Lima L, Tournoud M, et al. A fast and agnostic method for bacterial genome-wide association studies: bridging the gap between k-mers and genetic events. PLoS Genet. 2018;14:e1007758. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgen.1007758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgen.1007758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6258240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30419019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drouin A, Gigu&#xe8;re S, D&#xe9;raspe M, et al. Predictive computational phenotyping and biomarker discovery using reference-free genome comparisons. BMC Genomics. 2016;17:754. doi: 10.1186/s12864-016-2889-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12864-016-2889-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5037627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaseghi H, Akrami SM, Rashidi-Nezhad A. The challenges in the interpretation of genetic variants detected by genomics techniques in patients with congenital anomalies. J Clin Lab Anal. 2023;37:e24967. doi: 10.1002/jcla.24967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcla.24967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10623530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37823350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serge Andigema A, Tania Cyrielle NN, Ekwelle E. Artificial intelligence in African healthcare: catalyzing innovation while confronting structural challenges. Preprint Posted Online June 23, 2025. doi: 10.20944/preprints202506.1824.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202506.1824.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse BT, Ashley EA, Ongarello S, et al. Antimicrobial resistance in Africa: a systematic review. BMC Infect Dis. 2017;17:616. doi: 10.1186/s12879-017-2713-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-017-2713-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5594539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28893183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SE, Pham DT, Pak GD, et al. The genomic epidemiology of multi-drug resistant invasive non-typhoidal Salmonella in selected sub-Saharan African countries. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e005659. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8330565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34341020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradigaravand D, Palm M, Farewell A, Mustonen V, Warringer J, Parts L. Prediction of antibiotic resistance in Escherichia coli from large-scale pan-genome data. PLoS Comput Biol. 2018;14:e1006258. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30550564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anyaegbunam ZKG, Mba IE, Doowuese Y, et al. Antimicrobial resistance containment in Africa: moving beyond surveillance. Biosaf Health. 2024;6:50-58. doi: 10.1016/j.bsheal.2023.12.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bsheal.2023.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11894975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40078303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesesky MW, Hussain T, Wallace M, et al. Evaluation of machine learning and rules-based approaches for predicting antimicrobial resistance profiles in gram-negative bacilli from whole genome sequence data. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:1887. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2016.01887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2016.01887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5124574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler NE, Price V, Cunningham-Oakes E, et al. Innovations in genomic antimicrobial resistance surveillance. Lancet Microbe. 2023;4:e1063-e1070. doi: 10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00285-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2666-5247(23)00285-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37977163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mass&#xe9; J, Lard&#xe9; H, Archambault M, et al. Conventional and unsupervised artificial intelligence analyses identified risk factors for antimicrobial resistance on dairy farms in the province of Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada. J Dairy Sci. 2024;107:11398-11414. doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39122153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirugo G, Williams SM, Tishkoff SA. The missing diversity in human genetic studies. Cell. 2019;177:26-31. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2019.02.048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2019.02.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7380073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djordjevic SP, Jarocki VM, Seemann T, et al. Genomic surveillance for antimicrobial resistance &#x2014; a One Health perspective. Nat Rev Genet. 2024;25:142-157. doi: 10.1038/s41576-023-00649-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41576-023-00649-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikonomou ED, Karvelis P, Giannakeas N, Vrachatis A, Glavas E, Tzallas AT. How natural language processing derived techniques are used on biological data: a systematic review. Netw Model Anal Health Inform Bioinform. 2024;13:23. doi: 10.1007/s13721-024-00458-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13721-024-00458-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng S, Wei Y, Zhou Y, et al. Deciphering genomic codes using advanced natural language processing techniques: a scoping review. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2025;32:761-772. doi: 10.1093/jamia/ocaf029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaf029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12005631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39998912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO. Implementation Status of Integrated AMR Surveillance within a One Health Approach in the WHO African Region. Accessed January 8, 2026. https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/32863215-b739-4a20-bbb4-1b3e07c81ebb/content</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C, Miliya T, Chansamouth V, et al. Automating the generation of antimicrobial resistance surveillance reports: proof-of-concept study involving seven hospitals in seven countries. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22:e19762. doi: 10.2196/19762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7568216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33006570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argim&#xf3;n S, Abudahab K, Goater RJE, et al. Microreact: visualizing and sharing data for genomic epidemiology and phylogeography. Microb Genom. 2016;2:e000093. doi: 10.1099/mgen.0.000093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/mgen.0.000093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5320705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudin C. Stop explaining black box machine learning models for high stakes decisions and use interpretable models instead. Nat Mach Intell. 2019;1:206-215. doi: 10.1038/s42256-019-0048-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-019-0048-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tacconelli E, Sifakis F, Harbarth S, et al. Surveillance for control of antimicrobial resistance. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018;18:e99-e106. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(17)30485-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(17)30485-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29102325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Ge X, Liu L, Hu G. Code interpreter for bioinformatics: are we there yet. Ann Biomed Eng. 2024;52:754-756. doi: 10.1007/s10439-023-03324-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10439-023-03324-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37482573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shue E, Liu L, Li B, Feng Z, Li X, Hu G. Empowering beginners in bioinformatics with ChatGPT. Quant Biol. 2023;11:105-108. doi: 10.15302/J-QB-023-0327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15302/J-QB-023-0327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10299548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merow C, Serra-Diaz JM, Enquist BJ, Wilson AM. AI chatbots can boost scientific coding. Nat Ecol Evol. 2023;7:960-962. doi: 10.1038/s41559-023-02063-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41559-023-02063-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37100951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H, Li X, Zhuang Y, et al. Neural network-based predictions of antimicrobial resistance phenotypes in multidrug-resistant Acinetobacter baumannii from whole genome sequencing and gene expression. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2024;68:e0144624. doi: 10.1128/aac.01446-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.01446-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11619347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39540735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Li H, Zhao C, Li S, Yin G, Wang H. Machine learning and feature extraction for rapid antimicrobial resistance prediction of Acinetobacter baumannii from whole-genome sequencing data. Front Microbiol. 2024;14:1320312. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2023.1320312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1320312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38274740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali T, Ahmed S, Aslam M. Artificial intelligence for antimicrobial resistance prediction: challenges and opportunities towards practical implementation. Antibiotics. 2023;12:523. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics12030523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics12030523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10044311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36978390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandve GK, Nekrutenko A, Taylor J, Hovig E. Ten simple rules for reproducible computational research. PLoS Comput Biol. 2013;9:e1003285. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3812051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24204232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolaia V, Kaas RS, Ruppe E, et al. ResFinder 4.0 for predictions of phenotypes from genotypes. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2020;75:3491-3500. doi: 10.1093/jac/dkaa345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkaa345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32780112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcock BP, Raphenya AR, Lau TTY, et al. CARD 2020: antibiotic resistome surveillance with the comprehensive antibiotic resistance database. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;48:D517-D525. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkz935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7145624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardy JL, Loman NJ. Towards a genomics-informed, real-time, global pathogen surveillance system. Nat Rev Genet. 2018;19:9-20. doi: 10.1038/nrg.2017.88</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrg.2017.88</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriksen RS, Bortolaia V, Tate H, Tyson GH, Aarestrup FM, McDermott PF. Using genomics to track global antimicrobial resistance. Front Public Health. 2019;7:242. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2019.00242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2019.00242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6737581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seale AC, Gordon NC, Islam J, Peacock SJ, Scott JAG. AMR Surveillance in low and middle&#x2014;income settings&#x2014;a roadmap for participation in the Global Antimicrobial Surveillance System (GLASS). Wellcome Open Res. 2017;2:92. doi: 10.12688/wellcomeopenres.12527.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.12527.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5645727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29062918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson TM, Ahmad R, Toumazou C, Georgiou P, Holmes AH. Artificial intelligence can improve decision-making in infection management. Nat Hum Behav. 2019;3:543-545. doi: 10.1038/s41562-019-0583-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-019-0583-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31190023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen M, Brettin T, Long SW, et al. Developing an in silico minimum inhibitory concentration panel test for Klebsiella pneumoniae. Sci Rep. 2018;8:421. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-18972-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-18972-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29323230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanam&#xe9; Pinedo LE, Franz E, Dallman TJ, et al. Genomic epidemiology of Salmonella Enteritidis human infections in the Netherlands, 2019 to 2023. Microb Genom. 2025;11:001394. doi: 10.1099/mgen.0.001394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/mgen.0.001394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12044193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40266678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabaan AA, Alhumaid S, Al Mutair A, et al. Application of artificial intelligence in combating high antimicrobial resistance rates. Antibiotics. 2022;11:784. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics11060784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics11060784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9220767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harandi H, Shafaati M, Salehi M, et al. Artificial intelligence-driven approaches in antibiotic stewardship programs and optimizing prescription practices: a systematic review. Artif Intell Med. 2025;162:103089. doi: 10.1016/j.artmed.2025.103089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.artmed.2025.103089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39955846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiens J, Saria S, Sendak M, et al. Do no harm: a roadmap for responsible machine learning for health care. Nat Med. 2019;25:1337-1340. doi: 10.1038/s41591-019-0548-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-019-0548-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31427808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wertheim HFL, Huong VTL, Kuijper EJ. Clinical microbiology laboratories in low-resource settings, it is not only about equipment and reagents, but also good governance for sustainability. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021;27:1389-1390. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2021.07.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2021.07.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34332110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argim&#xf3;n S, Yeats CA, Goater RJ, et al. A global resource for genomic predictions of antimicrobial resistance and surveillance of Salmonella Typhi at pathogenwatch. Nat Commun. 2021;12:2879. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-23091-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-23091-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34001879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascucci M, Royer G, Adamek J, et al. AI-based mobile application to fight antibiotic resistance. Nat Commun. 2021;12:1173. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-21187-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21187-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7895972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CLSI. M100-S24 Performance Standards for Antimicrobial. CLSI; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellner MJ, Koob JG, Gootenberg JS, Abudayyeh OO, Zhang F. SHERLOCK: nucleic acid detection with CRISPR nucleases. Nat Protoc. 2019;14:2986-3012. doi: 10.1038/s41596-019-0210-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41596-019-0210-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6956564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan WS, Au CH, Chung Y, et al. Rapid and economical drug resistance profiling with Nanopore MinION for clinical specimens with low bacillary burden of Mycobacterium tuberculosis. BMC Res Notes. 2020;13:444. doi: 10.1186/s13104-020-05287-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-020-05287-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Antimicrobial Resistance Surveillance System (GLASS) Report: Early Implementation. World Health Organization; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ombelet S, Ronat JB, Walsh T, et al. Clinical bacteriology in low-resource settings: today&#x2019;s solutions. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018;18:e248-e258. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30093-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30093-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29519767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatumo S, Yakubu A, Oyedele O, et al. Promoting the genomic revolution in Africa through the Nigerian 100K Genome Project. Nat Genet. 2022;54:531-536. doi: 10.1038/s41588-022-01071-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-022-01071-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omotoso OE, Teibo JO, Atiba FA, Oladimeji T, Adebesin AO, Babalghith AO. Bridging the genomic data gap in Africa: implications for global disease burdens. Global Health. 2022;18:103. doi: 10.1186/s12992-022-00898-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-022-00898-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9733397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36494695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mboowa G, Kakooza F, Egesa M, et al. The rise of pathogen genomics in Africa. F1000Res. 2024;13:468. doi: 10.12688/f1000research.147114.2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.147114.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11512136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39464779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguinkal JA, Zoclanclounon YAB, Molina A, et al. Assessment of the pathogen genomics landscape highlights disparities and challenges for effective AMR surveillance and outbreak response in the East African community. BMC Public Health. 2024;24:1500. doi: 10.1186/s12889-024-18990-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-18990-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11151545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38840103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laamarti M, El Fathi Lalaoui Y, Elfermi R, Daoud R, El Allali A. Afro-TB dataset as a large scale genomic data of Mycobacterium tuberuclosis in Africa. Sci Data. 2023;10:212. doi: 10.1038/s41597-023-02112-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-023-02112-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10102689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37059737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
African Union. Continental artificial intelligence strategy harnessing AI for Africa&#x2019;s development and prosperity. Published July 2024. Accessed November 19, 2025. https://au.int/sites/default/files/documents/44004-doc-EN-_Continental_AI_Strategy_July_2024.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT). The state of AI in Africa report. Published 2025. Accessed November 19, 2025. https://aiconference.cipit.org/documents/the-state-of-ai-in-africa-report.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>African Union. AUDA-NEPAD Champions AI Integration in Healthcare Regulation at 4th African Medicines Regulatory Harmonisation Week. African Union; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olufadewa II, Iyiola OP, Nnatus J, et al. National eHealth strategy frameworks in Africa: a comprehensive assessment using the WHO-ITU eHealth strategy toolkit and FAIR guidelines. Oxf Open Digit Health. 2024;2:oqae047. doi: 10.1093/oodh/oqae047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oodh/oqae047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11932408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40230969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ministry of Communications and Digitalisation with Smart Africa. Republic of Ghana national artificial intelligence strategy: 2023-2033. Published October 2022. Accessed November 19, 2025. https://www.africadataprotection.org/Ghana-AI-Strat.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
ICTworks. Introducing the National Artificial Intelligence Policy for Rwanda. Published December 20, 2023. Accessed November 19, 2025. https://www.ictworks.org/national-artificial-intelligence-policy-rwanda/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwogosi A. Revolutionizing primary health care in Tanzania: unravelling the contextual factors on electronic health record systems implementation for effective decision support [published online ahead of print August 5, 2024]. J Sci Technol Policy Manag. doi: 10.1108/JSTPM-11-2023-0205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JSTPM-11-2023-0205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ddamba A, Nsubuga B, Kamabare M, et al. Factors influencing the availability and use of electronic medical records systems in public health facilities in Uganda: a cross-sectional assessment. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2025;25:372. doi: 10.1186/s12911-025-03190-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-025-03190-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12512544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41074049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akanbi MO, Ocheke AN, Agaba PA, et al. Use of electronic health records in Sub-Saharan Africa: progress and challenges. J Med Trop. 2012;14:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4167769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25243111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Antimicrobial Resistance and Use Surveillance System (GLASS) Report 2021. World Health Organization; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph M. Challenges of educational digital infrastructure in Africa: a tale of hope and disillusionment. J Afr Stud Dev. 2019;11:59-63. doi: 10.5897/jasd2019.0539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/jasd2019.0539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaux POA, Lorenzon AF, Serpa M, da S. Challenges in high-performance computing. J Braz Comput Soc. 2023;29:51-62. doi: 10.5753/jbcs.2023.2219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5753/jbcs.2023.2219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethics and Governance of Artificial Intelligence for Health: WHO Guidance. World Health Organization; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Dhai A.
Using artificial intelligence in healthcare&#x2014;some ethical and legal considerations. S Afr J Bioeth Law. 2024;17:2. Accessed September 13, 2025. https://hdl.handle.net/10520/ejc-m_sajbl_v17_n3_a2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solaiman B. Legal and ethical considerations of artificial intelligence for residents in post-acute and long-term care. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2024;25:105105. doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2024.105105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2024.105105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38909630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratti E, Morrison M, Jakab I. Ethical and social considerations of applying artificial intelligence in healthcare&#x2014;a two-pronged scoping review. BMC Med Ethics. 2025;26:68. doi: 10.1186/s12910-025-01198-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12910-025-01198-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12107984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40420080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatumo S, Inouye M. African genomes hold the key to accurate genetic risk prediction. Nat Hum Behav. 2023;7:295-296. doi: 10.1038/s41562-023-01549-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-023-01549-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36823371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taddese AA, Addis AC, Tam BT. Data stewardship and curation practices in AI-based genomics and automated microscopy image analysis for high-throughput screening studies: promoting robust and ethical AI applications. Hum Genomics. 2025;19:16. doi: 10.1186/s40246-025-00716-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40246-025-00716-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11849233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39988670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chikowore T, L&#xe4;ll K, Micklesfield LK, et al. Variability of polygenic prediction for body mass index in Africa. Genome Med. 2024;16:74. doi: 10.1186/s13073-024-01348-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13073-024-01348-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinwalere SN, Ivanov V. Artificial intelligence in higher education: challenges and opportunities. Border Cross. 2022;12:1-15. doi: 10.33182/bc.v12i1.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33182/bc.v12i1.2015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>