<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41788318</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of low-load blood flow restriction resistance training on Sirtuin-1 and endothelial-related biochemical markers in men with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>98</StartPage><MedlinePgn>98</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">98</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-026-01910-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The present study aimed to investigate the effects of a period of resistance training with blood flow restriction on serum levels of Sirtuin-1 (SIRT1), Nitric Oxide (NO), Endothelin-1 (ET-1), and blood pressure in individuals with type 2 diabetes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this randomized controlled clinical trial, 45 male patients with type 2 diabetes were purposefully selected and randomly assigned into three equal groups: high-resistance training (HRT), resistance training with blood flow restriction (RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;BFR), and control (CO). The HRT group performed resistance exercises at 70-80% of one-repetition maximum (1 RM), while the RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;BFR group trained at 20-30% of 1 RM using restrictive cuffs for 16 weeks. Before and after the training period, blood samples were taken to assess serum levels of SIRT1, NO, and ET-1. Data were analyzed using ANCOVA with post hoc Tukey tests, and significance was set at <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After the training intervention, serum levels of SIRT1 and NO significantly increased in both the HRT group (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001 and <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, respectively) and the RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;BFR group (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001 and <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, respectively) compared to the control group. Besides, ET-1 levels significantly decreased in the HRT group (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) and the RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;BFR group (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) compared to the control group. Systolic blood pressure significantly decreased only in the HRT group compared to the control (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03). Nevertheless, there were no significant differences between the two training groups in the mean values of SIRT1, NO, or systolic blood pressure (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Low-intensity resistance training with BFR, similar to high-intensity resistance training, can increase SIRT1 and NO levels, reduce ET-1 and blood pressure, and thereby exert a positive effect on biochemical markers associated with endothelial function in diabetic patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Registered retrospectively in the Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (Registration Number: IRCT20241004063256N1) on November 24, 2024. Access at https://irct.behdasht.gov.ir/trial/79384.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2026. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fatehi</LastName><ForeName>Mahdiyeh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Faculty of Educational Sciences and Psychology, University of Sistan and Baluchestan, Zahedan, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02n43xw86</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412796.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0612 766X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nayebifar</LastName><ForeName>Shila</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Faculty of Educational Sciences and Psychology, University of Sistan and Baluchestan, Zahedan, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02n43xw86</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412796.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0612 766X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghasemi</LastName><ForeName>Elham</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Zabol, Zabol, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03d9mz263</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412671.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0382 462X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimkoshteh</LastName><ForeName>Azra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Assistant professor, Adult endocrinology and metabolism specialist, Department of internal medicine of ali Ebn Abitaleb hospital, Zahedan university of medical sciences, Zahedan, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03r42d171</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.488433.0</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0612 8339</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sirtuin-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular dilation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41788318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12957679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-026-01910-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tinajero MG, Malik VS. An update on the epidemiology of type 2 diabetes: A global perspective. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2021;50(3):337&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecl.2021.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34399949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan BB, Magliano DJ, Boyko EJ. IDF Diabetes Atlas 11th edition 2025: global prevalence and projections for 2050. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2025;41(1):7&#x2013;9. 10.1093/ndt/gfaf177. PMID: 40874767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40874767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, McAlister FA, Walker RL, Hemmelgarn BR, Campbell NR. Cardiovascular outcomes in Framingham participants with diabetes: the importance of blood pressure. Hypertension. 2011;57(5):891&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.110.162446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21403089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansbury BE, Hill BG. Regulation of obesity and insulin resistance by nitric oxide. Free Radic Biol Med. 2014;73:383&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2014.05.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4112002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Guan S, Gao Z, et al. Pathological hyperinsulinemia and hyperglycemia in the impaired glucose tolerance stage mediate endothelial dysfunction through miR-21, PTEN/AKT/eNOS, and MARK/ET-1 pathways. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2021;12:644159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.644159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8104127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33967958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S, Cai X, Yin H, Sun Z, Z&#xfc;gel M, Steinacker JM, et al. Exercise training and endothelial function in patients with type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2018;17:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-018-0711-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold DA, Sinclair DA. Sirtuin evolution at the dawn of animal life. Mol Biol Evol. 2022;39(9):msac192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msac192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9486876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36065792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K, Velagapudi S, Akhmedov A, Kraler S, Lapikova-Bryhinska T, Schmiady MO, Wu X, Geng L, Camici GG, Xu A, L&#xfc;scher TF. Chronic SIRT1 supplementation in diabetic mice improves endothelial function by suppressing oxidative stress. Cardiovasc Res. 2023;119(12):2190&#x2013;201. 10.1093/cvr/cvad102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvad102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10578911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37401647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karbasforooshan H, Karimi G. The role of SIRT1 in diabetic cardiomyopathy. Biomed Pharmacother. 2017;90:386&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2017.03.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28380414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirkhizi F, Taghizadeh M, Khalese-Ranjbar B, Hamedi-Shahraki S, Asghari S. The clinical value of serum sirtuin-1 concentration in the diagnosis of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease. BMC Gastroenterol. 2025;25(1):27. 10.1186/s12876-025-03613-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12876-025-03613-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11753077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39844087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansur AP, Roggerio A, Goes MFS, Avakian SD, Leal DP, Maranh&#xe3;o RC, Strunz CMC. Serum concentrations and gene expression of Sirtuin 1 in healthy and slightly overweight subjects after caloric restriction or Resveratrol supplementation: A randomized trial. Int J Cardiol. 2017;227:788&#x2013;94. 10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.10.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2016.10.058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AMA, Abd Elfatah Abo Saif HF, El-Moatasem Mohamed AM. Effect of Jyoti-Trataka on intraocular pressure, autonomic control, and blood glucose in diabetic patients with high-tension primary open-angle glaucoma: a randomized-controlled trial. J Complement Integr Med. 2021;19(4):1013&#x2013;1018. 10.1515/jcim-2021-0041. PMID: 34303323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34303323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan B, Ge L, Xun Y-q, Chen Y-j, Gao C-y, Han X, et al. Exercise training modalities in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2018;15:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-018-0703-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6060544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Tam WWS, Hounsri K, Kusuyama J, Wu VX. Effectiveness of combined aerobic and resistance exercise on Cognition, metabolic Health, physical Function, and Health-related quality of life in Middle-aged and older adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2024;105(8):1585&#x2013;99. 10.1016/j.apmr.2023.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2023.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson AK, Chan LX, Lubans DR, Duncan MJ, Plotnikoff RC. Effect of resistance training on HbA1c in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus and the moderating effect of changes in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care. 2022;10(2):e002595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjdrc-2021-002595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35273011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhati P, Hussain ME, Deepak K, Masood S, Anand P. Progressive resistance training ameliorates deteriorating cardiac autonomic dysfunction, subclinical inflammation and endothelial dysfunction in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized control trial. Diab Metabolic Syndrome Clin Res Rev. 2023;17(5):102778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37178513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani S, Porrahim Ghouroghchi A, Yaghobi M, Afroundeh R, Rasouli M. The Effect of Eight Weeks of Resistance Training on the Plasma Levels of Preptin and Endothelin 1 in Men with Type 2 Diabetes. ijdld 2023; 23 (2) :80-90&#xa0;http://ijdld.tums.ac.ir/article-1-6206-en.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanian H, Matinhomaee H, Peeri M. The effect of circuit resistance training on plasma concentration of Endothelin-1, nitric oxide and vascular diameter in elderly men. J Clin Res Paramed Sci. 2019;8(1):e80932. 10.5812/jcrps.80932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/jcrps.80932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb DA, Moore JH, Mesquita PHC, Smith MA, Vann CG, Osburn SC, et al. Resistance training increases muscle NAD&#x2009;+&#x2009;and NADH concentrations as well as NAMPT protein levels and global Sirtuin activity in middle-aged, overweight, untrained individuals. Aging. 2020;12(10):9447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.103218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma JK, Scribbans TD, Edgett BA, Boyd JC, Simpson CA, Little JP et al. Extremely low-volume, high-intensity interval training improves exercise capacity and increases mitochondrial protein content in human skeletal muscle. Open J of Mol Integrat Physiol 2013;2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saatmann N, Zaharia OP, Loenneke JP, Roden M, Pesta DH. Effects of blood flow restriction exercise and possible applications in type 2 diabetes. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2021;32(2):106&#x2013;17. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2020.11.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33358931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deus LAd, Correa HL, Neves RVP, Reis AL, Honorato FS, Ara&#xfa;jo TB, et al. Metabolic and hormonal responses to chronic blood-flow restricted resistance training in chronic kidney disease: a randomized trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2022;47(2):183&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi Moghadam A, Askari R, Hamedinia MR, Haghighi AH. A comparison of the effects of three strength training programs with and without blood flow restriction on strength, hypertrophy and mobility function in elderly women. J Paramedical Sci Rehabilitation. 2020;8(4):26&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, LaRoche DP, Villa MR, Barile H, Manini TM. Blood flow restricted resistance training in older adults at risk of mobility limitations. Exp Gerontol. 2017;99:138&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2017.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5660944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khabbaz Kababi MH, Rezaeian N, Negahban Sioki H, Yaghoubi A. Effect of resistance training with blood flow restriction on Sitruin-1, Visfatin, and nitric oxide levels in elite male athletes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Sci J Rehabilitation Med. 2023;12(4):648&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi SS, Heidarianpour A, Shokri E. Effect of resistance training and high-intensity interval training on metabolic parameters and serum level of Sirtuin1 in postmenopausal women with metabolic syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Lipids Health Dis. 2023;22(1):177. 10.1186/s12944-023-01940-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-023-01940-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37858156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength Testing&#x2014;Predicting a One-Rep max from Reps-to-Fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance. 1993;64:88&#x2013;90. 10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of Methodology, Application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10:533. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, Bauman AE, Booth ML, Ainsworth BE, Pratt M, Ekelund U, Yngve A, Sallis JF, Oja P. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(8):1381&#x2013;95. 10.1249/01.MSS.0000078924.61453.FB.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000078924.61453.FB</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML, Ward A. Generalized equations for predicting body density of women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1980;12:175&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198023000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7402053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarlak Z, Eidi A, Ghorbanzadeh V, Moghaddasi M, Mortazavi P. miR-34a/SIRT1/HIF-1&#x3b1; axis is involved in cardiac angiogenesis of type 2 diabetic rats: the protective effect of sodium butyrate combined with treadmill exercise. Biofactors. 2023;49(5):1085&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/biof.1979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37560982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Lin X, Zhou L, Li W, Yi Q, Lei F, et al. The effect of blood flow-restrictive resistance training on the risk of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in middle-aged patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Front Endocrinol. 2024;15:1482985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2024.1482985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11473333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39411313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales MM, de Sousa CV, de Paula Santana HA, et al. Nitric oxide and blood pressure responses to short-term resistance training in adults with and without type-2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Sport Sci Health. 2018;14:597&#x2013;606. . 10.1007/s11332-018-0468-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-018-0468-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AMA, Tolba AMN. Effectiveness of lifestyle-modification approach (a randomized-controlled program of diet restriction and treadmill walking exercise) on elderly&#x2019;s metabolic syndrome-associated subjective tinnitus. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2025;282(8):4307&#x2013;15. 10.1007/s00405-025-09494-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00405-025-09494-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12399441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40500514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Feng J, Zhang J, Kang X, Qian D. Quercetin modulates AMPK/SIRT1/NF-&#x3ba;B signaling to inhibit inflammatory/oxidative stress responses in diabetic high fat diet-induced atherosclerosis in the rat carotid artery. Exp Ther Med. 2020;20(6):280. 10.3892/etm.2020.9410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2020.9410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7664594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AMA, Morsy MM. Effect of Baduanjin exercise on lipid profile, blood pressure, and thyroid-stimulating hormone in elderly with subclinical hypothyroidism and mild cognitive impairment: a randomized-controlled trial in women. Geriatr Nurs. 2025;64:103434. 10.1016/j.gerinurse.2025.103434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40582060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AMA, El-Azeim ASA, Saif HFAEA. Effect of aerobic exercise alone or combined with mediterranean diet on dry eye in obese hypertensive elderly. Ir J Med Sci. 2023;192(6):3151&#x2013;61. 10.1007/s11845-023-03387-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11845-023-03387-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10692261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37160570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>