<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41576690</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0039-3681</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>116</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Studies in history and philosophy of science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stud Hist Philos Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rethinking psychological measurement: Validity potential versus realised validity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.shpsa.2026.102123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0039-3681(26)00009-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We propose a concept of validity with a novel feature that we argue can facilitate improved measurement validation practices in the psychological sciences. Following Borsboom and colleagues, our concept of validity is measurement-specific and causal. This contrasts with current guidelines linking validity to the acceptability of both measurement and non-measurement-based interpretations of test scores. Benefits of a measurement-specific concept of validity are that it can make the requirements for valid measurement clearer and make validity claims easier to interpret, which we illustrate by comparing the use of test scores for measurement versus prediction. Our concept of validity also maintains that a causal relationship of sufficient strength from the attribute being measured to the measurement outcomes is necessary and sufficient for valid measurement. This places causal explanations at the centre of the validation process. While causal complexity will make the evaluation of psychological measurements as causal inferences extremely challenging, we describe how the interventionist theory of causation and related work on causal inference can serve as a starting point for addressing this challenge. The novel feature of our concept of validity is that it makes a distinction between the validity potential of measurement procedures in abstracto (e.g., tests) and the realised validity of concrete measurement outcomes (e.g., specific test scores). We describe key benefits of this novel distinction, including its potential to encourage the theoretical refinement of concepts, guide the selection of appropriate measurement procedures for use in research, and increase sample-specific validity evidence reporting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higgins</LastName><ForeName>Wendy C</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Melbourne, Melbourne School of Psychological Sciences, VIC, 3010, Australia; Macquarie University, School of Psychological Sciences, NSW, 2109, Australia. Electronic address: wendy.higgins@unimelb.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaplan</LastName><ForeName>David M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Macquarie University, School of Psychological Sciences, NSW, 2109, Australia; Macquarie University, Performance and Expertise Research Centre, NSW, 2109, Australia; Macquarie University, Minds and Intelligences Research Centre, NSW 2109, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillett</LastName><ForeName>Alexander J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Macquarie University, School of Humanities, NSW, 2109, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sutton</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Stirling, Centre for the Sciences of Place and Memory, Stirling, FK9 4LA, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Robert M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Macquarie University, School of Humanities, NSW, 2109, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stud Hist Philos Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1250602</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0039-3681</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations of interest WCH was supported by an Australian Government Research Training Program (RTP) Scholarship, a Macquarie University Research Excellence Scholarship, and an Australian Research Council (ARC) Future Fellowship Grant (grant ID: FT210100652). AJG and JS were supported by the John Templeton Foundation (grant ID: 61924). RMR was supported by the John Templeton Foundation (grant ID: 62631).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41576690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.shpsa.2026.102123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0039-3681(26)00009-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>