<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41709252</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations between ergometer performance, postural stability, cognitive function, and physical performance in adolescent rowers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">155</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01611-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Rowing is an Olympic sport that simultaneously encompasses multiple components of physical performance, including anaerobic endurance, strength endurance, and maximal strength.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM">The aim of this study is to examine the relationship between rowing-specific performance, as assessed by ergometer testing, and physical performance, cognitive function, and reaction time in elite adolescent rowers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 28 adolescent rowing athletes were included in this study. The assessments were conducted at Hereke Nuh &#xc7;imento Rowing Club and Be&#x15f;ikta&#x15f; Rowing Club. Static balance was evaluated using the GYKO inertial sensor system, while dynamic balance was assessed with the Y Balance Test. Reaction time was measured using the BlazePod light-based sensor system, and muscle strength was assessed with the Meloq EasyForce dynamometer. Cognitive function was evaluated using the Stroop test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A negative relationship was observed between ergometer performance time and muscle strength (<i>r</i> = &#x2212;&#x2009;0.875 to &#x2212;&#x2009;0.591, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) reaction time repetition count (<i>r</i> = -0.657 to -0.574, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). A positive relationship was observed between ergometer performance time and static postural stability sway area (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.474, 0.447, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">These findings indicate that ergometer performance in adolescent rowers is associated with muscle strength, reaction time, and static postural stability, whereas dynamic balance and cognitive performance show no significant relationship with ergometer outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dingirdan Gultekinler</LastName><ForeName>Birgul</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Department, Faculty of Health Sciences, Sakarya University of Applied Sciences, Sakarya, Turkey. birguldingirdan@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey. birguldingirdan@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayrakc&#x131; Tunay</LastName><ForeName>Volga</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical functional performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postural balance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Ethics Committee of Sakarya University of Applied Sciences (approval number: 61/03, approval date: 18/09/2025). The study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Before the data collection process, the researchers informed the participants about the purpose of the study, emphasized that participation was voluntary, assured them that their anonymity would be protected, and stated that their data would be used solely for this research. Informed consent was obtained from the parents of all participants. Additionally, the participants were informed that they could withdraw from the study at any time without providing any reason. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41709252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13019858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01611-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01611-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thiele D, Prieske O, Lesinski M, Granacher U. Eeffects of equal volume heavy-resistance strength training versus strength endurance training on physical fitness and sport-specific performance in young elite female rowers. Front Physiol. 2020;11:888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e T, Perez-Turpin JA, Cortell-Tormo JM, Chinchilla-Mira IJ, Cejuela-Anta R, M&#xe4;estu J, et al. Relationship between rowing ergometer performance and physiological responses to upper and lower body exercises in rowers. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(4):434&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2009.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19836997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton TW, Cronin JB, McGuigan MR. Strength, power, and muscular endurance exercise and elite rowing ergometer performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(7):1928&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182772f27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23085974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesinski M, Prieske O, Granacher U. Effects and dose-response relationships of resistance training on physical performance in youth athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):781&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledergerber R, Jacobs MW, Roth R, Schumann M. Contribution of different strength determinants on distinct phases of olympic rowing performance in adolescent athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23(12):2311&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2023.2230937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;estu J, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e J, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e T. Monitoring of performance and training in rowing. Sports med. 2005;35(7):597&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535070-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16026173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerasola D, Bellafiore M, Cataldo A, Zangla D, Bianco A, Proia P, et al. Predicting the 2000-m rowing ergometer performance from anthropometric, maximal oxygen uptake and 60-s mean power variables in national level young rowers. J Hum Kinet. 2020;75:77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ak&#xe7;a F. Prediction of rowing ergometer performance from functional anaerobic power, strength and anthropometric components. J Hum Kinet. 2014;41:133&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4120446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C-J, Nesser TW, Edwards JE. Strength and power determinants of rowing performance. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2007;10(4):43&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Stone M, Sands WA. Principles and practice of resistance training. Human Kinetics. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0486-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs MW, Schumann M. Individual load-velocity measures are associated with 2,000-m rowing ergometer performance in German national rowers. Front Sports Act Living. 2025;7:1688650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2025.1688650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12538512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41126928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Editorial. Advancing biomechanics: enhancing sports performance, mitigating injury risks, and optimizing athlete rehabilitation. Front Sports Act Living. 2025;7:1556024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2025.1556024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11832503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39968189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinkovi&#x107; D, Pavlovi&#x107; S, Madi&#x107; D, Obradovic B, N&#xe9;meth Z, Belic A. Postural stability&#x2013;a comparison between rowers and field sport athletes. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horak FB. Postural orientation and equilibrium: what do we need to know about neural control of balance to prevent falls? Age Ageing. 2006;35(Suppl 2):ii7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afl077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes PA, Chen A, Blouin JS. Sensorimotor control of standing balance. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;159:61&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-63916-5.00004-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrysomallis C. Balance ability and athletic performance. Sports Med. 2011;41(3):221&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11538560-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stambolieva K, Diafas V, Bachev V, Christova L, Gatev P. Postural stability of canoeing and kayaking young male athletes during quiet stance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(5):1807&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2151-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21909987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemkov&#xe1; E. Assessment of balance in sport: science and reality. Serb J Sports Sci. 2011;(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan NE, Henry DA, Hillman CH, Kramer AF. Trained athletes and cognitive function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2023;21(4):725&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1612197X.2022.2084764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteban-Cornejo I, Cabanas-S&#xe1;nchez V, Higueras-Fresnillo S, Ortega FB, Kramer AF, Rodriguez-Artalejo F, et al. editors. Cognitive frailty and mortality in a national cohort of older adults: the role of physical activity. Mayo Clin Proc. Elsevier; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss MW, Soto C, Yoo S, Sodoma M, Vivar C, van Praag H. Exercise and hippocampal memory systems. Trends Cogn Sci. 2019;23(4):318&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2019.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6422697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss MW, Kramer AF, Basak C, Prakash RS, Roberts B. Are expert athletes &#x2018;expert&#x2019;in the cognitive laboratory? A meta-analytic review of cognition and sport expertise. Appl Cogn Psychol. 2010;24(6):812&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acp.1588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomporowski PD, McCullick B, Pendleton DM, Pesce C. Exercise and children&#x2019;s cognition: the role of exercise characteristics and a place for metacognition. J Sport Health Sci. 2015;4(1):47&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2014.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirifar A, Keil A, Beckmann J, Ehrlenspiel F. No effects of neurofeedback of beta band components on reaction time performance. J Cogn Enhanc. 2019;3(3):251&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41465-018-0093-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Brito MA, Fernandes JR, Esteves NS, M&#xfc;ller VT, Alexandria DB, P&#xe9;rez DIV, et al. The effect of neurofeedback on the reaction time and cognitive performance of athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16:868450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2022.868450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35795260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo D, Hristovski R, Seifert L, Carvalho J, Davids K. Ecological cognition: expert decision-making behaviour in sport. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750984X.2017.1349826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsaee S, Alboghbish S, Abdolahi H, Alirajabi R, Anbari A. Effect of a period of selected SMR/Theta neurofeedback training on visual and auditory reaction time in veterans and disabled athletes. Iran J War Public Health. 2018;10(1):15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29252/ijwph.10.1.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John Karl PTD, Birendra Dewan P, Michael Masaracchio P, Kaitlin Kirker PTD. Reliability and validity of the EasyForce<sup>&#xae;</sup> dynamometer compared to handheld dynamometry for isometric strength testing of the upper and lower extremities: a pilot study. Orthop Phys Ther Pract. 2024;36(4):28&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devices M. EasyForce - Force Measurement Videos. 2025. Available from: https://meloqdevices.com/pages/easyforce-videos.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de-Oliveira LA, Matos MV, Fernandes IGS, Nascimento DA, da Silva-Grigoletto ME. Test-retest reliability of a visual-cognitive technology (BlazePod&#x2122;) to measure response time. J Sports Sci Med. 2021;20(1):179&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2021.179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33708001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huerta Ojeda &#xc1;, Lizama Tapia P, Pulgar &#xc1;lvarez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Cruz C, Yeomans-Cabrera MM, Contreras Vera J. Relationship between attention capacity and hand-eye reaction time in adolescents between 15 and 18 years of age. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(17).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9518379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36078604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaworski J, Ambro&#x17b;y T, Lech G, Spieszny M, Bujas P, &#x17b;ak M, et al. Absolute and relative reliability of several measures of static postural stability calculated using a GYKO inertial sensor system. Acta Bioeng Biomech. 2020;22(2):94&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37190/ABB-01502-2019-02</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souaifi M, Dhahbi W, Jebabli N, Ceylan H&#x130;, Boujabli M, Muntean RI, et al. Artificial intelligence in sports biomechanics: a scoping review on wearable technology, motion analysis, and injury prevention. Bioeng (Basel). 2025;12(8):887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12383302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40868401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldager FN, Aslerin S, S BK, T&#xf8;nning LU, Mechlenburg I. Interrater, test-retest reliability of the y balance test: a reliability study including 51 healthy participants. Int J Exerc Sci. 2023;16(4):182&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10124723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang MH, Kim GM, Kwon OY, Weon JH, Oh JS, An DH. Relationship between the kinematics of the trunk and lower extremity and performance on the Y-balance test. PM R. 2015;7(11):1152&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2015.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25978949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonell AC, Romero JA, Soler LM. Relationship between the y balance test scores, and soft tissue injury incidence in a soccer team. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10(7):955&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaka&#x15f; S, Erdo&#x11f;an E, Sak L, Soysal A&#x15e;, Ulusoy T, Ulusoy &#x130;Y, et al. Stroop Testi TBAG Formu: T&#xfc;rk k&#xfc;lt&#xfc;r&#xfc;ne standardizasyon &#xe7;al&#x131;&#x15f;malar&#x131;, g&#xfc;venirlik ve ge&#xe7;erlik. Klin Psikiyatr. 1999;2(2):75&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugent FJ, Flanagan EP, Wilson F, Warrington GD. Strength and conditioning for competitive rowers. Strength Cond J. 2020;42(3):6&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann U, Mader A, Wasser K, Klauer I. Peak force, velocity, and power during five and ten maximal rowing ergometer strokes by world class female and male rowers. Int J Sports Med. 1993;14(Suppl 1):S42&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1021224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8262708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinacker JM. Physiological aspects of training in rowing. Int J Sports Med. 1993;14(Suppl 1):S3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8262704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckeridge EM, Bull AM, McGregor AH. Biomechanical determinants of elite rowing technique and performance. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(2):e176&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25039605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Materne O, Chamari K. Rethinking knee injury prevention strategies: joint-by-joint training approach paradigm versus traditional focused knee strengthening. Biol Sport. 2025;42(4):59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.148544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12490306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruzbarska B, Cech P, Bakalar P, Vaskova M, Sucka J. Cognition and sport: how does sport participation affect cognitive function? Monten J Sports Sci Med. 2025;14(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Q, Zou L, Loprinzi PD, Quan M, Huang T. Effects of open versus closed skill exercise on cognitive function: a systematic review. Front Psychol. 2019;10:1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6718477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31507472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podstawski R, Borys&#x142;awski K, Alf&#xf6;ldi Z, Ferenc I, W&#x105;sik J. The effect of confounding variables on the relationship between anthropometric and physiological features in 2000-m rowing ergometer performance. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1195641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1195641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37334050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>