<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41758176</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2335-6936</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing. Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pac Symp Biocomput</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of using PRS-CSx and pruning and thresholding for polygenic partitioning of apparent treatment resistant hypertension.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>664</StartPage><EndPage>678</EndPage><MedlinePgn>664-678</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1142/9789819824755_0048</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Apparent treatment-resistant hypertension (aTRH) is a clinically challenging condition with heterogeneous etiologies. Understanding the biological pathways underlying resistance to antihypertensive treatment could inform targeted therapeutic strategies. To evaluate how methodological choices in SNP selection influence biological inference, we applied two approaches to select aTRH-associated variants for clustering: PRS-CSx and pruning and thresholding (P&amp;T). Using k-means clustering, we grouped aTRH-associated variants based on their association profiles across 91 cardiometabolic-related phenotypes. We then performed pathway and tissue enrichment analyses to evaluate the biological processes represented by each cluster. Both methods identified multiple genetic clusters, but the distribution of variants and biological signals differed. Clustering based on PRS-CSx produced unequally distributed clusters of SNPs and yielded limited tissue enrichment, while P&amp;T-based clustering captured more uniform trends across cardiometabolic traits and broader tissue and pathway enrichment. These results demonstrate that methodological choices in SNP selection influence downstream clustering and biological interpretation. Despite some overlap in identified pathways and tissue enrichment, each approach identified unique biological signals, highlighting the potential of pairing polygenic methods and k-means clustering to elucidate the biological heterogeneity of aTRH and guide future mechanistic studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors Open Access chapter published by World Scientific Publishing Company and distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial (CC BY-NC) 4.0 License.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seagle</LastName><ForeName>Hannah M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vanderbilt Genetics Institute, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA2Division of Genetic Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA3Department of Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA4Division of Epidemiology, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA9Joseph Maxwell Cleland Atlanta VA Medical Center, Atlanta, GA, 37203, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jeewoo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vanderbilt Genetics Institute, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA2Division of Genetic Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA3Department of Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA5Division of Quantitative Science, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA6Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA7Vanderbilt Medical Scientist Training Program, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akerele</LastName><ForeName>Alexis T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vanderbilt Genetics Institute, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA5Division of Quantitative Science, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA6Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA10School of Graduate Studies, Meharry Medical College, Nashville, TN, 37208, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>VA Million Veteran Program</CollectiveName></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Adriana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA8Division of Nephrology and Hypertension, Vanderbilt University, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA11VA Tennessee Valley Healthcare System (626), Nashville, TN, 37203, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hellwege</LastName><ForeName>Jacklyn N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Genetic Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA, jacklyn.hellwege@vumc.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edwards</LastName><ForeName>Todd L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA4Division of Epidemiology, Medical Center, Nashville, TN, 37203, USA11VA Tennessee Valley Healthcare System (626), Nashville, TN, 37203, USA, todd.l.edwards@vumc.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pac Symp Biocomput</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9711271</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2335-6928</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000959">Antihypertensive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020412" MajorTopicYN="N">Multifactorial Inheritance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019295" MajorTopicYN="N">Computational Biology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016000" MajorTopicYN="N">Cluster Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004351" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Resistance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000959" MajorTopicYN="N">Antihypertensive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41758176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/9789819824755_0048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">9789819824755_0048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>