<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41523439</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An In Vitro Analysis of Surface Treatment Effects on the Tensile Bond Strength Between Heat-Cured Denture Base and Heat-Polymerized Polymethyl Methacrylate Liner.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e98898</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e98898</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e98898</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.98898</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Successful relining of complete dentures requires strong interfacial adhesion between the existing heat-cured polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA) denture base and the newly applied heat-polymerized PMMA liner to prevent delamination under functional stress. This in vitro investigation examined the efficacy of different surface conditioning methods in enhancing bond integrity and microstructural characteristics at the resin-resin interface.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">48 rectangular specimens were prepared from heat-cured PMMA resin and subjected to standardized long-cycle polymerization. Each specimen was sectioned at the midline to expose a uniform bonding surface and randomly allocated to six experimental groups (n = 8): no treatment (control), methyl methacrylate monomer application, 36% phosphoric acid etching, 50 &#xb5;m alumina particle sandblasting, erbium, chromium, yttrium-scandium-gallium-garnet (Er,Cr:YSGG) laser irradiation followed by phosphoric acid etching, and laser irradiation followed by alumina sandblasting. All procedures used calibrated equipment, digital timing, and custom positioning jigs to ensure reproducibility. The liner was applied using an identical resin from the same batch, trial-packed under controlled pressure, and polymerized using the same technique. The specimens were stored in distilled water for 30 days before testing. The tensile bond strength was determined by three-point bending using a universal testing machine. The selected samples underwent gold sputter coating and examination using field-emission scanning electron microscopy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The tensile bond strength varied significantly across groups (p &lt; 0.001). The untreated control recorded the lowest mean tensile strength at 0.92 &#xb1; 0.06 megapascals (MPa). Monomer application achieved the highest value of 1.89 &#xb1; 0.04 MPa, followed by laser plus phosphoric acid at 1.74 &#xb1; 0.03 MPa, laser plus sandblasting at 1.41 &#xb1; 0.04 MPa, sandblasting alone at 1.24 &#xb1; 0.03 MPa, and phosphoric acid alone at 1.15 &#xb1; 0.02 MPa. Post-hoc comparisons confirmed the statistical superiority of the monomer group over all other modalities, and positioned the laser-phosphoric acid combination as the next most effective approach. Scanning electron microscopy revealed smooth, non-retentive control surfaces with adhesive failure, whereas monomer-treated interfaces displayed polymer interdiffusion and cohesive failure. Laser-phosphoric acid samples exhibited deep micro-undercuts with extensive resin penetration, whereas sandblasting produced superficial grooves with incomplete infiltration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Monomer application was found to be the most reliable and clinically practical method for maximizing liner adhesion through chemical interpenetration. The laser phosphoric acid protocol provides a viable alternative when advanced equipment is available, combining precise ablation with enhanced wettability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Verma et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verma</LastName><ForeName>Sumit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gulati</LastName><ForeName>Manmeet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Manmohit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goyal</LastName><ForeName>Ram R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Aalok</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grover</LastName><ForeName>Silky</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Desh Bhagat Dental College and Hospital, Mandi Gobindgarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Manish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Pathology, Jawahar Medical Foundation's Annasaheb Chudaman Patil Dental College, Dhule, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymethyl methacrylate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41523439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12786586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.98898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Polymeric denture base materials: a review. Alqutaibi AY, Baik A, Almuzaini SA, et al. Polymers (Basel) 2023;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10422349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37571151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond strength of resilient lining materials to denture base resin: a systematic review and meta-analysis. &#xd6;zdemir H, &#xd6;zdo&#x11f;an A. J Prosthodont. 2018;27:828&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond strength of soft liners to denture base resins and the influence of different surface treatments and thermocycling: a systematic review. Muddugangadhar BC, Mawani DP, Das A, Mukhopadhyay A. J Prosthet Dent. 2020;123:800&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31703921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of phosphoric acid pre-etching on chemisorption between enamel and MDP-containing universal adhesives: chemical and morphological characterization, and evaluation of its potential. Han F, Liang R, Xie H. ACS Omega. 2021;6:13182&#x2013;13191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8158842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of sandblasting on bond strength of soft liners to denture base resins: a systematic review and meta-analysis of in vitro studies. Hamedirad F, Alikhasi M, Hasanzade M. Int J Dent. 2021;2021:5674155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8716237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34976062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of different surface treatments and thermocycling on bond strength of a silicone-based denture liner to a denture base resin. Nakhaei M, Dashti H, Ahrari F, Vasigh S, Mushtaq S, Shetty RM. J Contemp Dent Pract. 2016;17:154&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanning electron microscopy in modern dentistry research. Paradella TC, Bottino MA. Braz Dent Sci. 2012;15:43&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of tensile bond strength of a soft liner to the denture base resin with different surface treatments: an in vitro study. Almuraikhi T. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36259300/ J Contemp Dent Pract. 2022;23:613&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36259300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of chemical surface treatments of different denture base resins on the shear bond strength of denture repair. Sarac YS, Sarac D, Kulunk T, Kulunk S. J Prosthet Dent. 2005;94:259&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative evaluation of tensile bond strength between silicon soft liners and processed denture base resin conditioned by three modes of surface treatment: an invitro study. Surapaneni H, Ariga P, Haribabu R, Ravi Shankar Y, Kumar VH, Attili S. J Indian Prosthodont Soc. 2013;13:274&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3732717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24431747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Investigation of bonding properties of denture bases to silicone-based soft denture liner immersed in isobutyl methacrylate and 2-hydroxyethyl methacrylate. Akin H, Tugut F, Mutaf B, Guney U. J Adv Prosthodont. 2014;6:121&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4024556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24843397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of surface treatments on the bond strength of soft denture lining materials to an acrylic resin denture base. Gundogdu M, Yesil Duymus Z, Alkurt M. J Prosthet Dent. 2014;112:964&#x2013;971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24726594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of tensile bond strength of soft liners to an acrylic resin denture base with various curing methods and surface treatments. Haghi HR, Shiehzadeh M, Gharechahi J, Nodehi D, Karazhian A. https://www.quintessence-publishing.com/usa/en/article/850176/the-international-journal-of-prosthodontics/2020/01/comparison-of-tensile-bond-strength-of-soft-liners-to-an-acrylic-resin-denture-base-with-various-curing-methods-and-surface-treatments. Int J Prosthodont. 2020;33:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31860914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application of laser treatment in adhesive bonding of liners to polymethyl methacrylate denture resins: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Alhamdan MM. Photobiomodul Photomed Laser Surg. 2023;41:608&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37910776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of laser surface treatment on shear bond strength between polyetheretherketone and heat-activated polymethylmethacrylate resin. Kuttuva Balasubramanian Sivaprakash Babu AD, Singaravel Chidambara Nathan A, Balasubramanium MK. J Prosthodont. 2024;33:490&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37578028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimizing dental bond strength: insights from comprehensive literature review and future implications for clinical practice. Fan-Chiang YS, Chou PC, Hsiao YW, et al. Biomedicines. 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10669570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38001996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>