<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41291919</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on cerebral palsy football: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>381</StartPage><MedlinePgn>381</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">381</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01436-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM">This study conducts the first scoping review in cerebral palsy (CP) football, a field that has received limited and uneven research attention. While the existing literature has primarily focused on aspects like match load and performance analysis, critical areas such as training interventions and health outcomes have not been consolidated or comprehensively reviewed. This review therefore aims to summarize available evidence, identify key research needs, and provide a comprehensive overview of existing knowledge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This scoping review was conducted following the PRISMA-ScR guidelines. Four selected databases (Web of Science, SPORTDiscus, PubMed and Scopus) were searched on 07/01/2025. Any original research written in FIFA languages published in peer-reviewed journals at any level, any age, and on any subject was eligible for inclusion in this study. All included studies were scoped for authors, journals, titles and abstracts. Population assessed number of participants, age groups, sex groups, level of play and the themes of publication were extracted. Data from the included studies were extracted and then examined to identify key research themes and gaps.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 299 records were found, but only 51 met the selection criteria and therefore scoped. The results highlighted the recent interest in the scientific literature. Match load and strength and conditioning topics constituted two top frequently explored areas. Notably, no studies focusing on the theme of medicine or psychology were identified. Regarding the participant population, the majority of studies were focused on professional players, most of whom were male players. The majority of research were conducted by Spanish scholars, showing the need for research in diverse socio-cultural contexts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">In recent years, a continuous growth in academic attention has been observed in the field of CP football, reflecting broader trends in para-sport where increased participation, institutional investment, and professionalization, particularly within para-sport, have stimulated expanded research on the performance and physiological characteristics of athletes with disabilities. International competitions such as the IFCPF World Cup further elevate the visibility of the sport and underscore the practical need for evidence-based approaches to training, classification, and performance optimization. This study contributes to identifying the research gaps for further studies in this multifaceted, diverse and evolving area of CP football. More specifically, the findings of this study suggested that future research should address the gaps in the area of medicine and psychology, focus on female players and non-professional players, and conduct investigations within diverse sociocultural contexts, while also providing guidance for practices, such as the optimization of CP football training programs and the establishment of a comprehensive support system for footballers with CP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01436-4.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9121-4556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Health, East China Normal University, Shanghai, China. rb816125@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xinpu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HE Sport, Loughborough College, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yuchen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lee Shau Kee School of Business and Administration, Hong Kong Metropolitan University, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xf3;mez Ruano</LastName><ForeName>Miguel &#xc1;ngel</ForeName><Initials>M&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Facultad de Ciencias de la Actividad F&#xed;sica y del Deporte, Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disabled</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soccer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: No ethics approval and consent to participate was needed in this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41291919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12752311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01436-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01436-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>(2015) What is CP Football? <i>IFCPF</i>. IFCPF, Retrived. December 10, 2024, from: https://www.ifcpf.com/what-is-cp-football</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd C, Barnes C, Eaves SJ, Morse CI, Roach N, Williams AG. A time-motion analysis of paralympic football for athletes with cerebral palsy. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2016;11(4):552&#x2013;8. 10.1177/1747954116654786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954116654786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Sarabia JM, Manresa-Rocamora A, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. International football players with cerebral palsy maintained their physical fitness after a self-training program during the COVID-19 lockdown. PeerJ. 2022;10:e13059. 10.7717/peerj.13059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.13059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coswig V, Silva ADACE, Barbalho M, De Faria FR, Nogueira CD, Borges M, et al. Assessing the validity of the MyJUMP2 app for measuring different jumps in professional cerebral palsy football players: an experimental study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019;7(1):e11099. 10.2196/11099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6372935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30698529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamonales JM, Mu&#xf1;oz-Jim&#xe9;nez J, G&#xf3;mez-Carmona CD, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez SJ. Comparative external workload analysis based on the new functional classification in cerebral palsy football 7-a-side. A full-season study. Res Sports Med. 2022;30(3):295&#x2013;307. 10.1080/15438627.2021.1888105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2021.1888105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33579162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Cornejo MI, Albaladejo-Garc&#xed;a C, Messiaen C, Roldan A, Yanci J, Reina R. Physical performance and technical specific skills of women football players with cerebral palsy. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):20831. 10.1038/s41598-024-71967-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-71967-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11385890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39251832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Iturricastillo A, Sabido R, Campayo-Piernas M, Yanci J. Vertical and horizontal jump capacity in international cerebral palsy football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(5):597&#x2013;603. 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29182436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J, Castagna C, Los Arcos A, Santalla A, Grande I, Figueroa J, Camara J. Muscle strength and anaerobic performance in football players with cerebral palsy. Disabil Health J. 2016;9(2):313&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.dhjo.2015.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dhjo.2015.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26723466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite WS. Physiological demands in football, futsal and beach soccer: a brief review. Eur J Phys Educ Sport Sci. 2016;2(4):1&#x2013;9. 10.46827/ejpe.v0i0.382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46827/ejpe.v0i0.382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreira J, da Silva Junior JEP, de Souza CP. Research on women&#x2019;s futsal: a scoping review. Sci Med Footb. 2024;8(4):405&#x2013;17. 10.1080/24733938.2024.2310503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2024.2310503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38314677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okholm Kryger K, Wang A, Mehta R, Impellizzeri FM, Massey A, McCall A. Research on women&#x2019;s football: a scoping review. Sci Med Footb. 2022;6(5):549&#x2013;58. 10.1080/24733938.2020.1868560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2020.1868560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36540910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;73. 10.7326/M18-0850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MD, Marnie C, Tricco AC, Pollock D, Munn Z, Alexander L, et al. Updated methodological guidance for the conduct of scoping reviews. JBI Evid Synth. 2020;18(10):2119&#x2013;26. 10.11124/JBIES-20-00167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-20-00167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson N, Phillips M. Rayyan for systematic reviews. J Electron Resour Librariansh. 2018;30(1):46&#x2013;8. 10.1080/1941126X.2018.1444339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1941126X.2018.1444339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O&#x2019;brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5:1&#x2013;9. 10.1186/1748-5908-5-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-5-69</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elston DM. Mendeley. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2019;81(5):1071. 10.1016/j.jaad.2019.06.1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.06.1291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31279032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardin M. I consider myself an empowered woman: the interaction of sport, gender and disability in the lives of wheelchair basketball players. Women Sport Phys Activity J. 2007;16(1):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/wspaj.16.1.39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark B, Mesch J. A global perspective on disparity of gender and disability for deaf female athletes. In: Sport and Disability. Routledge; 2018. p. 64&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culver DM, Shaikh M, Alexander D, Fournier K. Gender equity in disability sport: a rapid scoping review. J Clin Sport Psychol. 2022;16(4):383&#x2013;405. 10.1123/jcsp.2021-0074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jcsp.2021-0074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J, Castillo D, Iturricastillo A, Urb&#xe1;n T, Reina R. External match loads of footballers with cerebral palsy: a comparison among sport classes. Int Journal Sports Physiol Performance. 2018;13(5):590&#x2013;6. 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29035588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J, Castillo D, Iturricastillo A, Reina R. Evaluation of the official match external load in soccer players with cerebral palsy. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(3):866&#x2013;73. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Iturricastillo A, Castillo D, Urb&#xe1;n T, Yanci J. Activity limitation and match load in para-footballers with cerebral palsy: an approach for evidence&#x2010;based classification. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(3):496&#x2013;504. 10.1111/sms.13583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31657483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Iturricastillo A, Castillo D, Roldan A, Toledo C, Yanci J. Is impaired coordination related to match physical load in footballers with cerebral palsy of different sport classes? J Sports Sci. 2021;39(sup1):140&#x2013;9. 10.1080/02640414.2021.1880740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2021.1880740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33525957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez IP, Marin JMS, Triguero DM, Ramon MM, Puerto JMG. Relationship between physical performance and match load and effects of twoconsecutive matches in cerebral palsy footballers. Retos: Nuevas Tendencias en Educaci&#xf3;n F&#xed;sica, Deporte y Recreaci&#xf3;n. 2021;41:728&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v41i0.86424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh AM, Ma&#x2019;ayah F, Harms CA, Newton RU, Drinkwater EJ. Global positioning system activity profile in male para footballers with cerebral palsy: does training meet the match-play intensity in a 3-day National tournament? Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;101(12):1163&#x2013;7. 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34740223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamonales JM, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Beltr&#xe1;n V, Mu&#xf1;oz-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Mendoza-L&#xe1;iz N, Espada MC, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez SJ. Analysis of the competitive demands in 7-a-side football players with cerebral palsy. Apunts Sports Medicine. 2024;59(221):100434. 10.1016/j.apunsm.2024.100434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apunsm.2024.100434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, de Campos LFC, Mu&#xf1;oz-Hinrichsen F, Cornejo MI, Yanci J, Reina R. Neuromuscular fatigue in cerebral palsy football players after a competitive match according to sport classification and playing position. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(10):6070. 10.3390/ijerph19106070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19106070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9140681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35627606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Castillo D, Yanci J, Iturricastillo A, Reina R. Physical responses by cerebral palsy footballers in matches played at sea level and moderate altitude. Res Sports Med. 2023;31(3):296&#x2013;308. 10.1080/15438627.2021.1966011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2021.1966011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriquez MJ, Kokaly M, Herrera F, Reina R. The relationship among repeated sprint and change of direction abilities in football players with cerebral palsy. Kinesiology. 2020;52(2):208&#x2013;16. 10.26582/k.52.2.6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26582/k.52.2.6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Javaloyes A, Sarabia JM, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Assessing the sprint force-velocity profile in international football players with cerebral palsy: validity, reliability and sport class&#x2019; profiles. J Hum Kinet. 2022;82(1):253&#x2013;62. 10.2478/hukin-2022-0065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovcharenko S, Yakovenko A, Sydorchuk T, Stepanova I, Pikiner O. Criteria for assessing the level of physical fitness and physical state of football players with cerebral paralysis, taking into account their sports classes. Pedagogy Phys Cult Sports. 2021;25(2):125&#x2013;31. 10.15561/26649837.2021.0207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/26649837.2021.0207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Physical performance preparation for the cerebral palsy football world cup: a team study. Apunts Sports Med. 2023;58(218):100413. 10.1016/j.apunsm.2023.100413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apunsm.2023.100413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Sarabia JM, Caballero C, Yanci J. How does the ball influence the performance of change of direction and sprint tests in para-footballers with brain impairments? Implications for evidence-based classification in CP-Football. PLoS One. 2017;12(11):e0187237. 10.1371/journal.pone.0187237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0187237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5669430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29099836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriquez M, Riquelme S, Abarca M, Morales F, Reina R. Physical demands of para-footballers with cerebral palsy in a small-sided game. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2020;60(9):1247&#x2013;53. 10.23736/s0022-4707.20.10514-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/s0022-4707.20.10514-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Henr&#xed;quez M, Garc&#xed;a-Hern&#xe1;ndez JJ, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Relationship between physical fitness parameters and match time motion performance in international footballers with cerebral palsy. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2024;(1):16. 10.1080/24748668.2024.2387905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Sarabia JM, Yanci J, Garc&#xed;a-Vaquero MP, Campayo-Piernas M. Change of direction ability performance in cerebral palsy football players according to functional profiles. Front Physiol. 2016;6:409. 10.3389/fphys.2015.00409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2015.00409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26779037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Henr&#xed;quez M, Sarabia JM, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Age does not influence the physical performance of football players with cerebral palsy. Science &amp; Sports. 2024;39(4):377&#x2013;83. 10.1016/j.scispo.2023.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2023.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Ozaeta E, Castillo D, Reina R, Cornejo MI, Iturricastillo A, et al. Assessing the match physical responses of international referees for footballers with cerebral palsy: a tournaments and halves comparative analysis. Sensors. 2024;24(5):1595. 10.3390/s24051595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24051595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10935441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38475129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamonales JM, Le&#xf3;n K, Jim&#xe9;nez A, Mu&#xf1;oz-Jim&#xe9;nez J. Sport performance indicators in football 7-A-Side for people with cerebral palsy. Int J Med Sci Phys Activity Sport / Revista Int De Med Y Ciencias De La Actividad F&#xed;sica Y Del Deporte. 2019;19(74):309&#x2013;28. 10.15366/rimcafd2019.74.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15366/rimcafd2019.74.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J. Analysis of goals scored by players with cerebral palsy in official football 7-a-side matches. Kinesiology. 2015;47(2):202&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Maggiolo JF, Rold&#xe1;n A, Sarabia JM. Analysis of scored goals in cerebral palsy football Spanish league. Eur J Hum Mov. 2022;48:46&#x2013;53. 10.21134/eurjhm.2022.48.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21134/eurjhm.2022.48.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Maggiolo JF, Javaloyes A, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Analysis of scored goals in the cerebral palsy football world cup. J Sports Sci. 2023;40(22):2509&#x2013;16. 10.1080/02640414.2023.2167257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2023.2167257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36652545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Maggiolo JF, Romero AR, Ramon MM. Analysis of goal scoring patterns as a factor in Understanding the evolution of international cerebral palsy football. Retos: Nuevas Tendencias En Educaci&#xf3;n F&#xed;sica Deporte Y Recreaci&#xf3;n. 2024;57:362&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v57.104718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh AM, Drinkwater EJ, Harms CA, Scanlan M, Newton RU, Ma&#x2019;ayah F. Characteristics of goals scored in open play at the 2017 and 2018 Australian National cerebral palsy football championship. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2023;18(3):858&#x2013;66. 10.1177/17479541221095941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541221095941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor D, Campayo-Piernas M, Pastor JT, Reina R. A mathematical model for decision-making in the classification of para-footballers with different severity of coordination impairments. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(12):1403&#x2013;10. 10.1080/02640414.2018.1560617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1560617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30583709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarabia JM, Roldan A, Henr&#xed;quez M, Reina R. Using decision trees to support classifiers&#x2019; decision-making about activity limitation of cerebral palsy footballers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(8):4320. 10.3390/ijerph18084320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18084320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Roldan A, Toledo C, Urb&#xe1;n T, Reina R. Change-of-direction ability of para-footballers with cerebral palsy under a new evidence-based and sport-specific classification system. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;16(2):267&#x2013;72. 10.1123/ijspp.2019-0656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J, Castillo D, Iturricastillo A, Aracama A, Roldan A, Reina R. Performance analysis in football-specific tests by para-footballers with cerebral palsy: implications for evidence-based classification. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(9):1328&#x2013;34. 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Albaladejo&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a C, Sadarangani KP, Reina R. Sex differences in change of direction deficit and asymmetries in footballers with cerebral palsy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(8):1519&#x2013;30. 10.1111/sms.14383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37149724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarabia JM, Dom&#xe9;nech C, Roche E, Vicente-Salar N, Reina R. Anthropometrical features of para-footballers according to their cerebral palsy profiles and compared to controls. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(23):9071. 10.3390/ijerph17239071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17239071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7730112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33291750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Gomes O, da Cunha Le&#xe3;o, Ferreira CM, Soares Vieira V. Differences in body composition between affected and nonaffected sides in cerebral palsy football athletes: Preliminary findings. Retos. 2022;44:416&#x2013;20. 10.47197/retos.v44i0.89905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v44i0.89905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Sarabia JM, Roldan A, Manresa-Rocamora A, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. Physical performance differences between Spanish selected and nonselected para-footballers with cerebral palsy for the National team. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(11):1676&#x2013;83. 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33952712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorla JI, Nogueira CD, Gon&#xe7;alves HR, De Faria FR, Buratti JR, Nunes N, et al. Body composition and somatotype profile of football-seven Brazilian players with Cerebral Palsy by functional classification. Contribution to paralympic sport |Composici&#xf3;n Corporal y Perfil Somatot&#xed;pico de Jugadores Brasile Nos de F&#xfa;tbol Siete Con Par&#xe1;lis. Retos. 2019;35:326&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v0i35.58931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Iturricastillo A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Olgu&#xed;n A, Herrera F, Riquelme S, Reina R. Time&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;motion characteristics and physiological responses of para-footballers with cerebral palsy in two small-sided games and a simulated game. Adapt Phys Activ Q. 2021;38(2):232&#x2013;47. 10.1123/apaq.2020-0077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/apaq.2020-0077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33596537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roldan A, Henr&#xed;quez M, Iturricastillo A, Castillo D, Yanci J, Reina R. To what degree does limb spasticity affect motor performance in para-footballers with cerebral palsy? Front Physiol. 2022;12:807853. 10.3389/fphys.2021.807853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.807853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35140631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvarez-Hern&#xe1;ndez S, Castillo D, Villa-Vicente JG, Yanci J, Marqu&#xe9;s-Jim&#xe9;nez D, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A. Analyses of physical and physiological responses during competition in para-footballers with cerebral palsy: a systematic review. Appl Sci. 2024;14(9):3812. 10.3390/app14093812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14093812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Barbado D, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; H, Roldan A. Dynamic and static stability in para&#x2010;athletes with cerebral palsy considering their impairment profile. PM R. 2021;14(3):366&#x2013;76. 10.1002/pmrj.12579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33599066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henr&#xed;quez M, Sabido R, Barbado D, Roldan A, Elvira JL, Yanci J, et al. Differences in kinetic characteristics during countermovement jump of football players with cerebral palsy according to impairment profiles. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1121652. 10.3389/fphys.2023.1121652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1121652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina R, Elvira JL, Valverde M, Rold&#xe1;n A, Yanci J. Kinematic and kinetic analyses of the vertical jump with and without header as performed by para-footballers with cerebral palsy. Sports. 2019;7(9):209. 10.3390/sports7090209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7090209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31547248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogueira CD, de S&#xe1; KSG, de Faria FR, Borges M, de Athay Costa A, Gorla JI. Validation of split jump and the side-stepping jump coordination tests for cerebral palsy football athletes. Retos: nuevas tendencias en educaci&#xf3;n f&#xed;sica, deporte y recreaci&#xf3;n. 2022;46:425&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v46.93234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel LF, Reina R, Gorla JI, Bastos T, Roldan A. Validity and reliability of a test battery to assess change of directions with ball dribbling in para-footballers with cerebral palsy. Brain Sci. 2020;10(2):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci10020074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32023834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broman D, Ahmed OH, Tscholl PM, Weiler R. Medication and supplement use in disability Football World Championships. PM&amp;R. 2017;9(10):990&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.pmrj.2017.02.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2017.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivaratnam C, Howells K, Stefanac N, Reynolds K, Rinehart N. Parent and clinician perspectives on the participation of children with cerebral palsy in community-based football: a qualitative exploration in a regional setting. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(3):1102. 10.3390/ijerph17031102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17031102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7037465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32050514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti G, Iaia FM, Arcelli E, Cavaggioni L, Rampinini E. Goal scoring patterns in major European soccer leagues. Sport Sci Health. 2013;9:151&#x2013;3. 10.1007/s11332-013-0154-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-013-0154-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>