<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41717720</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Head &amp; neck</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Head Neck</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Student-Led Tele-Expiratory Muscle Strength Training (EMST) Program for Head and Neck Cancer (HNC) Survivors-A Pilot Implementation Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hed.70206</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Expiratory muscle strength training (EMST) is a non-invasive, evidence-based treatment that is used to improve swallowing in head and neck cancer (HNC) survivors. This prospective, pilot implementation study evaluated the feasibility, acceptability, and potential clinical effectiveness of a novel student-led tele-EMST program for HNC survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">HNC survivors (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) completed an eight-week tele-EMST program. Acceptability was measured using the Theoretical Framework of Acceptability Questionnaire (TFAQ) and the Telehealth Usability Questionnaire (TUQ). Feasibility was tracked weekly. Swallowing performance, airway clearance, and quality of life were evaluated using the Timed Water Swallow Test (TWST), peak expiratory flow rate (PEFR), and SWAL-QoL, respectively. Data were collected with REDCap. Descriptive and non-parametric statistics were performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Acceptability of the tele-EMST program was high, as evidenced by high ratings on the TUQ (mean: 88.1/100%, SD: 16.3) and significant improvement on the TFAQ (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Technical issues occurred in 24% of sessions but were all resolved. Swallowing performance (TWST, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), self-reported dysphagia symptoms, and mental health scores (SWAL-QoL, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) significantly improved. No significant changes in PEFR were observed (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.59).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of this small pilot feasibility suggest that a student-led, tele-EMST program is a promising, scalable approach to reduce treatment inequities and support survivorship care for HNC survivors with dysphagia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Head &amp; Neck published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blyth</LastName><ForeName>Katrina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4053-0092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Speech Pathology, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tam</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9925-6263</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Speech Pathology, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech Pathology Department, The Royal North Shore Hospital, Northern Sydney Local Health District, New South Wales Health, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Rachelle</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech Pathology Department, Prince of Wales Hospital, South-Eastern Sydney Local Health District, New South Wales Health, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0563-8225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Speech Pathology, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech Pathology Department, The Royal North Shore Hospital, Northern Sydney Local Health District, New South Wales Health, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Emma S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5329-1222</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Speech Pathology, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Sydney Health Partners</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Head Neck</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8902541</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1043-3074</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telehealth</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41717720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hed.70206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>H. Sung, J. Ferlay, R. L. Siegel, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Cancer Statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 71, no. 3 (2021): 209&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gormley, G. Creaney, A. Schache, K. Ingarfield, and D. I. Conway, &#x201c;Reviewing the Epidemiology of Head and Neck Cancer: Definitions, Trends and Risk Factors,&#x201d; British Dental Journal 233, no. 9 (2022): 780&#x2013;786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Health and Welfare, &#x201c;Head and Neck Cancer in Australia,&#x201d; 2014 [cited 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Patterson, E. McColl, P. N. Carding, and J. A. Wilson, &#x201c;Swallowing Beyond Six Years Post (Chemo)radiotherapy for Head and Neck Cancer; a Cohort Study,&#x201d; Oral Oncology 83 (2018): 53&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y.&#x2010;H. Chiu, W. H. Tseng, J. Y. Ko, and T. G. Wang, &#x201c;Radiation&#x2010;Induced Swallowing Dysfunction in Patients With Head and Neck Cancer: A Literature Review,&#x201d; Journal of the Formosan Medical Association 121, no. 1, Part 1 (2022): 3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. A. Hutcheson, J. S. Lewin, D. A. Barringer, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Late Dysphagia After Radiotherapy&#x2010;Based Treatment of Head and Neck Cancer,&#x201d; Cancer 118, no. 23 (2012): 5793&#x2013;5799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Y. Feng, H. M. Kim, T. H. Lyden, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Intensity&#x2010;Modulated Chemoradiotherapy Aiming to Reduce Dysphagia in Patients With Oropharyngeal Cancer: Clinical and Functional Results,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Oncology 28, no. 16 (2010): 2732&#x2013;2738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. A. Hutcheson, M. P. Barrow, C. L. Warneke, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cough Strength and Expiratory Force in Aspirating and Nonaspirating Postradiation Head and Neck Cancer Survivors,&#x201d; Laryngoscope 128, no. 7 (2018): 1615&#x2013;1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Xu, I. J. Boero, L. Hwang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Aspiration Pneumonia After Concurrent Chemoradiotherapy for Head and Neck Cancer,&#x201d; Cancer 121, no. 8 (2015): 1303&#x2013;1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. U. Hunter, O. E. Lee, T. H. Lyden, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Aspiration Pneumonia After Chemo&#x2010;Intensity&#x2010;Modulated Radiation Therapy of Oropharyngeal Carcinoma and Its Clinical and Dysphagia&#x2010;Related Predictors,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 36, no. 1 (2014): 120&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. A. Hutcheson, M. P. Barrow, E. K. Plowman, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Expiratory Muscle Strength Training for Radiation&#x2010;Associated Aspiration After Head and Neck Cancer: A Case Series,&#x201d; Laryngoscope 128, no. 5 (2018): 1044&#x2013;1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M. Szczesniak, J. Maclean, T. Zhang, P. H. Graham, and I. J. Cook, &#x201c;Persistent Dysphagia After Head and Neck Radiotherapy: A Common and Under&#x2010;Reported Complication With Significant Effect on Non&#x2010;Cancer&#x2010;Related Mortality,&#x201d; Clinical Oncology (Royal College of Radiologists) 26, no. 11 (2014): 697&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Mancopes, S. Smaoui, and C. M. Steele, &#x201c;Effects of Expiratory Muscle Strength Training on Videofluoroscopic Measures of Swallowing: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; American Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 29, no. 1 (2020): 335&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Brooks, E. McLaughlin, and N. Shields, &#x201c;Expiratory Muscle Strength Training Improves Swallowing and Respiratory Outcomes in People With Dysphagia: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 21, no. 1 (2019): 89&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Hutcheson, M. P. Barrow, E. K. Plowman, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Expiratory Muscle Strength Training: Results of a Pilot Prospective Trial,&#x201d; Dysphagia 34, no. 6 (2019): 995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Malandraki, G. A. Malandraki, R. H. Arkenberg, S. S. Mitchell, and J. B. Malandraki, &#x201c;Telehealth for Dysphagia Across the Life Span: Using Contemporary Evidence and Expertise to Guide Clinical Practice During and After COVID&#x2010;19,&#x201d; American Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 30, no. 2 (2021): 532&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Sevitz, J. C. Borders, A. E. Dakin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Rehabilitation of Airway Protection in Individuals With Movement Disorders: A Telehealth Feasibility Study,&#x201d; American Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 31, no. 6 (2022): 2741&#x2013;2758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. C. Ward, S. Sharma, C. Burns, D. Theodoros, and T. Russell, &#x201c;Validity of Conducting Clinical Dysphagia Assessments for Patients With Normal to Mild Cognitive Impairment via Telerehabilitation,&#x201d; Dysphagia 27, no. 4 (2012): 460&#x2013;472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. C. Ward and C. Burns, &#x201c;Dysphagia Management via Telerehabilitation: A Review of the Current Evidence,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology Research 3, no. 5 (2017): 1088&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. M. Starmer, R. Abrams, K. Webster, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Feasibility of a Mobile Application to Enhance Swallowing Therapy for Patients Undergoing Radiation&#x2010;Based Treatment for Head and Neck Cancer,&#x201d; Dysphagia 33, no. 2 (2018): 227&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Constantinescu, J. Rieger, H. Seikaly, and D. Eurich, &#x201c;Adherence to Home&#x2010;Based Swallowing Therapy Using a Mobile System in Head and Neck Cancer Survivors,&#x201d; American Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 30, no. 6 (2021): 2465&#x2013;2475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Yang, Y. du, M. Chen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effectiveness of Home&#x2010;Based Telerehabilitation Interventions for Dysphagia in Patients With Head and Neck Cancer: Systematic Review,&#x201d; Journal of Medical Internet Research 25 (2023): e47324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Moullin, D. Sabater&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F. Fernandez&#x2010;Llimos, and S. I. Benrimoj, &#x201c;A Systematic Review of Implementation Frameworks of Innovations in Healthcare and Resulting Generic Implementation Framework,&#x201d; Health Research Policy and Systems 13, no. 1 (2015): 16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aspire Products LLC, &#x201c;Precautions and Contraindications,&#x201d; [cited 2025 27th June], https://emst150.com/wp&#x2010;content/uploads/2021/03/Contraindications&#x2010;11&#x2010;2019.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Troche, M. S. Okun, J. C. Rosenbek, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Aspiration and Swallowing in Parkinson Disease and Rehabilitation With EMST: A Randomized Trial,&#x201d; Neurology 75, no. 21 (2010): 1912&#x2013;1919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sekhon, M. Cartwright, and J. J. Francis, &#x201c;Development of a Theory&#x2010;Informed Questionnaire to Assess the Acceptability of Healthcare Interventions,&#x201d; BMC Health Services Research 22, no. 1 (2022): 279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Parmanto, A. N. Jr Lewis, K. M. Graham, and M. H. Bertolet, &#x201c;Development of the Telehealth Usability Questionnaire (TUQ),&#x201d; International Journal of Telerehabilitation 8, no. 1 (2016): 3&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. L. Burns, E. C. Ward, A. J. Hill, S. Kularatna, J. Byrnes, and L. M. Kenny, &#x201c;Randomized Controlled Trial of a Multisite Speech Pathology Telepractice Service Providing Swallowing and Communication Intervention to Patients With Head and Neck Cancer: Evaluation of Service Outcomes,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 39, no. 5 (2017): 932&#x2013;939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Collins, C. L. Burns, E. C. Ward, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Home&#x2010;Based Telehealth Service for Swallowing and Nutrition Management Following Head and Neck Cancer Treatment,&#x201d; Journal of Telemedicine and Telecare 23, no. 10 (2017): 866&#x2013;872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. R. Wall, E. C. Ward, B. Cartmill, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Prophylactic Swallowing Therapy for Patients With Head and Neck Cancer: A Three&#x2010;Arm Randomized Parallel&#x2010;Group Trial,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 42, no. 5 (2020): 873&#x2013;885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. H&#xe4;gglund, P. Karlsson, and F. Karlsson, &#x201c;The Timed Water Swallow Test (TWST): Normative Data on Swallowing Capacity for Healthy People Aged 60&#x2009;Years and Older,&#x201d; International Journal of Speech&#x2010;Language Pathology 25, no. 4 (2023): 479&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>