<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41391907</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1769-664X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>7S1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives de pediatrie : organe officiel de la Societe francaise de pediatrie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Respiratory care in Duchenne muscular dystrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7S25</StartPage><EndPage>7S31</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7S25-7S31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0929-693X(25)00250-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0929-693X(25)00250-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Respiratory complications are amajor cause of morbidity and mortality in Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD). Progressive weakness of inspiratory and expiratory muscles leads to ineffective cough, mucus retention, sleep-disordered breathing, nocturnal hypoventilation, and ultimately chronic respiratory failure. Before the advent of mechanical ventilation, respiratory failure was the leading cause of early death. Advances in multidisciplinary care, including noninvasive ventilation (NIV), airway clearance techniques, corticosteroid therapy, scoliosis management, and cardioprotective treatments, have markedly improved survival and quality of life. Respiratory decline typically follows loss of ambulation, reflecting the progressive loss of muscle strength. Hypoventilation first appears during REM sleep and evolves into daytime hypercapnia. Regular monitoring-annually before and biannually after loss of ambulation-is essential. Key respiratory monitoring parameters include decreased vital capacity, maximal inspiratory and expiratory pressures, and peak cough flow. Sleep studies are critical for early detection of nocturnal hypoventilation and sleep-disordered breathing. NIV remains the cornerstone of therapy, improving gas exchange, sleep quality, and life expectancy. As weakness increases, patients may become ventilator dependent; invasive ventilation is reserved for NIV failure. Adjunctive strategies such as lung volume recruitment and mechanical insufflation-exsufflation enhance cough efficacy and secretion clearance. Long-term corticosteroid therapy delays respiratory decline, while scoliosis correction and infection prevention further optimize outcomes. Nutritional management also supports respiratory health. Overall, early detection, individualized ventilatory management, and comprehensive multidisciplinary care are critical to improving survival and quality of life in patients with DMD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 French Society of Pediatrics. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS. All rights reserved. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prigent</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology Department, Hopital Raymond Poincar&#xe9; GHU APHP Universit&#xe9; Paris Saclay, 92380 Garches, France; UFR Simone Veil, Universit&#xe9; Versailles Saint Quentin en Yvelines - Universit&#xe9; Paris Saclay, 78180 Montigny-le-Bretonneux, France; U1179 Universit&#xe9; Versailles Saint Quentin en Yvelines - Universit&#xe9; Paris Saclay, 78180 Montigny-le-Bretonneux, France. Electronic address: helene.prigent@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9421356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0929-693X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020388" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscular Dystrophy, Duchenne</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="N">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Airway clearance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alveolar hypoventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory muscle weakness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Restrictive respiratory failure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest H. Prigent declares competing interest for occasional advisory consultancy for Amicus therapeutics; for invitations to congresses as a speaker by SOS oxygene, Lowenstein Medical, ASV sant&#xe9;, Roche and Pfizer; for invitations to congresses as a participant (expenses paid) by SOS oxygene. This article is part of a supplement entitled Duchenne muscular dystrophy published with institutional support from Pfizer.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41391907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0929-693X(25)00250-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0929-693X(25)00250-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>