<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41235457</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lower knee self-efficacy is associated with greater asymmetries in quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump-landing biomechanics post-ACL reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70192</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To (1) compare psychological factors and asymmetries in quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump-landing biomechanics between patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) and healthy controls and (2) determine whether psychological factors relate to these asymmetric outcomes in the ACLR cohort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty participants (26 patients with ACLR [time since surgery: 39.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;35.1 months] and 14 healthy controls) were included. Psychological assessments included measures of fear of reinjury (Tampa Scale of Kinesiophobia), knee self-efficacy (Knee Self-Efficacy Scale) and readiness for return to sport (anterior cruciate ligament-return to sport after injury). Bilateral quadriceps strength (maximal voluntary isometric contraction) and activation (central activation ratio) were evaluated via a multimodal dynamometer. Bilateral peak knee extension moment (KEM) and peak vertical ground reaction force (vGRF) during jump-landing were assessed using a three-dimensional motion capture system. Limb symmetry indices were calculated for all neuromuscular and biomechanical variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared to healthy controls, patients with ACLR demonstrated significantly worse psychological outcomes (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001 for all questionnaires; Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.35-1.94) and greater asymmetries in quadriceps strength (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.016; Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.84), peak KEM (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.47) and peak vGRF (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002; Cohen's d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.10). Among patients with ACLR, lower knee self-efficacy was moderately to strongly associated with greater asymmetries across all neuromuscular and biomechanical measures (&#x3c1;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.420-0.737; p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.033). Greater fear of reinjury (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.403; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.041) and lower readiness for return to sport (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.522; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006) were moderately associated with greater asymmetry in peak vGRF.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with ACLR displayed worse psychological outcomes and greater asymmetries in quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump-landing biomechanics compared to healthy controls. Knee self-efficacy was consistently associated with asymmetries in quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump-landing biomechanics following ACLR. Asymmetry in vGRF may be particularly sensitive to psychological factors in patients with ACLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sungwan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2531-0617</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sports Medicine, Department of Orthopedics, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Micheli Center for Sports Injury Prevention, Waltham, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burland</LastName><ForeName>Julie P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3961-0212</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sports Medicine, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central activation ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee extension moment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vertical ground reaction force</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41235457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Beischer S, Hamrin Senorski E, Thome&#xe9; C, Samuelsson K, Thome&#xe9; R. How is psychological outcome related to knee function and return to sport among adolescent athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Am J Sports Med. 2019;47:1567&#x2013;1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borawski J, Brindle RA, Florkiewicz E, Mason JS, Pitt W, Cameron KL, et al. Psychological factors are related to neuromuscular asymmetries after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Sports Health. 2025;17:262&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottoni CR. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstructions in active&#x2010;duty military patients. Oper Tech Sports Med. 2005;13:169&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand E, Nyland J. Patient outcomes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the influence of psychological factors. Orthopedics. 2009;32:335&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burland JP, Lepley AS, Cormier M, DiStefano LJ, Lepley LK. Examining the relationship between neuroplasticity and learned helplessness after ACLR: early versus late recovery. J Sport Rehabil. 2021;30:70&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burland JP, Lepley AS, Frechette L, Lepley LK. Protracted alterations in muscle activation strategies and knee mechanics in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28:3766&#x2013;3772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burland JP, Toonstra J, Werner JL, Mattacola CG, Howell DM, Howard JS. Decision to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, part I: a qualitative investigation of psychosocial factors. J Athl Train. 2018;53:452&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burland JP, Toonstra JL, Howard JS. Psychosocial barriers after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a clinical review of factors influencing postoperative success. Sports Health. 2019;11:528&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chmielewski TL, Zeppieri Jr, G, Lentz TA, Tillman SM, Moser MW, Indelicato PA, et al. Longitudinal changes in psychosocial factors and their association with knee pain and function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther. 2011;91:1355&#x2013;1366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. New York: Routledge; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat A, Barton C, Emery C, Brussoni M, Bruder A. &#x201c;I don't have confidence in my knee&#x201d;: knee self&#x2010;efficacy impacting female adolescent athletes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25:S43&#x2013;S44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goerger BM, Marshall SW, Beutler AI, Blackburn JT, Wilckens JH, Padua DA. Anterior cruciate ligament injury alters preinjury lower extremity biomechanics in the injured and uninjured leg: the JUMP&#x2010;ACL study. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:188&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Bisschop M, Benjaminse A, Myer GD, Eppinga P, Otten E. Quadriceps function following ACL reconstruction and rehabilitation: implications for optimisation of current practices. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22:1163&#x2013;1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin LY, Albohm MJ, Arendt EA, Bahr R, Beynnon BD, DeMaio M, et al. Understanding and preventing noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34:1512&#x2013;1532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:804&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart JM, Pietrosimone B, Hertel J, Ingersoll CD. Quadriceps activation following knee injuries: a systematic review. J Athl Train. 2010;45:87&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes G, Musco P, Caine S, Howe L. Lower limb asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in adolescent athletes: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Athl Train. 2020;55:811&#x2013;825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Glaviano NR, Park J. Exercise&#x2010;induced fatigue affects knee proprioceptive acuity and quadriceps neuromuscular function more in patients with ACL reconstruction or meniscus surgery than in healthy individuals. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:5428&#x2013;5437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kim D, Park J. Knee joint and quadriceps dysfunction in individuals with anterior knee pain, anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, and meniscus surgery: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. J Sport Rehabil. 2021;30:112&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenze CM, Hertel J, Weltman A, Diduch D, Saliba SA, Hart JM. Persistent neuromuscular and corticomotor quadriceps asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2015;50:303&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Kuenze CM. Hip and knee kinematics and kinetics during landing tasks after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Athl Train. 2018;53:144&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Lepley LK. Mechanisms of arthrogenic muscle inhibition. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31:707&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisee C, Lepley AS, Birchmeier T, O'Hagan K, Kuenze C. Quadriceps strength and volitional activation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Health. 2019;11:163&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mall NA, Chalmers PN, Moric M, Tanaka MJ, Cole BJ, Bach BR, et al. Incidence and trends of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the United States. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2363&#x2013;2370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mclean SG, FELIN RE, Suedekum N, Calabrese G, Passerallo A, Joy S. Impact of fatigue on gender&#x2010;based high&#x2010;risk landing strategies. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:502&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momaya AM, Wood AS, Benson EM, Kwapisz AL. The influence of psychosocial factors on patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Sports Health. 2024;16:230&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedder VJ, Raju AG, Moyal AJ, Calcei JG, Voos JE. Impact of psychological factors on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Sports Health. 2025;17:291&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri&#x2010;Smith RM, Thomas AC. A neuromuscular mechanism of posttraumatic osteoarthritis associated with ACL injury. Exerc Spotr Sci Rev. 2009;37:147&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Ty Hopkins J. Quadriceps activation normative values and the affect of subcutaneous tissue thickness. J Electromyography Kinesiol. 2011;21:136&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Schmitt LC, Ford KR, Rauh MJ, Myer GD, Huang B, et al. Biomechanical measures during landing and postural stability predict second anterior cruciate ligament injury after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:1968&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peebles AT, Savla J, Ollendick TH, Queen RM. Landing asymmetry is associated with psychological factors after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:1446&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone B, Lepley AS, Kuenze C, Harkey MS, Hart JM, Blackburn JT, et al. Arthrogenic muscle inhibition following anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31:694&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone B, Lepley AS, Murray AM, Thomas AC, Bahhur NO, Schwartz TA. Changes in voluntary quadriceps activation predict changes in muscle strength and gait biomechanics following knee joint effusion. Clin Biomech. 2014;29:923&#x2013;929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Magnusson C, Andersson S, Mannerkorpi K, Thome&#xe9; R, Samuelsson K, et al. Some, but not all, patients experience full symptom resolution and a positive rehabilitation process after ACL reconstruction: an interview study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:2927&#x2013;2935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlog L, Wadey R, Caron J, Fraser JJ, Ivarsson A, Heil J, et al. Psychological readiness to return to sport following injury: a state&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;art review. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2024;17:753&#x2013;772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pua Y&#x2010;H, Low J, Woon E&#x2010;L, Tay OS&#x2010;M, Cheong P, Thumboo J, et al. Knee performance and self&#x2010;efficacy trajectory curves after ACL reconstruction: a longitudinal study. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;49:157&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JL, Glaviano NR, Norte GE. Assessment of quadriceps corticomotor and spinal&#x2010;reflexive excitability in individuals with a history of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51:961&#x2013;990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JL, Grooms DR, Burland JP, Murray AM, Bazett&#x2010;Jones DM, Norte GE. Examining neurocognitive profiles and single&#x2010;limb landing mechanics following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther Sport. 2025;74:18&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Samaan MA, Tanaka MS, Pedoia V, Souza RB, Li X, et al. Abnormal biomechanics at 6 months are associated with cartilage degeneration at 3 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy. 2019;35:511&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater LV, Hart JM, Kelly AR, Kuenze CM. Progressive changes in walking kinematics and kinetics after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: a review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Athl Train. 2017;52:847&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Te Wierike SCM, van der Sluis A, Van Den Akker&#x2010;Scheek I, Elferink&#x2010;Gemser MT, Visscher C. Psychosocial factors influencing the recovery of athletes with anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23:527&#x2013;540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; P, W&#xe4;hrborg P, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. Self&#x2010;efficacy, symptoms and physical activity in patients with an anterior cruciate ligament injury: a prospective study. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17:238&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; P, W&#xe4;hrborg P, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. A new instrument for measuring self&#x2010;efficacy in patients with an anterior cruciate ligament injury. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2006;16:181&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, Senorski EH, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Prill R. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: decades of change. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1178&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlaeyen JWS, Kole&#x2010;Snijders AMJ, Boeren RGB, van Eek H. Fear of movement/(re) injury in chronic low back pain and its relation to behavioral performance. Pain. 1995;62:363&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ. 2007;335:806&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh BM, Porter KH, Hoch MC. Optimizing health&#x2010;related outcomes following musculoskeletal injury through the integration of self&#x2010;efficacy theory and the fear avoidance model. Int J Athl Ther Train. 2024;29:195&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh M, Boling MC, McGrath M, Blackburn JT, Padua DA. Lower extremity muscle activation and knee flexion during a jump&#x2010;landing task. J Athl Train. 2012;47:406&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward SH, Blackburn JT, Padua DA, Stanley LE, Harkey MS, Luc&#x2010;Harkey BA, et al. Quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump&#x2010;landing sagittal&#x2010;plane knee biomechanics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2018;53:135&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA, Lambros C. Development and preliminary validation of a scale to measure the psychological impact of returning to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Phys Ther Sport. 2008;9:9&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Nagelli CV, Hewett TE, Feller JA. Factors associated with psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46:1545&#x2013;1550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuk EF, Kim S, Burland JP, Glaviano NR. The comparison of psychological barriers between individuals with a history of anterior knee pain, anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, and healthy individuals. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18:92&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>