<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41244367</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-3121</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SAGE open medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SAGE Open Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ameliorative effects of multiple bedside-assisted exercise on the rehabilitation of mechanically ventilated patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20503121251377284</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20503121251377284</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20503121251377284</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20503121251377284</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Early exercise is beneficial for mechanically ventilated intensive care unit patients. However, there remains a paucity of research data on the pattern of early assisted exercise delivery and the role of active and passive exercise modalities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Herein, we collected 349 mechanically ventilated patients admitted to the intensive care unit of Tianjin First Central Hospital from April 2020 to 2022 and divided them into a control group (176 patients) and an exercise intervention group (173 patients) according to whether or not early rehabilitative exercise was performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results showed that the maximum negative inspiratory pressure, rapid shallow breathing index, limb muscle strength, swelling index, some clinical physicochemical indexes, the number of days of endotracheal intubation, the use of sedative and analgesic drugs, the duration of delirium, and the final prognosis of patients in the intervention group were all improved to different degrees. Subgroup analyses showed that compound and active movement patterns were more conducive to the recovery of limb muscle strength than single assisted movement patterns, but faced higher consumption of sedative and analgesic drugs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our results suggest that early bedside-assisted exercise is beneficial, but still needs to be matched appropriately to the patient's condition in order to maximize the patient's prognosis. Our study provides valuable data to support subsequent clinical practice of early bedside-assisted training and the establishment of relevant guidelines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Zhu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongjie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xiubao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Hua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1595-8143</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Tianjin First Central Hospital, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SAGE Open Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-3121</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bedside-assisted exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">development and prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intensive care unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41244367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12612515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121251377284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20503121251377284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Taran S, Coiffard B, Huszti E, et al. Association of days alive and at home at day 90 after intensive care unit admission with long-term survival and functional status among mechanically ventilated patients. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6(3): e233265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36929399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari NK, Fowler RA, Bhagwanjee S, et al. Critical care and the global burden of critical illness in adults. Lancet 2010; 376(9749): 1339&#x2013;1346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7136988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsen M-MW, Holm A, Kvande ME, et al. Communication with mechanically ventilated patients in intensive care units: a concept analysis. J Adv Nurs 2023; 79(2): 563&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36443915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaber S, De Jong A. Weaning from mechanical ventilation in intensive care units: a call for new international consensus guidelines. Lancet Respir Med 2023; 11(5): 398&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36693399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilbur J, Rockafellow J, Shian B. Post-ICU care in the outpatient setting. Am Fam Physician 2021; 103(10): 590&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puthucheary ZA, Rawal J, McPhail M, et al. Acute skeletal muscle wasting in critical illness. JAMA 2013; 310(15): 1591&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmkuhl L, Dreyer P, Laerkner E, et al. Getting the body back on track &#x2013; Understanding the phenomenon of mobilisation when conscious and mechanically ventilated patients are mobilised in the intensive care unit. Intensive Crit Care Nurs 2023; 78: 103450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37172466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Hirasawa J, Naito Y, et al. Association between the early mobilization of mechanically ventilated patients and independence in activities of daily living at hospital discharge. Sci Rep 2023; 13(1): 4265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10015081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36918635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szymkowicz E, Bodet-Contentin L, Marechal Y, et al. Comparison of communication interfaces for mechanically ventilated patients in intensive care. Intensive Crit Care Nurs 2024; 80; 103562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson CL, Bailey M, Bellomo R, et al. Early active mobilization during mechanical ventilation in the ICU. N Engl J Med 2022; 387(19): 1747&#x2013;1758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36286256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayambu G, Boots R, Paratz J. Early physical rehabilitation in intensive care patients with sepsis syndromes: a pilot randomised controlled trial. Intensive Care Med 2015; 41(5): 865&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25851383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Hua Y, Wang L, et al. The effects of early mobilization in mechanically ventilated adult ICU patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023; 10: 1202754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37448799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan X-Y, Zhang J, Xu P, et al. Early passive orthostatic training prevents diaphragm atrophy and dysfunction in intensive care unit patients on mechanical ventilation: a retrospective case-control study. Heart Lung 2023; 59: 37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36709529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nydahl P, Jeitziner MM, Vater V, et al. Early mobilisation for prevention and treatment of delirium in critically ill patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. Intensive Crit Care Nurs 2023; 74: 103334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37440187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nydahl P, Sricharoenchai T, Chandra S, et al. Safety of patient mobilization and rehabilitation in the intensive care unit. systematic review with meta-analysis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017; 14(5): 766&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28231030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R-Y, Yeh H-J, Chang K-J, et al. Effects of different types and frequencies of early rehabilitation on ventilator weaning among patients in intensive care units: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 2023; 18(4): e0284923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10124886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37093879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmkuhl L, Olsen HT, Br&#xf8;nd JC, et al. Daily variation in physical activity during mechanical ventilation and stay in the intensive care unit. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand 2023; 67(4): 462&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton M, Chan S, Serpa Neto A, et al. Association of active mobilisation variables with adverse events and mortality in patients requiring mechanical ventilation in the intensive care unit: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Respir Med 2024; 12(5): 386&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38513675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenbroucke JP, von Elm E, Altman DG, et al. Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE): explanation and elaboration. Int J Surg 2014; 12(12): 1500&#x2013;1524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25046751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quickfall D, Sklar MC, Tomlinson G, et al. The influence of drugs used for sedation during mechanical ventilation on respiratory pattern during unassisted breathing and assisted mechanical ventilation: a physiological systematic review and meta-analysis. eClin Med 2024; 68: 102417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38235422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez L, Brennan K, Karim S, et al. Disease characteristics, clinical management, and outcomes of young patients with colon cancer: a population-based study. Clin Colorectal Cancer 2018; 17(4): e651&#x2013;e661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30061036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahu A, Banna S, Applefeld W, et al. Liberation from mechanical ventilation in the cardiac intensive care unit. JACC Adv 2023; 2(1): 100173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11198553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38939038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanne Elliot Z, Charlton Elliot S. An overview of mechanical ventilation in the intensive care unit. Nurs Stand 2018; 32(28): 41&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qie X-J, Liu Z-H, Guo L-M. Evaluation of progressive early rehabilitation training mode in intensive care unit patients with mechanical ventilation. World J Clin Cases 2022; 10(23): 8152&#x2013;8160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang K, Chen B, Wang M, et al. The effect of early mobilization in critically ill patients: a meta-analysis. Nurs Crit Care 2020; 25(6): 360&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31219229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaller SJ, Anstey M, Blobner M, et al. Early, goal-directed mobilisation in the surgical intensive care unit: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2016; 388(10052): 1377&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipping CJ, Harrold M, Holland A, et al. The effects of active mobilisation and rehabilitation in ICU on mortality and function: a systematic review. Intensive Care Med 2017; 43(2): 171&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27864615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin JW, Skrobik Y, G&#xe9;linas C, et al. Practice guidelines for the prevention and management of pain, agitation/sedation, delirium, immobility, and sleep disruption in adult patients in the ICU. Crit Care Med 2018; 46(9): e825&#x2013;e873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweickert WD, Patel BK, Kress JP. Timing of early mobilization to optimize outcomes in mechanically ventilated ICU patients. Intensive Care Med 2022; 48(10): 1305&#x2013;1307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10139766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35925320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho ME, Berney S, Connolly B. Physical rehabilitation in the intensive care unit: past, present, and future. Intensive Care Med 2023; 49(7): 864&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweickert WD, Pohlman MC, Pohlman AS, et al. Early physical and occupational therapy in mechanically ventilated, critically ill patients: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2009; 373(9678): 1874&#x2013;1882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Wang F, Dong R, et al. Efficacy and safety of remimazolam tosilate combined with esketamine for analgesic sedation in mechanically ventilated ICU patients: a single-arm clinical study protocol. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9: 832105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willgress L, Sava D, Daniels R, et al. Sedation and analgesia practices for less invasive surfactant administration, elective endotracheal intubation, and mechanical ventilation: a national UK survey. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed 2024; 110(1): 113&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39043557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolesta S, Burry L, Perreault MM, et al. International analgesia and sedation weaning and withdrawal practices in critically ill adults: the adult iatrogenic withdrawal study in the ICU. Crit Care Med 2023; 51(11): 1502&#x2013;1514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37283558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payen JF, Chanques G, Mantz J, et al. Current practices in sedation and analgesia for mechanically ventilated critically ill patients: a prospective multicenter patient-based study. Anesthesiology 2007; 106(4): 687&#x2013;895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel BK, Wolfe KS, Patel SB, et al. Effect of early mobilisation on long-term cognitive impairment in critical illness in the USA: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med 2023; 11(6): 563&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10238598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36693400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashem MD, Nelliot A, Needham DM. Early mobilization and rehabilitation in the ICU: moving back to the future. Respir Care 2016; 61(7): 971&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27094396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarissa C, Salisbury L, Rodgers S, et al. Early mobilisation in mechanically ventilated patients: a systematic integrative review of definitions and activities. J Intensive Care 2019; 7: 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6337811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30680218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>