<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41408395</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimization design and experimental verification of magnetic pulse spot welding system of dissimilar metal sheets based on a field shaper.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3228</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3228</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3228</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33063-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Magnetic pulse welding based on a field shaper using a single-turn multi-layer flat coil and enhancing the magnetic field in local areas with the field shaper can achieve point welding of metal sheets, with broad application prospects in dissimilar metal welding. By reasonably optimizing the structural parameters of the flat coil and the field shaper, the magnetic field strength and eddy current density in the local area can be effectively improved, thereby increasing the Lorentz force to improve the collision speed of the sheet, and ultimately improving the welding quality of the sheets. In view of this, the goal of this work was to maximize magnetic pressure, optimize the structural parameters of the flat coil and field shaper, and innovatively propose a new type of field shaper with an arc-shaped hole structure, which effectively improved the welding quality without changing the welding energy. Furthermore, a magnetic pulse spot welding (MPSW) experimental platform was built using the optimized magnet device, achieving the spot welding of AA1060 aluminum sheets and stainless steel (SS304) sheets both with a thickness of 1&#xa0;mm. Through peeling and stretching experiments, it was proven that the strength of the welded joint exceeded that of the base metal, indicating that the effective welding of dissimilar metals has been achieved. In addition, through microscopic analysis, it could be seen that a waveform composite interface was formed at the welding interface, which further indicated that the welding performance of the welded joint was good. The results indicated that the use of the new field shaper with an arc-shaped hole structure could reduce the critical discharge voltage for effective welding by 2&#xa0;kV, directly converting it into lower energy consumption requirements and a wider process window, which had important economic value for industrial applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy Engineering, Huanghuai University, Zhumadian, 463000, People's Republic of China. zhanghang@huanghuai.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National High Magnetic Field Center, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Hongfa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National High Magnetic Field Center, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, People's Republic of China. dhf@hust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>25B430016</GrantID><Agency>Henan Provincial Science and Technology Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arc-shaped hole</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Field shaper</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic pulse welding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Single-turn multi-layer flat coil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wavy composite interface</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12830595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33063-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33063-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gavel, K. S. et al. A novel tool design for magnetic pulse welding of sheet metal using compression coil. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>144</b>, 261&#x2013;277 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2025.03.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang, H. &amp; Yu, H. Improving the quality of Al-Fe tube joints manufactured via magnetic pulse welding using an inclined-wall field shaper. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>73</b>, 78&#x2013;89 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.10.054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lueg-Althoff, J., Bellmann, J., Hahn, M., Schulze, S. &amp; Beyer, E. Joining dissimilar Thin-Walled tubes by magnetic pulse welding. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech.</i><b>279</b>, 116562 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2019.116562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. A novel actuator for precise design of the spatial-distributed Lorentz force in electromagnetic sheet metal forming: process principle, optimization methodology, and experimental validation. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Tech.</i><b>131</b>, 4425&#x2013;4445 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-13271-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Peng, W., Chen, Y., Liu, W. &amp; Zhang, H. Simulation and experimental analysis of Al/Ti plate magnetic pulse welding based on multi-seams coil. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>83</b>, 290&#x2013;299 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2022.09.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. et al. A novel electromagnetic forming actuator for curved sheet forming: analytical optimization, simulation, and experimental validation. <i>Int. Int J. Adv. Manuf. Tech</i>. <b>139</b>, 485&#x2013;501 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-025-15873-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, J. et al. Interfacial microstructure and mechanical properties of the Al/Ti joint by magnetic pulse welding. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>194</b>, 112462 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Relaxation of residual stress in aluminum alloy rings by pulsed high magnetic field: relieving mechanisms and performance evaluation. <i>J Mater. Process. Tech</i><b>338, </b>118778 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvari, M., Abdollah-Zadeh, A. &amp; Naffakh-Moosavy, H. Investigation of variations of metallurgical and morphological phenomena of interface in the magnetic pulse welding of Al&#x2013;Cu. <i>J. Mater. Res. Technol.</i><b>36</b>, 448&#x2013;458 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.03.093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Z. et al. Interfacial microstructure and local bonding strength of magnetic pulse welding joint between commercially pure aluminum 1060 and AISI 304 stainless steel. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>46</b>, 59&#x2013;66 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2019.07.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. et al. Mechanical properties and joining mechanisms of Al-Fe magnetic pulse welding by spot form for automotive application. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>76</b>, 504&#x2013;517 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2022.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, H., Jiang, X. &amp; Zhang, M. An innovative coil for magnetic pulse welding of dissimilar sheet metals: numerical simulation and experiments. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech.</i><b>324</b>, 118230 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2023.118230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Z. et al. Magnetic pulse welding of aluminum to steel tubes using a field-shaper with multiple seams. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>65</b>, 214&#x2013;227 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.03.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoelison, R. N. et al. Gradient of nanostructures at the interface of Al/Cu welded joints produced by the high strain-rate collision during magnetic pulse impact welding. <i>Journal Alloys Metall. Systems</i><b>5</b>, 100060 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. et al. Bonding and microstructure evolution in electromagnetic pulse welding of hardenable al alloys. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech.</i><b>290</b>, 116965 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoelison, R. N. et al. Effect of the nanopores in the Al-Cu intermetallic phase on nanoindentation instabilities at the Al/Cu interface of a magnetic pulse impact weld. <i>Materialia</i><b>32</b>, 101955 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtla.2023.101955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shotri, R., Racineux, G. &amp; De, A. Probing magnetic pulse welding of aluminium and steel sheets. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>72</b>, 309&#x2013;319 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.10.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Luo, K., Sun, T., Li, G. &amp; Cui, J. Corrosion behavior and failure mechanism of electromagnetic pulse welded joints between galvanized steel and aluminum alloy sheets. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>64</b>, 937&#x2013;947 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.02.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Mechanical properties and interfacial microstructures of magnetic pulse welding joints with aluminum to zinc-coated steel. <i>Mat. Sci. Eng. A-Struct</i>. <b>788</b>, 139425 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2020.139425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huihui, G., Jingqi, M., Xu, Z., Guangyao, L. &amp; Junjia, C. Strain rate sensitivity of Al-Fe magnetic pulse welds. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech.</i><b>262</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Ding, H., Li, X. &amp; Cao, Q. A new method of magnetic pulse welding of dissimilar metal plates using a uniform pressure electromagnetic actuator based on pre-deformation. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thibaudeau, E. &amp; Kinsey, B. L. Analytical design and experimental validation of uniform pressure actuator for electromagnetic forming and welding. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech.</i><b>215</b>, 251&#x2013;263 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2014.08.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Liu, N., Li, X., Wang, Q. &amp; Ding, H. Optimization design and experimental research of magnetic pulse welding system based on uniform pressure electromagnetic actuator. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Tech.</i><b>121</b>, 8447&#x2013;8465 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-022-09797-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, X., Yu, H. &amp; Li, H. Optimization of novel coil structure parameters for controlling Al/Fe magnetic pulse welding process. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>134</b>, 117&#x2013;134 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2024.12.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoelison, R. N., Sapanathan, T., Buiron, N. &amp; Rachik, M. Magnetic pulse welding of Al/Al and Al/Cu metal pairs: consequences of the dissimilar combination on the interfacial behavior during the welding process. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>20</b>, 112&#x2013;127 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2015.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Magnetic pulse welding of large-diameter aluminum-steel dissimilar metal tubes: actuator design, welding process, and mechanism. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Tech.</i><b>139</b>, 1343&#x2013;1361 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-025-15912-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, J. et al. Magnetic pulse welding of high-strength aluminum alloy with enhanced Lorentz force via novel hollow field shaper. <i>J. Mater. Process. Tech</i>. ;339(2025). (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joern, L. A. et al. Influence of the flyer kinetics on magnetic pulse welding of tubes. <b>J Mater. Process. Tech. 262, 189-203</b> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Li, X., Cao, Q. &amp; Ding, H. Field shaper-based solutions to the bulging problem in magnetic pulse spot welding of dissimilar metal plates. <i>Sci Rep</i><b>14</b>, 29418 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11599714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39592822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y. et al. Investigation of flyer plate dynamic behavior in electromagnetic pulse welding. <i>J Manuf Process</i>. <b>68</b>, 189&#x2013;197 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.07.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, H., Xia, Z., Zhang, X., Li, G. &amp; Cui, J. Microstructures and mechanical properties of the welded AA5182/HC340LA joint by magnetic pulse welding. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>138</b>, 229&#x2013;237 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2018.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fangxiong, D., Quanliang, C., Xiaotao, H. &amp; Liang, L. Electromagnetic pulse spot welding of aluminum to stainless steel sheets with a field shaper. <i>Int J. Adv. Manuf. Tech.</i><b>98</b>, 1903-1911 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. H., Kim, D. &amp; Lee, M. Experimental and numerical analysis of a rectangular helical coil actuator for electromagnetic bulging. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Tech.</i><b>78</b> (5-8), 825&#x2013;839 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-014-6680-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manurung, Y. H. <i>Suhaila Abd Halim, and Low Cheng Yee. Fundamentals of Artificial Neural Network for Manufacturing Engineer Using Python Language with Gui Development</i> (and Executable Conversion(Penerbit UTHM, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, N. et al. Optimization and modeling of spot welding parameters with simultaneous multiple response consideration using multi-objective Taguchi method and RSM. <i>J. Mech. Sci. Technol.</i><b>26</b> (8), 2365&#x2013;2370 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12206-012-0618-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, N. et al. Model development for quality features of resistance spot welding using multi-objective Taguchi method and response surface methodology. <i>J. Intell. Manuf.</i><b>24</b> (6), 1175&#x2013;1183 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-012-0648-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd Halim, S. et al. Quality prediction and classification of resistance spot weld using artificial neural network with open-sourced, self-executable and GUI-based application tool Q-Check. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 3013 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-29906-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36810419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>