<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41444277</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Targeted exercise improves functional movement performance and alters movement screening relationships in females with flexible flatfeet.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>44472</StartPage><MedlinePgn>44472</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">44472</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-28174-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Flatfeet are a common condition associated with altered foot biomechanics, leading to potential functional limitations and increased risk of musculoskeletal injuries. This condition disrupts the kinetic chain, impacting proximal segments such as the core and hips, which are crucial for maintaining stability, balance, and agility. While various interventions have been explored, the role of generalized lower-extremity strengthening programs, such as calisthenics, in addressing these functional deficits is not well-established. This study investigated the impact of a 16-week calisthenics program on functional movement, core strength, balance, and agility in female university students with and without flexible flatfeet. We aimed to assess whether this generalized strengthening intervention could improve these key performance metrics and whether the relationship between Functional Movement Screen (FMS) scores and other functional measures differed between the two groups. The study also explored the correlation between FMS scores and other measures of performance in these two distinct groups. A total of 96 female university students (25 with flexible flatfeet, 71 with normal feet) participated in a 16-week calisthenics program. Assessments included FMS, core strength (partial curl-up, plank), balance (Sharpened Romberg, Y-balance test), and agility (4&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;9-m shuttle run). Statistical analyses included non-parametric tests to assess within-group changes and between-group differences, as well as correlation and regression analyses to explore the relationship between FMS scores and performance variables. Both groups showed significant improvements in FMS scores, core strength, balance, and agility following the intervention. In the normal feet group, FMS scores correlated positively with core strength, static balance, and dynamic balance; conversely, these correlations were not observed in the flexible flatfeet group, suggesting a potential influence of altered biomechanics on the relationship between FMS and performance. While a generalized calisthenics-based training program yields significant improvements in functional movement capabilities, core stabilization, equilibrium, and rapid directional changes in both cohorts, the association between FMS metrics and other performance variables differed in individuals presenting with flexible flatfeet. This variation suggests that functional movement in this population is modulated by factors beyond those typically assessed by FMS, potentially due to the unique biomechanical adaptations induced by flatfeet. Therefore, a deeper understanding of the physiological responses to generalized training in individuals with flatfeet is imperative for the creation of targeted interventions to enhance movement efficiency and performance results. The lack of correlation in this group suggests that further research is needed before generalizing these findings to a broader population. Clinical Trials Registration IRCT20130109012078N8: Registered 2023-02-03, Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT); IRCT20130109012078N7: Registered 2023-01-19, Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ghorbani</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Kharazmi University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yaali</LastName><ForeName>Rasoul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8159-4570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Motor Behavior, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Kharazmi University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran. r.yaali@khu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sadeghi</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomechanics and Sports Injuries, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Kharazmi University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005528" MajorTopicYN="Y">Foot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009068" MajorTopicYN="N">Movement</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calisthenics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Core strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flatfeet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional Movement Screen (FMS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lower-extremity strengthening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study obtained ethical clearance from the Sport Sciences Research Institute. Prior to participation, all students were informed about the study&#x2019;s objectives, and written and verbal informed consent was obtained from each participant. Clinical trials registration: For the registration of this clinical trial, the trial registration numbers are IRCT20130109012078N8 and IRCT20130109012078N7, which were obtained from the Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT). IRCT20130109012078N8 Registered 2023&#x2013;02-03, Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT), https://irct.behdasht.gov.ir/ IRCT20130109012078N7 Registered 2023&#x2013;01-19, Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT), https://irct.behdasht.gov.ir/ Consent for publication: We give our consent for the publication of identifiable details, which can include details within the text (&#x201c;Material&#x201d;) to be published in the above Journal and Article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41444277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12739119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-28174-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-28174-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Page, P., Frank, C. C. &amp; Lardner, R. Assessment and treatment of muscle imbalance. (No Title). 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X., Gu, Y., Yu, J., Ma, Y. &amp; Zhou, Z. Do arch height and arch stiffness relate to physical performance in adult men?. <i>J. Foot Ankle Surg.</i><b>61</b>(2), 259&#x2013;263 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jfas.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34353731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan, M. T. &amp; Staheli, L. T. Arch height and lower limb pain: An adult civilian study. <i>Foot Ankle Int.</i><b>23</b>(1), 43&#x2013;47 (2002).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/107110070202300108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pita-Fernandez, S. et al. Flat foot in a random population and its impact on quality of life and functionality. <i>J. Clin. Diagn. Res. JCDR</i><b>11</b>(4), LC22 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5449819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28571173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dare, N., Onyije, F. &amp; Osoma, S. Pes planus (flatfoot) in male and female adults of Bayelsa-Nigeria. <i>Electron. J. Biomed.</i><b>3</b>, 17&#x2013;21 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer, M., Kotz, R., Ledl, T., Hauser, G. &amp; Sluga, M. Prevalence of flat foot in preschool-aged children. <i>Pediatrics</i><b>118</b>(2), 634&#x2013;639 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2005-2126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, L.-C., Yu, B., Mercer, V. S. &amp; Gross, M. T. Comparison of different structural foot types for measures of standing postural control. <i>J. Orthop. Sports Phys. Ther.</i><b>36</b>(12), 942&#x2013;953 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2006.2336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17193872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffetone, P. The assessment and treatment of muscular imbalance&#x2013;The janda approach. <i>J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther.</i><b>14</b>(3), 287&#x2013;288 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2009.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothari, A., Dixon, P., Stebbins, J., Zavatsky, A. &amp; Theologis, T. Are flexible flat feet associated with proximal joint problems in children?. <i>Gait Posture</i><b>45</b>, 204&#x2013;210 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2016.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26979907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamis, S. &amp; Yizhar, Z. Effect of feet hyperpronation on pelvic alignment in a standing position. <i>Gait Posture</i><b>25</b>(1), 127&#x2013;134 (2007).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2006.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price J. The BioMechanics Method for Corrective Exercise: Human Kinetics; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izraelski, J. Assessment and treatment of muscle imbalance: The janda approach. <i>J. Can Chiropr. Assoc.</i><b>56</b>(2), 158 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menz, H. B., Morris, M. E. &amp; Lord, S. R. Foot and ankle risk factors for falls in older people: A prospective study. <i>J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci.</i><b>61</b>(8), 866&#x2013;870 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/61.8.866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frances, J. M. &amp; Feldman, D. S. Management of idiopathic and nonidiopathic flatfoot. <i>Instr. Course Lect.</i><b>64</b>, 429&#x2013;440 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25745926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demetracopoulos, C. A., Nair, P., Malzberg, A. &amp; Deland, J. T. Outcomes of a stepcut lengthening calcaneal osteotomy for adult-acquired flatfoot deformity. <i>Foot Ankle Int.</i><b>36</b>(7), 749&#x2013;755 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1071100715574933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domaradzki, J. &amp; Ko&#x17a;lenia, D. Clustered associations between Musculoskeletal Fitness Tests and Functional Movement Screen in physically active men. <i>Biomed. Res. Int.</i><b>2023</b>(1), 5942329 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/5942329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9940965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36814800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sortwell, A. et al. Associations between fundamental movement skills, muscular fitness, self-perception and physical activity in primary school students. <i>J. Funct. Morphol. Kinesiol.</i><b>9</b>(4), 272 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9040272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11679965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39728256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, U. H., Johnson, A. W. &amp; Adamson, B. Relationship between functional movement screen scores, core strength, posture, and body mass index in school children in Moldova. <i>J. Strength Cond. Res.</i><b>29</b>(5), 1172&#x2013;1179 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukprasert, O. et al. Effects of foot muscle exercise on hard and elastic surfaces in persons with low-arched feet. <i>Suranaree J Sci Technol.</i><b>29</b>, 0700421&#x2013;0700427 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, E.-K. &amp; Kim, J. S. The effects of short foot exercises and arch support insoles on improvement in the medial longitudinal arch and dynamic balance of flexible flatfoot patients. <i>J. Phys. Ther. Sci.</i><b>28</b>(11), 3136&#x2013;3139 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.28.3136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5140815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27942135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulligan, E. P. &amp; Cook, P. G. Effect of plantar intrinsic muscle training on medial longitudinal arch morphology and dynamic function. <i>Man. Ther.</i><b>18</b>(5), 425&#x2013;430 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.math.2013.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23632367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, D.-b &amp; Choi, J.-d. The effects of foot intrinsic muscle and tibialis posterior strengthening exercise on plantar pressure and dynamic balance in adults flexible pes planus. <i>Phys. Ther. Korea.</i><b>23</b>(4), 27&#x2013;37 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12674/ptk.2016.23.4.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murley, G. S., Menz, H. B. &amp; Landorf, K. B. Foot posture influences the electromyographic activity of selected lower limb muscles during gait. <i>J. Foot Ankle Res.</i><b>2</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2009).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1757-1146-2-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2788543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19939283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goo, Y.-M., Kim, T.-H. &amp; Lim, J.-Y. The effects of gluteus maximus and abductor hallucis strengthening exercises for four weeks on navicular drop and lower extremity muscle activity during gait with flatfoot. <i>J. Phys. Ther. Sci.</i><b>28</b>(3), 911&#x2013;915 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.28.911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4842464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27134383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsak, B. et al. Effects of a lower extremity exercise program on gait biomechanics and clinical outcomes in children and adolescents with obesity: A randomized controlled trial. <i>Gait Posture</i><b>70</b>, 122&#x2013;129 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2019.02.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30851623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engkananuwat, P. &amp; Kanlayanaphotporn, R. Comparisons between lower-extremity strengthening exercises and foot orthoses for improving medial longitudinal arch height in individuals with flexible flat foot: An 8-week randomised clinical trial <i>Physiother. Q.</i> 33(2) (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinpeerasathian, C., Sin Oo, P., Siriphorn, A. &amp; Pensri, P. Effect of foot orthoses on balance among individuals with flatfoot: A systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>PLoS ONE</i><b>19</b>(3), e0299446 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0299446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10923465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, R. <i>Effect of pilates, calisthenics and combined exercises on selected physical motor fitness</i> (Pondicherry University, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, R., Sakthignanavel, D. &amp; Singh, V. Effect of pilates exercise, calisthenics exercise and combination of pilates and calisthenics exercise on flexibility &amp; strength of school boys. <i>Int. J. Manag. Econ. Soc. Sci.</i><b>2</b>(2), 75&#x2013;77 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;, H. &amp; Gen&#xe7;, H. Effect of the calisthenics exercises on static and dynamic balance in tennis players. <i>Int. J. Appl. Exerc. Physiol.</i> 9 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panihar, U. &amp; Rani D. The effect of calisthenics training on physical fitness parameters and sports specific skills of soccer players: A randomized controlled trial. <i>Adv. Rehab</i>. <b>36</b>(1) (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurudut, P., Welling, A. A. &amp; Naik, R. Comparative effect of calisthenic and proprioceptive exercises on pain, proprioception, balance and function in chronic osteoarthritis of knee. <i>J. Exerc. Sci. Physiother.</i><b>14</b>(2) (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrader, J. A., Popovich, J. M. Jr., Gracey, G. C. &amp; Danoff, J. V. Navicular drop measurement in people with rheumatoid arthritis: Interrater and intrarater reliability. <i>Phys. Ther.</i><b>85</b>(7), 656&#x2013;664 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/85.7.656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15982172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuil-Escobar, J. C., Mart&#xed;nez-Cepa, C. B., Mart&#xed;n-Urrialde, J. A. &amp; G&#xf3;mez-Conesa, A. Medial longitudinal arch: Accuracy, reliability, and correlation between navicular drop test and footprint parameters. <i>J. Manip. Physiol. Ther.</i><b>41</b>(8), 672&#x2013;679 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmpt.2018.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30573198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. S. &amp; Lee M. Y. The effect of short foot exercise using visual feedback on the balance and accuracy of knee joint movement in subjects with flexible flatfoot Medicine <b>99</b>(13) (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7220527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayati, R., Fatemi, E., Hajihasani, A., Ehsani, F. &amp; Ramezanpour S. The attention needed for balance controlling in young patients with flatfoot <i>Koomesh</i> 25&#x2013;34 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozcan Kahraman, B., Salik Sengul, Y., Kahraman, T. &amp; Kalemci, O. Developing a reliable core stability assessment battery for patients with nonspecific low back pain. <i>Spine</i><b>41</b>(14), E844&#x2013;E850 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BRS.0000000000001403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26679886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidney, K. &amp; Jett&#xe9;, M. The partial curl-up to assess abdominal endurance: Age and sex standards. <i>Res. Sports Med. Int. J.</i><b>2</b>(1), 47&#x2013;56 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurson, K. R. Baptista, F. Mahar, M. T., Welk, G. J. &amp; Janz, K. F. Designing health-referenced standards for the plank test of core muscular endurance <i>Meas. Phys. Educ. Exerc. Sci.</i> 1&#x2013;8 (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yim-Chiplis, P. K. &amp; Talbot, L. A. Defining and measuring balance in adults. <i>Biol. Res. Nurs.</i><b>1</b>(4), 321&#x2013;331 (2000).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/109980040000100408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11232210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisky, P. J., Rauh, M. J., Kaminski, T. W. &amp; Underwood, F. B. Star excursion balance test as a predictor of lower extremity injury in high school basketball players. <i>J. Orthop. Sports Phys. Ther.</i><b>36</b>(12), 911&#x2013;919 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2006.2244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17193868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhlouf, I. et al. Combination of agility and plyometric training provides similar training benefits as combined balance and plyometric training in young soccer players. <i>Front. Physiol.</i><b>9</b>, 1611 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.01611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, G., Burton, L. &amp; Hoogenboom, B. Pre-participation screening: The use of fundamental movements as an assessment of function&#x2013;Part 2. <i>North Am. J. Sports Phys. Ther. NAJSPT.</i><b>1</b>(3), 132 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, G., Burton, L. &amp; Hoogenboom, B. Pre-participation screening: The use of fundamental movements as an assessment of function&#x2013;part 1. <i>North Am. J. Sports Phys. Ther. NAJSPT.</i><b>1</b>(2), 62 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everard, E. M., Harrison, A. J. &amp; Lyons, M. Examining the relationship between the functional movement screen and the landing error scoring system in an active, male collegiate population. <i>J. Strength Cond. Res.</i><b>31</b>(5), 1265&#x2013;1272 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori G, Medicine ACoS. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy, K. L. &amp; Troiano, R. P. Physical activity guidelines for Americans from the US department of health and human services: Cardiovascular benefits and recommendations. <i>Circ. Cardiovasc. Qual. Outcomes</i><b>11</b>(11), e005263 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.118.005263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakinah, M. H. et al. The effect of 12-week calisthenics exercise on physical fitness among obese female students. <i>Phys. Educ. Theory Methodol.</i><b>22</b>(3s), S45&#x2013;S50 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17309/tmfv.2022.3s.06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elataar, F. F., Abdelmajeed, S. F., Abdellatif, N. M. &amp; Mohammed, M. M. Core muscles&#x2019; endurance in flexible flatfeet: A cross-sectional study. <i>J. Musculoskelet. Neuron. Interact.</i><b>20</b>(3), 404 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panihar, U. &amp; Rani D. The effect of calisthenics training on physical fitness parameters and sports specific skills of soccer players: A randomized controlled trial <i>Adv. Rehab</i>. <b>36</b>(2) (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukprasert, O., Boonyarom, O. &amp; Somthavil, S. Flexible flatfoot: Effects of foot muscle exercises on dynamic balance, plantar pressure, and muscle strength. <i>J. Health Res.</i><b>38</b>(1), 11&#x2013;19 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56808/2586-940X.1055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N. Strength training and conditioning (acsm&#x2019;s foundations). Usa: Indianapolis. (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton, J. D. et al. The effects of a novel quadrupedal movement training program on functional movement, range of motion, muscular strength, and endurance. <i>J. Strength Cond. Res.</i><b>36</b>(8), 2186&#x2013;2193 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33021583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcak, P. Differential effects of strength training volumes on functional movement screen&#x2122; performance in elite soccer players. <i>J. Phys. Educ. Sport.</i><b>24</b>(9), 1267&#x2013;1274 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campa, F., Spiga, F. &amp; Toselli, S. The effect of a 20-week corrective exercise program on functional movement patterns in youth elite male soccer players. <i>J. Sport Rehabil.</i><b>28</b>(7), 746&#x2013;751 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30222494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojic, F. et al. Implementation of an unstable surface exercise program in physical education curriculum: Effects on strength and morphological features. <i>Kinesiologia Slovenica.</i><b>28</b>(1), 19&#x2013;32 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52165/kinsi.28.1.19-32</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legerlotz, K., Marzilger, R., Bohm, S. &amp; Arampatzis, A. Physiological adaptations following resistance training in youth athletes&#x2014;A narrative review. <i>Pediatr. Exerc. Sci.</i><b>28</b>(4), 501&#x2013;520 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2016-0023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27705536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharrock, C., Cropper, J., Mostad, J., Johnson, M. &amp; Malone, T. A pilot study of core stability and athletic performance: Is there a relationship?. <i>Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther.</i><b>6</b>(2), 63 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21713228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mear, E., Gladwell, V. F. &amp; Pethick, J. The effect of breaking up sedentary time with calisthenics on neuromuscular function: A preliminary study. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</i><b>19</b>(21), 14597 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192114597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9653850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;z, A. K. &amp; &#x130;nce, P. T. The correlation between functional movement screen and core stabilization and y balance test in handball players. <i>J. Orthop. Res. Rehab.</i><b>1</b>(3), 52&#x2013;57 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anam, K. et al. Functional movement screen score to predict injury risk of sports students: A review of foot shape and body mass index. <i>Pedagogy Phys. Culture Sports.</i><b>28</b>(2), 124&#x2013;131 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/26649837.2024.0206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, S. C., Rowe, N. D., Adnan, M., Brown, S. M. &amp; Mulcahey, M. K. Effective interventions for improving functional movement screen scores among &#x201c;high-risk&#x201d; athletes: A systematic review. <i>Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther.</i><b>17</b>(2), 131 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.31001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8805097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35136681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>