<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41875017</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Validity and Reliability of an AI-Based Jump Height App vs. Infrared Contact Mat: Minimal Influence of Skin Pigmentation Under Standardized Lighting.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005433</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>R&#xed;os-Gallardo, PT, Carranza-Garc&#xed;a, LE, Dietze-Hermosa, M, Gonzalez, MP, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez, C, Dorgo, S, and Montalvo, S. Validity and reliability of an AI-based jump height app vs. infrared contact mat: minimal influence of skin pigmentation under standardized lighting. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-This study examined the validity, reliability, and visual robustness of an artificial intelligence-based mobile application (My Jump Lab) for measuring countermovement jump (CMJ) and squat jump (SJ) height across a heterogeneous athletic population. A dual-session, test-retest design was implemented with 43 recreationally active adults (age: 21.2 &#xb1; 2.4 years), who performed 3 maximal-effort SJ and CMJ trials per session. Jump height was concurrently recorded using a force platform and the AI-based app. Validity was assessed through linear regression and Bland-Altman analyses, and reliability was evaluated using intraclass correlation coefficients (ICC) and coefficient of variation (CV). A linear mixed-effects model tested whether body dimensions, lighting conditions, or skin pigmentation influenced AI accuracy. The AI systematically overestimated jump height (bias = +2.81 cm, p &lt; 0.001), yet showed excellent concurrent validity (R2 = 0.94), strong within-session reliability (ICC = 0.97; CV = 4.2%), and good between-session reliability (ICC = 0.89). Countermovement jump values were more consistent than SJ. No significant effects were observed for lighting or pigmentation (p &gt; 0.05). Although absolute error was higher in SJ, AI-based estimates remained stable across conditions. The level of significance was set at p &#x2264; 0.05. In conclusion, the AI-based app provides a valid and reliable alternative for field-based jump assessment. However, practitioners should interpret absolute values cautiously, especially for SJ. These findings support the utility of computer vision and AI to democratize biomechanical assessments without sacrificing measurement quality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xed;os-Gallardo</LastName><ForeName>Pablo Tadeo</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Organization, Autonomous University of Nuevo Leon, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carranza-Garc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>Luis Enrique</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Organization, Autonomous University of Nuevo Leon, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dietze-Hermosa</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Performance and Recreation, Brigham Young University Idaho, Rexburg, Idaho.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Matthew P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Biomechanics and Sports Technology Research Group, Autonomous University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorgo</LastName><ForeName>Sandor</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montalvo</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3104-3428</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wu Tsai Human Performance Alliance, Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computer vision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explosive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">individual typology angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">markless analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vertical jump</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41875017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aleksic J, Kanevsky D, Mesaro&#x161; D, et al. Validation of automated countermovement vertical jump analysis: Markerless pose estimation vs. 3D marker-based motion capture system. Sensors 24: 6624, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amd M. Intra-group differences in skin tone influence evaluative and perceptual face processing. PLoS One 19: e0296172, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andriluka M, Pishchulin L, Gehler P, Schiele B. 2D human pose estimation: New benchmark and state of the art analysis. In: 2014 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. Columbus, OH: Martinez A, Basri R, Vidal R, Fermuller C. eds. IEEE, 2014. pp. 3686&#x2013;3693. Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6909866. Accessed September 24, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Varela-Olalla D. The validity and reliability of the My Jump Lab app for the measurement of vertical jump performance using artificial intelligence. Sensors (Basel, Switz) 24: 7897, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Glaister M, Lockey RA. The validity and reliability of an iPhone app for measuring vertical jump performance. J Sports Sci 33: 1574&#x2013;1579, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C. Real time estimation of vertical jump height with a markerless motion capture smartphone app: A proof-of-concept case study. Proc Inst Mech Eng P J Sports Eng Technol. Published online February 14, 2024. doi:10.1177/17543371241227817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17543371241227817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Haim Y, Saidel T, Yovel G, et al. The role of skin colour in face recognition. Perception 38: 145&#x2013;148, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A simple method for measurement of mechanical power in jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 50: 273&#x2013;282, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae HJ, Kim J-B, Park G, et al. An artificial intelligence exercise coaching Mobile app: Development and randomized controlled trial to verify its effectiveness in posture correction. Int J Med Res 12: e37604, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu C-Y, Chang C-C, Chiang Y-C, Chiang C-Y. Automatic video analysis of countermovement jump performance using a single uncalibrated camera. J Biomech 186: 112695, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citing RStudio. Posit Support, 2024. Available at: https://support.posit.co/hc/en-us/articles/206212048-Citing-RStudio.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colyer SL, Evans M, Cosker DP, Salo AIT. A review of the evolution of vision-based motion analysis and the integration of advanced computer vision methods towards developing a markerless system. Sports Med Open 4: 24, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x105;browska AK, Adlhart C, Spano F, et al. In vivo confirmation of hydration-induced changes in human-skin thickness, roughness and interaction with the environment. Biointerphases 11: 031015, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Bino S, Bernerd F. Variations in skin colour and the biological consequences of ultraviolet radiation exposure. Br J Dermatol 169: 33&#x2013;40, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Bino S, Duval C, Bernerd F, et al. Clinical and biological characterization of skin pigmentation diversity and its consequences on UV impact. Int J Mol Sci 19: 2668, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietze-Hermosa M, Montalvo S, Gonzalez MP, Rodriguez S, Cubillos NR, Dorgo S. Association and predictive ability of jump performance with sprint profile of collegiate track and field athletes. Sports Biomech 23: 2137&#x2013;2156, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorgo S, Perales JJ, Boyle JB, Hausselle J, Montalvo S. Sprint training on a treadmill vs. overground results in modality-specific impact on sprint performance but similar positive improvement in body composition in young adults. J Strength Cond Res 34: 463&#x2013;472, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everett JS, Budescu M, Sommers MS, et al. Making sense of skin color in clinical care. Clin Nurs Res 21: 495&#x2013;516, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feij&#xf3; Da Rocha E, Orssatto LBR, Diefenthaeler F, Dellagrana R. Jump height with smartphone apps&#x2014;Reliability and agreement with standard methods: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Strength Cond J 47: 211&#x2013;219, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo-Fuentes F, Gallardo-Fuentes J, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, et al. Intersession and intrasession reliability and validity of the My Jump App for measuring different jump actions in trained male and female athletes. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2049&#x2013;2056, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves C, Baptista R, Tufano J, Blazevich AJ, Vieira A. Error in jump height estimation using the flight time method: Simulation of the effect of ankle position between takeoff and landing. PeerJ 12: e17704, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilmersson M, Edvardsson I, Tornberg &#xc5;B, et al. Power of counter movement jumps with external load&#x2014;Coherence of three assessment methods. BMC Res Notes 8: 156, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linkert M, Rueden CT, Allan C, et al. Metadata matters: Access to image data in the real world. J Cell Biol 189: 777&#x2013;782, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne NP. Analysis of standing vertical jumps using a force platform. Am J Phys 69: 1198&#x2013;1204, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewen AM, Olander HL, Carlos C Jr, Ulman S. A comparison between manual and automated event detection for a drop vertical jump task using motion capture. Clin Biomech 113: 106220, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Dizdar D, Jukic I, Cardinale M. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. J Strength Cond Res 18: 551&#x2013;555, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta S, Abdolhosseini F, Rastegari M, et al. CVNets: High Performance Library for Computer Vision. Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Multimedia (MM &#x2019;22). New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo S, Gonzalez MP, Dietze-Hermosa MS, Eggleston JD, Dorgo S. Common vertical jump and reactive strength index measuring devices: A validity and reliability analysis. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1234&#x2013;1243, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo S, Gonzalez MP, Dietze-Hermosa MS, et al. Effects of different stretching modalities on the antagonist and agonist muscles on isokinetic strength and vertical jump performance in young men. J Strength Cond Res 39: 173&#x2013;183, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik BT, Hashmi MF, Bokde ND. A comprehensive review of computer vision in sports: Open issues, future trends and research directions. Appl Sci 12: 4429, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassis GP, Verhagen E, Brito J, Figueiredo P, Krustrup P. A review of machine learning applications in soccer with an emphasis on injury risk. Biol Sport 40: 233&#x2013;239, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nibali ML, Tombleson T, Brady PH, Wagner P. Influence of familiarization and competitive level on the reliability of countermovement vertical jump kinetic and kinematic variables. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2827&#x2013;2835, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulji&#x107; D, Karavas C, Mandroukas A, Stafylidis A. Validity of the enode sensor and My Jump 3 App for assessing countermovement jump performance. Appl Sci 14: 11989, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xed;os-Gallardo PT, Carranza-Garc&#xed;a LE, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Montalvo S. Reliability and validity of an AI-Driven smartphone application for measuring countermovement jump height: A comparison with force platform, infrared optical timing, and manual video analysis. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci 30: 1&#x2013;14, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggio F, Trovato B, Sortino M, Musumeci G. A comprehensive analysis of the machine learning pose estimation models used in human movement and posture analyses: A narrative review. Heliyon 10: e39977, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J, Arganda-Carreras I, Frise E, et al. Fiji: anopen-sourceplatformfor biological-imageanalysis. Nat Methods 9: 676&#x2013;682, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siontis GCM, Sweda R, Noseworthy PA, et al. Development and validation pathways of artificial intelligence tools evaluated in randomised clinical trials. BMJ Health Care Inform 28: e100466, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan ECH, Weng Onn S, Montalvo S. Measuring vertical jump height with artificial intelligence through a cell phone: A validity and reliability report. J Strength Cond Res 38: e529&#x2013;e533, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas G, Gade R, Moeslund TB, Carr P, Hilton A. Computer vision for sports: Current applications and research topics. Comput Vis Image Understand 159: 3&#x2013;18, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojahn C, Schario M, Dobos G, Blume-Peytavi U, Kottner J. Reliability and validity of two in vivo measurements for skin surface topography in aged adults. Skin Res Technol 21: 54&#x2013;60, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhlrich SD, Falisse A, Kidzi&#x144;ski &#x141;, et al. OpenCap: Human movement dynamics from smartphone videos. PLoS Comput Biol 19: e1011462, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Pecasse N, Meijer K, Essers JMN. The accuracy of markerless motion capture combined with computer vision techniques for measuring running kinematics. Scand J Med Sci Sports 33: 966&#x2013;978, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vec V, Toma&#x17e;i&#x10d; S, Kos A, Umek A. Trends in real-time artificial intelligence methods in sports: A systematic review. J Big Data 11: 148, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victor B, He Z, Morgan S, et al. Continuous video to simple signals for swimming stroke detection with convolutional neural networks. 2017 IEEE Conf Comput Vis Pattern Recognit Workshop CVPRW. Honolulu, HI, USA: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2017. pp. 122&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira A, Blazevich AJ, DA Costa AS, Tufano JJ, Bottaro M. Validity and test-retest reliability of the Jumpo App for jump performance measurement. Int J Exerc Sci 14: 677&#x2013;686, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Luo P, Xia S. Enhancing visual perception in sports environments: A virtual reality and machine learning approach. Buildings 14: 4012, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherall IL, Coombs BD. Skin color measurements in terms of CIELAB color space values. J Invest Dermatol 99: 468&#x2013;473, 1992.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>