<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41606722</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of pelvic stabilization exercises on knee valgus, muscle activity, and strength in individuals with dynamic knee valgus.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">163</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-026-09556-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Pelvic instability is often associated with angular deviations of lower limb and often causes valgus shift of the knee joint under load. In addition, non-contact ACL tears during sport activity are often caused by muscle weakness around the pelvis. Therefore, reinforcing the pelvic stabilizing muscles may counterbalance dynamic knee valgus (DKV). The aim of this research is to increase the activity of the pelvic stabilizing muscles through a specific exercise program and to investigate its effect of DKV after six-week pelvic stabilization training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty-two subjects (male/female: 15/7) participated in the study. They performed pelvic stabilization program for six-weeks. Before and after the training, DKV was determined on both sides by performing ten single leg squats using a Kinect camera, the Gluteus maximus, medius and vastus medialis muscles activity and strength were measured by EMG system and wireless dynamometer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">DKV decreased from 3.15% to 1.03% for the left knee and from 3.89% to 1.26% for the right knee, the magnitude of change was significant (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Maximal Isometric Force increased significantly in all tested muscles, including the gluteus maximus, gluteus medius, and biceps femoris (all <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 or <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). This functional improvement was supported by neuromuscular changes, with EMG amplitudes increasing considerably in all assessed muscles (gluteus maximus, gluteus medius, and vastus medialis obliquus), with all six sides showing significant change (all <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Strengthening the pelvic stabilization muscles induced a substantial improvement in knee valgus, and thus reduced the risk of developing cruciate ligament injuries. This study provides a direct link between an easy diagnosed predisposing factor a common sports injury, and offers a simple countermeasure in the form of specific exercises, that may be included against ACL injuries.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ambrus</LastName><ForeName>Mira</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Sports Physiology, Hungarian University of Sports Science, Budapest, Hungary. ambrus.mira@tf.hu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Gabriella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Semmelweis University, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moln&#xe1;r</LastName><ForeName>D&#xf3;ra</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Sports Physiology, Hungarian University of Sports Science, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soussi</LastName><ForeName>Badis</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Sports Physiology, Hungarian University of Sports Science, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horv&#xe1;th</LastName><ForeName>Tam&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Sports Physiology, Hungarian University of Sports Science, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horv&#xe1;th</LastName><ForeName>M&#xf3;nika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Semmelweis University, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacza</LastName><ForeName>Zsombor</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Sports Physiology, Hungarian University of Sports Science, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic knee valgus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic stabilization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All adult participants completed an informed consent form prior to data collection and voluntarily enrolled in the research study. For instances where participants were under the age of 18, informed assent was obtained together with informed consent from their parents or legal guardians. This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Health Research Ethics Committee of the Hungarian university of sports science (ethics number: TE-KEB/22/2021). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09556-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-026-09556-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Myer GD, Ford KR. Biomechanical measures of neuromuscular control and valgus loading of the knee predict ACL injury risk in female athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(4):492&#x2013;501. 10.1177/0363546504269591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15722287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markolf KL, Burchfield DM, Shapiro MM et al. Combined knee loading States that generate high ACL forces. J Orthop Res. 1995;13(6):930&#x2013;5. 10.1002/jor.1100130618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8544031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flandry F, Hommel G. Normal anatomy and biomechanics of the knee. Sports Med Arthrosc. 2011;19(2):82&#x2013;92. 10.1097/JSA.0b013e318210c0aa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSA.0b013e318210c0aa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollman JH, Galardi CM, Lin I-H, Voth BC, Whitmarsh CL. Frontal and transverse plane hip kinematics and gluteus Maximus recruitment correlate with frontal plane knee kinematics during single-leg squat tests in women. Clin Biomech. 2014;29(4):468&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2013.12.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2013.12.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24467971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi VG, Prill R, Jahnke S, et al. The influence of gluteal muscle strength deficits on dynamic knee valgus: a scoping review. J EXP ORTOP. 2022;9:81. 10.1186/s40634-022-00513-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40634-022-00513-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35976534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer K, Hebron C, Williams JM. A randomised trial into the effect of an isolated hip abductor strengthening programme and a functional motor control programme on knee kinematics and hip muscle strength. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015;16(1):105. 10.1186/s12891-015-0563-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-015-0563-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4424529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25935843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saad MC, de Vasconcelos RA, Mancinelli LV, de O, Munno MS, de Liporaci B, Grossi RF. Is hip strengthening the best treatment option for females with patellofemoral pain? A randomized controlled trial of three different types of exercises. Brazilian J Phys Ther. 2018;22(5):408&#x2013;16. 10.1016/j.bjpt.2018.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2018.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6157473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29661570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toor AS, Limpisvasti O, Ihn HE, McGarry MH, Banffy M, Lee TQ. The significant effect of the medial hamstrings on dynamic knee stability. Knee Surg Sport Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(8):2608&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s00167-018-5283-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-018-5283-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers CM. The influence of abnormal hip mechanics on knee injury: A Biomechanical perspective. J Orthop Sport Phys Ther. 2010;40(2):42&#x2013;51. 10.2519/jospt.2010.3337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.3337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiman MP, Bolgla LA, Lorenz D. Hip functions influence on knee dysfunction: a proximal link to a distal problem. J Sport Rehabil. 2009;18(1):33&#x2013;46. 10.1123/jsr.18.1.33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.18.1.33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19321905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skou ST, Wrigley TV, Metcalf BR, Hinman RS, Bennell KL. Association of knee confidence with Pain, knee Instability, muscle Strength, and dynamic Varus-Valgus joint motion in knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2014;66(5):695&#x2013;701. 10.1002/acr.22208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.22208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B, Herman D, Liu H, Garrett WE, Yu B. Prevention of ACL injury, part I: injury Characteristics, risk Factors, and loading mechanism. Res Sport Med. 2012;20(3&#x2013;4):180&#x2013;97. 10.1080/15438627.2012.680990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2012.680990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22742075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi H, Kanamura T, Koshida S, et al. Mechanisms of the anterior cruciate ligament injury in sports activities: a twenty-year clinical research of 1,700 athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9(4):669&#x2013;75. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24149795.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S, Nagano Y, Ito W, Kido Y, Okuwaki T. A retrospective study of mechanisms of anterior cruciate ligament injuries in high school basketball, handball, judo, soccer, and volleyball. Med (Baltim). 2019;98(26):e16030. 10.1097/MD.0000000000016030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000016030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6616929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31261507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffrey D, Placzek DAB. Orthopaedic physical therapy secrets. 3rd ed. Elsevier Inc.; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derman T, Wretling M-L, H&#xe4;nni M, et al. Higher frequency of osteoarthritis in patients with ACL graft rupture than in those with intact ACL grafts 30 years after reconstruction. Knee Surg Sport Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(7):2139&#x2013;46. 10.1007/s00167-019-05726-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-019-05726-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31664487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohmander LS, &#xd6;stenberg A, Englund M, Roos H. High prevalence of knee osteoarthritis, pain, and functional limitations in female soccer players twelve years after anterior cruciate ligament injury. Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50(10):3145&#x2013;52. 10.1002/art.20589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.20589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15476248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dix J, Marsh S, Dingenen B, Malliaras P. The relationship between hip muscle strength and dynamic knee valgus in asymptomatic females: A systematic review. Phys Ther Sport Off J Assoc Chart Physiother Sport Med. 2019;37:197&#x2013;209. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.05.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.05.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29859898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldon R, de Serr&#xe3;o M, Scattone Silva FV, Piva R. Effects of functional stabilization training on Pain, Function, and lower extremity biomechanics in women with patellofemoral pain: A randomized clinical trial. J Orthop Sport Phys Ther. 2014;44(4):240&#x2013;51. 10.2519/jospt.2014.4940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2014.4940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahabuddin FNA, Jamaludin NI, Amir NH, Shaharudin S. The effects of hip- and ankle-focused exercise intervention on dynamic knee valgus: a systematic review. van den Bogert A, ed. <i>PeerJ</i>. 2021;9:e11731. 10.7717/peerj.11731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lins L, Carvalho FM. SF-36 total score as a single measure of health-related quality of life: scoping review. SAGE Open Med. 2016;4:205031211667172. 10.1177/2050312116671725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312116671725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5052926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27757230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tegner Y, Lysholm J. Rating systems in the evaluation of knee ligament injuries. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1985;198:43&#x2013;9. 10.1097/00003086-198509000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003086-198509000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4028566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysholm J, Gillquist J. Evaluation of knee ligament surgery results with special emphasis on use of a scoring scale. Am J Sports Med. 1982;10(3):150&#x2013;4. 10.1177/036354658201000306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354658201000306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6896798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhl&#xe1;r &#xc1;, Ambrus M, K&#xe9;kesi M, Fodor E, Grand L, Szathm&#xe1;ry G, R&#xe1;cz K, Lacza Z. Kinect Azure&#x2013;Based accurate measurement of dynamic valgus position of the Knee&#x2014;A corrigible predisposing factor of osteoarthritis. Appl Sci. 2021;11(12):5536. 10.3390/app11125536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11125536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur D, Gupta R, Shikha. Core stabilization exercises after ACL reconstruction surgery provide better outcomes: A randomized controlled trial. Int J Physiotherapy. 2015;2(6):899&#x2013;904. 10.15621/ijphy/2015/v2i6/80746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15621/ijphy/2015/v2i6/80746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieske O, Muehlbauer T, Borde R, Gube M, Bruhn S, Behm DG, Granacher U. Effects of core strength training on sport performance in youth athletes: A meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(3):567&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung DS, Kim YH, Lee SY, Park JW. Effects of a core stability exercise program on pain and function in patients with knee injuries. J Orthop Trauma Rehabilitation. 2022;23:39&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.jotr.2016.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jotr.2016.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piva SR, Fitzgerald GK, Wisniewski S, Delitto A. Predictors of pain and function outcome after rehabilitation in patients with patellofemoral pain syndrome. J Rehabil Med. 2009;41(8):604&#x2013;12. 10.2340/16501977-0372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-0372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder BJ, Kivlin JE. Electromyographic analysis of the hip musculature during pelvic stabilization exercises. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2012;42(6):470&#x2013;8. 10.2519/jospt.2012.4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.4002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distefano LJ, Blackburn JT, Marshall SW, Padua DA. Gluteal muscle activation during common therapeutic exercises. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2009;39(7):532&#x2013;40. 10.2519/jospt.2009.2886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2009.2886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leetun DT, Ireland ML, Willson JD, Ballantyne BT, Davis IM. Core stability measures as risk factors for lower extremity injury in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(6):926&#x2013;34. 10.1249/01.MSS.0000128145.75199.CB.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000128145.75199.CB</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15179160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cichanowski HM, Schmitt LC, Johnson RJ, Niemuth PE. Hip strength in collegiate female athletes with patellofemoral pain. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1227&#x2013;32. 10.1249/mss.0b013e3180601115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3180601115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock GS, Shultz SJ, Schmitz RJ, Nguyen AD. The effect of hip and core strengthening on gluteus medius activation during walking in healthy adults: A randomized controlled trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2017;47(5):321&#x2013;8. 10.2519/jospt.2017.7136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.7136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhl&#xe1;r &#xc1;, Ambrus M, K&#xe9;kesi M, et al. Kinect Azure&#x2013;Based accurate measurement of dynamic valgus position of the Knee&#x2014;A corrigible predisposing factor of osteoarthritis. Appl Sci. 2021;11(12). 10.3390/app11125536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers CM. The influence of abnormal hip mechanics on knee injury: A Biomechanical perspective. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2010;40(2):42&#x2013;51. 10.2519/jospt.2010.3337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.3337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Ford KR, Brent JL, Hewett TE. The relationship of hamstrings and quadriceps strength to anterior cruciate ligament injury risk in female athletes: A systematic review. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2013;43(9):619&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazulak BT, Hewett TE, Reeves NP, Goldberg B, Cholewicki J. Deficits in neuromuscular control of the trunk predict knee injury risk: a prospective biomechanical-epidemiologic study. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(7):1123&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546507301585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto D, Myer GD, McKeon JM, Hewett TE. Evaluation of the effectiveness of neuromuscular training to reduce anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(6):787&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>