<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41848692</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feelings in the Lift: Comparing Perceptual Responses to Cluster and Traditional Resistance Training Protocols.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005360</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>de Souza Soares, B, Mohammad, J, Cantelmo, CE, Gomes Alves, MC, de Oliveira Barros, BC, and Vieira de Oliveira, G. Feelings in the lift: Comparing perceptual responses to cluster and traditional resistance training protocols. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-This study compared the acute effects of traditional vs. cluster resistance training (RT) protocols on affective valence, arousal, enjoyment, and rating of perceived exertion (RPE) in resistance-trained young adults. Sixteen subjects completed 2 lower-limb RT sessions in a randomized crossover design: 1 with a traditional configuration and another with cluster sets. Affective valence declined during and after the traditional session (p &lt; 0.05), but remained stable across time in the cluster session, with a significant protocol &#xd7; time interaction (p &lt; 0.001). Perceived activation increased in both conditions (p &lt; 0.001) but was significantly higher after the traditional protocol (p = 0.04; d = 0.7, 95% confidence interval (CI) [0.12-1.21]). Enjoyment was significantly greater (p &lt; 0.01; d = 0.7, 95% CI [-1.31 to -0.18]), and RPE significantly lower (p &lt; 0.001; d = 1.2, 95% CI [0.52-1.82]) following the cluster session. Rating of perceived exertion negatively correlated with enjoyment (r = -0.54, p = 0.03) and affective valence (r = -0.54, p = 0.032) in the traditional condition. These results suggest that RT set configuration acutely modulates psychoaffective outcomes. Cluster RT elicits more favorable affective and perceptual responses, which may enhance exercise enjoyment and support long-term adherence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Souza Soares</LastName><ForeName>Bianca</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences Applied to Health, Medical Sciences Institute, Multidisciplinary Center, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Maca&#xe9;, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammad</LastName><ForeName>Josef</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charit&#xe9;-Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantelmo</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences Applied to Health, Medical Sciences Institute, Multidisciplinary Center, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Maca&#xe9;, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomes Alves</LastName><ForeName>Maria Clara</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences Applied to Health, Medical Sciences Institute, Multidisciplinary Center, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Maca&#xe9;, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Oliveira Barros</LastName><ForeName>Bruna Cristina</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences Applied to Health, Medical Sciences Institute, Multidisciplinary Center, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Maca&#xe9;, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Gustavo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences Applied to Health, Medical Sciences Institute, Multidisciplinary Center, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Maca&#xe9;, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multicenter Postgraduate Program in Physiological Sciences, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>E-26/210.754/2024</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Carlos Chagas Filho de Amparo &#xe0; Pesquisa do Estado do Rio de Janeiro</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>E-26/210.617/2025</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Carlos Chagas Filho de Amparo &#xe0; Pesquisa do Estado do Rio de Janeiro</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perceived exertion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychophysiologic response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training intensity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41848692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bastos V, Rodrigues F, Davis P, Teixeira DS. Assessing affective valence and activation in resistance training with the feeling scale and the felt arousal scale: A systematic review. PLoS One 18: e0294529, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Granacher U, Warneke K, Arag&#xe3;o-Santos JC, Da Silva-Grigoletto ME, Konrad A. Minimalist training: Is lower dosage or intensity resistance training effective to improve physical fitness? A narrative review. Sports Med 54: 289&#x2013;302, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellezza PA, Hall EE, Miller PC, Bixby WR. The influence of exercise order on blood lactate, perceptual, and affective responses. J Strength Cond Res 23: 203&#x2013;208, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder AJ, Hargreaves EA, Hodge K. Great expectations: A qualitative analysis of the factors that influence affective forecasts for exercise. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 551, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carraro A, Paoli A, Gobbi E. Affective response to acute resistance exercise: A comparison among machines and free weights. Sport Sci Health 14: 283&#x2013;288, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavarretta DJ, Hall EE, Bixby WR. The effects of increasing training load on affect and perceived exertion. J Strength Cond Res 36: 16&#x2013;21, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciolac EG, Rodrigues-da-Silva JM. Resistance training as a tool for preventing and treating musculoskeletal disorders. Sports Med 46: 1239&#x2013;1248, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekkekakis P, Parfitt G, Petruzzello SJ. The pleasure and displeasure people feel when they exercise at different intensities: Decennial update and progress towards a tripartite rationale for exercise intensity prescription. Sports Med 41: 641&#x2013;671, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel A, Rozen Smukas II, Halperin I. The effects of lifting lighter and heavier loads on subjective measures. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 176&#x2013;183, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flewwelling LD, Hannaian SJ, Cao V, Chaillou T, Churchward-Venne TA, Cheng AJ. What are the potential mechanisms of fatigue-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy with low-load resistance exercise training? Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 328: C1001&#x2013;C1014, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC, Garver MJ, Cotter JA, Devor ST, Lucas AR, Fairman CM. Affective responses to acute resistance exercise performed at self-selected and imposed loads in trained women. J Strength Cond Res 29: 3067&#x2013;3074, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JM, McIntosh JR, Hornsby J, Timme L, Gover L, Mayes JL. Effect of exercise duration on session RPE at an individualized constant workload. Eur J Appl Physiol 107: 501&#x2013;507, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy CJ, Rejeski WJ. Not what, but how one feels: The measurement of affect during exercise. J Sport Exerc Psychol 11: 304&#x2013;317, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchinson JC, Zenko Z, Santich S, Dalton PC. Increasing the pleasure and enjoyment of exercise: A novel resistance-training protocol. J Sport Exerc Psychol 42: 143&#x2013;152, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft JA, Green JM, Thompson KR. Session ratings of perceived exertion responses during resistance training bouts equated for total work but differing in work rate. J Strength Cond Res 28: 540&#x2013;545, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullen SP, Olson EA, Phillips SM, et al. Measuring enjoyment of physical activity in older adults: Invariance of the Physical Activity Enjoyment Scale (PACES) across groups and time. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 8: 103, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy SL, Eaves DL. Exercising for the pleasure and for the pain of it: The implications of different forms of hedonistic thinking in theories of physical activity behavior. Front Psychol 7: 843, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Jenke S, Phillips MD, Mitchell JB, Jones MT. Acute response to cluster sets in trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2383&#x2013;2393, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulo AC, Tricoli V, Queiroz AC, Laurentino G, Forjaz CL. Blood pressure response during resistance training of different work-to-rest ratio. J Strength Cond Res 33: 399&#x2013;407, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price M, Moss P. The effects of work:rest duration on physiological and perceptual responses during intermittent exercise and performance. J Sports Sci 25: 1613&#x2013;1621, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Marston KJ, Teo SY, et al. The intensity of a resistance exercise session can be quantified by the work rate of exercise. PLoS One 18: e0291857, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan GM, Feinn R. Using effect size&#x2014;or why the P value is not enough. J Grad Med Educ 4: 279&#x2013;282, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svebak S, Murgatroyd S. Metamotivational dominance: A multimethod validation of reversal theory constructs. J Pers Soc Psychol 48: 107&#x2013;116, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas-Molina S, Garc&#xed;a-Sillero M, Maroto-Izquierdo S, et al. Cluster sets and traditional sets elicit similar muscular hypertrophy: A volume and effort-matched study in resistance-trained individuals. Eur J Appl Physiol 125: 1725&#x2013;1734, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Way KL, Thomas HJ, Parker L, et al. Cluster sets to prescribe interval resistance training: A potential method to optimise resistance training safety, feasibility and efficacy in cardiac patients. Sports Med Open 9: 86, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: Effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep 11: 209&#x2013;216, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>