<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41159536</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-2358</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gerodontology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gerodontology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oral Healthcare Experiences and Needs of Older Adults in Residential Care Facilities: A Qualitative Exploration of Care Managers' Perception in the Indian Context.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ger.70026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Improved dental services have increased the retention of natural teeth and prostheses, creating complex oral care needs among older adults. Care managers are key in overseeing residents' oral health; their perceptions can inform strategies to improve geriatric oral health in residential aged care facilities (RACFs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore care managers' perceptions of the oral healthcare experiences and needs of older adults in RACFs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A descriptive qualitative study, grounded in a constructivist paradigm, was conducted using the Socio-Ecological Model to guide data collection and analysis at individual, interpersonal, organisational, community and policy levels. Ten care managers were purposively sampled and interviewed online using a semi-structured guide. Data were analysed using reflexive thematic analysis following Braun and Clarke's framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10; age 28-59&#x2009;years; mean age 41.7; 5 males, 5 females) were from urban and semi-urban areas of western India. Five themes were identified: (1) A Moral Duty to Care-Personal Beliefs and Emotional Drivers of Oral Health Practice; (2) Navigating Relational Complexities-Care Amidst Resistance, Trust and Support; (3) Systemic Gaps and Adaptive Practices in Resource-Limited Settings; (4) Disconnected Services and the Social Devaluation of Residents' Oral Health; and (5) Calls for Oral Health Care Delivery/Systemic Reforms-Embedding Oral Health in Aged Care Policy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Care managers perceived residents' oral health as often being deprioritized in RACFs due to competing general health demands. An interdisciplinary care team, including a dentist, stronger policy support, and targeted training for care managers and staff, was strongly recommended to improve older adults' oral health outcomes in residential settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Gerodontology Association and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shigli</LastName><ForeName>Kamal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6860-8942</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, DY Patil Dental School, Pune, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nayak</LastName><ForeName>Sushma</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3620-3593</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Dentist, Bangalore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lagali-Jirge</LastName><ForeName>Vasanti</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1752-1948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine and Radiology, KLE VK Institute of Dental Sciences, KAHER, Belagavi, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karuveettil</LastName><ForeName>Vineetha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5358-4391</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Dentistry, Amrita School of Dentistry, Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Kochi, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Gerodontology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8215850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0734-0664</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">care manager</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geriatric oral health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare experiences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral health needs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">residential care</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41159536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ger.70026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Ageing and Health, https://www.who.int/news&#x2010;room/fact&#x2010;sheets/detail/ageing&#x2010;and&#x2010;health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elderly in India, https://mospi.gov.in/sites/default/files/publication_reports/Elderly%20in%20India%202021.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Menezes and T. M. Thomas, &#x201c;Status of the Elderly and Emergence of Old Age Homes in India,&#x201d; International Journal of Social Sciences and Management 5, no. 1 (2018): 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Jiang, C. H. Chu, D. Duangthip, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Perspectives of Oral Health Policies and Oral Healthcare Schemes for Older Adult Populations,&#x201d; Frontiers in Oral Health 2 (2021): 703526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Shah, &#x201c;Oral Health Care System for Elderly in India,&#x201d; Geriatrics &amp; Gerontology International 4 (2004): S162&#x2013;S164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eduindex News, https://eduindex.org/2021/07/14/the&#x2010;reason&#x2010;behind&#x2010;the&#x2010;rising&#x2010;number&#x2010;of&#x2010;old&#x2010;age&#x2010;homes&#x2010;in&#x2010;india/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Press Information Bureau. Government of India. Ministry of Social Justice &amp; Empowerment, https://pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1781361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Pandian, S. Naik, U. Ramachandran, G. A. Grace, and S. Gopalakrishnan, &#x201c;Social Factors Influencing Utilization of Old Age Homes by Elderly in Urban Area of South Chennai, Tamil Nadu,&#x201d; Indian Journal of Community Medicine 49, no. 1 (2024): 41&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Social Justice &amp; Empowerment, Schemes for The Welfare of Senior Citizens, https://pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1806506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senior Care Reforms in India: Reimagining the Senior Care Paradigm, A Position Paper, https://www.niti.gov.in/sites/default/files/2024&#x2010;02/Senior%20Care%20Reforms%20in%20India%20FINAL%20FOR%20WEBSITE_compressed.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. K. Sha, A. Khan, K. Eswara, D. L. Venkata Suvarna, K. Kannaiyan, and N. Pottem, &#x201c;Assessment of Periodontal Health and Necessity of Dental Treatment in the Institutionalized Elderly Population of East Godavari District, Andhra Pradesh,&#x201d; Journal of Pharmacy &amp; Bioallied Sciences 11, no. Suppl 2 (2019): S188&#x2013;S193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Roma, M. Sen, K. Mala, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Critical Assessment on Unmet Oral Health Needs and Oral Health&#x2010;Related Quality of Life Among Old Age Home Inhabitants in Karnataka, India,&#x201d; Clinical, Cosmetic and Investigational Dentistry 13 (2021): 181&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. A. Razak, K. M. Richard, R. P. Thankachan, K. A. Hafiz, K. N. Kumar, and K. M. Sameer, &#x201c;Geriatric Oral Health: A Review Article,&#x201d; Journal of International Oral Health 6, no. 6 (2014): 110&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Chung, P. Mojon, and E. Budtz&#x2010;J&#xf8;rgensen, &#x201c;Dental Care of Elderly in Nursing Homes: Perceptions of Managers, Nurses, and Physicians,&#x201d; Special Care in Dentistry 20, no. 1 (2000): 12&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Patterson Norrie, A. R. Villarosa, A. C. Kong, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Oral Health in Residential Aged Care: Perceptions of Nurses and Management Staff,&#x201d; Nursing Open 7 (2020): 536&#x2013;546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. James, S. Km, and P. Krishnappa, &#x201c;Perception of Caregivers About Oral Health Services for Institutionalized Older Adults: A Mixed Method Study,&#x201d; Annals of Geriatric Medicine and Research 28, no. 3 (2024): 362&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sandelowski, &#x201c;Whatever Happened to Qualitative Description?,&#x201d; Research in Nursing &amp; Health 23, no. 4 (2000): 334&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. G. Guba and Y. S. Lincoln, &#x201c;Competing Paradigms in Qualitative Research,&#x201d; in Handbook of Qualitative Research vol. 2 (Sage Publications, Inc., 1994), 163&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. Bronfenbrenner, &#x201c;Ecological Models of Human Development,&#x201d; International Encyclopedia of Education 3, no. 2 (1994): 37&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Braun and V. Clarke, &#x201c;Using Thematic Analysis in Psychology,&#x201d; Qualitative Research in Psychology 3, no. 2 (2006): 77&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Braun and V. Clarke, &#x201c;One Size Fits All? What Counts as Quality Practice in (Reflexive) Thematic Analysis?,&#x201d; Qualitative Research in Psychology 18, no. 3 (2021): 328&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Braun and V. Clarke, &#x201c;Conceptual and Design Thinking for Thematic Analysis,&#x201d; Qualitative Psychology 9, no. 1 (2022): 3&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Salmons, &#x201c;Designing and Conducting Research With Online Interviews,&#x201d; in Cases in Online Interview Research, ed. J. Salmons (SAGE Publications, Ltd, 2012), 1&#x2013;30, https://doi.org/10.4135/9781506335155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. A. Paley, L. M. Slack&#x2010;Smith, and M. J. O'Grady, &#x201c;Aged Care Staff Perspectives on Oral Care for Residents: Western Australia,&#x201d; Gerodontology 21, no. 3 (2004): 146&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. R. Villarosa, S. Clark, A. C. Villarosa, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Promoting Oral Health Care Among People Living in Residential Aged Care Facilities: Perceptions of Care Staff,&#x201d; Gerodontology 35 (2018): 177&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Soilemezi, K. Wanyonyi, V. Hill, and J. Manthorpe, &#x201c;Views of Homecare Staff and Carers on Oral Needs and Dental Care for People Living With Dementia: A Qualitative Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry 38, no. 12 (2023): e6039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Bellander, E. Angelini, P. Andersson, C. H&#xe4;gglin, and H. Wijk, &#x201c;A Preventive Care Approach for Oral Health in Nursing Homes: A Qualitative Study of Healthcare Workers' Experiences,&#x201d; BMC Geriatrics 24, no. 1 (2024): 803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Hoben, A. Clarke, K. T. Huynh, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Barriers and Facilitators in Providing Oral Care to Nursing Home Residents, From the Perspective of Care Aides: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Studies 73 (2017): 34&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. G. Johnson, M. Z. Morgan, and R. J. Jones, &#x201c;Oral Care, Loss of Personal Identity and Dignity in Residential Care Homes,&#x201d; Gerodontology 40, no. 2 (2023): 200&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. L. Dalgarno, V. Gillan, A. Roberts, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Home Care in Dementia: The Views of Informal Carers From a Co&#x2010;Designed Consultation,&#x201d; Dementia 20, no. 7 (2021): 2261&#x2013;2277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. G. Barbe, H. E. Kottmann, S. Hamacher, S. H. M. Derman, and M. J. Noack, &#x201c;Efficacy and Acceptance of Professional Dental Cleaning Among Nursing Home Residents,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Investigations 23, no. 2 (2019): 707&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. P. Sweeney, C. Williams, C. Kennedy, L. M. Macpherson, S. Turner, and J. Bagg, &#x201c;Oral Health Care and Status of Elderly Care Home Residents in Glasgow,&#x201d; Community Dental Health 24, no. 1 (2007): 37&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Doshi, J. Mann, L. Quentin, L. Morton&#x2010;Holtham, and K. A. Eaton, &#x201c;Mouth Care Training and Practice: A Survey of Nursing Staff Working in National Health Service Hospitals in England,&#x201d; Journal of Research in Nursing 26, no. 6 (2021): 574&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Idris, S. Aghanwa, J. O'Halloran, A. Durey, and L. Slack&#x2010;Smith, &#x201c;Homebound Oral Care for Older Adults: A Qualitative Study of Professional Carers' Perspectives in Perth, Western Australia,&#x201d; Gerodontology 41, no. 1 (2024): 94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Hoang, T. Barnett, G. Maine, and L. Crocombe, &#x201c;Aged Care Staff's Experiences of &#x2018;Better Oral Health in Residential Care Training&#x2019;: A Qualitative Study,&#x201d; Contemporary Nurse 54, no. 3 (2018): 268&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. E. Gallagher and J. Fiske, &#x201c;Special Care Dentistry: A Professional Challenge,&#x201d; British Dental Journal 202, no. 10 (2007): 619&#x2013;629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. H. Fazli, N. Nordin, M. S. Mohamad, A. J. Khan, and M. S. Ahmad, &#x201c;Exploring Barriers to Oral Healthcare at Private Residential Aged Care Facilities in Selangor, Malaysia: A Pilot Study,&#x201d; Discover Public Health 21, no. 1 (2024): 168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. West, J. Saunders, and L. Slack&#x2010;Smith, &#x201c;Integrating Dental Professionals Into Aged Care With Focus on Australia: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; Gerodontology 42, no. 2 (2025): 147&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Wallace, J. Mohammadi, L. G. Wallace, and J. A. Taylor, &#x201c;Senior Smiles: Preliminary Results for a New Model of Oral Health Care Utilizing the Dental Hygienist in Residential Aged Care Facilities,&#x201d; International Journal of Dental Hygiene 14, no. 4 (2016): 284&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Bala, V. Sargaiyan, S. A. Rathi, S. S. Mankar, A. K. Jaiswal, and S. A. Mankar, &#x201c;Mobile Dental Clinic for Oral Health Services to Underserved Rural Indian Communities,&#x201d; Bioinformation 19, no. 13 (2023): 1383&#x2013;1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, NICE Guidelines, https://www.nice.org.uk/about/what&#x2010;we&#x2010;do/our&#x2010;programmes/nice&#x2010;guidance/nice&#x2010;guidelines.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Hearn and L. Slack&#x2010;Smith, &#x201c;Engaging Dental Professionals in Residential Aged&#x2010;Care Facilities: Staff Perspectives Regarding Access to Oral Care,&#x201d; Australian Journal of Primary Health 22, no. 5 (2016): 445&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Shigli, S. S. Nayak, S. Sharma, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Interprofessional Education&#x2014;A Case for Gerodontology Training,&#x201d; Gerontology &amp; Geriatrics Education 42, no. 2 (2021): 151&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. O. Ben&#x2010;Omran, A. A. Livinski, D. T. Kopycka&#x2010;Kedzierawski, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Use of Teledentistry in Facilitating Oral Health for Older Adults: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; Journal of the American Dental Association 152, no. 12 (2021): 998&#x2013;1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Patel, M. Mian, C. Robertson, N. B. Pitts, and J. E. Gallagher, &#x201c;Crisis in Care Homes: The Dentists Don't Come,&#x201d; BDJ Open 7, no. 1 (2021): 20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Gopalakrishnan, E. Kahu, L. Jones, and P. Brunton, &#x201c;Access and Barriers to Oral Health Care for Dependent Elderly People Living in Rest Homes,&#x201d; Gerodontology 36, no. 2 (2019): 149&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. L. Teh, E. Abdin, P. V. Asharani, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Measuring Social Desirability Bias in a Multi&#x2010;Ethnic Cohort Sample: Its Relationship With Self&#x2010;Reported Physical Activity, Dietary Habits, and Factor Structure,&#x201d; BMC Public Health 23, no. 1 (2023): 415.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>