<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41129674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Force Production and Barbell Velocity Characteristics Across Multiple Sets of Different Accentuated Eccentric Loading Conditions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127</StartPage><EndPage>135</EndPage><MedlinePgn>127-135</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005282</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cantwell, CJ, Schroeder, ZS, Marshall-Ciochon, LK, Campbell, BA, Taber, CB, and Suchomel, TJ. Force production and barbell velocity characteristics across multiple sets of different accentuated eccentric loading conditions. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): 127-135, 2026-The purpose of this study was to examine the impact that multiple accentuated eccentric loaded (AEL) back squat sets have on force production and barbell velocity characteristics within 2 different loading conditions. Sixteen resistance-trained men performed 3 sets of 3 back squat repetitions while using 100% of their 1 repetition maximum (1RM) during the eccentric phase of the first repetition and either 60% (100-60) or 80% (100-80) 1RM on the concentric phase of the first repetition and the eccentric-concentric phases of the subsequent 2 repetitions. Braking and propulsion net mean force, duration, and net impulse as well as mean and peak barbell velocity were compared between loading schemes and sets using a series of 2-way repeated measures ANOVA. Significantly greater propulsion net mean force and mean barbell velocity were produced during the 100-60 condition than during the 100-80 condition across all sets ( p &lt; 0.001). In addition, significantly greater ( p &lt; 0.001) set-averaged braking net mean force and net impulse and peak barbell velocity were produced during the 100-60 condition while greater braking and propulsion duration ( p &lt; 0.001) and net impulse ( p = 0.031) were produced during the 100-80 condition. Within each loading condition, trivial-small differences existed across sets for all variables ( g &#x2264; 0.39). Multiple sets of AEL back squats can be prescribed using 100-60 and 100-80 loading schemes without negatively affecting force or velocity characteristics. Strength and conditioning practitioners may prescribe 100-60 to enhance rapid force production characteristics and 100-80 to provide a strength stimulus to enhance force development.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantwell</LastName><ForeName>Conor J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletics, William &amp; Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroeder</LastName><ForeName>Zachary S</ForeName><Initials>ZS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emplify Health Titletown Sports Medicine and Orthopedics, Green Bay, Wisconsin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall-Ciochon</LastName><ForeName>Lauren K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness, Movement Fitness Rockford, Rockford, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Brookelyn A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletics, University of Houston, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taber</LastName><ForeName>Chrstopher B</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, Sacred Heart University, Fairfield, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suchomel</LastName><ForeName>Timothy J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Nutrition, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Psychology and Sport, University of Salford, Greater Manchester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impulse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of force development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">velocity-based training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41129674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aboodarda SJ, Yusof A, Abu Osman NA, Thompson MW, Mokhtar AH. Enhanced performance with elastic resistance during the eccentric phase of a countermovement jump. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 181&#x2013;187, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: A review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med 35: 841&#x2013;851, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg J, Docherty D. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on strength, muscle hypertrophy, and neural adaptations in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 16: 25&#x2013;32, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell BA, Cantwell CJ, Marshall-Ciochon LK, et al. A comparison of the braking and propulsion phase characteristics of traditional and accentuated eccentric loaded back squats in resistance-trained women. Appl Sci 15: 661, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Snijders T, McKay BR, et al. Eccentric exercise increases satellite cell content in type II muscle fibers. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 230&#x2013;237, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae S, Long A, Lis R, et al. Combined accentuated eccentric loading and rest redistribution in high-volume back squat: Acute kinetics and kinematics. J Strength Cond Res 38: 640&#x2013;647, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doan BK, Newton RU, Marsit JL, et al. Effects of increased eccentric loading on bench press 1RM. J Strength Cond Res 16: 9&#x2013;13, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Chronic adaptations to eccentric training: A systematic review. Sports Med 47: 917&#x2013;941, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Effects of accentuated eccentric loading on muscle properties, strength, power, and speed in resistance-trained rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2750&#x2013;2761, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmer S, Hahn S, McAllister P, Leong C, Martin J. Improvements in multi-joint leg function following chronic eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 22: 653&#x2013;661, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>English KL, Loehr JA, Lee SMC, Smith SM. Early-phase musculoskeletal adaptations to different levels of eccentric resistance after 8 weeks of lower body training. Eur J App Physiol 114: 2263&#x2013;2280, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross M, L&#xfc;thy F, Kroell J, M&#xfc;ller E, Hoppeler H, Vogt M. Effects of eccentric cycle ergometry in alpine skiers. Int J Sports Med 31: 572&#x2013;576, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Nimphius S. Training principles for power. Strength Cond J 34: 2&#x2013;12, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handford MJ, Bright TE, Mundy P, Lake J, Theis N, Hughes JD. The need for eccentric speed: A narrative review of the effects of accelerated eccentric actions during resistance-based training. Sports Med 52: 2061&#x2013;2083, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden M, Wolf A, Evans M, Hicks KM, Thomas K, Howatson G. Four weeks of augmented eccentric loading using a novel leg press device improved leg strength in well-trained athletes and professional sprint track cyclists. PLoS One 15: e0236663, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Garzarella L, de Hoyos D, Pollock ML. Single versus multiple sets in long-term recreational weightlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 235&#x2013;242, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander DB, Kraemer RR, Kilpatrick MW, et al. Maximal eccentric and concentric strength discrepancies between young men and women for dynamic resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 21: 34&#x2013;40, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A Scale of Magnitude for Effect Statistics. Lexington, MA: ScienceOpen, Inc, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Katch FI. Eccentric and concentric torque-velocity relationships during arm flexion and extension. Influence of strength level. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 60: 395&#x2013;401, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo T, Li M. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple sets of weight training: Impact of volume, intensity, and variation. J Strength Cond Res 11: 143&#x2013;147, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1150&#x2013;1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lates AD, Greer BK, Wagle JP, Taber CB. Accentuated eccentric loading and cluster set configurations in the bench press. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1485&#x2013;1489, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstedt SL, LaStayo PC, Reich TE. When active muscles lengthen: Properties and consequences of eccentric contractions. News Physiol Sci 16: 256&#x2013;261, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Tufano JJ, Falzone M, Jones MT. Effectiveness of accentuated eccentric loading: Contingent on concentric load. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 66&#x2013;72, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mian Qaisar S, Fesquet L, Renaudin M. Adaptive rate sampling and filtering based on level crossing sampling. EURASIP J Adv Sig Proc 2009: 971656, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mike J, Kerksick CM, Kravitz L. How to incorporate eccentric training into a resistance training program. Strength Cond J 37: 5&#x2013;17, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munger C, Jones B, Halloran I, et al. Short-term effects of eccentric overload versus traditional back squat training on strength and power. Int J Kines Sports Sci 10: 1&#x2013;8, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munger CN, Archer DC, Leyva WD, et al. Acute effects of eccentric overload on concentric front squat performance. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1192&#x2013;1197, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Nosaka K, Steele J. The eccentric: concentric strength ratio of human skeletal muscle in vivo: Meta-analysis of the influences of sex, age, joint action, and velocity. Sports Med 53: 1125&#x2013;1136, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojasto T, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Effects of different accentuated eccentric load levels in eccentric-concentric actions on acute neuromuscular, maximal force, and power responses. J Strength Cond Res 23: 996&#x2013;1004, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Myklestad D, Raastad T. The influence of volume of exercise on early adaptations to strength training. J Strength Cond Res 17: 115&#x2013;120, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: A review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res 19: 950&#x2013;958, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Ball SD, Burkett LN. Three sets of weight training superior to 1 set with equal intensity for eliciting strength. J Strength Cond Res 16: 525&#x2013;529, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanborn K, Boros R, Hruby JOE, et al. Short-term performance effects of weight training with multiple sets not to failure vs. a single set to failure in women. J Strength Cond Res 14: 328&#x2013;331, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlumberger A, Stec J, Schmidtbleicher D. Single- vs. multiple-set strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res 15: 284&#x2013;289, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, de Villarreal ES, Haff GG. The temporal profile of postactivation potentiation is related to strength level. J Strength Cond Res 28: 706&#x2013;715, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, de Boer M, Narici MV. Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 102: 368&#x2013;373, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard J, Hobson S, Barker M, et al. The effect of training with accentuated eccentric load counter-movement jumps on strength and power characteristics of high-performance volleyball players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 3: 355&#x2013;363, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkey DB, Pollock ML, Ishida Y, et al. Effect of resistance training volume on strength and muscle thickness. Med Sci Sports Exerc 28: 1311&#x2013;1320, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone M, Johnson RL, Carter DR. A short term comparison of two different methods of resistance training on leg strength and power. Ath Train 14: 158&#x2013;160, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Cantwell CJ, Campbell BA, Schroeder ZS, Marshall LK, Taber CB. Braking and propulsion phase characteristics of traditional and accentuated eccentric loaded back squats. J Hum Kinet 91: 121&#x2013;133, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, McKeever SM, Sijuwade O, Carpenter L. Propulsion phase characteristics of loaded jump variations in resistance-trained women. Sports 11: 44, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, McKeever SM, Sijuwade O, et al. The effect of load placement on the power production characteristics of three lower extremity jumping exercises. J Hum Kinet 68: 109&#x2013;122, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: Training considerations. Sports Med 48: 765&#x2013;785, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Sato K, DeWeese BH, Ebben WP, Stone MH. Potentiation following ballistic and non-ballistic complexes: The effect of strength level. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1825&#x2013;1833, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Wagle JP, Douglas J, et al. Implementing eccentric resistance training-part 1: A brief review of existing methods. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 4: 38, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Wagle JP, Douglas J, et al. Implementing eccentric resistance training-part 2: Practical recommendations. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 4: 55, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber C, Butler C, Dabek V, et al. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on barbell and trap Bar countermovement jumps. Inter J Strength Cond 3: 4&#x2013;14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber CB, Morris JR, Wagle JP, Merrigan JJ. Accentuated eccentric loading in the bench press: Considerations for eccentric and concentric loading. Sports 9: 54, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt M, Hoppeler HH. Eccentric exercise: Mechanisms and effects when used as training regime or training adjunct. J Appl Physiol (1985) 116: 1446&#x2013;1454, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Cunanan AJ, Carroll KM, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading and cluster set configurations in the back squat: A kinetic and kinematic analysis. J Strength Cond Res 35: 420&#x2013;427, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Carroll KM, et al. Repetition-to-repetition differences using cluster and accentuated eccentric loading in the back squat. Sports 6: 59, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Cunanan AJ, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading for training and performance: A review. Sports Med 47: 2473&#x2013;2495, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Blazevich AJ, Haff GG, Tufano JJ, Newton RU, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Greater strength gains after training with accentuated eccentric than traditional isoinertial loads in already strength-trained men. Front Physiol 7: 149, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarrow JF, Borsa PA, Borst SE, Sitren HS, Stevens BR, White LJ. Early-phase neuroendocrine responses and strength adaptations following eccentric-enhanced resistance training J Strength Cond Res 22: 1205&#x2013;1214, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>