<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41719153</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise during 14 days of head down tilt bedrest attenuates motor unit impairments in older humans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093398</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Head-down tilt bedrest (HDBR) models the effects of mechanical unloading on neuromuscular function. The efficacy of exercise in preserving motor unit (MU) function in older adults during HDBR remains unclear. This study investigated the effects of 14-day HDBR on MU properties in older adults and the protective role of exercise. Fifteen participants aged 55-65&#xa0;years were randomized to Control group (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;7, passive mobilization only) or Exercise group (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;8, daily mixed resistance and aerobic training) during 14&#xa0;days of strict HDBR. Knee extensor strength and leg lean mass were measured, and intramuscular EMG was used to record MU firing rate (MUFR), MU potential (MUP) area and complexity, and neuromuscular junction (NMJ) transmission instability during contractions normalized to 25% of pre-bedrest strength. Plasma C-terminal agrin fragment (CAF) was also measured. Following HDBR, knee extensor strength decreased more in the Control group (-33.4&#xa0;N&#xa0;m; P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001; &#x223c;18% decrease) than in the Exercise group (-14.5&#xa0;N&#xa0;m; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.027; &#x223c;8% decrease; interaction P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.045). Leg lean mass decreased similarly in both groups (-0.418&#xa0;kg; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.013). Exercise prevented the decrease in MUP area observed in Controls (-65&#xa0;mV&#xb7;ms, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.240&#xa0;vs. -253&#xa0;mV&#xb7;ms, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001) and led to a reduction in MUFR (-1.05&#xa0;pulses/s, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001) not seen in Controls. NMJ transmission stability and CAF levels were unchanged in both groups. HDBR reduced leg lean mass and strength. Exercise attenuated declines in strength and MUP area, likely by preserving muscle fibre size despite reduced MUFR, without evidence of NMJ disruption. Exercise effectively attenuates neuromuscular decrements following HDBR in older adults, with implications for clinical care and spaceflight.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St-Martin</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9824-2072</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pluridisciplinaire Hubert Curien, Universit&#xe9; de Strasbourg, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lagac&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Christophe</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9101-9900</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruel</LastName><ForeName>Mathil</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7105-3045</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghachem</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xe9;onard</LastName><ForeName>Guillaume</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riesco</LastName><ForeName>Eleonor</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7804-4631</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piasecki</LastName><ForeName>Mathew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Metabolism, Ageing &amp; Physiology (COMAP) Injury, Recovery &amp; Inflammation Sciences, School of Medicine, NIHR Nottingham BRC, University of Nottingham, Royal Derby Hospital Centre, Derby, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McPhee</LastName><ForeName>Jamie S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3659-0773</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Manchester Metropolitan University Institute of Sport, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dionne</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre on Aging, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>CAPMC</Acronym><Agency> CIHR</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Vanier Canada Graduate Scholarship</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deconditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disuse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spaceflight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41719153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bates, D., M&#xe4;chler, M., Bolker, B., &amp; Walker, S. (2015). Fitting linear mixed&#x2010;effects models using lme4. Journal of Statistical Software, 67(1), 1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besomi, M., Hodges, P. W., Van Die&#xeb;n, J., Carson, R. G., Clancy, E. A., Disselhorst&#x2010;Klug, C., Holobar, A., Hug, F., Kiernan, M. C., Lowery, M., McGill, K., Merletti, R., Perreault, E., S&#xf8;gaard, K., Tucker, K., Besier, T., Enoka, R., Falla, D., Farina, D., &#x2026; Wrigley, T. (2019). Consensus for experimental design in electromyography (CEDE) project: Electrode selection matrix. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology, 48, 128&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deane, C. S., Piasecki, M., &amp; Atherton, P. J. (2024). Skeletal muscle immobilisation&#x2010;induced atrophy: Mechanistic insights from human studies. Clinical Science, 138(12), 741&#x2013;756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio, A., Holobar, A., Falla, D., Felici, F., Enoka, R. M., &amp; Farina, D. (2020). Tutorial: Analysis of motor unit discharge characteristics from high&#x2010;density surface EMG signals. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology, 53, 102426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo, F. G., Fiotti, N., Milanovi&#x107;, Z., Situlin, R., Mearelli, F., Vinci, P., &#x160;imuni&#x10d;, B., Pi&#x161;ot, R., Narici, M., &amp; Biolo, G. (2021). The aging muscle in experimental bed rest: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Frontiers in Nutrition, 8, 633987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirks, M. L., Wall, B. T., Van De Valk, B., Holloway, T. M., Holloway, G. P., Chabowski, A., Goossens, G. H., &amp; Van Loon, L. J. C. (2016). One week of bed rest leads to substantial muscle atrophy and induces whole&#x2010;body insulin resistance in the absence of skeletal muscle lipid accumulation. Diabetes, 65(10), 2862&#x2013;2875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulac, M., Hajj&#x2010;Boutros, G., Sonjak, V., Faust, A., Hussain, S. N. A., Chevalier, S., Dionne, I. J., Morais, J. A., &amp; Gouspillou, G. (2024). A multimodal exercise countermeasure prevents the negative impact of head&#x2010;down tilt bed rest on muscle volume and mitochondrial health in older adults. The Journal of Physiology, 603(13), 3813&#x2013;3836. JP285897..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka, R. M., &amp; Duchateau, J. (2017). Rate coding and the control of muscle force. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 7(10), a029702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes, M., Figueiredo, D., Teixeira, L., Poveda, V., Pa&#xfa;l, C., Santos&#x2010;Silva, A., &amp; Costa, E. (2017). Physical inactivity among older adults across Europe based on the SHARE database. Age and ageing, 46(1), 71&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X., Zhou, Y., Li, X., &amp; Mu, J. (2025). Resistance exercise training improves disuse&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle atrophy in humans: A meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders, 26(1), 134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., Jones, E. J., &#x160;karabot, J., Inns, T. B., Phillips, B. E., Atherton, P. J., &amp; Piasecki, M. (2024). Common synaptic inputs and persistent inward currents of vastus lateralis motor units are reduced in older male adults. GeroScience, 46(3), 3249&#x2013;3261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajj&#x2010;Boutros, G., Sonjak, V., Faust, A., Balram, S., Lagac&#xe9;, J., St&#x2010;Martin, P., Divsalar, D. N., Sadeghian, F., Liu&#x2010;Ambrose, T., Blaber, A. P., Dionne, I. J., Duchesne, S., Kontulainen, S., Theou, O., &amp; Morais, J. A. (2024). Myths and methodologies: Understanding the health impact of head down bedrest for the benefit of older adults and astronauts. Study protocol of the canadian bedrest study. Experimental Physiology, 109(5), 812&#x2013;827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajj&#x2010;Boutros, G., Sonjak, V., Faust, A., Hedge, E., Mastrandrea, C., Lagac&#xe9;, J. C., St&#x2010;Martin, P., Naz Divsalar, D., Sadeghian, F., Chevalier, S., Liu&#x2010;Ambrose, T., Blaber, A. P., Dionne, I. J., Duchesne, S., Hughson, R., Kontulainen, S., Theou, O., &amp; Morais, J. A. (2024). Impact of 14 days of bed rest in older adults and an exercise countermeasure on body composition, muscle strength, and cardiovascular function: Canadian space agency standard measures. Gerontology, 69(11), 1284&#x2013;1294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy, E. J. O., Inns, T. B., Hatt, J., Doleman, B., Bass, J. J., Atherton, P. J., Lund, J. N., &amp; Phillips, B. E. (2022). The time course of disuse muscle atrophy of the lower limb in health and disease. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 13(6), 2616&#x2013;2629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins, M. S., Storti, K. L., Richardson, C. R., King, W. C., Strath, S. J., Holleman, R. G., &amp; Kriska, A. M. (2009). Objectively measured physical activity of USA adults by sex, age, and racial/ethnic groups: A cross&#x2010;sectional study. International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity, 6(1), 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedge, E. T., Patterson, C. A., Mastrandrea, C. J., Sonjak, V., Hajj&#x2010;Boutros, G., Faust, A., Morais, J. A., &amp; Hughson, R. L. (2022). Implementation of exercise countermeasures during spaceflight and microgravity analogue studies: Developing countermeasure protocols for bedrest in older adults (BROA). Frontiers in Physiology, 13, 928313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inns, T. B., Bass, J. J., Hardy, E. J. O., Wilkinson, D. J., Stashuk, D. W., Atherton, P. J., Phillips, B. E., &amp; Piasecki, M. (2022). Motor unit dysregulation following 15 days of unilateral lower limb immobilisation. The Journal of Physiology, 600(21), 4753&#x2013;4769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, E. J., Guo, Y., Martinez&#x2010;Valdes, E., Negro, F., Stashuk, D. W., Atherton, P. J., Phillips, B. E., &amp; Piasecki, M. (2023). Acute adaptation of central and peripheral motor unit features to exercise&#x2010;induced fatigue differs with concentric and eccentric loading. Experimental Physiology, 108(6), 827&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, E. J., Piasecki, J., Ireland, A., Stashuk, D. W., Atherton, P. J., Phillips, B. E., McPhee, J. S., &amp; Piasecki, M. (2021). Lifelong exercise is associated with more homogeneous motor unit potential features across deep and superficial areas of vastus lateralis. GeroScience, 43(4), 1555&#x2013;1565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuiken, T. A., Lowery, M. M., &amp; Stoykov, N. S. (2003). The effect of subcutaneous fat on myoelectric signal amplitude and cross&#x2010;talk. Prosthetics &amp; Orthotics International, 27(1), 48&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, E.&#x2010;J., Jeong, H.&#x2010;B., Bae, J., &amp; Kim, S.&#x2010;J. (2025). A nationwide analysis of physical inactivity and sedentary behavior among stroke survivors in Korea. Scientific Reports, 15(1), 12174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marusic, U., Narici, M., Simunic, B., Pisot, R., &amp; Ritzmann, R. (2021). Nonuniform loss of muscle strength and atrophy during bed rest: A systematic review. Journal of Applied Physiology, 131(1), 194&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti, E., Reggiani, C., Franchi, M. V., Toniolo, L., Sandri, M., Armani, A., Zampieri, S., Giacomello, E., Sarto, F., Sirago, G., Murgia, M., Nogara, L., Marcucci, L., Ciciliot, S., &#x160;imunic, B., Pi&#x161;ot, R., &amp; Narici, M. V. (2021). Neuromuscular junction instability and altered intracellular calcium handling as early determinants of force loss during unloading in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 599(12), 3037&#x2013;3061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motanova, E., Sarto, F., Negro, S., Pirazzini, M., Rossetto, O., Rigoni, M., Stashuk, D. W., Gasparini, M., &#x160;imunic, B., Pi&#x161;ot, R., &amp; Narici, M. V. (2025). Neuromuscular junction instability with inactivity: Morphological and functional changes after 10 days of bed rest in older adults. The Journal of Physiology, 604(2), 868&#x2013;885. JP288448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtagh, E. M., Murphy, M. H., Murphy, N. M., Woods, C., Nevill, A. M., &amp; Lane, A. (2015). Prevalence and correlates of physical inactivity in community&#x2010;dwelling older adults in Ireland. PLoS ONE, 10(2), e0118293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes, E. A., Stokes, T., McKendry, J., Currier, B. S., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2022). Disuse&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle atrophy in disease and nondisease states in humans: Mechanisms, prevention, and recovery strategies. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 322(6), C1068&#x2013;C1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki, M. (2024). Motor unit adaptation to disuse: Crossing the threshold from firing rate suppression to neuromuscular junction transmission. The Journal of Physiology, 603(13), 3701&#x2013;3709. JP284159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki, M., Garn&#xe9;s&#x2010;Camarena, O., &amp; Stashuk, D. W. (2021). Near&#x2010;fiber electromyography. Clinical Neurophysiology, 132(5), 1089&#x2013;1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki, M., Ireland, A., Coulson, J., Stashuk, D. W., Hamilton&#x2010;Wright, A., Swiecicka, A., Rutter, M. K., McPhee, J. S., &amp; Jones, D. A. (2016). Motor unit number estimates and neuromuscular transmission in the tibialis anterior of master athletes: Evidence that athletic older people are not spared from age&#x2010;related motor unit remodeling. Physiological Reports, 4(19), e12987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki, M., Ireland, A., Jones, D. A., &amp; McPhee, J. S. (2016). Age&#x2010;dependent motor unit remodelling in human limb muscles. Biogerontology, 17(3), 485&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki, M., Ireland, A., Piasecki, J., Stashuk, D. W., Swiecicka, A., Rutter, M. K., Jones, D. A., &amp; McPhee, J. S. (2018). Failure to expand the motor unit size to compensate for declining motor unit numbers distinguishes sarcopenic from non&#x2010;sarcopenic older men. Journal of Physiology, 596(9), 1627&#x2013;1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy, P. T., Lindsay, C. C., McKenzie, A. I., Fry, C. S., Supiano, M. A., Marcus, R. L., LaStayo, P. C., &amp; Drummond, M. J. (2018). Aging&#x2010;related effects of bed rest followed by eccentric exercise rehabilitation on skeletal muscle macrophages and insulin sensitivity. Experimental Gerontology, 107, 37&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., &amp; Gruber, M. (2024). Neuromuscular mechanisms for the fast decline in rate of force development with muscle disuse&#x2014;a narrative review. The Journal of Physiology, 604(2), 735&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarto, F., Stashuk, D. W., Franchi, M. V., Monti, E., Zampieri, S., Valli, G., Sirago, G., Candia, J., Hartnell, L. M., Paganini, M., McPhee, J. S., De Vito, G., Ferrucci, L., Reggiani, C., &amp; Narici, M. V. (2022). Effects of short&#x2010;term unloading and active recovery on human motor unit properties, neuromuscular junction transmission and transcriptomic profile. The Journal of Physiology, 600(21), 4731&#x2013;4751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;lberg, E., Van Dijk, H., Falck, B., Kimura, J., Neuwirth, C., Pitt, M., Podnar, S., Rubin, D. I., Rutkove, S., Sanders, D. B., Sonoo, M., Tankisi, H., &amp; Zwarts, M. (2019). Standards for quantification of EMG and neurography. Clinical Neurophysiology, 130(9), 1688&#x2013;1729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;lberg, E. V., &amp; Sonoo, M. (1994). Assessment of variability in the shape of the motor unit action potential, the &#x201c;jiggle,&#x201d; at consecutive discharges. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 17(10), 1135&#x2013;1144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta, C., Hvid, L. G., Justesen, L., Christensen, U., Neergaard, K., Simonsen, L., Ortenblad, N., Magnusson, S. P., Kjaer, M., &amp; Aagaard, P. (2009). Effects of aging on human skeletal muscle after immobilization and retraining. Journal of Applied Physiology, 107(4), 1172&#x2013;1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troiano, R. P., Berrigan, D., Dodd, K. W., M&#xe2;sse, L. C., Tilert, T., &amp; Mcdowell, M. (2008). Physical activity in the United States measured by accelerometer. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 40(1), 181&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valli, G., Sarto, F., Casolo, A., Del Vecchio, A., Franchi, M. V., Narici, M. V., &amp; De Vito, G. (2024). Lower limb suspension induces threshold&#x2010;specific alterations of motor units properties that are reversed by active recovery. Journal of Sport and Health Science, 13(2), 264&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>