<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41114010</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Elevating surgical outcomes: a comprehensive analysis of innovative nursing practices in intraoperative care across diverse specialties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1665160</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1665160</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1665160</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2025.1665160</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The landscape of surgical care is undergoing a profound transformation, driven by rapid advancements in technology and a persistent focus on enhancing patient outcomes. At the forefront of this evolution are innovative nursing practices within the intraoperative setting, which are proving instrumental in elevating patient safety, optimizing operational efficiency, and significantly reducing complications across a spectrum of surgical specialties. This report provides a comprehensive analysis of these cutting-edge nursing interventions from the foundational principles of perioperative care to the integration of advanced technologies such as Artificial Intelligence (AI), robotics, virtual reality, and personalized medicine. Perioperative nurses, traditionally recognized for their critical roles in maintaining sterile environments and advocating for patient wellbeing, are now embracing expanded responsibilities as technological integrators, data interpreters, and champions of evidence-based protocols such as Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS). The adoption of these innovative practices has led to demonstrable improvements, including shorter hospital stays, reduced opioid consumption, and decreased complication rates. However, the path to widespread adoption is not without its challenges, encompassing human factors such as resistance to change, organizational barriers such as insufficient resources, and technical complexities related to data accuracy and regulation. To fully harness the potential of innovative intraoperative nursing, healthcare organizations must strategically invest in continuous, accessible training programs that balance technological proficiency with core nursing judgment. Cultivating a culture that empowers nurse-led innovation, prioritizes human-centered technology design, and strengthens multidisciplinary collaboration is paramount. Furthermore, a commitment to evidence-based implementation and addressing health equity in technology access will ensure that advancements benefit all patients and that the nursing profession continues to thrive as a vital force in shaping the future of surgical care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Guo, Zuo, Sun and Qian.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ling</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Huanying</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asthma Center, Children's Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yongmei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia and Surgery, Zibo Central Hospital, Zibo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Chengcheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intraoperative nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical innovation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41114010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12531267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1665160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hussain AK, Kakakhel MM, Ashraf MF, Shahab M, Ahmad F, Luqman F, et al. Innovative approaches to safe surgery: a narrative synthesis of best practices. Cureus. (2023) 15:e49723. 10.7759/cureus.49723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei Mohammadi A, Keihani Far Y, Hossein Zadeh R, Bagherian Kenari SBP, Erfan Ghanbarzadeh MK, Seyed Mohammad Ali Fazayel, PY, et al. Contemporary Surgical Innovations: A Comprehensive Guide to Emerging Technologies and Practices. Iran: Independently; (2024). p. 283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chellam Singh B, Arulappan J. Operating room nurses' understanding of their roles and responsibilities for patient care and safety measures in intraoperative practice. SAGE Open Nurs. (2023) 9:23779608231186247. 10.1177/23779608231186247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23779608231186247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10350747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37465651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao L, Lu Q, Hou X, Ou J, Wang M. Effectiveness of a nursing innovation workshop at enhancing nurses' innovation abilities: a quasi-experimental study. Nurs Open. (2022) 9:418&#x2013;27. 10.1002/nop2.1080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.1080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8685873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard N. Nursing care delivery models. The perioperative environment. Aorn J. (1993) 57:481&#x2013;8. 10.1016/S0001-2092(07)64104-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0001-2092(07)64104-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8424634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clipper B. The Innovation Handbook: A Nurse Leader's Guide to Transforming Nursing. Indianapolis, IN: Sigma Theta Tau; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lives SSS. WHO Guidelines for Safe Surgery 2009. Geneva: World Health Organization; (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23762968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqarny HAM, Algarni ANM, Alshehri ASM, Alshehri MAY, Alshehri MMM, Alshehri AA, et al. Interdisciplinary collaboration in healthcare: the synergy of nurses, laboratory services, anesthesiologists, emergency, and operative teams. J Int Crisis Risk Commun Res. (2024) 7:1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanawi MK, Hilal FM, Aljohani AM, Bader HA, Almalky MA, Shiekh KE, et al. Exploring the role of operating room technician in maintaining safety and accuracy in anesthetic drug delivery. J Int Crisis Risk Commun Res. (2024) 7:3119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen PD. Artificial intelligence and nursing practice. Rehabil Nurs. (2024) 49:73&#x2013;4. 10.1097/RNJ.0000000000000454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RNJ.0000000000000454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38696432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stella M, Zaytseva A. Forma mentis networks map how nursing and engineering students enhance their mindsets about innovation and health during professional growth. PeerJ Comput Sci. (2020) 6:e255. 10.7717/peerj-cs.255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj-cs.255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33816907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baradaran K, Gracia C, Alimohammadi E. Exploring strategies to enhance patient safety in spine surgery: a review. Patient Saf Surg. (2025) 19:3. 10.1186/s13037-025-00426-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13037-025-00426-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11730817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39810234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamina M, Gi&#xe9; O, Demartines N, Ris F. Contemporary perioperative care strategies. J Br Surg. (2013) 100:38&#x2013;54. 10.1002/bjs.8990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bjs.8990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23165446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean HF, Carter F, Francis NK. Modern perioperative medicine - past, present, and future. Innov Surg Sci. (2019) 4:123&#x2013;31. 10.1515/iss-2019-0014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/iss-2019-0014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8059350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almansour MS, Althobiti NMA, Alharthi FFA, Alharthi MAG, Alharthi ASD, Al Mansour MHA, et al. Preparing the operating room for various surgical procedures. J Int Crisis Risk Commun Res. (2024) 7:3258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein AM. Enhancing patient safety in the operating room: a comprehensive guide from a nurse's perspective. Open J Nurs. (2024) 14:252&#x2013;66. 10.4236/ojn.2024.146018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojn.2024.146018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar Maya &#xc1;M, Osorio Galeano SP. Nursing care related with surgical position. Investigaci&#xf3;n y educaci&#xf3;n en enfermer&#xed;a. Invest Educ Enferm. (2023) 41:03. 10.17533/udea.iee.v41n1e03</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17533/udea.iee.v41n1e03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10152920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37071860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderton J. The prone position for the surgical patient: a historical review of the principles and hazards. Br J Anaesth. (1991) 67:452&#x2013;63. 10.1093/bja/67.4.452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/67.4.452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1931403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham J, Rosen M, Greilich PE. Improving perioperative handoffs: moving beyond standardized checklists and protocols. Joint Comm J Qual Patient Saf. (2023) 49:341&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.jcjq.2023.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcjq.2023.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10754391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37353400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achrekar MS. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) nursing programme. Asia-Pac J Oncol Nurs. (2022) 9:3. 10.1016/j.apjon.2022.02.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apjon.2022.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35620398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithany RH, Daniel N, Shahid MH, Aslam S, Abdelmaseeh M, Gerges F, et al. Revolutionizing surgical care: the power of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS). Cureus. (2023) 15:e48795. 10.7759/cureus.48795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.48795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10646429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38024087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzzi G, Ricciuti RA, Della Torre A, Lo Turco E, Lavano A, Longhini F, et al. Intraoperative neurophysiological monitoring in neurosurgery. J Clin Med. (2024) 13:2966. 10.3390/jcm13102966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13102966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38792507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliva AM, Montejano J, Simmons CG, Vogel SA, Isaza CF, Clavijo CF. New frontiers in intraoperative neurophysiologic monitoring: a narrative review. Ann Transl Med. (2023) 11:388. 10.21037/atm-22-4586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/atm-22-4586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10632568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37970609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Wu L. Analysis of the effects of evidence-based nursing interventions on promoting functional recovery in neurology and general surgery intensive care patients. Altern Ther Health Med. (2024) 30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38518143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson U, Gruen R, Myles P. Postoperative recovery: the importance of the team. Anaesthesia. (2020) 75:e158&#x2013;64. 10.1111/anae.14869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.14869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31903575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peate I. Alexander's Nursing Practice: Hospital and Home. London: Elsevier; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titler MG. The evidence for evidence-based practice implementation. In:Hughes RG, editor. Patient safety and Quality: An Evidence-based handBook for Nurses. Rockville, MD: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21328752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernstmeyer K, Christman E. Chapter 4: Nursing process. In:Open Resources for Nursing (Open RN); Ernstmeyer K, Christman E, editors. Nursing Fundamentals. Eau Claire, WI: Chippewa Valley Technical College; (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37196137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari L, Aarabi A, Bahrami M. Challenges of intraoperative documentation and its role in patient safety: an integrative review. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. (2025) 30:141&#x2013;9. 10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_413_23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_413_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12017641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhaseri MOM, Ashour AS, Albishri BH, Al-Mutairi AH, Al-Hazmi MA, Alhujaily YM, et al. The Role of Operating Room and Anesthesia Technicians in Ensuring Surgical Success and Patient Safety. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loftus TJ, Tighe PJ, Filiberto AC, Efron PA, Brakenridge SC, Mohr AM, et al. Artificial intelligence and surgical decision-making. JAMA Surg. (2020) 155:148&#x2013;58. 10.1001/jamasurg.2019.4917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2019.4917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31825465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi O. Innovations in surgical healthcare: the future of medicine. Int J Res Med Health Sci. (2025) 1:1&#x2212;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singam A. Revolutionizing patient care: a comprehensive review of artificial intelligence applications in anesthesia. Cureus. (2023) 15:e49887. 10.7759/cureus.49887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10762564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38174199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijkamp N, Wakefield E. The Future of Artificial Intelligence in Perioperative Nursing. Lyndoch, SA: ACORN; (2024). p. e1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon D, Sattar H, Moros N, Kesireddy SR, Ahsan H, Lakkimsetti M, et al. Unveiling the influence of AI predictive analytics on patient outcomes: a comprehensive narrative review. Cureus. (2024) 16:e59954. 10.7759/cureus.59954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.59954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11161909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38854327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Pan S, Liu X, Hong M, Nong C, Zhang W. The integration of AI in nursing: addressing current applications, challenges, and future directions. Front Med. (2025) 12:1545420. 10.3389/fmed.2025.1545420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1545420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11850350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40007584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rony MKK, Alrazeeni DM, Akter F, Nesa L, Chandra Das D, Uddin MJ, et al. The role of artificial intelligence in enhancing nurses' work-life balance. J Med Surg Public Health. (2024) 3:100135. 10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rony MKK, Parvin MR, Ferdousi S. Advancing nursing practice with artificial intelligence: enhancing preparedness for the future. Nurs Open. (2024) 11:2070. 10.1002/nop2.2070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.2070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10733565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38268252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleki Varnosfaderani S, Forouzanfar M. The Role of AI in hospitals and clinics: transforming healthcare in the 21st century. Bioengineering. (2024) 11:337. 10.3390/bioengineering11040337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering11040337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38671759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal AI, Aamir A, Hammad A, Hafsa H, Basit A, Oduoye MO, et al. Immersive technologies in healthcare: an in-depth exploration of virtual reality and augmented reality in enhancing patient care, medical education, and training paradigms. J Prim Care Community Health. (2024) 15:21501319241293311. 10.1177/21501319241293311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501319241293311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11528804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havola S, Haavisto E, M&#xe4;kinen H, Engblom J, Koivisto J-M. The effects of computer-based simulation game and virtual reality simulation in nursing students' self-evaluated clinical reasoning skills. CIN: Comput Inf Nurs. (2021) 39:725&#x2013;35. 10.1097/CIN.0000000000000748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CIN.0000000000000748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keny C. The Potential of Immersive Virtual Reality as a Non-Pharmacological Method for Postoperative Pain Relief Among Older Adults. San Francisco, CA: University of California, San Francisco; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyonkuru E, Iqbal MA, Zhang X, Ma P. Complementary approaches to postoperative pain management: a review of non-pharmacological interventions. Pain Ther. (2025) 14:121&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s40122-024-00688-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40122-024-00688-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11751213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39681763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlet M. Chapter 7 - Surgery of the future: harnessing the power of virtual reality and augmented reality. In:Hemanth DJ, Jeyanthi PM, editors. Leveraging Metaverse and Analytics of Things (AoT) in Medical Systems. Cambridge, MA: Academic Press; (2025). p. 125&#x2013;45. 10.1016/B978-0-443-24049-2.00003-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-443-24049-2.00003-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruscher A. Optimizing Postoperative Care: The Significance of Simulation Training in Reducing Adverse Events and Promoting Patient Safety. Boston, MA: Northeastern University; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeghe EP, Okolo CA, Ojeyinka OT. A review of wearable technology in healthcare: monitoring patient health and enhancing outcomes. OARJ Multidiscip Stud. (2024) 7:142&#x2013;8. 10.53022/oarjms.2024.7.1.0019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53022/oarjms.2024.7.1.0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelboom G, Yang AH, Christophe BR, Bruce EM, Slomian J, Bruy&#xe8;re O, et al. The promise of wearable activity sensors to define patient recovery. J Clin Neurosci. (2014) 21:1089&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.jocn.2013.12.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2013.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24534628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalid N, Zaidan A, Zaidan B, Salman OH, Hashim M, Muzammil H. Based real time remote health monitoring systems: a review on patients prioritization and related&#x201c; big data&#x201d; using body sensors information and communication technology. J Med Syst. (2018) 42:1&#x2013;30. 10.1007/s10916-018-0916-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10916-018-0916-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29288419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddahchouri Y, Peelen RV, Koeneman M, Touw HR, van Goor H, Bredie SJ. Effect of continuous wireless vital sign monitoring on unplanned ICU admissions and rapid response team calls: a before-and-after study. Br J Anaesth. (2022) 128:857&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.bja.2022.01.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2022.01.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang HS, Exworthy M. Wearing the future&#x2014;wearables to empower users to take greater responsibility for their health and care: scoping review. JMIR mHealth uHealth. (2022) 10:e35684. 10.2196/35684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/35684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35830222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tariq MU. Advanced wearable medical devices and their role in transformative remote health monitoring. In: Transformative Approaches to Patient Literacy and Healthcare Innovation. London: IGI Global; (2024). p. 308&#x2013;26. 10.4018/979-8-3693-3661-8.ch015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-3661-8.ch015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima S. Transforming healthcare with AI and machine learning: revolutionizing patient care through advanced analytics. Int J Educ Sci Res Rev. (2024) 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przadka M, Pajak W, Kleinrok J, Pec J, Michno K, Karpi&#x144;ski R, et al. Advances in 3D printing applications for personalized orthopedic surgery: from anatomical modeling to patient-specific implants. J Clin Med. (2025) 14:3989. 10.3390/jcm14113989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14113989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12156138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40507750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malukhin K, Ehmann K. Mathematical modeling and virtual reality simulation of surgical tool interactions with soft tissue: a review and prospective. J Eng Sci Med Diagn Ther. (2018) 1:020802. 10.1115/1.4039417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4039417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadero PE, Shah M. Three dimensional (3D) modelling and surgical planning in trauma and orthopaedics. Surgeon. (2014) 12:328&#x2013;33. 10.1016/j.surge.2014.03.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surge.2014.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24821263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong AJ, Smith M, Langerman A. Efficiency improvement in the operating room. J Surg Res. (2016) 204:371&#x2013;83. 10.1016/j.jss.2016.04.054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jss.2016.04.054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27565073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakshi I, Rawat HS, Singh S. Exploring the impact of 3D printing on advancing reconstructive surgery: a comprehensive review. Int Multidiscip Res J. (2024) 6:1&#x2013;16. 10.36948/ijfmr.2024.v06i02.14675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36948/ijfmr.2024.v06i02.14675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paxton NC, Tetsworth K, Woodruff MA. Personalization for surgical implants. In:Paul G, Doweidar MH, editors. Digital Human Modeling and Medicine. London: Elsevier; (2023). p. 849&#x2013;74. 10.1016/B978-0-12-823913-1.00019-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-823913-1.00019-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SE, Chen Y. Blockchain in health care innovation: literature review and case study from a business ecosystem perspective. J Med Internet Res. (2020) 22:e19480. 10.2196/19480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Crespo RG, Mart&#xed;nez OS. Enhancing privacy and data security across healthcare applications using blockchain and distributed ledger concepts. Healthcare. (2020) 8:243. 10.3390/healthcare8030243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare8030243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7684467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32751325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Beshi ZI, Altuwayr GM, Alaryani SA, Beshi FI, Alghamdi SSA, Alobayli MYS. Leveraging the Implementation of Technology in Enhancing Nursing Practice and Patient Outcomes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Ding H, Shen C, Liu Y, Jia N. Evaluating the role of nursing interventions in enhanced recovery after surgery for minimally invasive spine surgery: a retrospective analysis. Fron Surg. (2025) 12:1519135. 10.3389/fsurg.2025.1519135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsurg.2025.1519135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40046500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Yan C, Li J, Wang Q, Zhang J, Qiang W, et al. A nurse-driven enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) nursing program for geriatric patients following lung surgery. Thorac Cancer. (2020) 11:1105&#x2013;13. 10.1111/1759-7714.13372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1759-7714.13372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7113056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32120450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain SN, Lamture Y, Krishna M. Enhanced recovery after surgery: exploring the advances and strategies. Cureus. (2023) 15:e47237. 10.7759/cureus.47237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.47237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10654132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38022245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail MF, Sharma R. Redefining Perioperative Care: The Pivotal Role of Anesthesiologists in Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) Protocols.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tippireddy S, Ghatol D. Anesthetic Management for Enhanced Recovery After Major Surgery (ERAS). Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34662081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman AD, Helpman L, McGee J, Samou&#xeb;lian V, Auclair MH, Brar H, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery: implementing a new standard of surgical care. CMAJ. (2019) 191:E469&#x2013;75. 10.1503/cmaj.180635</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.180635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6488471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31036609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TE, Roche AM, Mythen M. Fluid management and goal-directed therapy as an adjunct to Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS). Can J Anaesth. (2015) 62:158&#x2013;68. 10.1007/s12630-014-0266-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12630-014-0266-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25391735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazreean R, Nelson G, Twomey R. Early mobilization in enhanced recovery after surgery pathways: current evidence and recent advancements. J Comp Eff Res. (2022) 11:121&#x2013;9. 10.2217/cer-2021-0258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2021-0258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou D, Mundis G, Wang M, Fu K-M, Shaffrey C, Okonkwo D, et al. Minimally invasive surgery for mild-to-moderate adult spinal deformities: impact on intensive care unit and hospital stay. World Neurosurg. (2019) 127:e649&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.wneu.2019.03.237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2019.03.237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30947010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echeverria-Villalobos M, Stoicea N, Todeschini AB, Fiorda-Diaz J, Uribe AA, Weaver T, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS): a perspective review of postoperative pain management under ERAS pathways and its role on opioid crisis in the United States. Clin J Pain. (2020) 36:219&#x2013;26. 10.1097/AJP.0000000000000792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AJP.0000000000000792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balfour A, Amery J, Burch J, Smid&#x2013;Nanninga H. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS<sup>&#xae;</sup>): barriers and solutions for nurses. Asia-Pac J Oncol Nurs. (2022) 9:100040. 10.1016/j.apjon.2022.02.002
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apjon.2022.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan VS, editor Maximizing Workforce. HRD for Developing States and Companies: Proceedings of the 2005 Brunei Darussalam AEMC Convention. Singapore: Institute of Southeast Asian Studies; (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Yu B, Ou Y, Zhou X, Zou S, Peng H, et al. Progress of research on methods of human resource allocation in operating room nursing. Front Public Health. (2025) 13:1539108. 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1539108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1539108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12164728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40520322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaw KW, Alnoor A, Al-Abrrow H, Tiberius V, Ganesan Y, Atshan NA. Reactions towards organizational change: a systematic literature review. Curr Psychol. (2022) 1&#x2013;24. 10.1007/s12144-022-03070-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-022-03070-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9006211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths P, Saville C, Ball J, Jones J, Pattison N, Monks T. Nursing workload, nurse staffing methodologies and tools: a systematic scoping review and discussion. Int J Nurs Stud. (2020) 103:103487. 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.103487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.103487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31884330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cenacchi C, Giusti M, Peghetti A, Quirini S, Tinelli F, Giorgi S, et al. Optimization of nursing staff standards in the perioperative settings of the IRCCS University Hospital of Bologna. An improvement project. Front Public Health. (2025) 13:1601290. 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1601290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1601290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12241087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40642247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namaganda GN, Whitright A, Maniple EB. Lessons learned from implementation of the Workload Indicator of Staffing Need (WISN) methodology: an international Delphi study of expert users. Hum Resour Health. (2022) 19:138. 10.1186/s12960-021-00675-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-021-00675-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8796553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35090491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-R, Zhou K, Zhang W. Application progress of nursing intervention in cardiac surgery. World J Clin Cases. (2023) 11:7943. 10.12998/wjcc.v11.i33.7943</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i33.7943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10698403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38075584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmetwaly RM, El Sayed RA. Chest tube removal: efficacy of cold application and breathing exercises on pain and anxiety level. Evid-Based Nurs Res. (2020) 2:12. 10.47104/ebnrojs3.v2i4.159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47104/ebnrojs3.v2i4.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K, Shao X, Lv X, Yang F, Shen Q, Fang J, et al. Perioperative psychological issues and nursing care among patients undergoing minimally invasive surgeries. Laparosc Endosc Robot Surg. (2022) 5:92&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.lers.2022.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lers.2022.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobdell KW, Appoo JJ, Rose GA, Ferguson B, Chatterjee S. Technological advances to enhance recovery after cardiac surgery. J Hosp Manag Health Policy. (2021) 5. 10.21037/jhmhp-20-114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jhmhp-20-114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raheem AA, Song HJ, Chang KD, Choi YD, Rha KH. Robotic nurse duties in the urology operative room: 11 years of experience. Asian J Urol. (2017) 4:116&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.ajur.2016.09.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajur.2016.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29264216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardin SR, Kaplow R. Cardiac Surgery Essentials for Critical Care Nursing. Burlington, MA: Jones &amp; Bartlett Learning; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu X. Nurse-led intervention in the management of patients with cardiovascular diseases: a brief literature review. BMC Nurs. (2024) 23:6. 10.1186/s12912-023-01422-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-023-01422-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10759353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38163878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J. Impacts of operating room refined nursing on orthopedic surgery patients. Bone Arthrosurg Sci. (2023) 1:14&#x2013;20. 10.26689/bas.v1i3.5726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26689/bas.v1i3.5726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong KC. 3D-printed patient-specific applications in orthopedics. Orthop Res Rev. (2016) 8:57&#x2013;66. 10.2147/ORR.S99614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/ORR.S99614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6209352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30774470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almutairi AND, Alshahrani WAF, Almansour HAA, Alotaibi KM, Alqasmi LH, Sheikh MM, et al. The role of advanced prosthetic technologies in enhancing patient mobility and independence: implications for nursing practice in orthopedic surgery. J Ecohumanism. (2024) 3:13048&#x2013;55. 10.62754/joe.v3i8.6169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62754/joe.v3i8.6169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Ahedo C, Lopez-Reyes A, Martinez-Armenta C, Martinez-Gomez LE, Martinez-Nava GA, Pineda C, et al. Revolutionizing orthopedics: a comprehensive review of robot-assisted surgery, clinical outcomes, and the future of patient care. J Robot Surg. (2023) 17:2575&#x2013;81. 10.1007/s11701-023-01697-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11701-023-01697-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37639163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struemph JM, Chong AC, Wooley PH. Evaluation of different experience levels of orthopaedic residents effect on polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA) bone cement mechanical properties. Iowa Orthop J. (2015) 35:193&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora M, Chan EK, Gupta S, Diwan AD. Polymethylmethacrylate bone cements and additives: a review of the literature. World J Orthop. (2013) 4:67&#x2013;74. 10.5312/wjo.v4.i2.67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v4.i2.67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23610754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shady RHA, El-Shaboury RHR, Elsaid RAA, Ahmed SAE-M, Badawy GG, Hamed WE, et al. Enhancing nursing practice through patient outcome measures: a framework for optimizing care in intracranial surgery. BMC Nurs. (2025) 24:402. 10.1186/s12912-025-02960-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-02960-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11987256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40211266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagzoog N. Feasibility of Skull Base Neuronavigation Using Optical Topographic Imaging Toward Guidance of Human and Robotic Drill Operators. Toronto, ON: University of Toronto; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertsch JH, Moreira JJ, Lee GR, Hastings JD, Ritzl E, Eccher MA, et al. Practice guidelines for the supervising professional: intraoperative neurophysiological monitoring. J Clin Monit Comput. (2019) 33:175&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s10877-018-0201-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10877-018-0201-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6420431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30374759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagpal K, Vats A, Lamb B, Ashrafian H, Sevdalis N, Vincent C, et al. Information transfer and communication in surgery: a systematic review. Ann Surg. (2010) 252:225&#x2013;39. 10.1097/SLA.0b013e3181e495c2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0b013e3181e495c2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshammri A, Almalki A, Alasmary M, Alshihre M, Al-Qarni H, Alqahtani T, et al. The impact of patient-centered care at work: make a difference to the patient experience. Int J Sci Res. (2022) 1:171&#x2013;87. 10.59992/IJSR.2022.v1n2p8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59992/IJSR.2022.v1n2p8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darko EM, Kleib M, Lemermeyer G, Tavakoli M. Robotics in nursing: protocol for a scoping review. JMIR Res Protoc. (2023) 12:e50626. 10.2196/50626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/50626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10682918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37955956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos R. Healing Milestones: Charting Medicine's Remarkable Voyage Through Time (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anurogo D, Hidayat NA. The Art Of Televasculobiomedicine 5.0. Makassar: Nas Media Pustaka (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani Z, Chouk I. Consumer resistance to innovation in services: challenges and barriers in the internet of things era. J Prod Innov Manag. (2018) 35:780&#x2013;807. 10.1111/jpim.12463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpim.12463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary G. Unveiling the black box: bringing algorithmic transparency to AI. Masaryk Univ J Law Technol. (2024) 18:93&#x2013;122. 10.5817/MUJLT2024-1-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5817/MUJLT2024-1-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone M, Way DP, Leung CG, Danforth D, Maicher K, Vakil J, et al. Evaluation of high-fidelity and virtual reality simulation platforms for assessing fourth-year medical students' encounters with patients in need of urgent or emergent care. Ann Med. (2024) 56:2382947. 10.1080/07853890.2024.2382947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2024.2382947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11290289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39078334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed H, Olanrewaju OA, Owusu FA, Saleem A, Pavani P, Tariq H, et al. Challenges and solutions in postoperative complications: a narrative review in general surgery. Cureus. (2023) 15:e50942. 10.7759/cureus.50942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.50942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10803891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38264378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngafeeson M. Understanding User Resistance to Information Technology in Healthcare: The Nature and Role Of Perceived Threats. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin SM, El-Gazar HE, Zoromba MA, El-Sayed MM, Atta MHR. Sentiment of nurses towards artificial intelligence and resistance to change in healthcare organisations: a mixed-method study. J Adv Nurs. (2025) 81:2087&#x2013;98. 10.1111/jan.16435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jan.16435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39235193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor M, Boland M, Buus N. Autonomy, evidence and intuition: nurses and decision-making. J Adv Nurs. (2010) 66:1584&#x2013;91. 10.1111/j.1365-2648.2010.05317.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2648.2010.05317.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20497271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AT, Ramasamy RK, Subbarao A. Barriers to and facilitators of technology adoption in emergency departments: a comprehensive review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2025) 22:479. 10.3390/ijerph22040479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph22040479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12027005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40283708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward D, Bungay V, Wolff AC, MacDonald V. A qualitative study of experienced nurses' voluntary turnover: learning from their perspectives. J Clin Nurs. (2016) 25:1336&#x2013;45. 10.1111/jocn.13210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.13210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26990238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konda NN, Lewis TL, Furness HN, Miller GW, Metcalfe AJ, Ellard DR. Surgeon views regarding the adoption of a novel surgical innovation into clinical practice: systematic review. BJS Open. (2024) 8:zrad141. 10.1093/bjsopen/zrad141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjsopen/zrad141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10807848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38266120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin P, Jamal O, Bozorg S, Khullar T, Workman R. Overcoming the Barriers to AI Adoption in Transport. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adepoju AH, Austin-Gabriel B, Eweje A, Collins A. Framework for automating multi-team workflows to maximize operational efficiency and minimize redundant data handling. IRE J. (2022) 5:663&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AMERICAN NURSES Association. The Ethical Use of Artificial Intelligence in Nursing practice. Position Statement by ANA Center for Ethics and Human Rights. Silver Spring, MD: American Nurses Association; (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balahur A, Jenet A, Hupont IT, Charisi V, Ganesh A, Griesinger CB, et al. Data Quality Requirements for Inclusive, Non-Biased and Trustworthy AI. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson SM, Prybutok V. Balancing privacy and progress: a review of privacy challenges, systemic oversight, and patient perceptions in AI-driven healthcare. Appl Sci. (2024) 14:675. 10.3390/app14020675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14020675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn M. The digital dilemma in nursing: a critique of care in the digital age. Br J Nurs. (2024) 33:496&#x2013;9. 10.12968/bjon.2024.0023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/bjon.2024.0023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38850140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson EA, Galatzan BJ. A critical juncture: reimagining nursing professional identity and regulation in the ethical integration of innovation and technology in healthcare. J Nurs Regul. (2025) 16:10&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jnr.2025.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnr.2025.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahsan MJ. Cultivating a culture of learning: the role of leadership in fostering lifelong development. Learn Organ. (2025) 32:282&#x2013;306. 10.1108/TLO-03-2024-0099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/TLO-03-2024-0099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metwaly A. A Design-Led Approach to Driving Successful R&amp;D Transformations. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bynens M. Empowering Excellence: Strategies for Cultivating a Culture of Bold Decision-Making in Teams.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madanchian M. Leadership dynamics in innovative teams. In: Mastering Innovation in Business. London: IGI Global; (2025). p. 103&#x2013;30. 10.4018/979-8-3693-3759-2.ch005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-3759-2.ch005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes JO, Olleros FX. Microfactories and the new economies of scale and scope. J Manuf Technol Manag. (2020) 31:72&#x2013;90. 10.1108/JMTM-07-2018-0213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JMTM-07-2018-0213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koukourikos K, Tsaloglidou A, Kourkouta L, Papathanasiou IV, Iliadis C, Fratzana A, et al. Simulation in clinical nursing education. Acta Inform Med. (2021) 29:15&#x2013;20. 10.5455/aim.2021.29.15-20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/aim.2021.29.15-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8116070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elendu C, Amaechi DC, Okatta AU, Amaechi EC, Elendu TC, Ezeh CP, et al. The impact of simulation-based training in medical education: a review. Medicine. (2024) 103:e38813. 10.1097/MD.0000000000038813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000038813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38968472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen FQ, Leng YF, Ge JF, Wang DW, Li C, Chen B, et al. Effectiveness of virtual reality in nursing education: meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res. (2020) 22:e18290. 10.2196/18290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/18290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32930664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips-Wren G, AI. tools in decision making support systems: a review. Int J Artif Intell Tools. (2012) 21:1240005. 10.1142/S0218213012400052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218213012400052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoman H. Identification Ranking and Prioritization of Decision-Making Criteria for the Early Adoption of Innovative Surgical Technologies into the Canadian Healthcare System: A Multi-Criteria Decision Analysis. Montreal, QC: McGill University; (2023). 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.43703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.43703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broome ME. Transformational Leadership in Nursing: From Expert Clinician to Influential Leader. Cham: springer publishing company. (2024). 10.1891/9780826192554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/9780826192554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider M. Public Policy [Master Thesis]. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A, McGough D, Austin S, editors. Integration of BIM in higher education: case study of the adoption of bim into coventry university's department of civil engineering, architecture and building. In: Sustainable Building and Construction Conference. Coventry: Coventry University; (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton JL, Miller KJ. Professional and regulatory infection control guidelines: collaboration to promote patient safety. AORN J. (2017) 106:201&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.aorn.2017.07.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aorn.2017.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams K. Guidelines in practice: patient information management. AORN J. (2023) 117:52&#x2013;60. 10.1002/aorn.13844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aorn.13844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36573752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Applequist J, Miller-Day M, Cronholm PF, Gabbay RA, Bowen DS. &#x201c;In principle we have agreement, but in practice it is a bit more difficult&#x201d;: obtaining organizational buy-in to patient-centered medical home transformation. Qual Health Res. (2017) 27:909&#x2013;22. 10.1177/1049732316680601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732316680601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27909251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston KA, Taylor M. Engagement as communication: pathways, possibilities, and future directions. In: Johnston KA, Taylor M, editors. The Handbook of Communication Engagement. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons; (2018). p. 1&#x2013;15. 10.1002/9781119167600.ch1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781119167600.ch1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camargo FC, Iwamoto HH, Galv&#xe3;o CM, Monteiro DAT, Goulart MB, Garcia LAA. Models for the implementation of evidence-based practice in hospital based nursing: a narrative review1. Texto Contexto-Enfermagem. (2018) 26. 10.1590/0104-07072017002070017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0104-07072017002070017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimb&#xf6;ck F, Eichhorn J. Creating A Virtual Nursing Journal Club: AN Innovative Teaching Method to Achieve Evidence-Based Practice in Healthcare. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T. How to Implement Evidence-based Healthcare. Hoboken, NJ: John John Wiley &amp; Sons; (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda N, Perez N, Tsangaris E, Edelen M, Pusic A, Zheng F, et al. Enhancing patient-centered surgical care with mobile health technology. J Surg Res. (2022) 274:178&#x2013;84. 10.1016/j.jss.2022.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jss.2022.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekbolatova M, Mayer J, Ong CW, Toma M, editors. Transformative potential of AI in healthcare: definitions, applications, and navigating the ethical landscape and public perspectives. Healthcare. (2024) 12:125. 10.3390/healthcare12020125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare12020125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10815906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangun AV, Pragholapati A. Enhancing critical thinking skills in nursing higher education in preparation for the industrial revolution 4.0. KnE Life Sci. (2021) 793&#x2212;804. 10.18502/kls.v6i1.8756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/kls.v6i1.8756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King CR, Shambe A, Abraham J. Potential uses of AI for perioperative nursing handoffs: a qualitative study. JAMIA Open. (2023) 6:ooad015. 10.1093/jamiaopen/ooad015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamiaopen/ooad015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10019806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36935899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez AMR, Bhatia I, Pinto SF. Navigating Artificial Intelligence from a Human Rights Lens: Impacts, Tradeoffs and Regulations for Groups in Vulnerable Situations. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George AS, Baskar T, Srikaanth PB. The erosion of cognitive skills in the technological age: how reliance on technology impacts critical thinking, problem-solving, and creativity. Partners Univers Innov Res Publ. (2024) 2:147&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leoni L, Gueli G, Ardolino M, Panizzon M, Gupta S. AI-empowered KM processes for decision-making: empirical evidence from worldwide organisations. J Knowl Manag. (2024) 28:320&#x2013;47. 10.1108/JKM-03-2024-0262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JKM-03-2024-0262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavanya C. Nursing Management and Leadership. Bhopal: Academic Guru Publishing House; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelne S, Chaudhary M, Dod K, Sayyad A, Sharma R. Harnessing the power of AI: a comprehensive review of its impact and challenges in nursing science and healthcare. Cureus. (2023) 15:e49252. 10.7759/cureus.49252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10744168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38143615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>