<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41099029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-1078</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-regulation as a stronger predictor than motivation of translation competence: a mixed-methods study of undergraduate translation students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1582455</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1582455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1582455</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1582455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study moves beyond the traditional focus on motivation to critically examine the dominant role of self-regulation in shaping translation competence within a flipped classroom setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A mixed-methods design was employed with data collected from 131 undergraduate translation students through questionnaires, translation tests, and interviews. Regression analyses were used to assess the predictive strength of motivation and self-regulation, and qualitative interviews provided further insights into students' learning experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings reveal that while motivation initiates learner engagement, it is self-regulation-encompassing goal-setting, self-monitoring, and strategic adaptation-that ultimately determines students' ability to navigate the complex demands of translation tasks. Regression results confirmed that self-regulation is a stronger and more consistent predictor of translation competence than motivation. Qualitative data further showed that highly motivated students without self-regulatory strategies often struggled to succeed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">These results highlight the limitations of motivation alone and call for a paradigm shift in translator education. Pedagogical models should move beyond motivation enhancement to explicitly cultivate learners' self-regulation skills. Embedding cognitive and metacognitive training into translation curricula can better prepare students for the complexities of professional practice. This study contributes empirical evidence and pedagogical insights to both translation studies and educational psychology, advocating the development of strategic, self-directed translation professionals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Xu and Gu&#xe9;nier.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Advanced Translation and Interpretation, Dalian University of Foreign Languages, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu&#xe9;nier</LastName><ForeName>Amily D Wang</ForeName><Initials>ADW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Global Affairs, Lancaster University, Lancaster, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-1078</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flipped classroom</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">translation competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">undergraduate translation students</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41099029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12518226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1582455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abeysekera L., Dawson P. (2015). Motivation and cognitive load in the flipped classroom: definition, rationale and a call for research. High. Educ. Res. Dev. 34, 1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/07294360.2014.934336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07294360.2014.934336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams N. E. (2015). Bloom&#x2019;s taxonomy of cognitive learning objectives. J. Med. Libr. Assoc: JMLA. 103:152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4511057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameri S., Ghahari S. (2018). Developing a motivational framework in translation training programs: a mixed methods study following self-determination and social capital theories. Interpr. Transl. Train. 12, 227&#x2013;243. doi: 10.1080/1750399X.2018.1465678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750399X.2018.1465678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameri S., Sadrnia P. (2025). Examining the interplay between translation students&#x2019; grit, self-efficacy and academic achievement. Babel.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherzadeh H. S., Ghaemi H., Izadysadr A. (2021). The effects of pot-luck flipped classrooms (PFC) on the development of translation competence: a study of novice translators. Applied Res Eng Lang 10, 1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.22108/are.2021.128132.1707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22108/are.2021.128132.1707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakat F. H. (2024). The effect of using self-regulation strategies on developing translation skills and attitude towards translation for university students. Sohag University Int J Educ Res. 9, 1&#x2013;36. doi: 10.21608/suijer.2024.339387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/suijer.2024.339387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnard L., Lan W. Y., To Y. M., Paton V. O., Lai S. L. (2009). Measuring self-regulation in online and blended learning environments. Internet High. Educ. 12, 1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.iheduc.2008.10.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iheduc.2008.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann J., Sams A. (2012). Flip your classroom: Reach every student in every class every day. Arlington, VI: International Society for Technology in Education.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeby A., Fern&#xe1;ndez M., Fox O., Hurtado Albir A., Kuznik A., Neunzig W., et al. (2011). Results of the validation of the PACTE translation competence model: Translation problems and translation competence. In Methods and Strategies of Process Research: Integrative Approaches in Translation Studies. John Benjamins Publishing Company. 317&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeby A., Fern&#xe1;ndez M., Fox O., Albir A., Kozlova I., Kuznik A., et al. (2009). Results of the validation of the PACTE translation competence model: Acceptability and decision making. Across Languages and Cultures. 10, 207&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bola&#xf1;os-Medina A., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez J. L. (2022). Autonomy support, critical thinking, and motivation as key predictors of translator trainees' strategic competence. Across Lang. Cult. 23, 131&#x2013;147. doi: 10.1556/084.2022.00266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/084.2022.00266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V., Clarke V. (2019). Reflecting on reflexive thematic analysis. Qual. Res. Sport Exerc. Health 11, 589&#x2013;597. doi: 10.1080/2159676X.2019.1628806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2019.1628806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs N. (2018). Neural machine translation tools in the language learning classroom: Students&#x2019; use, perceptions, and analyses. The JALT CALL Journal 14, 3&#x2013;24. doi: 10.29140/jaltcall.v14n1.221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29140/jaltcall.v14n1.221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo R. (2019). The interplay between intrinsic motivation and self-efficacy in translation education. Interpr. Transl. Train. 13, 189&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen L., Manion L., Morrison K. (2018). Research methods in education. 8th Edn. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomo-Maga&#xf1;a E., Soto-Varela R., Ruiz-Palmero J., G&#xf3;mez-Garc&#xed;a M. (2020). University students&#x2019; perception of the usefulness of the flipped classroom methodology. Educ. Sci. 10:275. doi: 10.3390/educsci10100275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci10100275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. W. (2015). Educational research: Planning, conducting, and evaluating quantitative and qualitative research (5th ed.). Pearson.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci E. L., Ryan R. M. (2000). The &#x201c;what&#x201d; and &#x201c;why&#x201d; of goal pursuits: human needs and the self-determination of behavior. Psychol. Inq. 11, 227&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1207/S15327965PLI1104_01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327965PLI1104_01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci E. L., Ryan R. M. (2013). Intrinsic motivation and self-determination in human behavior. Cham: Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Mar Haro-Soler M. (2018). Self-confidence and its role in translator training. London: John Benjamins Publishing Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xf6;rnyei Z., Ushioda E. (2021). Teaching and researching motivation. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccles J. S., Wigfield A. (2020). From expectancy-value theory to situated expectancy-value theory: a developmental, social cognitive, and sociocultural perspective on motivation. Contemp. Educ. Psychol. 61:101859. doi: 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccles J. S., Wigfield A. (2023). Expectancy-value theory to situated expectancy-value theory: reflections on the legacy of 40+ years of working together. Motiv. Sci. 9, 1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1037/mot0000275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/mot0000275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMT . (2009). Competences for professional translators, experts in multilingual and multimedia communication. January 2009. Available online at: http://ec.europa.eu/dgs/translation/programmes/emt/key_documents/emt_competences_tr anslators_en.pdf (accessed November 12, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMT . (2022). European master&#x2019;s in translation competence framework 2022. Available online at: https://commission.europa.eu/news/updated-versionemt-competence-framework-now-available-2022-10-21_en (accessed November 2, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatma &#xdc;. N. A. L., &#xc7;oban F. (2022). Developing a translation competence scale (TCS) and evaluating the opinions of prospective translators and professional translators in Turkey regarding translation competence. &#xc7;eviribilim ve Uygulamalar&#x131; Dergisi 32, 55&#x2013;90. doi: 10.37599/ceviri.1118561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37599/ceviri.1118561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;pferich S., J&#xe4;&#xe4;skel&#xe4;inen R. (2009). Process research into the development of translation competence: where are we, and where do we need to go? Across Lang. Cult. 10, 169&#x2013;191. doi: 10.1556/Acr.10.2009.2.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/Acr.10.2009.2.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorard S. (2003). Quantitative methods in social science research. New York, NY: Continuum.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadwin A. F., Rostampour R., Winne P. H. (2025). Advancing self-reports of self-regulated learning: validating new measures to assess students&#x2019; beliefs, practices, and challenges. Educ. Psychol. Rev. 37:8. doi: 10.1007/s10648-024-09977-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10648-024-09977-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haro-Soler M. D. M., Kiraly D. (2019). Exploring self-efficacy beliefs in symbiotic collaboration with students: an action research project. Interpreting Transl. Train. 13, 255&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1080/1750399X.2019.1656401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750399X.2019.1656401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu H. C. K., Wang C. V., Levesque-Bristol C. (2019). Reexamining the impact of self-determination theory on learning outcomes in the online learning environment. Educ. Inf. Technol. 24, 2159&#x2013;2174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H. W., Lin Q., Darragh J. J. (2020). &#x201c;Understanding EFL Learners&#x2019; Self-efficacy of Collaborative Translation in a Blended English Course&#x201d; in Proceedings of the 2020 4th International Conference on E-Education, E-Business and E-Technology, 78&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z., Zheng B., Wang X. (2021). The impact of a metacognitive self-regulation inventory in translator self-training: a pre-post study with English-Chinese translation students. Interpr. Transl. Train. 15, 430&#x2013;449. doi: 10.1080/1750399X.2020.1844436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750399X.2020.1844436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado Albir A. (2015). The acquisition of translation competence: competences, tasks, and assessment in translator training. Meta 60, 256&#x2013;280. doi: 10.7202/1032857ar</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7202/1032857ar</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado Albir A., Taylor P. (2015). The acquisition of translation competence. Competences Tasks Assessment Translator Training 60, 256&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado Albir A., Kuznik A., Rodr&#xed;guez-In&#xe9;s P. (2022). La competencia traductora y su adquisici&#xf3;n.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imhof M., Worthington D., Burger J., Bellh&#xe4;user H. (2024). Resilience and self-regulated learning as predictors of student competence gain in times of the COVID 19 pandemic&#x2013;evidence from a binational sample. In Frontiers in Education. Frontiers Media SA. 9:1293736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judy Shih H. C., Huang S. H. (2022). EFL learners&#x2019; metacognitive development in flipped learning: a comparative study Interactive Learning Environments. 30, 1448&#x2013;1460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiraly D. (2000). A social constructivist approach to translator education: Empowerment from theory to practice. Manchester and Northampton: St. Jerome Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiraly D. (2014). A social constructivist approach to translator education: Empowerment from theory to practice. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kormos J., Csiz&#xe9;r K. (2014). The interaction of motivation, self-regulatory strategies, and autonomous learning behavior in different learner groups. TESOL Q. 48, 275&#x2013;299. doi: 10.1002/tesq.129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tesq.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreutzer J., Riezler S. (2019). Self-regulated interactive sequence-to-sequence learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:1907.05190. Available at: https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Gao Z., Liao H. (2023). The effect of critical thinking on translation technology competence among college students: the chain mediating role of academic self-efficacy and cultural intelligence. Psychol. Res. Behav. Manag. 16, 1233&#x2013;1256. doi: 10.2147/PRBM.S408477, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PRBM.S408477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10120820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37089820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Lee W. (2022). Meta-analysis of self-regulated learning interventions across online and blended learning environments. J. Educ. Technol. Soc. 28, 563&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Shi X. (2021). Exploring the impact of motivation on task performance in computer-assisted translation contexts. Transl. Spaces 10, 51&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Yu C. (2019). Understanding students&#x2019; motivation in translation learning: a case study from the self-concept perspective. Asia-Pac. J. Second Foreign Lang. Educ. 4, 1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1186/s40862-019-0066-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40862-019-0066-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S., Xiangling W., Shuya M. (2022). Investigating the relationship between online information seeking and translation performance among translation students: the mediating role of translation self-efficacy. Front. Psychol. 13:944265. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.944265, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.944265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9539674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muali C., Aisyah N., Faizah N. (2023). Student motivation and learning outcomes through online flipped classroom based on student self-regulation in coastal areas. Pedagogik: Jurnal Pendidikan 10, 188&#x2013;202. doi: 10.33650/pjp.v10i2.5735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33650/pjp.v10i2.5735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen Q. N. (2021). A case study of the flipped classroom approach for translation studies in Vietnam (doctoral dissertation). Nottingham: University of Nottingham.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen N. Q., Lee K. W., Szabo C. Z., Nguyen D. N. P. (2022). A case study of technology-assisted flipped learning in enhancing learner translation capabilities and its mitigated challenges. Int. J. Comput.-Assist. Lang. Learn. Teach. 12, 1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.4018/IJCALLT.291109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/IJCALLT.291109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitzke J., Hansen-Schirra S. (2021). A short guide to post-editing, vol. 16. London: Language Science Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni&#xf1;o A. (2008). Evaluating the use of machine translation post-editing in the foreign languages class. Computer Assisted Language Learning 21, 29&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1080/09588220701865482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09588220701865482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunnally J. C. (1978). Psychometric theory. 2nd Edn. New York, NY: McGraw-Hill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omarchevska Y., van Leeuwen A., Mainhard T. (2024). The flipped classroom: first-time student preparatory activity patterns and their relation to course performance and self-regulation. J. Comput. High. Educ. 37, 1&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s12528-024-09399-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12528-024-09399-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwuegbuzie A. J., Collins K. M. (2007). A typology of mixed methods sampling designs in social science research. Qual. Rep. 12, 281&#x2013;316. doi: 10.46743/2160-3715/2007.1638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2007.1638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PACTE Group (2017). &#x201c;PACTE translation competence model: A holistic, dynamic model of translation competence&#x201d; in Researching translation competence by PACTE group (John Benjamins Publishing Company; ), 35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panadero E. (2017). A review of self-regulated learning: six models and four directions for research. Front. Psychol. 8:422. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00422, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patton M. Q. (2014). Qualitative research &amp; evaluation methods: Integrating theory and practice: Sage publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzak P. (2021). Metacognitive translator competence: from other-regulation to self-regulation. Koni&#x144;skie Stud. J&#x119;zyk. 9, 229&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzak P. (2018). The effects of students&#x2019; self-regulation on translation quality. Babel 64, 819&#x2013;839. doi: 10.1075/babel.00064.pie</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1075/babel.00064.pie</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintrich P. R., De Groot E. V. (1990). Motivational and self-regulated learning components of classroom academic performance. J. Educ. Psychol. 82, 33&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1037/0022-0663.82.1.33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.82.1.33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintrich P. R., Smith D. A. F., Garc&#xed;a T., McKeachie W. J. (1991). A manual for the use of the motivated strategies for learning questionnaire (MSLQ). London: National Center for Research to Improve Postsecondary Teaching and Learning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintrich P. R. (2003). A motivational science perspective on the role of student motivation in learning and teaching contexts. J. Educ. Psychol. 95:667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintrich P. R. (2004). A conceptual framework for assessing motivation and self-regulated learning in college students. Educ. Psychol. Rev. 16, 385&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purwanto A., Rasyid Y., Anwar M., Mayuni I. (2022). Modle-Based Flipped Learning-Model to Increase Basic Translation Skills and 21st Century Skills. Scope. Engl. Lang. Teach. 7, 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pym A. (2011). &#x201c;Training translators&#x201d; in The Oxford handbook of translation studies. eds. Malmkj&#xe6;r K., Windle K. (Oxford: Oxford University Press; ), 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pym A., Malmkj&#xe6;r K., Guti&#xe9;rrez-Col&#xf3;n M. (2013). Translation and language learning: The role of translation in the teaching of languages in the European Union. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert I. S., Remael A., Ureel J. J. (2017). Towards a model of translation revision competence. Interpr. Transl. Train. 11, 1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1080/1750399X.2016.1198183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750399X.2016.1198183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland L., Dewaele J. M., Costa B. (2019). Planning and conducting ethical interviews: Power, language and emotions. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L. (2000). Intrinsic and extrinsic motivations: Classic definitions and new directions. Contemp. Educ. Psychol. 25, 54&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10620381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L. (2020). Intrinsic and extrinsic motivation from a self-determination theory perspective: definitions, theory, practices, and future directions. Contemp. Educ. Psychol. 61:101860. doi: 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L. (2023). Acting as one: Self-determination theory&#x2019;s scientific and existential import. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L. (2024). Springer international publishing (springer international publishing), encyclopedia of quality of life and well-being research. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 6229&#x2013;6235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L., Vansteenkiste M., Soenens B. (2021). A legacy unfinished: an appreciative reply to comments on self-determination theory&#x2019;s frontiers and challenges. Motiv. Sci. 7, 120&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1037/mot0000237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/mot0000237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunk D. H., Usher E. L. (2019). &#x201c;Social cognitive theory and motivation&#x201d; in The Oxford handbook of human motivation. ed. Ryan R. M.. 2nd ed (Oxford: Oxford University Press; ), 11&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (2012a). &#x201c;Motivation: an essential dimension of self-regulated learning&#x201d; in Motivation and self-regulated learning: Theory, research, and applications. eds. Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (London: Routledge; ), 1&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (2012b). Self-regulation and learning. Handbook of psychology. Second Edn. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (Eds.) (2023). Self-regulation of learning and performance: Issues and educational applications. New York, NY: Taylor &amp; Francis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shreve G. M. (2017). &#x201c;Text linguistics, translating, and interpreting&#x201d; in The Routledge handbook of translation studies and linguistics. ed. Malmkj&#xe6;r K. (London: Routledge; ), 165&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer N. (2022). How committed are you to becoming a translator? Defining translator identity statuses. Interpr. Transl. Train. 16, 141&#x2013;157. doi: 10.1080/1750399X.2022.2074695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1750399X.2022.2074695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer N., Soler M. D. M. H. (2022). &#xbf;La pr&#xe1;ctica hace al traductor? El impacto de la pr&#xe1;ctica de traducci&#xf3;n en las creencias de autoeficacia de los estudiantes. Mutatis Mutandis: Revista Latinoamericana de Traducci&#xf3;n 15, 294&#x2013;314. doi: 10.17533/udea.mut.v15n2a06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17533/udea.mut.v15n2a06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Zhao X., Li X., Yu F. (2023). Effectiveness of the flipped classroom on self-efficacy among students: a meta-analysis. Cogent Educ. 10:2287886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng S. S., Yeh H. C. (2019). Fostering EFL teachers&#x2019; CALL competencies through project-based learning. Educ. technol. soc. 22, 94&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valero-Garc&#xe9;s C., Cedillo Corrochano C. (2018). Approaches to didactics for technologies in translation and interpreting. Trans-kom 11, 154&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Praag B., Sanchez H. S. (2015). Mobile technology in second language classrooms: Insights into its uses, pedagogical implications, and teacher beliefs. ReCALL 27, 288&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhang W. (2024). The relationship between college students&#x2019; learning engagement and academic self-efficacy: a moderated mediation model. Frontiers in Psychology. 15, 1425172. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1425172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1425172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11407112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39291178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chen H., Chen Y. (2022). How do task value and self-efficacy affect learning outcomes in online education? A moderated mediation analysis. Front. Psychol. 13:833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J., Zhang J., Yang Y., Cai Y. (2023). Development and validation of the self-regulated translation learning strategy scale (SRTLSS). Stud. Educ. Eval. 78:101292. doi: 10.1016/j.stueduc.2023.101292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stueduc.2023.101292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilss W. (1996). Translation as intelligent behaviour. Benjamins Transl. Library 18, 161&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Z. (2022). Flipped-learning approach in business English translation course in a Chinese independent college. Engl. Lang. Teach. 15, 61&#x2013;72. doi: 10.5539/elt.v15n2p61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/elt.v15n2p61</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z., Zhao Y., Zhang B., Liew J., Kogut A. (2023). A meta-analysis of the efficacy of self-regulated learning interventions on academic achievement in online and blended environments in K-12 and higher education. Behav. Inf. Technol. 42, 2911&#x2013;2931. doi: 10.1080/0144929X.2022.2151935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0144929X.2022.2151935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Wang X. (2023). Predicting student translators&#x2019; performance in machine translation post-editing: interplay of self-regulation, critical thinking, and motivation. Interact. Learn. Environ. 31, 340&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1080/10494820.2020.1786407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10494820.2020.1786407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf M. (2011). The impact of self-efficacy, achievement motivation, and self-regulated learning strategies on students&#x2019; academic achievement. Procedia Soc. Behav. Sci. 15, 2623&#x2013;2626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZabihiAtergeleh N., Ahmadian M., Karimi S. N. (2025). The motivational paths to self-regulated language learning: a structural equation modeling approach. Stud. Self-Access Learn. J. 16, 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Wang X., Liu X. (2022). The impact of task complexity and translating self-efficacy belief on students&#x2019; translation performance: Evidence from process and product data. Front. Psychol. 13:911850. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.911850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.911850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36405151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J. (2000). Attaining self-regulation: A social cognitive perspective. San Diego, CA: Academic Press, 13&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J. (2002). Becoming a self-regulated learner: an overview. Theory Pract. 41, 64&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1207/s15430421tip4102_2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15430421tip4102_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J. (2023). &#x201c;Dimensions of academic self-regulation: a conceptual framework for education&#x201d; in Self-regulation of learning and performance. eds. Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (London: Routledge; ), 3&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J., Greenberg D., Weinstein C. E. (2023). &#x201c;Self-regulating academic study time: a strategy approach&#x201d; in Self-regulation of learning and performance. eds. Schunk D. H., Zimmerman B. J. (London: Routledge; ), 181&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J., Kitsantas A. (2014). Comparing students&#x2019; self-discipline and self-regulation measures and their prediction of academic achievement. Contemp. Educ. Psychol. 39, 145&#x2013;155. doi: 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2014.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2014.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B. J., Schunk D. H. (2011). Handbook of self-regulation of learning and performance. London: Routledge/Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>