<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41553033</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increased contralateral dynamic valgus in female athletes following ACL reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70291</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Female athletes have a higher risk of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury, which has been associated with neuromuscular deficits and dynamic valgus, while contralateral risk profiles after ACL reconstruction remain insufficiently characterized. The purpose of this study was to investigate whether female patients after ACL reconstruction exhibit greater contralateral valgus angles compared with male patients, indicating a higher risk profile for secondary ACL injury. It was hypothesized that dynamic valgus would be more pronounced in women than in men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this predefined subanalysis of a controlled laboratory study, 26 patients (17 male and 9 female) were analysed approximately eight months after primary ACL reconstruction with either semitendinosus or quadriceps tendon autograft. Isokinetic strength testing and three-dimensional (3D) motion capture analysis were performed. Participants executed vertical drop jumps and single-leg jumps for distance. The primary outcome was the maximal contralateral knee valgus angle; secondary outcomes included hip and knee flexion angles, valgus moments and hamstrings-to-quadriceps (H/Q) ratio. Mann-Whitney U test was used for testing between male and female patients after testing for parametric distribution using Shapiro-Wilk test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the vertical drop jump, females demonstrated a significantly larger median maximal valgus angle compared to males (-2.9&#xb0; [valgus] [interquartile range, IQR (-9.8) to 2.0] vs. 6.7&#xb0; [varus] [IQR (-0.2) to 8.5], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.016). No significant sex-specific differences were observed in secondary kinematic parameters, single-leg jump performance or isokinetic strength measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Female patients exhibited greater contralateral dynamic valgus during drop jump landings after ACL reconstruction, suggesting sex-specific neuromuscular risk patterns. These findings support the need for individualized rehabilitation and prevention strategies with a focus on dynamic valgus in female athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaugg</LastName><ForeName>Fredrik</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3797-4177</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Martin Luther Hospital, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Humboldt University and Charit&#xe9; University Medicine, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bierke</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Martin Luther Hospital, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hees</LastName><ForeName>Tilman</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Martin Luther Hospital, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Humboldt University and Charit&#xe9; University Medicine, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siem&#xdf;en</LastName><ForeName>Kerstin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Martin Luther Hospital, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Humboldt University and Charit&#xe9; University Medicine, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolfarth</LastName><ForeName>Bernd</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Humboldt University and Charit&#xe9; University Medicine, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petersen</LastName><ForeName>Wolf</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Martin Luther Hospital, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>AGA-Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Arthroskopie und Gelenkchirurgie</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gender differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41553033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alentorn&#x2010;Geli E, Myer GD, Silvers HJ, Samitier G, Romero D, L&#xe1;zaro&#x2010;Haro C, et al. Prevention of non&#x2010;contact anterior cruciate ligament injuries in soccer players. Part 1: mechanisms of injury and underlying risk factors of article. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2009;17:705&#x2013;729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arms SW, Pope MH, Johnson RJ, Fischer RA, Arvidsson I, Eriksson E. The biomechanics of anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation and reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 1984;12:8&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaeda M, Deie M, Fujita N, Kono Y, Terai C, Kuwahara W, et al. Gender differences in the restoration of knee joint biomechanics during gait after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2017;24:280&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni BM, Ruas CV, Ribeiro&#x2010;Alvares JB, Pinto RS. Hamstring&#x2010;to&#x2010;quadriceps torque ratios of professional male soccer players: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:281&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer S, Meredith SJ, Wilson KW, de Sa D, Pauyo T, Byrne K, et al. Knee morphological risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review. J Bone Jt Surg. 2020;102:703&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender R, Lange S. Adjusting for multiple testing&#x2014;when and how? J Clin Epidemiol. 2001;54:343&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biodex Medical Systems: Biodex System 3 Software Manual. https://www.biodex.com/sites/default/files/830000man_05387.pdf (2021). Accessed 5 Aug 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn JT, Norcross MF, Cannon LN, Zinder SM. Hamstrings stiffness and landing biomechanics linked to anterior cruciate ligament loading. J Athl Train. 2013;48:764&#x2013;772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell JD, Yu B, Kirkendall DT, Garrett WE. A comparison of knee kinetics between male and female recreational athletes in stop&#x2010;jump tasks. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30:261&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda Y, Woo SLY, Loh JC, Tsuda E, Tang P, McMahon PJ, et al. A quantitative analysis of valgus torque on the ACL: a human cadaveric study. J Orthop Res. 2003;21:1107&#x2013;1112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaugg F, Bierke S, Hees T, Siem&#xdf;en K, Wolfarth B, Petersen W. Dynamic valgus after ACL reconstruction: quadriceps&#x2010; vs. semitendinosus tendon grafts. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2025;145:377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gornitzky AL, Lott A, Yellin JL, Fabricant PD, Lawrence JT, Ganley TJ. Sport&#x2010;specific yearly risk and incidence of anterior cruciate ligament tears in high school athletes: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2716&#x2013;2723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrington L. The effects of 4 weeks of jump training on landing knee valgus and crossover hop performance in female basketball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:3427&#x2013;3432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrington L, Munro A. Drop jump landing knee valgus angle; normative data in a physically active population. Phys Ther Sport. 2010;11:56&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertel P, Behrend H, Cierpinski T, Musahl V, Widjaja G. ACL reconstruction using bone&#x2010;patellar tendon&#x2010;bone press&#x2010;fit fixation: 10&#x2010;year clinical results. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2005;13:248&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Ford KR, Hoogenboom BJ, Myer GD. Understanding and preventing ACL injuries: current biomechanical and epidemiologic considerations &#x2010; update 2010. N Am J Sports Phys Ther. 2010;5:234&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Myer GD, Ford KR, Heidt RS, Colosimo AJ, McLean SG, et al. Biomechanical measures of neuromuscular control and valgus loading of the knee predict anterior cruciate ligament injury risk in female athletes: a prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33:492&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Myer GD, Zazulak BT. Hamstrings to quadriceps peak torque ratios diverge between sexes with increasing isokinetic angular velocity. J Sci Med Sport. 2008;11:452&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y&#x2010;L, Jung J, Mulligan CMS, Oh J, Norcross MF. A majority of anterior cruciate ligament injuries can be prevented by injury prevention programs: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials and cluster&#x2013;randomized controlled trials with meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:1505&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huston LJ, Vibert B, Ashton&#x2010;Miller JA, Wojtys EM. Gender differences in knee angle when landing from a drop&#x2010;jump of article. Am J Knee Surg. 2001;14(4):215&#x2013;219; discussion 219&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huston LJ, Wojtys EM. Neuromuscular performance characteristics in elite female athletes. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24:427&#x2013;436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Knee Documentation Committee. Formbl&#xe4;tter des International Knee Documentation Committee IKDC (Internationaler Ausschuss zur Dokumentation von Knieverletzungen). https://www.sportsmed.org/AOSSMIMIS/members/downloads/research/IKDCGerman.pdf. Accessed 31 Jul 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabacinski J, Murawa M, Mackala K, Dworak LB. Knee strength ratios in competitive female athletes of article. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0191077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanamori A, Woo SLY, Ma CB, Zeminski J, Rudy TW, Li G, et al. The forces in the anterior cruciate ligament and knee kinematics during a simulated pivot shift test: a human cadaveric study using robotic technology. Arthroscopy. 2000;16:633&#x2013;639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong PW, Burns SF. Bilateral difference in hamstrings to quadriceps ratio in healthy males and females. Phys Ther Sport. 2010;11:12&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krosshaug T, Nakamae A, Boden BP, Engebretsen L, Smith G, Slauterbeck JR, et al. Mechanisms of anterior cruciate ligament injury in basketball: video analysis of 39 cases. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:359&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre K, Delestre C, Mezghani N, Shabani B, Ch&#xe8;ze L, Lustig S, et al. Gait adaptations following anterior cruciate ligament rupture are sex specific. Knee. 2025;56:168&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lephart SM, Ferris CM, Riemann BL, Myers JB, Fu FH. Gender differences in strength and lower extremity kinematics during landing of article. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2002;401:162&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majewski M, Susanne H, Klaus S. Epidemiology of athletic knee injuries: a 10&#x2010;year study. Knee. 2006;13:184&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo AM, Schneider DK, Yut L, Webster KE, Beynnon B, Kocher MS, et al. &#x201c;What's my risk of sustaining an ACL injury while playing sports?&#x201d; A systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1003&#x2013;1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Ford KR, Barber Foss KD, Liu C, Nick TG, Hewett TE. The relationship of hamstrings and quadriceps strength to anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes. Clin J Sport Med. 2009;19:3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Ford KR, Khoury J, Succop P, Hewett TE. Development and validation of a clinic&#x2010;based prediction tool to identify female athletes at high risk for anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:2025&#x2013;2033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Rauh MJ, Schmitt LC, Ford KR, Hewett TE. Incidence of contralateral and ipsilateral anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury after primary ACL reconstruction and return to sport. Clin J Sport Med. 2012;22:116&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, Diermeier T, Mehl J, St&#xf6;hr A, Ellermann A, M&#xfc;ller P, et al. Pr&#xe4;vention von Knieverletzungen und VKB&#x2010;Rupturen. Empfehlungen des DKG Komitees Ligamentverletzungen of article. OUP. 2016;10:542&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, St&#xf6;hr A, Ellermann A, Achtnich A, M&#xfc;ller PE, Stoffels T, et al. Wiederkehr zum Sport nach VKB&#x2010;Rekonstruktion of article. OUP. 2016;5:166&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, Taheri P, Forkel P, Zantop T. Return to play following ACL reconstruction: a systematic review about strength deficits. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2014;134:1417&#x2013;1428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujol N, Giordano AO, Wong SE, Beaufils P, Monllau JC, Arhos EK, et al. The formal EU&#x2010;US Meniscus Rehabilitation 2024 Consensus: an ESSKA&#x2010;AOSSM&#x2010;AASPT initiative. Part I&#x2014;rehabilitation management after meniscus surgery (meniscectomy, repair and reconstruction). Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:3002&#x2013;3013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran AK, Pedley JS, Moeskops S, Oliver JL, Myer GD, Hsiao HI, et al. Influence of neuromuscular training interventions on jump&#x2010;landing biomechanics and implications for ACL injuries in youth females: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Med. 2025;55:1265&#x2013;1292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi VG, Prill R, Jahnke S, Zaffagnini S, Becker R. The influence of gluteal muscle strength deficits on dynamic knee valgus: a scoping review of article. J Exp Orthop. 2022;9:81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami M, Sedaghati P, Daneshmandi H. Effects of a warm&#x2010;up program on jump&#x2010;landing pattern and lumbopelvic function in female basketball players with dynamic knee valgus. Sci Rep. 2025;15:27918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen X, Liu T, Xu S, Chen B, Tang X, Xiao J, et al. Optimal timing of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in patients with anterior cruciate ligament tear: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2242742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derman K, Alfredson H, Pietil&#xe4; T, Werner S. Risk factors for leg injuries in female soccer players: a prospective investigation during one out&#x2010;door season. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2001;9:313&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilopoulos T, Morey TE, Dhatariya K, Rice MJ. Limitations of significance testing in clinical research: a review of multiple comparison corrections and effect size calculations with correlated measures. Anesth Analg. 2016;122:825&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicon Motion Systems. Plug&#x2010;in gait reference guide. Oxford: Vicon Motion Systems; 2021. https://docs.vicon.com/download/attachments/124850166/Plug-in%20Gait%20Reference%20Guide.pdf. Accessed 21 Oct 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, Stanfield D, Webster KE, Myer GD. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:1861&#x2013;1876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild CY, Steele JR, Munro BJ. Insufficient hamstring strength compromises landing technique in adolescent girls. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:497&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright RW, Magnussen RA, Dunn WR, Spindler KP. Ipsilateral graft and contralateral ACL rupture at five years or more following ACL reconstruction: a systematic review. J Bone Joint Surg. 2011;93:1159&#x2013;1165.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>