<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41318419</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2407</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and factors associated with chemotherapy-induced adverse events in cancer treatment centers in Amhara national regional state comprehensive referral hospitals, 2024: multicenter prospective follow up study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38</StartPage><MedlinePgn>38</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">38</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12885-025-15384-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Chemotherapy drugs remain the gold standard treatment for cancer. However, the side effects limit chemotherapy treatment and make treatment outcome poor. This makes chemotherapy side effects a big public health problem globally.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To assess prevalence and factors associated with chemotherapy-induced adverse events in cancer treatment centers in Amhara national regional state comprehensive referral hospitals, Norwest Ethiopia 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY">Multi-center prospective observational study was conducted. Data was collected using questionnaire and checklist. Adverse events were collected and graded using National Cancer Institute Common Terminology CTCAE version 4.0. Data was transformed from Epi data to SPSS and logistic regression analysis was done. Both crude and adjusted odds ratio were used to assess the strength of association. Variables with a p-value of less than 0.05 were considered as statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 572 patients were included in the study with a response rate of 99.5%. The overall prevalence of chemotherapy related adverse events was 78.49% with (95%, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.7783&#x2013;0.7817). Cisplatin causes adverse events in 152 (95%), oxaliplatin 59 (100%), paclitaxel 28 (100%), docetaxel 42 (76.4%), gemcitabine 68 (68%) patients, 5-Flurouracil 65 (51.2%) and cyclophosphamide 10 (29.4%) patients respectively. The commonest severe (grades 3&#x2013;4) adverse events were peripheral neuropathy or pain (36.7%), nausea and vomiting (28.5%), hair loss (22.9%), fatigue (22%), itching (19.1%), cyanosis (18%), leukopenia (16.9%) and diarrhea (16.3%). Being female (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.201, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.580&#x2013;6.217), history of motion (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.001, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.410&#x2013;5.201), history of morning sickness (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.610, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;101&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;3.1), second cycle chemotherapy (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.701, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;201&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;8.09) and third cycle of chemotherapy (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.201, CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.91&#x2013;5.302) were associated with chemotherapy related adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION AND RECOMMENDATIONS">The prevalence of chemotherapy-induced adverse events was high in the study settings. We recommend early cycle by cycle risk assessment of patients and management of adverse events. Additionally, training should be given for oncologic nurses about the risk assessment and management of adverse events. High emphasis should be given for patients who will receive oxaliplatin, cisplatin, paclitaxel, docetaxel and gemcitabine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12885-025-15384-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demilie</LastName><ForeName>Atalay Eshetie</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, College of Medicine and Health Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayu</LastName><ForeName>Habtu Tsehayu</ForeName><Initials>HT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, College of Medicine and Health Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taye</LastName><ForeName>Mahder Metenu</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, College of Medicine and Health Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diress</LastName><ForeName>Fikadu Tadesse</ForeName><Initials>FT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, College of Medicine and Health Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebremedhn</LastName><ForeName>Endale Gebreegziabher</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, P. O. Box 196, Gondar, Ethiopia. endalege@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2407</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adverse events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Highly emetogenic chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Moderately emetogenic chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nausea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vomiting</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the ethical review committee of School of Medicine, Bahir Dar University ethical review committee with ethical registration number 003/2024) and official permission letter was obtained from Tibebe Ghion and Felege hiwot hospitals. All methods in this study were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations .The patients provided written informed consent prior to participate in the study and were able to withdraw from the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41318419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12781528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-15384-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12885-025-15384-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chabner BA, Roberts TG. Chemotherapy and the war on cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2005;5(1):65&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrc1529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15630416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan K, Hinke A, Grothey A, Voigt W, Arnold D, Wolf H-H, et al. A meta-analysis comparing the efficacy of four 5-HT3-receptor antagonists for acute chemotherapy-induced emesis. Support Care Cancer. 2007;15:1023&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17205281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslam MS, Naveed S, Ahmed A, Abbas Z, Gull I, Athar MA. Side effects of chemotherapy in cancer patients and evaluation of patients opinion about starvation based differential chemotherapy. Journal of Cancer Therapy. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankhala KK, Pandya DM, Sarantopoulos J, Soefje SA, Giles FJ, Chawla SP. Prevention of chemotherapy induced nausea and vomiting: a focus on aprepitant. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2009;5(12):1607&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17425250903451675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teunissen SC, Wesker W, Kruitwagen C, de Haes HC, Voest EE, de Graeff A. Symptom prevalence in patients with incurable cancer: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manag. 2007;34(1):94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2006.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17509812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flemm LA. Aprepitant for chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting. Clin J Oncol Nurs. 2004;8(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love RR, Leventhal H, Easterling DV, Nerenz DR. Side effects and emotional distress during cancer chemotherapy. Cancer. 1989;63(3):604&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1097-0142(19890201)63:3&lt;604::AID-CNCR2820630334&gt;3.0.CO;2-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2912536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaRusso J, Waldman SA, Kraft WK. Aprepitant for the prevention of nausea and vomiting associated with chemotherapy and postoperative recovery. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2008;1(1):27&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1586/17512433.1.1.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24410507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez LY, Huestis SE, Yap TY, Zyzanski S, Drotar D, Kodish E. Potential chemotherapy side effects: what do oncologists tell parents? Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2009;52(4):497&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.21835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2643320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19101994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel L, Lindley C. Aprepitant&#x2013;a novel NK1-receptor antagonist. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2003;4(12):2279&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/14656566.4.12.2279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14640927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabila El -SS, Amal A, el, Amal A, El-A, Fathyia S. Effect of nursing intervention for chemotherapy induced nausea and vomiting among breast cancer women. Int J Novel Res Healthc Nurs. 2019;6(1):803&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DCS. ASHP therapeutic guidelines on the Pharmacologic management of nausea and vomiting in adult and pediatric patients receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy or undergoing surgery. Am J Health-System Pharm. 1999;56(8):729&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajhp/56.8.729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10326616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endale Gebreegziabher Gebremedhn PJS, David Anthony Mahns. Variability of Oxaliplatin-Induced neuropathic pain symptoms in each cycle and its implications on the management of colorectal cancer patients: A retrospective study in South Western Sydney local health district Hospitals, Sydney, Australia. J Oncol. 2019. 10.1155/2019/4828563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/4828563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endale G, David AM. The incidence of acute oxaliplatin-induced neuropathy and its impact on treatment in the first cycle: a systematic review. BMC Cancer. 2018;18:410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-018-4185-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5897924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29649985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belachew SA, Erku DA, Mekuria AB, Gebresillassie BM. Pattern of chemotherapy-related adverse effects among adult cancer patients treated at Gondar university referral Hospital, ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. Drug Healthc Patient Saf. 2016;8:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DHPS.S116924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5153262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27994485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conklin KA. Dietary antioxidants during cancer chemotherapy: impact on chemotherapeutic effectiveness and development of side effects. Nutr Cancer. 2000;37(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327914NC3701_1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10965514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuderer NM, Desai A, Lustberg MB, Lyman GH. Mitigating acute chemotherapy-associated adverse events in patients with cancer. Nat Reviews Clin Oncol. 2022;19(11):681&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41571-022-00685-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36221000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingrand I, Defossez G, Lafay-Chebassier C, Chavant F, Ferru A, Ingrand P, et al. Serious adverse effects occurring after chemotherapy: A general cancer registry-based incidence survey. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2020;86(4):711&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.14159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31658394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce A, Haas M, Viney R, Pearson SA, Haywood P, Brown C, et al. Incidence and severity of self-reported chemotherapy side effects in routine care: A prospective cohort study. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(10):e0184360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0184360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5634543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teunissen SCCM, Wesker W, Kruitwagen C, de Haes HCJM, Voest EE, de Graeff A. Symptom prevalence in patients with incurable cancer: A systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manag. 2007;34(1):94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2006.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17509812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews PLR, Sanger GJ. Abdominal vagal afferent neurones: an important target for the treatment of Gastrointestinal dysfunction. Curr Opin Pharmacol. 2002;2(6):650&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1471-4892(02)00227-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12482726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seretny M, Currie GL, Sena ES, Ramnarine S, Grant R, MacLeod MR, et al. Incidence, prevalence, and predictors of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2014;155(12):2461&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pain.2014.09.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25261162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xfc;eb R. Chemotherapy-induced hair loss. Skin Therapy Lett. 2010;15(7):5&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20700552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger JM, Vaidya R, Albain KS, LeBlanc M, Minasian LM, Gotay CC, et al. Sex differences in risk of severe adverse events in patients receiving immunotherapy, targeted therapy, or chemotherapy in cancer clinical trials. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40(13):1474&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.21.02377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9061143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35119908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo SH, Kim S-E, Kang Y-K, Ryoo B-Y, Ryu M-H, Jeong JH, et al. Association of nutritional status-related indices and chemotherapy-induced adverse events in gastric cancer patients. BMC Cancer. 2016;16:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-016-2934-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5116147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27863481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrow GR. Clinical characteristics associated with the development of anticipatory nausea and vomiting in cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy treatment. J Clin Oncol. 1984;2(10):1170&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.1984.2.10.1170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6491699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji Y, Baba H, Takeda K, Kobayashi M, Oki E, Gotoh M, et al. Chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting (CINV) in 190 colorectal cancer patients: a prospective registration study by the CINV study group of Japan. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2017;18(8):753&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2017.1317746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28395603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JW, Lee Y-G, Hwang IG, Song HS, Koh SJ, Ko YH, et al. Predicting cumulative incidence of adverse events in older patients with cancer undergoing first-line palliative chemotherapy: Korean cancer study group (KCSG) multicentre prospective study. Br J Cancer. 2018;118(9):1169&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41416-018-0037-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5943243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29576622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid N, Koh HA, Baca HC, Li Z, Malecha S, Abidoye O, et al. Clinical impact of chemotherapy-related adverse events in patients with metastatic breast cancer in an integrated health care system. J Managed Care Specialty Pharm. 2015;21(10):863&#x2013;b71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18553/jmcp.2015.21.10.863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10398121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26402387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motoori M, Yano M, Miyata H, Sugimura K, Saito T, Omori T, et al. Randomized study of the effect of synbiotics during neoadjuvant chemotherapy on adverse events in esophageal cancer patients. Clin Nutr. 2017;36(1):93&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2015.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrstedt J, Dombernowsky P. Anti-emetic therapy in cancer chemotherapy: current status. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2007;101(3):143&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1742-7843.2007.00122.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17697032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baburaj G, Abraham AM, George L, Shetty V, Thempalangad RM, Rajesh K, et al. A study on utilization and evaluation of antiemetics in chemotherapy&#x2013;induced nausea and vomiting. Indian J Med Pediatr Oncol. 2017;38(03):334&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijmpo.ijmpo_116_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5686978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29200685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>