<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41616272</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond Jump Height: The Value of Phase-Specific Metrics for Monitoring Fatigue in Basketball.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005352</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Palanisamy, AC, Ahluwalia, J, Bahrami, B, Randhawa, A, and Kobsar, D. Beyond jump height: The value of phase-specific metrics for monitoring fatigue in basketball. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-Basketball athletes must balance intense training demands with recovery to maintain peak performance, while minimizing fatigue-related injuries. Assessing the acute effects of basketball practice on countermovement jump (CMJ) metrics offers a valuable approach to evaluating the impact of practice volume on neuromuscular performance. Fourteen male athletes from the McMaster University basketball team participated in this study, with data collected pre- and postpractice for a 10-week period. Results revealed significant decreases in performance output metrics, such as jump height and modified reactive strength index, after practice. In addition, phase-specific temporal metrics, including braking phase duration, increased, whereas driver metrics, such as eccentric mean braking force and eccentric rate of force development, decreased, indicating altered neuromuscular strategies due to fatigue. However, these changes had limited associations to practice volume measured by inertial sensors, suggesting substantial individual variability in fatigue responses. These findings demonstrate the sensitivity of CMJ metrics to acute fatigue, particularly phase-specific force-time components, providing deeper insights into neuromuscular adaptations beyond performance output alone. Although CMJ metrics effectively capture fatigue-related changes, the magnitude of these changes does not exhibit a clear relationship with practice load, highlighting the complexity of monitoring fatigue responses in team sports. This study enhances the understanding of player fatigue and underscores the practical application of force plate technology in sports science to inform individualized training and recovery strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palanisamy</LastName><ForeName>Anil C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahluwalia</LastName><ForeName>Jasriya</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahrami</LastName><ForeName>Bahman</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Randhawa</LastName><ForeName>Anaikh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobsar</LastName><ForeName>Dylan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">applied sport science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">force plates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">load management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wearable technology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41616272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adesida Y, Papi E, McGregor AH. Exploring the role of wearable technology in sport kinematics and kinetics: A systematic review. Sensors 19: 1597&#x2013;26, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alba-Jim&#xe9;nez C, Moreno-Doutres D, Pe&#xf1;a J. Trends assessing neuromuscular fatigue in team sports: A narrative review. Sports 10: 33&#x2013;15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage M, Beato M, McErlain-Naylor SA. Inter-unit reliability of IMU step metrics using IMeasureU blue trident inertial measurement units for running-based team sport tasks. J Sports Sci 39: 1512&#x2013;1518, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker LA, Harry JR, Mercer JA. Relationships between countermovement jump ground reaction forces and jump height, reactive strength index, and jump time. J Strength Cond Res 32: 248&#x2013;254, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: Comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance profiling, neuromuscular fatigue monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Condit J 45: 545&#x2013;553, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burland JP, Outerleys JB, Lattermann C, Davis IS. Reliability of wearable sensors to assess impact metrics during sport-specific tasks. J Sports Sci 39: 406&#x2013;411, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabarkapa D, Cabarkapa DV, Philipp NM, et al. Pre-post practice changes in countermovement vertical jump force-time metrics in professional Male basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 37: e609&#x2013;e612, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabarkapa D, Johnson QR, Cabarkapa DV, et al. Changes in countermovement vertical jump force-time metrics during a game in professional Male basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1326&#x2013;1329, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The Concept of Power Analysis. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. ((2nd ed)). New York, NY: Routledge, 2013. pp. 8&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards T, Spiteri T, Piggott B, et al. Monitoring and managing fatigue in basketball. Sports 6: 19&#x2013;14, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis M, Myers T, Taylor R, Morris R, Akubat I. The dose&#x2013;response relationship between training-load measures and changes in force&#x2013;time components during a countermovement jump in Male academy soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 1634&#x2013;1641, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Translating fatigue to human performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 2228&#x2013;2238, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole R. Countermovement Jump Assessment for Athlete Neuromuscular Fatigue Monitoring [Thesis], 2023. pp. 10&#x2013;14. Available at: https://dspace.library.uvic.ca/handle/1828/5642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollhofer A, Komi PV, Miyashita M, Aura O. Fatigue during stretch-shortening cycle exercises: Changes in mechanical performance of human skeletal muscle. Int J Sports Med 8: 71&#x2013;78, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb R, Shalom A, Calleja-Gonzalez J. Physiology of basketball&#x2014;Field tests. Review article. J Hum Kinet 77: 159&#x2013;167, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guess TM, Gray AD, Willis BW, et al. Force-time waveform shape reveals countermovement jump strategies of collegiate athletes. Sports 8: 159&#x2013;13, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamill J, Palmer C, Van Emmerik REA. Coordinative variability and overuse injury. Sports Med Arthrosc Rehabil Ther Technol 4: 45&#x2013;9, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heishman AD, Daub BD, Miller RM, et al. Countermovement jump reliability performed with and without an arm swing in NCAA Division 1 intercollegiate basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 34: 546&#x2013;558, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy RA, Drake D. The effect of acute fatigue on countermovement jump performance in rugby union players during preseason. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 57: 1261&#x2013;1266, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh JAJ, Bishop C, Ruder MC, Kobsar D. Tracking the reliability of force plate-derived countermovement jump metrics over time in female basketball athletes: A comparison of principal component analysis vs. conventional methods. J Sci Sport Exerc, 2025. pp. 9&#x2013;12. Available at: https://doi.org/10.1007/s42978-023-00239-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-023-00239-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi PV. Stretch-shortening cycle: A powerful model to study normal and fatigued muscle. J Biomech 33: 1197&#x2013;1206, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Suchomel TJ, Lake JP, Comfort P. Understanding the key phases of the countermovement jump force-time curve. Strength Cond J 40: 96&#x2013;106, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol C, Avela J, Komi PV. The stretch-shortening cycle: A model to study naturally occurring neuromuscular fatigue. Sports Med 36: 977&#x2013;999, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philipp NM, Cabarkapa D, Blackburn SD, Fry AC. Dose-response relationship for external workload and neuromsuclar performance over a female, collegiate, basketball season. J Strength Cond Res 38: e253&#x2013;e263, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson D, Caldwell G, Hamill J, Kamen G, Whittlesey S. Biomechanics Analysis Techniquies: A Primer. Research Methods in Biomechanics. ((2nd ed)). United States: Human Kinetics, 2013. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor TS, Rebel M, Watling C, et al. Making sense of fatigue: Implications of social constructs of fatigue in clinical training and practice. J Graduate Med Edu 7: 696&#x2013;1, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde AS, Hayano T, Jamison ST, Outerleys J, Davis IS. Tibial acceleration measured from wearable sensors is associated with loading rates in injured runners. Pharm Manag PM R 12: 679&#x2013;684, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trezise J, Bartlett R, Bussey M. Effects of fatigue on coordination variability in sprinters. J Sci Med Sport 12: S60-7, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanrenterghem J, Nedergaard N, Robinson M, Drust B. Training load monitoring in team sports: A novel framework separating physiological and biomechanical load-adaptation pathways. Sports Med 47: 2135&#x2013;2142, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald ForceDecks technical glossary. 2025. pp. 9&#x2013;12 Available at: https://support.vald.com/hc/article_attachments/31552911571353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu P, Gong Z, Meng Y, et al. The acute influence of running-induced fatigue on the performance and biomechanics of a countermovement jump. Appl Sci 10: 4319&#x2013;13, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>