<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41160418</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Relationship Between Sleep Hygiene Recommendations and Outcomes in Sleep, Fatigue, and Cognitive Performance Among Student-Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>48</StartPage><EndPage>55</EndPage><MedlinePgn>48-55</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005255</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Varesco, G, Germain, M, Szocs, S, Martin, A, Toussaint, P-M, and Simonelli, G. Exploring the relationship between sleep hygiene recommendations and outcomes in sleep, fatigue, and cognitive performance among student-athletes. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): 48-55, 2026-Student-athletes often neglect sleep because of academic and training demands, highlighting the value of interventions targeting poor sleep habits. However, sleep hygiene research remains limited to individualized approaches, limiting reproducibility and posing challenges for implementation in large groups, such as collegiate sports teams. In this 4-week study, we assessed the sleep health of an elite collegiate Canadian football team through questionnaires (week 1). Players with poor sleep habits (Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index &gt; 5; 24 out of 64) participated in a 2-week sleep hygiene intervention. After a familiarization session (week 2), they completed 2 weeks of sleep assessment (actigraphy, sleep diary) and a post-training test, including a fatigue 10-cm visual analog scale, psychomotor vigilance task (PVT), and paced visual serial addition test (PVSAT). Subjects were unaware to be selected based on their poor sleep habits. After week 3, athletes received feedback on poor sleep habits and standardized written, evidence-based sleep hygiene recommendations. They were asked to comply with these recommendations before repeating experimental procedures at the end of week 4. Improvements were observed only in perceived total sleep time (sleep duration; 7:43 &#xb1; 1:29 vs. 8:03 &#xb1; 1:34 h:mm, p = 0.045) and PVSAT performance (1.44 &#xb1; 1.8 vs. 1.36 &#xb1; 1.63 seconds, p = 0.004), while PVT speed decreased (3.6 &#xb1; 0.4 vs. 3.5 &#xb1; 0.4 Hz, p = 0.043). Objective sleep duration (6:53 &#xb1; 1:19 vs. 7:04 &#xb1; 1:19 h:mm, p = 0.21), fatigue (6 &#xb1; 2.1 vs. 5.8 &#xb1; 2.1 AU, p = 0.55), and other outcomes remained unchanged ( p &gt; 0.37). These results indicate that unsupervised and standardized sleep hygiene recommendations were not associated with changes in sleep habits, with changes in cognitive performance and fatigue level that could not be reconducted to better sleep.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varesco</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Research in Sleep Medicine, H&#xf4;pital du Sacr&#xe9;-Coeur de Montr&#xe9;al, CIUSSS du Nord de l'&#xce;le-de- Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Sport of Qu&#xe9;bec, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Germain</LastName><ForeName>Micka&#xeb;l</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Research in Sleep Medicine, H&#xf4;pital du Sacr&#xe9;-Coeur de Montr&#xe9;al, CIUSSS du Nord de l'&#xce;le-de- Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szocs</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Research in Sleep Medicine, H&#xf4;pital du Sacr&#xe9;-Coeur de Montr&#xe9;al, CIUSSS du Nord de l'&#xce;le-de- Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Research in Sleep Medicine, H&#xf4;pital du Sacr&#xe9;-Coeur de Montr&#xe9;al, CIUSSS du Nord de l'&#xce;le-de- Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toussaint</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Mary</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Sport of Qu&#xe9;bec, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carabins de Montr&#xe9;al, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simonelli</LastName><ForeName>Guido</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Research in Sleep Medicine, H&#xf4;pital du Sacr&#xe9;-Coeur de Montr&#xe9;al, CIUSSS du Nord de l'&#xce;le-de- Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neuroscience, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>297725</GrantID><Agency>Minist&#xe8;re de l'&#xc9;ducation, du Loisir et du Sport Qu&#xe9;bec, Fonds de recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec - Sant&#xe9;</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070263" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Hygiene</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011597" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychomotor Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="N">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056044" MajorTopicYN="N">Actigraphy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Canadian football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elite sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41160418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202601000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Avedesian JM, Forbes W, Covassin T, Dufek JS. Influence of cognitive performance on musculoskeletal injury risk: A systematic review. Am J Sports Med 50: 554&#x2013;562, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basner M. Ultra-short objective alertness assessment: An adaptive duration version of the 3 minute PVT (PVT-BA) accurately tracks changes in psychomotor vigilance induced by sleep restriction. Sleep Adv 3: zpac038, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien CH, Valli&#xe8;res A, Morin CM. Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Med 2: 297&#x2013;307, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke TM, Lisman PJ, Maguire K, et al. Examination of sleep and injury among college football athletes. J Strength Cond Res 34: 609&#x2013;616, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Scott TJ, Halson SL, Kelly VG. The influence of sleep hygiene education on sleep in professional rugby league athletes. Sleep Health 4: 364&#x2013;368, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney CE, Buysse DJ, Ancoli-Israel S, et al. The consensus sleep diary: Standardizing prospective sleep self-monitoring. Sleep 35: 287&#x2013;302, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaput J-P, Dutil C, Featherstone R, et al. Sleep timing, sleep consistency, and health in adults: A systematic review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 45: S232&#x2013;S247, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha LA, Costa JA, Marques EA, Brito J, Lastella M, Figueiredo P. The impact of sleep interventions on athletic performance: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 9: 58, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daub BD, McLean BD, Heishman AD, Peak KM, Coutts AJ. The relationship between mental fatigue and shooting performance over the course of a National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I basketball season. J Strength Cond Res 38: 334&#x2013;341, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zambotti M, Goldstein C, Cook J, et al. State of the science and recommendations for using wearable technology in sleep and circadian research. Sleep 47: zsad325, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietch JR, Taylor DJ, Sethi K, Kelly K, Bramoweth AD, Roane BM. Psychometric evaluation of the PSQI in U.S. college students. J Clin Sleep Med 12: 1121&#x2013;1129, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosseville F, Laborde S, Lericollais R. Validation of a chronotype questionnaire including an amplitude dimension. Chronobiol Int 30: 639&#x2013;648, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckard EW. Does the NCAA's collegiate model promote competitive balance? Power-5 conference football versus the NFL. J Sports Econ 20: 654&#x2013;670, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbaz M, Yauy K, Metlaine A, Martoni M, Leger D. Validation of a new Actigraph MotionWatch versus Polysomnography on 70 healthy and suspected sleep disordered subjects. J Sleep Res 21: 218, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright T, Refinetti R. Chronotype, class times, and academic achievement of university students. Chronobiol Int 34: 445&#x2013;450, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs ER, Boiling S, Balanos GM. The effects of time of day and chronotype on cognitive and physical performance in healthy volunteers. Sports Med Open 4: 47, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fos LA, Greve KW, South MB, Mathias C, Benefield H. Paced visual serial addition test: An alternative measure of information processing speed. Appl Neuropsychol 7: 140&#x2013;146, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Scanlan AT, Stanton R, Sargent C. Insufficient sleep in young athletes? Causes, consequences, and potential treatments. Sports Med 50: 461&#x2013;470, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Meyer T. The effect of an acute sleep hygiene strategy following a late-night soccer match on recovery of players. Chronobiol Int 33: 490&#x2013;505, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves MT, Malafaia S, Moutinho Dos Santos J, Roth T, Marques DR. Epworth sleepiness scale: A meta-analytic study on the internal consistency. Sleep Med 109: 261&#x2013;269, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Johnston RD, Appaneal RN, et al. Sleep quality in elite athletes: Normative values, reliability and understanding contributors to poor sleep. Sports Med 52: 417&#x2013;426, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MJ, Dunican IC, Murray K, et al. The psychomotor vigilance test: A comparison of different test durations in elite athletes. J Sports Sci 36: 2033&#x2013;2037, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M, Nieuwenhuys A, Maase K, et al. Effects of natural between-days variation in sleep on elite athletes' psychomotor vigilance and sport-specific measures of performance. J Sports Sci Med 17: 515&#x2013;524, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach GD, Halson SL, Sargent C. The chronotype of elite athletes. J Hum Kinet 54: 219&#x2013;225, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazeron RHC, Rombouts SARB, de Sonneville L, Barkhof F, Scheltens P. A paced visual serial addition test for fMRI. J Neurol Sci 213: 29&#x2013;34, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecci S, Cataldi J, Betta M, Bernardi G, Heinzer R, Siclari F. Electroencephalographic changes associated with subjective under- and overestimation of sleep duration. Sleep 43: zsaa094, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Kezirian EJ, Marcello BM, Dement WC. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. Sleep Health 4: 251&#x2013;257, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mairesse O, Damen V, Newell J, Kornreich C, Verbanck P, Neu D. The Brugmann fatigue scale: An analogue to the Epworth sleepiness scale to measure behavioral rest propensity. Behav Sleep Med 17: 437&#x2013;458, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltezos A, Perrault AA, Walsh NA, et al. Methodological approach to sleep state misperception in insomnia disorder: Comparison between multiple nights of actigraphy recordings and a single night of polysomnography recording. Sleep Med 115: 21&#x2013;29, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin JS, H&#xe9;bert M, Ledoux &#xc9;, Gaudreault M, Laberge L. Relationship of chronotype to sleep, light exposure, and work-related fatigue in student workers. Chronobiol Int 29: 295&#x2013;304, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Yousfi N, Mhenni T, et al. Does one night of partial sleep deprivation affect the evening performance during intermittent exercise in Taekwondo players? J Exerc Rehabil. 12: 47&#x2013;53, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messman BA, Petrie KA, Moore EWG, Petrie TA. Sleep disturbances and risk of sports injury among collegiate student-athletes. Clin J Sport Med 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Driller MW. Sleep-hygiene education improves sleep indices in elite female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci 10: 522&#x2013;530, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon M, Wickwire EM, Hirshkowitz M, et al. National Sleep Foundation's sleep quality recommendations: First report. Sleep Health 3: 6&#x2013;19, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pivovarnicek P, Kondratova D, Kentiba E, Jancokova L, Maly T. Does the chronotype distribution vary between different level football leagues? Insights gained from Czech elite football players. Chronobiol Int 38: 1162&#x2013;1169, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roenneberg T. How can social jetlag affect health? Nat Rev Endocrinol 19: 383&#x2013;384, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryswyk EV, Weeks R, Bandick L, et al. A novel sleep optimisation programme to improve athletes' well-being and performance. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 144&#x2013;151, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The validity of activity monitors for measuring sleep in elite athletes. J Sci Med Sport 19: 848&#x2013;853, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanski EJ, Wyatt JK. Use of sleep hygiene in the treatment of insomnia. Sleep Med Rev 7: 215&#x2013;225, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinbourne R, Gill N, Vaile J, Smart D. Prevalence of poor sleep quality, sleepiness and obstructive sleep apnoea risk factors in athletes. Eur J Sport Sci 16: 850&#x2013;858, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner RW, Vissa K, Hall C, et al. Sleep problems are associated with academic performance in a national sample of collegiate athletes. J Am Coll Health 69: 74&#x2013;81, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dort CJ. Locus coeruleus neural fatigue: A potential mechanism for cognitive impairment during sleep deprivation. Sleep 39: 11&#x2013;12, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verwey M, Amir S. From genes to chronotypes: The influence of circadian clock genes on our daily patterns of sleep and wakefulness. Ann Transl Med 4: 184, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, et al. Sleep and the athlete: Narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med 55: 356&#x2013;368, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>