<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41519923</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-0294</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pharmaceutical health care and sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pharm Health Care Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Knowledge, attitude and practice towards antimicrobial resistance among final-year undergraduate students in the health sciences at Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40780-025-00534-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Globally, antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is a complex and growing public health challenge, primarily driven by the inappropriate use of antimicrobials. Promoting the rational use of these agents is the most effective strategy for preventing AMR. This can be achieved by improving the knowledge, attitudes, and practices of both prescribers and dispensers. Hence, this study will aim to assess knowledge, attitude and practice (KAP) of final year health sciences students regarding AMR, which helps to rationalize the use of antimicrobials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To assess KAP towards AMR among final year health sciences students at Addis Ababa University</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The research employed a cross-sectional study design, involving 230 final-year health sciences students from various programs, including medicine, pharmacy, nursing, midwifery, anesthesia, medical radiology technology, and medical laboratory sciences. Data were collected by Kobo toolbox online structured questionnaire and analyzed using SPSS version 27.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT">The findings indicated that while 74.5% of participants possessed moderate knowledge and 81.4% displayed positive attitudes, notable gaps were evident. Among the participants, 137(59.6%) mistakenly believed that antibiotics can eliminate viruses, and 166(72.2%) thought antibiotics were effective against colds and flu. Furthermore, concerning practices such as reserving antibiotics for future use 98(42.6 %) and 73(31.7%) participants responded sharing antibiotics with others. Despite these deficiencies, students exhibited a strong awareness of the consequences of AMR 217(94.7%) and acknowledged the role of overuse in fostering resistance 205(89.0%). Attitudes were predominantly positive, with 189(82.2%) advocating for increased AMR education and 192(83.5%) recognizing that improper use contributes to resistance. However, practical behaviors, such as prematurely discontinuing antibiotics 68(29.6 %) and an overall poor practice 52(22.5%) underscored the necessity for enhanced optimized training for health sciences students. Despite no significant link between gender or field of study and KAP, participants with moderate and good AMR knowledge were significantly more likely to have optimal practices than those with poor knowledge (AOR = 9.44 and 3.9, (P&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.017 and 0.021) respectively). Similarly, a positive attitude significantly increases optimal practice chances by about 3.39 fold (P&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.012).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The study revealed moderate AMR knowledge and overall positive attitudes, but persistent misconceptions about antibiotic use. Moderate or good knowledge and neutral or positive attitudes were associated with more optimal practices. Suboptimal practices highlight the need for strengthening education, and institutional interventions including short term trainings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40780-025-00534-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bedada</LastName><ForeName>Fasil Dejene</ForeName><Initials>FD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Pharmacy School of Pharmacy, College of Health Sciences, Addis Ababa University, Churchill Avenue, P.O. Box 1176, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muhammed</LastName><ForeName>Oumer Sada</ForeName><Initials>OS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Pharmacy School of Pharmacy, College of Health Sciences, Addis Ababa University, Churchill Avenue, P.O. Box 1176, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nasir</LastName><ForeName>Beshir Bedru</ForeName><Initials>BB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Clinical Pharmacy School of Pharmacy, College of Health Sciences, Addis Ababa University, Churchill Avenue, P.O. Box 1176, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. beshir.bedru@aau.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Pharm Health Care Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672177</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-0294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attitude and practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health sciences students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: Ethical clearance was secured from the institutional review board of the School of Pharmacy, Addis Ababa University (ERB/SOP/42.25/17/2025). A written consent was obtained from the participants with an explanation about the purpose of the study, confidentiality, and the respondents&#x2019; right to take part or not to take part in the this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41519923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40780-025-00534-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40780-025-00534-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Antimicrobial resistance: A global threat. WHO; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vila J, Pal T. Update on Antibacterial Resistance in Low-Income Countries: Factors Favoring the Emergence of Resistance, 2010. The Open Infectious Diseases Journal, 2010, 4, 38&#x2013;54. 10.2174/1874279301004020038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Precha N, Sukmai S, Hengbaru M et al. Jan., Knowledge, attitudes, and practices regarding antibiotic use and resistance among health science and non-health science university students in Thailand, PLoS One, vol. 19, no. 1 January, 2024, 10.1371/journal.pone.0296822</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10769033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38180959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melku L, Wubetu M, Dessie B. Irrational drug use and its associated factors at Debre Markos referral hospital&#x2019;s outpatient pharmacy in East Gojjam, Northwest Ethiopia. SAGE Open Med. 2021;9. 10.1177/20503121211025146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8202335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34178342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulcini C, Wencker F, Frimodt-M&#xf8;ller N, et al. European survey on principles of prudent antibiotic prescribing teaching in undergraduate students. Clin Microbiol Infect. Apr. 2015;21(4):354&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.cmi.2014.11.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation (IHME). (2023). <i>The burden of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in Ethiopia</i>. IHME. https://www.healthdata.org/sites/default/files/2023-09/Ethiopia.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diriba K, Awulachew E, Gemede A, Anja A. The magnitude of extended-spectrum beta-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae from clinical samples in ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Access Microbiol. 2021;3(3):000195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/acmi.0.000195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8209701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34151151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse YB, Kassaw AT, Belachew EA. Evaluating self-medication practices in Ethiopia. J Pharm Policy Pract. 2023;16:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-023-00553-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10029313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36945071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haile KT, Yabeyu AB. Knowledge, attitude and practice of pharmacy professionals against dispensing antibiotics without prescription in Ethiopia. Integr Pharm Res Pract. 2022 Jan;1:167&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9717598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36465587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min S, Zhou Y, Sun Y, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practice associated with antimicrobial resistance among medical students between 2017 and 2022: A survey in East China. Front Public Health. 2022;10:1010582. 10.3389/fpubh.2022.1010582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1010582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9637849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36353280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthymiou P, Gkentzi D, Dimitriou G. Knowledge, attitudes and perceptions of medical students on antimicrobial stewardship. Antibiotics. 2020;9(11):821. 10.3390/antibiotics9110821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics9110821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7698472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33213047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa&#x2019;adatu Sunusi L, Mohamed Awad M, Makinga N, Hassan, Abubakar Isa C. Assessment of knowledge and attitude toward antibiotic use and resistance among students of international university of Africa, medical complex, Sudan. Glob Drugs Ther. 2019;4(2). 10.15761/gdt.1000171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid MA, Hussen MS. Knowledge and attitude towards antimicrobial resistance among final year undergraduate paramedical students at university of Gondar, Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. Jul. 2018;18(1). 10.1186/s12879-018-3199-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6035414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29980174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadasivam K, Chinnasami B, Ramraj B, Karthick N, Saravanan A. Knowledge, attitude and practice of paramedical staff towards antibiotic usage and its resistance. Biomedical Pharmacol J. 2016;9(1):337&#x2013;43. 10.13005/bpj/944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13005/bpj/944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Implementing the WHO stop TB strategy: a handbook for National TB control programmes. World Health Organization; 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26269864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emera NM, El-Baraky IA, Abbassi MM, Sabry NA. Knowledge, Attitude, and practice towards antibiotics use among medical sector Final-Year students in Egypt. Med Sci Educ Dec. 2024. 10.1007/s40670-024-02117-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40670-024-02117-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11698705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Xie J, Chen Q, et al. Knowledge, Attitude, and practice about antibiotic use and antimicrobial resistance among nursing students in china: A cross sectional study. Infect Drug Resist. 2024 Dec;31:1085&#x2013;98. 10.2147/IDR.S454489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10960542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38525475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varshney S, Karthika P, Ahmad S, Mehnaz S. Knowledge, Attitude and Practices Regarding Antimicrobial Resistance among Undergraduate Students, Indian J Community Health, vol. 36, no. 4, pp. 556&#x2013;564, 2024, 10.47203/IJCH.2024.v36i04.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orok E, Ikpe F, Williams T, Ekada I. Impact of educational intervention on knowledge of antimicrobial resistance and antibiotic use patterns among healthcare students: a pre- and post-intervention study. BMC Med Educ. Dec. 2025;25(1). 10.1186/s12909-025-06856-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11843993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuniawati H, Hassali MAA, Suryawati S, Ismail WI, Taufik T, Hossain MS. Assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice of antibiotic use among the population of boyolali, indonesia: A cross-sectional study, Int J Environ Res Public Health, vol. 18, no. 16, Aug. 2021, 10.3390/ijerph18168258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higuita-Guti&#xe9;rrez LF, Roncancio Villamil GE, Jim&#xe9;nez JN, Quiceno. Knowledge, attitude, and practice regarding antibiotic use and resistance among medical students in colombia: a cross-sectional descriptive study. BMC Public Health. Dec. 2020;20(1). 10.1186/s12889-020-09971-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33276767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merahi MK, Yallew WW. Physicians&#x2019; perception towards continuing professional development in government teaching hospitals of addis Ababa, Ethiopia-mixed method design. BMC Health Serv Res. 2025;25(1):111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-12261-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11748240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39833785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebregzabher EH, Tesfaye F, Cheneke W, Negesso AE, Kedida G. Continuing professional development (CPD) training needs assessment for medical laboratory professionals in Ethiopia. Hum Resour Health. 2023;21(1):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-023-00837-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10283226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37340429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldu MA. Antimicrobial resistance in ethiopia: current landscape, challenges, and strategic interventions. Discover Med. 2024;1(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44337-024-00090-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalew MB. Self-medication practice in Ethiopia: a systematic review. Patient preference and adherence. 2017;1:401&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5338978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>