<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41803799</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-6148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC veterinary research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Vet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Promoting antimicrobial stewardship on dairy farms in Mekelle, Northern Ethiopia: a field intervention with One Health implications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12917-026-05385-z</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsegay</LastName><ForeName>Haftom Yirga</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Basics and Diagnostic Sciences, College of Veterinary Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia. haftom.yirga@mu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sisay</LastName><ForeName>Tadelech Yilma</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Basics and Diagnostic Sciences, College of Veterinary Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hailu</LastName><ForeName>Mebrahtu Weldegebriel</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Clinical Medicine and Epidemiology, College of Veterinary Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tekleargis</LastName><ForeName>Werkey Araya</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Basics and Diagnostic Sciences, College of Veterinary Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahle</LastName><ForeName>Muuz Gebru</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Basics and Diagnostic Sciences, College of Veterinary Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Doctoral School of Biology and Environmental Sciences, University of Debrecen, Debrecen, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RADO/EXTERINAL/MS0025/2024</GrantID><Agency>Norwegian University of Life Sciences (NMBU) under the MU-HU-NMBU-ICP V Research Projects</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Vet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101249759</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-6148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dairy farm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Farmer training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">One Health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was reviewed and approved by Mekelle University, College of Veterinary Sciences Research and Ethics Review Committee. All the participating farm owners and workers were informed about the study objectives and procedures, and written informed consent was obtained before data collection. Participation was voluntary, and all the data were anonymized to ensure confidentiality. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41803799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-026-05385-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12917-026-05385-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sawant RSH, Meena L, Panda, Ajit Ramesh. Antimicrobials: Advances in Pharmaceutical and Medicinal Research. Antimicrobials in Pharmaceutical and Medicinal Research. 1st edition. Boca Raton: CRC; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Antimicrobial resistance. 2023. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/antimicrobial-resistance.&#xa0;&#xa0;Cited 8 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brun-Buisson C. Prudent antibiotic use in response to the antimicrobial resistance challenges. Rev Prat. 2017;67(2):217&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukushima Y, Kino E, Furutani A, Minamino T, Honkawa K, Horii Y, et al. Effect of Major Diseases on Productivity of a Large Dairy Farm in a Temperate Zone in Japan. Dairy. 2022;3(4):789&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong E, McCubbin KD, Speksnijder D, Dufour S, Middleton JR, Ruegg PL, et al. Invited review: Selective treatment of clinical mastitis in dairy cattle. J Dairy Sci. 2023;106(6):3761&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges N, Regassa F, Yilma T, Unakal CG. Isolation and Antimicrobial Susceptibility of Bacteria from Dairy Cows with Clinical Endometritis. J Reprod Infertility. 2013; 4(1): 04-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yohannes G, Isolation. Identification and Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing of Escherichia coli Isolated from Selected Dairy Farms in and Around Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia. J Vet Sci Technol. 2018;09(02). Available from: https://doi.org/10.4172/2157-7579.1000518 Cited 8 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalayu AA, Woldetsadik DA, Woldeamanuel Y, Wang SH, Gebreyes WA, Teferi T. Burden and antimicrobial resistance of S. aureus in dairy farms in Mekelle, Northern Ethiopia. BMC Vet Res. 2020;16(1):20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold KE, Laing G, McMahon BJ, Fanning S, Stekel DJ, Pahl O, et al. The need for One Health systems-thinking approaches to understand multiscale dissemination of antimicrobial resistance. Lancet Planet Health. 2024;8(2):e124&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey S, Doo H, Keum GB, Kim ES, Kwak J, Ryu S, et al. Antibiotic resistance in livestock, environment and humans: One Health perspective. J Anim Sci Technol. 2024;66(2):266&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wee BA, Muloi DM, van Bunnik BAD. Quantifying the transmission of antimicrobial resistance at the human and livestock interface with genomics. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26(12):1612&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doron S, Davidson LE. Antimicrobial Stewardship. Mayo Clin Proc. 2011;86(11):1113&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrink KA, DeRonde KJ, Jimenez A, Rosello G, Natori Y, Claeys KC, et al. Impact of a real-time diagnostic and antimicrobial stewardship workflow on time to appropriate therapy for infections caused by multidrug-resistant Gram-negative organisms. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2023;61(6):106811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha J, Zahra F, Cannady J. Antimicrobial Stewardship. In: StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK572068/.&#xa0; Cited 8 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garzon A, Portillo R, Habing G, Silva-del-Rio N, Karle BM, Pereira R. Development and implementation of an onfarm animal health and diagnostic educational training program for farm workers in antimicrobial stewardship in adult dairy cattle. American Association of Bovine Practitioners Conference Proceedings. 2022;(55):179&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allerton F, Russell J. Antimicrobial stewardship in veterinary medicine: a review of online resources. JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2023;5(3):dlad058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motegi T, Fukuoka R, Tsuyuki Y, Nagakubo D, Maeda S, Yonezawa T, et al. Evaluating a Targeted Antimicrobial Stewardship Program and Its Temporal Association with Resistance Trends in a Veterinary Referral Hospital. Veterinary Sci. 2025;12(8):743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espadamala A, Pallar&#xe9;s P, Lago A, Silva-del-R&#xed;o N. Fresh-cow handling practices and methods for identification of health disorders on 45 dairy farms in California. J Dairy Sci. 2016;99(11):9319&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espadamala A, Pereira R, Pallar&#xe9;s P, Lago A, Silva-del-R&#xed;o N. Metritis diagnosis and treatment practices in 45 dairy farms in California. J Dairy Sci. 2018;101(10):9608&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portillo-Gonzalez R, Garzon-Audor A, Pereira RVV, Silva-del-Rio N, Karle BM, Habing GG. Quantification of antimicrobial usage on dairy farms before, during and after the implementation of farmworker stewardship training. American Association of Bovine Practitioners Conference Proceedings. 2022;55:171&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garzon A, Portillo R, Habing G, Silva-del-Rio N, Karle BM, Pereira RV. Antimicrobial stewardship on the dairy: Evaluating an on-farm framework for training farmworkers. Journal of Dairy Science. 2023;106(6):4171&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibt U, Kl&#xf6;tzer P, Rachidi F, Truyen U, Speck S, Starke A, et al. Development of an electronic interface for transfer of antimicrobial administration data in dairy farms. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(12):e0278267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju&#xe1;rez-Carrillo PM, Liebman AK, Reyes IAC, Ninco S&#xe1;nchez YV, Keifer MC. Applying Learning Theory to Safety and Health Training for Hispanic Immigrant Dairy Workers. Health Promotion Practice. 2017;18(4):505&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pempek J, Masterson M, Portillo-Gonzalez R, Creutzinger K, Cheng TY, Habing G. The Impact of Antimicrobial Stewardship Training on Calf Producers&#x2019; Knowledge, Treatment Behaviors and Quantified Antimicrobial Use. Microorganisms. 2022;10(8):1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Nickerson R, Zhang W, Peng X, Shang Y, Zhou Y, et al. The impacts of animal agriculture on One Health&#x2014;Bacterial zoonosis, antimicrobial resistance, and beyond. One Health. 2024;1:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez A, Lee J, Kang H. Navigating the Interconnected Web of Health: A Comprehensive Review of the One Health Paradigm and Its Implications for Disease Management. Yonsei Med J. 2025;66(4):203&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta A, Roland-Holst D, Nicolli F, Tirkaso W, Rocha JS, Song J. A One Health framework to assess the economic returns on investment in livestock antimicrobial stewardship. One Health. 2025;21:101188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelfattah EM, Ekong PS, Okello E, Williams DR, Karle BM, Rowe JD, et al. 2019 Survey of Antimicrobial Drug Use and Stewardship Practices in Adult Cows on California Dairies: Post Senate Bill 27. Microorganisms. 2021;9(7):1507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallu SA, Kebede N, Kassa T, Wubaye AM, Kainga H, Mekonnen H, et al. Knowledge, Attitudes, Practices, and Risk Perception of Antimicrobial Use and Antimicrobial Resistance Among Dairy Farm Owners/Workers in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Infect Drug Resist. 2024;17:1839&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global action plan on antimicrobial resistance [Internet]. 2016 [cited 2025 Oct 22]. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241509763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. The FAO Action Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance 2021&#x2013;2025. Supporting innovation and resilience in food and agriculture sectors. Rome, Italy. 2021. Available from: https://openknowledge.fao.org/handle/20.500.14283/cb5545en. Cited 22 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WOAH. Chapter 6.10. Responsible and Prudent Use of Antimicrobial Agents in Veterinary Medicine [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2025 Oct 22]. Available from: https://www.woah.org/fileadmin/Home/eng/Health_standards/tahc/2024/en_chapitre_antibio_use.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufa TB, Regassa F, Amenu K, Stegeman JA, Hogeveen H. Livestock producers&#x2019; knowledge, attitude, and behavior (KAB) regarding antimicrobial use in Ethiopia. Front Vet Sci. 2023;10:1167847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirwa EM, Mujawamariya G, Shimelash N, Shyaka A. Evaluation of cattle farmers&#x2019; knowledge, attitudes, and practices regarding antimicrobial use and antimicrobial resistance in Rwanda. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(4):e0300742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkema HW, von Keyserlingk MAG, Kastelic JP, Lam TJGM, Luby C, Roy JP, et al. Invited review: Changes in the dairy industry affecting dairy cattle health and welfare. J Dairy Sci. 2015;98(11):7426&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KE, Weary DM, von Keyserlingk MAG. Graduate Student Literature Review: Challenges and opportunities for human resource management on dairy farms *. J Dairy Sci. 2021;104(1):1192&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higham LE, Deakin A, Tivey E, Porteus V, Ridgway S, Rayner AC. A survey of dairy cow farmers in the United Kingdom: knowledge, attitudes and practices surrounding antimicrobial use and resistance. Vet Rec. 2018;183(24):746&#x2013;746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasquez AK, Foditsch C, Duli&#xe8;pre SAC, Siler JD, Just DR, Warnick LD, et al. Understanding the effect of producers&#x2019; attitudes, perceived norms, and perceived behavioral control on intentions to use antimicrobials prudently on New York dairy farms. PLoS ONE. 2019;11(9):e0222442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobo-Angel C, LeBlanc SJ, Roche SM, Ritter C. A Focus Group Study of Canadian Dairy Farmers&#x2019; Attitudes and Social Referents on Antimicrobial Use and Antimicrobial Resistance. Front Vet Sci. 2021;8:645221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipkens Z, Piepers S, De Vliegher S. Impact of Selective Dry Cow Therapy on Antimicrobial Consumption, Udder Health, Milk Yield, and Culling Hazard in Commercial Dairy Herds. Antibiot (Basel). 2023;12(5):901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portillo-Gonzalez R, Garzon A, Pereira RVV, Silva-Del-Rio N, Karle BM, Habing GG. Effect of a dairy farmworker stewardship training program on antimicrobial drug usage in dairy cows. J Dairy Sci. 2024;107(5):2941&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruegg PL, Realities. Challenges and Benefits of Antimicrobial Stewardship in Dairy Practice in the United States. Microorganisms. 2022;10(8):1626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green MJ, Leach KA, Breen JE, Green LE, Bradley AJ. National intervention study of mastitis control in dairy herds in England and Wales. Vet Rec. 2007;160(9):287&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam TJGM, van den Borne BHP, Jansen J, Huijps K, van Veersen JCL, van Schaik G, et al. Improving bovine udder health: A national mastitis control program in the Netherlands. J Dairy Sci. 2013;96(2):1301&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haxhiaj K, Wishart DS, Ametaj BN, Mastitis. What It Is, Current Diagnostics, and the Potential of Metabolomics to Identify New Predictive Biomarkers. Dairy. 2022;3(4):722&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panicker A, Changaroth A, Gangadharan SV, Yamamoto T, Noothalapati H, Nambudiri MK, et al. From farms to homes: navigating antimicrobial resistance landscapes from livestock to humans. One Health Adv. 2025;18(1):20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita AW, Werner K, Jacob JT, Tschopp R, Mamo G, Mihret A, et al. Antimicrobial Resistance Through the Lens of One Health in Ethiopia: A Review of the Literature Among Humans, Animals, and the Environment. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;119:120&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeru F, Adamu H, Woldearegay YH, Tessema TS, Hansson I, Boqvist S, Occurrence. Risk factors and Antimicrobial resistance of Campylobacter from Poultry and Humans in Central Ethiopia: A One Health Approach. medRxiv; 2025. p. 2025.02.14.25322269. Available from: https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2025.02.14.25322269v1.&#xa0;&#xa0;Cited 9 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufa TB, Amenu K, Fasil N, Regassa F, Beyene TJ, Revie CW, et al. Prudent use and antimicrobial prescription practices in Ethiopian veterinary clinics located in different agroecological areas. BMC Vet Res. 2024;20(1):538.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>