<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41214568</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers and facilitators to implementing the birth preparedness and complication readiness strategy: midwives' perceptions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1186</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1186</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1186</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-025-08307-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Maternal mortality remains a major public health concern in Nigeria, largely due to delays in accessing skilled care. Birth Preparedness and Complication Readiness (BPCR) is a strategy designed to improve timely access to care. This study explores midwives&#x2019; perspectives on barriers and facilitators to BPCR implementation in Ogbomoso, Nigeria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A qualitative study was conducted involving in-depth semi-structured interviews with 14 purposively selected midwives from four healthcare facilities in Ogbomoso. Data were analyzed using Tesch&#x2019;s eight-step thematic analysis approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Barriers to BPCR implementation included poverty, cultural resistance, health illiteracy, staffing shortages, geographical barriers, and limited male involvement. Facilitators included visual health education, support from community and religious leaders, family involvement, peer support among midwives, and NGO assistance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Midwives face complex barriers in promoting BPCR in resource-limited settings. Strengthening health systems, enhancing community engagement, and improving training and support for midwives are key to improving maternal health outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esan</LastName><ForeName>Deborah Tolulope</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing Sciences, College of Health Sciences, Bowen University, Iwo, Nigeria. deborah.esan@bowen.edu.ng.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onilude</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth Akintunde</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing Sciences, College of Health Sciences, Bowen University, Iwo, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Guillermo</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of California, San Diego, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antenatal care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Barriers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Birth preparedness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complication readiness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Facilitators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maternal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Midwives</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from Bowen University Teaching Hospital Research Ethics Committee, which is part of the&#xa0;Bowen University Teaching Hospital, Ogbomoso, Oyo State, Nigeria. The approval number is BUTH/REC-2564. Written informed consent was obtained from each of the study participants. The study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki, ensuring respect for participants' rights, welfare, and dignity. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12604185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-08307-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-025-08307-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdul HM, Hunter B, Warren LE, Sakellariou D. Experiences of workplace adversity among midwives in labour wards of tertiary hospitals in northern Nigeria. Afr J Midwifery Women&#x2019;s Health. 2023;17(3):1&#x2013;12.&#xa0;10.12968/ajmw.2022.0028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/ajmw.2022.0028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameh CA, Msuya SE, Tarimo EA. Traditional birth attendants and maternal health care in Nigeria: Understanding the challenges and opportunities for better integration. Afr J Reprod Health. 2021;25(3):27&#x2013;37. 10.29063/ajrh2021/v25i3.4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29063/ajrh2021/v25i3.4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinwale B, Omisore O. Midwives' experiences with BPCR education in Nigeria. J Midwifery Pract. 2025;22(3):145&#x2013;160. [Not yet published; placeholder for future citation].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajibade BL, Afolabi MO, Adeniran OM. Barriers to the utilization of birth preparedness and complication readiness among women in rural Nigeria. Afr J Reprod Health. 2022;26(4):44&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doku DT, Neupane S, Seidu AA. Birth preparedness and complication readiness and associated factors among women attending antenatal care in Ghana: a cross-sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2019;19:107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedefa D. Enhancing maternal health literacy: a community-based approach. J Public Health Educ. 2025;31(1):57&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliyasu Z, Abubakar IS, Galadanci HS, Aliyu MH. Birth preparedness and complication readiness among pregnant women in rural communities in northern Nigeria. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):636. 10.1186/s12884-020-03372-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-03372-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JHPIEGO. Monitoring birth preparedness and complication readiness: Tools and indicators for maternal and newborn health. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karkee R, Lee AH, Binns CW. Birth preparedness and skilled attendance at birth in Nepal: implications for achieving Millennium Development Goal 5. Midwifery. 2013;29(10):1206&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.midw.2013.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.midw.2013.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23751594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukasse M, Henriksen L. Norwegian midwives&#x2019; perceptions of their practice environment: a mixed methods study. Nurs Open. 2019;6(4):1559&#x2013;70. 10.1002/nop2.358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mgbekem MU, Umeora OUJ, Ejikeme BN. The impact of workload and stress on midwives&#x2019; performance in Nigeria. Int J Nurs Pract. 2020;26(2):e12815. 10.1111/ijn.12815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijn.12815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32034848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran AC, Sangli G, Dine D, Rawlins B, Osrin D. Birth preparedness and complication readiness interventions to reduce maternal and neonatal mortality in developing countries: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18(1):263. 10.1186/s12884-018-1854-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-018-1854-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24708719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachinab GT, Yakong VN, Dubik JD, Klutse KD, Asumah MN, Bimpong BN, et al. Perceptions on birth preparedness and complication readiness: perspectives of pregnant women. SAGE Open. 2023;13(4):21582440231207136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21582440231207136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njiku FG, Magwilla CM, Nyamhanga T. Influence of male involvement on birth preparedness and complication readiness among pregnant women in Tanzania. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2022;22(1):487. 10.1186/s12884-022-04911-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-022-04911-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogbuabor DC, Okoronkwo IL. Midwives&#x2019; perspectives on person-centred maternity care in public hospitals in South-east Nigeria: a mixed-method study. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(12):e0261147. 10.1371/journal.pone.0261147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0261147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8664165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguntunde O, Olaleye A, Adeoye O. Health system challenges in implementing birth preparedness and complication readiness in Nigeria. Niger J Health Sci. 2023;23(1):55&#x2013;62. 10.4314/njhs.v23i1.8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/njhs.v23i1.8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogo KO, Mbugua B, Kamau M. Assessment of infrastructure and maternal health service availability in primary health facilities in Kenya. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21:1123. 10.1186/s12913-021-07181-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-07181-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendo E, Msuya S, Mahande MJ. Cultural beliefs and maternal health care seeking behaviors in Tanzania. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):30. 10.1186/s12884-020-2731-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-2731-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soubeiga D, Gauvin L, Hatem M, Johri M. Birth preparedness and complication readiness interventions to reduce maternal and neonatal mortality in developing countries: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2014;14(1). 10.1186/1471-2393-14-129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24708719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaddeus S, Maine D. Too far to walk: maternal mortality in context. Soc Sci Med. 1994;38(8):1091&#x2013;110. 10.1016/0277-9536(94)90226-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0277-9536(94)90226-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8042057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tura GA, Fantahun M, Worku A. Birth preparedness and complication readiness among pregnant women in Ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20:363. 10.1186/s12884-020-03050-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-03050-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund (UNICEF). Maternal and newborn health in Nigeria. 2022. https://data.unicef.org/country/nga/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank. Maternal mortality ratio (modeled estimate, per 100,000 live births) &#x2013; Nigeria. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Strategies toward ending preventable maternal mortality (EPMM). 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Trends in maternal mortality: 2000 to 2017. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahaya I, Akinyemi OO, Ogunleye OO. Challenges facing midwives in rural Nigeria: Impact on maternal health care delivery. Int J Nurs Midwifery. 2020;12(5):45&#x2013;54. 10.5897/IJNM2019.0372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/IJNM2019.0372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>