<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41639893</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1465-993X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respiratory research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respir Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prognostic models for mortality and hospitalisation risk in a contemporary Australian chronic obstructive pulmonary disease cohort.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">118</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12931-026-03531-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) poses significant public health and economic challenges and performant prognostic models may be useful to direct treatment. The purpose of this study was to develop predictive models, validate the DOSE and updated ADO predictive models, and identify predictors of future hospitalisation and mortality in contemporary Australian COPD patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Data from 8,578 inpatients and outpatients diagnosed with COPD (via post-bronchodilator spirometry) between 2006 and 2021 at a large South Australian tertiary public hospital were analysed. Multivariate logistic models and Cox regression, utilising penalised regularisation in multiply imputed data, were used to investigate predictors of hospitalisation due to COPD exacerbation at 1-, 3-, and 5-years post-diagnosis, and COPD-specific mortality at 3- and 5-years. Haemoglobin-corrected DLCO (DLCOc) was used to extend the DOSE and updated ADO models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Locally developed models could predict COPD-specific 1-year hospitalisation risk with AUCs 0.80 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.76, 0.83]) in males and 0.82 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.78, 0.86]) in females on a temporally distinct hold-out set, with 3- and 5-year AUCs falling within this range. COPD-specific mortality was predicted with AUCs of 0.90 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.85, 0.94]) and 0.89 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.84, 0.92]) at 3 and 5&#xa0;years in females, and 0.90 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.86, 0.93]) and 0.88 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.84, 0.92]) in males. Cox regression models predicted survival well in the test set for both females (C-index&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.88, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.85, 0.90]) and males (C-index&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.86, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.82, 0.88]). Local model performance was superior to that of the DOSE and updated ADO models for all outcomes, although not always significantly. Among the selected predictors, reduced DLCOc was strongly predictive of all outcomes. and acts as a short-term survival risk for follow-up durations less than 10&#xa0;years. There was no significant difference in performance between sex, and there were differences in selected features and feature strength between sexes. Extending the extant clinical models with DLCOc significantly improved updated ADO and DOSE model fit and improved discriminatory performance, with the extended ADO index achieving AUC of 0.77 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.75, 0.79]) and 0.87 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.84, 0.89]) for predicting 5-year hospitalisation and mortality respectively across the full cohort. The extended DOSE index performed similarly with AUCs 0.77 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;[0.75, 0.79]) and 0.87 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.83, 0.89)) for 5-year hospitalisation and mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Ours is the only large clinical cohort and prognostic study of Australian COPD patients to date. Locally developed models achieved greater discriminative performance than the original updated ADO and DOSE models within our cohort. Extending the ADO and DOSE models with DLCOc significantly improved model fit in our cohort. We recommend further research into the use of DLCOc as a prognostic index for COPD, and its inclusion in future modelling attempts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Retrospectively registered. Clinical trial number: Not Applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12931-026-03531-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Luke A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia. luke.a.smith@adelaide.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia. luke.a.smith@adelaide.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Minyan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bird</LastName><ForeName>Alix</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rose</LastName><ForeName>Anand</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Flinders Medical Centre, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mukherjee</LastName><ForeName>Sutapa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Sleep Medicine, Flinders Medical Centre, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Public Health, Flinders University, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palmer</LastName><ForeName>Lyle J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Respir Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101090633</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1465-9921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic obstructive&#x2019;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exacerbation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#x2018;Pulmonary disease</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Deidentified data was collected retrospectively with a waiver of consent under SAC HREC approval code LNR/22/SAC/2. This study was conducted in accordance with the Australian Code for the Responsible Conduct of Research, 2018. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: LS and AB are supported by a GlaxoSmithKline and Australian Government Research Training Program Scholarship. MZ is supported by an Australian Government Research Training Program Scholarship.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41639893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12964674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-026-03531-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12931-026-03531-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cho MH, Hobbs BD, Silverman EK. Genetics of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: understanding the pathobiology and heterogeneity of a complex disorder. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:485&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11197974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoller JK, Aboussouan LS. &#x3b1;1-antitrypsin deficiency. Lancet. 2005;365:2225&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15978931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation (IHME). GBD Results. Seattle, WA: IHME, University of Washington; 2020. Available from: https://vizhub.healthdata.org/gbd-results/. Cited 2023, 9th September.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Health and Welfare. Australian Burden of Disease Study 2022. Canberra: AIHW; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Health and Welfare. COPD. Canberra: AIHW; 2023.. Available from: https://www.aihw.gov.au/reports/chronic-respiratory-conditions/copd. Cited 2023 Oct. 3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafari Z, Li S, Eakin MN, Bellanger M, Reed RM. Projecting long-term health and economic burden of COPD in the United States. Chest. 2021;159:1400&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33011203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A, Wilkinson TMA. Digital healthcare in COPD management: a narrative review on the advantages, pitfalls, and need for further research. Ther Adv Respir Dis. 2022;16:175346662210754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8894614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; A, Celli BR, Criner GJ, Halpin D, Anzueto A, Barnes P, et al. Global initiative for chronic obstructive lung disease 2023 report: GOLD executive summary. Eur Respir J. 2023;61:2300239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10066569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36858443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabscheck E, George J, Hermann K, McDonald CF, McDonald VM, McNamara R, et al. COPD-X Australian guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: 2022 update. Med J Aust. 2022;217:415&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst JR, Han MK, Singh B, Sharma S, Kaur G, De Nigris E, et al. Prognostic risk factors for moderate-to-severe exacerbations in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic literature review. Respir Res. 2022. 10.1186/s12931-022-02123-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-022-02123-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellou V, Belbasis L, Konstantinidis AK, Tzoulaki I, Evangelou E. Prognostic models for outcome prediction in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: systematic review and critical appraisal. BMJ. 2019;367:l5358. 10.1136/bmj.l5358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6776831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celli BR, Cote CG, Marin JM, Casanova C, de Montes Oca M, Mendez RA, et al. The body-mass index, airflow obstruction, dyspnea, and exercise capacity index in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. N Engl J Med. 2004;350:1005&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14999112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Garcia-Aymerich J, Frey M, ter Riet G, Ant&#xf3; JM, Agust&#xed; AG, et al. Expansion of the prognostic assessment of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: the updated BODE index and the ADO index. Lancet. 2009;374:704&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19716962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RC, Donaldson GC, Chavannes NH, Kida K, Dickson-Spillmann M, Harding S, et al. Derivation and validation of a composite index of severity in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2009;180:1189&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19797160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LA, Oakden-Rayner L, Bird A, Zeng M, To M-S, Mukherjee S, et al. Machine learning and deep learning predictive models for long term prognosis in COPD patients - a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Digital Health 2023. [in press].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38000872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOLD. Global Strategy for the Diagnosis, Management, and Prevention of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease: Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han MK, Agusti A, Calverley PM, Celli BR, Criner G, Curtis JL, et al. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease phenotypes: the future of COPD. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2010;182:598&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6850732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20522794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health AIo, Welfare. Measures of health and health care for Australia and similar countries. Canberra: AIHW; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health AIo, Welfare. Older Australians. Canberra: AIHW; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahler DA, Wells CK. Evaluation of clinical methods for rating dyspnea. Chest. 1988;93:580&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3342669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. ICD-10: international statistical classification of diseases and related health problems&#x202f;: tenth revision. 2nd ed. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A. Scaling regression inputs by dividing by two standard deviations. Stat Med. 2008;27:2865&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17960576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertheiss J, Tutz G. Sparse modeling of categorial explanatory variables. Ann Appl Stat. 2010;4:2150&#x2013;80, 2131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S, Groothuis-Oudshoorn K. mice: Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations in R. J Stat Softw. 2011;45:1&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S. Flexible imputation of missing data. 2nd ed. Boca Raton: Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2018. p. 444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LoMauro A, Aliverti A. Sex and gender in respiratory physiology. Eur Respir Rev. 2021;30:210038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal S, Diaz-Guzman E, Mannino DM. Influence of sex on chronic obstructive pulmonary disease risk and treatment outcomes. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2014;9:1145&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4206206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25342899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman J, Hastie T, Tibshirani R. Regularization paths for generalized linear models via coordinate descent. J Stat Softw. 2010;33:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2929880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20808728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rix A, Du J. miselect: Variable Selection for Multiply Imputed Data. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin X, Hu J, Liu L. On the oracle property of a generalized adaptive elastic-net for multivariate linear regression with a diverging number of parameters. J Multivariate Anal. 2017;162:16&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Multiple imputation for nonresponse in surveys. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Calster B, McLernon DJ, van Smeden M, Wynants L, Steyerberg EW, Bossuyt P, et al. Calibration: the Achilles heel of predictive analytics. BMC Med. 2019;17:230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6912996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31842878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Hansel NN, Sobradillo P, Enright P, Lange P, Hickson D, et al. Large-scale international validation of the ADO index in subjects with COPD: an individual subject data analysis of 10 cohorts. BMJ Open. 2012;2:e002152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23242246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong ER, DeLong DM, Clarke-Pearson DL. Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves: a nonparametric approach. Biometrics. 1988;44:837&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon N, Friedman J, Hastie T, Tibshirani R. Regularization paths for Cox&#x2019;s proportional hazards model via coordinate descent. J Stat Softw. 2011;39:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4824408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27065756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm S. A simple sequentially rejective multiple test procedure. Scand J Stat. 1979;6:65&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owusuaa C, Dijkland SA, Nieboer D, Van Der Rijt CCD, Van Der Heide A. Predictors of mortality in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pulmonary Med. 2022;22:125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8978392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranucci M, Castelvecchio S, Menicanti L, Frigiola A, Pelissero G. Accuracy, calibration and clinical performance of the EuroSCORE: can we reduce the number of variables? Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2010;37:724&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19819158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Reitsma JB, Altman DG, Moons KGM. Transparent reporting of a multivariable prediction model for Individual Prognosis Or Diagnosis (TRIPOD): the TRIPOD statement. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25560714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Huber JC Jr. Evaluation of multiple imputation with large proportions of missing data: how much is too much? Iran J Public Health. 2021;50:1372&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8426774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34568175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, Lee HJ, Lee J-K, Park TY, Jin KN, Heo EY, et al. Diffusing capacity as an independent predictor of acute exacerbations in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Sci Rep. 2024;14:2936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38316813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhang R, Shan H, Shi W, Feng X, Chen H, et al. FVC/DLCO identifies pulmonary hypertension and predicts 5-year all-cause mortality in patients with COPD. Eur J Med Res. 2023;28:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10184375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian A, Putcha N, MacIntyre NR, Jensen RL, Kinney G, Stringer WW, et al. Diffusing capacity and mortality in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2023;20:38&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9819262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Torres JP, O&#x2019;Donnell DE, Mar&#xed;n JM, Cabrera C, Casanova C, Mar&#xed;n M, et al. Clinical and prognostic impact of low diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide values in patients with global initiative for obstructive lung disease I COPD. Chest. 2021;160:872&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng N, Tan C, Yuan L, Xu W, Wang P, Zhao P. The U-shaped relationship between admission peripheral oxygen saturation and all-cause hospital mortality in acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a retrospective analysis using the MIMIC III database. J Thorac Dis. 2025;17:60&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11833588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39975750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golpe R, Esteban C, Figueira-Gon..alves JM, Amado-Diago CA, Blanco-Cid N, Aramburu A, et al. Development and validation of a prognostic index (BODEXS90) for mortality in stable chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Pulmonology. 2023; 29: 276&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33272909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt SP, Kim Y-i, Wells JM, Bailey WC, Ramsdell JW, Foreman MG, et al. FEV1/FEV6 to diagnose airflow obstruction. Comparisons with computed tomography and morbidity indices. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2014;11:335&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst JR, Han MK, Singh B, Sharma S, Kaur G, de Nigris E, et al. Prognostic risk factors for moderate-to-severe exacerbations in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic literature review. Respir Res. 2022;23:213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundh J, Janson C, Lisspers K, St&#xe4;llberg B, Montgomery S. The dyspnoea, obstruction, smoking, exacerbation (DOSE) index is predictive of mortality in COPD. Prim Care Respir J. 2012;21:295&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22786813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Liu A, Dong F, Gu F, Gama J, Zhang G. Learning under concept drift: a review. IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng. 2019;31:2346&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MI, Khan MMKS, Mannino DM. The new epidemiology of COPD. In: Wedzicha JA, Allinson JP, Calverley PMA, editors. COPD in the 21st Century (ERS monograph). Sheffield: European Respiratory Society; 2024. p. 63&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestbo J, Vogelmeier C. Guidelines and strategies of management. In: Wedzicha JAAJ, Calverley PMA, editors. COPD in the 21st Century (ERS Monograph). Sheffield: European Respiratory Society; 2024. p. 204&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackstock FC, Zuwallack R, Nici L, Lareau SC. Why don&#x2019;t our patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease listen to us? The enigma of nonadherence. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2016;13:317&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26882499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz DA, Muehlenbruch DR, Brown RL, Fiore MC, Baker TB, Group ASCGS. Effectiveness of implementing the agency for healthcare research and quality smoking cessation clinical practice guideline: a randomized, controlled trial. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2004;96:594&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7666639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15100337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpern SD, French B, Small DS, Saulsgiver K, Harhay MO, Audrain-McGovern J, et al. Randomized trial of four financial-incentive programs for smoking cessation. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:2108&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25970009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stead LF, Koilpillai P, Fanshawe TR, Lancaster T. Combined pharmacotherapy and behavioural interventions for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;3:CD008286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10042551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27009521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore MC, Ja&#xe9;n CR, Baker TB. A clinical practice guideline for treating tobacco use and dependence: 2008 update. Am J Prev Med. 2008;35:158&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18617085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>