<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792800</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tempo-specific complex training improves lower-limb strength and neuromuscular function in male collegiate soccer players: an experimental study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01631-x</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Mingqi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Enjing</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, China. giraffelej@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, 152 Luoyu Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan, 430079, China. giraffelej@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complex Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eccentric Contraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-activation Performance Enhancement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Squat Tempo</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the School of Physical Education, Central China Normal University (approval No.: CCNU-IRB-2024-008). All participants provided written informed consent prior to participation. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Written informed consent for publication of data and anonymized images was obtained from all participants. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01631-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01631-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Paul DJ, Nassis GP. Testing strength and power in soccer players: the application of conventional and traditional methods of assessment. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(6):1748&#x2013;1758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas TT, Pereira LA, Alcaraz PE, Arruda AFS, Guerriero A, Azevedo PHSM, et al. Influence of strength and power capacity on change of direction speed and deficit in elite team-sport athletes. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68:167&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Lanza MB, Folland JP. Effect of long&#x2010;term maximum strength training on explosive strength, neural, and contractile properties. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32:685&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Requena B, De S&#xe1;ez-S&#xe1;ez E, Gapeyeva H, Ereline J, Garc&#xed;a I, P&#xe4;&#xe4;suke M. Relationship between postactivation potentiation of knee extensor muscles, sprinting and vertical jumping performance in professional soccer players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2011;25:367&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygaard Falch H, Guldteig R&#xe6;derg&#xe5;rd H, Van Den Tillaar R. Effect of different physical training forms on change of direction ability: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med - Open. 2019;5:53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbadry N, Hamza A, Pietraszewski P, Alexe DI, Lupu G. Effect of the french contrast method on explosive strength and kinematic parameters of the triple jump among female college athletes. J Hum Kinet. 2019;69:225&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biel P, Ewertowska P, Stastny P, Krzysztofik M. Effects of complex training on jumping and change of direction performance, and post-activation performance enhancement response in basketball players. Sports. 2023;11:181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Smith IC, Jordan MJ, MacIntosh BR, L&#xf3;pez-Contreras G, Arellano R, et al. Nonlocalized postactivation performance enhancement (PAPE) effects in trained athletes: A pilot study. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42:1122&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Babault N. Post-activation potentiation versus post-activation performance enhancement in humans: historical perspective, underlying mechanisms, and current issues. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormier P.Complex and contrast training: Does strength and power training sequence affect performance- based adaptations in team sports? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1461&#x2013;1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portella DL, Jatene P, Da Silva AO, Dos Santos GS, Monteiro D, Teixeira JE, et al. Comparison of force variables and dynamic strength index between age groups in elite young brazilian football goalkeepers. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1282214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Mart&#xed;nez-Amat A, Hita-Contreras F, Mart&#xed;nez-L&#xf3;pez EJ, Latorre-Rom&#xe1;n PA. Effects of a contrast training program without external load on vertical jump, kicking speed, sprint, and agility of young soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2452&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagrove RC, Howatson G, Hayes PR. Use of loaded conditioning activities to potentiate middle- and long-distance performance: a narrative review and practical applications. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2288&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Makar P, Alexe DI, Stanciu S, Piwowar R, Wilk M et al. Post-activation performance enhancement: save time with active intra-complex recovery intervals. Front Physiol. 2022;13:840722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess KE, Connick MJ, Graham-Smith P, Pearson SJ. Plyometric vs. Isometric training influences on tendon properties and muscle output. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudi&#x107; D, Nosaka K. Eccentric-only versus concentric-only isokinetic strength training effects on maximal voluntary eccentric, concentric and isometric contraction strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med - Open. 2025;11:95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum D, Barbosa TM. Brief review: Effects of isometric strength training on strength and dynamic performance. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40:363&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Hughes J, Taber C, Baumert P, Suchomel TJ. The rationale and application of eccentric-based exercises in sports: Practical suggestions for its implementation. Strength Cond J. 2022:10.1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarosz J, Gawel D, Grycmann P, Aschenbrenner P, Spieszny M, Wilk M et al. How repeatable is PAPE effect: the impact of in-season isometric squat activation on countermovement jump performance enhancement in national level soccer players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17(1):115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford C, Challoumas D, Paul L, Syme G, Millar NL. Effectiveness of isometric exercise in the management of tendinopathy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised trials. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2020;6:e000760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#x17a;lenia D, Domaradzki J. Effects of post-activation protocols based on slow tempo bodyweight squat and isometric activity on vertical jump height enhancement in trained males: A randomized controlled trial. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handford MJ, Bright TE, Mundy P, Lake J, Theis N, Hughes JD. The need for eccentric speed: A narrative review of the effects of accelerated eccentric actions during resistance-based training. Sports Med. 2022;52:2061&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Eccentric exercise: physiological characteristics and acute responses. Sports Med. 2017;47:663&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart A, Vetrovsky T, Cochrane-Snyman KC, Vieira A, Tufano JJ. Investigating the consistency in countermovement jump performance after high-velocity and high-force PAPE: a multiday analysis. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2025;39(7):e843&#x2013;e853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditch JC, Kilian JR, Savage J, Davis JK. Acute potentiation on propulsive-only jump (POJ) performance following supramaximal accentuated eccentric loading in high school basketball players. International Journal of Strength and Conditioning. 2025;5(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#x17a;lenia D, Domaradzki J. Postsubmaximal isometric full squat jump potentiation in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38:459&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Sabido R, Omar-Garc&#xed;a M, Boullosa D. Why should athletes brake fast? Influence of eccentric velocity on concentric performance during countermovement jumps at different loads. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19:375&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebelo A, Pereira JR, Valente-dos-Santos J. Effects of a preseason triphasic resistance training program on athletic performance in elite volleyball players&#x2014;an observational study. Ger J Exerc Sport Res. 2023;53:163&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12662-023-00877-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Wagle JP, Douglas J, Taber CB, Harden M, Haff GG, et al. Implementing eccentric resistance training&#x2014;part 1: a brief review of existing methods. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2019;4:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Cunanan AJ, Bingham GE, Carroll KM, DeWeese BH, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading for training and performance: A review. Sports Med. 2017;47:2473&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Zajac A, Tufano JJ. The influence of movement tempo during resistance training on muscular strength and hypertrophy responses: A review. Sports Med. 2021;51:1629&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappa DF, Behm DG. Training specificity of hurdle vs. Countermovement jump training. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:2715&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibele A. Possibilities and limitations in the biomechanical analysis of countermovement jumps: A methodological study. J Appl Biomech. 1998;14:105&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JC. Using python to analyze multiple countermovement vertical jumps over time. Strength Cond J. 2024;46:369&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A simple method for measurement of mechanical power in jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1983;50:273&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Petushek EJ. Using the reactive strength index modified to evaluate plyometric performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1983&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrigna L, Amato A, Longo G, Castorina A, Pajaujiene S, Musumeci G. A standard operating procedure for the evaluation of vertical jumps performance through surface electromyography assessment: a scoping review. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2025;83:103028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10:361&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;king P, Born D-P, Sperlich B. The SpeedCourt: Reliability, usefulness, and validity of a new method to determine change-of-direction speed. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11:130&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataky TC, Vanrenterghem J, Robinson MA. The probability of false positives in zero-dimensional analyses of one-dimensional kinematic, force and EMG trajectories. J Biomech. 2016;49:1468&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Suchomel TJ, Lake JP, Comfort P. Understanding the key phases of the countermovement jump force-time curve. Strength Cond J. 2018;40:96&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffalt PC, Alkj&#xe6;r T, Simonsen EB. Intra-subject variability in muscle activity and co&#x2010;contraction during jumps and landings in children and adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27:820&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Storey AG, Nelson AR, Cronin JB. Isometric training and long-term adaptations: Effects of muscle length, intensity, and intent: a systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29:484&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Nelson AR, Lum D, Natera AO, Bittmann FN, Schaefer LV. &#x2018;pushing&#x2019; versus &#x2018;holding&#x2019; isometric muscle actions; what we know and where to go: A scoping and systematic review with meta-analyses. medRxiv 2024.11.04.24316609 [Preprint].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terbalyan A, Miko&#x142;ajec K, Krzysztofik M, Urba&#x144;ski R, Jarosz J, Stastny P, et al. Effects of overcoming isometric unilateral conditioning activity on subsequent single-leg drop jump in elite and amateur volleyball players: a randomized crossover trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17:30&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Kraemer WJ, Cormie P, Volek JS, Maresh CM, Joseph M, et al. Influence of muscle&#x2013;tendon unit structure on rate of force development during the squat, countermovement, and drop jumps. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:340&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi PV. Stretch-shortening cycle: a powerful model to study normal and fatigued muscle. J Biomech. 2000;33:1197&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Yata H, Kanehisa H, Fukunaga T. Effects of isometric squat training on the tendon stiffness and jump performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;96:305&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh U, Leicht A, Connor J, Brice S, Alves A, Doma K. Biomechanical determinants of change of direction performance: A systematic review. J Sci Med Sport. 2024;27:S3&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Young WB. Agility literature review: Classifications, training and testing. J Sports Sci. 2006;24:919&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Nimphius S, Hart NH, Specos C, Sheppard JM, Newton RU. Contribution of strength characteristics to change of direction and agility performance in female basketball athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2415&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata K, Takizawa K, Nosaka K, Mizuno M. Effects of prolonging eccentric phase duration in parallel back-squat training to momentary failure on muscle cross-sectional area, squat one repetition maximum, and performance tests in university soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:668&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gepfert M, Terbalyan A, Roczniok R, Go&#x142;as A. The effects of in-season complex contrast training on anaerobic performance metrics in elite female soccer players. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2022:10.1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio T, Marinho D, Teixeira JE, Oliveira J, Morais J. Clustering U-14 portuguese regional team football players by lower limb strength, power, dynamic balance, speed and change of direction: understanding the field position factor. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischerova P, Krosta R, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A, Terbalyan A, Nitychoruk M, Maszczyk A. Effect of power on agility, linear speed and change of direction deficit in female soccer players. Phys Act Rev. 2021;9:109&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha J, Cruz H, Teixeira JE, Vila-Ch&#xe3; C, Bartolomeu RF, Ribeiro JN, et al. Field position-related variations in body mass, postural control, and isokinetic strength in portuguese professional football. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2025;10:447&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Maio E, Afonso P, Encarna&#xe7;&#xe3;o S, Machado GF, Morgans R, et al. Mapping football tactical behavior and collective dynamics with artificial intelligence: a systematic review. Front Sports Act Living. 2025;7:1569155.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>