<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41369551</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Three Different Volumes of In-Water Warm-Up Protocols in Acute Physiologic Responses and 100 m Swimming Performance Across All Strokes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>191</StartPage><EndPage>197</EndPage><MedlinePgn>191-197</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005299</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Saini, AS, Sharma, SK, Kushwah, GS, Phukan, MI, McCabe, C, and Thapa, RK. Effects of three different volumes of in-water warm-up protocols in acute physiologic responses and 100 m swimming performance across all strokes. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): 191-197, 2026-This study examined the effects of 3 in-water warm-up (WU) protocols of varying volumes (600, 1,200, and 1,800 m) on acute physiologic responses and 100-m swimming performance across all strokes. Forty male national-level swimmers (21.0 &#xb1; 2.0 years) participated in a randomized crossover study, performing each WU protocol followed by a 100-m time trial in their respective strokes. Physiologic metrics, including blood lactate, temperature, heart rate, and rating of perceived exertion (RPE), were recorded. A repeated measures ANOVA was used to investigate the effects of the 3 protocols on physiologic and swimming performance across all the strokes. Results showed that the regular WU (1,200 m) led to significantly faster times in backstroke (65.56 &#xb1; 1.14 seconds vs 67.02 &#xb1; 1.20 seconds), breaststroke (70.73 &#xb1; 0.94 seconds vs 72.73 &#xb1; 0.94 seconds), and butterfly (58.64 &#xb1; 0.77 seconds vs 60.53 &#xb1; 0.86 seconds) than the long WU (1,800 m) ( p &lt; 0.05). For the butterfly, the short WU (600 m) also resulted in significantly better swimming performance than the long WU. No significant differences were observed in freestyle performance among the 3 WU protocols, nor were there differences in heart rate across all strokes ( p &gt; 0.05). Higher blood lactate and tympanic temperatures were observed after regular WU, while RPE was lowest after the short WU. This study emphasizes the importance of optimizing WU volumes based on stroke-specific demands in swimming. In addition, it also suggests practitioners to be cautious about using heart rate as a sole marker of WU effectiveness in swimming.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saini</LastName><ForeName>Ankur S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advance Training and Coaching, Swarnim Gujarat Sports University, Desar, India</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Sudhir K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Swarnim Gujarat Sports University, Desar, India</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kushwah</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Rashtriya Raksha University, Gandhinagar, India</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phukan</LastName><ForeName>Max I</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Science, Ulster University, Belfast, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCabe</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Science, Ulster University, Belfast, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapa</LastName><ForeName>Rohit K</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1258-9065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis School of Sports Sciences, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, India</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Swimming</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063996" MajorTopicYN="Y">Warm-Up Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="N">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001831" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Temperature</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal and neural physiologic phenomena</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water sports</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Heart rate monitoring: Applications and limitations. Sports Med 33: 517&#x2013;538, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams S, Psycharakis SG. Comparison of the effects of active, passive and mixed warm ups on swimming performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 54: 559&#x2013;565, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Nawaiseh A, Albiero A, Bishop P. Impact of different warmup procedures on a 50-yard swimming sprint. Int J Acad Res 5: 44&#x2013;48, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmussen E, B&#xf8;je O. Body temperature and capacity for work. Acta Physiol Scand 10: 1&#x2013;22, 1945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balilionis G, Nepocatych S, Ellis CM, et al. Effects of different types of warm-up on swimming performance, reaction time, and dive distance. J Strength Cond Res 26: 3297&#x2013;3303, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa TM, Fernandes R, Keskinen KL, et al. Evaluation of the energy expenditure in competitive swimming strokes. Int J Sports Med 27: 894&#x2013;899, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa TM, Marinho DA, Costa MJ, Silva AJ. Biomechanics of competitive swimming strokes. In: Biomechanics in Applications, Vol. 23. Klika V, ed. London: InTech, 2011. pp. 367&#x2013;388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. Warm up I: Potential mechanisms and the effects of passive warm up on exercise performance. Sports Med 33: 439&#x2013;454, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coen B, Schwarz L, Urhausen A, Kindermann W. Control of training in middle- and long-distance running by means of the individual anaerobic threshold. Int J Sports Med 12: 519&#x2013;524, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports 10: 155&#x2013;158, 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewe H, Tucker R, Noakes TD. The rate of increase in rating of perceived exertion predicts the duration of exercise to fatigue at a fixed power output in different environmental conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol 103: 569&#x2013;577, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Boullosa D, L&#xf3;pez-Belmonte &#xd3;, et al. Swimming warm-up and beyond: Dryland protocols and their related mechanisms-a scoping review. Sports Med Open 8: 120, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalamitros AA, Semaltianou E, Toubekis AG, Kabasakalis A. Muscle oxygenation, heart rate, and blood lactate concentration during submaximal and maximal interval swimming. Front Sports Act Living 3: 759925, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes A, Costa MJ, Mez&#xea;ncio B, Vilas-Boas JP, Fernandes RJ. Breaststroke and butterfly intercycle kinematic variation according to different competitive levels with statistical parametric mapping analysis. J Biomech 176: 112380, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonjo T, McCabe C, Coleman S, et al. Does back crawl require greater energy expenditure than front crawl at equivalent sub-anaerobic threshold speed? Reis 47: 135&#x2013;140, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonjo T, Narita K, McCabe C, et al. Front crawl is more efficient and has smaller active drag than backstroke swimming: Kinematic and kinetic comparison between the two techniques at the same swimming speeds. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 8: 570657, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin ML, Harris JE, Hern&#xe1;ndez A, Gladden LB. Blood lactate measurements and analysis during exercise: A guide for clinicians. J Diabetes Sci Technol 1: 558&#x2013;569, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellard P, Pla R, Rodr&#xed;guez FA, Simbana D, Pyne DB. Dynamics of the metabolic response during a competitive 100-m freestyle in elite male swimmers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 1011&#x2013;1020, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houmard JA, Johns RA, Smith LL, et al. The effect of warm-up on responses to intense exercise. Int J Sports Med 12: 480&#x2013;483, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilduff LP, Cunningham DJ, Owen NJ, et al. Effect of postactivation potentiation on swimming starts in international sprint swimmers. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2418&#x2013;2423, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King M, Duffield R. The effects of recovery interventions on consecutive days of intermittent sprint exercise. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1795&#x2013;1802, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann M, Foster C, Keul J. Overtraining in endurance athletes: A brief review. Med Sci Sports Exerc 25: 854&#x2013;862, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglischo EW. Warming up and swimming down. In: Swimming Fastest. Champaign: Human Kinetics, 2003. pp. 747&#x2013;752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CJ, Pyne DB, Raglin JS, Thompson KG, Rattray B. Current warm-up practices and contemporary issues faced by elite swimming coaches. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3471&#x2013;3480, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CJ, Pyne DB, Thompson KG, Rattray B. Warm-up strategies for sport and exercise: Mechanisms and applications. Sports Med 45: 1523&#x2013;1546, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CJ, Pyne DB, Thompson KG, Rattray B. Evaluating warm-up strategies for elite sprint breaststroke swimming performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 975&#x2013;978, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JB, Huston JS. The effect of high- and low-intensity warm-up on the physiological responses to a standardized swim and tethered swimming performance. J Sports Sci 11: 159&#x2013;165, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neiva HP, Marques MC, Barbosa TM, et al. Effects of 10 min vs. 20 min passive rest after warm-up on 100 m freestyle time-trial performance: A randomized crossover study. J Sci Med Sport 20: 81&#x2013;86, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neiva HP, Marques MC, Barbosa TM, et al. The effects of different warm-up volumes on the 100-m swimming performance: A randomized crossover study. J Strength Cond Res 29: 3026&#x2013;3036, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neiva HP, Marques MC, Fernandes RJ, et al. Does warm-up have a beneficial effect on 100-m freestyle? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 9: 145&#x2013;150, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol E, Pearson S, Saxby D, Minahan C, Tor E. Stroke kinematics, temporal patterns, neuromuscular activity, pacing and kinetics in elite breaststroke swimming: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 8: 75, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimah MM, Bshesh K, Callahan JD, Jacobs BR. Infrared tympanic thermometry in comparison with other temperature measurement techniques in febrile children. Pediatr Crit Care Med 7: 48&#x2013;55, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugent FJ, Comyns TM, Burrows E, Warrington GD. Effects of low-volume, high-intensity training on performance in competitive swimmers: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 31: 837&#x2013;847, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole DC, Jones AM. Oxygen uptake kinetics. Compr Physiol 2: 933&#x2013;996, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Costill DL, Fink WJ, et al. Effects of warm-up on blood gases, lactate and acid-base status during sprint swimming. Int J Sports Med 11: 273&#x2013;278, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romney NC, Nethery VM. The effects of swimming and dryland warm-ups on 100-yard freestyle performance in collegiate swimmers. J Swim Res 9: 5&#x2013;9, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skorski S, Faude O, Urhausen A, Kindermann W, Meyer T. Intensity control in swim training by means of the individual anaerobic threshold. J Strength Cond Res 26: 3304&#x2013;3311, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solli GS, Haugnes P, Kocbach J, et al. The effects of a short specific versus a long traditional warm-up on time-trial performance in cross-country skiing sprint. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 941&#x2013;948, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strza&#x142;a M, Stanula A, Kr&#x119;&#x17c;a&#x142;ek P, et al. Butterfly sprint swimming technique, analysis of somatic and spatial-temporal coordination variables. J Hum Kinet 60: 51&#x2013;62, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo W, McGuigan MR, Newton MJ. The effects of circadian rhythmicity of salivary cortisol and testosterone on maximal isometric force, maximal dynamic force, and power output. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1538&#x2013;1545, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomaras EK, MacIntosh BR. Less is more: Standard warm-up causes fatigue and less warm-up permits greater cycling power output. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111: 228&#x2013;235, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toubekis AG, Tsolaki A, Smilios I, et al. Swimming performance after passive and active recovery of various durations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 3: 375&#x2013;386, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troup J. Aerobic:anaerobic characteristics of the four competitive strokes. In: International Center for Aquatic Research Annual Colorado. Colorado: United States Swimming Press, 1991. pp. 3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DJ, Dietzig BM, Bracken RM, et al. Influence of post-warm-up recovery time on swim performance in international swimmers. J Sci Med Sport 16: 172&#x2013;176, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods K, Bishop P, Jones E. Warm-up and stretching in the prevention of muscular injury. Sports Med 37: 1089&#x2013;1099, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanci J, Iturri J, Castillo D, Pardeiro M, Nakamura FY. Influence of warm-up duration on perceived exertion and subsequent physical performance of soccer players. Biol Sport 36: 125&#x2013;131, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zochowski T, Johnson E, Sleivert GG. Effects of varying post-warm-up recovery time on 200-m time-trial swim performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2: 201&#x2013;211, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>