<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41394358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1682-024X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pakistan journal of medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pak J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prescribing patterns of antibiotics according to the WHO access, watch, and reserve (AWaRe) classification in the pediatric outpatient department: A prospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3169</StartPage><EndPage>3176</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3169-3176</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12669/pjms.41.11.12169</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) poses a significant global health threat, disproportionately affecting young children, especially in low- and middle-income countries. The World Health Organization (WHO) introduced the Access, Watch, and Reserve (AWaRe) classification system to guide responsible antibiotic prescribing. This study evaluates antibiotic prescribing patterns in pediatric outpatient departments in Pakistan using the WHO AWaRe framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A prospective, cross-sectional, multicentric study was conducted in four urban Level two teaching hospitals affiliated with Aga Khan University Hospital in Pakistan. Data was collected monthly for one year (August, 2023 - July, 2024), involving pediatric patients aged one month to twelve years. Prescriptions were categorized into AWaRe groups, with frequencies analyzed by clinical indication and patient age.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Of 1,802 pediatric encounters analyzed, antibiotics were prescribed in 529 cases (29.4%), predominantly orally (77.9%). Azithromycin (19.5%) and Amoxicillin-Clavulanic acid (19.1%) were the most commonly prescribed agents. Watch antibiotics represented 69.2% of prescriptions, significantly exceeding WHO recommendations (&#x2264;40%). Antibiotic prescription rates varied substantially by diagnosis, being highest for enteric fever (89.6%), sepsis (82.4%), and UTIs (75.0%), with notable inappropriate prescribing for viral conditions such as URTIs (33.2%), acute febrile illness (31.7%), and bronchiolitis (31%). Narrow-spectrum Access antibiotics were underutilized (29.7%), while Reserve antibiotics were rarely prescribed (1.1%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study concludes that the poor implementation of AWaRe among pediatricians in Pakistan indicates urgent need for multiple interventions. There is a dire need to improve antibiotic prescribing practices, ranging from antibiotic prescription policies, training of pediatricians in antibiotic use, AWaRe implementation, and regular monitoring in the form of clinical audits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Pakistan Journal of Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramzan</LastName><ForeName>Sobia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sobia Ramzan, (SR), FCPS - Pediatrics, MRCPCH. Senior Instructor, Department of Pediatric Medicine and Child Health, Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butt</LastName><ForeName>Afia Tariq</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Afia Tariq Butt, (ATB), FCPS - Pediatrics, MRCPCH. Senior Instructor, Department of Pediatric Medicine and Child Health, Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khowaja</LastName><ForeName>Waqar</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Waqar Khowaja, (WK), FCPS - Pediatrics, FCPS - Neonatology. Clinical Assistant Professor, Department of Pediatric Medicine and Child Health, Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghani</LastName><ForeName>Siddiqa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Siddiqa Ghani, (SG), FCPS - Pediatrics. Senior Instructor, Department of Pediatric Medicine and Child Health, Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Pakistan</Country><MedlineTA>Pak J Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100913117</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1681-715X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AWaRe classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outpatient care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric prescribing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41394358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12697030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.41.11.12169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PJMS-41-3169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antimicrobial Resistance Collaborators. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in 2019:a systematic analysis. Lancet. 2022;399(10325):629&#x2013;655. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IHME. Antimicrobial resistance (AMR)  [(last cited Feb. 06, 2025)].  Available on: https://www.healthdata.org/research-analysis/health-risks-issues/antimicrobial-resistance-amr .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laxminarayan R, Matsoso P, Pant S, Brower C, Rottingen JA, Klugman K, et al. Access to effective antimicrobials:a worldwide challenge. Lancet. 2016;387(10014):168&#x2013;175. do:10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00474-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26603918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costelloe C, Metcalfe C, Lovering A, Mant D, Hay AD. Effect of antibiotic prescribing in primary care on antimicrobial resistance in individual patients:systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2010;340:c2096. doi:10.1136/bmj.c2096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global action plan on antimicrobial resistance. 2016.  [(last cited Feb. 06, 2025)].  Available from URL: https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/193736/9789241509763_eng.pdf?sequence=1 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO model list of essential medicines for children - 8th list, 2021. World Health Organization. 2021.  
https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MHP-HPS-EML-2021.03. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. AWaRe classification of antibiotics for evaluation and monitoring of use, 2023.  [(Last visited June, 2025)].  Available on URL: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MHP-HPS-EML-2023.04 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Ferreira JP, Ullah RW, Flanagan P, Zaheer MU, Tahir MF, et al. Assessment of the implementation of Pakistan's national action plan on antimicrobial resistance in the agriculture and food sectors. Antibiotics. 2024;13(3):206. doi:10.3390/antibiotics13030206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10967498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38534641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulis G, Adam P, Nafade V, Gore G, Daniels B, Daftary A, et al. Antibiotic prescription practices in primary care in low- and middle-income countries:a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med. 2020;17(6):e1003139. doi:10.1371/journal.pmed.1003139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7297306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32544153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keren R, Shah SS, Srivastava R, Rangel S, Bendel-Stenzel M, Harik N, et al. Comparative effectiveness of intravenous vs oral antibiotics for postdischarge treatment of acute osteomyelitis in children. JAMA Pediatr. 2015;169(2):120&#x2013;128. doi:10.1001/jamapediatrics.2014.2822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25506733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir N, Mehmood BK, Awan S, Sattar S, Tajuddin S. Evaluation of hospital antibiotic prescription patterns using WHO AWaRe Classification in Karachi, Pakistan. Journal of Global Antimicrobial Resistance. 2024 Dec 1;39:29. doi:10.1016/j.jgar.2024.10.091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajjad U, Afzal N, Asif M, Rehman MB, Afridi AU, Kazmi T. Evaluation of antibiotic prescription patterns using WHO AWaRe classification. East Mediterr Health J. 2024;30(2):156&#x2013;162. doi:10.26719/emhj.24.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38491901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah S, Saleem Z, Godman B, Hashmi FK, Haseeb A, Al-Rawi MB, et al. Surge of branded generics and antimicrobial resistance:analyzing the antibiotic market dynamics in Pakistan through the WHO essential medicines and AWaRe lens. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2025;23(7):513&#x2013;521. doi:10.1080/147&#x2211;0.2025.2511958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40418538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh S, Saleem Z, Afzal S, Qamar MU, Raza AA, Haider Naqvi SZ, et al. Identifying targets for antibiotic stewardship interventions in pediatric patients in Punjab, Pakistan:point prevalence surveys using AWaRe guidance. Front Pediatr. 2025;12:1469766. doi:10.3389/fped.2024.1469766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11759272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39867700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt AT, Ramzan S, Shabbir D, Sajjad A, Shaikh M, Syed MI, et al. Prescribing patterns of antibiotics in pediatric wards of secondary care centers:a retrospective study based on WHO AWaRe classification. Glob Pediatr Health. 2024;11:2333794X241291409. doi:10.1177/2333794X241291409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11526230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39483613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CN, Huttner BD, Magrini N, Cheng Y, Tong J, Li S, et al. Pediatric antibiotic prescribing in China according to the 2019 World Health Organization access, watch, and reserve (aware) antibiotic categories. J Pediatr. 2020;220:125&#x2013;131. doi:10.1016/j.jpeds.2020.01.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein EY, Milkowska-Shibata M, Tseng KK, Sharland M, Gandra S, Pulcini C, et al. Assessment of WHO antibiotic consumption and access targets in 76 countries, 2000-15:an analysis of pharmaceutical sales data. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):107&#x2013;115. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30332-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa ZU, Salman M, Yasir M, Godman B, Majeed HA, Kanwal M, et al. Antibiotic consumption among hospitalized neonates and children in Punjab province, Pakistan. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2022;20(6):931&#x2013;939. doi:10.1080/147&#x2211;0.2021.19&#x21be;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34591720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul Mustafa Z, Khan AH, Salman M, Harun SN, Meyer JC, Godman B. Assessment of rational antibiotic use among children being treated in primary care facilities in Punjab, Pakistan:findings and implications. Drugs Ther Perspect. 2024;40(4):160&#x2013;71. doi:10.1007/s40267-024-01059-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wushouer H, Du K, Yu J, Zhang W, Hu L, Ko W, et al. Outpatient antibiotic prescribing patterns in children among primary healthcare institutions in China:a nationwide retrospective study, 2017-2019. Antibiotics. 2024;13(1):70. doi:10.3390/antibiotics13010070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10812453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38247629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Feghaly RE, Herigon JC, Kronman MP, Wattles BA, Poole NM, Smith MJ, et al. Benchmarking of outpatient pediatric antibiotic prescribing:results of a multicenter collaborative. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2023;12(6):364&#x2013;371. doi:10.1093/jpids/piad039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37262431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yehualaw A, Taferre C, Bantie AT, Demsie DG. Appropriateness and pattern of antibiotic prescription in pediatric patients at Adigart General Hospital, Tigray, Ethiopia. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021:6640892. doi:10.1155/2021/6640892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33937405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi S, Resham S, Hashmi M, Naveed AB, Haq Z, Ali SA. A retrospective review of antibiotic use in acute watery diarrhea in children in a tertiary care hospital of Karachi, Pakistan. PLoS One. 2021;16(7):e0253712. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0253712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8282082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Bian J, Han X, Zhang M, Zhan S. Outpatient antibiotic use associated with acute upper respiratory infections in China:a nationwide cross-sectional study. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;56(6):106193. doi:10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.106193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehrer BJ, Mutamba G, Thure KA, Evans CD, Hersh AL, Banerjee R, et al. Optimal pediatric outpatient antibiotic prescribing. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(10):e2437409. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.37409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11450517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39361280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul Mustafa Z, Khan AH, Salman M, Harun SN, Meyer JC, Godman B. Paediatricians'knowledge, perceptions, preparedness and involvement towards paediatric antimicrobial stewardship in Pakistan:findings and the implications. JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2024;6(6):dlae193. doi:10.1093/jacamr/dlae193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11631149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39659643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sujon H, Sarker MHR, Uddin A, Banu S, Islam MR, Amin MR, et al. Beyond the regulatory radar:knowledge and practices of rural medical practitioners in Bangladesh. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23(1):1322. doi:10.1186/s12913-023-10317-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10688090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38037022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabre V, Cosgrove SE, Lessa FC, Patel TS, Reyes-Morales G, Aleman WR, et al. Knowledge, attitudes, and perceptions of Latin American healthcare workers relating to antibiotic stewardship and antibiotic use:a cross-sectional multi-country study. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2024;13(1):47. doi:10.1186/s13756-024-01400-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11045452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38664757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>