<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41760856</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers to and facilitators of adherence to evidence-based standard antimicrobial treatment guidelines among physicians in Ethiopia: a formative qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11298</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41472-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Rational antimicrobial prescribing is critical to curb antimicrobial resistance, yet adherence to standard antimicrobial treatment guidelines remains inconsistent in Ethiopia. Understanding the barriers and facilitators influencing physicians&#x2019; adherence is essential to inform context-appropriate interventions. We conducted a formative qualitative study from April to June 2023 in 20 public hospitals across four Ethiopian regions. Using maximum variation purposive sampling, 47 physicians participated in in-depth interviews. Data were analyzed using the Theoretical Domains Framework embedded within the COM-B model, with thematic coding in MAXQDA and reporting guided by COREQ. Physicians faced multiple barriers to standard antimicrobial treatment guidelines adherence. The guidelines were often bulky, outdated, and misaligned with patient needs. Limited training, low confidence, and resistance from senior clinicians further reduced adherence. Delayed dissemination, restricted access to medicines, heavy clinical workloads, and inconsistent practices in private facilities compounded these challenges. Facilitators supporting adherence included peer collaboration, routine clinical audits, trust in locally developed guidelines, and professional motivation. Study participants recommended developing smartphone application of standard antimicrobial treatment guidelines for point-of-care access. Study participants highlighted digital solutions, such as mobile STG applications, to enhance accessibility and recommended interventions including training, digital access, audits, and policy enforcement. Adherence to standard treatment guidelines is influenced by individual, institutional, and system-level factors. Updating and digitalizing guidelines, integrating adherence into continuous professional development training, strengthening institutional support, and implementing policy measures are key strategies to improve adherence and rational antimicrobial prescription.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-41472-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boltena</LastName><ForeName>Minyahil Tadesse</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5081-1480</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Evidence Based Health Care Centre: A Joanna Briggs Institute Center of Excellence, Health Behavior and Society Department, Faculty of Public Health, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia. minyahil.tadesse@ahri.gov.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence and Digital Health Innovation Lab, Armauer Hansen Research Institute, Ministry of Health, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. minyahil.tadesse@ahri.gov.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woldie</LastName><ForeName>Mirkuzie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Policy and Management Departments, Faculty of Public Health, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fenot Project, Fenot Associates Plc, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Khatib</LastName><ForeName>Ziad</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Public Health Department, Karolinska Institute, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siraneh</LastName><ForeName>Yibeltal</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Policy and Management Departments, Faculty of Public Health, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kebede</LastName><ForeName>Abraham Sahilemichael</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lero SFI Research Centre for Software, Health Research Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tadesse</LastName><ForeName>Zelalem</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Health, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amanuel</LastName><ForeName>Wondwossen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Africa Centers for Diseases Control and Prevention (Africa CDC), Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morankar</LastName><ForeName>Sudhakar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Evidence Based Health Care Centre: A Joanna Briggs Institute Center of Excellence, Health Behavior and Society Department, Faculty of Public Health, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COM-B model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physicians&#x2019; adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rational antimicrobial prescription</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Standard treatment guidelines (STGs)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest related to this project. No funding sources influenced the design, conduct, or reporting of this research. Consent to participate: All the study procedures involving human participants were conducted in accordance with ethical standards and approved by the relevant institutional review board. Prior to participation, each study participants were informed about the nature and purpose of the study, and written consent was obtained. Study participants were assured of their right to withdraw at any time from the study. Ethical approval: This research was approved by the Institutional Ethics Review Committee of the Armauer Hansen Research Institute. The study is part of a PhD project at Jimma University, Institute of Health. Written informed consent Accepted manuscript ACCEPTED MANUSCRIPT was obtained from all participants, and confidentiality and privacy were strictly maintained.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41472-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41472-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13048980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. <i>Global antimicrobial resistance and use surveillance system (GLASS) report 2022</i> (WHO, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naghavi, M. et al. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis with forecasts to 2050. <i>Lancet</i><b>404</b>, 1199&#x2013;1226 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)01867-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11718157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39299261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulis, G., Sayood, S. &amp; Gandra, S. Antimicrobial resistance in low-and middle-income countries: current status and future directions. <i>Expert Rev. anti-infective therapy</i>. <b>20</b>, 147&#x2013;160 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14787210.2021.1951705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34225545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mzumara, G. W. et al. Protocols, policies and practices for antimicrobial stewardship in hospitalized patients in least-developed and low-income countries: a systematic review. <i>Antimicrob. Resist. Infect. Control</i>. <b>12</b>, 131 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-023-01335-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10666353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37993964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maina, M., McKnight, J., Tosas-Auguet, O., Schultsz, C. &amp; English, M. Using treatment guidelines to improve antibiotic use: insights from an antibiotic point prevalence survey in Kenya. <i>BMJ Glob Health</i> ;6. (2021). https://gh.bmj.com/content/6/1/e003836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7798408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamil, E. et al. Global variation in antibiotic prescribing guidelines and the implications for decreasing AMR in the future. <i>Front. Pharmacol.</i><b>16</b>, 1600787 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2025.1600787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12368364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40852607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tata, E. B. et al. Barriers to implementing clinical pharmacogenetics testing in Sub-Saharan Africa. A critical review. <i>Pharmaceutics</i><b>12</b>, 809 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics12090809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32858798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldu, M. A. et al. Antimicrobial resistance in Ethiopia: current landscape, challenges, and strategic interventions. <i>Discover Med.</i><b>1</b>, 68 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44337-024-00090-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arega, B. et al. Guideline recommendations for empirical antimicrobial therapy: an appraisal of research evidence for clinical decision-making in Ethiopia. <i>Infect. Dis. Therapy</i>. <b>9</b>, 451&#x2013;465 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-020-00308-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7452993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32572787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe, R. B., Ayal, B. M., Alemu, M. A. &amp; Zeleke, T. K. Antibiotic appropriateness at outpatient settings in Ethiopia: the need for an antibiotic stewardship programme. <i>Drugs in Context</i><b>13</b>, 2023-2012-2022 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11090269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eticha, E. M. et al. Adherence to guidelines for assessment and empiric antibiotics recommendations for community-acquired pneumonia at Ambo University Referral Hospital: Prospective observational study. <i>Patient preference adherence</i>, 467&#x2013;473 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7920623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33658770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmamaw, G. et al. Assessment of private health sector prescribing patterns and adherence to prescription format using World Health Organization core drug use indicators in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. <i>J. Pharm. Policy Pract.</i><b>15</b>, 11 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-022-00408-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisay, M. et al. Hospital-Level Antibacterial Prescribing and its completeness in Ethiopia: did it adhere to good prescribing practice? <i>International J. Gen. Medicine</i>, 1025&#x2013;1034 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boltena, M. T. et al. Adherence to evidence-based implementation of antimicrobial treatment guidelines among prescribers in sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>J. Pharm. Policy Pract.</i><b>16</b>, 137 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-023-00634-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10629154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37936215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demoz, G. T. et al. Prescribing pattern of antibiotics using WHO prescribing indicators among inpatients in Ethiopia: a need for antibiotic stewardship program. <i>Infection Drug Resistance</i>, 2783&#x2013;2794 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32884305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gile, P. P., Van De Klundert, J. &amp; Buljac-Samardzic, M. Human resource management in Ethiopian public hospitals. <i>BMC Health Serv. Res.</i><b>22</b>, 763 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08046-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9188153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35689209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtenay, M. et al. Examining influences on antibiotic prescribing by nurse and pharmacist prescribers: a qualitative study using the Theoretical Domains Framework and COM-B. <i>BMJ Open.</i><b>9</b>, e029177 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-029177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6588983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Types of Purposive Sampling Techniques with Their. Examples and Application in Qualitative Research Studies. <i>Br. J. Multidisciplinary Adv. Stud.</i><b>5</b>, 90&#x2013;99 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37745/bjmas.2022.0419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steeman, S. et al. Qualitative drivers of postoperative prophylactic antibiotics use and resistance in Ethiopia. <i>BMC Health Serv. Res.</i><b>24</b>, 1267 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-11650-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11495102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39434119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mather, M. et al. Barriers and facilitators to clinical behaviour change by primary care practitioners: a theory-informed systematic review of reviews using the Theoretical Domains Framework and Behaviour Change Wheel. <i>Syst. Rev.</i><b>11</b>, 180 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-022-02030-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9429279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36042457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna, R. et al. Application of the COM-B model to facilitators and barriers to HIV and STI testing among people from Black African and Black Caribbean communities in the UK: a scoping review. <i>Sex. Transm. Infect.</i><b>101</b>, 259 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/sextrans-2024-056259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12128783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39740996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leo, A. et al. Exploring the usability of the COM-B model and Theoretical Domains Framework (TDF) to define the helpers of and hindrances to evidence-based practice in midwifery. <i>Implement. Sci. Commun.</i><b>2</b>, 7 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43058-020-00100-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33436092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, E. et al. Healthcare professionals&#x2019; perspective on delivering personalised and holistic care: using the Theoretical Domains Framework. <i>BMC Health Serv. Res.</i><b>22</b>, 281 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-07630-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8887936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie, S. et al. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. <i>Implement. Sci.</i><b>6</b>, 42 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh, L. K. et al. Application of the COM-B model to barriers and facilitators to chlamydia testing in general practice for young people and primary care practitioners: a systematic review. <i>Implement. Sci.</i><b>13</b>, 130 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-018-0821-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6196559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30348165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. K. et al. The pillars of trustworthiness in qualitative research. <i>J. Med. Surg. Public. Health</i>. <b>2</b>, 100051 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.glmedi.2024.100051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmermans, S. et al. Theory construction in qualitative research: From grounded theory to abductive analysis. <i>Sociol. theory</i>. <b>30</b>, 167&#x2013;186 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0735275112457914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, A. et al. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. <i>Int. J. Qual. Health Care</i>. <b>19</b>, 349&#x2013;357 (2007).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey, K. et al. Which strategies support the effective use of clinical practice guidelines and clinical quality registry data to inform health service delivery? A systematic review. <i>Syst. Reviews</i>. <b>11</b>, 237 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-022-02104-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9644489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36352475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernooij, R. W. M. et al. Updated clinical guidelines experience major reporting limitations. <i>Implement. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 120 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-017-0651-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5639761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29025429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orangi, S. et al. Understanding factors influencing the use of clinical guidelines in low-income and middle-income settings: a scoping review. <i>BMJ open.</i><b>13</b>, e070399 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-070399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10314507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37344115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingemansson, M. et al. Practice guidelines in the context of primary care, learning and usability in the physicians&#x2019; decision-making process&#x2013;a qualitative study. <i>BMC Fam. Pract.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2296-15-141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25143046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worku, T. et al. Evidence-based medicine among physicians working in selected public hospitals in eastern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. <i>BMC Med. Inf. Decis. Mak.</i><b>19</b>, 107 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-019-0826-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. et al. Barriers and enablers to implementing clinical practice guidelines in primary care: an overview of systematic reviews. <i>BMJ Open.</i><b>13</b>, e062158 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-062158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9827241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36609329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katende-Kyenda, L. N. et al. Non-Adherence to Treatment Among Patients Attending a Public Primary Healthcare Setting in South Africa: Prevalence and Associated Factors. <i>Int J. Environ. Res. Public. Health</i><b>22</b> (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12652721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41302611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obakiro, S. B. et al. Are antibiotic prescription practices in Eastern Uganda concordant with the national standard treatment guidelines? A cross-sectional retrospective study. <i>J. Glob Antimicrob. Resist.</i><b>29</b>, 513&#x2013;519 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgar.2021.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitaka, J. et al. Combating antibiotic resistance using guidelines and enhanced stewardship in Kenya: a protocol for an implementation science approach. <i>BMJ Open.</i><b>10</b>, e030823 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-030823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7170570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mung&#x2019;ong&#x2019;o, G. S. et al., <i>Adherence to National Standard Treatment Guidelines in the Management of Hypertension and Associated Factors Among Healthcare Providers at Public District Hospitals in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. medRxiv, 2025.2012.2029.25343177</i> (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djochie, R. D. A. et al. Adherence to WHO/INRUD prescription indicators in public hospitals: evidence from the Ashanti Region, Ghana. <i>Ther. Adv. Drug Saf.</i><b>16</b>, 20420986251346321 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20420986251346321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12146595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40491668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baykemagn, N. D. et al. Acceptance of mobile application-based clinical guidelines among health professionals in Northwestern Ethiopia: A mixed-methods study. <i>Digit. Health</i>. <b>10</b>, 20552076241261930 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076241261930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11369868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39229466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adejumo, O. et al. Facilitators and barriers to use of clinical practice guidelines among physicians in Nigeria: a cross-sectional study. <i>BMJ Open.</i><b>15</b>, e089535 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-089535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11873348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40021197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiffer-Smadja, N. et al. Implementation of a Clinical Decision Support System for Antimicrobial Prescribing in Sub-Saharan Africa: Multisectoral Qualitative Study. <i>J. Med. Internet Res.</i><b>26</b>, e45122 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/45122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11494254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39374065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyomugabo, A. et al. Exploring facilitators and barriers to healthcare professionals&#x2019; use of clinical guidelines to prevent surgical site infection in Rwandan hospitals. <i>Int. J. Afr. Nurs. Sci.</i><b>21</b>, 100792 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, S. et al. Closing the quality gap from awareness to adoption of standard treatment guidelines in clinical practice in India. <i>Discover Health Syst.</i><b>4</b>, 54 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44250-025-00231-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>