<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41102810</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1466-609X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Critical care (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Crit Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance training and &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate for functional recovery in critical illness: a multicenter 2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;2 factorial randomized trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>438</StartPage><MedlinePgn>438</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">438</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13054-025-05660-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Combined nutrition and rehabilitation is a top research priority for ICU-acquired weakness, yet the optimal strategy and clinical benefits remain unclear. This study aimed to evaluate the independent and combined effects of resistance training (RT) and &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) in critically ill adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a multicenter, open-label, 2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;2 factorial randomized controlled trial with blinded outcome assessment in 266 adult ICU patients. Participants were randomized to receive RT, HMB supplementation, combined interventions, or standard care. Treatments began in the ICU and continued until discharge. Primary outcomes at discharge included six-minute walk distance (6MWD) and the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB). Secondary outcomes included muscle strength and mass, patient-reported outcomes, and mortality at 1, 6, and 12 months. Analyses followed the intention-to-treat principle, using linear mixed-effects models to estimate the independent and interactive effects of RT and HMB.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">RT significantly improved physical function at discharge, with higher SPPB scores (mean difference:1.32 points; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003) and longer 6MWD (56.20&#xa0;m; <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), compared with patients who did not receive RT. It was associated with lower 6-month (OR, 0.51; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.011) and 12-month mortality (OR, 0.55; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.014), and increased grip strength (3.19&#xa0;kg; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.008), appendicular skeletal muscle mass (0.997&#xa0;kg; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005), and skeletal muscle index (0.428&#xa0;kg/m&#xb2;; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.025). RT reduced fatigue and improved sleep quality and psychological symptoms (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), but had no effect on cognition or overall quality of life. HMB modestly increased phase angle (0.367; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.020) and reduced fatigue (&#x2013;1.069 points, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005), but had no effect on other outcomes; hyperglycemia occurred in 3 of 134 patients receiving HMB. No interaction between RT and HMB was detected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This expanded trial provides novel evidence that RT not only improves physical function but also increases muscle mass, enhances patient-reported outcomes, and lowers 6- and 12-month mortality in critically ill patients. HMB supplementation offered only modest effects on phase angle and fatigue, with no synergistic benefit when combined with RT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">ChiCTR2200057685 (https://www.chictr.org.cn/) was registered on March 15th, 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13054-025-05660-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Tingting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350005, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the FirstAffliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350212, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Intensive Care Unit, the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350005, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Yueqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Intensive Care Unit, Fuzhou University Affiliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350028, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Second Affiliated Hospital of Fujian Medical University, Quanzhou, 362000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jingbing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Intensive Care Unit, Fuzhou University Affiliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xiuxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Intensive Care Unit, Fuzhou University Affiliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Yaoning</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory and Intensive Care Unit, Putan College Affiliated Hospital, Putian, 351106, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Chenjuan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Nanping City First Hospital, Nanping, 353000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Meilian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Longyan City First Hospital, Longyan, 364000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xuexian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Ningde Normal University Affiliated Ningde City Hospital, Ningde, 352100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Zhizhong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, No. 420 Fuma Road, Fuzhou, 350014, Fujian, China. linzhizhong2012@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Fujian Medical University, No.1 Xuefu North Road, Minhou County, Fuzhou, 350122, Fujian, China. leehong99@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023Y9326</GrantID><Agency>the Innovation of Science and Technology, Fujian Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YJRC4219</GrantID><Agency>the Talent Recruitment Scientific Research Project at the First Affiliated Hospital of Fujian Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZHKYQ202222</GrantID><Agency>the Research Projects of the Chinese Nursing Association</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Crit Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9801902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1364-8535</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ICU-acquired weakness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive care unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Prior to enrollment, all participants received a detailed explanation of the study&#x2019;s purpose, procedures, and content, and provided written informed consent. Participant confidentiality was strictly maintained throughout. Ethical approval was obtained from the Ethics Committee of Fujian Provincial Hospital (Approval No. K2021-04-004). Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41102810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12532832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-025-05660-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13054-025-05660-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hurley JC. Trends in ICU mortality and underlying risk over three decades among mechanically ventilated patients. A group level analysis of cohorts from infection prevention studies. Ann Intensive Care. 2023;13:62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13613-023-01159-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herridge MS, Azoulay &#xc9;. Outcomes after critical illness. N Engl J Med. 2023;388:913&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra2104669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36884324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramnarain D, Aupers E, den Oudsten B, Oldenbeuving A, de Vries J, Pouwels S. Post intensive care syndrome (PICS): an overview of the definition, etiology, risk factors, and possible counseling and treatment strategies. Expert Rev Neurother. 2021;21:1159&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2021.1981289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierre A, Favory R, Bourel C, Howsam M, Romien R, Lancel S, et al. Muscle weakness after critical illness: unravelling biological mechanisms and clinical hurdles. Crit Care. 2025;29:248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-025-05462-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12175454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40528196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazzini B, M&#xe4;rkl T, Costas C, Blobner M, Schaller SJ, Prowle J, et al. The rate and assessment of muscle wasting during critical illness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2023;27:2&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-022-04253-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9808763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36597123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiser SL, Casey K, Nydahl P, Hodgson CL, Needham DM. Intensive care unit acquired weakness and physical rehabilitation in the ICU. BMJ. 2025;388:e077292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-077292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39870417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Aerde N, Meersseman P, Debaveye Y, Wilmer A, Gunst J, Casaer MP, et al. Five-year outcome of respiratory muscle weakness at intensive care unit discharge: secondary analysis of a prospective cohort study. Thorax. 2021;76:561&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33712505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latronico N, Herridge M, Hopkins RO, Angus D, Hart N, Hermans G, et al. The ICM research agenda on intensive care unit-acquired weakness. Intensive Care Med. 2017;43:1270&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-017-4757-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formenti P, Menozzi A, Sabbatini G, Gotti M, Galimberti A, Bruno G, et al. Combined effects of early mobilization and nutrition on ICU-acquired weakness. Nutrients. 2025;17:1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17061073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11945635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40292494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabheru R, Langan A, Merriweather J, Connolly B, Whelan K, Bear DE. Reporting of nutritional screening, status, and intake in trials of nutritional and physical rehabilitation following critical illness: a systematic review. Am J Clin Nutr. 2025;121:703&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajcnut.2024.12.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11923378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39746396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyland DK, Patel J, Compher C, Rice TW, Bear DE, Lee Z-Y, et al. The effect of higher protein dosing in critically ill patients with high nutritional risk (EFFORT protein): an international, multicentre, pragmatic, registry-based randomised trial. Lancet. 2023;401:568&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)02469-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano H, Naraba H, Hashimoto H, Mochizuki M, Takahashi Y, Sonoo T, et al. Novel protocol combining physical and nutrition therapies, intensive goal-directed rehabilitation with electrical muscle stimulation and nutrition (IGREEN) care bundle. Crit Care. 2021;25:415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-021-03827-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34863251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wappel S, Tran DH, Wells CL, Verceles AC. The effect of high protein and mobility-based rehabilitation on clinical outcomes in survivors of critical illness. Respir Care. 2021;66:73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.07840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathmacher JA, Pitchford LM, Stout JR, Townsend JR, J&#xe4;ger R, Kreider RB, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB). J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2025;22:2434734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2434734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11740297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39699070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bear DE, Langan A, Dimidi E, Wandrag L, Harridge SDR, Hart N, et al. beta-Hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate and its impact on skeletal muscle mass and physical function in clinical practice: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2019;109:1119&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqy373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30982854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bideshki MV, Behzadi M, Jamali M, Jamilian P, Zarezadeh M, Gargari BP. Ergogenic benefits of &#x3b2;-hydroxy&#x2010;&#x3b2;&#x2010;methyl butyrate (HMB) supplementation on body composition and muscle strength: an umbrella review of meta&#x2010;analyses. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2025;16:e13671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11724150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Song Y, Li T, Chen X, Zhou J, Pan Q, et al. Effects of Beta-Hydroxy-Beta-Methylbutyrate supplementation on older adults with sarcopenia: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. J Nutr Health Aging. 2023;27:329&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12603-023-1911-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Gao Y-B, Yu D-X, Huang H-B. Beta-hydroxy-beta-methyl butyrate supplementation in critically ill patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Nutr. 2025;12:1505797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1505797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11798817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39917745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Rech A, Molinari T, Markarian AM, Petropoulou M, Granacher U, et al. Effects of resistance training volume on physical function, lean body mass and lower-body muscle hypertrophy and strength in older adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 151 randomised trials. Sports Med. 2025;55:167&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02123-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39405023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YT, Lang JK, Haines KJ, Skinner EH, Haines TP. Physical rehabilitation in the ICU: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care Med. 2022;50(3):375&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000005285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris PE, Berry MJ, Files DC, Thompson JC, Hauser J, Flores L, et al. Standardized rehabilitation and hospital length of stay among patients with acute respiratory failure: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2016;315:2694&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.7201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27367766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu T-T. Resistance training combined with &#x3b2;-hydroxy &#x3b2;-methylbutyrate for patients with critical illness: a four-arm, mixed-methods, feasibility randomised controlled trial. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2024;82:103616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iccn.2023.103616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38246040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu T-T, Chen Q-L, Lin X-X, Xu M-L, Chen X-X, Luo C-J, et al. Effects of a multilevel intervention of resistance training with or without beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate in critical illness patients during entire hospitalisation: a four-arm multicentre randomised controlled trial. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-023-04698-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10724983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38102705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jonghe B, Sharshar T, Lefaucheur JP, Authier FJ, Durand-Zaleski I, Boussarsar M, et al. Paresis acquired in the intensive care unit: a prospective multicenter study. JAMA. 2002;288:2859&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.288.22.2859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12472328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor BE, McClave SA, Martindale RG, Warren MM, Johnson DR, Braunschweig C, et al. Guidelines for the provision and assessment of nutrition support therapy in the adult critically ill patient: society of critical care medicine (SCCM) and American society for parenteral and enteral nutrition (A.S.P.E.N). Crit Care Med. 2016;44:390&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000001525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26771786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, et al. A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol. 1994;49:M85&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geronj/49.2.M85</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8126356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland AE, Spruit MA, Troosters T, Puhan MA, Pepin V, Saey D, et al. An official European Respiratory Society/American Thoracic Society technical standard: field walking tests in chronic respiratory disease. Eur Respir J. 2014;44:1428&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00150314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Pee G, Hermans G, Segers J, Gosselink R. Assessment of limb muscle strength in critically ill patients: a systematic review. Crit Care Med. 2014;42:701&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000000030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24201180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali NA, O&#x2019;Brien JM, Hoffmann SP, Phillips G, Garland A, Finley JC, et al. Acquired weakness, handgrip strength, and mortality in critically ill patients. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2008;178:261&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200712-1829OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18511703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalder T, Berelowitz G, Pawlikowska T, Watts L, Wessely S, Wright D, et al. Development of a fatigue scale. J Psychosom Res. 1993;37:147&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3999(93)90081-P</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8463991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28:193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein MF, Folstein SE, McHugh PR. Mini-mental state. A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. J Psychiatr Res. 1975;12:189&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3956(75)90026-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67:361&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0447.1983.tb09716.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christianson S, Marren J. The impact of event scale-revised (IES-R). Medsurg Nurs. 2012;21:321&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). i. Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care. 1992;30:473&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-199206000-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ely EW, Margolin R, Francis J, May L, Truman B, Dittus R, et al. Evaluation of delirium in critically ill patients: validation of the confusion assessment method for the intensive care unit (CAM-ICU). Crit Care Med. 2001;29:1370&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003246-200107000-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Fitschen PJ, Campbell B, Wilson GJ, Zanchi N, Taylor L, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB). J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23374455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Stob&#xe4;us N, Pirlich M, Bosy-Westphal A. Bioelectrical phase angle and impedance vector analysis&#x2013;clinical relevance and applicability of impedance parameters. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:854&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2012.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22698802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira JP, da Rebou&#xe7;as C, de Prado A, Gonzalez CM, Cabral MC, Diniz PC da. Phase angle as a marker of muscle quality: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nutr. 2024;43:308&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39549478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa GB, Lukaski HC, Sardinha LB. The science of bioelectrical impedance-derived phase angle: insights from body composition in youth. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2025;26(4):603&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11154-025-09964-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12316808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40208410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima J, Eckert I, Gonzalez MC, Silva FM. Prognostic value of phase angle and bioelectrical impedance vector in critically ill patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Clin Nutr. 2022;41:2801&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2022.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36395589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana MV, Becce F, Pantet O, Schmidt S, Bagnoud G, Thaden JJ, et al. Impact of &#x3b2; &#x2013;&#x2009;hydroxy-&#x3b2; &#x2013;&#x2009;methylbutyrate (HMB) on muscle loss and protein metabolism in critically ill patients: a RCT. Clin Nutr. 2021;40(8):4878&#x2013;87. 10.1016/j.clnu.2021.07.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonamine CY, Teixeira SS, Campello RS, Gerlinger-Romero F, Rodrigues CF, Guimar&#xe3;es-Ferreira L, et al. Beta hydroxy beta methylbutyrate supplementation impairs peripheral insulin sensitivity in healthy sedentary Wistar rats. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2014;212:62&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24962220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan B, Sharples AP. Molecular responses to acute exercise and their relevance for adaptations in skeletal muscle to exercise training. Physiol Rev. 2023;103:2057&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00054.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36395350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fossat G, Baudin F, Courtes L, Bobet S, Dupont A, Bretagnol A, et al. Effect of in-bed leg cycling and electrical stimulation of the quadriceps on global muscle strength in critically ill adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2018;320:368&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.9592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Spiegl M, Altmann K, Winkler A, Salamon A, Themessl-Huber M, et al. Muscle mass, strength and functional outcomes in critically ill patients after cardiothoracic surgery: does neuromuscular electrical stimulation help? the catastim 2 randomized controlled trial. Crit Care. 2016;20:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-016-1199-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaller SJ, Scheffenbichler FT, Bein T, Blobner M, Grunow JJ, Hamsen U, et al. Guideline on positioning and early mobilisation in the critically ill by an expert panel. Intensive Care Med. 2024;50:1211&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-024-07532-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39073582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The TEAM Study Investigators and the ANZICS Clinical Trials Group. Early active mobilization during mechanical ventilation in the ICU. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:1747&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2209083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36286256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>