<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41712497</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1421-9751</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Design and Rationale of the EARMI Trial: A Randomized Controlled Trial on Early-Phase Cardiac Rehabilitation Post-Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Acute Myocardial Infarction Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>9</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000551060</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cardiac rehabilitation (CR) is a key component of secondary prevention in patients with coronary artery disease. However, the optimal timing, structure, and feasibility of exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation initiated during hospitalization following acute myocardial infarction (AMI) treated with percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) remain underexplored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The EARMI trial is a multicenter, randomized, parallel-group controlled trial designed to assess the efficacy and safety of a structured, phase-specific CR program initiated within 24 h post-PCI. This intervention will be implemented across three distinct recovery phases: intensive care unit, hospital ward, and home-based rehabilitation. Eighty AMI patients will be randomized (1:1) to receive exercise-based CR or usual care. The intervention consists of progressive aerobic and resistance training, with individualized progression tailored to each patient's clinical status. The primary outcomes include left ventricular function (measured by left ventricular ejection fraction, LVEDD, LVESD), exercise capacity (assessed by VO<sub>2</sub> peak, 6MWT, and METs), and autonomic function (evaluated by heart rate variability [HRV]). Secondary outcomes include health-related quality of life (assessed by SF-36), metabolic markers, and major adverse cardiovascular events. Over the 12 weeks intervention period, the study is powered to detect clinically significant improvements in myocardial function, exercise tolerance, and autonomic regulation. Safety and feasibility will be assessed through continuous surveillance of adverse events and quantification of adherence rates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The EARMI trial is one of the first studies to evaluate the impact of initiating a structured early-phase CR model during the acute phase of AMI. The findings may provide crucial insights into scalable, time-sensitive rehabilitation strategies for post-AMI recovery and contribute to the integration of CR into modern cardiovascular care pathways.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cen</LastName><ForeName>Kaiyuan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Department, Guidong People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Wuzhou, China, cky163163@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia, cky163163@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Department, The Affiliated Guidong Hospital of Guilin Medical University, Wuzhou, China, cky163163@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmedy</LastName><ForeName>Fatimah</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia, fatimahmedy@ums.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sabah Rehabilitation Research and Service Group, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia, fatimahmedy@ums.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcus</LastName><ForeName>Mexmollen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shukor</LastName><ForeName>Mohd Fadzli</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darsin Singh</LastName><ForeName>Sukhbeer Kaur</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, UMS, Kota Kinabalu, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1266406</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0008-6312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41712497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000551060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000551060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>