<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41628118</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of human training data (HTD) explanation on purchase intention for artificial intelligence (AI) technologies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0339482</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0339482</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0339482</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0339482</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Consumers exhibit resistance to Artificial Intelligence (AI) technologies despite their widespread deployment. One common thread linking various reasons for this is the perceptions of AI technologies' lack of inherent human qualities. This paper explores the effect of human training data (HTD) explanation on purchase intention for AI technologies as a potential source-based explainable AI (XAI) solution to this problem. We define HTD explanation as a statement that describes the role that humans play within a given AI system's training data in lay terms that is easy to understand for end-users. This includes descriptions of what human data is used and for what purpose (e.g., "Our ready-made meals are developed by an AI system trained on millions of people's food and taste preferences"). We predict HTD explanation to have a positive effect on consumer purchase intention that is mediated by perceived transfer of human essence. We tested our hypotheses in four between-subjects experiments. Study 1 supports the proposed main effect. Studies 2 and 3 show evidence for the mediation mechanism. Study 4 provides marginal evidence that HTD explanation may reduce adoption intention among consumers high pre-existing trust in AI technologies. Our findings suggest that the psychological processes linking HTD explanation to consumer outcomes may be more complex than originally theorized. This study introduces HTD as a form of source-based XAI solution and offers preliminary insight into PET and deep humanization effects, where consumers may perceive AI technologies to possess human qualities by virtue of HTD use.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Dharmaputri et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dharmaputri</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie Kwari</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-8648-1796</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Management and Marketing, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nyilasy</LastName><ForeName>Greg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5222-1636</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Management and Marketing, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagpal</LastName><ForeName>Anish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3950-4364</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Management and Marketing, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Management and Marketing, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D033182" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003258" MajorTopicYN="Y">Consumer Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41628118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12863500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0339482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-15023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Puntoni S, Reczek RW, Giesler M, Botti S. Consumers and artificial intelligence: an experiential perspective. J Mark. 2021;85(1):131&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan R, Shams R, Rahman M. Consumer trust and perceived risk for voice-controlled artificial intelligence: the case of Siri. J Bus Res. 2021;131:591&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantano E, Scarpi D. I robot, you, consumer: Measuring artificial intelligence types and their effect on consumers emotions in service. J Serv Res. 2022;25(4):583&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriuchi E. An empirical study on anthropomorphism and engagement with disembodied AIs and consumers&#x2019; re&#x2010;use behavior. Psychol Mark. 2021;38(1):21&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blut M, Wang C, W&#xfc;nderlich NV, Brock C. Understanding anthropomorphism in service provision: a meta-analysis of physical robots, chatbots, and other AI. J Acad Mark Sci: Off Public Acad Mark Sci. 2021;49(4):632&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitardi V, Marriott HR. Alexa, she&#x2019;s not human but&#x2026; unveiling the drivers of consumers&#x2019; trust in voice-based artificial intelligence. Psychol Mark. 2021;38(4):626&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neon. Introducing Neon, a new kind of life [Internet]. 2020. Available from: https://www.neon.life/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Sung Y. Anthropomorphism brings us closer: the mediating role of psychological distance in User&#x2013;AI assistant interactions. Comput Hum Behav. 2021;118:106680. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2021.106680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2021.106680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Im I. Anthropomorphic response: understanding interactions between humans and artificial intelligence agents. Comput Hum Behav. 2023;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waytz A, Heafner J, Epley N. The mind in the machine: anthropomorphism increases trust in an autonomous vehicle. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2014;52:113&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roesler E, Manzey D, Onnasch L. A meta-analysis on the effectiveness of anthropomorphism in human-robot interaction. Sci Robot. 2021;6(58).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34516745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi OH, Jia S, Li Y, Gursoy D. Developing a formative scale to measure consumers&#x2019; trust toward interaction with artificially intelligent (AI) social robots in service delivery. Comput Hum Behav. 2021;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelo N, Bos MW, Lehmann DR. Task-dependent algorithm aversion. J Mark Res. 2019;56(5):809&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longoni C, Bonezzi A, Morewedge CK. Resistance to medical artificial intelligence. J Consum Res. 2019;46(4):629&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1093/jcr/ucz013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jcr/ucz013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drenik G. How AI Is Revolutionizing Customer Service with Human-Like Responses [Internet]. Forbes. 2023. Available from: https://www.forbes.com/sites/garydrenik/2023/12/06/how-ai-is-revolutionizing-customer-service-with-human-like-responses/?sh=4d1b09255b02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juravle G, Boudouraki A, Terziyska M, Rezlescu C. Trust in artificial intelligence for medical diagnoses. Progress Brain Res. 2020;253:263&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longoni C, Cian L. Artificial intelligence in utilitarian vs. hedonic contexts: The &#x201c;word-of-machine&#x201d; effect. J Mark. 2022;86(1):91&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Freitas J, Agarwal S, Schmitt B, Haslam N. Psychological factors underlying attitudes toward AI tools. Nat Hum Behav. 2023;7(11):1845&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37985913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerlings J, Shollo A, Constantiou I. Reviewing the need for explainable artificial intelligence (xAI). 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt B. Speciesism: an obstacle to AI and robot adoption. Mark Lett. 2020;31(1):3&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslam N. Dehumanization: an integrative review. Pers Soc Psychol Rev. 2006;10(3):252&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1207/s15327957pspr1003_4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15327957pspr1003_4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16859440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canhoto AI, Clear F. Artificial intelligence and machine learning as business tools: a framework for diagnosing value destruction potential. Bus Horizons. 2020;63(2):183&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koren G, Souroujon D, Shaul R, Bloch A, Leventhal A, Lockett J, et al. &#x201c;A patient like me&#x201d; - An algorithm-based program to inform patients on the likely conditions people with symptoms like theirs have. Medicine (Baltimore). 2019;98(42):e17596. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000017596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000017596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6824689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyholm S, Smids J. Automated cars meet human drivers: responsible human-robot coordination and the ethics of mixed traffic. Ethics Inf Technol. 2020;22(4):335&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai A. Explainable AI: from black box to glass box. J Acad Mark Sci: Off Public Acad Mark Sci. 2020;48(1):137&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Cao CC, Shi Y, Bai W, Gao H, Qiu L. A survey of data-driven and knowledge-aware explainable AI. IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng. 2022;34(1):29&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed W, Omlin C. Explainable AI (XAI): A systematic meta-survey of current challenges and future opportunities. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrardi L, Cambini C, Rondi L. Artificial intelligence, firms and consumer behavior: A survey. J Econ Surv. 2022;36(4):969&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacker P. A legal framework for AI training data&#x2014;from first principles to the Artificial Intelligence Act. Law Innov Technol. 2021;13(2):257&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musib M, Wang F, Tarselli MA, Yoho R, Yu KH, Andr&#xe9;s RM, et al. Artificial intelligence in research. Science. 2017;357(6346):28&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28684488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameen N, Tarhini A, Reppel A, Anand A. Customer experiences in the age of artificial intelligence. Comput Human Behav. 2021;114:106548. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2020.106548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2020.106548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32905175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport T, Guha A, Grewal D, Bressgott T. How artificial intelligence will change the future of marketing. J Acad Mark Sci. 2020;48(1):24&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmuganathan M. Behavioural finance in an era of artificial intelligence: Longitudinal case study of robo-advisors in investment decisions. J Behav Exp Fin. 2020;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrett R, Mascagni P, Beldi G, Padoy N, Lavanchy JL. Technical skill assessment in minimally invasive surgery using artificial intelligence: a systematic review. Surg Endosc: Other Interven Tech. 2023;37(10):7412&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10520175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37584774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivas-Blanco I, Perez-Del-Pulgar CJ, Garcia-Morales I, Munoz VF. A review on deep learning in minimally invasive surgery. IEEE Access. 2021;9:48658&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marr B. The amazing ways Coca-Cola uses generative AI in art and advertising. Forbes. 2023. Available from: https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2023/09/08/the-amazing-ways-coca-cola-uses-generative-ai-in-art-and-advertising/?sh=46738dd42874</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovland CI, Rosenberg MJ. Cognitive, affective, and behavioral components of attitudes. In: Hovland CI, Rosenberg MJ, editors. Attitude organization and change: An analysis of consistency among attitude components. New Haven (CT): Yale University Press. 1960. pp. 1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzagalli DA. A new chapter for cognitive, affective &amp; behavioral neuroscience. Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci. 2021;21(2):267&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3758/s13415-021-00867-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/s13415-021-00867-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33594644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenck MW. Fundamentals of cognition. New York: Psychology Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberg RJ, Sternberg K. Cognitive psychology. 6th ed. Belmont (CA): Wadsworth Cengage Learning; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogg MA, Abrams D, Martin GN. Social cognition and attitudes. In: Martin GN, Carlson NR, Buskist W, editors. Psychology. Harlow (UK): Pearson Education Limited; 2010. pp. 646&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieters R, van Raaij WF. Functions and management of affect: applications to economic behavior. J Econ Psychol. 1988;9(2):251&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman D. How AI is making sentiment analysis easy [Internet]. Forbes. 2019. Available from: https://www.forbes.com/sites/danielnewman/2019/11/22/how-ai-is-making-sentiment-analysis-easy/?sh=61c16e5e2991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mende M, Scott ML, van Doorn J, Grewal D, Shanks I. Service robots rising: how humanoid robots influence service experiences and elicit compensatory consumer responses. J Mark Res. 2019;56(4):535&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1177/0022243718822827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0022243718822827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conick H. The past, present, and future of AI in marketing. Marketing News. 2017;51(1):26&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortony A, Norman DA, Revelle W. Effective functioning: A three-level model of affect, motivation, cognition, and behavior. In: Fellous J, Arbib M, editors. Who needs emotions? The brain meets the machine. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2005. pp. 173&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajita S, Hirukawa H, Harada K, Yokoi K. Introduction to humanoid robotics. Berlin: Springer Verlag; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo E, Bo JW, Cheong A, Lau MWS, Hedley J. Development of a robotic waiter system. IFAC-PapersOnLine. 2016;49(21).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker L. Sick of house chores? Robot maids could soon be reality [Internet]. The Brussels Times. 2022. Available from: https://www.brusselstimes.com/228766/sick-of-house-chores-robot-maids-could-soon-be-reality</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers M. Emotion AI, explained. MIT Management Sloan School. 2019. Available from: https://mitsloan.mit.edu/ideas-made-to-matter/emotion-ai-explained</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozin P, Nemeroff C, Wane M, Sherrod A. Operation of the sympathetic magical law of contagion in interpersonal attitudes among Americans. Bull Psychon Soc. 1989;27(4):367&#x2013;70. doi: 10.3758/bf03334630</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03334630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemeroff C, Rozin P. Back in touch with contagion: some essential issues. J Assoc Consum Res. 2018;3(4):612&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1086/699971</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/699971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemeroff C, Rozin P. The contagion concept in adult thinking in the United States: transmission of germs and of interpersonal influence. Ethos. 1994;22(2):158&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman GE, Diesendruck G, Bloom P. Celebrity contagion and the value of objects. J Consum Res. 2011;38(2):215&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1086/658999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/658999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskine KJ, Novreske A, Richards M. Moral contagion effects in everyday interpersonal encounters. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2013;49(5):947&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.jesp.2013.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesp.2013.04.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contenta S, Zerbisias A. Military burns Russell Williams&#x2019;s uniform. Toronto Star. 2010. Available from: http://www.thestar.com/news/gta/article/893392-{}-military-burns-russell-williams-s-uniform</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argo JJ, Dahl DW, Morales AC. Positive consumer contagion: responses to attractive others in a retail context. J Mark Res. 2008;45(6):690&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman GE, Bloom P. Physical contact influences how much people pay at celebrity auctions. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111(10):3705&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1313637111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1313637111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3956169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24567388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman GE, Bloom P. Art and authenticity: the importance of originals in judgments of value. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2012;141(3):558&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1037/a0026035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0026035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22082113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang JY, Ackerman JM, Newman GE. Catching (up with) magical contagion: a review of contagion effects in consumer contexts. J Assoc Consum Res. 2017;2(4):430&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1086/693533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/693533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemeroff C, Rozin P. The makings of the magical mind. In: Rosengren KS, Johnson CN, Harris PL, editors. Imagining the impossible: Magical, scientific, and religious thinking in children. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2000. pp. 1&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordell VV, Wongtada N, Kieschnick RLJ. Counterfeit purchase intentions: role of lawfulness attitudes and product traits as determinants. J Bus Res. 1996;35(1):41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aron A, Aron EN, Smollan D. Inclusion of Other in the Self Scale and the structure of interpersonal closeness. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1992;63(4):596&#x2013;612. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.63.4.596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.63.4.596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AF. Introduction to mediation, moderation, and conditional process analysis: A regression-based approach. 3rd ed. New York: The Guilford Press; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Zomeren M, Fischer AH, Spears R. Testing the limits of tolerance: how intergroup anxiety amplifies negative and offensive responses to out-group-initiated contact. Pers Soc Psychol Bull. 2007;33(12):1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18000103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cugurullo F, Acheampong RA. Fear of AI: an inquiry into the adoption of autonomous cars in spite of fear, and a theoretical framework for the study of artificial intelligence technology acceptance. AI Soc. 2023;39(4):1569&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1007/s00146-022-01598-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00146-022-01598-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo W, Zheng G, Yan J, Sun L, Han L. Interacting with medical artificial intelligence: Integrating self-responsibility attribution, human&#x2013;computer trust, and personality. Comput Hum Behav. 2022;132:107253. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2022.107253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2022.107253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillath O, Ai T, Branicky MS, Keshmiri S, Davison RB, Spaulding R. Attachment and trust in artificial intelligence. Comput Hum Behav. 2021;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadis S, Kyrezis N. Linking trust to use intention for technology-enabled bank channels: The role of trusting intentions. Psychol Mark. 2010;27(8):799&#x2013;820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi OH, Chi CG, Gursoy D, Nunkoo R. Customers&#x2019; acceptance of artificially intelligent service robots: The influence of trust and culture. Int J Inf Manag. 2023;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz D, Rucker DD. When in doubt, shout! The paradoxical impact of confidence and knowledge on resistance to persuasion. J Consum Res. 2022;49(1):96&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt P, Biessmann F, Teubner T. Transparency and trust in artificial intelligence systems. J Decision Syst. 2020;29(4):260&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1080/12460125.2020.1819094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/12460125.2020.1819094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh V, Thong JYL, Xu X. Consumer acceptance and use of information technology: extending the unified theory of acceptance and use of technology. MIS Q. 2012;36(1):157&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirdeshmukh D, Singh J, Sabol B. Consumer trust, value, and loyalty in relational exchanges. J Mark. 2002;66(1):15&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias O, Markovic S, Rialp J. How does sensory brand experience influence brand equity? Considering the roles of customer satisfaction, customer affective commitment, and employee empathy. J Bus Res. 2019;96:343&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung JH, Yoo JJ, Arnold TJ. The influence of a retail store manager in developing frontline employee brand relationship, service performance and customer loyalty. J Bus Res. 2021;122:362&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.jbusres.2020.09.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2020.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiband M, Buschek D, Hussmann H. The impact of placebic explanations on trust in intelligent systems. Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI &#x2018;18). 2018. pp. 331&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T. Explanation in artificial intelligence: insights from the social sciences. Artif Intell. 2019;267:1&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1016/j.artint.2018.07.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.artint.2018.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>