<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41103844</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Delayed Diagnosis of Lumbosacral Lipomyelomeningocele With Tethered Cord: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e92310</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e92310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e92310</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.92310</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lipomyelomeningocele (LMMC) is a rare form of closed spinal dysraphism arising from primary neurulation defects, characterized by a lipomatous mass that anchors the spinal cord. Early diagnosis is critical to prevent progressive neurological deterioration; however, in resource-limited settings, detection is often delayed. We report the case of a nine-year-old girl with a congenital lumbosacral mass identified at birth but underestimated during the initial neonatal assessment. Over time, she developed progressive gait disturbances and right equinovarus deformity. Magnetic resonance imaging performed later revealed a lumbosacral LMMC with tethered cord and occult spina bifida. The patient underwent a 15-hour surgical procedure consisting of LMMC excision and cord untethering, with no intraoperative complications. Postoperatively, she presented with preserved motor strength, residual hypoesthesia in the lower limbs, and bladder management with neuromodulation. At two-week follow-up, she showed stable neurological function, improved gait with rehabilitation, and satisfactory wound healing. This case underscores the importance of recognizing lumbosacral cutaneous stigmata as markers of occult spinal dysraphism, highlights the challenges associated with delayed diagnosis, and emphasizes the need for a multidisciplinary approach in the management of complex surgical cases. Furthermore, it reflects the global epidemiological burden of neural tube defects estimated at 18.6 per 10,000 live births and the disparities in diagnosis and access to specialized care in rural areas, reinforcing the importance of improving neonatal screening, the availability of imaging studies, and healthcare provider training to reduce preventable disability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Rodriguez Campian et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodriguez Campian</LastName><ForeName>Fiorella G</ForeName><Initials>FG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universidad de Aquino Bolivia, Santa Cruz, BOL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vargas Casta&#xf1;eda</LastName><ForeName>Alejandra C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, San Juan Bautista Private University, Lima, PER.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puch Ramirez</LastName><ForeName>Mauricio D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Surgery, Hospital de Ni&#xf1;os Dr. Mario Ort&#xed;z Su&#xe1;rez, Santa Cruz, BOL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tueros Salazar</LastName><ForeName>Brigida Del Pilar G</ForeName><Initials>BDPG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Universidad Nacional Federico Villareal, Lima, PER.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres Abono</LastName><ForeName>Leslie I</ForeName><Initials>LI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Universidad de Aquino Bolivia, Santa Cruz, BOL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luna</LastName><ForeName>Jesus S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Facultad de Medicina Humana, Universidad Nacional Jos&#xe9; Faustino S&#xe1;nchez Carri&#xf3;n, Huacho, PER.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romero</LastName><ForeName>Carlos A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Prisma Health Greenville, South Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">closed neural tube defect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">delayed diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">equinovarus deformity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipomyelomeningocele</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lumbosacral mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric neurosurgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal dysraphism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tethered cord syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41103844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12521038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.92310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Neural tube defect in a resource limited setting: clinical profile and short term outcome. Mengiste FG, Shibeshi MS, Gechera DY. Pediatr Health Med Ther. 2023;14:289&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10517686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37746523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A study on facial features of children with Williams syndrome in China based on three-dimensional anthropometric measurement technology. Ji C, Yao D, Li MY, Chen WJ, Lin SL, Zhao ZY. Am J Med Genet A. 2020;182:2102&#x2013;2109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between the five-minute Apgar score and neurodevelopmental outcomes among children aged 8-66 months in Australia. Hassen TA, Chojenta C, Egan N, Loxton D. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maternal factors for neural tube defects in offspring: an umbrella review. Arabzadeh H, Jenabi E, Masoumi SZ. Open Med (Wars) 2024;19:20241061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11491881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39434859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of neural tube defects according to maternal body mass index: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vena F, D'Ambrosio V, Paladini V, et al. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2022;35:7296&#x2013;7305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34219595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neural tube defects: a review of global prevalence, causes, and primary prevention. Kancherla V. Childs Nerv Syst. 2023;39:1703&#x2013;1710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International consensus statement on the radiological evaluation of dysraphic malformations of the spine and spinal cord. Balani A, Sidpra J, Sudhakar S, et al. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2024;45:673&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11288609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38360788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early- and long-term surgical outcomes in 109 children with lipomyelomeningocele. Vora TK, Girishan S, Moorthy RK, Rajshekhar V. Childs Nerv Syst. 2021;37:1623&#x2013;1632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33404713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radical resection of lumbosacral lipomas in children: the Great Ormond Street Hospital experience. De Vloo P, Sharma J, Alderson L, et al. Childs Nerv Syst. 2022;38:1113&#x2013;1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35262755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Not just an anchor: the human filum terminale contains stretch sensitive and nociceptive nerve endings and responds to electrical stimulation with paraspinal muscle activation. Klinge PM, McElroy A, Leary OP, Donahue JE, Mumford A, Brinker T, Gokaslan ZL. Neurosurgery. 2022;91:618&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9447435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35852974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The surgical histopathology of the filum terminale: findings from a large series of patients with tethered cord syndrome. Abdulrazeq H, Leary OP, Tang OY, et al. J Clin Med. 2023;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10779556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38202013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh P, Apaydin E, Briggs RG, et al.  Diagnosis and Treatment of Tethered Spinal Cord. Comparative Effectiveness Review No. 274. Rockville, MD: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); October.  [
Sep;
2025 
]. 2024. https://effectivehealthcare.ahrq.gov/products/tethered-spinal-cord/research https://effectivehealthcare.ahrq.gov/products/tethered-spinal-cord/research</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39541488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Five-minute Apgar score and risk of neonatal mortality, severe neurological morbidity and severe non-neurological morbidity in term infants - an Australian population-based cohort study. Hong J, Crawford K, Jarrett K, Triggs T, Kumar S. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2024;44:101011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10825608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38292653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apgar score and risk of neonatal death among preterm infants. Cnattingius S, Johansson S, Razaz N. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:49&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32609981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of neurological health disparities in Peru. Almubaslat F, Sanchez-Boluarte SS, Diaz MM. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1210238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10513391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37744515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>