<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41304003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Waste Rubber Powder on the Mechanical and Abrasion Resistance Properties of Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5157</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18225157</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the river environments of Xinjiang characterized by high sediment content and high flow velocities, hydraulic concrete is highly susceptible to damage from the impact and abrasion of bed load. Consequently, this imposes more stringent requirements on its mechanical properties and abrasion resistance. The incorporation of crumb rubber, a recyclable material, into concrete presents a dual benefit: it enables resource recycling while simultaneously offering a novel pathway for the development of concrete technology. This study takes rubber powder concrete as the research object. With the same water-to-binder ratio, rubber powder was incorporated at three volume fractions: 0%, 5%, and 10% of the cementitious material. The drop weight impact test and underwater steel ball method are adopted to evaluate its impact resistance and anti-scouring-abrasion performance, respectively. By testing the compressive strength, impact toughness, wear rate, anti-scouring-abrasion strength and three-dimensional morphological characteristics, the influence of rubber powder content on the mechanical properties and anti-scouring-abrasion performance of concrete is systematically analyzed. The research results show that the addition of rubber powder reduces the compressive strength of concrete, but significantly improves its impact resistance and anti-scouring-abrasion performance. Among all test groups, the concrete with 10% rubber powder content has the most significant decrease in compressive strength, with a decrease of about 37% compared with the 5% content group, while the 5% content group has a decrease of about 27% compared with the control group. However, its impact toughness at 3d, 7d and 15d is increased by about 84.7%, 88.4% and 84.4%, respectively, compared with the control group, showing the largest improvement range. At the same time, the wear rate of this group is reduced by about 42.5%, and the anti-scouring-abrasion strength is increased by about 61%. Combined with the three-dimensional morphology analysis, it can be seen that the specimens in this group exhibit the optimal anti-scouring-abrasion performance. In terms of microstructure, the porosity of rubber powder concrete increases, the generation of C-S-H gel decreases and its continuity is damaged, leading to a significant decrease in compressive strength. The reduction in the generation of delayed ettringite enhances the toughness and anti-scouring-abrasion performance. In general, the increase in rubber powder content will lead to a decrease in the compressive strength of concrete, but within a certain range, it can significantly improve its impact resistance and anti-scouring-abrasion performance. Crumb rubber effectively enhances the impact and abrasion resistance of hydraulic concrete, demonstrating strong application potential in high-flow, sediment-laden river environments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Shuangxi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Xinjiang Agricultural University, Urumqi 830052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Dongzheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Xinjiang Agricultural University, Urumqi 830052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Chunmeng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5200-0008</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Xinjiang Agricultural University, Urumqi 830052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Zhimin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Xinjiang Agricultural University, Urumqi 830052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Mai</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Xinjiang Agricultural University, Urumqi 830052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Tianze Engineering Management Co., Ltd., Shihezi 832003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>XJEDU2024J045</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52269028</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024TSYCCX0037</GrantID><Agency>Tianshan Talent Training Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abrasion resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydraulic concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impact resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rubber powder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Zhong Li was employed by the company Xinjiang Tianze Engineering Management Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41304003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12654505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18225157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18225157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hisbani N., Shafiq N., Shams M.A., Farhan S.A., Zahid M. Properties of concrete containing crumb rubber as partial replacement of fine Aggregate&#x2014;A review. Hybrid Adv. 2025;10:100481. doi: 10.1016/j.hybadv.2025.100481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hybadv.2025.100481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C., Li S., Jiang L., Tang X. Evaluation of abrasion resistance of low-heat cement concrete under freeze-thaw cycles. J. Yangtze River Sci. Res. Inst. 2023;40:163&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Gao Y., Wang C., Li Y., Fan T. Impact Resistance Test and Numerical Simulation Study of Scrap Steel Fiber Rubber Concrete. Buildings. 2025;15:2857. doi: 10.3390/buildings15162857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15162857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C., Wang P., Sun M. Experimental study on air content and slump of waste rubber aggregate concrete mixture. Concrete. 2014:53&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Zhai S., Kang J., Hou C., Gao S., Chang D., Yu Z., Niu X. Study on impact resistance and wear resistance of rubber aggregate concrete and mechanistic analysis. Concrete. 2025:103&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Tyre &amp; Rubber Manufacturers&#x2019; Association . End-of-Life Tyres Management: Europe 2021 Figures. European Tyre &amp; Rubber Manufacturers&#x2019; Association; Brussels, Belgium: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abobakr H., Raji M., Essabir H., Bensalah M.O., Bouhfid R., Qaiss A.E.K. Sustainable Acoustic Insulation in Nonstructural Concrete: Enhancing Performance with Ground Tire Rubber. J. Constr. Eng. Manag. 2025;151:04025147. doi: 10.1061/JCEMD4.COENG-16374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JCEMD4.COENG-16374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Shenyang University; Shenyang, China: 2024. Numerical Simulation Study on Mechanical Properties of Rubber Concrete Based on Random Aggregate Model.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma J., Chaturvedy G.K., Pandey U.K. Sustainable rubberized concrete: The role of nano-titanium dioxide in enhancing mechanical and durability properties. Front. Struct. Civ. Eng. 2025;19:1418&#x2013;1439. doi: 10.1007/s11709-025-1216-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11709-025-1216-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamees A.A., Tameemi W.A., Sulaiman E.A., Al-Rammahi A.A. Structural and Mechanical Characteristics of Sustainable Concrete Composite Panels Reinforced with Pre-Treated Recycled Tire Rubber. Rev. Compos. Mat&#xe9;riaux Avanc&#xe9;s J. Compos. Adv. Mater. 2023;33:371&#x2013;378. doi: 10.18280/rcma.330604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18280/rcma.330604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin H., Wang Z., Zhao C. Parameter inversion analysis of rubber-mortar cohesive zone model in rubberized concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:133996. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan K., Rahaman M.M., Ali M.B., Urmi M.A., Fariha N.A., Islam M.T., Nahar T.T., Yahaya F.M. A comprehensive review of the application of waste tire rubber in concrete/mortar as fine aggregate replacement. Archit. Struct. Constr. 2023;4:91&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1007/s44150-023-00102-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44150-023-00102-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Andersen L.V., Zhang M., Wu M. Abrasion damage of concrete for hydraulic structures and mitigation measures: A comprehensive review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;422:135754. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Li L., Andersen L.V., Wu M. Studying the abrasion damage of concrete for hydraulic structures under various flow conditions. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;135:104849. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai S., Liu G., Pang B., Liu C., Zhang Z., Zhang L., Liu L., Yang Y., Liu Z., Zhang Y. Investigation on the influence of modified waste rubber powder on the abrasion resistance of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;357:129409. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh A., Harsha A.P., Ghosh M.K. Solid particle erosion of unidirectional fibre reinforced thermoplastic composites. Wear. 2009;267:1516&#x2013;1524. doi: 10.1016/j.wear.2009.03.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2009.03.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu&#x161;i&#x107; R., Gazi&#x107; G., Gulja&#x161; I., Mili&#x10d;evi&#x107; I. Experimental determination of double-K fracture parameters for self-compacting concrete with waste tire rubber and silica fume. Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech. 2025;139:105021. doi: 10.1016/j.tafmec.2025.105021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tafmec.2025.105021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdo A., Elshazli M.T., Alashker Y., Ahmed S. Improving flexural response of rubberized RC beams with multi-dimensional sustainable approaches. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;449:138400. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawar M.T., Selim M., Zaghlal M., El-Zohairy A., Emara M. Performance of GFRP-Confined Rubberized Engineered Cementitious Composite Columns. J. Compos. Sci. 2024;8:330. doi: 10.3390/jcs8080330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcs8080330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed S., Elemam H., Seleem M.H., Sallam H.E.-D.M. Effect of fiber addition on strength and toughness of rubberized concretes. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:4346. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-54763-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54763-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10884028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38388634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouabaz A., Djebien R., Belachia M. Effect of Brick and Ceramic Powders on Fresh and Hardened Properties of Rubberized Concrete. Iran. J. Sci. Technol. Trans. Civ. Eng. 2024;49:3713&#x2013;3728. doi: 10.1007/s40996-024-01689-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40996-024-01689-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaloo A.R., Dehestani M., Rahmatabadi P. Mechanical Properties of Concrete Containing a High Volume of Tire-Rubber Particles. Waste Manag. 2008;28:2472&#x2013;2482. doi: 10.1016/j.wasman.2008.01.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wasman.2008.01.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18372166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Code for Hydraulic Concrete. Benliu Electronic Audio-Visual Publishing (Beijing) Co., Ltd.; Beijing, China: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specification for Mix Design of Hydraulic Concrete. China Electric Power Press; Beijing, China: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C., Gong J., Jiang L., Chen C., Tang X. Research on Time-varying Behavior and Its Influence Factors of Low Heat Cement Concrete Under Abrasion. Mater. Rep. 2023;37:155&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C., An S., Li S., Wu B. Evaluation and prediction of abrasion resistance of hydraulic concrete based on three-dimensional topography. China Concr. Cem. Prod. 2024:82&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran T.Q., Li S., Ji B., Zhao X. Mitigating Zinc Leachate from End-of-Life Tire Rubber in Stabilized Clayey Soils. J. Geotech. Geoenviron. Eng. 2024;150:88&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1061/JGGEFK.GTENG-12302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JGGEFK.GTENG-12302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jie Y., Guan R., Di H., Peng J., Zhou C. Experimental Study on Peak Shear Strength Criterion for Rock Joints. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2016;49:821&#x2013;835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z., Xiang G., Zhong F., Tian Y., Li H., Lei J., Yuan Q. Unveiling the impact of organic phase aging on the long-term damping capacity of cement-styrene butadiene rubber composites. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;437:136916. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin B., Lin Z., Li T., Qi D., Wang P., Han K., Hou D. Enhancing cement-based composites via regulated hydration and concurrent construction of robust organic-inorganic network. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;445:137902. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing Y., Zhang C., Lin G., Niu Y., Zhao M., Lin Z. Enhancing rubber concrete with supercritical fluid-assisted Nano-SiO2 embedding and high-temperature stirred waste rubber. J. Build. Eng. 2024;96:110530. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta T., Siddique S., Sharma R.K., Chaudhary S. Behaviour of waste rubber powder and hybrid rubber concrete in aggressive environment. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;217:283&#x2013;291. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Sun D., Liu D., Meng K., Ni C., Shao Z., Sun L. Simulation of ultrasonic propagation in porous cellular concrete materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;285:122852. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Fu Q., Zhang Z., Fang Y., Wang Y., Wang F., Song Y., Pittman C.U., Jr., Wang Q. Efficient flame-retardant hybrid coatings on wood plastic composites by layer-by-layer assembly. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;321:128949. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.128949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.128949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>