<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41724978</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-6148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC veterinary research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Vet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic relationships and development of resistance of enrofloxacin and cefquinome in combination therapy against Klebsiella pneumoniae in chicks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12917-026-05301-5</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Yanzhe</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shiyan Key Laboratory of Natural Medicine Nano Formulation Research, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine, Renmin Road No. 30, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Key Laboratory for Veterinary Drug Development and Safety Evaluation, College of Veterinary Medicine, South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fuhui</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Key Laboratory for Veterinary Drug Development and Safety Evaluation, College of Veterinary Medicine, South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xilong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Key Laboratory for Veterinary Drug Development and Safety Evaluation, College of Veterinary Medicine, South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xinyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shiyan Key Laboratory of Natural Medicine Nano Formulation Research, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine, Renmin Road No. 30, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tongfei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shiyan Key Laboratory of Natural Medicine Nano Formulation Research, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine, Renmin Road No. 30, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China. litongfeihappy@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yafei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Quality Standard and Monitoring Technology for Agro-products of Guangdong Academy of Agricultural Sciences, Guangzhou, 510640, China. liyafei@gdaas.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Huanzhong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Key Laboratory for Veterinary Drug Development and Safety Evaluation, College of Veterinary Medicine, South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China. hzding@scau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024QDJZR020</GrantID><Agency>Faculty Development Grants from Hubei University of Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>X202510929061</GrantID><Agency>Hubei University of Medicine 2025 College Students' Innovation Training Program Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023YFD1800904</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Vet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101249759</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-6148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Klebsiella pneumoniae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cefquinome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chick</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combination therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enrofloxacin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PK/PD model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of South China Agricultural University (Approval number: 2021C052, 2023A002). The experiment plans to purchase chicks from the Guangdong Academy of Agricultural Sciences for the study, with the species, quantity, and grouping of animals adhering to the 3R principles. The experiments will be conducted in laboratories that meet national requirements in China, ensuring compliance with welfare principles. Following the experiment, chicks will be humanely euthanized by cervical dislocation after administration of 20% ethyl carbamate for deep general anesthesia, in strict compliance with the Guidelines for Euthanasia of Laboratory Animals&#x200c; (GB/T 39760&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;2021). Consent for publication: The author confirms: 1.&#xa0;that the work described has not been published before (except in the form of an abstract or as part of a published lecture, review, or thesis); 2.&#xa0;that it is not under consideration for publication elsewhere; 3.&#xa0;that its publication has been approved by all co-authors, if any; 4.&#xa0;that its publication has been approved (tacitly or explicitly) by the responsible authorities at the institution where the work carried out. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41724978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-026-05301-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12917-026-05301-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baym M, Stone LK, Kishony R. Multidrug evolutionary strategies to reverse antibiotic resistance. Science. 2016;351(6268):aad3292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SLM, Oliver KBMM. Antibiotic resistance threats in the United States: stepping back from the brink. Am Fam Physician. 2014;89(12):938&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez JL. Bottlenecks in the transferability of antibiotic resistance from natural ecosystems to human bacterial pathogens. FRONT MICROBIOL. 2011;2:265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lappin MR, Blondeau J, Boothe D, Breitschwerdt EB, Guardabassi L, Lloyd DH, Papich MG, Rankin SC, Sykes JE, Turnidge J, et al. Antimicrobial use guidelines for treatment of respiratory tract disease in dogs and cats: antimicrobial guidelines working group of the international society for companion animal infectious diseases. J VET INTERN MED. 2017;31(2):279&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Xu L, Yuan G, Wang Y, Qu Y, Zhou M. Synergistic combination of two antimicrobial agents closing each other&#x2019;s mutant selection windows to prevent antimicrobial resistance. Sci Rep-UK. 2018;8(1):7237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drlica K, Zhao X. Mutant selection window hypothesis updated. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;44(5):681&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Gefen O, Ronin I, Bar-Meir M, Balaban NQ. Effect of tolerance on the evolution of antibiotic resistance under drug combinations. Science. 2020;367(6474):200&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Ji X, Zhang F, Zhang S, Deng Q, Ding H. PK-PD integration of Enrofloxacin and cefquinome alone and in combination against Klebsiella pneumoniae using an in vitro dynamic model. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2023;14:1226936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia B, Raphenya AR, Alcock B, Waglechner N, Guo P, Tsang KK, Lago BA, Dave BM, Pereira S, Sharma AN, et al. CARD 2017: expansion and model-centric curation of the comprehensive antibiotic resistance database. NUCLEIC ACIDS RES. 2017;45(D1):D566&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enault F, Briet A, Bouteille L, Roux S, Sullivan MB, Petit M. Phages rarely encode antibiotic resistance genes: a cautionary tale for virome analyses. ISME J. 2017;11(1):237&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Helm E, Imamovic L, Hashim EM, van Schaik W, Koza A, Sommer M. Rapid resistome mapping using nanopore sequencing. NUCLEIC ACIDS RES. 2017;45(8):e61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Li Y, Zhao H, Zhao Y, Wang Y, Ding H. Pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic relationships of Enrofloxacin against Klebsiella pneumoniae in an in vivo infection model in young chicks. Poult Sci. 2024;103(8):103868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wu X, Huang Z, Zhang N, Wu Y, Cai Q, et al. Pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic assessment of cefquinome against Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae in a piglet tissue cage infection model. Vet Microbiol. 2018;219:100&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N, Wu Y, Huang Z, Yao L, Zhang L, Cai Q, et al. The PK-PD relationship and resistance development of danofloxacin against Mycoplasma gallisepticum in an in vivo infection model. Front Microbiol. 2017;8:926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AF, Kristoffersson AN, Karvanen M, Nielsen EI, Cars O, Friberg LE. Dynamic interaction of colistin and meropenem on a WT and a resistant strain of Pseudomonas aeruginosa as quantified in a PK/PD model. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2016;71(5):1279&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebriaei R, Rice SA, Stamper KC, Rybak MJ. Dalbavancin alone and in combination with ceftaroline against four different phenotypes of Staphylococcus aureus in a simulated pharmacodynamic/pharmacokinetic model. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.01743-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toutain PL, Del Castillo JRE, Bousquet-M&#xe9;lou A. The pharmacokinetic&#x2013;pharmacodynamic approach to a rational dosage regimen for antibiotics. RES VET SCI. 2002;73(2):105&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martel A, Baele M, Devriese LA, Goossens H, Wisselink HJ, Decostere A, et al. Prevalence and mechanism of resistance against macrolides and lincosamides in Streptococcus suis isolates. Vet Microbiol. 2001;83(3):287&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharatham N, Bhowmik P, Aoki M, Okada U, Sharma S, Yamashita E, Shanbhag AP, Rajagopal S, Thomas T, Sarma M, et al. Structure and function relationship of OqxB efflux pump from Klebsiella pneumoniae. NAT COMMUN. 2021;12(1):5400&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng F, Li Z, Lan S, Liu W, Li X, Zhou Z, Song Z, Wu J, Zhang M, Shan W. Characterization of Klebsiella pneumoniae associated with cattle infections in Southwest China using multi-locus sequence typing (MLST), antibiotic resistance and virulence-associated gene profile analysis. BRAZ J MICROBIOL. 2018;49(Suppl 1Suppl 1):93&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geetha PV, Aishwarya KVL, Mariappan S, Sekar U. Fluoroquinolone resistance in clinical isolates of Klebsiella pneumoniae. J Lab Phys. 2020;12(2):121&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llobet E, March C, Gimenez P, Bengoechea JA. Klebsiella pneumoniae OmpA confers resistance to antimicrobial peptides. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2009;53(1):298&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitondo-Silva A, Martins VV, Silva CF, Stehling EG. Conjugation between quinolone-susceptible bacteria can generate mutations in the quinolone resistance-determining region, inducing quinolone resistance. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2015;45(2):119&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robicsek A, Sahm DF, Strahilevitz J, Jacoby GA, Hooper DC. Broader distribution of plasmid-mediated quinolone resistance in the United States. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2005;49(7):3001&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger J, Navon-Venezia S, Chmelnitsky I, Hammer-Munz O, Leavitt A, Gold HS, et al. Extended-spectrum beta-lactamases among Enterobacter isolates obtained in Tel Aviv, Israel. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2005;49(3):1150&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Kang Z, Yao L, Gu X, Huang Z, Cai Q, Shen X, Ding H. Pharmacokinetic/Pharmacodynamic integration to evaluate the changes in susceptibility of Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae after repeated administration of Danofloxacin. FRONT MICROBIOL. 2018;9:2445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad I, Hao H, Huang L, Sanders P, Wang X, Chen D, Tao Y, Xie S, Xiuhua K, Li J, et al. Integration of PK/PD for dose optimization of cefquinome against Staphylococcus aureus causing septicemia in cattle. FRONT MICROBIOL. 2015;6:588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Yao L, Kang Z, Huang Z, Gu X, Shen X, Ding H. Microdialysis determination of cefquinome pharmacokinetics in murine thigh from Healthy, Neutropenic, and Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae-Infected mice. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2019;10:249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wantuch PL, Knoot CJ, Robinson LS, Vinogradov E, Scott NE, Harding CM, Rosen DA. Capsular polysaccharide inhibits vaccine-induced O-antigen antibody binding and function across both classical and hypervirulent K2:O1 strains of Klebsiella pneumoniae. PLOS PATHOG. 2023;19(5):e1011367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristoffersson AN, Bissantz C, Okujava R, Haldimann A, Walter I, Shi T, et al. A novel mechanism-based pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic (PKPD) model describing ceftazidime/avibactam efficacy against beta-lactamase-producing Gram-negative bacteria. J Antimicrob Chemoth. 2020;75(2):400&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanScoy BD, Tenero D, Turner S, Livermore DM, McCauley J, Conde H, et al. Pharmacokinetics-pharmacodynamics of tazobactam in combination with cefepime in an in vitro infection model. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.01052-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Deng B, Liao W, Wang P, Chen P, Wei J. High rate of multiresistant Klebsiella pneumoniae from human and animal origin. Infect Drug Resist. 2019;12:2729&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi T, Latt KM, Tarigan E, Yano F, Sato H, Minamino T, et al. A 1-year investigation of extended-spectrum beta-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae isolated from bovine mastitis at a Large-Scale dairy farm in Japan. Microb Drug Resist (Larchmont N Y). 2021;27(10):145&#x2013;1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Xie S, Chen D, Pan Y, Tao Y, Qu W, et al. Pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic modeling of Cyadox against clostridium perfringens in swine. Sci Rep-UK. 2017;7(1):4011&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delattre IK, Taccone FS, Jacobs F, Hites M, Dugernier T, Spapen H, Laterre P, Wallemacq PE, Van Bambeke F, Tulkens PM. Optimizing &#x3b2;-lactams treatment in critically-ill patients using pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics targets: are first conventional doses effective? EXPERT REV ANTI-INFE. 2017;15(7):677&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez DEM, Gumpert H, Munck C, Thomsen TT, Sommer MO. Collateral resistance and sensitivity modulate evolution of high-level resistance to drug combination treatment in Staphylococcus aureus. Mol Biol Evol. 2015;32(5):1175&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEVY SB. Plasmid-determined tetracycline resistance involves new transport systems for tetracycline. Nat (Lond). 1978;276(5683):90&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Pl&#xe9;siat P, Nikaido H. The challenge of efflux-mediated antibiotic resistance in Gram-negative bacteria. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2015;28(2):337&#x2013;418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilla E, Llobet E, Domenech-Sanchez A, Martinez-Martinez L, Bengoechea JA, Alberti S. Klebsiella pneumoniae acrab efflux pump contributes to antimicrobial resistance and virulence. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2010;54(1):177&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialek-Davenet S, Lavigne JP, Guyot K, Mayer N, Tournebize R, Brisse S, et al. Differential contribution of acrab and OqxAB efflux pumps to multidrug resistance and virulence in Klebsiella pneumoniae. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2015;70(1):81&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair JM, Richmond GE, Piddock LJ. Multidrug efflux pumps in Gram-negative bacteria and their role in antibiotic resistance. Future Microbiol. 2014;9(10):1165&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomovskaya O, Warren MS, Lee A, Galazzo J, Fronko R, Lee M, Blais J, Cho D, Chamberland S, Renau T, et al. Identification and characterization of inhibitors of multidrug resistance efflux pumps in Pseudomonas aeruginosa: novel agents for combination therapy. ANTIMICROB AGENTS CH. 2001;45(1):105&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Q, Xu Y, Wang B, Yu J, Shen X, Liu L, et al. Distribution of fluoroquinolone resistance determinants in carbapenem-resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae clinical isolates associated with bloodstream infections in China. BMC Microbiol. 2021;21(1):164.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>