<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888937</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute effects of percussion massage therapy on balance, functional performance, and pain in adolescent cyclists: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">168</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01607-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Percussion massage therapy (PMT) is increasingly used in sport as a warm-up and recovery tool, yet its acute effects on neuromuscular performance in youth athletes are unclear. This study examined whether a single PMT session is associated with short-term changes in dynamic balance, functional performance and pain in adolescent cyclists.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this assessor-blinded randomized controlled trial, 32 licensed cyclists aged 12&#x2013;15 years were allocated to a PMT group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) or control group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;16). PMT was delivered bilaterally to the gluteus maximus, quadriceps femoris, and gastrocnemius muscles using a handheld percussive device (Compex<sup>&#xae;</sup> Fixx&#x2122; 2.0; 41.7&#xa0;Hz) for a total of 18&#xa0;min, while controls rested for an equivalent period. Outcomes were assessed pre- and immediately post-intervention and included Y Balance Test (YBT) composite score, Triple Hop Test distance, isometric lower-limb strength (handheld dynamometry), and lower-limb pain (Numeric Rating Scale, NRS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with controls, the PMT group showed significantly greater improvements in YBT composite scores (dominant limb: <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.015, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.91; non-dominant: <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.016, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.90). Within-group improvements were observed in Triple Hop Test distance in the PMT group; however, post-intervention between-group differences were not consistently observed across all outcomes. Isometric strength of the gastrocnemius, quadriceps femoris, and gluteus maximus did not change significantly in either group (all <i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). NRS scores decreased markedly after PMT (within-group d = &#x2212;&#x2009;2.18), with change scores favoring PMT over control (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, d = &#x2212;&#x2009;1.33).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A single PMT session was associated with short-term improvements in dynamic balance, selected aspects of functional performance, and pain perception in adolescent cyclists, without altering maximal isometric strength. These findings should be interpreted as acute and exploratory, suggesting that PMT may serve as a complementary pre-activity modality primarily through short-term neuromuscular and pain-modulating mechanisms rather than definitive performance enhancement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Prospectively registered in the ClinicalTrials.gov registry (NCT07206576) on 26/09/2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-026-01607-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dansuk</LastName><ForeName>Emre</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4415-8101</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Istanbul Medipol University, Istanbul, Turkey. edansuk@medipol.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menek</LastName><ForeName>Burak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5206-0254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Istanbul Medipol University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bursa Uludag University, Bursa, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Tayfun</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7865-7510</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Center, Sinop Provincial Directorate of Youth and Sports, Sinop, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okur</LastName><ForeName>Selim</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Center, Sinop Provincial Directorate of Youth and Sports, Sinop, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent athletes; cycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain perception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percussion massage therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All participants provided written informed assent, and written informed consent to participate was obtained from the parents or legal guardians of all participants younger than 16 years of age. The study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The study protocol received approval from the non-interventional ethics committee at Istanbul Medipol University (File number: E-10840098-202.3.02-6304). All participants provided written informed consent. Consent for publication: Written consent for publication has been obtained from the patient shown in f&#x131;gure 2. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13045070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01607-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01607-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Mujika I. Optimizing strength training for running and cycling endurance performance: A review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:603&#x2013;12. 10.1111/sms.12104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23914932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaj&#x105;c B, Mika A, Gaj PK, Ambro&#x17c;y T. Does cycling training reduce quality of functional movement motor patterns and dynamic postural control in adolescent cyclists? A pilot study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:12109. 10.3390/ijerph191912109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191912109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9566619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36231409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake OM, Wakeling JM. Muscle coordination during an outdoor cycling time trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:939&#x2013;48. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182404eb4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182404eb4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mater A, Clos P, Lepers R. Effect of cycling Cadence on neuromuscular function: A systematic review of acute and chronic alterations. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7912. 10.3390/ijerph18157912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18157912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J. Vibration as an exercise modality: how it May work, and what its potential might be. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:877&#x2013;904. 10.1007/s00421-009-1303-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1303-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moezy A, Olyaei G, Hadian M, Razi M, Faghihzadeh S. A comparative study of whole body vibration training and conventional training on knee proprioception and postural stability after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2008;42:373&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.038554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18182623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tankisheva E, Bogaerts A, Boonen S, Delecluse C, Jansen P, Verschueren SMP. Effects of a Six-Month local vibration training on bone Density, muscle Strength, muscle Mass, and physical performance in postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2613&#x2013;22. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25992656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheatham SW, Baker RT, Behm DG, Stull K, Kolber MJ. Mechanical percussion devices: A survey of practice patterns among healthcare professionals. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16:766&#x2013;77. 10.26603/001c.23530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.23530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erayata BN, Menek B. Investigating the effects of percussion massage therapy on pain, functionality, muscle diameter, and proprioception in &#x131;ndividuals with ACL reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2025;20:e0319731. 10.1371/journal.pone.0319731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0319731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11940657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40138389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Glash&#xfc;ttner C, Reiner MM, Bernsteiner D, Tilp M. The acute effects of a percussive massage treatment with a hypervolt device on plantar flexor muscles&#x2019; range of motion and performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19:690&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bart&#xed;k P, Pacholek M. The effect of percussion and manual activation massage on explosive strength and balance in young adult males: A crossover pilot study. Heliyon. 2024;10:e39619. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e39619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e39619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11532880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39497958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menek MY, Menek B. Effects of percussion massage therapy, dynamic stretching, and static stretching on physical performance and balance. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2024;37:183&#x2013;93. 10.3233/BMR-230069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-230069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37661870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trainer JH, Pascarella M, Paul RW, Thomas SJ. Acute effects of percussive therapy on the posterior shoulder muscles differ based on the athlete&#x2019;s soreness response. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2022;17:887&#x2013;95. 10.26603/001c.37254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.37254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer SW, Teyhen DS, Lorenson CL, Warren RL, Koreerat CM, Straseske CA, et al. Y-balance test: a reliability study involving multiple raters. Mil Med. 2013;178:1264&#x2013;70. 10.7205/MILMED-D-13-00222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7205/MILMED-D-13-00222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24183777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisky PJ, Rauh MJ, Kaminski TW, Underwood FB. Star excursion balance test as a predictor of lower extremity injury in high school basketball players. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2006;36:911&#x2013;9. 10.2519/jospt.2006.2244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2006.2244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17193868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler RJ, Lehr ME, Fink ML, Kiesel KB, Plisky PJ. Dynamic balance performance and noncontact lower extremity injury in college football players: an initial study. Sports Health. 2013;5:417&#x2013;22. 10.1177/1941738113498703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738113498703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24427412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonell AC, Romero JAP, Soler LM, Relationship between the y balance test scores, and soft tissue injury incidence in a soccer team. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10:955&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powden CJ, Dodds TK, Gabriel EH, The reliability of the star excursion balance test, and lower quarter y-balance test in healthy adults. A systematic review. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14:683&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20190683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31598406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwiertz G, Brueckner D, Schedler S, Kiss R, Muehlbauer T. Performance and reliability of the lower quarter Y balance test in healthy adolescents from grade 6 to 11. Gait Posture. 2019;67:142&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2018.10.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2018.10.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30336348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid A, Birmingham TB, Stratford PW, Alcock GK, Giffin JR. Hop testing provides a reliable and valid outcome measure during rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther. 2007;87:337&#x2013;49. 10.2522/ptj.20060143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20060143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17311886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logerstedt D, Grindem H, Lynch A, Eitzen I, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA, et al. Single-legged hop tests as predictors of self-reported knee function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40:2348&#x2013;56. 10.1177/0363546512457551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512457551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentiplay BF, Perraton LG, Bower KJ, Adair B, Pua Y-H, Williams GP, et al. Assessment of lower limb muscle strength and power using Hand-Held and fixed dynamometry: A reliability and validity study. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0140822. 10.1371/journal.pone.0140822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0140822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4624940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26509265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmon AR, Pozzi F, Alnahdi AH, Zeni JA, The validity of plantarflexor, Strength measures obtained through hand-held dynamometry measurements of force. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2013;8:820&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3867075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24377068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu Y, Tsutsui S, Katoh M. Examination and reliability of measuring muscle strength of ankle plantar flexion with knee extended. J Phys Ther Sci. 2023;35:619&#x2013;23. 10.1589/jpts.35.619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.35.619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10475641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37670756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Stride M, Villa FD. Assessing and treating gluteus maximus weakness &#x2013; a clinical commentary. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14:655&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20190655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31440415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katoh M, Yamasaki H. Comparison of reliability of isometric leg muscle strength measurements made using a Hand-Held dynamometer with and without a restraining belt. J Phys Ther Sci. 2009;21:37&#x2013;42. 10.1589/jpts.21.37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.21.37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson A, Hoggart B. Pain: a review of three commonly used pain rating scales. J Clin Nurs. 2005;14:798&#x2013;804. 10.1111/j.1365-2702.2005.01121.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2702.2005.01121.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipa A, Byrnes R, Paterno MV, Myer GD, Hewett TE. Neuromuscular training improves performance on the star excursion balance test in young female athletes. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40:551&#x2013;8. 10.2519/jospt.2010.3325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.3325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3439814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20710094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gribble PA, Hertel J. Considerations for normalizing measures of the star excursion balance test. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci. 2003;7:89&#x2013;100. 10.1207/S15327841MPEE0702_3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327841MPEE0702_3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;91. 10.3758/bf03193146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 1992;1:98&#x2013;101. 10.1111/1467-8721.ep10768783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-8721.ep10768783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sams L, Langdown BL, Simons J, Vseteckova J. The effect of percussive therapy on musculoskeletal performance and experiences of pain: A systematic literature review. Int J Sports Phys Therapy. 2023;18:309&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.73795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C-L, Chu I-H, Lyu B-J, Chang W-D, Chang N-J. Comparison of vibration rolling, nonvibration rolling, and static stretching as a warm-up exercise on flexibility, joint proprioception, muscle strength, and balance in young adults. J Sports Sci. 2018;36:2575&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1469848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29697023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Benito AM, Valldecabres R, Ceca D, Richards J, Barrachina Igual J, Pablos A. Effect of vibration vs non-vibration foam rolling techniques on flexibility, dynamic balance and perceived joint stability after fatigue. PeerJ. 2019;7:e8000. 10.7717/peerj.8000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.8000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6883953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31788353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menek B, Dansuk E, Arslan T. The effects of soft tissue mobilization and vibration therapy on Balance, explosive Strength, and functional performance in elite rowers. J Strength Cond Res. 2025. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000005305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Custer L, Peer KS, Miller L. The effects of local vibration on Balance, Power, and Self-Reported pain after exercise. J Sport Rehabil. 2017;26:193&#x2013;201. 10.1123/jsr.2015-0125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2015-0125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27632847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menek B, Tayboga UI. Examining acute impacts of soft tissue mobilization, percussion massage, and dynamic stretching on hamstring tightness. Gazz Med Ital - Arch Sci Med. 4:296&#x2013;304.10.23736/S0393-3660.23.05180-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W-C, Lee C-L, Chang N-J. Acute effects of dynamic stretching followed by vibration foam rolling on sports performance of badminton athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19:420&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32390736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves BS, Barbieri Coutinho LO, Caetano RO, de Oliveira Lauria F, Fonseca DS, Fel&#xed;cio DC. Percussive massage improved quadriceps pain Intensity, Fatigue, and perceived recovery after habitual running but had no effect on vertical jump: randomized trial. Clin J Sport Med. 2025;35:431&#x2013;4. 10.1097/JSM.0000000000001355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40135996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sams L, Langdown BL, Simons J, Vseteckova J. The impact of protocol designs for using massage guns on lower body flexibility: A randomised cross-over design study. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2025;41:85&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.11.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.11.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39663100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Luo L, Zhang J, Cheng P, Wu Q, Wen X. The effect of percussion massage therapy on the recovery of delayed onset muscle soreness in physically active young men-a randomized controlled trial. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1561970. 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1561970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1561970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11979224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40206177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz Menek M, Dansuk E, Tayboga UI. Effect of local vibration therapy on Pain, joint position Sense, Kinesiophobia, and disability in cervical disc herniation: A randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2024;13:4566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13154566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11312703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39124832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboodarda SJ, Spence AJ, Button DC. Pain pressure threshold of a muscle tender spot increases following local and non-local rolling massage. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015;16:265. 10.1186/s12891-015-0729-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-015-0729-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4587678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26416265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>