<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41685777</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-3115</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disability and rehabilitation. Assistive technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Knowledge, attitudes, and practices of New Zealand council members when developing accessible public playgrounds for children of all abilities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/17483107.2026.2628320</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Unstructured or "free play" is essential for children's psychological, emotional, social, and physical development. For disabled children, accessible playgrounds function as assistive environments that enable participation and inclusion. However, many playgrounds remain inaccessible due to limited awareness of inclusive design among those responsible for planning and development. This study explored the knowledge, practices, and perceived barriers among New Zealand local councils in the context of accessible playground design. All 78 councils, across 23 regions, were invited to complete an online questionnaire examining stakeholder involvement, current and desired knowledge, perceived importance of design features, and barriers to accessibility. Twenty-nine councils (37.2%), representing 17 regions, participated. All respondents reported public consultation in the design process, and most (93%) involved specific external groups. Key barriers to inclusive design included funding constraints, limited awareness or expertise, challenges sourcing suitable equipment, and space limitations. While many council staff believed they understood accessibility needs, they identified a lack of knowledge among contractors and other departments. These findings highlight the role of inclusive playgrounds as assistive infrastructure that promotes participation for disabled children. There is a clear need for targeted training and the development of research-informed, standardised design guidelines to support universal design practices. Such resources could improve both the financial feasibility and inclusivity of playgrounds. Participants also stressed the importance of prioritising social inclusion and wellbeing alongside physical and environmental considerations in future playground planning.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belcher</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8479-540X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Department, Centre for Health and Social Practice, Waikato Institute of Technology (Wintec), Hamilton, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Master of Physiotherapy Practice, School of Exercise, Sport and Rehabilitation Sciences, The University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crump</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Department, Centre for Health and Social Practice, Waikato Institute of Technology (Wintec), Hamilton, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Proactive Rehab, Papamoa, Tauranga, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Meredith</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1602-4421</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Health Activity and Rehabilitation Research, School of Physiotherapy, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampath</LastName><ForeName>Kesava Kovanur</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9908-3659</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Department, Centre for Health and Social Practice, Waikato Institute of Technology (Wintec), Hamilton, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Osteopathy, School of Health and Biomedical Sciences, STEM College, RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101255937</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-3107</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Access to playgrounds for all children is essential to allow equal opportunities for child physical, psychological, emotional, spiritual, and social wellbeing and risk perception development.Inclusive play environments function as a form of assistive technology for children with disabilities, supporting improved motor coordination, joint mobility, aerobic fitness and strength.Developing standardised reference designs for external developers could improve the creation of financially viable user-friendly playground, offering greater opportunities for effective engagement, development and rehabilitative prospects for children with and without disabilities.Playground development planning should consider equal emphasis on social inclusion and wellness, alongside physical and environmental determinants, to increase equitable accessibility and meet al.l physical and psychosocial needs for all children.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">council policy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">free play</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">play spaces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social inclusion</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41685777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2026.2628320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>