<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41736376</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Blood Flow Restriction Training Combined With Conventional Physical Therapy on Pain, Muscle Architecture, Strength, Function, and Psychosocial Outcomes in Chronic Lateral Epicondylitis: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e951969</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e951969</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e951969</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.951969</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND Chronic lateral epicondylitis (LE) causes persistent pain and functional impairment. Blood flow restriction training (BFRT) can improve strength and pain under low-load conditions, but evidence in chronic LE remains limited. This study investigated the effects of combining BFRT with conventional therapy on pain, muscle strength, function, and psychosocial outcomes. MATERIAL AND METHODS A single-blind randomized controlled trial was conducted with 22 participants diagnosed with chronic LE (&gt;3 months). Participants were randomly assigned to an Experimental Group (EG; BFRT + conventional therapy) or a Control Group (CG; conventional therapy). After 2 dropouts, 20 participants (10 per group) completed the 6-week intervention. Both groups received 60-minute supervised sessions twice weekly, consisting of conventional modalities and progressive exercise. In the EG, BFRT was applied at 40% to 50% of individual arterial occlusion pressure. Outcome measures included pain intensity (NPRS), pressure pain threshold (PPT), pennation angle (PA), pain-free grip strength (PFGS), wrist extensor strength (WES), functional performance (PRTEE, Quick-DASH), fear-avoidance beliefs (FABQ), and health-related quality of life (SF-12). RESULTS Both groups demonstrated significant improvements in pain, strength, and function (P&lt;0.05). The EG exhibited greater gains in PRTEE (P=0.001) and Quick-DASH (P=.025) scores, as well as larger improvements in FABQ (P=.039) and the physical component of SF-12 (P=.003), compared to the CG. Between-group differences in pain and strength changes were not statistically significant. No adverse events were reported. CONCLUSIONS BFRT combined with conventional therapy effectively enhanced functional and psychosocial recovery in patients with chronic LE. This low-load, time-efficient adjunct appears safe and beneficial for improving rehabilitation outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Ho</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Graduate School, Daejeon University, Daejeon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ho</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Armed Forces Daejeon Hospital, Daejeon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Myung-Mo</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Daejeon University, Daejeon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013716" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tennis Elbow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059408" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Management</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> None declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41736376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12951797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.951969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">951969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stegink-Jansen CW, Jung B, Somerson JS. Translation of Runge&#x2019;s 1873 publication &#x201c;On the etiology and treatment of writer&#x2019;s cramp&#x201d;: The first description of &#x201c;tennis elbow&#x201d;. Clin Anat. 2022;35(3):316&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34967051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraushaar BS, Nirschl RP. Tendinosis of the elbow (tennis elbow): Clinical features and findings of histological, immunohistochemical, and electron microscopy studies. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1999;81(2):259&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10073590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Wiesbusch M, Bisset L, et al. Adherence to therapeutic exercise for lateral elbow tendinopathy: A scoping review. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25:S66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38820868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiri R, Viikari-Juntura E, Varonen H, et al. Prevalence and determinants of lateral and medial epicondylitis: A population study. Am J Epidemiol. 2006;164(11):1065&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16968862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenoir H, Mares O, Carlier Y. Management of lateral epicondylitis. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2019;105(8):S241&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31543413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KS, Jang KU. Determining the degree of disability in workers with upper limb musculoskeletal disorders using DASH. J Ergon Soc Korea. 2010;29(3):311&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook J, Purdam CR. Is tendon pathology a continuum? Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(6):409&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18812414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasinopoulos D, Stasinopoulos I. Comparison of effects of eccentric training, eccentric-concentric training, and eccentric-concentric training combined with isometric contraction in the treatment of lateral elbow tendinopathy. J Hand Ther. 2017;30(1):13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27823901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Baker NA. Effectiveness of eccentric strengthening in the treatment of lateral elbow tendinopathy: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Hand Ther. 2021;34(1):18&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaugh B, Ihm JM. Eccentric training for the treatment of tendinopathies. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013;12(3):175&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza TMF, Libardi CA, Cavaglieri CR, et al. Concurrent training with blood flow restriction does not decrease inflammatory markers. Int J Sports Med. 2018;40(1):29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29121681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, et al. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(1):95&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman RJ, Brown SM, Savage-Elliott I, et al. Blood flow restriction training for athletes: A systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(7):1938&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Thrower AD, Balapur A, et al. Blood flow&#x2013;restricted walking does not result in an accumulation of metabolites. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2012;32(1):80&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles D, White R, Reyes C, et al. A systematic review of the effects of blood flow restriction training on quadriceps muscle atrophy and circumference post ACL reconstruction. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(6):882&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuddeford T, Brumitt J. In season rehabilitation program using blood flow restriction therapy for two decathletes with patellar tendinopathy: A case report. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(6):1184&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safford DW, Shah KM, McClure PW. Blood flow restriction training as an adjunct to conventional care in a patient with adhesive capsulitis and rotator cuff tendinopathy: A case report. JOSPT Cases. 2021;1(4):289&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisset LM, Collins NJ, Offord SS. Immediate effects of 2 types of braces on pain and grip strength in people with lateral epicondylalgia: A randomized controlled trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2014;44(2):120&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanasios S, Korakakis V, Moutzouri M, et al. Low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction is effective for managing lateral elbow tendinopathy: A randomized, sham-controlled trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52(12):803&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36099170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Uchida Y, et al. Effects of low-load, elastic band resistance training combined with blood flow restriction on muscle size and arterial stiffness in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2015;70(8):950&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes DZ, Weber VMR, da Silva MPA, et al. Effects of blood flow restriction training on handgrip strength and muscular volume of young women. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(6):901&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tennent DJ, Hylden CM, Johnson AE, et al. Blood flow restriction training after knee arthroscopy: A randomized controlled pilot study. Clin J Sport Med. 2017;27(3):245&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27749358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson M, Butler S, Eriksson M, et al. A randomized controlled trial of eccentric vs concentric graded exercise in chronic tennis elbow. Clin Rehabil. 2014;28(9):862&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24634444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung M-k, Jeon J-g, Shin E-j. Effects of multi-site and single-site functional massage and stretching on pain, tenderness threshold and grip strength in patients with lateral epicondylalgia. Korean Acad Ortho Man Phys Ther. 2023;29(3):13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafaee N, Divandari A, Negahban H, et al. Shoulder and scapula muscle training plus conventional physiotherapy versus conventional physiotherapy only: A randomized controlled trial of patients with lateral elbow tendinopathy. Physiother Theory Pract. 2022;38(9):1153&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz DS, Bailey L, Wilk KE, et al. Blood flow restriction training. J Athl Train. 2021;56(9):937&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34530434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, et al. Effects of blood flow restricted low-intensity concentric or eccentric training on muscle size and strength. PLoS One. 2012;7(12):e52843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3534116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23300795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts BR, Dankel SJ, Barnett BE, et al. Influence of relative blood flow restriction pressure on muscle activation and muscle adaptation. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(3):438&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26137897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker GA, Mian S, Kendzerska T, et al. Measures of adult pain: visual analog scale for pain, numeric rating scale for pain, McGill pain questionnaire, short-form McGill pain questionnaire, chronic pain grade scale, short form-36 bodily pain scale, and measure of intermittent and constant osteoarthritis pain. Arthritis Care Res. 2011;63(S11):S240&#x2013;S52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamwong P, Nosaka K, Pirunsan U, et al. Reliability of muscle function and sensory perception measurements of the wrist extensors. Physiother Theory Pract. 2010;26(6):408&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20658927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S-J, Lee SW. Rehabilitative ultrasound imaging findings of the change in the pennation angle of the extensor carpi radialis brevis in patients with tennis elbow. Indian J Sci Technol. 2015;8:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Liu Y, Lin T, et al. Reliability and validity of two hand dynamometers when used by community-dwelling adults aged over 50 years. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35840905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toemen A, Dalton S, Sandford F. The intra- and inter-rater reliability of manual muscle testing and a hand-held dynamometer for measuring wrist strength in symptomatic and asymptomatic subjects. Hand Ther. 2011;16(3):67&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDermid J. Update: The patient-rated forearm evaluation questionnaire is now the patient-rated tennis elbow evaluation. J Hand Ther. 2005;18(4):407&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16271687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turchin DC, Beaton DE, Richards RR. Validity of observer-based aggregate scoring systems as descriptors of elbow pain, function, and disability. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1998;80(2):154&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9486721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo M-K, Kim T-Y, Kim J-T, et al. Reliability and validity of the Korean version of the fear-avoidance beliefs questionnaire. Phys Ther Korea. 2009;16(2):24&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X, George ML, Kakouras I, et al. Reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the short form 12-item survey (SF-12) in patients with back pain. Spine. 2003;28(15):1739&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12897502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber C, Thai V, Neuheuser K, et al. Efficacy of physical therapy for the treatment of lateral epicondylitis: a meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015;16(1):223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4549077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>