<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41734359</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Playing Level and Position Influence Strength and Power Profiles in Female Rugby League Athletes?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005404</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brassington, RJ, Mara, JK, Ball, NB, Waddington, G, Paul, K, and Cooke, J. Does playing level and position influence strength and power profiles in female rugby league athletes? J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-The purpose of this study was to compare the physical characteristics and physical qualities of elite and subelite female rugby league athletes, with a focus on strength, power, and positional differences between forwards and backs. Fifty-one female athletes participated (subelite: n = 26, height: 167.1 &#xb1; 6.0 cm, mass: 69.1 &#xb1; 10.7 kg, age: 17.4 &#xb1; 0.5 years; elite: n = 25, height: 167.5 &#xb1; 6.3 cm, mass: 78.3 &#xb1; 12.6 kg, age: 23.6 &#xb1; 4.3 years). Assessments included anthropometry, 3-repetition maximum (3RM) trap bar deadlift (TBD), 3RM bench press (BP), countermovement jump (CMJ), squat jump (SJ), and drop jump (DJ) tests using dual force plates. Elite athletes demonstrated significantly greater maximal strength in the TBD (B = 39.84 kg [19.97, 59.72], p &lt; 0.001, ES = 1.75) and BP (B = 9.13 kg [-0.14, 18.41], p = 0.053, ES = 1.33). In the CMJ, elite players recorded greater peak power (B = 571.04 W [230.76, 911.33], p = 0.002, ES = 1.00) and longer eccentric and concentric durations (B = 43.37 ms [20.53, 66.22], p &lt; 0.001, ES = 1.62), reflecting distinct movement strategies. They also produced higher SJ jump height (B = 3.89 cm [0.98, 6.79], p = 0.01, ES = 1.36), peak power (B = 670.74 W [349.31, 992.16], p &lt; 0.001, ES = 1.62), and concentric impulse (B = 33.66 N&#xb7;s [17.76, 49.56], p &lt; 0.001, ES = 1.71). Drop jump results showed fewer differences, with level effects limited to concentric impulse (B = 34.01 N&#xb7;s [13.78, 54.22], p = 0.002, ES = 1.29). Positional effects indicated forwards were heavier (B = 9.10 kg [0.03, 18.2], p = 0.049, ES = 1.02) and produced greater SJ take-off force (B = 240.80 N [20.18, 461.43], p = 0.033, ES = 1.05). Elite female rugby league athletes display superior maximal strength, lower-body power, and distinct jump strategies compared with subelite players. These characteristics likely underpin the increased physical demands of elite competition. Strength and conditioning programs for subelite athletes should emphasize maximal strength, concentric impulse, and eccentric control, with position-specific emphasis on collision strength for forwards and reactive strength for backs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brassington</LastName><ForeName>Riley J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mara</LastName><ForeName>Jocelyn K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ball</LastName><ForeName>Nick B</ForeName><Initials>NB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waddington</LastName><ForeName>Gordon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Kiera</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooke</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiological characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">positional demands</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41734359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Addie C, Arnett J, Neltner T, et al. Effects of drop height on drop jump performance. Int J Kinesiol Sports Sci 7: 28&#x2013;32, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agar-Newman DJ, Goodale TL, Klimstra MD. Anthropometric and physical qualities of international level female rugby sevens athletes based on playing position. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1346&#x2013;1352, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attia A, Dhahbi W, Chaouachi A, et al. Measurement errors when estimating the vertical jump height with flight time using photocell devices: The example of Optojump. Biol Sport 34: 63&#x2013;70, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Nance S. The relation between running speed and measures of strength and power in professional Rugby League players. J Strength Cond Res 13: 230&#x2013;235, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DG, Newton RU. Comparison of lower body strength, power, acceleration, speed, agility, and sprint momentum to describe and compare playing rank among professional Rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 22: 153&#x2013;158, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball NB, Stock CG, Scurr JC. Bilateral contact ground reaction forces and contact times during plyometric drop jumping. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2762&#x2013;2769, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black GM, Gabbett TJ, Johnston RD, et al. The influence of physical qualities on activity profiles of female Australian football match play. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 524&#x2013;529, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabarkapa D, Cabarkapa DV, Nagy D, et al. Differences in anthropometric and vertical jump force-time characteristics between U16 and U18 female basketball players. Front Sports Active Living 6: 1&#x2013;7, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collings TJ, Lima YL, Dutaillis B, Bourne MN. Concurrent validity and test-retest reliability of VALD ForceDecks' strength, balance, and movement assessment tests. J Sci Med Sport 27: 572&#x2013;580, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Graham-Smith P, Matthews MJ, Bamber C. Strength and power characteristics in English elite Rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1374&#x2013;1384, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins C, Orr R. Analysis of physical collisions in elite National Rugby League match play. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 732&#x2013;739, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins C, Melinz J, King DA, Sanctuary C, Murphy AJ. Call to action: A collaborative framework to better support female rugby league players. Br J Sports Med 54: 501&#x2013;502, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins C, Charlton G, Paul D, et al. Women&#x2019;s rugby league: Positional groups and peak locomotor demands. Front Sports Act Living 3: 1&#x2013;6, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle B, Browne D, Horan D. Differences in anthropometric and physical performance characteristics between U17, U19, and senior Irish female international football players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 16: 352&#x2013;359, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes JFT, Daniels M, Myler L, Twist C. Influence of playing standard on upper- and lower-body strength, power, and velocity characteristics of elite rugby league players. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 4: 1&#x2013;11, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan EP, Comyns TM. The use of contact time and the reactive strength index to optimize fast stretch-shortening cycle training. Strength Cond J 30: 32&#x2013;38, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flannery L, Secomb JL, West MA, Compton HR, Dascombe BJ. The strength and power profile of junior and senior female rugby league athletes. J Strength Cond Res 38: 2129&#x2013;2135, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Hulin BT. Activity and recovery cycles and skill involvements of successful and unsuccessful elite rugby league teams: A longitudinal analysis of evolutionary changes in National Rugby League match-play. J Sports Sci 36: 180&#x2013;190, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Seibold AJ. Relationship between tests of physical qualities, team selection, and physical match performance in semiprofessional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 27: 3259&#x2013;3265, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Abernethy B. Physiological and anthropometric correlates of tackling ability in junior elite and subelite rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2989&#x2013;2995, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Abernethy B. Correlates of tackling ability in high-performance rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 25: 72&#x2013;79, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Abernethy B. Relationships between physiological, anthropometric, and skill qualities and playing performance in professional rugby league players. J Sports Sci 29: 1655&#x2013;1664, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Abernethy B. Relative importance of physiological, anthropometric, and skill qualities to team selection in professional rugby league. J Sports Sci 29: 1453&#x2013;1461, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Physiological and anthropometric characteristics of amateur rugby league players. Br J Sports Med 34: 303&#x2013;307, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Influence of physiological characteristics on selection in a semi-professional first grade rugby league team: A case study. J Sports Sci 20: 399&#x2013;405, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Physiological characteristics of junior and senior rugby league players. Br J Sports Med 36: 334&#x2013;339, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Physiological and anthropometric characteristics of elite women rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 21: 875&#x2013;881, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Physiological and anthropometric correlates of tackling ability in rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 23: 540&#x2013;548, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Quantifying the physical demands of collision sports: Does microsensor technology measure what it claims to measure? J Strength Cond Res 27: 2319&#x2013;2322, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Influence of playing standard on the physical demands of junior rugby league tournament match-play. J Sci Med Sport 17: 212&#x2013;217, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geeson-Brown T, Jones B, Till K, Chantler S, Deighton K. Body composition differences by age and playing standard in male Rugby union and Rugby league: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 38: 2161&#x2013;2176, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glassbrook DJ, Doyle TLA, Alderson JA, Fuller JT. The demands of professional Rugby league match-play: A meta-analysis. Sports Med Open 5: 1&#x2013;20, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodale TL, Gabbett TJ, Stellingwerff T, Tsai MC, Sheppard JM. Relationship between physical qualities and minutes played in international women's rugby sevens. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 489&#x2013;494, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test-retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 6: 1&#x2013;16, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulbin JP, Croser MJ, Morley EJ, Weissensteiner JR. An integrated framework for the optimisation of sport and athlete development: A practitioner approach. J Sports Sci 31: 1319&#x2013;1331, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gundersen AH, van den Tillaar R, Falch HN, Fredriksen AB, Larsen S. A biomechanical comparison between conventional, sumo, and hex-bar deadlifts among resistance trained women. J Strength Cond Res 39: 281&#x2013;288, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyward O, McCormack S, Emmonds S, et al. Strength and speed characteristics of women's super league players. In: 2019 NSCA National Conference, Washington DC, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Samozino P, Brughelli M, Morin JB. Effectiveness of an individualized training based on force-velocity profiling during jumping. Frontier Physiol 7: 1&#x2013;13, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston R, Gabbett T, Jenkins D. Applied sport science of Rugby league. Sports Med (Auckl NZ) 44: 1087&#x2013;1100, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones B, Till K, Barlow M, et al. Anthropometric and three-compartment body composition differences between super league and championship Rugby League players: Considerations for the 2015 season and beyond. PLoS One 10: 1&#x2013;11, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones B, Emmonds S, Hind K, et al. Physical qualities of international female Rugby league players by playing position. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1333&#x2013;1340, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy RA, Drake D. Improving the signal-to-noise ratio when monitoring countermovement jump performance. J Strength Cond Res 35: 85&#x2013;90, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King DA, Clark TN, Hume PA, Hind K. Match and training injury incidence in rugby league: A systematic review, pooled analysis, and update on published studies. Sports Med Health Sci 4: 75&#x2013;84, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropractic Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzyszkowski J, Chowning LD, Harry JR. Phase-specific predictors of countermovement jump performance that distinguish good from poor jumpers. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1257&#x2013;1263, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauersen JB, Andersen TE, Andersen LB. Strength training as superior, dose-dependent and safe prevention of acute and overuse sports injuries: A systematic review, qualitative analysis and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 52: 1557&#x2013;1563, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth RV. Emmeans: Estimated marginal means, aka least-squares means (R package version 2.0.0). J Stat Software 2024. https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=emmeans.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne NP. Analysis of standing vertical jumps using a force platform. Am J Phys 69: 1198&#x2013;1204, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonergan B, Cohen DD, Williams S, et al. Inter-day reliability of countermovement jump metrics in elite academy soccer players. Int J Strength Cond 5: 1&#x2013;11, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Pereira LA, Moraes JE, et al. Jump-squat and half-squat exercises: Selective influences on speed-power performance of elite rugby sevens players. PLoS One 12: 1&#x2013;11, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ, Gill ND. Strength and power profiling of athletes: Selecting tests and how to use the information for program design. Strength Cond J 35: 7&#x2013;14, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Lake JP, Ripley NJ, Comfort P. Vertical jump testing in rugby league: A rationale for calculating take-off momentum. J Appl Biomech 36: 370&#x2013;374, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Lake JP, Comfort P. Identifying and reporting position-specific countermovement jump outcome and phase characteristics within rugby league. PLoS One 17: 1&#x2013;15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Lake JP, Dos'Santos T, et al. Countermovement jump standards in Rugby league: What is a &#x201c;Good&#x201d; performance? J Strength Cond Res 36: 1691&#x2013;1698, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meir R, Newton R, Curtis E, Fardell M, Butler B. Physical fitness qualities of professional rugby league football players: Determination of positional differences. J Strength Cond Res 15: 450&#x2013;458, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minahan CL, Newans T, Quinn KM, et al. Strong, fast, fit, lean, and safe: A positional comparison of physical and physiological qualities within the 2020 Australian women's rugby league team. J Strength Cond Res 35: S11&#x2013;S19, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Samozino P. Interpreting power-force-velocity profiles for individualized and specific training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 267&#x2013;272, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin JB, Edouard P, Samozino P. Technical ability of force application as a determinant factor of sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1680&#x2013;1688, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Protocols for the Assessment of Strength and Power. Australian Institute of Sport &amp; National/State Institutes and Academy of Sport, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson B, Dinsdale A, Jones B, Till K. Sprint and jump mechanical profiles in academy Rugby league players: Positional differences and the associations between profiles and sprint performance. Sports (Basel) 9: 1&#x2013;18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Thapa RK, Afonso J, et al. Effects of plyometric jump training on the reactive strength index in healthy individuals across the lifespan: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 53: 1029&#x2013;1053, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Kelly VG, Connick MJ, Beckman EM. Predicting Rugby league tackle outcomes using strength and power principal components. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 278&#x2013;285, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 20: S135&#x2013;S145, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samozino P, Edouard P, Sangnier S, et al. Force-velocity profile: Imbalance determination and effect on lower limb ballistic performance. Int J Sports Med 35: 505&#x2013;510, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savolainen EHJ, Ihalainen JK, Weckstr&#xf6;m K, V&#xe4;nttinen T, Walker S. Female football players' key physical qualities: Playing-position specific comparison between national-team selected and non-selected players. Biol Sport 42: 109&#x2013;117, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scantlebury S, McCormack S, Sawczuk T, et al. The anthropometric and physical qualities of women&#x2019;s rugby league Super League and international players; identifying differences in playing position and level. PLoS One 17: 1&#x2013;13, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scantlebury S, Ramirez C, Cummins C, et al. Injury risk factors and barriers to their mitigation for women playing Rugby league: A Delphi study. J Sports Sci 40: 1436&#x2013;1449, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirotic AC, Coutts AJ, Knowles H, Catterick C. A comparison of match demands between elite and semi-elite Rugby league competition. J Sports Sci 27: 203&#x2013;211, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirotic AC, Knowles H, Catterick C, Coutts AJ. Positional match demands of professional Rugby league competition. J Strength Cond Res 25: 3076&#x2013;3087, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleivert G, Taingahue M. The relationship between maximal jump-squat power and sprint acceleration in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 46&#x2013;52, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JC, Lamont HS, Barefoot M. Comparison of different take-off thresholds when assessing vertical jump performance. Int J Exerc Sci 17: 660&#x2013;668, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southey B, Willshire M, Connick MJ, et al. Reactive strength index as a key performance indicator in different athlete populations&#x2014;A systematic review. Sci Sports 39: 129&#x2013;143, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taube W, Leukel C, Lauber B, Gollhofer A. The drop height determines neuromuscular adaptations and changes in jump performance in stretch-shortening cycle training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 22: 671&#x2013;683, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Till K, Scantlebury S, Jones B. Anthropometric and physical qualities of elite male youth Rugby league players. Sports Med 47: 2171&#x2013;2186, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods CT, Robertson S, Sinclair WH, Collier NF. Non-metric multidimensional performance indicator scaling reveals seasonal and team dissimilarity within the National Rugby League. J Sci Med Sport 21: 410&#x2013;415, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao X, Curtis C, Turner A, et al. Anthropometric profiles and physical characteristics in competitive female English Premiership Rugby Union Players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 1234&#x2013;1241, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>