<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41348763</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influencing factors and optimization paths of teachers' fulfillment of school bullying governance responsibilities in China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0319640</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0319640</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0319640</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0319640</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effective fulfillment of teachers' responsibilities is crucial to the governance of school bullying. Guided by Grounded Theory and utilizing NVivo11 qualitative analysis software, this paper used 316 texts from 55 cases of school bullying in China to conduct open coding, spindle coding and selective coding, analyzed the behavior of teachers, explored the impetus factors and resistance factors influencing teachers' fulfillment of their responsibilities, and constructed a "two-factors model". The reasons why these factors in the model affect school bullying governance responsibility of teachers were analyzed through Street-Level Bureaucracy Theory. On the one hand, teachers are legally obligated to provide fair and equitable educational services to students. The media and the public are important forces in monitoring teachers' fulfillment of their responsibilities. Additionally, leaders from school and the local government such as police department utilize interdependency and gaming relationships with teachers to promote teachers' fulfillment of their responsibilities. Furthermore, the formulation of laws and policies is an important basis for supervising teachers' behavior. These factors collectively promote teachers' fulfillment of school bullying governance responsibilities. On the other hand, teachers have discretion and are difficult to supervise and hold accountable. The interests of different governance subjects may diverge or conflict. Moreover, the complexity and diversity of school bullying exacerbate governance challenges. Furthermore, systems such as laws and policies often fall short in restraining undesirable behavior. These reasons present obstacles to teachers' fulfilling their responsibilities of school bullying governance. In order to strengthen the impetus factors for teachers to fulfill their responsibilities and mitigate resistance, China needs to optimize the governance path. This involves improving the relevant systems, enhancing publicity, providing education and training for teachers, strengthening the supervision of the local government, the media and the public on teachers, and improving the overall governance environment for school bullying. These measures will encourage teachers to hold themselves to higher standards and effectively fulfill their responsibilities in the governance process of school bullying.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Li et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Fuyu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1072-8983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Criminal Investigation and Counter-Terrorism College, Research Center of National Security Governance, Criminal Investigation Police University of China, Shenyang, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Marxism, Shihezi University, Shihezi, Xinjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Shifang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Humanities and Law, Northeastern University, Shenyang, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Haibo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Marxism, Wenzhou University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058445" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bullying</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070777" MajorTopicYN="Y">School Teachers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012574" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schools</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41348763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12680240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0319640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-23-36318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>UNESCO. School violence and bullying global status report. UNESCO. 2017. http://unesdoc.unesco.org/images/0024/002469/246970e.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Educational Statistics. Student reports of bullying: Results from the 2017 school crime supplement to the national crime victimization survey. 2019. https://nces.ed.gov/pubs2019/20190504.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olweus D. School bullying: development and some important challenges. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2013;9:751&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-050212-185516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-050212-185516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23297789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennehy R, Meaney S, Walsh KA, Sinnott C, Cronin M, Arensman E. Young people&#x2019;s conceptualizations of the nature of cyberbullying: A systematic review and synthesis of qualitative research. Aggression and Violent Behavior. 2020;51:101379. doi: 10.1016/j.avb.2020.101379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avb.2020.101379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y, Yang Y, Lin P, Xiao Y, Sun Y, Qian Y, et al. School Bullying Victimization and Associated Factors Among School-Aged Adolescents in China. J Interpers Violence. 2023;38(1&#x2013;2):NP1787&#x2013;814. doi: 10.1177/08862605221092074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08862605221092074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35475706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess Dowdell E, Noel J. Risk behavior of high school students who report knowing someone who self-harms. Issues in Mental Health Nursing. 2020;41(5):415&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31944136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carretero Bermejo R, Nolasco Hern&#xe1;ndez A, S&#xe1;nchez LG. Study of the Relationship of Bullying with the Levels of Eudaemonic Psychological Well-Being in Victims and Aggressors. Sustainability. 2022;14(9):5609. doi: 10.3390/su14095609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14095609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arseneault L. Annual Research Review: The persistent and pervasive impact of being bullied in childhood and adolescence: implications for policy and practice. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2018;59(4):405&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1111/jcpp.12841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpp.12841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29134659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husky MM, Bitfoi A, Carta MG, Goelitz D, Ko&#xe7; C, Lesinskiene S, et al. Bullying involvement and suicidal ideation in elementary school children across Europe. J Affect Disord. 2022;299:281&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2021.12.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.12.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34915081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>deLara EW. Consequences of Childhood Bullying on Mental Health and Relationships for Young Adults. J Child Fam Stud. 2018;28(9):2379&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1007/s10826-018-1197-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10826-018-1197-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H, Cao L, Xu B, Li Y, Xie J, Wang J, et al. Involvement in bullying and sleep disorders in Chinese early adolescents. Front Psychiatry. 2023;14:1115561. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1115561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1115561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10172573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37181869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamoto J, Schwartz D. The association between peer victimization and functioning at school among urban Latino children. Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology. 2011;32(3):89&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/j.appdev.2011.02.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appdev.2011.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juvonen J, Yueyan Wang, Espinoza G. Bullying Experiences and Compromised Academic Performance Across Middle School Grades. The Journal of Early Adolescence. 2010;31(1):152&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1177/0272431610379415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272431610379415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski RM, Limber SP, McCord A. A developmental approach to cyberbullying: Prevalence and protective factors. Aggression and Violent Behavior. 2019;45:20&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.avb.2018.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avb.2018.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer A. Room for Me: An Analysis of Whether Mediation Is a Viable Solution to School Bullying. Cardozo Journal of Conflict Resolution. 2014;16(1):224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNESCO. Behind the Numbers: Ending School Violence and Bullying. 2019. https://www.dge.mec.pt/sites/default/files/ERTE/pdf_unesco.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianlong Y. China&#x2019;s path to prevent student bullying: Comment on the recent policies to combat school bullying. Journal of Chinese Youth Social Science. 2017;36(1):22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Y, Ning L, Weiwei C, Jiani T, Mengjie Z, Lijun Z, et al. Relationship between middle school students&#x2019; bullying behavior and family environment and education style. Chinese Journal of School Health. 2023;44(2):234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Supreme People&#x2019;s Procuratorate of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. The white paper on juvenile procuratorial work. 2023. https://www.spp.gov.cn/xwfbh/wsfbt/202306/t20230601_615967.shtml#2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan G, Zhouzhuo F, Guirong Z. Risk analysis of campus security incidents. Beijing, China: China Social Sciences Press. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuxiang W, Yanying W. Characteristics and Attribution of Internetbullying among Teenagers. Journal of Chinese Youth Social Science. 2021;40(2):71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dongmei L, Yunlong H, Shuyuan W. Research on strategy of improving teachers&#x2019; response to adolescent cyberbullying through an investigation. Teacher Education Research. 2021;2:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stien N. Bullying or sexual harassment? The missing discourse of rights in an era of zero tolerance. Arizona Law Review. 2003;45(3):785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbaugh KB. Bullying prevention and boyhood. Boston University Law Review. 2013;93(3):1029&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roland E. The broken curve: Effects of the Norwegian manifesto against bullying. International Journal of Behavioral Development. 2011;35(5):383&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1177/0165025411407454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0165025411407454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olweus D. Bullying at school and later criminality: findings from three Swedish community samples of males. Crim Behav Ment Health. 2011;21(2):151&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1002/cbm.806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbm.806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21370301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PK, Mahdavi J, Carvalho M, Fisher S, Russell S, Tippett N. Cyberbullying: its nature and impact in secondary school pupils. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2008;49(4):376&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7610.2007.01846.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7610.2007.01846.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18363945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang F. Policy and reflection on local government promoting bullying management on campus: Analysis based on the texts of bullying policies in 17 districts. Theory and Practice of Education. 2019;39(28):27&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishna F, Sanders JE, McNeil S, Fearing G, Kalenteridis K. &#x201c;If Somebody is Different&#x201d;: A critical analysis of parent, teacher and student perspectives on bullying and cyberbullying. Children and Youth Services Review. 2020;118:105366. doi: 10.1016/j.childyouth.2020.105366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.childyouth.2020.105366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eroglu M, Gunay Kilic B. Peer bullying among children with autism spectrum disorder in formal education settings: Data from Turkey. Research in Autism Spectrum Disorders. 2020;75:101572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennell D, Campbell M, Tangen D, Runions K, Brooks J, Cross D. Facilitators and barriers to the implementation of motivational interviewing for bullying perpetration in school settings. Scand J Psychol. 2020;61(1):143&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1111/sjop.12502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sjop.12502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30536868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang A. An exploration on the school tort liability of school bullying. Journal of Chinese Youth Social Science. 2017;36(5):102&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foody M, Murphy H, Downes P, O&#x2019;Higgins Norman J. Anti-bullying procedures for schools in Ireland: principals&#x2019; responses and perceptions. Pastoral Care in Education. 2018;36(2):126&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1080/02643944.2018.1453859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02643944.2018.1453859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan O. Bullying at school: what we know and what we can do. Oxford, UK: Blackwell. 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middlemiss S. Legal protection for school pupils who are victims of bullying in the United Kingdom?. Education Law Journal. 2012;4:237&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lijun X. The legal responsibility of schools and teachers in school bullying and their avoidance strategies. Primary and Secondary School Management. 2016;8:15&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuesta I, Montes&#xf3;-Curto P, Metzler Sawin E, Jim&#xe9;nez-Herrera M, Puig-Llobet M, Seabra P, et al. Risk factors for teen suicide and bullying: An international integrative review. Int J Nurs Pract. 2021;27(3):e12930. doi: 10.1111/ijn.12930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijn.12930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33830586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel MS, Eric JF. School and law enforcement efforts to combat cyberbullying. Preventing School Failure. 2011;55(2):81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan D. Promotion of the government preventive duties in anti-bullying socialized system from the perspective of government purchasing educational services. Contemporary Youth Research. 2020;1:91&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawes M, Gariton C, Starrett A, Irdam G, Irvin MJ. Preservice Teachers&#x2019; Knowledge and Attitudes Toward Bullying: A Systematic Review. Review of Educational Research. 2023;93(2):195&#x2013;235. doi: 10.3102/00346543221094081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/00346543221094081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantus S, Newman PA. Promoting a positive school climate for sexual and gender minority youth through a systems approach: A theory-informed qualitative study. Am J Orthopsychiatry. 2021;91(1):9&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1037/ort0000513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/ort0000513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huihui W, Eryong X. Governance confusion and system design of school bullying. Social Science Front. 2021;3:233&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caina L, Haishan Z. Teachers&#x2019; role construction in the prevention and intervention of school bullying. Journal of Beijing Normal University (Social Sciences). 2023;2:128&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert KY. Case study research: design and methods. Chongqing, China: Chongqing University Press. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhenbo W. An overview and critique of the domestic case study method. Journal of Management Case Studies. 2022;15(3):337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerry D. Journal of the Medical Library Association. 2022;110(2):270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael L. Street-level Bureaucracy: Dilemmas of the Individual in Public Services. New York: Russell Sage Foundation, USA, 2010. 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore ST. The Theory of Street-Level Bureaucracy. Administration &amp; Society. 1987;19(1):74&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1177/009539978701900104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/009539978701900104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deborah R. Street-level bureaucrats and the welfare state: toward a micro-institutionalist theory of policy implementation. Administration &amp; Society. 2012;45(9):1038&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haitao R. The definition of school bullying and its legal liability. Journal of East China Normal University (Educational Sciences). 2017;2:43&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klanien&#x117; I, Bra&#x17e;inskien&#x117;-Gru&#x17e;ausk&#x117; A. Social pedagogical assistance for students who experience bullying situations at school. SIE. 2021;3:292&#x2013;304. doi: 10.17770/sie2021vol3.6299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17770/sie2021vol3.6299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanrikulu I. Teacher reports on early childhood bullying: how often, who, what, when and where. Early Child Development and Care. 2018;190(4):489&#x2013;501. doi: 10.1080/03004430.2018.1479404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03004430.2018.1479404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sticks CG. Sticks and stones have remedies at law-it is name-calling that hurts kids: Can state anti-bullying statutes really help kids who are victims of in-school bullying. Journal of Law and Social Challenges. 2002;4:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez I, Ruiz-Esteban C, Ortega E. Impact of the Physical Activity on Bullying. Front Psychol. 2019;10:1520. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6614442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Zhang D, Shao HL. The softening of Chinese digital propaganda: Evidence from the People&#x2019;s Daily Weibo account during the pandemic. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1049671. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1049671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1049671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10013709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36925586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asomah JY. What role do social accountability actors play in resisting media capture in sub-Saharan Africa? Evidence from Ghana. Third World Quarterly. 2022;43(8):2025&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1080/01436597.2022.2077185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01436597.2022.2077185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B, Li Q. Research on Supervision Mechanism of Big Data Discriminatory Pricing on the Asymmetric Service Platform&#x2014;Based on SD Evolutionary Game Model. JTAER. 2022;17(4):1243&#x2013;63. doi: 10.3390/jtaer17040063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jtaer17040063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriela CG. Bullying, Teaching Action and School Responsibility. Andamios. 2020;17(43):345&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles D, Yale R, Magrass. Bully nation: how the American establishment creates a bullying society. Beijing, China: Xinhua Publishing House. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L. The school bullying behavior in primary and middle schools and their influencing factors. Youth Studies. 2020;6:24&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amar-Rodr&#xed;guez V. El ciberacoso. Una aproximaci&#xf3;n a la opini&#xf3;n del alumnado de Educaci&#xf3;n Primaria. Revista Colombiana de Educaci&#xf3;n. 2021;1(83):1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>