<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41635476</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surgery resident pain knowledge and perceptions: gaps and implications for medical training in Canada.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1392</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1392</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1392</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001392</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Healthcare provider pain knowledge is critical in surgical settings, where effective pain management plays a key role in the prevention of chronic postsurgical pain. Despite this, little is known about the pain training and knowledge of surgical residents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To comprehensively assess Canadian surgery residents' knowledge and attitudes toward pain - including associated factors, training sources, understanding of biopsychosocial and pediatric pain management, and perceived preparedness for managing pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">General and orthopedic surgery residents (N = 110, median age = 29.9 years) recruited from 27 accredited residency programs across Canada completed measures of pain training, perceptions, and experience as well as the Knowledge and Attitudes Survey Regarding Pain (KASRP)-a validated 41-item measure of provider pain knowledge. Descriptive statistics examined overall pain knowledge (% correct on the KASRP), pain knowledge sources and training, perceived preparedness, personal pain experiences, and knowledge of the biopsychosocial model. Multiple linear regression examined resident factors (eg, sex, speciality) associated with increased pain knowledge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Residents scored 75.1% (<i>SD</i> = 8.6, range = 43.9-95.1) on average on the KASRP-which is below the 80% passing score. Three items pertaining to opioid tolerance and opioid administration were answered incorrectly by &gt;70% of residents. In contrast, an average correct score of 86.5% was obtained on pediatric pain knowledge items. Personal experience with postsurgical pain was associated with greater overall pain knowledge (<i>&#x3b2;</i> = 0.24, <i>P</i> = 0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Canadian surgery residents demonstrated pain knowledge below the level generally considered adequate among health care providers, with areas of relative strength and gaps in knowledge identified. Collectively, these results underscore the importance of expanding both the breadth and depth of surgery residents' pain education and training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burcheri</LastName><ForeName>Adam J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Concordia University, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galvin</LastName><ForeName>Claire R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Concordia University, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pich&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Nelson</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Sainte-Justine, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frett</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Anesthesiology, St. Jude Children's Research Hospital, Memphis, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alschuler</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alberts</LastName><ForeName>Nicole M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7159-8156</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Concordia University, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postgraduate medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflict of interest to declare.Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41635476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12863863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-25-0101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al Omari O. Knowledge and attitudes of Jordanian nursing students toward children's pain assessment and management: a cross-sectional study. JNEP 2015;6:p51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Quliti KW, Alamri MS. Assessment of pain: knowledge, attitudes, and practices of health care providers in Almadinah Almunawwarah, Saudi Arabia. NSJ 2015;20:131&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4727624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25864065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameringer S, Fisher D, Sreedhar S, Ketchum JM, Yanni L. Pediatric pain management education in medical students: impact of a web-based module. J Palliat Med 2012;15:978&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22747064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin JA, Sierpina VS, Forys K, Clarridge B. Integration of the biopsychosocial model: perspectives of medical students and residents. Acad Med 2008;83:20&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18162746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Baeyer CL, Stevens BJ, Craig KD, Finley GA, Johnston CC, Grunau RVE, Chambers CT, Pillai Riddell RR, Stinson JN, McGrath PJ. Pain in child health from 2002 to 2015: the early years of an international research training initiative. Can J Pain 2019;3:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8730544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35005389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blyth FM, Huckel Schneider C. Global burden of pain and global pain policy&#x2014;creating a purposeful body of evidence. PAIN 2018;159:S43&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Residency Match Service (CaRMS). Quota and applications by discipline. Available at: https://www.carms.ca/data-reports/r1-data-reports/r-1-match-interactive-data/. Accessed July 3, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;novas L, Carrascosa A-J, Garc&#xed;a M, Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Calvo A, Monsalve V, Soriano J-F, Empathy Study Group. Impact of empathy in the patient-doctor relationship on chronic pain relief and quality of life: a prospective study in Spanish pain clinics. Pain Med 2018;19:1304&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers CT, Dol J, Tutelman PR, Langley CL, Parker JA, Cormier BT, Macfarlane GJ, Jones GT, Chapman D, Proudfoot N, Grant A, Marianayagam J. The prevalence of chronic pain in children and adolescents: a systematic review update and meta-analysis. PAIN 2024;165:2215&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11404345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38743558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen I, Goodman B, Galicia-Castillo M, Quidgley-Nevares A, Krebs M, Gliva-McConvey G. The EVMS pain education initiative: a multifaceted approach to resident education. J Pain 2007;8:152&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16949879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeland CS, Cleeland LM, Dar R, Rinehardt LC. Factors influencing physician management of cancer pain. Cancer 1986;58:796&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2873882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correll D. Chronic postoperative pain: recent findings in understanding and management. F1000Research 2017;6:1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5499782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuff PA, Vanselow NA. Committee on Behavioral and Social Sciences in Medical School Curricula. Improving medical education: Enhancing the behavioral and social science content of medical school curricula. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20669422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Carr DB, Schatman ME. Pain psychology and the biopsychosocial model of pain treatment: ethical imperatives and social responsibility. Pain Med 2017;18:1413&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5914334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27425187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmalingam TK, Muniandy RK. Doctors' knowledge and attitudes on pain assessment and management in Queen Elizabeth Hospital, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah. Med J Malaysia 2020;75:68&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Chiaro B, Sweigert PJ, Patel PP, Kabaker AS. Many medical students applying for surgical residency feel inadequately prepared to prescribe post-operative opioids. Am J Surg 2020;219:411&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31727260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillman DA, Smyth JD, Christian LM. Internet, phone, mail, and mixed-mode surveys: The tailored design method. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott TE, Murray DM, Elliott BA, Braun B, Oken MM, Johnson KM, Post-White J, Lichtblau L. Physician knowledge and attitudes about cancer pain management: a survey from the Minnesota cancer pain project. J Pain Symptom Manage 1995;10:494&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8537691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellison HB, Young KA, Van Enkevort EA, Davis MP, Falcone JL. Broad needs assessment of pain education in graduate medical education. J Pain Symptom Manage 2022;63:e451&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34856336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel GL. The clinical application of the biopsychosocial model. J Med Philos 1981;6:101&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7264472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenta E, Kibret S, Hunie M, Tamire T, Eshetie D, Seid S, Fentie Y, Amaha E, Desse T, Dejen B, Essa K, Teshome D. Nurses' knowledge and attitude towards children pain management: a multi-site survey study. Front Pediatr 2023;11:1182529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37425257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrell BR, McCaffery M. Knowledge and attitudes survey regarding pain (KASRP), 2014. Available at: https://prc.coh.org/Knowldege%20%20%26%20Attitude%20Survey%207-14.pdf. Accessed January 21, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finestone AS, Raveh A, Mirovsky Y, Lahad A, Milgrom C. Orthopaedists' and family practitioners' knowledge of simple low back pain management. Spine 2009;34:1600&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullen BM, Baxter GD, O'Donovan BGG, Doody C, Daly L, Hurley DA. Doctors' attitudes and beliefs regarding acute low back pain management: a systematic review. PAIN 2008;136:388&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia J, Ohanisian L, Sidley A, Ferris A, Luck G, Basich G, Garcia A. Resident knowledge and perception of pain management. Cureus 2019;11:e6107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6901364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31886047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatchel RJ, Peng YB, Peters ML, Fuchs PN, Turk DC. The biopsychosocial approach to chronic pain: scientific advances and future directions. Psychol Bull 2007;133:581&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerbershagen HJ, Aduckathil S, van Wijck AJM, Peelen LM, Kalkman CJ, Meissner W. Pain intensity on the first day after SurgeryA prospective cohort study comparing 179 surgical procedures. Anesthesiology 2013;118:934&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23392233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg DS, McGee SJ. Pain as a global public health priority. BMC Public Health 2011;11:770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3201926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21978149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon DB, Dahl JL, Miaskowski C, McCarberg B, Todd KH, Paice JA, Lipman AG, Bookbinder M, Sanders SH, Turk DC, Carr DB. American Pain Society recommendations for improving the quality of acute and cancer pain management: American Pain Society quality of care task force. Arch Int Med 2005;165:1574&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16043674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CR, Wheeler JRC, Marchant B, LaPorte F, Guerrero E. Analysis of the physician variable in pain management. Pain Med 2001;2:317&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Canadian pain task force report: June 2019, 2019. Available at: https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/corporate/about-health-canada/public-engagement/external-advisory-bodies/canadian-pain-task-force/report-2019.html. Accessed March 23, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Canadian pain task force report: March 2021, 2021. Available at: https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/corporate/about-health-canada/public-engagement/external-advisory-bodies/canadian-pain-task-force/report-2021.html. Accessed February 6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Standards Organization. HSO and SKIP release the first pediatric pain management standard. Available at: https://healthstandards.org/uncategorized/hso-and-skip-release-the-first-pediatric-pain-management-standard/. Accessed April 12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudon A, Augeard N, Tansey CM, Houston E, Bostick G, Wideman TH. Does feeling pain help prepare future clinicians to treat pain? A qualitative exploration of a novel experiential approach to teaching health professional students about pain. Physiother Theor Pract 2024;40:2550&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37682624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IBM SPSS statistics for Mac. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson T, Thomas S, Stabile V, Han X, Shotwell M, McQueen K. Prevalence of chronic pain in low-income and middle-income countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet 2015;385:S10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26313056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaini PA, Lee JS-H. A review of 21st century utility of a biopsychosocial model in United States medical school education. J Lifestyle Med 2015;5:49&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4711959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26770891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalloo C, Mohabir V, Campbell F, Sun N, Klein S, Tyrrell J, Mesaroli G, Ataollahi-Eshqoor S, Osei-Twum J, Stinson J. Pediatric project ECHO&#xae; for pain: implementation and mixed methods evaluation of a virtual medical education program to support interprofessional pain management in children and youth. BMC Med Educ 2023;23:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9883812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36709273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeser JD, Schatman ME. Chronic pain management in medical education: a disastrous omission. Postgrad Med 2017;129:332&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28276788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manworren RCB, Basco M. Effectiveness and dissemination of the interprofessional pediatric pain PRN curriculum. J Contin Educ Health Prof 2022;42:135&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9133003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manworren RCB, Laprise J. Development of the pediatric healthcare provider's knowledge and attitudes survey regarding pain. Pediatr Nurs 2021;47:275&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moceri JT, Drevdahl DJ. Nurses' knowledge and attitudes toward pain in the emergency department. J Emerg Nurs 2014;40:6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22841012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley-Forster PK, Clark AJ, Speechley M, Moulin DE. Attitudes toward opioid use for chronic pain: a Canadian physician survey. Pain Res Manag 2003;8:189&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14679412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine. The role of nonpharmacological approaches to pain management: Proceedings of a workshop. Washington, DC: National Academies Press, 2019. doi: 10.17226/25406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17226/25406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31145569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines. National comprehensive cancer network, 2014. Available at: https://www.nccn.org/guidelines/nccn-guidelines. Accessed April 20, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen AT, Dang AK, Nguyen HTT, Nguyen TX, Nguyen TN, Nguyen TTH, Pham T, Nguyen AL, Nguyen TTN, Nguyen Thi H, Nguyen TH, Nguyen SH, Tran BX, Latkin C, Ho RC, Ho CS, Vu HTT. Assessing knowledge and attitudes regarding pain management among nurses working in a geriatric hospital in Vietnam. JMDH 2021;14:799&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8052125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz MI, Cuevas-Su&#xe1;rez CE, Cari&#xf1;o-Cort&#xe9;s R, Navarrete-Hern&#xe1;ndez JdJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Montiel CA. Nurses knowledge and attitude regarding pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nurse Educ Pract 2022;63:103390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35803183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pag&#xe9; G, Stinson J, Campbell F, Isaac L, Katz J. Identification of pain-related psychological risk factors for the development and maintenance of pediatric chronic postsurgical pain. J Pain Res 2013;6:167&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23503375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provenzano DA, Kamal KM, Giannetti V. Evaluation of primary care physician chronic pain management practice patterns. Pain Physician 2018;21:E593&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30508990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabey M, Slater H, Hebron C, Moloney N. Societal beliefs about pain may be more balanced than previously thought. Results of the Guernsey pain survey. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2024;25:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38238802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice ASC, Smith BH, Blyth FM. Pain and the global burden of disease. PAIN 2016;157:791&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbloom BN, Pag&#xe9; MG, Isaac L, Campbell F, Stinson JN, Wright JG, Katz J. Pediatric chronic postsurgical pain and functional disability: a prospective study of risk factors up to one year after major surgery. J Pain Res 2019;12:3079&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31814752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seers T, Derry S, Seers K, Moore RA. Professionals underestimate patients' pain: a comprehensive review. PAIN 2018;159:811&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shipton EE, Bate F, Garrick R, Steketee C, Shipton EA, Visser EJ. Systematic review of pain medicine content, teaching, and assessment in medical school curricula internationally. Pain Ther 2018;7:139&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30058045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simanski CJP, Althaus A, Hoederath S, Kreutz KW, Hoederath P, Lefering R, Pape-K&#xf6;hler C, Neugebauer EAM. Incidence of chronic postsurgical pain (CPSP) after general surgery. Pain Med (United States) 2014;15:1222&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24716774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens BJ, Abbott LK, Yamada J, Harrison D, Stinson J, Taddio A, Barwick M, Latimer M, Scott SD, Rashotte J, Campbell F, Finley GA. Epidemiology and management of painful procedures in children in Canadian hospitals. Can Med Assoc J 2011;183:E403&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3080557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa P, Bhuvan KC, Lee SWH, Dujaili JA, Gyawali S, Mohamed Ibrahim MI, Alrasheedy AA. Managing pain in low resource settings: Healthcare professionals' knowledge, attitude and practice regarding pain management in Western Nepal. J Pain Res 2022;15:1587&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson K, Johnson MI, Milligan J, Briggs M. Twenty-five years of pain education research&#x2014;what have we learned? Findings from a comprehensive scoping review of research into pre-registration pain education for health professionals. PAIN 2018;159:2146&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30052574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner LL, Warner PA, Eldrige JS. Orthopedic resident education on postoperative pain control: bridging knowledge gaps to enhance patient safety. Int J Med Educ 2018;9:72&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5951775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29537969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt-Watson J, McGillion M, Hunter J, Choiniere M, Clark AJ, Dewar A, Johnston C, Lynch M, Morley-Forster P, Moulin D, Thie N, Von Baeyer CL, Webber K. A survey of prelicensure pain curricula in health science faculties in Canadian universities. Pain Res Manag 2009;14:439&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2807771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20011714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinrib AZ, Azam MA, Birnie KA, Burns LC, Clarke H, Katz J. The psychology of chronic post-surgical pain: new frontiers in risk factor identification, prevention and management. Br J Pain 2017;11:169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29123661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO guidelines for the pharmacological and radiotherapeutic management of cancer pain in adults and adolescents. World Health Organization, 2018.  Available at: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241550390. Accessed April 18, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30776210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuazua-Rico D, Maestro-Gonz&#xe1;lez A, Mosteiro-D&#xed;az MP, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Garrido J. Spanish version of the knowledge and attitudes survey regarding pain. Pain Manag Nurs 2019;20:497&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31147253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>