<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41492040</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1869-4101</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Insights into imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Insights Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intratumoral and peritumoral radiomics for the pretreatment prediction of response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in rhabdomyosarcoma: a multicenter retrospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13244-025-02178-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma (RMS), the most common soft-tissue sarcoma in children, exhibits heterogeneous responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC), necessitating reliable biomarkers for early prediction. This multicenter study evaluates MRI-derived radiomic features of intratumoral and peritumoral regions to predict NAC response in the largest pediatric RMS cohort to date.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective analysis included 519 RMS patients from three Chinese centers. Radiologists manually segmented tumors and 2-mm peritumoral regions on standardized T1-weighted contrast-enhanced (T1CE) and T2-weighted fat-saturated (T2Fs) MRI sequences. PyRadiomics extracted 1015 radiomic features, with robustness ensured (ICC&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.80) and predictive features selected via LASSO regression. Twelve XGBoost models (intra-/peritumoral, multisequence) were developed, validated internally/externally, and compared using DeLong's test, net reclassification improvement (NRI), and integrated discrimination improvement (IDI). SHAP analysis interpreted feature contributions. Clinical variables (age, fusion gene) were assessed for incremental value.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The T1CE-based combined intratumoral-peritumoral model (T1CE_IntraPeri2mm) demonstrated the best generalizability, achieving AUCs of 0.917 (training), 0.760 (internal validation), 0.837 (external test1) and 0.843 (external test2). It significantly outperformed intratumoral-only and multisequence fusion models in DeLong, NRI, and IDI analyses (all p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The combined clinical-radiomic model did not provide incremental benefit (AUC: 0.843 vs. 0.838, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.891). SHAP analysis indicated that features reflecting peritumoral structural irregularity and enhancement heterogeneity were key predictors of NAC resistance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">T1CE-based peritumoral radiomics robustly predicts NAC response in pediatric RMS, emphasizing tumor-microenvironment interactions. This approach offers a non-invasive tool for personalized therapy stratification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CRITICAL RELEVANCE STATEMENT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study establishes peritumoral MRI radiomics as a critical predictor of chemotherapy response in pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma, addressing the unmet need for non-invasive biomarkers and advancing precision oncology through tumor-microenvironment interaction analysis in clinical radiology practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Integrated tumor/peritumoral MRI features enhance neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) response prediction. T1CE MRI best captures tumor-microenvironment treatment interactions. Non-invasive radiomics model outperforms clinical factors for therapy adjustment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology Oncology Center, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Jugao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, Beijing Tongren Hospital, Capital Medical University, Key Laboratory of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery (Capital Medical University), Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanhu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Shunyi Maternal and Children's Hospital of Beijing Children's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Huanming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Hongcheng</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urological Surgery, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Dong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Guoxia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Stomatology, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shengcai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8628-5216</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China. wsc820329@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Pediatric Head and Neck Tumors, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China. wsc820329@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Beijing Children's Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Center for Children's Health, Beijing, China. nixin@bch.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Pediatric Head and Neck Tumors, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China. nixin@bch.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022-1-2092</GrantID><Agency>Capital's Funds for Health Improvement and Research</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BRWEP2024W102090111</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Research Ward Excel lence Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YN2020402</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Innovation Development Project, Beijing Children's Hospital, CapitalMedical University, National Center for Children's Health</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Insights Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532453</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1869-4101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI radiomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neoadjuvant chemotherapy response prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peritumoral</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical guidelines of the Helsinki Declaration and approved by the ethics committees of the following institutions: (1) Beijing Children&#x2019;s Hospital (approval number: [2022]-E-097-Y); (2) Beijing Tongren Hospital (approval number: TREC2024-KY093); (3) Shunyi Maternal and Children&#x2019;s Hospital of Beijing Children&#x2019;s Hospital (approval number: 2024-020-1). Consent for publication: The requirement for informed consent was waived by all ethics committees due to the retrospective nature of the study. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41492040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12770143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-025-02178-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13244-025-02178-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Skapek SX, Ferrari A, Gupta AA et al (2019) Rhabdomyosarcoma. Nat Rev Dis Prim 5:1. 10.1038/s41572-018-0051-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-018-0051-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberoi S, Crane JN, Haduong JH et al (2023) Children&#x2019;s Oncology Group&#x2019;s 2023 blueprint for research: soft tissue sarcomas. Pediatr Blood Cancer 70:e30556. 10.1002/pbc.30556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.30556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10519430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37430436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa S, Hayashi K, Taniguchi Y et al (2024) What are the optimal systemic treatment options for rhabdomyosarcoma? Curr Treat Options Oncol 25:784&#x2013;797. 10.1007/s11864-024-01206-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11864-024-01206-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38750399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke M, Anderson JR, Kao SC et al (2007) Assessment of response to induction therapy and its influence on 5-year failure-free survival in group III rhabdomyosarcoma: the Intergroup Rhabdomyosarcoma Study-IV experience&#x2014;a report from the soft tissue sarcoma committee of the Children&#x2019;s Oncology Group. J Clin Oncol 25:4909&#x2013;4913. 10.1200/JCO.2006.10.4257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2006.10.4257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17971587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koscielniak E, Blank B, Vokuhl C et al (2022) Long-term clinical outcome and prognostic factors of children and adolescents with localized rhabdomyosarcoma treated on the CWS-2002P protocol. Cancers (Basel) 14:899. 10.3390/cancers14040899</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14040899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8870315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35205646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoot RA, McHugh K, van Rijn RR et al (2013) Response assessment in pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma: can response evaluation criteria in solid tumors replace three-dimensional volume assessments? Radiology 269:870&#x2013;878. 10.1148/radiol.13122607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.13122607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23985275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inarejos Clemente EJ, Navallas M, Barber Mart&#xed;nez De La Torre I et al (2020) MRI of rhabdomyosarcoma and other soft-tissue sarcomas in children. Radiographics 40:791&#x2013;814. 10.1148/rg.2020190119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/rg.2020190119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32243230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cromb&#xe9; A, Spinnato P, Italiano A et al (2023) Radiomics and artificial intelligence for soft-tissue sarcomas: current status and perspectives. Diagn Interv Imaging 104:567&#x2013;583. 10.1016/j.diii.2023.09.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diii.2023.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37802753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillies RJ, Anderson AR, Gatenby RA, Morse DL (2010) The biology underlying molecular imaging in oncology: from genome to anatome and back again. Clin Radiol 65:517&#x2013;521. 10.1016/j.crad.2010.04.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crad.2010.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4009364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valli&#xe8;res M, Freeman CR, Skamene SR, El Naqa I (2015) A radiomics model from joint FDG-PET and MRI texture features for the prediction of lung metastases in soft-tissue sarcomas of the extremities. Phys Med Biol 60:5471&#x2013;5496. 10.1088/0031-9155/60/14/5471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0031-9155/60/14/5471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26119045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennaro N, Reijers S, Bruining A et al (2021) Imaging response evaluation after neoadjuvant treatment in soft tissue sarcomas: where do we stand? Crit Rev Oncol Hematol 160:103309. 10.1016/j.critrevonc.2021.103309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.critrevonc.2021.103309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33757836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Jiang Y, Xiong W et al (2022) Noninvasive imaging of the tumor immune microenvironment correlates with response to immunotherapy in gastric cancer. Nat Commun 13:5095. 10.1038/s41467-022-32816-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-32816-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9427761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36042205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braman NM, Etesami M, Prasanna P et al (2017) Intratumoral and peritumoral radiomics for the pretreatment prediction of pathological complete response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy based on breast DCE-MRI. Breast Cancer Res 19:57. 10.1186/s13058-017-0846-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13058-017-0846-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28521821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang S, Rudzinski ER et al (2022) Deep learning of rhabdomyosarcoma pathology images for classification and survival outcome prediction. Am J Pathol 192:917&#x2013;925. 10.1016/j.ajpath.2022.03.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpath.2022.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9194647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel AO, Lathara M, Shaw CY et al (2022) Machine learning for rhabdomyosarcoma histopathology. Mod Pathol 35:1193&#x2013;1203. 10.1038/s41379-022-01075-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41379-022-01075-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35449398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski D, Jung H, Brown GT (2023) Predicting molecular subtype and survival of rhabdomyosarcoma patients using deep learning of H&amp;E images: a report from the Children&#x2019;s Oncology Group. Clin Cancer Res 29:364&#x2013;378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9843436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36346688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee I, Crawley A, Bhethanabotla M et al (2018) Transfer learning on fused multiparametric MR images for classifying histopathological subtypes of rhabdomyosarcoma. Comput Med Imaging Graph 65:167&#x2013;175. 10.1016/j.compmedimag.2017.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compmedimag.2017.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambin P, Woodruff HC, Mali SA et al (2025) Radiomics Quality Score 2.0: towards radiomics readiness levels and clinical translation for personalized medicine. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 22:831&#x2013;846. 10.1038/s41571-025-01067-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41571-025-01067-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40903523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocak B, Baessler B, Bakas S et al (2023) CheckList for EvaluAtion of Radiomics research (CLEAR): a step-by-step reporting guideline for authors and reviewers endorsed by ESR and EuSoMII. Insights Imaging 14:75. 10.1186/s13244-023-01415-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-023-01415-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10160267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37142815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocak B, Akinci D&#x2019;Antonoli T, Mercaldo N et al (2024) METhodological RadiomICs score (METRICS): a quality scoring tool for radiomics research endorsed by EuSoMII. Insights Imaging 15:8. 10.1186/s13244-023-01572-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-023-01572-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10792137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38228979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields BKK, Demirjian NL, Cen SY et al (2023) Predicting soft tissue sarcoma response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy using an MRI-based delta-radiomics approach. Mol Imaging Biol 25:776&#x2013;787. 10.1007/s11307-023-01803-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11307-023-01803-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10333397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhn KJ, Cloutier JM, Boutin RD et al (2021) Soft tissue pathology for the radiologist: a tumor board primer with 2020 WHO classification update. Skelet Radiol 50:29&#x2013;42. 10.1007/s00256-020-03567-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-020-03567-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32743671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Xiong W, Tang L et al (2023) Non-invasive CT imaging biomarker to predict immunotherapy response in gastric cancer: a multicenter study. J Immunother Cancer 11:e007807. 10.1136/jitc-2023-007807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2023-007807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10668251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38179695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Xie C, Yang H et al (2020) Assessment of intratumoral and peritumoral computed tomography radiomics for predicting pathological complete response to neoadjuvant chemoradiation in patients with esophageal squamous cell carcinoma. JAMA Netw Open 3:e2015927. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.15927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.15927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32910196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun C, Tian X, Liu Z et al (2019) Radiomic analysis for pretreatment prediction of response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in locally advanced cervical cancer: a multicentre study. EBioMedicine 46:160&#x2013;169. 10.1016/j.ebiom.2019.07.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2019.07.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6712288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plava J, Cihova M, Burikova M et al (2019) Recent advances in understanding tumor stroma-mediated chemoresistance in breast cancer. Mol Cancer 18:67. 10.1186/s12943-019-0960-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-019-0960-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30927930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Park JE, Jo Y et al (2019) Incorporating diffusion- and perfusion-weighted MRI into a radiomics model improves diagnostic performance for pseudoprogression in glioblastoma patients. Neuro Oncol 21:404&#x2013;414. 10.1093/neuonc/noy133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuonc/noy133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6380413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30107606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Tan Y, Xie C et al (2020) Development and validation of a preoperative magnetic resonance imaging radiomics-based signature to predict axillary lymph node metastasis and disease-free survival in patients with early-stage breast cancer. JAMA Netw Open 3:e2028086. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.28086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.28086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Elmpt W, Zegers CML, Reymen B et al (2016) Multiparametric imaging of patient and tumour heterogeneity in non-small-cell lung cancer: quantification of tumour hypoxia, metabolism and perfusion. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 43:240&#x2013;248. 10.1007/s00259-015-3169-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-015-3169-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4700090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cromb&#xe9; A, P&#xe9;rier C, Kind M et al (2019) T2-based MRI delta-radiomics improve response prediction in soft-tissue sarcomas treated by neoadjuvant chemotherapy. J Magn Reson Imaging 50:497&#x2013;510. 10.1002/jmri.26589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.26589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeken JC, Asadpour R, Specht K et al (2021) MRI-based delta-radiomics predicts pathologic complete response in high-grade soft-tissue sarcoma patients treated with neoadjuvant therapy. Radiother Oncol 164:73&#x2013;82. 10.1016/j.radonc.2021.08.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2021.08.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34506832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberlin O, Rey A, Sanchez de Toledo J et al (2012) Randomized comparison of intensified six-drug versus standard three-drug chemotherapy for high-risk nonmetastatic rhabdomyosarcoma and other chemotherapy-sensitive childhood soft tissue sarcomas: long-term results from the International Society of Pediatric Oncology MMT95 study. J Clin Oncol 30:2457&#x2013;2465. 10.1200/JCO.2011.40.3287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.40.3287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22665534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautz TB, Chi Y, Tian J et al (2020) Relationship between tumor response at therapy completion and prognosis in patients with group III rhabdomyosarcoma: a report from the Children&#x2019;s Oncology Group. Int J Cancer 147:1419&#x2013;1426. 10.1002/ijc.32896</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.32896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32012255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantonello TM, Stark M, Timmermann B et al (2015) Tumour volume reduction after neoadjuvant chemotherapy impacts outcome in localised embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma. Pediatr Blood Cancer 62:16&#x2013;23. 10.1002/pbc.25207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.25207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25263634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbou S, Klega K, Tsuji J et al (2023) Circulating tumor DNA is prognostic in intermediate-risk rhabdomyosarcoma: a report from the Children&#x2019;s Oncology Group. J Clin Oncol 41:2382&#x2013;2393. 10.1200/JCO.22.00409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.00409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10150913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lak NSM, Van Zogchel LMJ, Zappeij-Kannegieter L et al (2023) Cell-free DNA as a diagnostic and prognostic biomarker in pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma. JCO Precis Oncol. 10.1200/PO.22.00113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9928631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36652664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Missiaglia E, Williamson D, Chisholm J et al (2012) <i>PAX3/FOXO1</i> fusion gene status is the key prognostic molecular marker in rhabdomyosarcoma and significantly improves current risk stratification. J Clin Oncol 30:1670&#x2013;1677. 10.1200/JCO.2011.38.5591
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.38.5591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22454413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Plas E, Darji H, Srivastava DK et al (2024) Risk factors for neurocognitive impairment, emotional distress, and poor quality of life in survivors of pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma: a report from the Childhood Cancer Survivor Study. Cancer 130:2224&#x2013;2236. 10.1002/cncr.35236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.35236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11139574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38373075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuetze SM (2005) Imaging and response in soft tissue sarcomas. Hematol Oncol Clin North Am 19:471&#x2013;487. 10.1016/j.hoc.2005.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hoc.2005.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DL, Mandeville H, Bradley JA et al (2022) Local control of parameningeal rhabdomyosarcoma: an expert consensus guideline from the International Soft Tissue Sarcoma Consortium (INSTRuCT). Pediatr Blood Cancer 69:e29751. 10.1002/pbc.29751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.29751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35484997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparber-Sauer M, Dietzschold M, Sch&#xf6;nstein A et al (2024) Radiotherapy and long-term sequelae in pediatric patients with parameningeal rhabdomyosarcoma: results of two Cooperative Weichteilsarkom Studiengruppe (CWS) trials and one registry. Pediatr Blood Cancer 71:e30742. 10.1002/pbc.30742</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.30742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37880926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantonello TM, Int-Veen C, Harms D et al (2009) Cooperative trial CWS-91 for localized soft tissue sarcoma in children, adolescents, and young adults. J Clin Oncol 27:1446&#x2013;1455. 10.1200/JCO.2007.15.0466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2007.15.0466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19224858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koscielniak E, Harms D, Henze G et al (1999) Results of treatment for soft tissue sarcoma in childhood and adolescence: a final report of the German Cooperative Soft Tissue Sarcoma Study CWS-86. J Clin Oncol 17:3706&#x2013;3719. 10.1200/JCO.1999.17.12.3706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.1999.17.12.3706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10577842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparber-Sauer M, Von Kalle T, Seitz G et al (2017) The prognostic value of early radiographic response in children and adolescents with embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma stage IV, metastases confined to the lungs: a report from the Cooperative Weichteilsarkom Studiengruppe (CWS). Pediatr Blood Cancer 64:e26510. 10.1002/pbc.26510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.26510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28306214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medin CR, Cardona K (2023) Response evaluation of neoadjuvant therapies in sarcoma. Curr Treat Options Oncol 24:515&#x2013;527. 10.1007/s11864-023-01075-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11864-023-01075-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36976453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagars GK, Ballo MT, Pisters PWT et al (2003) Prognostic factors for patients with localized soft-tissue sarcoma treated with conservation surgery and radiation therapy: an analysis of 1225 patients. Cancer 97:2530&#x2013;2543. 10.1002/cncr.11365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.11365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12733153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>