<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41799305</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6973</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Infection and drug resistance</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infect Drug Resist</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Critical Gaps in Infection Prevention and Control in Somalia: Insights from the 2024 Nationwide Harmonized Health Facility Assessment Data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>581753</StartPage><MedlinePgn>581753</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">581753</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IDR.S581753</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Preventing outbreaks, antibiotic resistance, and healthcare-associated infections (HAIs), infection prevention and control (IPC) is the cornerstone of safe, robust health systems. There is little data on IPC readiness across the country in Somalia due to its weak health system. The study aims to evaluate the preparedness of IPC systems in Somali healthcare facilities by looking at policies, fundamental procedures, and essential resources; to find gaps that guide focused interventions to improve patient safety and the resilience of the health system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We carried out a cross-sectional secondary analysis of the 2024 Harmonized Health Facility Assessment (HHFA), which included 1,219&#xa0;healthcare facilities of various categories spread over six states. Data were collected through structured interviews, observations, and facility record reviews. IPC indicators were presented using descriptive and inferential statistics. STATA Version 16 was used for the analyses, and a significance level of p &lt; 0.05 was used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">All Somali facilities have inadequate IPC readiness. Just 24% and 18%, respectively, have rules for standard precautions and healthcare waste management; 21% reported waste management training for workers. Hand hygiene supplies (39%), sterilizing equipment (26%), gloves (87%), masks (61%), and protective gowns (61%) were among the critical resources that differed in availability. There were significant regional differences (p &lt; 0.001), with Benadir frequently having better resources than Southwest, Jubaland, Puntland, Galmudug, and Hirshabelle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study identifies significant gaps in the infection prevention and control (IPC) systems of Somali healthcare facilities, such as a lack of resources, procedures, and regulations that are critical to patient safety. Geographical disparities were apparent. These results underline the necessity of targeted, system-wide interventions to raise IPC readiness, increase resource accessibility, and guarantee uniform policy integration and training, all of which will contribute to the development of a more secure and robust healthcare system in Somalia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Adam et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Abdikarim Abdi</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-5317-0471</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Jamhuriya University of Science and Technology, Mogadishu, Somalia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health and Climate, IPC Section, Federal Ministry of Health and Human Services, Mogadishu, Somalia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Hassan</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Jamhuriya University of Science and Technology, Mogadishu, Somalia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osman</LastName><ForeName>Nor Haji</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8051-0977</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Jamhuriya University of Science and Technology, Mogadishu, Somalia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Policy and Planning, HIS Section, Directorate of Health and Human Services, Banadir Regional Administration, Mogadishu, Somalia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Infect Drug Resist</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550216</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6973</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Somalia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">harmonized health facility assessments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare facilities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infection prevention and control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personal protective equipment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">waste management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41799305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12967039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S581753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">581753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adam AA, Mohamed HD, Anyiam FE. Assessment of infection prevention and control in somali healthcare facilities using the WHO infection prevention and control assessment framework. <i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2025;14(1):103. doi: 10.1186/s13756-025-01584-9
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-025-01584-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12403908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40898374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanos GL, Islam MS, Huang Y, et al. Infection prevention and control programme priorities for sustainable health and environmental systems. <i>BMC Global Public Health</i>. 2024;2(1):6. doi: 10.1186/s44263-023-00031-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44263-023-00031-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39681863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debie A, Nigusie A, Gedle D, Khatri RB, Assefa Y. Building a resilient health system for universal health coverage and health security: a systematic review. <i>Glob Heal Res Policy</i>. 2024;9(1):2. doi: 10.1186/s41256-023-00340-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41256-023-00340-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38173020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghar S, Atif M, Masood I, Khan M. A comprehensive review of current status of infection prevention and control program in low- and middle-income countries. <i>Infection Disease Health</i>. 2025;30(3):260&#x2013;11.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40199642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamas N, Stokle E, Ashiru-Oredope D, Wesangula E. Challenges of implementing antimicrobial stewardship tools in low to middle income countries (LMICs). <i>Infect Prev Pract</i>. 2023;5(4):100315.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10724472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38107237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Id BB, Scambler S, Najwa A, Khairuddin M, Gallagher E. Health system strengthening in fragile and conflict-affected states: a review of systematic reviews. <i>PloS one</i>. 2024;19(6):1&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0305234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0305234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11178226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38875266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global report on infection prevention and control. Who. 2022. 1&#x2013;182 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomczyk S, Twyman A, de Kraker MEA, et al. The first WHO global survey on infection prevention and control in health-care facilities. <i>Lancet Infect Dis</i>. 2022;22(6):845&#x2013;856. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00809-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00809-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maki G, Zervos M. Health care-acquired infections in low- and middle-income countries and the role of infection prevention and control. <i>Infect Dis Clin North Am</i>. 2021;35(3):827&#x2013;839. doi: 10.1016/j.idc.2021.04.014
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.idc.2021.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8331241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines Review Committee IHS. Guidelines on core components of infection prevention and control programmes at the national and acute health care facility level [Internet]. World Health Organization. 2016. Available from: http://apps.who.int/bookorders. Accessed February
24, 2026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27977095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storr J, Twyman A, Zingg W, et al. Core components for effective infection prevention and control programmes: new WHO evidence-based recommendations. <i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2017;6(1):6. doi: 10.1186/s13756-016-0149-9
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-016-0149-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomczyk S, Storr J, Kilpatrick C, Allegranzi B. Infection prevention and control (IPC) implementation in low-resource settings: a qualitative analysis. <i>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</i>. 2021;10(1):113. doi: 10.1186/s13756-021-00962-3
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-021-00962-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34332622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas S. The challenges of implementing infection prevention and antimicrobial stewardship programs in resource-constrained settings. <i>Antimicrob Stewardship Healthcare Epidemiol</i>. 2024;4(1):e45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38628374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Access I, Services I, Outcomes BH. USAID medicines, technologies, and pharmaceutical serviceS (MTAPS) program strengthening infection prevention and control (IPC) at the national and health care facility levels in Bangladesh. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinson C, Kilpatrick C, Rasa K, et al. Global surgery is stronger when infection prevention and control is incorporated: a commentary and review of the surgical infection landscape. <i>BMC Surg</i>. 2024;24(1):397. doi: 10.1186/s12893-024-02695-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-024-02695-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11662438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey K. Exploring the context of governance, structure and evaluation of australian infection prevention and control exploring the context of governance, Structure and Evaluation of Australian Infection Prevention and Control. 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas MAAJ, Adams SJ, Xing L, Mondal P, Szafron M. Exploring healthcare facilities&#x2019; readiness for standard precautions in infection prevention and control: a cross-country comparative analysis of six low- and middle-income countries using national cross-sectional surveys. <i>J Glob Health</i>. 2025;15:4205. doi: 10.7189/jogh.15.04205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.15.04205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12278887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40689730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabego L, Balde T, Barasa D, et al. Analysing the implementation of infection prevention and control measures in health care facilities during the COVID-19 pandemic in the African Region. <i>BMC Infect Dis</i>. 2023;23(1):824. doi: 10.1186/s12879-023-08830-8
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-023-08830-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10668477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeves M, Bancroft E, Lessa FC, Godfrey C, Allegranzi B. The case for strengthening infection prevention and control in primary care. <i>J Infect Dis</i>. 2025;232Supplement_2:S140&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiaf371
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiaf371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40976858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irakiza JJ, Mazimpaka C, Ndatimana D, et al. Status of infection prevention and control programs in 25 facilities of Rwanda: results from the WHO infection prevention and control assessment framework. <i>Public Health Challenges</i>. 2024;3(2):e183. doi: 10.1002/puh2.183
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/puh2.183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12039614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40496167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiruneh MG, Fenta ET, Delie AM, Masresha SA. Service availability and readiness to provide comprehensive emergency obstetric and newborn care services in post&#x2013;conflict at North Wollo Zone hospitals, Northeast Ethiopia: mixed survey. <i>BMC Health Serv Res</i>. 2023:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/s12913-023-09165-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-09165-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9976532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36859188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa DK, Acharya K, Karki A, Cleary M. Health facility readiness to provide antenatal care (ANC) and non-communicable disease (NCD) services in Nepal and Bangladesh: analysis of facility-based surveys. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2023;18(3):e0281357. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0281357
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0281357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10010536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36913361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriram V, Yilmaz V, Kaur S, Andres C, Cheng M, Meessen B. The role of private healthcare sector actors in health service delivery and financing policy processes in low-and middle-income countries: a scoping review. <i>BMJ Glob Heal</i>. 2024;8(Suppl 5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11077349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38316466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peck R, Mghamba J, Vanobberghen F, et al. Preparedness of Tanzanian health facilities for outpatient primary care of hypertension and diabetes: a cross-sectional survey. <i>Lancet Glob Heal</i>. 2014;2(5):e285&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4013553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24818084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam AA, Anyiam FE, Shube MA, Mohamed HD, Ahmed HA, Osman NH. Assessment of Medical Waste Segregation, Disposal Practices for Infectious and Sharps Waste in Healthcare Facilities in Somalia: implications for Infection Prevention and Control. <i>Infect Drug Resist</i>. 2025;18:3605&#x2013;3615. doi: 10.2147/IDR.S525134
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S525134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12301244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40727384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janay AI, Kilic B, Unal B. Healthcare workers&#x2019; compliance with COVID-19 2 preventive and control measures at De Martino. <i>medRxiv</i>. 2024. doi: 10.1101/2024.03.29.24305060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.03.29.24305060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39333892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berihun G, Walle Z, Desye B, et al. Healthcare waste management practices and associated factors among healthcare workers in Sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2025;20(10 October):1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0334290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0334290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12517534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41082551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mugambe RK, Wanyenze RK, Ssekamatte T, et al. Infection prevention and control and water, sanitation, and hygiene status of healthcare facilities in the Greater Kampala Metropolitan region during the COVID-19 pandemic in Uganda. <i>PLOS Water</i>. 2025;4(1):1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1371/journal.pwat.0000189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pwat.0000189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakim S, Chowdhury MAB, Uddin MJ, Leslie HH. Availability of basic infection control items and personal protection equipment in 7948&#xa0;health facilities in eight low- and middle-income countries: evidence from national health system surveys. <i>J Glob Health</i>. 2024;14:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.7189/jogh.14.04042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.14.04042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10906347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38426844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>