<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41191262</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of Competition Time on Soccer Players' Performance Factors: A Scoping Review with Evidence Gap Map.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>169</StartPage><EndPage>199</EndPage><MedlinePgn>169-199</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02321-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Performance in team sports is influenced by physical, technical, tactical, and psychological factors. Understanding the disparities in playing time between starters and nonstarters is crucial for optimizing training strategies and performance management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This systematic scoping review with an evidence gap map (EGM) aimed to (i) synthesize findings from studies comparing the performance factors of starters and nonstarters, (ii) identify compensatory strategies for players with reduced playing times and barriers to the implementation of these strategies, and (iii) provide an EGM to guide future research toward addressing the most relevant gaps in the literature. This review followed the PRISMA 2020 guidelines and the respective extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR). Electronic databases such as the Cochrane Library, PubMed, Scopus, SPORTDiscus, and Web of Science (Core Collection) were searched on 31/08/2023. The RoBANS tool was used to assess the risk of bias. Among 32,613 articles, 57 trials from 70 publications were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Female soccer players were represented in only 15.8% of the trials. The physical performance factor (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;56, 98.2%) has been extensively studied in relation to the differences between starters and nonstarters. Few studies have analyzed technical and psychological performance factors, while tactical factors have not been addressed. Starters presented higher values of external absolute intensity (EAI, measured by the total distance and sprint distance), higher internal absolute intensity (IAI, assessed through heart rate-based measures as above 70% maximal heart rate), along with greater improvements in exercise performance measurements (countermovement jump and 20-m sprint), than nonstarters did. The most adopted categorization was based on match participation (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;33, 57.9%), with starters defined as players who played for&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;66.7% of a match time (14.0%). The day commonly used for compensatory training was 24 h after a match (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;16; 37.5%). Several strategies attempting to reproduce competitive loads were used, such as small-sided games (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;9; 56.3%), running-based drills (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;8, 50.0%), small-positional games (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;3, 18.8%), tactical-technical drills (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;2, 12.5%), strength training (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;2, 12.5%), and friendly matches (k&#x2009;=&#x2009;1, 6.5%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This scoping review highlights the necessity of placing increased emphasis on technical, tactical, and psychological performance factors and compensatory training strategies (including the day and types of exercise). These measures aim to replicate the competitive match demands for nonstarters, maintaining or enhancing the physical adaptations, psychological factors, and tactical-technical skills required for performance improvement throughout the season. This review proposes three main future research areas for the topic: (i) investigating the effects of compensatory training on nonstarters' weekly loads when distributed across multiple days; (ii) investigating additional cutoffs or more refined time classifications for nonstarters; and (iii) directing more studies toward female soccer players. The protocol was registered in the Open Science Framework (project: https://osf.io/36pum/ ; registration: https://osf.io/9rmz6 ) and made public on December 30, 2021, prior to being performed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Milheiro</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2530-8357</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal. up201507435@fade.up.pt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baptista</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science and Technology, UiT, The Arctic University of Norway, 9037, Troms&#xf8;, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio Y</ForeName><Initials>FY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development (CIDESD), University of Maia, Maia, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarmento</LastName><ForeName>Hugo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit for Sport and Physical Activity (CIDAF), Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clemente</LastName><ForeName>Filipe Manuel</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, 80-336, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Escola Superior Desporto e Lazer, Instituto Polit&#xe9;cnico de Viana do Castelo, Rua Escola Industrial e Comercial de Nun'&#xc1;lvares, 4900-347, Viana do Castelo, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Physical Activity and Health Research and Innovation Center, Viana do Castelo, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Renato</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>N2i, Instituto Polit&#xe9;cnico da Maia, Universidade da Maia, Maia, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afonso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003163" MajorTopicYN="Y">Competitive Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094505" MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence Gaps</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of Interest: The authors have no conflicts of interest. Availability of Data and Material: Not applicable. Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Code Availability: Not applicable. Author Contributions: We followed ICJME guidelines. Therefore, all authors have provided substantial contributions for the conceptualization and design of the study, acquisition, analysis, and interpretation of data, as well as drafting and revising the manuscript critically. AM developed the original idea for the manuscript. IB, HS, FMC, JRS, and JA helped to conceptualize the work and were actively involved in all stages of the manuscript, including the establishment of the pre-registered protocol. FYN was actively involved in the data analysis and writing of the manuscript. All authors have read and agreed to the published version of the manuscript. Furthermore, all authors agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work. Registration: The protocol was registered in the Open Science Framework (project: https://osf.io/36pum/ ; registration: https://osf.io/9rmz6 ) and made public on December 30, 2021, before the searches were performed.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41191262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02321-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02321-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gim&#xe9;nez JV, Leicht AS, Gomez MA. Physical performance differences between starter and non-starter players during professional soccer friendly matches. J Hum Kinet. 2019;69:283&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31666910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6815094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Los Arcos A, Mendez-Villanueva A, Martinez-Santos R. In-season training periodization of professional soccer players. Biol Sport. 2017;34(2):149&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28566808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5424454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampinini E, Impellizzeri FM, Castagna C, Coutts AJ, Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Technical performance during soccer matches of the Italian Serie A league: effect of fatigue and competitive level. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12(1):227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collet C. The possession game? A comparative analysis of ball retention and team success in European and international football, 2007&#x2013;2010. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(2):123&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lago-Ballesteros J, Lago-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rey E. The effect of playing tactics and situational variables on achieving score-box possessions in a professional soccer team. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(14):1455&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22856388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miguel M, Oliveira R, Loureiro N, Garc&#xed;a-Rubio J, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez SJ. Load measures in training/match monitoring in soccer: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7967450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling C, McCall A, Le Gall F, Dupont G. The impact of in-season National team soccer play on injury and player availability in a professional club. J Sports Sci. 2015;33(17):1751&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling C, McCall A, Le Gall F, Dupont G. What is the extent of exposure to periods of match congestion in professional soccer players? J Sports Sci. 2015;33(20):2116&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26460635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. The training&#x2014;injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(5):273&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4789704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L, Orme P, Di Michele R, Close GL, Milsom J, Morgans R, et al. Quantification of seasonal-long physical load in soccer players with different starting status from the English Premier League: implications for maintaining squad physical fitness. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(8):1038&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26915393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis RM, Huggins RA, Benjamin CL, Sekiguchi Y, Arent MS, Armwald BC, et al. Seasonal accumulated workloads in collegiate men&#x2019;s soccer: a comparison of starters and reserves. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;35:3184&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Garcia A, Diaz AG, Bradley PS, Morera F, Casamichana D. Quantification of a professional football team&#x2019;s external load using a microcycle structure. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(12):3511&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30199452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Oliveira R, Clemente FM, Adsuar JC, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Carlos-Vivas J, et al. Comparisons of accelerometer variables training monotony and strain of starters and non-starters: a full-season study in professional soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(18):6547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32916804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7558857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalen T, Lor&#xe5;s H. Monitoring training and match physical load in junior soccer players: starters versus substitutes. Sports (Basel). 2019. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports7030070 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7030070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31581544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6835290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Magalh&#xe3;es JF, Ascens&#xe3;o AA, Oliveira EM, Seabra AF, Rebelo AN. Individual match playing time during the season affects fitness-related parameters of male professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(10):2729&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21912284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens TGA, de Ruiter CJ, Twisk JWR, Savelsbergh GJP, Beek PJ. Quantification of in-season training load relative to match load in professional Dutch Eredivisie football players. Sci Med Football. 2017;1(2):117&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staunton CA, Abt G, Weaving D, Wundersitz DWT. Misuse of the term &#x201c;load&#x201d; in sport and exercise science. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;25:439&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgans R, Di Michele R, Drust B. Soccer match play as an important component of the power-training stimulus in premier league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(5):665&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28422525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sporis G, Jovanovic M, Omrcen D, Matkovic B. Can the official soccer game be considered the most important contribution to player&#x2019;s physical fitness level? J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2011;51(3):374&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Wright S, Bruce-Low S, Nanni G, Sturdy T, Gross AS, et al. Recommendations for hamstring injury prevention in elite football: translating research into practice. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(7):449&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30413424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colby MJ, Dawson B, Peeling P, Heasman J, Rogalski B, Drew MK, et al. Improvement of prediction of noncontact injury in Elite Australian Footballers with repeated exposure to established high-risk workload scenarios. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(9):1130&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hills SP, Barrett S, Busby M, Kilduff LP, Barwood MJ, Radcliffe JN, et al. Profiling the post-match top-up conditioning practices of professional soccer substitutes: an analysis of contextual influences. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2805&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Brito JP, Martins A, Mendes B, Marinho DA, Ferraz R, et al. In-season internal and external training load quantification of an elite European soccer team. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(4):e0209393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6476476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Managing high-speed running load in professional soccer players: the benefit of high-intensity interval training supplementation. Sport Perform Sci Rep. 2019;53:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L, Orme P, Di Michele R, Close GL, Morgans R, Drust B, et al. Quantification of training load during one-, two- and three-game week schedules in professional soccer players from the English Premier League: implications for carbohydrate periodisation. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(13):1250&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26536538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hills SP, Radcliffe JN, Barwood MJ, Arent SM, Cooke CB, Russell M. Practitioner perceptions regarding the practices of soccer substitutes. PLoS ONE. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0228790 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33326504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7744046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Wong DP, McKenna M, Dellal A. Heart rate responses and technical comparison between small-vs. large-sided games in elite professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(8):2104&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21642858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Afonso J, Sarmento H. Small-sided games: an umbrella review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(2):e0247067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7880470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White H, Albers B, Gaarder M, Korn&#xf8;r H, Littell J, Marshall Z, et al. Guidance for producing a Campbell evidence and gap map. Campbell Syst Rev. 2020;16(4):e1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37016607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8356343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahdab F, Murad MH. Evidence maps: a tool to guide research agenda setting. BMJ Evid Based Med. 2019;24(6):209&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8005924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 2nd ed. Chichester: Wiley; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rechenchosky L, Menegassi VM, Jaime MO, Borges PH, Sarmento H, Mancha-Triguero D, et al. Scoping review of tests to assess tactical knowledge and tactical performance of young soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2021;39(18):2051&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34486926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan RL, Whaley P, Thayer KA, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ. Identifying the PECO: a framework for formulating good questions to explore the association of environmental and other exposures with health outcomes. Environ Int. 2018;121(Pt 1):1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30166065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6908441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SS-L, Wilczynski NL, Haynes RB. Developing optimal search strategies for detecting clinically sound treatment studies in EMBASE. J Med Libr Assoc. 2006;94(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16404468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1324770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AK, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Park JE, Lee YJ, Seo H-J, Sheen S-S, Hahn S, et al. Testing a tool for assessing the risk of bias for nonrandomized studies showed moderate reliability and promising validity. J Clin Epidemiol. 2013;66(4):408&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23337781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viswanathan M, Patnode CD, Berkman ND, Bass EB, Chang S, Hartling L, et al. Assessing the risk of bias in systematic reviews of health care interventions. Methods guide for effectiveness and comparative effectiveness reviews. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilamitjana J, Vaccari JC, Toedtli M, Navone D, Rodr&#xed;guez-Buteler JM, Verde PE, et al. Monitoring biochemical markers in professional soccer players during the season and preseason preparation phase. Ricyde-Revista Internacional De Ciencias Del Deporte. 2017;13(49):211&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alijanpour N, Nobari H, Bolboli L, Afroundeh R, Garcia-Ramos A. Using global positioning system to compare training monotony and training strain of starters and non-starters across of full-season in professional soccer players. Sustainability. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/su14063560 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14063560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskandarifard E, Silva R, Nobari H, Clemente FM, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Figueiredo AJ. Maturational effect on physical capacities and anabolic hormones in under-16 elite footballers: a cross-sectional study. Sport Sci Health. 2022;18(2):297&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes R, Brito JP, Vieira LHP, Martins AD, Clemente FM, Nobari H, et al. In-season internal load and wellness variations in professional women soccer players: comparisons between playing positions and status. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(23):12817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34886543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8657164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia GR, Goncalves LGC, Clemente FM, Nakamura FY, Nobari H, Bedo BLS, et al. Effects of congested fixture and matches&#x2019; participation on internal and external workload indices in professional soccer players. Sci Rep. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-05792-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-05792-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36528648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9759537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Aliaga A, Mart&#xed;n-Castellanos A, Nieto MM, Solana DM, Resta R, del Campo RL, et al. Effect of increasing the number of substitutions on physical performance during periods of congested fixtures in football. Sports. 2023;11(2):25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9962594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Los Arcos A, Mendez-Villanueva A, Yanci J, Martinez-Santos R. Respiratory and muscular perceived exertion during official games in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(3):301&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26217923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marqu&#xe9;s-Jim&#xe9;nez D, Sampaio J, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Echeazarra I. A random forest approach to explore how situational variables affect perceived exertion of elite youth soccer players. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2023;67:102429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37665882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Gholizadeh R, Martins AD, De la Vega R, Oliveira R. Variations of high-intensity GPS derived measures between playing status during a full soccer season in a professional male team. J Mens Health. 2022;18(6):137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rago V, Abreu R, Vasconcellos F, Teixeira VH, Rebelo A, Figueiredo P, et al. Physical and technical demands of the extra time: a multiple FIFA world cups&#x2019; analysis. Sci Med Footb. 2020;4(3):171&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Castillo D, Yanci J, Los Arcos A. Assessing the perceived exertion in elite soccer players during official matches according to situational factors. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(2):410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31936269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7013681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sams ML, Wagle JP, Sato K, DeWeese BH, Sayers AL, Stone MH. Using the session rating of perceived exertion to quantify training load in a men&#x2019;s college soccer team. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2793&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Oliveira R, Siahkouhian M, Perez-Gomez J, Cazan F, Ardigo LP. Variations of accelerometer and metabolic power global positioning system variables across a soccer season: a within-group study for starters and non-starters. Appl Sci Basel. 2021;11(15):6747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Pra&#xe7;a GM, Clemente FM, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Carlos Vivas J, Ahmadi M. Comparisons of new body load and metabolic power average workload indices between starters and non-starters: a full-season study in professional soccer players. Proc Inst Mech Eng Part P J Sports Eng Technol. 2021;235(2):105&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Silva R, Manuel Clemente F, Oliveira R, Carlos-Vivas J, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J. Variations of external workload across a soccer season for starters and non-starters. Proc Inst Mech Eng Part P J Sports Eng Technol. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1177/17543371211039297 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17543371211039297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, S&#xf6;g&#xfc;t M, Oliveira R, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Suzuki K, Zouhal H. Wearable inertial measurement unit to accelerometer-based training monotony and strain during a soccer season: a within-group study for starters and non-starters. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18158007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18158007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8750450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azc&#xe1;rate U, Los Arcos A, Yanci J. Variability of professional soccer players&#x2019; perceived match load after successive matches. Res Sports Med. 2021;29(4):349&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33327764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azc&#xe1;rate U, Yanci J, Los Arcos A. Influence of match playing time and the length of the between-match microcycle in Spanish professional soccer players&#x2019; perceived training load. Sci Med Footb. 2018;2(1):23&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis RM, Huggins RA, Benjamin CL, Sekiguchi Y, Adams WM, Arent SM, et al. Contextual factors influencing external and internal training loads in collegiate men&#x2019;s soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(2):374&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholizadeh R, Nobari H, Bolboli L, Siahkouhian M, Brito JP. Comparison of measurements of external load between professional soccer players. Healthcare. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare10061116 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10061116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35742170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9223007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Castillo D, Clemente FM, Carlos-Vivas J, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J. Acute, chronic and acute/chronic ratio between starters and non-starters professional soccer players across a competitive season. Proc Inst Mech Eng P J Sports Eng Technol. 2022;236(4):285&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Chen YS, Kargarfard M, Clemente FM, Carlos-Vivas J, Perez-Gomez J. Comparisons of accelerometer variables acute, chronic and acute/chronic workload ratio between starters and non-starters: a full-season study in professional soccer players. Sci Sports. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scispo.2021.03.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2021.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Ceylan HI, Brito JP, Martins A, Nalha M, Mendes B, et al. Within- and between-mesocycle variations of well-being measures in top elite male soccer players: a longitudinal study. J Mens Health. 2022;18(4):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Palucci Vieira LH, Martins A, Brito JP, Nalha M, Mendes B, et al. In-season internal and external workload variations between starters and non-starters-a case study of a Top Elite European Soccer Team. Medicina (Kaunas). 2021;57(7):645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34201642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8306595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Castillo D. Quantification of perceived effort in elite young footballers throughout a season. Apunts Educ Fis Deportes. 2020;140:63&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa Coelho D, Martins Coelho LG, Figueiredo Morandi R, Batista Ferreira Junior J, Bouzas Marins JC, Sales Prado L, et al. Effect of player substitutions on the intensity of second-half soccer match play. Braz J Kineanthropometry Hum Perform. 2012;14(2):183&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreira J, Nakamura FY, Ferreira R, Pereira J, Aquino R, Figueiredo P. Season Match Loads of a Portuguese Under-23 Soccer Team: differences between different starting statuses throughout the season and specific periods within the season using global positioning systems. Sensors (Basel). 2022;22(17):6379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36080835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9460033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley PS, Lago-Pe&#xf1;as C, Rey E. Evaluation of the match performances of substitution players in elite soccer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(3):415&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24413912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder&#xf3;n-Pellegrino G, Gallardo L, Garcia-Unanue J, Felipe JL, Hernandez-Martin A, Paredes-Hern&#xe1;ndez V, et al. Physical demands during the game and compensatory training session (MD + 1) in elite football players using global positioning system device. Sensors (Basel). 2022;22(10):3872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35632281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9145854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling C, Espi&#xe9; V, Le Gall F, Bloomfield J, Jullien H. Work-rate of substitutes in elite soccer: a preliminary study. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(2):253&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19560969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casamichana D, Mart&#xed;n-Garc&#xed;a A, D&#xed;az AG, Bradley PS, Castellano J. Accumulative weekly load in a professional football team: with special reference to match playing time and game position. Biol Sport. 2021;39(1):115&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8805368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-T&#xe9;llez JL, Figueiredo A, Chinchilla-Minguet JL, Onetti-Onetti W. Starters and non-starters soccer players in competition: is physical performance increased by the substitutions? BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az-Serradilla E, Castillo D, Rodr&#xed;guez-Marroyo JA, Raya Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Villa Vicente JG, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A. Effect of different nonstarter compensatory strategies on training load in female soccer players: a pilot study. Sports Health. 2023;30:19417381231176556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filho MJS, Albuquerque MR, da Costa IT, Malloy-Diniz LF, da Costa VT. Comparison of the motivation level of soccer players with high and low played time in matches under-20. J Phys Educ (Maringa). 2018. https://doi.org/10.4025/jphyseduc.v29i1.2911 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4025/jphyseduc.v29i1.2911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtado Mesa M, Stout JR, Redd MJ, Fukuda DH. Accumulated workload differences in collegiate women&#x2019;s soccer: starters versus substitutes. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2023;8(2):78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37367242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10299686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gai Y, Volossovitch A, Leicht AS, G&#xf3;mez M&#xc1;. Technical and physical performances of Chinese Super League soccer players differ according to their playing status and position. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2019;19(5):878&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualtieri A, Rampinini E, Sassi R, Beato M. Workload monitoring in top-level soccer players during congested fixture periods. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41(10):677&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez D, S&#xe1;nchez M, Martin V, Ben&#xe9;itez-Andr&#xe9;s E, S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez J. Contextual variables and weekly external load in a semi-professional football team. Apunts Educacion Fisica y Deportes. 2021;146:61&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppe MW, Barnics V, Freiwald J, Baumgart C. Contrary to endurance, power associated capacities differ between different aged and starting-nonstarting elite junior soccer players. PLoS ONE. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0232118 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0232118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7508371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Askow AT, Carvalho V, Murphy J, Luedke JA, Erickson JL. Seasonal accumulated workloads in collegiate women&#x2019;s soccer: a comparison of starters and reserves. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2022;7(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35076561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8788463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jajtner AR, Hoffman JR, Scanlon TC, Wells AJ, Townsend JR, Beyer KS, et al. Performance and muscle architecture comparisons between starters and nonstarters in National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I women&#x2019;s soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(9):2355&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23719503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, French DN, Paxton NJ, Hakkinen K, Volek JS, Sebastianelli WJ, et al. Changes in exercise performance and hormonal concentrations over a big ten soccer season in starters and nonstarters. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(1):121&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubayi A. Work rate and technical performance analyses of substitute players during the UEFA euro 2016. Med Sport. 2020;73(4):626&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez CE, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Luna &#xc1;, Felipe JL, Viejo D, S&#xe1;nchez J. Estimaci&#xf3;n Sobre la Variaci&#xf3;n de la Composici&#xf3;n Corporal y el Somatotipo en un Equipo de F&#xfa;tbol de Primera Divisi&#xf3;n./Estimation on the Variation in the Corporal Composition and Somatotype in a First Division Football Team. Revista Kronos. 2017;16(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenzo-Mart&#xed;nez M, Padr&#xf3;n-Cabo A, Rey E, Memmert D. Analysis of physical and technical performance of substitute players in professional soccer. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2021;92(4):599&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magrini MA, Colquhoun RJ, Sellers JH, Conchola EC, Hester GM, Thiele RM, et al. Can squat jump performance differentiate starters vs. nonstarters in Division I female soccer players? J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(8):2348&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning CN, Sekiguchi Y, Benjamin CL, Spaulding MR, Dierickx EE, Spaulding JM, et al. Deconstructing stereotypes: stature, match-playing time, and performance in elite women&#x2019;s world cup soccer. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:1067190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9795175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins AD, Oliveira R, Brito JP, Loureiro N, Querido SM, Nobari H. Intra-season variations in workload parameters in Europe&#x2019;s elite young soccer players: a comparative pilot study between starters and non-starters. Healthcare. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare9080977 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9080977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34574979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8469708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Petrucelli C, Coyle EF. Maximal power output and perceptual fatigue responses during a Division I female collegiate soccer season. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(12):3189&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22996020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Alijanpour N, Martins AD, Oliveira R. Acute and chronic workload ratios of perceived exertion, global positioning system, and running-based variables between starters and non-starters: a male professional team study. Front Psychol. 2022;13:860888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35369219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8970311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padr&#xf3;n-Cabo A, Rey E, Vidal B, Garc&#xed;a-Nu&#xf1;ez J. Work-rate analysis of substitute players in professional soccer: analysis of seasonal variations. J Hum Kinet. 2018;65(1):165&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6341962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer TB, Akehi K. Rate of torque development as a discriminator of playing level in collegiate female soccer players. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2022;22(3):326&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36046988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9438514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadakis L, Patras K, Georgoulis AD. In-season concurrent aerobic endurance and CMJ improvements are feasible for both starters and non-starters in professional soccer players: a case study. J Aust Strength Cond. 2015;23(5):19&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevas G, Hadjicharalambous M. Aerobic fitness of starter and non-starter soccer players in the champion&#x2019;s league. J Hum Kinet. 2018;61(Mar):99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5873340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reche-Soto P, Rojas-Valverde D, Bastida-Castillo A, Gomez-Carmona CD, Rico-Gonzalez M, Vieira LHP, et al. Using ultra-wide band to analyze soccer performance through load indicators during a full season: a comparison between starters and non-starters. Appl Sci Basel. 2022;12(24):12675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestre R, Kraemer WJ, West C, Judelson DA, Spiering BA, Vingren JL, et al. Body composition and physical performance during a National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I men&#x2019;s soccer season. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(4):962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17149986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sydney MG, Wollin M, Chapman D, Ball N, Mara JK. Substitute running outputs in elite youth male soccer players: less peak but greater relative running outputs. Biol Sport. 2023;40(1):241&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Branquinho L, Ferraz R, Leal M, Silva AJ, Barbosa TM, et al. Weekly training load across a standard microcycle in a sub-elite youth football academy: a comparison between starters and non-starters. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(18):11611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9517031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titton A. Competitive evaluation in male elite junior soccer players: entire match, replaced, and substitute players. J Exerc Rehabil. 2020;16(3):286&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32724787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7365729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanetti V, Aoki MS, Bradley P, Carling C, Marino TK, Moreira A. Running performance and hormonal, maturity and physical variables in starting and non-starting elite U14 soccer players during a congested match schedule. J Hum Kinet. 2021;80(1):287&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34868436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8607771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalen T, J&#xf8;rgen I, Gertjan E, Geir Havard H, Ulrik W. Player load, acceleration, and deceleration during forty-five competitive matches of elite soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(2):351&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26057190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampinini E, Bosio A, Ferraresi I, Petruolo A, Morelli A, Sassi A. Match-related fatigue in soccer players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(11):2161&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miake-Lye IM, Hempel S, Shanman R, Shekelle PG. What is an evidence map? A systematic review of published evidence maps and their definitions, methods, and products. Syst Rev. 2016;5(1):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snilstveit B, Vojtkova M, Bhavsar A, Stevenson J, Gaarder M. Evidence &amp; gap maps: a tool for promoting evidence informed policy and strategic research agendas. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;79:120&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Ramirez-Campillo R, Beato M, Moran J, Kawczynski A, Makar P, et al. Arbitrary absolute vs. individualized running speed thresholds in team sports: a scoping review with evidence gap map. Biol Sport. 2023;40(3):919&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10286616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rein R, Memmert D. Big data and tactical analysis in elite soccer: future challenges and opportunities for sports science. Springerplus. 2016;5(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah MR, Musa RM, Maliki ABHMB, Kosni NA, Suppiah PK. Role of psychological factors on the performance of elite soccer players. J Phys Educ Sport. 2016;16(1):170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Hopkins WG, G&#xf3;mez M-A. Modelling relationships between match events and match outcome in elite football. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16(5):516&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26190577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellano J, Casamichana D, Lago C. The use of match statistics that discriminate between successful and unsuccessful soccer teams. J Hum Kinet. 2012;31:139&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3588662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran T, Appleton PR, Hill AP, Hall HK. Passion and burnout in elite junior soccer players: the mediating role of self-determined motivation. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2011;12(6):655&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Mas A, Palou P, Gili M, Ponseti X, Borras PA, Vidal J, et al. Commitment, enjoyment and motivation in young soccer competitive players. Span J Psychol. 2010;13(2):609&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Wong DP, Paul D, Dellal A. Physical and technical comparisons between various-sided games within professional soccer. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(4):286&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24022576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Nakamura FY, Baptista I, Rendeiro-Pinho G, Brito J, Figueiredo P. Microdosing: old wine in a new bottle? Current state of affairs and future avenues. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(11):1649&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36202386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>