<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41787045</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hybrid generative-ensemble approach for predicting recycled aggregate concrete strength properties.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42598-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study proposes a hybrid generative-ensemble framework to predict key mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete from mix proportions. An established database of 112 mixes was used to model compressive strength, split tensile strength, flexural strength, and elastic modulus. To mitigate data scarcity, a conditional variational autoencoder was trained on the training data only and used to generate additional physically plausible input samples, after which seven supervised learning algorithms were trained and compared using cross-validation. Gradient boosting and support vector regression achieved the most accurate and stable predictions across all targets, outperforming baseline linear models and commonly used empirical correlations. Feature-attribution analysis was used to identify the dominant drivers of each property, showing that binder-related variables primarily govern strength, while aggregate-related variables dominate stiffness. The results support practical, data-driven screening of recycled aggregate concrete mixes and provide interpretable guidance for sustainable mix design.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Awoyera</LastName><ForeName>Paul O</ForeName><Initials>PO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Prince Mohammad Bin Fahd University, Al Khobar, 34754, Saudi Arabia. pawoyera@pmu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simwanda</LastName><ForeName>Lenganji</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Czech Technical University in Prague, Klokner Institute, Solinova 7, Praha 6, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Milica V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Materials, Institute for Testing of Materials, Bulevar vojvode Mi&#x161;i&#x107;a 43, Beograd, 11040, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mydin</LastName><ForeName>Md Azree Othuman</ForeName><Initials>MAO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Housing, Building and Planning, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, 11800, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imoh</LastName><ForeName>Udeme Udo</ForeName><Initials>UU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Structural and Geotechnical Engineering, Faculty of Architecture, Civil Engineering and Transport Sciences, Sz&#xe9;chenyi Istv&#xe1;n University, Gy&#x151;r, H-9026, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadugba</LastName><ForeName>Olaolu George</ForeName><Initials>OG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Nigeria. ogfadugba@kab.ac.ug.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Kabale University, P.O Box 317, Kabale Municipality, Kabale, Uganda. ogfadugba@kab.ac.ug.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asiz</LastName><ForeName>Andi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Prince Mohammad Bin Fahd University, Al Khobar, 34754, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rad</LastName><ForeName>Majid Movahedi</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Structural and Geotechnical Engineering, Faculty of Architecture, Civil Engineering and Transport Sciences, Sz&#xe9;chenyi Istv&#xe1;n University, Gy&#x151;r, H-9026, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Conditional variational autoencoder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-validation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gradient boosting regression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SHAP values</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synthetic data augmentation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Data availability: Raw data are available at75, and code used to reproduce all tables and figures is available in the project repository: https://github.com/hybridML_CVAE_RAC.git, including scripts, trained models, and an environment specification file. Generative AI and AI-assisted technologies in the writing process: During the preparation of this work the authors used Copilot Microsoft tool to improve parts of the text for the purpose of improved writing. After using this tool, the authors reviewed and edited the content as needed and take full responsibility for the content of the publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41787045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42598-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42598-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hanifa, M., Agarwal, R., Sharma, U., Thapliyal, P. C. &amp; Singh, L. P. A review on CO2 capture and sequestration in the construction industry: Emerging approaches and commercialised technologies. J. CO2 Util. 67, 102292. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2022.102292 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbhuiya, S., Das, B. B. &amp; Adak, D. Roadmap to a net-zero carbon cement sector: Strategies, innovations and policy imperatives. J. Environ. Manage. 359, 121052. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121052 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawzy, S., Osman, A. I., Doran, J. &amp; Rooney, D. W. Strategies for mitigation of climate change: a review, (2020). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10311-020-01059-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, K. A., Ahmad, M. I. &amp; Yusup, Y. Issues, impacts, and mitigations of carbon dioxide emissions in the building sector. Sustainability https://doi.org/10.3390/SU12187427 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;aloza, D., Erlandsson, M., Berlin, J., W&#xe5;linder, M. &amp; Falk, A. Future scenarios for climate mitigation of new construction in Sweden: Effects of different technological pathways. J. Clean. Prod. 187, 1025&#x2013;1035. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.03.285 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffar, S. H., Burman, M. &amp; Braimah, N. Pathways to circular construction: An integrated management of construction and demolition waste for resource recovery. J. Clean. Prod. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.118710 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Yan, L., Fu, Q. &amp; Kasal, B. A Comprehensive Review on Recycled Aggregate and Recycled Aggregate Concrete, (2021). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.105565</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedeljkovi&#x107;, M., Visser, J., &#x160;avija, B., Valcke, S. &amp; Schlangen, E. Use of fine recycled concrete aggregates in concrete: A critical review, (2021). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabduljabbar, H., Farooq, F., Alyami, M. &amp; Hammad, A. W. A. Assessment of the split tensile strength of fiber reinforced recycled aggregate concrete using interpretable approaches with graphical user interface. Mater. Today. Commun. 38, 108009. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.108009 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, T., Mathur, P., Oza, P., Agrawal, S. &amp; Narmawala, H. Predictive modelling of sustainable concrete compressive strength using advanced machine learning algorithms. Advances in Civil and Architectural Engineering 15(29 SE-Articles), 168&#x2013;192. https://doi.org/10.13167/2024.29.11 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phoeuk, M. &amp; Kwon, M. Accuracy prediction of compressive strength of concrete incorporating recycled aggregate using ensemble learning algorithms: Multinational dataset. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2023(1), 5076429. https://doi.org/10.1155/2023/5076429 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipu, R. K., Shah, O. A., Vats, S. &amp; Purohit, S. Enhancing Concrete Properties Through the Integration of Recycled Coarse Aggregate: A Machine Learning Approach for Sustainable Construction, in 4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management (ICIPTM), 2024, pp. 1&#x2013;5., 2024, pp. 1&#x2013;5. (2024). https://doi.org/10.1109/ICIPTM59628.2024.10563490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaglan, A. &amp; Singh, R. R. Recycled Aggregate Concrete Incorporating GGBS and Polypropylene Fibers Using RSM and Machine Learning Techniques, (2025). https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings15010066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A. A., Ahmed, I., Aqsa, T. &amp; Javed, H. Experimental and machine learning investigation of potential strength of recycled aggregate concrete. The Asian Bulletin of Big Data Management 4(1), 33&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.62019/abbdm.v4i1.120 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipu, R. K., Batra, V., Suman, K. S., Pandya &amp; Panchal, V. R. Efficient compressive strength prediction of concrete incorporating recycled coarse aggregate using Newton&#x2019;s boosted backpropagation neural network (NB-BPNN). Structures 58, 105559. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.istruc.2023.105559 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, F. &amp; Li, H. A two-level machine learning prediction approach for RAC compressive strength. Buildings https://doi.org/10.3390/buildings14092885 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falah, M. W. et al. Compressive strength prediction using coupled deep learning model with extreme gradient boosting algorithm: Environmentally friendly concrete incorporating recycled aggregate. Complexity 2022(1), 5433474. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/5433474 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. Prediction of compressive strength of recycled aggregate concrete using hybrid decision tree models. Appl. Math. Nonlinear Sci. 9(1), 1&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.2478/amns-2024-3554 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, L., Xu, J., Yuan, J. &amp; Yu, Y. Compressive strength and elastic modulus of RBAC: An analysis of existing data and an artificial intelligence based prediction. Case. Stud. Constr. Mater. 18, e02184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02184 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J., Chen, W., Yu, Y., Xu, J. &amp; Zhao, X. Data-driven analysis on compressive behavior of unconfined and confined recycled aggregate concretes. Constr. Build. Mater. 356, 129282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129282 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, L., Xu, J., Ying, W., Yu, Y. &amp; Zhou, L. Post-fire compressive mechanical behaviors of concrete incorporating coarse and fine recycled aggregates. Constr. Build. Mater. 461, 139948. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.139948 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Performance-based design of FRP-confined recycled aggregate concrete powered by machine learning techniques. Eng. Struct. 336, 120478. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.120478 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Service life evaluation of marine concrete structures considering spatial and temporal characteristics: A framework based on multi training-MCS-NLS. Eng. Struct. 322, 119193. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.119193 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K. et al. Intelligent design of limit states for recycled aggregate concrete filled steel tubular columns. Structures 58, 105338. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.istruc.2023.105338 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Xia, P., Gong, F., Zhao, Y. &amp; Lin, P. A Bayesian-physical informed conditional tabular generative adversarial network framework for low-carbon concrete data augmentation and hyperparameter optimization. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 152, 110811. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engappai.2025.110811 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholampour, A., Gandomi, A. H. &amp; Ozbakkaloglu, T. New formulations for mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete using gene expression programming. Constr. Build. Mater. 130, 122&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.10.114 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C. &amp; Chen, Z. Mechanical properties of recycled concrete made with different types of coarse aggregate. Constr. Build. Mater. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.163 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar, J., Balaji, S., Jegatheeswaran, D. &amp; Awoyera, P. Prediction of the mechanical properties of fibre-reinforced quarry dust concrete using response surface and artificial neural network techniques. Adv. Civ. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1155/2023/8267639 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, Z., Hou, S., Poon, C. S., Xiao, J. &amp; Liu, Y. Using neural networks to determine the significance of aggregate characteristics affecting the mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete. Appl. Sci. https://doi.org/10.3390/app8112171 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinkovi&#x107;, S., Radonjanin, V., Male&#x161;ev, M. &amp; Ignjatovi&#x107;, I. Comparative environmental assessment of natural and recycled aggregate concrete. Waste Manage. 30 (11), 2255&#x2013;2264. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wasman.2010.04.012 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdanbakhsh, A., Bank, L. C., Baez, T. &amp; Wernick, I. Comparative LCA of concrete with natural and recycled coarse aggregate in the New York City area. Int. J. Life Cycle Assess. 23 (6), 1163&#x2013;1173. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11367-017-1360-5 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinkovi&#x107;, S., Draga&#x161;, J., Ignjatovi&#x107;, I. &amp; To&#x161;i&#x107;, N. Environmental assessment of green concretes for structural use. J. Clean. Prod. 154, 633&#x2013;649. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.04.015 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhachhia, A. Concrete mix design by IS, ACI and BS methods: A comparative analysis. J. Building Mater. Sci. 2(1), 30&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.30564/jbms.v2i1.2636 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Investigation of spatial stratified heterogeneity of cemented paste backfill characteristics in construction demolition waste recycled aggregates. J. Clean. Prod. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.119332 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, A., Singh, J. &amp; Kaur, S. Machine learning approach for optimizing usability of healthcare websites. Sci. Rep. 15 (1), 1&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-99449-z (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufera, A. G., Liu, T. &amp; Xu, J. Regression models of Pearson correlation coefficient. Stat. Theory Relat. Fields 7(2), 97&#x2013;106. https://doi.org/10.1080/24754269.2023.2164970 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsyth, D. Applied Machine Learning (2019). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-18114-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Properties of concrete. Choice Reviews Online, 50, 10, pp. 50-5613-50&#x2013;5613, 2013, https://doi.org/10.5860/choice.50-5613</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormann, C. F. et al. Collinearity: A review of methods to deal with it and a simulation study evaluating their performance. Ecography 36(1), 27&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0587.2012.07348.x (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. &amp; Zhao, Q. Ensemble learning, in Handbook On Computer Learning And Intelligence, vol. 2&#x2013;2, pp. 635&#x2013;660. (2022). https://doi.org/10.1142/9789811247323_0016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K. et al. An intelligent hybrid machine learning framework for compressive strength prediction of alkali-activated binders based on fly ash characteristics. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 154, 110971. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engappai.2025.110971 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charilaou, P. &amp; Battat, R. Machine learning models and over-fitting considerations. World J. Gastroenterol. 28 (5), 605&#x2013;607. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v28.i5.605 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblatt, M., Tejavibulya, L., Jiang, R., Noble, S. &amp; Scheinost, D. Data leakage inflates prediction performance in connectome-based machine learning models. Nat. Commun. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46150-w (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, S. &amp; Rajan, H. Fair preprocessing: Towards understanding compositional fairness of data transformers in machine learning pipeline, in ESEC/FSE 2021 - Proceedings of the 29th ACM Joint Meeting European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, pp. 981&#x2013;993. (2021). https://doi.org/10.1145/3468264.3468536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Carrasco, J., Mat&#xe9;, A. &amp; Trujillo, J. A Data-Driven Methodology for Guiding the Selection of Preprocessing Techniques in a Machine Learning Pipeline, in Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing, pp. 34&#x2013;42. (2023). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-34674-3_5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchene, M. M. &amp; Fatima, M. Normalized mean difference (NMD): A novel filter-based feature selection method. Int. J. Mach. Learn. Cybern. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13042-025-02648-3 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelli, K., Grie&#xdf;er, H., Neumeyr, C., Hohenleitner, R. &amp; Pachnicke, S. Degradation prediction of semiconductor lasers using conditional variational autoencoder. J. Lightwave Technol. 40(18), 6213&#x2013;6221. https://doi.org/10.1109/JLT.2022.3188831 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, I.-T. &amp; Prayogo, H. Interpretable data-augmented machine learning framework for robust failure mode classification of RC shear wall. J. Build. Eng. 112, 113960. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2025.113960 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Z., Zhang, C. &amp; Lu, Y. Prediction of ultimate bearing capacity for rubberized concrete filled steel tube columns based on tabular variational autoencoder method and stacking ensemble strategy. Structures 70, 107667. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.istruc.2024.107667 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiba, T., Sano, S., Yanase, T., Ohta, T. &amp; Koyama, M. Optuna: A Next-generation Hyperparameter Optimization Framework, in Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, pp. 2623&#x2013;2631. (2019). https://doi.org/10.1145/3292500.3330701</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simwanda, L., David, A. B., Olalusi, O. B., Muhit, I. B. &amp; Sykora, M. Shear capacity prediction and reliability analysis of corroded reinforced concrete beams using deep generative modeling and ensemble learning. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 157, 111085. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engappai.2025.111085 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, M. et al. Interpretable ensemble-machine-learning models for predicting creep behavior of concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104295 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madirisha, M. M., Simwanda, L. &amp; Mtei, R. P. Predicting the Hydrogen storage capacity of Alumina pillared interlayer clays using interpretable ensemble machine learning. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.216 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal, S., Singh, R., Rathore, A., Kapoor, K. &amp; Patel, M. A novel data-driven machine learning techniques to predict compressive strength of fly ash and recycled coarse aggregates based self-compacting concrete. Mater. Today Commun. 39, 109294. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109294 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golafshani, E., Khodadadi, N., Ngo, T., Nanni, A. &amp; Behnood, A. Modelling the compressive strength of geopolymer recycled aggregate concrete using ensemble machine learning. Adv. Eng. Softw. 191, 103611. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.advengsoft.2024.103611 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, A. H. A., Jin, W. &amp; Ali, M. A. H. Comparative analysis of intelligent models for predicting compressive strength in recycled aggregate concrete. Model. Earth Syst. Environ. 10 (4), 5273&#x2013;5291. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40808-024-02063-7 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibragimov, B. &amp; Gusev, G. Minimal Variance Sampling in Stochastic Gradient Boosting, in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, H. Wallach, H. Larochelle, A. Beygelzimer, F. d\textquotesingle Alch&#xe9;-Buc, (eds Fox, E. &amp; Garnett, R.) Curran Associates, Inc., (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabiri, H., Kioumarsi, M., Kheyroddin, A., Kandiri, A. &amp; Sartipi, F. Compressive strength of concrete with recycled aggregate; a machine learning-based evaluation. Clean. Mater. 3, 100044. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clema.2022.100044 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abioye, S. O., Babatunde, Y. O., Abikoye, O. A., Shaibu, A. N. &amp; Bankole, B. J. Optimized machine learning algorithms with SHAP analysis for predicting compressive strength in high-performance concrete. AI in Civil Engineering 4(1), 16. https://doi.org/10.1007/s43503-025-00061-x (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosa, M. E., Villagr&#xe1;n Zaccardi, Y. A. &amp; Zega, C. J. A critical review of the resulting effective water-to-cement ratio of fine recycled aggregate concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 313, 125536. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125536 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adessina, A., Ben Fraj, A. &amp; Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my, J.-F. Improvement of the compressive strength of recycled aggregate concretes and relative effects on durability properties. Constr. Build. Mater. 384, 131447. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131447 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R., Nayak, D., Pandey, A., Kumar, R. &amp; Kumar, V. Effects of recycled fine aggregates on properties of concrete containing natural or recycled coarse aggregates: A comparative study. J. Build. Eng. 45, 103442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103442 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Gao, L. &amp; Bian, W. Mechanical performance of concrete made with recycled aggregates from concrete pavements. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020(1), 5035763. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/5035763 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Garc&#xed;a, R. et al. Impact of design parameters on the ratio of compressive to split tensile strength of self-compacting concrete with recycled aggregate. Materials https://doi.org/10.3390/ma14133480 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadesh, P. et al. Effect of design parameters on compressive and split tensile strength of self-compacting concrete with recycled aggregate: An overview. Appl. Sci. https://doi.org/10.3390/app11136028 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R., Tipu, R. K., Mir, A. A. &amp; Patel, M. Predictive modelling of flexural strength in recycled aggregate-based concrete: A comprehensive approach with machine learning and global sensitivity analysis. Iran. J. Sci. Technol. Trans. Civ. Eng. 49(2), 1089&#x2013;1114. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40996-024-01502-w (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Li, L. &amp; Cheng, S. Evaluation of modulus of elasticity of concrete containing both natural and recycled concrete aggregates. J. Clean. Prod. 447, 141591. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141591 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, C. et al. Determining the importance of recycled aggregate characteristics affecting the elastic modulus of concrete by modeled recycled aggregate concrete: Experiment and numerical simulation. Cem. Concr. Compos. 162, 106118. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2025.106118 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>scikit learn. Ensembles: Gradient boosting, random forests, bagging, voting, stacking. scikit-learn.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A. A., Chaudhari, O. &amp; Chandra, R. A review of ensemble learning and data augmentation models for class imbalanced problems: Combination, implementation and evaluation. Expert Syst. Appl. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122778 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smola, A. J. &amp; Sch&#xf6;lkopf, B. A tutorial on support vector regression. Stat. Comput. https://doi.org/10.1023/B:STCO.0000035301.49549.88 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shishegaran, A., Varaee, H., Rabczuk, T. &amp; Shishegaran, G. High correlated variables creator machine: Prediction of the compressive strength of concrete. Comput. Struct. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compstruc.2021.106479 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho, H. D. P., de Oliveira, J. F. L. &amp; de A. Fagundes, R. A. Dynamic selection of ensemble-based regression models: Systematic literature review. Expert Syst. Appl. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2025.128429 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. Parametric sensitivity analysis and modelling of mechanical properties of normal- and high-strength recycled aggregate concrete using grey theory, multiple nonlinear regression and artificial neural networks. Constr. Build. Mater. 211, 479&#x2013;491. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.234 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoyera, P. O. Mechanical Properties of Recycled Aggregate Concrete, Mendeley Data, vol. VI, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, J. Dynamic feature selection for silicon contentprediction in blast furnace using BOSVRRFE. Sci. Rep. 15, 20555. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-04542-y (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guido, R., Ferrisi, S., Lofaro, D., &amp; Conforti, D. An Overview on the Advancements of Support Vector Machine Models in Healthcare Applications: AReview. Information 15, 235. https://doi.org/10.3390/info15040235 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>