<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41490005</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Supportive Progressive Resistance Training Combined With Adjuvant Hypofractioned Radiation Therapy Improves Shoulder Complex Muscle Strength in Women With Breast Cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e312</StartPage><EndPage>e322</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e312-e322</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005306</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tu&#x11f;rul, E, Darandeli, A, Tu&#x11f;rul, F, Knicker, AJ, Soylu, AR, and Ertan, H. Supportive progressive resistance training combined with adjuvant hypofractioned radiation therapy improves shoulder complex muscle strength in women with breast cancer. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): e313-e323, 2026-Despite its benefits, radiation therapy (RT) causes a range of side effects that adversely affect individuals undergoing breast cancer (BC) treatment. Exercise is considered a simultaneous treatment alongside radiation therapy to mitigate side effects and to facilitate effective recovery in patients. The aim of this study was to investigate the effects of progressive resistance training (PRT) combined with adjuvant hypofractionated radiation therapy (HFRT) on shoulder complex muscle strength and muscle activation in patients with BC. Thirty-one patients with BC were assigned to either an exercise group (EG, n = 15) or a control group (CG, n = 16). EMG and force signals were recorded while the patients performed isokinetic shoulder internal and external rotation with their surgery limb and the contralateral limb at angular velocities of 1.047 rad/s and 2.094 rad/s. Common terminology criteria for adverse events (CTCAE) were used to evaluate the side effects of HFRT. Torque and EMG data for pre- and postintervention were compared between the 2 groups using linear mixed models. The torque produced during shoulder internal and external rotation at all angular velocities showed significantly greater improvement in EG compared with CG ( p &lt; 0.0001). Group and time interaction was statistically significant for mean functional control ratio (FCR) and maximal voluntary contraction torque values ( p &lt; 0.0001). Similarly, group and time interaction was statistically significant for peak EMG values ( p &lt; 0.0001). There was no statistically significant difference in CTCAE between the EG and the CG ( p &gt; 0.05). PRT combined with adjuvant HFRT is effective in increasing shoulder complex muscle strength, and FCR in women with BC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu&#x11f;rul</LastName><ForeName>Emel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1589-8648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Institute of Movement and Training Science, Eskisehir Technical University, Eskisehir, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darendeli</LastName><ForeName>Abdulkerim</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy, Movement and Rehabilitation Science, Northeastern University, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu&#x11f;rul</LastName><ForeName>Fuzuli</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Ac&#x131;badem Hospital, Eskisehir, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knicker</LastName><ForeName>Axel J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Movement and Neuroscience, German Sport University, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The German Research Center For Elite Sports, Momentum, German Sport University, Cologne, Germany ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soylu</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah Ruhi</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Biophysics Department, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ertan</LastName><ForeName>Hayri</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Institute of Movement and Training Science, Eskisehir Technical University, Eskisehir, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>24DRP004</GrantID><Agency>Eski&#x15f;ehir Teknik &#xdc;niversitesi</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance band</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41490005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alt T, Knicker AJ, Str&#xfc;der HK. Factors influencing the reproducibility of isokinetic knee flexion and extension test findings. Isokinet Exerc Sci 22: 333&#x2013;342, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade MDS, Fleury AM, de Lira CAB, Dubas JP, da Silva AC. Profile of isokinetic eccentric-to-concentric strength ratios of shoulder rotator muscles in elite female team handball players. J Sports Sci 28: 743&#x2013;749, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besomi M, Hodges PW, Clancy EA, et al. Consensus for experimental design in electromyography (CEDE) project: Amplitude normalization matrix. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 53: 102438, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghero YO, Salehpour M, McNeese MD, et al. Multileaf field-in-field forward-planned intensity-modulated dose compensation for whole-breast irradiation is associated with reduced contralateral breast dose: A phantom model comparison. Radiother Oncol 82: 324&#x2013;328, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borm KJ, Kleine Vennekate J, Vagedes J, et al. A comprehensive prospective comparison of acute skin toxicity after hypofractionated and normofractionated radiation therapy in breast cancer. Cancers (Basel) 13: 5826, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema BS, Kilbreath SL, Fahey PP, Delaney GP, Atlantis E. Safety and efficacy of progressive resistance training in breast cancer: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Breast Cancer Res Treat 148: 249&#x2013;268, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhikara BS, Parang K. Global cancer statistics 2022: The trends projection analysis. Chem Biol Lett 10: 451, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Garcia-Masso X, Triplett NT, et al. Construct and concurrent validation of a new resistance intensity scale for exercise with Thera-Band&#xae; elastic bands. J Sports Sci Med 13: 758&#x2013;766, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darendeli A, Ertan H, Cu&#x11f; M, Wikstrom E, Enoka RM. Comparison of EMG activity in shank muscles between individuals with and without chronic ankle instability when running on a treadmill. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 70: 102773, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira PA, Blasczyk JC, Souza Junior G, et al. Effects of elastic resistance exercise on muscle strength and functional performance in healthy adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Phys Act Health 14: 317&#x2013;327, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Casolo A, Negro F, et al. The increase in muscle force after 4 weeks of strength training is mediated by adaptations in motor unit recruitment and rate coding. J Physiology 597: 1873&#x2013;1887, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake JD, Callaghan JP. Elimination of electrocardiogram contamination from electromyogram signals: An evaluation of currently used removal techniques. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 16: 175&#x2013;187, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerland L, Baumann FT, Niels T. Resistance exercise for breast cancer patients? Evidence from the last decade. Breast Care 16: 657&#x2013;663, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PWM, Lonsdale C, et al. The effect of resistance training on markers of immune function and inflammation in previously sedentary women recovering from breast cancer: A randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 155: 471&#x2013;482, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Shorter KA, Marshall PW. Changes in unilateral upper limb muscular strength and electromyographic activity after a 16-week strength training intervention in survivors of breast cancer. J Strength Cond Res 33: 225&#x2013;233, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harput G, Demirci S, Soylu AR, Bayrakci Tunay V. Association between quadriceps muscle thickness and knee function in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed athletes: A cross-sectional study. Physiother Theory Practice 39: 2171&#x2013;2179, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen S, Foss&#xe5; K, Nesvold IL, Malinen E, Foss&#xe5; SD. Arm and shoulder morbidity following surgery and radiotherapy for breast cancer. Acta Oncol Madr 53: 521&#x2013;529, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson K, Ingvar C, Albertsson M, Ekdahl C. Arm lymphoedema, shoulder mobility and muscle strength after breast cancer treatment? A prospective 2-year study. Adv Physiother 3: 55&#x2013;66, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr AJ, Dodwell D, McGale P, et al. Adjuvant and neoadjuvant breast cancer treatments: A systematic review of their effects on mortality. Cancer Treat Rev 105: 102375, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kestin LL, Sharpe MB, Frazier RC, et al. Intensity modulation to improve dose uniformity with tangential breast radiotherapy: Initial clinical experience. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 48: 1559&#x2013;1568, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilbreath SL, Refshauge KM, Beith JM, et al. Upper limb progressive resistance training and stretching exercises following surgery for early breast cancer: A randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 133: 667&#x2013;676, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klassen O, Schmidt ME, Ulrich CM, et al. Muscle strength in breast cancer patients receiving different treatment regimes. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 8: 305&#x2013;316, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauridsen MC, Christiansen P, Hessov IB. The effect of physiotherapy on shoulder function in patients surgically treated for breast cancer: A randomized study. Acta Oncol Madr 44: 449&#x2013;457, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal NFBdS, Oliveira HFd, Carrara HHA. Supervised physical therapy in women treated with radiotherapy for breast cancer. Rev Latino-Am Enferm 24: e2755, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipps DB, Sachdev S, Strauss JB. Quantifying radiation dose delivered to individual shoulder muscles during breast radiotherapy. Radiother Oncol 122: 431&#x2013;436, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Y-C, Yasuda G, Fitzgerald TJ, Urie MM. Intensity modulation for breast treatment using static multi-leaf collimators. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 46: 187&#x2013;194, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Hui B, Yang D, et al. Efficacy and safety analysis of hypofractionated and conventional fractionated radiotherapy in postoperative breast cancer patients. BMC Cancer 24: 181, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marta GN, Coles C, Kaidar-Person O, et al. The use of moderately hypofractionated post-operative radiation therapy for breast cancer in clinical practice: A critical review. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol 156: 103090, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGovern A, Mahony N, Mockler D, Fleming N. Efficacy of resistance training during adjuvant chemotherapy and radiation therapy in cancer care: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer 30: 3701&#x2013;3719, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros Torres D, Jorge Koifman R, da Silva Santos S. Impact on fatigue of different types of physical exercise during adjuvant chemotherapy and radiotherapy in breast cancer: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer 30: 4651&#x2013;4662, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musanti R. A study of exercise modality and physical self-esteem in breast cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 352&#x2013;361, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noal S, Levy C, Hardouin A, et al. One-year longitudinal study of fatigue, cognitive functions, and quality of life after adjuvant radiotherapy for breast cancer. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 81: 795&#x2013;803, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Offersen BV, Boersma LJ, Kirkove C, et al. ESTRO consensus guideline on target volume delineation for elective radiation therapy of early stage breast cancer. Radiother Oncol 114: 3&#x2013;10, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen JR, Ashton A, Bliss JM, et al. Effect of radiotherapy fraction size on tumour control in patients with early-stage breast cancer after local tumour excision: Long-term results of a randomised trial. Lancet Oncol 7: 467&#x2013;471, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petito EL, Naz&#xe1;rio ACP, Martinelli SE, Facina G, De Guti&#xe9;rrez MGR. Application of a domicile-based exercise program for shoulder rehabilitation after breast cancer surgery. Rev Lat Am Enfermagem 20: 35&#x2013;43, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piraux E, Caty G, Aboubakar Nana F, Reychler G. Effects of exercise therapy in cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy treatment: A narrative review. SAGE Open Med 8: 2050312120922657, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potthoff K, Schmidt ME, Wiskemann J, et al. Randomized controlled trial to evaluate the effects of progressive resistance training compared to progressive muscle relaxation in breast cancer patients undergoing adjuvant radiotherapy: The BEST study. BMC Cancer 13: 162&#x2013;11, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp J, Hadamitzky C, Henkenberens C, Christiansen H, Steinmann D, Bruns F. Frequency and risk factors for arm lymphedema after multimodal breast-conserving treatment of nodal positive breast cancer - a long-term observation. Radiat Oncol 14: 39&#x2013;8, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt M, Wiskemann J, Krakowski-Roosen H, et al. Progressive resistance versus relaxation training for breast cancer patients during adjuvant chemotherapy: Design and rationale of a randomized controlled trial (BEATE study). Contemp Clin Trials 34: 117&#x2013;125, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt T, Weisser B, Duerkop J, et al. Comparing endurance and resistance training with standard care during chemotherapy for patients with primary breast cancer. Anticancer Res 35: 5623&#x2013;5630, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamley D, Lascurain-Aguirrebe&#xf1;a I, Oskrochi R, Srinaganathan R. Shoulder morbidity after treatment for breast cancer is bilateral and greater after mastectomy. Acta Oncol Madr 51: 1045&#x2013;1053, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamley DR, Srinanaganathan R, Weatherall R, et al. Changes in shoulder muscle size and activity following treatment for breast cancer. Breast Cancer Res Treat 106: 19&#x2013;27, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>START Trialists' Group, Bentzen SM, Agrawal RK, et al. The UK Standardisation of breast radiotherapy (START) trial B of radiotherapy hypofractionation for treatment of early breast cancer: A randomised trial. Lancet 371: 1098&#x2013;1107, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steindorf K, Schmidt ME, Klassen O, et al. Randomized, controlled trial of resistance training in breast cancer patients receiving adjuvant radiotherapy: Results on cancer-related fatigue and quality of life. Ann Oncol 25: 2237&#x2013;2243, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain D, Brawner CA. ACSM&#x2019;s Resource Manual for Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins: Human Movement Sciences Faculty Books, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Hayashi S, Kajiura Y, et al. Evaluation of the field-in-field technique with lung blocks for breast tangential radiotherapy. Nagoya J Med Sci 77: 339&#x2013;345, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-L, Fang H, Song Y-W, et al. Hypofractionated versus conventional fractionated postmastectomy radiotherapy for patients with high-risk breast cancer: A randomised, non-inferiority, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol 20: 352&#x2013;360, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham J, Pizzari T, Stansfeld K, Burnside A, Watson L. Quantifying &#x201c;normal&#x201d; shoulder muscle activity during abduction. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 20: 212&#x2013;222, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiskemann J, Schmidt ME, Klassen O, et al. Effects of 12&#x2010;week resistance training during radiotherapy in breast cancer patients. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 1500&#x2013;1510, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>