<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41781437</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Particle swarm optimized deep learning for jamming detection and throughput enhancement in cognitive radio networks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8715</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41642-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cognitive Radio Networks (CRNs) are essential for improving spectrum efficiency in 5G and beyond; however, their open and adaptive nature makes them highly vulnerable to jamming attacks. The purpose of this work is to develop an anti-jamming framework that jointly addresses jammer detection and frequency selection under adversarial conditions. The novelty of this work lies in jointly addressing strategic anti-jamming decision-making and data-driven jammer detection within a single unified framework. Motivated by the limitations of standalone game-theoretic, evolutionary, and deep learning approaches in dynamic adversarial environments, we propose a hybrid anti-jamming framework that integrates game theory, deep learning, and particle swarm optimization (PSO). Game theory is employed to model the strategic interaction between secondary users and jammers, enabling utility-aware frequency hopping (FH) decisions, while a PSO-driven deep neural network (DNN), termed DeepSwarm, is designed for accurate and robust jammer detection. The strength lies in leveraging PSO to enhance the convergence speed and robustness of the DNN in dynamic jamming environments. Simulation results demonstrate that DeepSwarm achieves 98.10% accuracy, 98.30% recall, 98.10% precision, and a 98.05% F1-score, outperforming SVM, linear regression, and stacking baselines. Furthermore, FH guided by the proposed detection framework improves channel utilization and increases normalized throughput by up to 32% compared to static selection under varying jamming probabilities. These findings confirm the scalability and effectiveness of the proposed framework for securing CRNs in adversarial environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imran</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Mobile Communications Research Laboratory, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Khalid</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Istanbul Ayd&#x131;n University, 34295, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhiwen</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Mobile Communications Research Laboratory, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Purple Mountain Laboratories, Nanjing, 211100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nan</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Mobile Communications Research Laboratory, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qahmash</LastName><ForeName>Ayman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Informatics and Computer Systems Department, King Khalid University, 61421, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atteia</LastName><ForeName>Ghada</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Technology, College of Computer and Information Sciences, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box 84428, Riyadh, 11671, Saudi Arabia. geatteiaallah@pnu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akram</LastName><ForeName>Tallha</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Systems, College of Computer Engineering and Sciences, Prince Sattam bin Abdulaziz University, 11942, Al-Kharj, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RGP2/283/46</GrantID><Agency>Deanship of Scientific Research, King Khalid University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PNURSP2026R748</GrantID><Agency>Deanship of Scientific Research, Princess Nourah Bint Abdulrahman University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PSAU/2026/R/1447</GrantID><Agency>Deanship of Scientific Research, Prince Sattam bin Abdulaziz University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-jamming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive radio networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Jammer detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PSO-optimized deep neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Throughput maximization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41781437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12979785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41642-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41642-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tejojith, G., Sharma, K., Singh, A. &amp; Hoque, S. Survey of AI and ML techniques for enhancing performance of 5G cognitive radio networks. In 2024 Second International Conference Computational and Characterization Techniques in Engineering &amp; Sciences (IC3TES), 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haykin, S. Cognitive radio: Brain-empowered wireless communications. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun.</i><b>23</b>, 201&#x2013;220 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSAC.2004.839380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akyildiz, I. F., Lee, W. Y., Vuran, M. C. &amp; Mohanty, S. Next generation/dynamic spectrum access/cognitive radio wireless networks: A survey. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>50</b>, 2127&#x2013;2159 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2006.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, U. V. et al. Ai-powered IoT: A survey on integrating artificial intelligence with IoT for enhanced security, efficiency, and smart applications. IEEE Access (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R. K. &amp; Rawat, D. B. Advances on security threats and countermeasures for cognitive radio networks: A survey. <i>IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutor.</i><b>17</b>, 1023&#x2013;1043 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2014.2380998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Matari, N. Y., Zahary, A. T., Al-Shargabi, A. &amp; A.,. A survey on advancements in blockchain-enabled spectrum access security for 6G cognitive radio IoT networks. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 30990 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11681167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39730759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahuja, P., Sethi, P. &amp; Chauhan, N. A comprehensive survey of security threats, detection, countermeasures, and future directions for physical and network layers in cognitive radio networks. <i>Multimed. Tools Appl.</i><b>83</b>, 32715&#x2013;32738 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-023-16642-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Dynamic spectrum anti-jamming communications: Challenges and opportunities. <i>IEEE Commun. Mag.</i><b>58</b>, 79&#x2013;85 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MCOM.001.1900530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K., Ng, S. X., Qureshi, I. M., Malik, A. N. &amp; Muhaidat, S. Anti-jamming game to combat intelligent jamming for cognitive radio networks. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 137941&#x2013;137956 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3117563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeem, M. M., Khan, A. B. &amp; Azeem, U. Application of short erasure correcting codes for cognitive radio. In <i>2017 IEEE 86th vehicular technology conference (VTC-Fall)</i>, 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito, A., Sebasti&#xe3;o, P. &amp; Velez, F. J. Hybrid matched filter detection spectrum sensing. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 165504&#x2013;165516 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3134796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budati, A. K. &amp; Valiveti, H. Identify the user presence by glrt and np detection criteria in cognitive radio spectrum sensing. <i>Int. J. Commun. Syst.</i><b>35</b>, e4142 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dac.4142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakhov, V. &amp; Koo, I. Applying change point detection technique to dynamically support network security. In <i>Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Res. Innov. Vis. Future (RIVF)</i>, 503&#x2013;507 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunori, S. K., Jain, S. &amp; Juneja, P. Dynamic spectrum allocation in 5G network using genetic algorithm and particle swarm optimization. In <i>Proc. Int. Conf. I-SMAC (IoT in Social, Mobile, Analytics &amp; Cloud)</i>, 527&#x2013;533 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K., Malik, A. N., Waseem, A., Roslee, M. B. &amp; Ahmed, S. Game-theoretic frameworks for anti-jamming in cognitive radio networks: Advancements and strategies. In <i>Proc. IEEE Multimedia Univ. Eng. Conf. (MECON)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran, M., Zhiwen, P., Nan, L., Sajjad, M. &amp; Butt, F. M. Anti-jamming for cognitive radio networks with stackelberg game-assisted DSSS approach. <i>EURASIP J. Wirel. Commun. Netw.</i><b>2024</b>, 73 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13638-024-02397-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran, M., Zhiwen, P., Nan, L. &amp; Ikram, M. Enhancing cognitive radio networks performance with game-theoretic anti-jamming strategies and trial-error learning. In <i>2024 9th International Conference on Mechatronics Engineering (ICOM)</i>, 368&#x2013;373 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarikhani, R. &amp; Keynia, F. Cooperative spectrum sensing meets machine learning: Deep reinforcement learning approach. <i>IEEE Commun. Lett.</i><b>24</b>, 1459&#x2013;1462 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LCOMM.2020.2984430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, A. &amp; Choi, K. Deep learning-based selective spectrum sensing and allocation in cognitive vehicular radio networks. <i>Veh. Commun.</i><b>41</b>, 100606 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benazzouza, S., Ridouani, M., Salahdine, F. &amp; Hayar, A. A novel prediction model for malicious users detection and spectrum sensing based on stacking and deep learning. <i>Sensors</i><b>22</b>, 6477 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22176477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36080936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar, A. H., Atia, G. &amp; Guirguis, M. Adaptive topologies against jamming attacks in wireless networks: A game-theoretic approach. <i>J. Netw. Comput. Appl.</i><b>121</b>, 44&#x2013;58 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnca.2018.06.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaichandran, R. et al. The defense against jamming attack in cognitive radio networks: Energy efficiency management perspective. <i>Microprocess. Microsyst.</i><b>82</b>, 103816 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micpro.2020.103816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha, Y. &amp; Sarasvathi, V. A model-free cognitive anti-jamming strategy using adversarial learning algorithm. <i>Cybern. Inf. Technol.</i><b>22</b>, 56&#x2013;72 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, H., Xu, L., Zou, Y., Wang, X. &amp; Choo, K.-K.R. Three-stage stackelberg game for defending against full-duplex active eavesdropping attacks in cooperative communication. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>67</b>, 10788&#x2013;10799 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2018.2868900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K., Qureshi, I. M., Malik, A. N. &amp; Ng, S. X. Bandwidth-efficient frequency hopping based anti-jamming game for cognitive radio assisted wireless sensor networks. In <i>2021 IEEE 93rd Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2021-Spring)</i>, 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Hierarchical coordinated anti-jamming channel access in clustering networks: a multi-leader multi-follower stackelberg game approach. <i>EURASIP J. Adv. Signal Process.</i><b>2021</b>, 42 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13634-021-00764-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K. et al. Mitigating rate-aware jamming attacks: A deceptive anti-jamming approach with enhanced utility. In 2023 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET), 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K. et al. Entice to trap: Enhanced protection against a rate-aware intelligent jammer in cognitive radio networks. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b>, 2957 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14052957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammour, I. &amp; Chalhoub, G. Evaluation of rate adaptation algorithms in IEEE 802.11 networks. <i>Electronics</i><b>9</b>, 1436 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics9091436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran, M., Ibrahim, K., Saleem, A., Waseem, A. &amp; Qureshi, R. Optimal deception in cognitive radio security: A joint nash equilibrium approach to rate adaptation and frequency hopping under jamming. In International Conference on Electrical, Communication and Computer Engineering (ICECCE), 1&#x2013;6 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, K., Qureshi, I. M., Malik, A. N. &amp; Waseem, A. Cover fire: Deceptive anti-jamming using pseudo secondary users in cognitive radio networks. In <i>2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)</i>, 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. S. et al. Support vector machine-based classification of malicious users in cognitive radio networks. <i>Wirel. Commun. Mobile Comput.</i><b>2020</b>, 8846948 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/8846948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H., Song, T., Wu, J., Li, X. &amp; Hu, J. Cooperative spectrum sensing algorithm based on support vector machine against ssdf attack. In <i>2018 IEEE international conference on communications workshops (ICC workshops)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazizadeh, E., Nikpour, B., Moghadam, D. A. &amp; Nezamabadi-pour, H. A PSO-based weighting method to enhance machine learning techniques for cooperative spectrum sensing in CR networks. In <i>Proc. 1st IEEE Conf. Swarm Intell. Evol. Comput</i>. (CSIEC), 113&#x2013;118 (IEEE, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha, Y. &amp; Sarasvathi, V. A novel self-exploration scheme for learning optimal policies against dynamic jamming attacks in cognitive radio networks. <i>Cybern. Inf. Technol</i>. 23, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dipinkrishnan, R. &amp; Kumaravelu, V. B. Enhancing sum spectral efficiency and fairness in NOMA systems: A comparative study of metaheuristic algorithms for power allocation. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>12</b>, 85165&#x2013;85177 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3415813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem, Y. &amp; Rehmani, M. H. Primary radio user activity models for cognitive radio networks: A survey. <i>J. Netw. Comput. Appl.</i><b>43</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnca.2014.04.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabuj, S. R., Asiedu, D. K. P., Lee, K.-J. &amp; Jo, H.-S. Delay optimization in mobile edge computing: Cognitive UAV-assisted embb and mMTC services. <i>IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw.</i><b>8</b>, 1019&#x2013;1033 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCCN.2022.3149089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabuj, S. R., Ahmed, S. &amp; Jo, H.-S. Multiple CUAV-enabled mMTC and URLLC services: Review of energy efficiency and latency performance. <i>IEEE Trans. Green Commun. Netw.</i><b>7</b>, 1369&#x2013;1382 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGCN.2023.3281350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Energy efficiency of secure cognitive radio networks with cooperative spectrum sharing. <i>IEEE Trans. Mobile Comput.</i><b>18</b>, 305&#x2013;318 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2018.2836902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Zheng, K., Liu, X.-Y., Wang, X. &amp; Zhu, Y. Hierarchical cooperation improves delay in cognitive radio networks with heterogeneous mobile secondary nodes. <i>IEEE Trans. Mobile Comput.</i><b>18</b>, 2871&#x2013;2884 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2018.2885268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munir, M. F., Basit, A., Khan, W., Saleem, A. &amp; Al-Salehi, A. A comprehensive study of past, present, and future of spectrum sharing and information embedding techniques in joint wireless communication and radar systems. <i>Wirel. Commun. Mobile Comput.</i><b>2022</b>, 9642849 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9642849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Zheng, K., Chi, K. &amp; Zhu, Y.-H. Cooperative spectrum sensing optimization in energy-harvesting cognitive radio networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun.</i><b>19</b>, 7663&#x2013;7676 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TWC.2020.3015260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, K., Jia, X., Chi, K. &amp; Liu, X. DDPG-based joint time and energy management in ambient backscatter-assisted hybrid underlay CRNs. <i>IEEE Trans. Commun.</i><b>71</b>, 441&#x2013;456 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2022.3221422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, W., Kim, M. &amp; Cho, D.-H. Deep cooperative sensing: Cooperative spectrum sensing based on convolutional neural networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>68</b>, 3005&#x2013;3009 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2019.2891291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, F., Qiu, R. C. &amp; Browning, J. P. Spectrum sensing with small-sized data sets in cognitive radio: Algorithms and analysis. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>64</b>, 77&#x2013;87 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2014.2321388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solanki, S., Dehalwar, V. &amp; Choudhary, J. Deep learning for spectrum sensing in cognitive radio. <i>Symmetry</i><b>13</b>, 147 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym13010147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J., Lou, H., Zhang, W. &amp; Sang, G. An intelligent anti-jamming scheme for cognitive radio based on deep reinforcement learning. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>8</b>, 202563&#x2013;202572 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3036027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed, S. N. et al. Deep neural networks for spectrum sensing: A review. <i>IEEE access</i><b>11</b>, 89591&#x2013;89615 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3305388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F., Zhang, X., Hu, R. Q., Papathanassiou, A. &amp; Meng, W. Resource allocation based on deep neural networks for cognitive radio networks. In <i>International Conference on Communications in China (ICCC)</i>, 40&#x2013;45 (IEEE, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rainio, O. et al. Comparison of thresholds for a convolutional neural network classifying medical images. <i>Int. J. Data Sci. Anal.</i><b>20</b>, 2093&#x2013;2099 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41060-024-00584-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>