<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41158153</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5370</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>89</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EClinicalMedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EClinicalMedicine</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recommendations for lung ventilation and perfusion assessment with chest electrical impedance tomography in critically ill adult patients: an international evidence-based and expert Delphi consensus study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103575</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103575</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103575</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.eclinm.2025.103575</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Electrical impedance tomography (EIT) is a non-invasive, radiation-free imaging technique that allows for monitoring of lung ventilation and perfusion at the bedside. However, there is a lack of evidence-based and international expert consensus statement of EIT clinical applications in adult critically ill patients. The purpose of this study was to provide evidence-based and expert consensus recommendations for lung ventilation and perfusion assessment with chest EIT in adult critically ill patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A English literature search was conducted of MEDLINE, EMBASE, Web of Science and Cochrane Library databases between January 1, 1990, and J March 22, 2024. Eligible literature included systematic reviews, meta-analyses, cohort/clinical trials, case reports and review articles that focused on chest EIT application for lung ventilation and perfusion in adult population. The animal studies were excluded. An international global panel of intensivists, physicians, biomedical engineers with expertise in the field of EIT clinical applications, guideline methodologists and biostatisticians, was convened. The Oxford Centre of Evidence Based Medicine's Levels of Evidence method was used to rate the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations. Subsequently, with a Delphi process (two online surveys at June 3 and September 13, 2024), a group of expanded global experts from 12 different countries developed recommendations. We defined a strong consensus as agreement of &gt;95% experts, consensus as agreement of 75-95% experts and no consensus as agreement&lt;75%. The study is registered with PREPARE, PREPARE-2024CN166.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The final 14 questions generated a total of 11,159 abstracts, of which 242 publications were identified relevant to develop 87 recommendations. The 87 statements focused on data acquisition and analysis, clinical application, and future perspectives were developed and modified. Twenty experts in the expanded group completed the survey in the first round, and eighteen experts in the expanded group completed the survey in the second round. At the end of the Delphi process, 15 recommendations were identified as strong consensus, 70 recommendations as consensus, and two recommendations did not reach consensus. The statements with strong consensus were focused on data acquisition, analysis, training and interpretation, assessment of posture effect on lung ventilation, lung perfusion and ventilation/perfusion match, and the statements without agreement were focused on regional ventilation delay ratio, perfusion assessment with heart-beat related EIT signal. Recommendations were mostly based on moderate quality of evidence (3/87 was A grade, 47/87 was B grade, 37/87 was C-D grade of recommendation).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our study provides evidence-based recommendations with high consensus for using chest EIT for lung ventilation and perfusion in adult critically ill patients. Evidence and expert consensus supports the application of EIT in the detection of dynamic pulmonary abnormalities and inhomogeneities, which may significantly influence clinical management and final diagnosis. High quality evidence is urgently needed for the development of EIT guidelines in the future.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">National High-Level Hospital Clinical Research Funding, National Key Research and Development Program, National Natural Science Foundation of China, Peking Union Medical College Hospital Talent Cultivation Program Category C.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Huaiwu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Department of Critical Care Medicine, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zhanqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Respiratory Diseases, Guangzhou Institute of Respiratory Health, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou Medical University, Department of Critical Care Medicine, Guangzhou Medical University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Engineering, Guangzhou Medical University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Technical Medicine, Furtwangen University, VS-Schwenningen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becher</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, University Medical Center Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Kiel, Kiel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellani</LastName><ForeName>Giacomo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Medical Sciences - CISMed, University of Trento, Trento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia and Intensive Care, Santa Chiara Hospital, Trento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshida</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amato</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo B P</ForeName><Initials>MBP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divisao de Pneumologia, Instituto do Coracao, Hospital das Clinicas HCFMUSP, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Sao Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, Department of Critical Care Medicine, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frerichs</LastName><ForeName>In&#xe9;z</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, University Medical Center Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Kiel, Kiel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>REspiratory and Critical Care medicine EIT study (RECCE) group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>EClinicalMedicine</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101733727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-5370</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chest electrical impedance tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Critically ill patient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence-based</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung perfusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung ventilation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>ZZ received consulting fee from Clario and Dr&#xe4;ger Medical. GB received lecturing fees from Dr&#xe4;ger Medical (various countries). IF reports institutional funding from the European Commission (WELMO project: Grant 825572) and personal support for attending a meeting with a honorarium for a guest speaker presentation (Dr&#xe4;ger Medical). MBPA reports that his experimental research laboratory has received grants in the last five years from Timpel S.A. MBPA is also a minority shareholder in Timpel. HH,TB, TY and YL declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayford</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berra</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bodenstein</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borges</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Batista</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira Costa</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo Leite</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goligher</LastName><ForeName>Ewan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heines</LastName><ForeName>Serge</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jonkman</LastName><ForeName>Annemijn</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mauri</LastName><ForeName>Tommaso</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piraino</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pulletz</LastName><ForeName>Sven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scaramuzzo</LastName><ForeName>Gaetano</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmidt</LastName><ForeName>Matthieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shono</LastName><ForeName>Atsuko</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spinelli</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fernando</LastName><ForeName>Suarez-Sipmann</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woo</LastName><ForeName>Eung Je</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wrigge</LastName><ForeName>Hermann</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Yelin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sang</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41158153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12555788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2025.103575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5370(25)00508-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scaramuzzo G., Pavlovsky B., Adler A., et al. Electrical impedance tomography monitoring in adult ICU patients: state-of-the-art, recommendations for standardized acquisition, processing, and clinical use, and future directions. Crit Care. 2024;28(1):377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11577873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39563476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro De Santis Santiago R., Xin Y., Gaulton T.G., et al. Lung imaging acquisition with electrical impedance tomography: tackling common pitfalls. Anesthesiology. 2023;139(3):329&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37402247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Amato M.B., van Kaam A.H., et al. Chest electrical impedance tomography examination, data analysis, terminology, clinical use and recommendations: consensus statement of the TRanslational EIT developmeNt stuDy group. Thorax. 2017;72(1):83&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5329047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27596161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisse J.J., Scaramuzzo G., Pellegrini M., et al. Clinical implementation of advanced respiratory monitoring with esophageal pressure and electrical impedance tomography: results from an international survey and focus group discussion. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2024;12(1):93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11493933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39432136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeremy Howick I.C., Paul G., Greenhalgh T., et al. Oxford Centre for Evidence-Based Medicine; 2011. The 2011 Oxford CEBM Levels of Evidence (Introductory Document)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwers M.C., Kerkvliet K., Spithoff K. The AGREE reporting checklist: a tool to improve reporting of clinical practice guidelines. BMJ. 2016;352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten J., Stueber T., Voigt N., Teschner E., Heinze H. Influence of different electrode belt positions on electrical impedance tomography imaging of regional ventilation: a prospective observational study. Crit Care. 2016;20:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer M.S., Wania V., Bastin B., et al. Electrical impedance tomography during major open upper abdominal surgery: a pilot-study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2014;14:51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4094413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25018668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koldova K., Rara A., Muller M., Tyll T., Roubik K. Cranial electrode belt position improves diagnostic possibilities of electrical impedance tomography during laparoscopic surgery with capnoperitoneum. Sensors (Basel) 2023;23(20):8644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37896737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue C., He H., Su L., et al. A novel method for diaphragm-based electrode belt position of electrical impedance tomography by ultrasound. J Intensive Care. 2023;11(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10518967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericsson E., Tesselaar E., Sjoberg F. Effect of electrode belt and body positions on regional pulmonary ventilation- and perfusion-related impedance changes measured by electric impedance tomography. PLoS One. 2016;11(6)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruana L., Barnett A., Tronstad O., Paratz J., Chang A., Fraser J. An observational study into the effect of gender and position on four methods of assessing ventilation using electrical impedance tomography. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2018;46(2):227&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Gao Z., Cao X., et al. The influence of gravity on electrical impedance tomography measurements during upper body position change. Heliyon. 2023;9(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun F., Proen&#xe7;a M., Lemay M., et al. Limitations and challenges of EIT-based monitoring of stroke volume and pulmonary artery pressure. Physiol Meas. 2018;39(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riera J., P&#xe9;rez P., Roca O., Masclans J.R., Rello J. Effect of high flow nasal cannula and body position on endexpiratory lung volume. A cohort study of healthy individuals using electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med. 2012;38:S41&#x2013;S42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graf M., Riedel T. Electrical impedance tomography signals in the lung are highly position dependent. Eur Respir J. 2014;44(Suppl 58):P1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graf M., Riedel T. Electrical impedance tomography: amplitudes of cardiac related impedance changes in the lung are highly position dependent. PLoS One. 2017;12(11)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Vogt B., Deuss K., Hennig V., Sch&#xe4;dler D., H&#xe4;ndel C. Distribution of regional lung function in upright healthy subjects determined by electrical impedance tomography in two chest examination planes. Physiol Meas. 2024;45(1):015001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holder D.S., Temple A. Clinical &amp; Physiological Applications of Electrical Impedance Tomography. 1993. Effectiveness of the Sheffield EIT system in distinguishing patients with pulmonary pathology from a series of normal subjects.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reifferscheid F., Elke G., Pulletz S., et al. Regional ventilation distribution determined by electrical impedance tomography: reproducibility and effects of posture and chest plane. Respirology. 2011;16(3):523&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21261780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun F., Proen&#xe7;a M., Adler A., Riedel T., Thiran J.P., Sol&#xe0; J. Accuracy and reliability of noninvasive stroke volume monitoring via ECG-gated 3D electrical impedance tomography in healthy volunteers. PLoS One. 2018;13(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krueger-Ziolek S., Schullcke B., Zhao Z., et al. Multi-layer ventilation inhomogeneity in cystic fibrosis. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2016;233:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27476932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulletz S., Elke G., Zick G., et al. Effects of restricted thoracic movement on the regional distribution of ventilation. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2010;54(6):751&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Braun P., Dudykevych T., Hahn G., Gen&#xe9;e D., Hellige G. Distribution of ventilation in young and elderly adults determined by electrical impedance tomography. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2004;143(1):63&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15477173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Dudykevych T., Hinz J., Bodenstein M., Hahn G., Hellige G. Gravity effects on regional lung ventilation determined by functional EIT during parabolic flights. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2001;91(1):39&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11408411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedel T., Richards T., Schibler A. The value of electrical impedance tomography in assessing the effect of body position and positive airway pressures on regional lung ventilation in spontaneously breathing subjects. Intensive Care Med. 2005;31(11):1522&#x2013;1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagenaar J., Adler A. Electrical impedance tomography in 3D using two electrode planes: characterization and evaluation. Physiol Meas. 2016;37(6):922&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27203154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Y., Ji Z., Zhang W., et al. Comparison of three kinds of electrode-skin interfaces for electrical impedance scanning. Ann Biomed Eng. 2010;38(6):2032&#x2013;2039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20437203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldmann A.D., Wodack K.H., M&#xe4;rz A., et al. Contact impedances of textile electrodes for electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2015;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Pulletz S., Elke G., Gawelczyk B., Frerichs A., Weiler N. Patient examinations using electrical impedance tomography--sources of interference in the intensive care unit. Physiol Meas. 2011;32(12):L1&#x2013;L10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22031540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T.T., Jang G.Y., Kim Y.E., Oh T.I., Wi H., Woo E.J. Influence of current injection scheme on electrical impedance tomography for monitoring of the respiratory function of obese subjects. J Appl Phys. 2020;128(17)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcala G., Morais C., De Santis R., et al. Distribution of ventilation in obese and Non-obese patients: obesity greatly attenuates peep-induced hyperdistension. Crit Care. 2018;22:200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6098836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30121090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce A.K., McGuire W.C., Elliott A.R., Fine J., Prisk G., Malhotra A. Effect of body position and Body Mass Index (BMI) on distribution of ventilation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;207:A5772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulton R., Millar J.E., Merza M., et al. Prophylactic postoperative high flow Nasal oxygen versus conventional oxygen therapy in Obese patients undergoing bariatric surgery (OXYBAR Study): a pilot randomised controlled trial. Obes Surg. 2021;31(11):4799&#x2013;4807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34387826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandao D., Goncalves C., Silva S.A., et al. Regional pulmonary ventilation analysis guided by electrical impedance tomography in morbid obese patients undergoing videolaparoscopic gastroplasty. Eur Respir J. 2017;50(Suppl 61):PA2472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlandsson K., Odenstedt H., Lundin S., Stenqvist O. Positive end-expiratory pressure optimization using electric impedance tomography in morbidly obese patients during laparoscopic gastric bypass surgery. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2006;50(7):833&#x2013;839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16879466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquis F., Coulombe N., Costa R., Gagnon H., Guardo R., Skrobik Y. Electrical impedance tomography's correlation to lung volume is not influenced by anthropometric parameters. J Clin Monit Comput. 2006;20(3):201&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16688390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nestler C., Simon P., Hammermuller S., et al. Feasibility of electric impedance tomography based peep-titration in morbidly obese patients during anesthesia. Intensive Care Med. 2013;39:S379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nestler C., Simon P., Petroff D., et al. Individualized positive end-expiratory pressure in Obese patients during general anaesthesia: a randomized controlled clinical trial using electrical impedance tomography. Br J Anaesth. 2017;119(6):1194&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29045567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon P., Nestler C., Hammerm&#xfc; Ller S., et al. Effects of individualized peep-adjustment in obese patients undergoing bariatric surgery. Intensive Care Med. 2013;39</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon P., Petroff D., Hammermuller S., et al. Regional ventilation distribution in obese patients with normal lungs: effects of individualized positive end-expiratory pressure. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;195:A3019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z.Y., Ye S.S., Fan Y., et al. Individualized positive end-expiratory pressure with and without recruitment maneuvers in obese patients during bariatric surgery. Kaohsiung J Med Sci. 2022;38(9):858&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11896333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35866347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun M., Ruscher L., Fuchs A., et al. Atelectasis in obese patients undergoing laparoscopic bariatric surgery are not increased upon discharge from post anesthesia care unit. Front Med. 2023;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon P., Girrbach F., Petroff D., et al. Individualized versus fixed positive end-expiratory pressure for intraoperative mechanical ventilation in obese patients: a secondary analysis. Anesthesiology. 2021;134(6):887&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli J., Santiago R.R.S., Teggia Droghi M., et al. Lung recruitment in Obese patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Anesthesiology. 2019;130(5):791&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Santis Santiago R., Teggia Droghi M., Fumagalli J., et al. High pleural pressure prevents alveolar overdistension and hemodynamic collapse in acute respiratory distress syndrome with class III obesity. A clinical trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;203(5):575&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Zhao Z.Q., Becher T. Simple electrical impedance tomography measures for the assessment of ventilation distribution. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;201(3):386&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6999101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31526320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Frerichs I. Prone positioning in COVID-19 ARDS: comment. Anesthesiology. 2023;138(6):666&#x2013;668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10168109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36880983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Fu F., Frerichs I., M&#xf6;ller K., Dai M., Zhao Z. The calculation of electrical impedance tomography based silent spaces requires individual thorax and lung contours. Physiol Meas. 2022;43(9):09NT02.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling S., Zhao Z. End-expiratory lung impedance measured with electrical impedance tomography at different days are not comparable. Crit Care Med. 2023;51(2):e70&#x2013;e72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36661473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadaro S., Mauri T., Bohm S.H., et al. Variation of poorly ventilated lung units (silent spaces) measured by electrical impedance tomography to dynamically assess recruitment. Crit Care. 2018;22:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29386048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli E., Kircher M., Stender B., et al. Unmatched ventilation and perfusion measured by electrical impedance tomography predicts the outcome of ARDS. Crit Care. 2021;25(1):192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Chang M.Y., Frerichs I., et al. Regional air trapping in acute exacerbation of obstructive lung diseases measured with electrical impedance tomography: a feasibility study. Minerva Anestesiol. 2020;86(2):172&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31808658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagiannidis C., Waldmann A.D., R&#xf3;ka P.L., et al. Regional expiratory time constants in severe respiratory failure estimated by electrical impedance tomography: a feasibility study. Crit Care. 2018;22(1):221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6148957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30236123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang L., Zhao Z., Yun P.J., et al. Qualitative and quantitative assessment of pendelluft: a simple method based on electrical impedance tomography. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8(19):1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33178748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinz J., Hahn G., Neumann P., et al. End-expiratory lung impedance change enables bedside monitoring of end-expiratory lung volume change. Intensive Care Med. 2003;29(1):37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12528020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikker I.G., Leonhardt S., Bakker J., Gommers D. Lung volume calculated from electrical impedance tomography in ICU patients at different PEEP levels. Intensive Care Med. 2009;35(8):1362&#x2013;1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19513694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grivans C., Lindgren S., Lundin S., Stenqvist O. Quantification of changes in end expiratory lung volume using electric impedance tomography, N2 washout/washin and cumulative inspiratory-expiratory tidal volume differences. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2009;53:53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grivans C., Lundin S., Stenqvist O., Lindgren S. Positive end-expiratory pressure-induced changes in end-expiratory lung volume measured by spirometry and electric impedance tomography. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2011;55(9):1068&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22092203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T., Eronia N., Turrini C., et al. Bedside assessment of the effects of positive end-expiratory pressure on lung inflation and recruitment by the helium dilution technique and electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med. 2016;42(10):1576&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27518321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher T., Wendler A., Eimer C., Weiler N., Frerichs I. Changes in electrical impedance tomography findings of ICU patients during rapid infusion of a fluid bolus: a prospective observational study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;199(12):1572&#x2013;1575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30875244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoyama M. Clinical application of the impedance pneumograph: respiratory effects of sedatives, analgesics and respiratory stimulants. Jpn J Anesthesiol. 1973;22(10):44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Hinz J., Herrmann P., et al. Detection of local lung air content by electrical impedance tomography compared with electron beam CT. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2002;93(2):660&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12133877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtveen J.H., Groot P.F., de Geus E.J. Validation of the thoracic impedance derived respiratory signal using multilevel analysis. Int J Psychophysiol. 2006;59(2):97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15893397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balleza M., Fornos J., Calaf N., et al. 13th International Conference on Electrical Bioimpedance/8th Conference on Electrical Impedance Tomography. 2007. Tidal volume monitoring with electrical impedance tomography. Validation for healthy subjects; p. 572. Graz, Austria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nebuya S., Kitamura K., Kobayashi H., Noshiro M., Brown B.H. 13th International Conference on Electrical Bioimpedance/8th Conference on Electrical Impedance Tomography. 2007. Measurement accuracy in pulmonary function test using electrical impedance tomography; pp. 539&#x2013;542. Graz, Austria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza R., Rattes C., Campos S., et al. Volume validation and correlation between electrical impedance measurements and pulmonary volumes. Eur Respir J. 2017;50:PA2481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo C., Leonhardt S., Zhang T., et al. Linearity of electrical impedance tomography during maximum effort breathing and forced expiration maneuvers. Physiol Meas. 2017;38(1):77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28004642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T., Alban L., Turrini C., et al. Optimum support by high-flow nasal cannula in acute hypoxemic respiratory failure: effects of increasing flow rates. Intensive Care Med. 2017;43(10):1453&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28762180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joussellin V., Janiak V., Bonny V., et al. Correlation between chest electrical impedance variation and tidal volume in mechanically ventilated patients. Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12:FC&#x2013;077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moerer O., Hahn G., Quintel M. Lung impedance measurements to monitor alveolar ventilation. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2011;17(3):260&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21478747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T., Bellani G., Suriano G., et al. Monitoring of ventilation by EIT at different end-expiratory volumes: a validation study. Intensive Care Med. 2014;40(1):S155&#x2013;S156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten J., Luepschen H., Grossherr M., et al. Effect of PEEP on regional ventilation during laparoscopic surgery monitored by electrical impedance tomography. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2011;55(7):878&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21658014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Hahn G., Golisch W., Kurpitz M., Burchardi H., Hellige G. Monitoring perioperative changes in distribution of pulmonary ventilation by functional electrical impedance tomography. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 1998;42(6):721&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9689281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann M., Oehler B., Zuber J., et al. Redistribution of pulmonary ventilation after lung surgery detected with electrical impedance tomography. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2020;64(4):517&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31830306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasarow L., Vogt B., Zhao Z., Balke L., Weiler N., Frerichs I. Regional lung function measures determined by electrical impedance tomography during repetitive ventilation manoeuvres in patients with COPD. Physiol Meas. 2021;42(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., H&#xe4;ndel C., Becher T., Sch&#xe4;dler D. Sex differences in chest electrical impedance tomography findings. Physiol Meas. 2024;45(7):075005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T., Piraino T., Lima C.A.S., Kavanagh B.P., Amato M.B.P., Brochard L. Regional ventilation displayed by electrical impedance tomography as an incentive to decrease positive end-expiratory pressure. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200(7):933&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31225973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Dai M., M&#xf6;ller K., et al. Lung regions identified with CT improve the value of global inhomogeneity index measured with electrical impedance tomography. Quant Imaging Med Surg. 2021;11(4):1209&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33816161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., M&#xf6;ller K., Steinmann D., Frerichs I., Guttmann J. Evaluation of an electrical impedance tomography-based global inhomogeneity index for pulmonary ventilation distribution. Intensive Care Med. 2009;35(11):1900&#x2013;1906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19652949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher T., Kott M., Sch&#xe4;dler D., et al. Influence of tidal volume on ventilation inhomogeneity assessed by electrical impedance tomography during controlled mechanical ventilation. Physiol Meas. 2015;36(6):1137&#x2013;1146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26007294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heines S.J.H., de Jongh S.A.M., Strauch U., van der Horst I.C.C., van de Poll M.C.G., Bergmans D. The global inhomogeneity index assessed by electrical impedance tomography overestimates PEEP requirement in patients with ARDS: an observational study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2022;22(1):258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9377133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Z., Yang L., Dai M., et al. Regional ventilation distribution before and after laparoscopic lung parenchymal resection. Physiol Meas. 2024;45(1):015004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joussellin V., Bonny V., Spadaro S., et al. Lung aeration estimated by chest electrical impedance tomography and lung ultrasound during extubation. Ann Intensive Care. 2023;13(1):91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10522557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;ner &#xd6;., Ergan B., Kizil A.S., Gurkok M.C., Dugral E., G&#xf6;kmen N. Investigation of high flow nasal cannule efficiency with electric impedance tomography based parameters in COVID-19 adults patients: a retrospective study. PeerJ. 2023;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi L.Y., Chi Y., Yuan S.Y., et al. Effect of prone positioning with individualized positive end-expiratory pressure in acute respiratory distress syndrome using electrical impedance tomography. Front Physiol. 2022;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Dai M., Cao X., et al. Regional ventilation distribution in healthy lungs: can reference values be established for electrical impedance tomography parameters? Ann Transl Med. 2021;9(9):789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa E.L., Borges J.B., Melo A., et al. Bedside estimation of recruitable alveolar collapse and hyperdistension by electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med. 2009;35(6):1132&#x2013;1137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Chang M.Y., Chang M.Y., et al. Positive end-expiratory pressure titration with electrical impedance tomography and pressure-volume curve in severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Ann Intensive Care. 2019;9(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6336593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dargvainis M., Ohnesorge H., Sch&#xe4;dler D., Alkatout I., Frerichs I., Becher T. Recruitable alveolar collapse and overdistension during laparoscopic gynecological surgery and mechanical ventilation: a prospective clinical study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2022;22(1):251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35933365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Lee L.C., Chang M.Y., et al. The incidence and interpretation of large differences in EIT-based measures for PEEP titration in ARDS patients. J Clin Monit Comput. 2020;34(5):1005&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher T., Buchholz V., Hassel D., et al. Individualization of PEEP and tidal volume in ARDS patients with electrical impedance tomography: a pilot feasibility study. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11(1):89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8171998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zick G., Elke G., Becher T., et al. Effect of PEEP and tidal volume on ventilation distribution and end-expiratory lung volume: a prospective experimental animal and pilot clinical study. PLoS One. 2013;8(8)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M.A.M., Hajjar L.A., Galas F.R.B.G., et al. Positive end expiratory pressure titration at bedside using electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2016;4(Suppl 1):A238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eronia N., Mauri T., Maffezzini E., et al. Bedside selection of positive end-expiratory pressure by electrical impedance tomography in hypoxemic patients: a feasibility study. Ann Intensive Care. 2017;7(1):76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5519511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28730554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowhagen K., Odenstedt H., Lindgren S., Lundin S., Stenqvist O. Potentially recruitable lung volume assessed by end-expiratory lung volume volume dependent compliance and electric impedance tomography. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2009;26:175&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19142094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowhagen K., Lindgren S., Odenstedt H., Stenqvist O., Lundin S. A new non-radiological method to assess potential lung recruitability: a pilot study in ALI patients. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2011;55(2):165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21039359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonkman A.H., Alcala G.C., Pavlovsky B., et al. Lung Recruitment Assessed by Electrical Impedance Tomography (RECRUIT): a multicenter study of COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;208(1):25&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10870845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37097986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruana L., Putt M., Fraser J. Alveolar recruitment in a case of severe lobar pneumonia seen through the eyes of electrical impedance tomography: a case study. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2009;37(6):1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T., Spinelli E., Scotti E., et al. Potential for lung recruitment and ventilation-perfusion mismatch in patients with the acute respiratory distress syndrome from coronavirus disease 2019. Crit Care Med. 2020;48(8):1129&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7188034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettenuzzo T., Sella N., Lorenzoni G., et al. The recruitment-to-inflation ratio is correlated with EIT-Derived collapse and overdistention in COVID-19 ARDS. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206(10):1284&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9746852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taenaka H., Yoshida T., Hashimoto H., et al. Personalized ventilatory strategy based on lung recruitablity in COVID-19-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome: a prospective clinical study. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10116825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37076900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Y., Liu D.W., He H.W., Zhao Z.Q. Positive end-expiratory pressure titration after alveolar recruitment directed by electrical impedance tomography. Chin Med J. 2015;128(11):1421&#x2013;1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand P., Antonio P., Elena S., et al. Global ventilation-perfusion mismatch improvement related to PEEP increase in patients with highly recruitable lungs. Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12(1):CO&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fossali T., Colombo R., Ottolina D.F., et al. Prone position is associated with recruitment and lower dead-space/shunt ratio in moderate and severe C-ARDS patients. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2021;9(SUPPL 1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Chi Y., Long Y., et al. Influence of overdistension/recruitment induced by high positive end-expiratory pressure on ventilation-perfusion matching assessed by electrical impedance tomography with saline bolus. Crit Care. 2020;24(1):586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Chi Y., Long Y., et al. Three broad classifications of acute respiratory failure etiologies based on regional ventilation and perfusion by electrical impedance tomography: a hypothesis-generating study. Ann Intensive Care. 2021;11(1):134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34453622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marongiu I., Spinelli E., Mauri T., et al. High dead space and dissociation between severe hypoxia and relatively low shunt might be distinguishing features of C-ARDS vs. ARDS. Intensive Care Med Experimental. 2020;8(SUPPL 2):000429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli E., Mauri T., Kircher M., et al. Heterogeneous distribution of pulmonary perfusion is associated with mortality in ARDS. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;201(1):875&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7124724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31870172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y.X., Zhong M., Dong M.H., et al. Prone positioning improves ventilation-perfusion matching assessed by electrical impedance tomography in patients with ARDS: a prospective physiological study. Crit Care. 2022;26(1):154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35624489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves C.N., Hirota A.S., Beraldo M.A., et al. Electrical impedance tomography (EIT) assessment of perfusion response to inhaled nitric oxide (INO) in a refractory hypoxemic pneumonia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012;185:A3795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M., He H., Long Y. Lung perfusion assessment by bedside electrical impedance tomography in critically ill patients. Front Physiol. 2021;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R., He C., Chi Y., et al. Electrical impedance tomography to aid in the identification of hypoxemia etiology: massive atelectasis or pneumothorax? A case report. Front Med. 2022;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putensen C., Hentze B., Muenster S., Muders T. Electrical impedance tomography for cardio-pulmonary monitoring. J Clin Med. 2019;8(8):1176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31394721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchineau G., Jonkman A.H., Piquilloud L., et al. Electrical impedance tomography to monitor hypoxemic respiratory failure. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;209(6):670&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38127779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ey&#xfc;bo&#x11f;lu B.M., Oner A.F., Baysal U., et al. Application of electrical impedance tomography in diagnosis of emphysema--a clinical study. Physiol Meas. 1995;16(3 Suppl A):A191&#x2013;A211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8528117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Golisch W., Hahn G., Michael K., Burchardi H., Hellige G. Heterogeneous distribution of pulmonary ventilation in intensive care patients detected by functional electrical impedance tomography. J Intensive Care Med. 1998;13(4):168&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher T., Bu&#xdf;meyer M., Lautenschl&#xe4;ger I., Sch&#xe4;dler D., Weiler N., Frerichs I. Comparison of electrical impedance tomography images in critically ill patients with and without pleural effusion. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2017;5(Suppl2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher T., Bu&#xdf;meyer M., Lautenschl&#xe4;ger I., Sch&#xe4;dler D., Weiler N., Frerichs I. Characteristic pattern of pleural effusion in electrical impedance tomography images of critically ill patients. Br J Anaesth. 2018;120(6):1219&#x2013;1228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29793589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arad M., Zlochiver S., Davidson T., Shoenfeld Y., Adunsky A., Abboud S. The detection of pleural effusion using a parametric EIT technique. Physiol Meas. 2009;30(4):421&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19332893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xe4;ser D., Becher T., Lautenschl&#xe4;ger I., et al. Impact of pleural fluid removal on continuous chest electrical impedance tomography examinations of intensive care patients. Intensive Care Med. 2014;40(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rara A., Roubik K., Tyll T. Effects of pleural effusion drainage in the mechanically ventilated patient as monitored by electrical impedance tomography and end-expiratory lung volume: a pilot study. J Crit Care. 2020;59:76&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32570053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves S.H., Amato M.B., Terra R.M., Vargas F.S., Caruso P. Lung reaeration and reventilation after aspiration of pleural effusions. A study using electrical impedance tomography. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2014;11(2):186&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24308560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morais C.C., De Santis Santiago R.R., Filho J.R., et al. Monitoring of pneumothorax appearance with electrical impedance tomography during recruitment maneuvers. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;195(8):1070&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite W.S., Campos S.L., Brand&#xe3;o D.C., Morais C.C.A., de Andrade A.D. Real-time distinct visualization of barotrauma risk monitored by electrical impedance tomography in a COVID-19 and latent tuberculosis case. Acute Crit Care. 2022;37(4):672&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9732201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36203229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa E.L.V., Chaves C.N., Gomes S., et al. Real-time detection of pneumothorax using electrical impedance tomogyaphy. Crit Care Med. 2008;36(4):1230&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Yuan S., Yi C., Long Y., Zhang R., Zhao Z. Titration of extra-PEEP against intrinsic-PEEP in severe asthma by electrical impedance tomography: a case report and literature review. Medicine (Baltim) 2020;99(26)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmann D., Stahl C.A., Minner J., et al. Electrical impedance tomography to confirm correct placement of double-lumen tube: a feasibility study. Br J Anaesth. 2008;101(3):411&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roz&#xe9; H., Boisselier C., Bonnardel E., et al. Electrical impedance tomography to detect airway closure heterogeneity in asymmetrical acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;203(4):511&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slobod D., Spinelli E., Scaramuzzo G., Lissoni A., Grasselli G., Mauri T. Redistribution of perfusion by prone positioning improves shunt in a patient with unilateral lung injury. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206(12):e76&#x2013;e78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., He H., Long Y., et al. Bedside electrical impedance tomography in early diagnosis of pneumothorax in mechanically ventilated ICU patients - a single-center retrospective cohort study. J Clin Monit Comput. 2023;37(2):629&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36333577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulletz S., Elke G., Zick G., et al. Performance of electrical impedance tomography in detecting regional tidal volumes during one-lung ventilation. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2008;52(8):1131&#x2013;1139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18840115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunst P.W., Vonk Noordegraaf A., Raaijmakers E., et al. Electrical impedance tomography in the assessment of extravascular lung water in noncardiogenic acute respiratory failure. Chest. 1999;116(6):1695&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10593797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun F., Proen&#xe7;a M., Wendler A., et al. Noninvasive measurement of stroke volume changes in critically ill patients by means of electrical impedance tomography. J Clin Monit Comput. 2020;34(5):903&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Chi Y., Long Y., et al. Influence of pulmonary embolism by saline contrast electrical impedance tomography method: a prospective observational study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202(10):1464&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Long Y., Frerichs I., Zhao Z. Detection of acute pulmonary embolism by electrical impedance tomography and saline bolus injection. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202(6):881&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S., He H., Long Y., Chi Y., Frerichs I., Zhao Z. Rapid dynamic bedside assessment of pulmonary perfusion defect by electrical impedance tomography in a patient with acute massive pulmonary embolism. Pulm Circ. 2021;11(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuk W.J., Wright N.R. Bedside diagnosis of pulmonary embolism using electrical impedance tomography: a case report. A A Pract. 2022;16(7)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins S.A., Weller D., Labout J.A.M., den Uil C.A. Electrical impedance tomography as a bedside diagnostic tool for pulmonary embolism. Crit Care Explor. 2023;5(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding C., Zhu Y., Zhang S., Zhao Z., Gao Y., Li Z. Bedside electrical impedance tomography to assist the management of pulmonary embolism: a case report. Heliyon. 2024;10(3)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen D.T., Jin C., Thiagalingam A., McEwan A.L. A review on electrical impedance tomography for pulmonary perfusion imaging. Physiol Meas. 2012;33(5):695&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22532291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safaee Fakhr B., Araujo Morais C.C., De Santis Santiago R.R., et al. Bedside monitoring of lung perfusion by electrical impedance tomography in the time of COVID-19. Br J Anaesth. 2020;125(5):e434&#x2013;e436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32859359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit H.J., Vonk Noordegraaf A., Marcus J.T., Boonstra A., de Vries P.M., Postmus P.E. Determinants of pulmonary perfusion measured by electrical impedance tomography. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92(1&#x2013;2):45&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14985995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit H.J., Vonk-Noordegraaf A., Marcus J.T., et al. Pulmonary vascular responses to hypoxia and hyperoxia in healthy volunteers and COPD patients measured by electrical impedance tomography. Chest. 2003;123(6):1803&#x2013;1809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12796153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit H.J., Vonk-Noordegraaf A., Boonstra A., de Vries P.M., Postmus P.E. Assessment of the pulmonary volume pulse in idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension by means of electrical impedance tomography. Respiration. 2006;73(5):597&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16205046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit H.J., Vonk Noordegraaf A., Roeleveld R.J., et al. Epoprostenol-induced pulmonary vasodilatation in patients with pulmonary hypertension measured by electrical impedance tomography. Physiol Meas. 2002;23(1):237&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11878269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonk Noordegraaf A., Kunst P.W., Janse A., et al. Pulmonary perfusion measured by means of electrical impedance tomography. Physiol Meas. 1998;19(2):263&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9626690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frerichs I., Pulletz S., Elke G., et al. Assessment of changes in distribution of lung perfusion by electrical impedance tomography. Respiration. 2009;77(3):282&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19147986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Songsangvorn N., Xu Y., Lu C., et al. Electrical impedance tomography-guided positive end-expiratory pressure titration in ARDS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Intensive Care Med. 2024;50(5):617&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11078723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38512400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M., Deng Y., Cha J., et al. PEEP titration by EIT strategies for patients with ARDS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Intensiva. 2023;47(7):383&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36243630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar S., Yalla B., Khanna P., Baishya M. Is EIT-guided positive end-expiratory pressure titration for optimizing PEEP in ARDS the white elephant in the room? A systematic review with meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis. J Clin Monit Comput. 2024;38(4):873&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38619718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Chi Y., Yang Y., et al. Early individualized positive end-expiratory pressure guided by electrical impedance tomography in acute respiratory distress syndrome: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Crit Care. 2021;25(1):230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8243615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu H.J., Chang H.T., Zhao Z., et al. Positive end-expiratory pressure titration with electrical impedance tomography and pressure-volume curve: a randomized trial in moderate to severe ARDS. Physiol Meas. 2021;42(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y.H., Pan Y., Yang M. Application of electrical impedance tomography for postoperative lung recruitment in patients undergoing off pump coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. J Shanghai Jiaot Univ (Med Sci) 2018;38(6):653&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai-Fen C., Mei Yun C., Hou-Tai C. A comparison of optimal positive end-expiratory pressure determination guided by electrical impedance tomography and using pressure-volume curve guided by EVITA 4 in moderate and severe acute respiratory distress syndrome patients. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2017;5(Suppl2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., He H., Chi Y., Frerichs I., Long Y., Zhao Z. Electrical impedance tomography guided positive end-expiratory pressure titration in critically ill and surgical adult patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pulm Med. 2024;24(1):582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11585246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39580405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira S.M., Tucci M.R., Morais C.C.A., et al. Individual positive end-expiratory pressure settings optimize intraoperative mechanical ventilation and reduce postoperative atelectasis. Anesthesiology. 2018;129(6):1070&#x2013;1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30260897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz S., Simon P., Hempel G., et al. Effects of individualized PEEP-adjustment in non-obese patients undergoing laparoscopic prostatectomy. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;197:A7214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon P., Schulz S., Hempel G., et al. Individualized PEEP-adjustment in obese and Non-obese patients undergoing laparoscopic abdominal surgery. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;197:A7235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K., Huang C., Xu M., et al. PEEP guided by electrical impedance tomography during one-lung ventilation in elderly patients undergoing thoracoscopic surgery. Ann Transl Med. 2019;7(23):757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girrbach F., Petroff D., Schulz S., et al. Individualised positive end-expiratory pressure guided by electrical impedance tomography for robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy: a prospective, randomised controlled clinical trial. Br J Anaesth. 2020;125(3):373&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L., Gao L., Yang L., et al. Effect of EIT-guided individualized PEEP setting on the incidence of hypoxemia in elderly patients undergoing robot-assisted radical prostatectomy. Natl Med J China (Peking) 2022;102(47):3727&#x2013;3733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Fu Y., Piao X., et al. Individualised positive end-expiratory pressure titrated intra-operatively by electrical impedance tomography optimises pulmonary mechanics and reduces postoperative atelectasis: a randomised controlled trial. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2023;40(11):805&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37789753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L., Yang L., Gao L., Zhao Z., Zhang J. Individualized PEEP without recruitment maneuvers improves intraoperative oxygenation: a randomized controlled study. Bioengineering (Basel) 2023;10(10):1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10604161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha J., Yu Y.J., Li G.R., et al. Lung protection effect of EIT-based individualized protective ventilation strategy in patients with partial pulmonary resection. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2023;27(12):5459&#x2013;5467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37401282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito T., Fregonese M., Morettini G., et al. Intraoperative individualization of positive-end-expiratory pressure through electrical impedance tomography or esophageal pressure assessment: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Clin Monit Comput. 2024;38(1):89&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37863862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacmarek R.M., Wanderley H.V., Villar J., Berra L. Weaning patients with obesity from ventilatory support. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2021;27(3):311&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickenbach J., Czaplik M., Polier M., Marx G., Marx N., Dreher M. Electrical impedance tomography for predicting failure of spontaneous breathing trials in patients with prolonged weaning. Crit Care. 2017;21(1):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28697778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuenzalida B., Lagos R., Bachmann M.C., et al. Electrical impedance tomography reveals the loss of aeration in dependent zones during T-tube trial in weaning patients from mechanical ventilation. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2018;6(Suppl 2):1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu Y.L., Chang M.Y., Zhao Z. Customized spontaneous breathing trials determined by electrical impedance tomography improved successful weaning rate in prolong mechanical ventilated patients. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2018;6(Suppl 2):0652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Zeng F., Yang F., et al. Electrical impedance tomography predicts weaning success in adult patients with delayed upper abdominal surgery: a single-center retrospective Study. Front Med. 2021;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima J.N.G., Fontes M.S., Szmuszkowicz T., Isola A.M., Maciel A.T. Electrical impedance tomography monitoring during spontaneous breathing trial: physiological description and potential clinical utility. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2019;63(8):1019&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31066031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longhini F., Andreoni C., Maugeri J., et al. Electric impedance tomography to predict weaning and extubation failure. Eur Respir J. 2016;48:PA3572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longhini F., Maugeri J., Andreoni C., et al. Electrical impedance tomography during spontaneous breathing trials and after extubation in critically ill patients at high risk for extubation failure: a multicenter observational study. Ann Intensive Care. 2019;9(1):88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31410738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon D.S., Huh J.W., Hong S.B., Koh Y., Lim C.M. Dynamic inhomogeneity of aeration along the vertical axis of the lung may predict weaning failure regardless of diaphragm dysfunction. J Crit Care. 2021;65:186&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Ning Y., He L., et al. Pendelluft as a predictor of weaning in critically ill patients: an observational cohort study. Front Physiol. 2023;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Zhang L., Li B., et al. The application of electrical impedance tomography during the ventilator weaning process. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:6875&#x2013;6883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8528545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34703292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wawrzeniak I.C., Victorino J.A., Vieira S.R., Amato M.B.P. Use of electrical impedance tomography in the evaluation of the spontaneous ventilation during the weaning of mechanical ventilation in patients with ARDS: pilot study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;197(MeetingAbstracts)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisse-Smit J., Goos T., Jonkman A., Endeman H.E., Reiss I., Gommers D. Electrical impedance tomography during weaning from mechanical ventilation: an observational study during the spontaneous breathing trial. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2023;11(Suppl 1):000225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Peng S.Y., Chang M.Y., et al. Spontaneous breathing trials after prolonged mechanical ventilation monitored by electrical impedance tomography: an observational study. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2017;61(9):1166&#x2013;1175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28832898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H.L., Liu Z.D., Shu H.Q., et al. Prone positioning in ARDS patients supported with VV ECMO, what we should explore? J Intensive Care. 2022;10(1):46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9531855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36195935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunelle T., Prud'homme E., Alphonsine J.E., et al. Awake prone position in COVID-19 acute respiratory failure: a randomised crossover study using electrical impedance tomography. ERJ Open Res. 2023;9(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ros&#xe0; T., Grieco D.L., Delle Cese L., et al. Physiological effects of awake prone position in moderate-to-severe acute hypoxemic respiratory failure. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2023;11(Suppl 1):000448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunin Y., Despres C., Pili-Floury S., Besch G. Lung recruiting effect of prone positioning in spontaneously breathing patients with COVID-19 assessed by electrical impedance tomography. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;204(4):476&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8480241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34170789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrakos C., van der Ven F., Smit M.R., et al. Prone positioning decreases inhomogeneity and improves dorsal compliance in invasively ventilated spontaneously breathing COVID-19 Patients-A Study using electrical impedance tomography. Diagnostics. 2022;12(10):2281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9600133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riera J., P&#xe9;rez P., Cort&#xe9;s J., Roca O., Masclans J.R., Rello J. Effect of high-flow nasal cannula and body position on end-expiratory lung volume: a cohort study using electrical impedance tomography. Respir Care. 2013;58(4):589&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23050520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appendino G., Nu&#xf1;ez Silveira J.M., Lovesio C. Evaluation of the response to the prone position through electrical impedance tomography. Med Intensiva. 2024;48(8):495&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38461143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachmann M.C., Jalil Y., Basoalto R., et al. Prone position improves ventilation-perfusion mismatch in patients with severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2021;9(Suppl 1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla Corte F., Mauri T., Spinelli E., et al. Dynamic bedside assessment of the physiologic effects of prone position in acute respiratory distress syndrome patients by electrical impedance tomography. Minerva Anestesiol. 2020;86(10):1057&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos Rocha A., Diaper J., Balogh A.L., et al. Effect of body position on the redistribution of regional lung aeration during invasive and non-invasive ventilation of COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fossali T., Pavlovsky B., Ottolina D., et al. Effects of prone position on lung recruitment and ventilation-perfusion matching in patients with COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome: a combined CT scan/electrical impedance tomography study. Crit Care Med. 2022;50(5):723&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35200194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchineau G., Br&#xe9;chot N., Hekimian G., et al. Prone positioning monitored by electrical impedance tomography in patients with severe acute respiratory distress syndrome on veno-venous ECMO. Ann Intensive Care. 2020;10(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32016593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasselli G., Mauri T., Lazzeri M., et al. Effects of prone position and recruitment manoeuvres on gas exchange and regional respiratory mechanics. Crit Care. 2017;21(Suppl 1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5278572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28132646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieco D.L., Delle Cese L., Menga L.S., et al. Physiological effects of awake prone position in acute hypoxemic respiratory failure. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10433569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37592288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotani T., Tanabe H., Yusa H., Saito S., Yamazaki K., Ozaki M. Electrical impedance tomography-guided prone positioning in a patient with acute cor pulmonale associated with severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. J Anesth. 2016;30(1):161&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann S., Leonhardt S., Ngo C., et al. Electrical impedance tomography as possible guidance for individual positioning of patients with multiple lung injury. Clin Respir J. 2018;12(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27058971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli M., Ottolina D., Slobod D., et al. Awake prone position in COVID-19 patients with helmet CPAP: effects on gas exchange, respiratory mechanics, and distribution of ventilation. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2022;10(Suppl 2):000471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mlcek M., Borges J.B., Ot&#xe1;hal M., et al. Real-time effects of lateral positioning on regional ventilation and perfusion in an experimental model of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Front Physiol. 2023;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ot&#xe1;hal M., Mlcek M., Borges J.B., et al. Prone positioning may increase lung overdistension in COVID-19-induced ARDS. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):16528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupier T., Gallo &#xc9;., Bonnardel E., et al. Daily evolution of lung dependent-area collapse between prone position sessions in ARDS evaluated by electrical impedance tomography. Respir Care. 2024;69(4):470&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11108115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ros&#xe9;n J., Frykholm P., Fagerlund M.J., et al. Lung impedance changes during awake prone positioning in COVID-19. A non-randomized cross-over study. PLoS One. 2024;19(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasino S., Sassanelli R., Marescalco C., Meroi F., Vetrugno L., Bove T. Electrical impedance tomography and prone position during ventilation in COVID-19 Pneumonia: case reports and a brief literature review. Semin CardioThorac Vasc Anesth. 2020;24(4):287&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32924792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Zhao Z., Chao Y., et al. Effects of early versus delayed application of prone position on ventilation-perfusion mismatch in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome: a prospective observational study. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38012731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarantonello F., Sella N., Pettenuzzo T., et al. Early physiologic effects of prone positioning in COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Anesthesiology. 2022;137(3):327&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35708999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaeth J., Daume K., Goebel U., Wirth S., Schumann S. Increasing positive end-expiratory pressure (re-)improves intraoperative respiratory mechanics and lung ventilation after prone positioning. Br J Anaesth. 2016;116(6):838&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27199315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mlcek M., Ot&#xe1;hal M., Borges J.B., et al. Targeted lateral positioning decreases lung collapse and overdistension in COVID-19-associated ARDS. BMC Pulm Med. 2021;21(1):133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8065309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nozoe M., Mase K., Takashima S., et al. Measurements of chest wall volume variation during tidal breathing in the supine and lateral positions in healthy subjects. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2014;193:38&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24418356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramanathan K., Mohammed H., Hopkins P., et al. Single-lung transplant results in position dependent changes in regional ventilation: an observational case series using electrical impedance tomography. Can Respir J. 2016;2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rold&#xe1;n R., Rodriguez S., Barriga F., et al. Sequential lateral positioning as a new lung recruitment maneuver: an exploratory study in early mechanically ventilated Covid-19 ARDS patients. Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8840950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bein T., Ploner F., Ritzka M., Pfeifer M., Schlitt H.J., Graf B.M. No change in the regional distribution of tidal volume during lateral posture in mechanically ventilated patients assessed by electrical impedance tomography. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2010;30(4):234&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2913102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20491842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitzmann A., Pulletz S., Gonzales-Rios P., et al. Regional ventilation in spontaneously breathing COVID-19 patients during postural maneuvers assessed by electrical impedance tomography. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2023;67(2):185&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9874544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36268561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiumello D., Bolgiaghi L., Formenti P., Pozzi T., Lucenteforte M., Coppola S. Effects on lung gas volume, respiratory mechanics and gas exchange of a closed-circuit suctioning system during volume- and pressure-controlled ventilation in ARDS patients. J Clin Med. 2021;10(23):5657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8658121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34884358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten J., Meier T., Iblher P., Schindler A., Paarmann H., Heinze H. The suitability of EIT to estimate EELV in a clinical trial compared to oxygen wash-in/wash-out technique. Biomed Tech. 2014;59(1):59&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindgren S., Odenstedt H., Erlandsson K., Grivans C., Lundin S., Stenqvist O. Bronchoscopic suctioning may cause lung collapse: a lung model and clinical evaluation. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2008;52(2):209&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18005383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindgren S., Odenstedt H., Oleg&#xe5;rd C., S&#xf6;ndergaard S., Lundin S., Stenqvist O. Regional lung derecruitment after endotracheal suction during volume- or pressure-controlled ventilation: a study using electric impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med. 2007;33(1):172&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17072587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corley A., Spooner A.J., Barnett A.G., Caruana L.R., Hammond N.E., Fraser J.F. End-expiratory lung volume recovers more slowly after closed endotracheal suctioning than after open suctioning: a randomized crossover study. J Crit Care. 2012;27(6):742.e741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinze H., Eichler W., Karsten J., Sedemund-Adib B., Heringlake M., Meier T. Functional residual capacity-guided alveolar recruitment strategy after endotracheal suctioning in cardiac surgery patients. Crit Care Med. 2011;39(5):1042&#x2013;1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21336125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corley A., Sharpe N., Caruana L.R., Spooner A.J., Fraser J.F. Lung volume changes during cleaning of closed endotracheal suction catheters: a randomized crossover study using electrical impedance tomography. Respir Care. 2014;59(4):497&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24046466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichler L., Mueller J., Grensemann J., Frerichs I., Z&#xf6;llner C., Kluge S. Lung aeration and ventilation after percutaneous tracheotomy measured by electrical impedance tomography in non-hypoxemic critically ill patients: a prospective observational study. Ann Intensive Care. 2018;8(1):110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6238017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30443867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnane M.P., Caruana L.R., Tronstad O., et al. A comparison of the effects of manual hyperinflation and ventilator hyperinflation on restoring end-expiratory lung volume after endotracheal suctioning: a pilot physiologic study. J Crit Care. 2019;49:77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30388492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim S., Saygili S.M., S&#xfc;ne&#xe7;li O., Kirakli C. Comparison of the effects of open and closed aspiration on end-expiratory lung volume in acute respiratory distress syndrome. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2024;77(1):115&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37211764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T., Torsani V., Gomes S., et al. Spontaneous effort causes occult pendelluft during mechanical ventilation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;188(12):1420&#x2013;1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24199628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su P.L., Zhao Z., Ko Y.F., Chen C.W., Cheng K.S. Spontaneous breathing and pendelluft in patients with acute lung injury: a narrative review. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9783194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez J.V., Weirauch A.J., Culter C.A., Choi P.J., Hyzy R.C. Electrical impedance tomography in acute respiratory distress Syndrome management. Crit Care Med. 2022;50(8):1210&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wettstein M., Radlinger L., Riedel T. Effect of different breathing aids on ventilation distribution in adults with cystic fibrosis. PLoS One. 2014;9(9)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Jiang H., Zhang C., Li Y., Zhao Z. Pulmonary rehabilitation throughout the weaning from mechanical ventilation for complete cervical spinal cord injury: a case report. Signa Vitae. 2020;16(2):210&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Dai M., Wu S., et al. Pulmonary rehabilitation ameliorates regional lung function in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a prospective single-arm clinical trial. Ann Transl Med. 2022;10(16):891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9469120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Li Y., Niu G., et al. Chest physiotherapy guided by electrical impedance tomography in high-dependency unit patients with pulmonary diseases: an introduction of methodology and feasibility. Crit Care. 2023;27(1):24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9847064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36650565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Huang M., Zhou J., et al. Enhancement of pulmonary function and reduction of complications through EIT-Guided yoga breathing exercise after esophagectomy. Med Sci Monit. 2024;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longhini F., Bruni A., Garofalo E., et al. Chest physiotherapy improves lung aeration in hypersecretive critically ill patients: a pilot randomized physiological study. Crit Care. 2020;24(1):479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Gao Z., Cao X., et al. Visualizing pursed lips breathing of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease through evaluation of global and regional ventilation using electrical impedance tomography. Physiol Meas. 2024;45(4):045005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arriagada R., Bachmann M.C., San Martin C., Rauseo M., Battaglini D. Electrical impedance tomography: usefulness for respiratory physiotherapy in critical illnesses. Med Intensiva. 2024;48(7):403&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38538496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S., Chi Y., Long Y., He H., Zhao Z. Effect of position change from the bed to a wheelchair on the regional ventilation distribution assessed by electrical impedance tomography in patients with respiratory failure. Front Med. 2021;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eimer C., Freier K., Weiler N., Frerichs I., Becher T. The effect of physical therapy on regional lung function in critically ill patients. Front Physiol. 2021;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchineau G., Brechot N., Lebreton G., et al. Bedside contribution of electrical impedance tomography (EIT) to set mechanical ventilation for severe acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) on extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) Ann Intensive Care. 2016;6(Suppl 1):O58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero A., Alonso B., Latorre I., Garc&#xed;a J. Respiratory monitoring with electrical impedance tomography for lung protective ventilation and alveolar recruitment maneuver in a patient with a single lung transplant and early graft dysfunction. Rev Esp Anestesiol Reanim. 2016;63(6):347&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26633603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchineau G., Br&#xe9;chot N., Lebreton G., et al. Bedside contribution of electrical impedance tomography to setting positive end-expiratory pressure for extracorporeal membrane oxygenation-treated patients with severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;196(4):447&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soule C., Puel F., Crognier L., Vardon F., Conil J.M. Optimal positive end-expiratory pressure: interest of electrical impedance tomography for veno-arterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation-treated patients. Ann Intensive Care. 2019;9(Suppl 1):P&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puel F., Crognier L., Soul&#xe9; C., et al. Assessment of electrical impedance tomography to set optimal positive end-expiratory pressure for veno-venous ECMO-treated severe ARDS patients. J Crit Care. 2020;60:38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32736198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soul&#xe9; C., Crognier L., Puel F., et al. Assessment of electrical impedance tomography to set optimal positive end-expiratory pressure for venoarterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation-treated patients. Crit Care Med. 2021;49(6):923&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33595959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pierro M., Giani M., Bronco A., et al. Bedside selection of positive end expiratory pressure by electrical impedance tomography in patients undergoing veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support: a comparison between COVID-19 ARDS and ARDS from other etiologies. J Clin Med. 2022;11(6):1639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35329965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Su L., He H., Liu D., Long Y. Whole-process respiratory management strategies based on electrical impedance tomography in a pregnant woman with diffuse alveolar hemorrhage induced by systemic lupus erythematosus under veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Pulm Circ. 2023;13(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu&#xe9;rin C. Individualization of positive end-expiratory pressure setting in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome under extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Inputs from electrical impedance tomography. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;196(4):404&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28809514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T., Mercat A., Grasselli G. What's new in electrical impedance tomography. Intensive Care Med. 2019;45(5):674&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30284639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli E., Giani M., Slobod D., et al. Physiologic effects of ECMO in patients with severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;210(5):629&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11389568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38526489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Jiang J., Xu M., et al. Saline bolus-based electrical impedance tomography method for rapid bedside assessment of regional lung perfusion during ECMO therapy. Crit Care. 2022;26(1):266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9443643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y.L., Zhang K., Li M.K., et al. Feasibility of 3D-EIT in identifying lung perfusion defect and V/Q mismatch in a patient with VA-ECMO. Crit Care. 2024;28(1):90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10956177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38509551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Wu Y., Gao X., et al. Effects of different VV ECMO blood flow rates on lung perfusion assessment by hypertonic saline bolus-based electrical impedance tomography. Crit Care. 2024;28(1):274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11330074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39154185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong H., Chi Y., Zhang R., et al. Multicentre, parallel, open-label, two-arm, randomised controlled trial on the prognosis of electrical impedance tomography-guided versus low PEEP/FiO2 table-guided PEEP setting: a trial protocol. BMJ Open. 2024;14(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Zhang R., Wang Y., et al. Effect of EIT-guided PEEP titration on prognosis of patients with moderate to severe ARDS: study protocol for a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2023;24(1):266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10088128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37041561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>