<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41304050</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strength Prediction Method for Phosphogypsum Concrete Based on Dynamic Weighted Transfer Learning.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5206</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18225206</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recycling industrial solid waste phosphogypsum into phosphogypsum concrete (PGC) is a crucial pathway for achieving high-value solid waste utilization. However, the scarcity of experimental samples for PGC has led to inaccurate predictions of compressive strength by traditional models, severely hindering its application. This study proposes a dynamic weighted transfer learning-based method for predicting the strength of PGC, addressing the characterization bottleneck under small-sample conditions by transferring knowledge from the strength patterns of conventional concrete. First, feature differences between conventional concrete and PGC are eliminated through component proportion normalization and feature alignment. Then, a data augmentation technique based on Bootstrap Resampling is developed to generate enhanced samples that comply with mix proportion constraints, effectively expanding the training samples. Finally, an error feedback-driven dynamic weight calculation and weighted loss optimization framework for transfer learning is designed, prioritizing the learning of samples in the prediction blind spots of the target domain. This enables the adaptive acquisition of PGC-specific knowledge while inheriting the general knowledge of conventional concrete. Experimental results show that the transfer learning model achieves a prediction accuracy of R<sup>2</sup> = 0.95 on the target domain test samples, a 15.9% improvement over traditional methods, while maintaining robust performance (R<sup>2</sup> = 0.97) on an external validation samples. Feature importance analysis and Shapley Additive Explanations (SHAP) analysis reveal the nonlinear coupling effects of PGC-specific parameters on strength. This study establishes a scientific approach for accurate strength prediction of PGC under small-sample conditions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Hubei Engineering University, Xiaogan 432000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Province Engineering Research Center for Cement-Based Ultra-High Performance Concrete and Prefabricated Building Technology, Xiaogan 432000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Hubei Engineering University, Xiaogan 432000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dongxu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Hubei Engineering University, Xiaogan 432000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Pengfei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Hubei Engineering University, Xiaogan 432000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Hongjun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6184-3453</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Wuhan University, Wuhan 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>B2024149</GrantID><Agency>Hubei Provincial Department of Education Scientific Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>51978539</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">data augmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphogypsum concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small-sample</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transfer learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41304050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12654723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18225206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18225206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hu N., Kong D., Wang L., Zhou S., Han Y., Feng J., Shu J., Liu A., Ni W., Khan N. Experimental design, mechanical performance and mechanism analysis of C30 phosphogypsum-based concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;443:137673. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Q., Wang Z., Zhou F., Yu W., Yin Z., Zhang Z., Chi R., Zhou J. The impurity removal and comprehensive utilization of phosphogypsum: A review. Materials. 2024;17:2067. doi: 10.3390/ma17092067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17092067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11595715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39597501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Ma L., Qiu S., Yin X., Dai Q., Du W. Sustainable Utilization of Phosphogypsum in Multi-Solid Waste Recycled Aggregates: Environmental Impact and Economic Viability. Sustainability. 2024;16:1161. doi: 10.3390/su16031161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16031161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang B., Song Y., Li Y., Wu F., Yu H., Wang Y., Yin Z., Luo X., Sant G., Bauchy M. Using machine learning to predict concrete&#x2019;s strength: Learning from small datasets. Eng. Res. Express. 2021;3:015022. doi: 10.1088/2631-8695/abe344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/abe344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Xia P., Chen K., Gong F., Wang H., Wang Q., Zhao Y., Jin W. Prediction and optimization model of sustainable concrete properties using machine learning, deep learning and swarm intelligence: A review. J. Build. Eng. 2023;80:108065. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.108065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.108065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.S., Qudoos A., Jakhrani S.H., Lee J.B., Kim H.G. Influence of coarse aggregates and Silica Fume on the mechanical properties, durability, and microstructure of concrete. Materials. 2019;12:3324. doi: 10.3390/ma12203324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma12203324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6829464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P., Xie W., Ling Y., Xu H. Optimal fiber mix and prediction model for compressive strength of hybrid fiber reinforced concrete. PLoS ONE. 2025;20:e0318713. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0318713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0318713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11838906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39970147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdeldjalil M., Chouicha K. Effect of the cement-to-water ratio and fractal granular model on the prediction of concretes compressive strength. Int. J. Concr. Struct. Mater. 2022;16:43. doi: 10.1186/s40069-022-00526-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40069-022-00526-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutassem F., Kharseh M. Sustainability-driven model for predicting compressive strength in concrete structures. Cogent Eng. 2024;11:2374947. doi: 10.1080/23311916.2024.2374947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311916.2024.2374947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Yang J., Zhang P. Water-cement-density ratio law for the 28-day compressive strength prediction of cement-based materials. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020;2020:7302173. doi: 10.1155/2020/7302173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/7302173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Xu W., Fan D., Dong E., Liu K., Xu L., Yu R. Understanding and predicting micro-characteristics of ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC) with green porous lightweight aggregates: Insights from machine learning techniques. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;446:138021. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Mir A., El-Zahab S., Sbarta&#xef; Z.M., Homsi F., Saliba J., El-Hassan H. Machine learning prediction of concrete compressive strength using rebound hammer test. J. Build. Eng. 2023;64:105538. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta T., Rao M.C. Predict. of compressive strength of geopolymer concrete using machine learning techniques. Struct. Concr. 2022;23:3073&#x2013;3090. doi: 10.1002/suco.202100354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.202100354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc;er K., &#xd6;zbeyaz A., G&#xf6;ymen S., G&#xfc;nayd&#x131;n O. A comparative investigation using machine learning methods for concrete compressive strength estimation. Mater. Today Commun. 2021;27:102278. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2021.102278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2021.102278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa J. Concrete Compressive Strength Prediction by Ensemble Machine Learning Approach. J. Eng. Sci. 2024;3:66&#x2013;73. doi: 10.3126/jes2.v3i1.66249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jes2.v3i1.66249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Lin J., Lei X., Wei T. Compressive strength prediction of basalt fiber reinforced concrete via random forest algorithm. Mater. Today Commun. 2022;30:103117. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2021.103117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2021.103117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal P., Gurjar G.K., Aggarwal Y., Kumar P. Prediction of compressive strength of self-compacting concrete using machine learning techniques. J. Asian Concr. Fed. 2023;9:17&#x2013;30. doi: 10.18702/acf.2023.9.1.17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18702/acf.2023.9.1.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Song Z. Prediction of compressive strength of rice husk ash concrete based on stacking ensemble learning model. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;382:135279. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.135279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.135279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Guo J., Ning C., Cheng R., Liu Z. Prediction of concrete compressive strength using a Deepforest-based model. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:18918. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-69616-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-69616-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39143140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood M.S., Elahi A., Zaid O., Alashker Y., &#x218;erb&#x103;noiu A.A., Gr&#x103;dinaru C.M., Ullah K., Ali T. Enhancing compressive strength prediction in self-compacting concrete using machine learning and deep learning techniques with incorporation of rice husk ash and marble powder. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;19:e02557. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao L., Xue X., Wang N., Ren Q., Hua J., Wang F. A transfer learning-based approach to fatigue life prediction of corroded bimetallic steel bars using small samples. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;400:132679. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F., Ye Z., Wang L. Deep transfer learning-based vehicle classification by asphalt pavement vibration. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;342:127997. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalakrishnan K., Khaitan S.K., Choudhary A., Agrawal A. Deep convolutional neural networks with transfer learning for computer vision-based data-driven pavement distress detection. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;157:322&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.09.110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.09.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford E., Maneparambil K., Kumar A., Sant G., Neithalath N. Transfer (machine) learning approaches coupled with target data augmentation to predict the mechanical properties of concrete. Mach. Learn. Appl. 2022;8:100271. doi: 10.1016/j.mlwa.2022.100271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mlwa.2022.100271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H.A.T., Pham D.H., Le A.T., Ahn Y., Oo B.L., Lim B.T.H. Transfer learning framework for modelling the compressive strength of ultra-high performance geopolymer concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;459:139746. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wang Z., Liu S., Wu K., Huang L. Back-propagation neural network model enhanced by transfer learning for the prediction method of compressive strength of alkali residue-based foamed concrete. J. Sustain. Cem.-Based Mater. 2024;13:1812&#x2013;1828. doi: 10.1080/21650373.2024.2414335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2024.2414335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chawla N.V., Bowyer K.W., Hall L.O., Kegelmeyer W.P. SMOTE: Synthetic minority over-sampling technique. J. Artif. Intell. Res. 2002;16:321&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1613/jair.953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1613/jair.953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efron B. Breakthroughs in Statistics: Methodology and Distribution. Springer; New York, NY, USA: 1992. Bootstrap methods: Another look at the jackknife; pp. 569&#x2013;593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke G., Meng Q., Finley T., Wang T., Chen W., Ma W., Ye Q., Liu T.Y. NIPS&#x2019;17: Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems. Curran Associates Inc; Red Hook, NY, USA: 2017. Lightgbm: A highly efficient gradient boosting decision tree; pp. 3149&#x2013;3157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh I.C. Modeling of strength of high-performance concrete using artificial neural networks. Cem. Concr. Res. 1998;28:1797&#x2013;1808. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(98)00165-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(98)00165-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Methods of Concrete Physical and Mechanical Properties. China Architecture Publishing &amp; Media Co., Ltd; Beijing, China: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Y., Dong S., Liu L., Wu F. A sustainable composite cementitious material manufactured by phosphogypsum waste. Appl. Sci. 2022;12:12718. doi: 10.3390/app122412718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app122412718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>