<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41684156</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-3372</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The plant genome</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plant Genome</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Using genomic selection to examine subgenome dominance and epistasis in allopolyploid strawberry.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70204</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/tpg2.70204</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Allopolyploids are organisms that possess multiple sets of chromosomes derived from distinct ancestral species, resulting in multiple subgenomes. Many important crops are allopolyploid, including wheat (Triticum aestivum), cotton (Gossypium hirsutum), coffee (Coffea arabica), and strawberry (Fragaria &#xd7; ananassa). In allopolyploids, subgenome dominance often emerges, with strong influence on gene expression, epigenetic regulation, and gene conservation. Subgenome dominance has been extensively characterized at the molecular level but very little at the phenotypic level. In this study, we investigated the importance of subgenome interactions for predicting nine phenotypes using a large dataset of 6718 genotypes from the University of Florida strawberry breeding population. We tested multi-kernel genomic selection models accounting for subgenome and epistasis effects to test the genetic contribution of each ancestral strawberry subgenome. Across three yield-related phenotypes, two fruit quality phenotypes, and four disease resistance phenotypes, the contributions of the four subgenomes were highly variable. On average, subgenome B contributed the most genetic variation, followed by subgenome A, then subgenome C, and lastly subgenome D. Using genomic selection models with epistasis kernels, we estimate that epistasis contributed between 12% and 46% of genetic variation for the nine phenotypes. Lastly, we used two different cross-validation scenarios to show that genomic selection models incorporating subgenome and epistatic effects improve predictive ability by 1%-34% depending on the phenotype and the genomic selection training set.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Plant Genome published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Crop Science Society of America.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sleper</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-0222-996X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plant Breeding Graduate Program, Horticultural Sciences Department, IFAS Gulf Coast Research and Education Center, University of Florida, Wimauma, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azevedo</LastName><ForeName>Camila F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Statistics and Biometry Program, Department of Statistics, Federal University of Vi&#xe7;osa, Vi&#xe7;osa, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrao</LastName><ForeName>Luis F</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9655-4838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plant Breeding Graduate Program, Horticultural Sciences Department, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitaker</LastName><ForeName>Vance M</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2172-3019</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plant Breeding Graduate Program, Horticultural Sciences Department, IFAS Gulf Coast Research and Education Center, University of Florida, Wimauma, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Florida Strawberry Research and Education Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2014-51181-22378</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Food and Agriculture</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2017-51181-26833</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Food and Agriculture</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-51181-38328</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Food and Agriculture</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Florida Agricultural Experiment Station</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Plant Genome</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101273919</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1940-3372</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031985" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fragaria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004843" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epistasis, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011123" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polyploidy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018745" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genome, Plant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Selection, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069600" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Breeding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Allopolyploids are organisms that inherit multiple sets of chromosomes from more than one ancestral species. Thus, allopolyploid species possess multiple subgenomes that usually differ in how much they retain and express genes. In this study, we investigated the importance of four different subgenomes in cultivated strawberry for predicting nine traits in 6000 strawberry varieties and selections from the University of Florida. We used genomic selection models accounting for subgenome effects and their interactions to determine the level of contribution from each ancestral strawberry subgenome. We observed highly variable subgenome contributions to each trait. In general, subgenomes A and B contributed the most genetic variation, followed by C and then D. Additionally, we demonstrated that accounting for subgenome effects and genetic interactions improves the ability to predict the best&#x2010;performing parents and varieties in strawberry breeding.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Plant Genome published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Crop Science Society of America.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41684156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tpg2.70204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alger, E. I., &amp; Edger, P. P. (2020). One subgenome to rule them all: Underlying mechanisms of subgenome dominance. Current Opinion in Plant Biology, 54, 108&#x2013;113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pbi.2020.03.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amadeu, R. R., Cellon, C., Olmstead, J. W., Garcia, A. A. F., Resende, M. F. R., &amp; Mu&#xf1;oz, P. R. (2016). AGHmatrix: R package to construct relationship matrices for autotetraploid and diploid species: A blueberry example. The Plant Genome, 9, plantgenome2016.01.0009. https://doi.org/10.3835/plantgenome2016.01.0009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anciro, A., Mangandi, J., Verma, S., Peres, N., Whitaker, V. M., &amp; Lee, S. (2018). FaRCg1: A quantitative trait locus conferring resistance to Colletotrichum crown rot caused by Colletotrichum gloeosporioides in octoploid strawberry. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 131, 2167&#x2013;2177. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;018&#x2010;3145&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates, D., M&#xe4;chler, M., Bolker, B., &amp; Walker, S. (2015). Fitting linear mixed&#x2010;effects models using lme4. Journal of Statistical Software, 67, 1&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v067.i01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardo, R. (2021). Subgenome contributions to quantitative genetic variation in bread wheat and durum wheat populations. Crop Science, 61, 1002&#x2013;1012. https://doi.org/10.1002/csc2.20372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird, K. A., VanBuren, R., Puzey, J. R., &amp; Edger, P. P. (2018). The causes and consequences of subgenome dominance in hybrids and recent polyploids. New Phytologist, 220, 87&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.15256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, C. L., &amp; Madden, L. V. (1990). Introduction to plant disease epidemiology. John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, F., Sun, C., Wu, J., Schnable, J., Woodhouse, M. R., Liang, J., Cai, C., Freeling, M., &amp; Wang, X. (2016). Epigenetic regulation of subgenome dominance following whole genome triplication in Brassica rapa. New Phytologist, 211, 288&#x2013;299. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.13884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas, J., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Di&#xe9;guez, D., Dreisigacker, S., Martini, J. W., Crespo&#x2010;Herrera, L., Lozano&#x2010;Ramirez, N., Singh, P. K., He, X., Huerta, J., &amp; Crossa, J. (2024). Modeling within and between sub&#x2010;genomes epistasis of synthetic Hexaploid wheat for genome&#x2010;enabled prediction of diseases. Genes, 15, 262. https://doi.org/10.3390/genes15030262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darrow, G. M. (1966). The strawberry. History, breeding and physiology (1st ed.). Holt, Rinehart and Winston.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edger, P. P., Poorten, T. J., VanBuren, R., Hardigan, M. A., Colle, M., McKain, M. R., Smith, R. D., Teresi, S. J., Nelson, A. D., Wai, C. M., &amp; Alger, E. I. (2019). Origin and evolution of the octoploid strawberry genome. Nature Genetics, 51, 541&#x2013;547. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588&#x2010;019&#x2010;0356&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endelman, J. B., Carley, C. A. S., Bethke, P. C., Coombs, J. J., Clough, M. E., da Silva, W. L., De Jong, W. S., Douches, D. S., Frederick, C. M., Haynes, K. G., &amp; Holm, D. G. (2018). Genetic variance partitioning and genome&#x2010;wide prediction with allele dosage information in autotetraploid potato. Genetics, 209, 77&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1534/genetics.118.300685</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Z., &amp; Whitaker, V. M. (2024). Genomic signatures of strawberry domestication and diversification. The Plant Cell, 36, 1622&#x2013;1636. https://doi.org/10.1093/plcell/koad314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, C., Jiang, N., Teresi, S. J., Platts, A. E., Agarwal, G., Niederhuth, C., Edger, P. P., &amp; Jiang, J. (2024). Dynamics of accessible chromatin regions and subgenome dominance in octoploid strawberry. Nature Communications, 15, 2491. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;024&#x2010;46861&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, C., Wang, J., Harris, A. J., Folta, K. M., Zhao, M., &amp; Kang, M. (2021). Tracing the diploid ancestry of the cultivated octoploid strawberry. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 38, 478&#x2013;485. https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msaa238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, B., Pazokitoroudi, A., Xue, A., Anand, A., Anand, P., Zaitlen, N., &amp; Sankararaman, S. (2023). A biobank&#x2010;scale test of marginal epistasis reveals genome&#x2010;wide signals of polygenic epistasis. bioRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.09.10.557084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geweke, J. (1992). Evaluating the accuracy of sampling&#x2010;based approaches to the calculation of posterior moments (No. 148). Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, H., Salinas, N., Barbey, C. R., Jang, Y. J., Fan, Z., Verma, S., Whitaker, V. M., &amp; Lee, S. (2025). A telomere&#x2010;to&#x2010;telomere phased genome of an octoploid strawberry reveals a receptor kinase conferring anthracnose resistance. GigaScience, 14, giaf005. https://doi.org/10.1093/gigascience/giaf005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardigan, M. A., Feldmann, M. J., Lorant, A., Bird, K. A., Famula, R., Acharya, C., Cole, G., Edger, P. P., &amp; Knapp, S. J. (2020). Genome synteny has been conserved among the octoploid progenitors of cultivated strawberry over millions of years of evolution. Frontiers in Plant Science, 10, 1789. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2019.01789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardigan, M. A., Feldmann, M. J., Pincot, D. D., Famula, R. A., Vachev, M. V., Madera, M. A., Zerbe, P., Mars, K., Peluso, P., Rank, D., &amp; Ou, S. (2021). Blueprint for phasing and assembling the genomes of heterozygous polyploids: Application to the octoploid genome of strawberry. BioRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.11.03.467115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardigan, M. A., Lorant, A., Pincot, D. D., Feldmann, M. J., Famula, R. A., Acharya, C. B., Lee, S., Verma, S., Whitaker, V. M., Bassil, N., &amp; Zurn, J. (2021). Unraveling the complex hybrid ancestry and domestication history of cultivated strawberry. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 38, 2285&#x2013;2305. https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msab024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, C. R. (1985). Best linear unbiased prediction of nonadditive genetic merits in noninbred populations. Journal of Animal Science, 60, 111&#x2013;117. https://doi.org/10.2527/jas1985.601111x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez, N. P., Bjornson, M., Famula, R. A., Pincot, D. D., Hardigan, M. A., Madera, M. A., Lopez Ramirez, C. M., Cole, G. S., Feldmann, M. J., &amp; Knapp, S. J. (2025). Loss&#x2010;of&#x2010;function mutations in the fruit softening gene POLYGALACTURONASE1 doubled fruit firmness in strawberry. Horticulture Research, 12, uhae315. https://doi.org/10.1093/hr/uhae315</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez, N. P., Feldmann, M. J., Famula, R. A., Pincot, D. D., Bjornson, M., Cole, G. S., &amp; Knapp, S. J. (2023). Harnessing underutilized gene bank diversity and genomic prediction of cross usefulness to enhance resistance to Phytophthora cactorum in strawberry. The Plant Genome, 16, e20275. https://doi.org/10.1002/tpg2.20275</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, X., Du, H., Zhu, C., Wan, H., Liu, F., Ruan, J., Mower, J. P., &amp; Zhu, A. (2023). Haplotype&#x2010;resolved genomes of wild octoploid progenitors illuminate genomic diversifications from wild relatives to cultivated strawberry. Nature Plants, 9, 1252&#x2013;1266. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41477&#x2010;023&#x2010;01473&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legarra, A. (2016). Comparing estimates of genetic variance across different relationship models. Theoretical Population Biology, 107, 26&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tpb.2015.08.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, A., Liu, D., Wu, J., Zhao, X., Hao, M., Geng, S., Yan, J., Jiang, X., Zhang, L., Wu, J., &amp; Yin, L. (2014). mRNA and small RNA transcriptomes reveal insights into dynamic homoeolog regulation of allopolyploid heterosis in nascent hexaploid wheat. The Plant Cell, 26, 1878&#x2013;1900. https://doi.org/10.1105/tpc.114.124388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, P. F., Liu, Y. L., Guo, C., Jin, G., Guo, Z. H., Mao, L., Yang, Y. Z., Niu, L. Z., Wang, Y. J., Clark, L. G., &amp; Kellogg, E. A. (2024). Genome assemblies of 11 bamboo species highlight diversification induced by dynamic subgenome dominance. Nature Genetics, 56, 710&#x2013;720. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588&#x2010;024&#x2010;01683&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangandi, J., Verma, S., Osorio, L., Peres, N. A., Van De Weg, E., &amp; Whitaker, V. M. (2017). Pedigree&#x2010;based analysis in a multiparental population of octoploid strawberry reveals QTL alleles conferring resistance to phytophthora cactorum. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 7, 1707&#x2013;1719. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.117.042119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini, J. W., Wimmer, V., Erbe, M., &amp; Simianer, H. (2016). Epistasis and covariance: How gene interaction translates into genomic relationship. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 129, 963&#x2013;976. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;016&#x2010;2675&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meuwissen, T. H. E., Hayes, B. J., &amp; Goddard, M. E. (2001). Prediction of total genetic value using genome&#x2010;wide dense marker maps. Genetics, 157, 1819&#x2013;1829. https://doi.org/10.1093/genetics/157.4.1819</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, J. R., Verma, S., Bassil, N. V., Finn, C. E., Hancock, J. F., Cole, G. S., Knapp, S. J., &amp; Whitaker, V. M. (2021). Discovery of three loci increasing resistance to charcoal rot caused by Macrophomina phaseolina in octoploid strawberry. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 11, jkab037. https://doi.org/10.1093/g3journal/jkab037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osorio, L. F., Gezan, S. A., Verma, S., &amp; Whitaker, V. M. (2021). Independent validation of genomic prediction in strawberry over multiple cycles. Frontiers in Genetics, 11, 596258. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2020.596258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez, P., &amp; De Los Campos, G. (2014). Genome&#x2010;wide regression and prediction with the BGLR statistical package. Genetics, 198, 483&#x2013;495. https://doi.org/10.1534/genetics.114.164442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeifer, M., Kugler, K. G., Sandve, S. R., Zhan, B., Rudi, H., Hvidsten, T. R., Mayer, K. F. X., &amp; Olsen, O.&#x2010;A. (2014). Genome interplay in the grain transcriptome of hexaploid bread wheat. Science, 345(6194), 1250091. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1250091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piaskowski, J., Hardner, C., Cai, L., Zhao, Y., Iezzoni, A., &amp; Peace, C. (2018). Genomic heritability estimates in sweet cherry reveal non&#x2010;additive genetic variance is relevant for industry&#x2010;prioritized traits. BMC Genetics, 19, 1&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12863&#x2010;018&#x2010;0609&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffo, M. A., Sarup, P., Guo, X., Liu, H., Andersen, J. R., Orabi, J., Jahoor, A., &amp; Jensen, J. (2022). Improvement of genomic prediction in advanced wheat breeding lines by including additive&#x2010;by&#x2010;additive epistasis. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 135, 965&#x2013;978. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;021&#x2010;04009&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santantonio, N., Jannink, J.&#x2010;L., &amp; Sorrells, M. (2019). Prediction of subgenome Additive and Interaction Effects in Allohexaploid Wheat. G3 (Bethesda), 9, 685&#x2013;698. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.118.200613</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnable, J. C., Springer, N. M., &amp; Freeling, M. (2011). Differentiation of the maize subgenomes by genome dominance and both ancient and ongoing gene loss. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108, 4069&#x2013;4074. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1101368108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Session, A. M., &amp; Rokhsar, D. S. (2023). Transposon signatures of allopolyploid genome evolution. Nature Communications, 14, 3180. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;023&#x2010;38560&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleper, J. A., &amp; Bernardo, R. (2018). Genomewide selection for unfavorably correlated traits in maize. Crop Science, 58, 1587&#x2013;1593. https://doi.org/10.2135/cropsci2017.12.0719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleper, J. A., Tapia, R., Lee, S., &amp; Whitaker, V. M. (2025). Within&#x2010;family genomic selection in strawberry: Optimization of marker density, trial design, and training set composition. The Plant Genome, 18, e20550. https://doi.org/10.1002/tpg2.20550</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y., Peng, Y., Liu, L., Li, G., Zhao, X., Wang, X., Cao, S., Muyle, A., Zhou, Y., &amp; Zhou, H. (2024). Phased gap&#x2010;free genome assembly of octoploid cultivated strawberry illustrates the genetic and epigenetic divergence among subgenomes. Horticulture Research, 11, uhad252. https://doi.org/10.1093/hr/uhad252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia, R., Abd&#x2010;Elrahman, A., Osorio, L., Whitaker, V. M., &amp; Lee, S. (2022). Combining canopy reflectance spectrometry and genome&#x2010;wide prediction to increase response to selection for powdery mildew resistance in cultivated strawberry. Journal of Experimental Botany, 73, 5322&#x2013;5335. https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erac136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessele, A., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Di&#xe9;guez, D. O., Crossa, J., Johnson, B. E., Morris, G. P., &amp; Fritz, A. K. (2025). Improving genomic selection in hexaploid wheat with sub&#x2010;genome additive and epistatic models. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 5(4), jkaf031. https://doi.org/10.1093/g3journal/jkaf031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, B. C., Pedersen, B., &amp; Freeling, M. (2006). Following tetraploidy in an Arabidopsis ancestor, genes were removed preferentially from one homeolog leaving clusters enriched in dose&#x2010;sensitive genes. Genome Research, 16, 934&#x2013;946. https://doi.org/10.1101/gr.4708406</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Peer, Y., Mizrachi, E., &amp; Marchal, K. (2017). The evolutionary significance of polyploidy. Nature Reviews Genetics, 18, 411&#x2013;424. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg.2017.26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Weg, E., Verma, S., Bassil, N. V., Harrison, R. J., Monfort, A., Hidalgo, J. M., Amaya, I., Denoyes, B., Mahoney, L., Davis, T. M., &amp; Fan, Z. (2016). Development and evaluation of the Axiom&#xae; Istraw35 384HT array for the allo&#x2010;octoploid cultivated strawberry Fragaria &#xd7; ananassa. VIII International Strawberry Symposium, 1156, 75&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864&#x2010;015&#x2010;1310&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanRaden, P. M. (2008). Efficient methods to compute genomic predictions. Journal of Dairy Science, 91, 4414&#x2013;4423. https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2007&#x2010;0980</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazco, J. G., Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;&#xc1;lvarez, M. X., Boer, M. P., Jordan, D. R., Eilers, P. H. C., Malosetti, M., &amp; Van Eeuwijk, F. A. (2017). Modelling spatial trends in sorghum breeding field trials using a two&#x2010;dimensional P&#x2010;spline mixed model. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 130, 1375&#x2013;1392. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;017&#x2010;2894&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, C., Abd&#x2010;Elrahman, A., Whitaker, V., &amp; Dalid, C. (2022). Prediction of strawberry dry biomass from UAV multispectral imagery using multiple machine learning methods. Remote Sensing, 14(18), 4511. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs14184511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X., Im, H. K., &amp; Lee, S. H. (2020). CORE GREML for estimating covariance between random effects in linear mixed models for complex trait analyses. Nature Communications, 11, 4208. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;020&#x2010;18085&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zingaretti, L. M., Gezan, S. A., Ferr&#xe3;o, L. F. V., Osorio, L. F., Monfort, A., Mu&#xf1;oz, P. R., Whitaker, V. M., &amp; P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Enciso, M. (2020). Exploring deep learning for complex trait genomic prediction in polyploid outcrossing species. Frontiers in Plant Science, 11, Article 25. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2020.00025</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>