<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41566419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1813-7253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European review of aging and physical activity : official journal of the European Group for Research into Elderly and Physical Activity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing prescription of resistance training for body composition, muscle strength, and physical performance in older adults with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s11556-025-00399-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to address key gaps in understanding the role of resistance training (RT) as an intervention to mitigate age-related sarcopenia. Specifically, it examined: (i) effects on body composition and physical performance; (ii) moderating influences of age and training intensity; and (iii) the presence of a dose-response relationship within the FITT-VP framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive search of multiple databases identified randomized controlled trials (RCTs) evaluating RT in older adults with sarcopenia. Data on body composition, muscle strength (MS), and functional performance were extracted. Moderator analyses assessed the impact of participant and intervention characteristics, and meta-regression was performed to explore dose-response patterns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-five RCTs involving 1,302 participants were included. RT produced significant improvements in MS (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.71), lean mass (LM, [ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.22]), fat mass (FM, [ES = -&#x2009;0.17]), walking ability (WA, [ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.41]), grip strength ([GS, [ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.55]), muscle quality (MQ, [ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.25]) (all p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), but this large effect size was based on only two studies and requires caution interpretation. Dose-response meta-regression revealed a significant non-linear relationship between total RT duration and functional gains, with optimal estimated cumulative volumes of ~&#x2009;2,716&#xa0;min for WA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">RT is a robust, evidence-based strategy for enhancing MS, functional performance, and body composition in sarcopenic older adults. Findings suggest approximate cumulative duration ranges (~&#x2009;1,043&#xa0;min for MS and ~&#x2009;2,716&#xa0;min for WA) that were associated with maximal gains in pooled analyses. These values should be interpreted as exploratory indicators supporting individualized programming within the FITT-VP framework. Clinicians and exercise practitioners should tailor intensity (60-80% 1RM), frequency, and progression to optimize adherence, effectiveness, and long-term functional outcomes in sarcopenia management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Belgrade, Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, Belgrade, Serbia. zhiyuan_5016@studentmail.fsfv.bg.ac.rs.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Normal University, School of Physical Education, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Regina, Faculty of Kinesiology &amp; Health Studies, Regina, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castagna</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Education and Sport Sciences, Pegaso Telematic University, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China University of Geosciences, School of Physical Education, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Huakun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai University of Sport, School of Exercise And Health, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101284836</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1813-7253</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aging population</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postural balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41566419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12908291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-025-00399-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s11556-025-00399-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pison G, Couppi&#xe9; E, Caporali A. The population of the world, 2022. Popul Soc. 2022;603(8):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupont J. Revised sarcopenia consensus: are we missing the preclinical stage? Online comment on. Age Ageing. 2018;48(1):1&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung SS, Reijnierse EM, Pham VK, et al. Sarcopenia and its association with falls and fractures in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2019;10(3):485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benz E, Trajanoska K, Lahousse L, Schoufour JD, Terzikhan N, De Roos E, et al. Sarcopenia in COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Respir Rev. 2019;28(154):190049. 10.1183/16000617.0049-2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31722892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fhon JRS, Silva ARF, Lima EFC, et al. Association between sarcopenia, falls, and cognitive impairment in older people: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(5):4156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10002412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36901167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Wan CS, Ktoris K, Reijnierse EM, Maier AB. Sarcopenia is associated with mortality in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gerontology. 2022;68(4):361&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(1):16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S, Larsson SC. Epidemiology of sarcopenia: Prevalence, risk factors, and consequences. Metabolism. 2023;144:155533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36907247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Haehling S, Morley JE, Anker SD. An overview of sarcopenia: facts and numbers on prevalence and clinical impact. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2010;1(2):129&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21475695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland Y, Dray C, Vellas B, Barreto PDS. Current and investigational medications for the treatment of sarcopenia. Metabolism. 2023;149:155597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37348598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak JY, Kwon K-S. Pharmacological interventions for treatment of sarcopenia: current status of drug development for sarcopenia. Annals Geriatric Med Res. 2019;23(3):98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32743297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, Singh MAF, et al. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(7):1510&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Merchant RA, Morley JE, et al. International exercise recommendations in older adults (ICFSR): expert consensus guidelines. J Nutr Health Aging. 2021;25(7):824&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12369211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34409961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, Izquierdo M, Kraemer WJ, Peterson MD, et al. Resistance Training for Older Adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2019&#x2013;52.&#xa0;10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, French DN. Resistance training for health and performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2002;1(3):165&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(2):249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang G, Wu X. Effects of resistance training combined with balance training on physical function among older adults: A protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2022;12(10):e062486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9535182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Mao L, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y, Chen N. Effects of different exercise training modes on muscle strength and physical performance in older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21(1):708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Shi Q, Nong K, et al. Exercise for sarcopenia in older people: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2023;14(3):1199&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10235889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37057640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Saco-Ledo G, Morales JS, et al. Effects of physical exercise on physical function in older adults in residential care: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2023;4(6):e247&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37182530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talar K, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Vetrovsky T, Steffl M, Ka&#x142;amacka E, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J. Benefits of resistance training in early and late stages of frailty and sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies. J Clin Med. 2021;10(8):1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8070531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavasini R, Serenelli M, Celis-Morales CA, et al. Grip strength predicts cardiac adverse events in patients with cardiac disorders: an individual patient pooled meta-analysis. Heart. 2019;105(11):834&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30455175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celis-Morales CA, Welsh P, Lyall DM, Steell L, Petermann F, Anderson J, et al. Associations of grip strength with cardiovascular, respiratory, and cancer outcomes and all cause mortality: prospective cohort study of half a million UK Biobank participants. BMJ. 2018;361:k1651. 10.1136/bmj.k1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5939721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckw&#xe9;e D, Delaere A, Aelbrecht S, et al. Exercise interventions for the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia. A systematic umbrella review. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23(6):494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12280365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31233069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C-D, Tsauo J-Y, Wu Y-T, et al. Effects of protein supplementation combined with resistance exercise on body composition and physical function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;106(4):1078&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reginster J-Y, Beaudart C, Al-Daghri N, et al. Update on the ESCEO recommendation for the conduct of clinical trials for drugs aiming at the treatment of sarcopenia in older adults. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2021;33(1):3&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7897619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32737844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P, Magnusson SP, Kj&#xe6;r M. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: strength training as a countermeasure. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(1):49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20487503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherrington C, Fairhall NJ, Wallbank GK, Tiedemann A, Michaleff ZA, Howard K, et al. Exercise for preventing falls in older people living in the community. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;1(1):CD012424.10.1002/14651858.CD012424.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30703272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steib S, Schoene D, Pfeifer K. Dose-response relationship of resistance training in older adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(5):902&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond MJ, Bramley-Tzerefos RE, Jeffs KJ, Winter A, Holland AE. Systematic review of high-intensity progressive resistance strength training of the lower limb compared with other intensities of strength training in older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(8):1458&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23473702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsekoura M, Billis E, Tsepis E, et al. The effects of group and home-based exercise programs in elderly with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2018;7(12):480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G, et al. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription[M]. American College of Sports Medicine, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman ME, Hernandez J. The assessment of affective responses within exercise prescription: a narrative review. Int J Sports Med. 2023;44(08):558&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;53(6):1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S, Kong S, Kim C-H, et al. Position statement: Evidence-Based exercise guidelines for sarcopenia in older adults: insights from the Korean working group on sarcopenia. Annals Geriatric Med Res. 2025;29(3):278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12489597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41025271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan Y, Tytko T, Hui B. Utilizing ASReview in screening primary studies for meta-research in SLA: A step-by-step tutorial. Res Methods Appl Linguistics. 2024;3(1):100101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Schoot R, De Bruin J, Schram R, et al. An open source machine learning framework for efficient and transparent systematic reviews. Nat Mach Intell. 2021;3(2):125&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;2019(10):ED000142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L-K, Woo J, Assantachai P, et al. Asian working group for sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21(3):300&#x2013;7. e302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Studenski SA, Peters KW, Alley DE et al. The FNIH sarcopenia project: rationale, study description, conference recommendations, and final estimates. Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biomedical Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2014;69(5):547&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3991146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24737557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donini LM, Busetto L, Bischoff SC, et al. Definition and diagnostic criteria for sarcopenic obesity: ESPEN and EASO consensus statement. Obes Facts. 2022;15(3):321&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9210010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Ragusa FS, Pegreffi F, et al. Sarcopenic obesity and health outcomes: an umbrella review of systematic reviews with meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2024;15(4):1264&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38897937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin O, Yassikaya MY. Validity and reliability analysis of the plotdigitizer software program for data extraction from single-case graphs. Perspect Behav Sci. 2022;45(1):239&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8894524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35342869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.&#xa0;10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Olkin I. Statistical methods for meta-analysis[M]. Academic press, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences[M]. routledge, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, et al. Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. JBI Evid Implement. 2015;13(1):9&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.&#xa0;10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Z, Castagna C, Krustrup P, et al. Exploring the use of 5 different Yo-Yo tests in evaluating V &#x2d9; O 2 max &#x2d9; V O _ 2\max and fitness profile in team sports: A systematic review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2025;35(5):e70054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40356566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Vist GE, Falck-Ytter Y, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ. What is quality of evidence and why is it important to clinicians? BMJ. 2008;336(7651):995&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2364804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18456631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VJHW. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Hoboken: Wiley. 2019;4(1002):14651858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials. 1986;7(3):177&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11(2):202&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElroy T, Sutcliffe A. An iterated parametric approach to nonstationary signal extraction. Comput Stat Data Anal. 2006;50(9):2206&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;-Carvajal A. Cochrane&#x2019;s contribution to global health: three decades of progress in sickle cell disease research. Front Hematol. 2025;4:1535100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Introduction to meta-analysis. John wiley &amp; sons.&#xa0;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli RN, Otto RM, Winnett RA. A CRITICAL ANALYSIS OF THE ACSM POSITION STAND ON RESISTANCETRAINING: INSUFFICIENT EVIDENCE TO SUPPORT RECOMMENDED TRAINING PROTOCOLS[J]. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2004;7(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desquilbet L, Mariotti F. Dose-response analyses using restricted cubic spline functions in public health research. Stat Med. 2010;29(9):1037&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20087875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muggeo VM. Segmented: an R package to fit regression models with broken-line relationships. R News. 2008;8(1):20&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters JL, Sutton AJ, Jones DR, Abrams KR, Rushton L. Contour-enhanced meta-analysis funnel plots help distinguish publication bias from other causes of asymmetry. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(10):991&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18538991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton E. Small sample adjustments for robust variance Estimation with meta-regression. Psychol Methods. 2015;20(3):375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24773356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y-H, Lee P-H, Lin L-F, Liao C-D, Liou T-H, Huang S-W. Effects of progressive elastic band resistance exercise for aged osteosarcopenic adiposity women. Exp Gerontol. 2021;147:111272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33549820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu S-C, Yang R-S, Yang R-J, Chang S-F. Effects of resistance training on body composition and functional capacity among sarcopenic obese residents in long-term care facilities: a preliminary study. BMC Geriatr. 2018;18(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5778732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29357826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>i Iranzo M&#xc0;C, Balasch-Bernat M, Tortosa-Chuli&#xe1; M&#xc1;, Balasch-Parisi S. Effects of resistance training of peripheral muscles versus respiratory muscles in older adults with sarcopenia who are institutionalized: a randomized controlled trial. J Aging Phys Act. 2018;26(4):637&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KJ, Son S, Kim KJ, Kim SG, Kim NH. Weight-adjusted waist as an integrated index for fat, muscle and bone health in adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2023;14(5):2196&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10570086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37550773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham MI, Aprahamian T, Won CW, Theou O. International Exercise Recommendations in Older Adults (ICFSR): Expert Consensus Guidelines.&#xa0;2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12369211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34409961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Schobersberger W. Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J Obes. 2011;2011(1):482564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CJ, Latham NK. Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;2009(3):CD002759.&#xa0;10.1002/14651858.CD002759.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4324332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(2):249&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93(4):1318&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico MJ, Kostek MC, Doldo NA, et al. Effects of moderate-velocity strength training on peak muscle power and movement velocity: do women respond differently than men? J Appl Physiol. 2005;99(5):1712&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves ND, Narici MV, Maganaris CN. Strength training alters the viscoelastic properties of tendons in elderly humans. Muscle Nerve: Official J Am Association Electrodiagn Med. 2003;28(1):74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12811776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR. Effects of aging on muscle fibre type and size. Sports Med. 2004;34(12):809&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15462613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Lindheimer JB, Brady AO, Dishman RK, Evans EM. Effects of resistance training on Lower-Extremity muscle power in Middle-Aged and older adults: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med. 2016;46(3):353&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M, Dirks ML, van der Zwaluw N, et al. Protein supplementation increases muscle mass gain during prolonged resistance-type exercise training in frail elderly people: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2012;13(8):713&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22770932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: strength training as a countermeasure. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(1):49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20487503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopka AR, Harber MP. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after aerobic exercise training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42(2):53&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CJ, Latham NK. Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;2009(3):Cd002759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4324332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart C, Dawson A, Shaw SC, et al. Nutrition and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia: systematic review. Osteoporos Int. 2017;28(6):1817&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, et al. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in vivo. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3(11):1014&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(5):1199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Kaasalainen T, et al. Postexercise myostatin and activin IIb mRNA levels: effects of strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(2):289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, et al. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-I and androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am J physiology-endocrinology Metabolism. 2001;280(3):E383&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Nederveen JP, McKay BR, et al. Satellite cells in human skeletal muscle plasticity. Front Physiol. 2015;6:283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4617172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Kallinen M, Izquierdo M, et al. Changes in agonist-antagonist EMG, muscle CSA, and force during strength training in middle-aged and older people. J Appl Physiol. 1998;84(4):1341&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9516202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Haun C, Itagaki T, Helms ER. Calculating set-volume for the limb muscles with the performance of multi-joint exercises: implications for resistance training prescription. Sports. 2019;7(7):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S, Parise G, Roy B, Tipton K, Wolfe R, Tarnopolsky M. Resistance-training-induced adaptations in skeletal muscle protein turnover in the fed state. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2002;80(11):1045&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12489923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese EJ, Mattson MP. How does hormesis impact biology, toxicology, and medicine? NPJ Aging Mech Disease. 2017;3(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5601424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(11):1286&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U. Dose&#x2013;response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(12):1693&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>