<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41808113</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A transdiagnostic mentalization-based parenting intervention versus care as usual for parents with mental disorders in adult mental health services in Denmark: protocol for a randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09587-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Mental disorders can impact parenting negatively, thus placing their children at risk of adversity. The current service support for parents in adult mental health (AMHS)&#xa0;service is limited. The objective of this randomized clinical trial will be to evaluate the effects of a transdiagnostic mentalization-based parenting program (Lighthouse MBT&#xa0;Parenting Program) versus care as usual (CAU) for parents with mental disorders in AMHS in Denmark.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This trial is designed as an investigator-initiated single-center open-label randomized clinical superiority trial of the Lighthouse MBT&#xa0;Parenting Program compared to CAU for parents with mental disorders. Participants will be recruited from Danish outpatient mental health clinics by the local service providers and will be included if they have a child 0-17 years of age, whom they are in regular contact with. We plan to randomize 170 parents with a 1:1 allocation ratio stratified by parental gender and baseline parenting stress score. The primary outcome will be level of parenting stress (Parenting Stress Index version 4 - Short Form). Secondary outcomes will be child psychological problems and functioning (Strength and Difficulties Questionnaire - Extended version), parental quality of life (brief abbreviated version of the World Health Organization Questionnaire of Life), family functioning (McMaster Family Assessment Device - General Functioning), exposure to child adversity in offspring (Adverse Child Experiences Questionnaire), parenting competence (Parenting Sense of Competence), parental psychiatric symptom severity (Brief Symptom Inventory), parental health-related quality of life and functioning (European Quality of Life - 5 Dimensions - 3 Levels), and parental use of drugs and alcohol (Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test and the Drug Use Disorders Identification Test - Extended). The primary and secondary outcomes will be assessed before randomization and at 6, 12, and 24 months after randomization. The primary time-point of assessment will be 6 months after randomization for all randomized participants. Exploratory outcomes include key theoretical concepts, including&#xa0;parental mentalizing (Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire), mind-mindedness (representational Mind-Mindedness), and epistemic trust (Epistemic Trust, Mistrust, and Credulity Questionnaire). Exploratory outcomes will be assessed at baseline and at 6 months follow-up. Adverse events will be systematically monitored throughout the trial period using the e-journal system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This trial will provide evidence of the effects of a transdiagnostic mentalization-based parenting intervention (Lighthouse MBT Parenting Program)&#xa0;compared to care as usual for parents with mental disorders in adult mental health services&#xa0;in Denmark.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov: NCT06315114. Registration on 01-03-2024.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hestbaek</LastName><ForeName>Emilie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0508-7929</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center Stolpeg&#xe5;rd, Copenhagen University Hospital - Mental Health Services CPH, Copenhagen, Denmark. emilie.hestbaek.jacobsen@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Copenhagen, &#xd8;ster Farimagsgade 2A, Copenhagen, 1353, Denmark. emilie.hestbaek.jacobsen@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>V&#xe6;ver</LastName><ForeName>Mette Skovgaard</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9675-3423</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juul</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6171-2904</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center Stolpeg&#xe5;rd, Copenhagen University Hospital - Mental Health Services CPH, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Copenhagen, &#xd8;ster Farimagsgade 2A, Copenhagen, 1353, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Intervention Research, Copenhagen Trial Unit, The Capital Region, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xf8;rensen</LastName><ForeName>Per</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1882-3856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center Stolpeg&#xe5;rd, Copenhagen University Hospital - Mental Health Services CPH, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sleed</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2321-2116</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anna Freud, 4-8 Rodney Street, London, N1 9JH, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simonsen</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5488-7562</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center Stolpeg&#xe5;rd, Copenhagen University Hospital - Mental Health Services CPH, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Copenhagen, &#xd8;ster Farimagsgade 2A, Copenhagen, 1353, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06315114</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>3101-00179B</GrantID><Agency>Danmarks Frie Forskningsfond</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lighthouse parenting program</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mentalization-based treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mentalizing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parenting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parents with mental disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transdiagnostic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Prior to commencing the trial, approval was obtained from the Regional Ethics Committee and from the Danish Data Protection Agency and Data Protection Act (ID: P-2023-15049). The trial will be conducted in compliance with the official trial protocol, the World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki [104], ICH-GCP guidelines [102], and the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) standards [105]. There are some potential ethical concerns relevant to this trial. First, participation in research assessments may be a minor burden to the parents. Secondly, as the target population includes parents with a mental disorder, who constitute a high-risk group in terms of child maltreatment, all therapists and on-site members of the research team will receive training in terms of policies and procedures for handling concerns about children&#x2019;s safety. Third, the interventions are not expected to be associated with any side effects or risk to parents or children. Both the experimental intervention and control intervention follow the clinical guidelines by the Mental Health Services, Capital Region. However, we are aware that participation in parenting-focused interventions for high-risk groups may be emotionally demanding and at times stressful, which could impact our outcome measures. In addition, random allocation of psychiatric patients may result in lack of trust and feelings of abandonment if allocated to an untoward intervention (typically CAU). This could potentially influence their motivation to continue receiving their usual psychiatric treatment and may thus pose a risk of the patients&#x2019; dropping out of the research project as well as their standard psychiatric treatment. The consent allows the investigators, sponsor, and representatives of the sponsor, as well as any regulatory authority, direct access to obtain information in the participant&#x2019;s records, including electronic records, to review details about the participant&#x2019;s health conditions that are necessary for the implementation of the research project, as well as for monitoring purposes, including self-inspection, quality control, and monitoring that they are obligated to perform. During the trial period, serious adverse events for participating parents will be carefully monitored throughout the trial, and we will assess, document, and report any adverse events to the regional research ethics committee. This committee monitors all reports of serious adverse events from trial sites. Exclusion from the trial only occurs in case of acute serious endangerment of the participant or his/her child. Participants can, at any time, withdraw their consent without any implications for current or future treatment in the Mental Health Service, Capital Region. The trial is covered by patient compensation. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09587-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09587-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Christesen AMS, Knudsen CK, Fonager K, Johansen MN, Heuckendorff S. Prevalence of parental mental health conditions among children aged 0&#x2013;16 years in Denmark: a nationwide register-based cross-sectional study. Scand J Public Health. 2021Oct;5:14034948211045462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psykiatrifonden. Grib b&#xf8;rnene. K&#xf8;benhavn; 2024.&#xa0;https://kombu.dk/files/media/document/Grib_boernene_rapport_psykiatrifonden_2024_0.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maybery D, Reupert AE. The number of parents who are patients attending adult psychiatric services. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2018;31(4):358&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reupert AE, J Maybery D, Kowalenko NM. Children whose parents have a mental illness: prevalence, need and treatment. Med J Austr. 2013;199(3):S7&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psykiatrifonden. Unders&#xf8;gelse af forekomst af psykisk sygdom blandt for&#xe6;ldre til b&#xf8;rn i alderen 0-18 &#xe5;r. K&#xf8;benhavn; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Santvoort F, Hosman CMH, Janssens JMAM, van Doesum KTM, Reupert A, van Loon LMA. The impact of various parental mental disorders on children&#x2019;s diagnoses: a systematic review. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2015Dec 1;18(4):281&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok PLH, Pedersen CB, Springate D, Astrup A, Kapur N, Antonsen S, et al. Parental psychiatric disease and risks of attempted suicide and violent criminal offending in offspring: a population-based cohort study. JAMA Psychiat. 2016Oct 1;73(10):1015&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranning A, Munk Laursen T, Thorup A, Hjorth&#xf8;j C, Nordentoft M. Serious mental illness and disrupted caregiving for children: a nationwide, register-based cohort study. J Clin Psychiatry. 2015;76(8):e1006-1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohl PL, Jonson-Reid M, Drake B. Maternal mental illness and the safety and stability of maltreated children. Child Abuse Negl. 2011;35(5):309&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leijdesdorff S, van Doesum K, Popma A, Klaassen R, van Amelsvoort T. Prevalence of psychopathology in children of parents with mental illness and/or addiction: an up to date narrative review. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2017;30(4):312&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster CE, Webster MC, Weissman MM, Pilowsky DJ, Wickramaratne PJ, Rush AJ, et al. Course and severity of maternal depression: associations with family functioning and child adjustment. J Youth Adolesc. 2008;37(8):906&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattejat F, Remschmidt H. The children of mentally ill parents. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2008;105(23):413&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashman SB, Dawson G, Panagiotides H. Trajectories of maternal depression over 7 years: relations with child psychophysiology and behavior and role of contextual risks. Dev Psychopathol. 2008;20(1):55&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen I, Kruse M. Samfunds&#xf8;konomiske konsekvenser af at v&#xe6;re barn af for&#xe6;ldre med mentale helbredsproblemer. Dansk Center for Sundheds&#xf8;konomi, Institut for Sundhedstjenesteforskning, Syddansk Universitet; 2022;66. Available from: https://www.epaper.dk/psykiatrifonden/rapport_barn_for_ldre_mentale_helbredsproblemer/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renneberg B, Rosenbach C. &#x201c;There is not much help for mothers like me&#x201d;: parenting skills for mothers with borderline personality disorder &#x2013; a newly developed group training program. Borderline Personal Disord Emot Dysregul. 2016 Dec 1 [cited 2020 Sep 7];3. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5131544/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reupert A, Bee P, Hosman C, Van Doesum K, Drost LM, Falkov A, et al. Editorial perspective: Prato Research Collaborative for change in parent and child mental health &#x2013; principles and recommendations for working with children and parents living with parental mental illness. Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2022;63(3):350&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman JJ. Giving kids a fair chance. Cambridge, Mass: The MIT Press; 2013. 137 (Boston review books).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegenthaler E, Munder T, Egger M. Effect of preventive interventions in mentally ill parents on the mental health of the offspring: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2012;51(1):8-17.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lannes A, Bui E, Arnaud C, Raynaud JP, Revet A. Preventive interventions in offspring of parents with mental illness: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Psychol Med. 2021;51(14):2321&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanh&#xe4;user M, Lemmer G, de Girolamo G, Christiansen H. Do preventive interventions for children of mentally ill parents work? Results of a systematic review and meta-analysis. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2017;30(4):283&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hestbaek E, Kofoed J, Barlow J, Thorup AAE, Sleed M, Simonsen S, et al. Protocol for a systematic review with meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis of preventive interventions versus any control intervention for parents with a mental disorder on offspring outcomes. Syst Rev. 2024Nov 27;13(1):292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosman CMH, van Doesum KTM, van Santvoort F. Prevention of emotional problems and psychiatric risks in children of parents with a mental illness in the Netherlands: I. The scientific basis to a comprehensive approach. Australian e-J Adv Mental Health. 2009;8(3):250&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harries CI, Smith DM, Gregg L, Wittkowski A. Parenting and serious mental illness (SMI): a systematic review and metasynthesis. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2023;26(2):303&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda T, Tran T, Popplestone S, Draper CE, Yousafzai AK, Romero L, et al. Parents&#x2019; mental health and the social-emotional development of their children aged between 24 and 59 months in low-and middle-income countries: a systematic review and meta-analyses. SSM - Mental Health. 2023;3:100197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyten P, Campbell C, Allison E, Fonagy P. The mentalizing approach to psychopathology: state of the art and future directions. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2020;16(1):297&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyten P, Nijssens L, Fonagy P, Mayes LC. Parental reflective functioning: theory, research, and clinical applications. Psychoanal Study Child. 2017Mar 31;70(1):174&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade A. Parental reflective functioning: an introduction. Attach Hum Dev. 2005;7(3):269&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman A, Fonagy P, American Psychiatric Association Publishing, editors. Handbook of mentalizing in mental health practice. Second edition. Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Association Publishing; 2019;2:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ensink K, Borelli JL, Roy J, Normandin L, Slade A, Fonagy P. Costs of not getting to know you: lower levels of parental reflective functioning confer risk for maternal insensitivity and insecure infant attachment. Infancy. 2019;24(2):210&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grienenberger JF, Kelly K, Slade A. Maternal reflective functioning, mother-infant affective communication, and infant attachment: exploring the link between mental states and observed caregiving behavior in the intergenerational transmission of attachment. Attach Hum Dev. 2005;7(3):299&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camoirano A. Mentalizing makes parenting work: a review about parental reflective functioning and clinical interventions to improve it. Front Psychol. 2017;8:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong K, Stacks AM, Rosenblum KL, Muzik M. Parental reflective functioning moderates the relationship between difficult temperament in infancy and behavior problems in toddlerhood. Merrill-Palmer Q. 2017;63(1):54&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade A, Sleed M. Parental reflective functioning on the parent development interview: a narrative review of measurement, association, and future directions. Infant Ment Health J. 2024;22:imhj.22114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblum KL, Mcdonough SC, Sameroff AJ, Muzik M. Reflection in thought and action: maternal parenting reflectivity predicts mind-minded comments and interactive behavior. Infant Ment Health J. 2008;29(4):362&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeegers MAJ, Colonnesi C, Stams GJJM, Meins E. Mind matters: a meta-analysis on parental mentalization and sensitivity as predictors of infant-parent attachment. Psychol Bull. 2017;143(12):1245&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacks AM, Muzik M, Wong K, Beeghly M, Huth-Bocks A, Irwin JL, et al. Maternal reflective functioning among mothers with childhood maltreatment histories: links to sensitive parenting and infant attachment security. Attach Hum Dev. 2014;16(5):515&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo CKM, Wong SY. The effectiveness of parenting programs in regard to improving parental reflective functioning: a meta-analysis. Attach Human Develop. 2020;0(0):1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne G, Murphy S, Connon G. Mentalization-based treatments with children and families: a systematic review of the literature. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2020Oct 1;25(4):1022&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne G, Sleed M, Midgley N, Fearon P, Mein C, Bateman A, et al. Lighthouse parenting programme: description and pilot evaluation of mentalization-based treatment to address child maltreatment. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2019;24(4):680&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchman NE, Ordway MR, de las Heras L, McMahon TJ. Mothering from the Inside Out: results of a pilot study testing a mentalization-based therapy for mothers enrolled in mental health services. Attach Human Develop. 2016;18(6):596&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchman NE, DeCoste CL, McMahon TJ, Dalton R, Mayes LC, Borelli J. Mothering from the inside out: results of a second randomized clinical trial testing a mentalization-based intervention for mothers in addiction treatment. Dev Psychopathol. 2017;29(2):617&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkert J, Georg A, Hauschild S, Herpertz SC, Neukel C, Byrne G, et al. Bindungskompetenzen psychisch kranker Eltern st&#xe4;rken: Adaptation und Pilottestung des mentalisierungsbasierten Leuchtturm-Elternprogramms. Prax Kinderpsychol Kinderpsychiatr. 2019Jan 10;68(1):27&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gervinskait&#x117;-Paulaitien&#x117; L, Byrne G, Barkauskien&#x117; R. Mentalization-based parenting program for child maltreatment prevention: a pre&#x2013;post study of 12-Week Lighthouse Group Program. Children. 2023Jun 12;10(6):1047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gervinskait&#x117;-Paulaitien&#x117; L, Ruggiero M, Taubner S, Volkert J, Barkauskien&#x117; R. A follow-up study of the &#x201c;Lighthouse&#x201d; mentalization-based parenting program: mentalization as a mediator of change. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2024;29(3):867&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hestbaek E, Mikkelsen PA, Thomas RE, Sleed M, Holm C, Corlin AB, et al. A mentalization-based parenting intervention (Lighthouse Parenting Programme) for parents with various mental disorders in adult mental health service: a feasibility study. Mental Health &amp; Prevention. 2025;38:200415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paris R, Herriott AL, Holt M. Parenting stress and competence among mothers of young children with substance use disorders: the roles of trauma and reflective functioning. Infant Ment Health J. 2023;44(2):228&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendelboe KI, Nielsen JS, Stuart AC, V&#xe6;ver MS. The parental reflective functioning questionnaire: infant version in fathers of infants and association with paternal postpartum mental health. Infant Ment Health J. 2022;43(6):921&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camisasca E, Procaccia R, Miragoli S, Valtolina GG, Di Blasio P. Maternal mind-mindedness as a linking mechanism between childbirth-related posttraumatic stress symptoms and parenting stress. Health Care Women Int. 2017Jun 3;38(6):593&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele KR, Townsend ML, Grenyer BFS. Parenting stress and competence in borderline personality disorder is associated with mental health, trauma history, attachment and reflective capacity. bord personal disord emot dysregul. 2020;7(1):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribas LH, Montezano BB, Nieves M, Kampmann LB, Jansen K. The role of parental stress on emotional and behavioral problems in offspring: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2024;100(6):565&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charpentier Mora S, Bastianoni C, Koren-Karie N, Cavanna D, Tironi M, Bizzi F. Parental mentalizing during middle childhood: how is the adoption of a reflective stance associated with child&#x2019;s psychological outcomes? IJERPH. 2022May 19;19(10):6205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AW, Tetzlaff JM, Altman DG, Laupacis A, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Krle&#x17e;a-Jeri&#x107; K, et al. SPIRIT 2013 statement: defining standard protocol items for clinical trials. Ann Intern Med. 2013Feb 5;158(3):200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutron I, Moher D, Altman DG, Schulz KF, Ravaud P, for the CONSORT Group. Extending the CONSORT statement to randomized trials of nonpharmacologic treatment: explanation and elaboration. Ann Intern Med. 2008;148(4):295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Schulz KF, Altman DG. The CONSORT statement: revised recommendations for improving the quality of reports of parallel group randomized trials. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2001Apr 20;1(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore GF, Audrey S, Barker M, Bond L, Bonell C, Hardeman W, et al. Process evaluation of complex interventions: Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2015;350(mar19 6):h1258&#x2013;h1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan DV. The Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.): the development and validation of a structured diagnostic psychiatric interview for DSM-IV and ICD-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecrubier Y, Sheehan D, Weiller E, Amorim P, Bonora I, Sheehan KH, et al. The Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). A short diagnostic structured interview: reliability and validity according to the CIDI. Eur psychiatr. 1997;12(5):224&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran P, Leese M, Lee T, Walters P, Thornicroft G, Mann A. Standardised assessment of personality &#x2013; abbreviated scale (SAPAS): preliminary validation of a brief screen for personality disorder. Br J Psychiatry. 2003;183(3):228&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukh JD, Bock C, Vinberg M, Gether U, Kessing LV. Clinical utility of standardised assessment of personality &#x2014; abbreviated scale (SAPAS) among patients with first episode depression. J Affect Disord. 2010;127(1&#x2013;3):199&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesse M, Moran P. Screening for personality disorder with the standardised assessment of personality: abbreviated scale (SAPAS): further evidence of concurrent validity. BMC Psychiatry. 2010;10(1):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felitti VJ, Anda RF, Nordenberg D, Williamson DF, Spitz AM, Edwards V, et al. Relationship of childhood abuse and household dysfunction to many of the leading causes of death in adults. Am J Prev Med. 1998;14(4):245&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy A, Steele M, Dube SR, Bate J, Bonuck K, Meissner P, et al. Adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) questionnaire and adult attachment interview (AAI): implications for parent child relationships. Child Abuse Negl. 2014;38(2):224&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan K, Clark C, Shaver P. Self-report measurement of adult attachment: an integrative overview. In: Attachment theory and close relationships. New York: Guilford Press; 1998;46&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha GMAD, Peixoto EM, Nakano TDC, Motta IFD, Wiethaeuper D. The experiences in close relationships - relationship structures questionnaire (ECR-RS): validity evidence and reliability. Psico-USF. 2017;22(1):121&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraley RC, Heffernan ME, Vicary AM, Brumbaugh CC. The experiences in close relationships&#x2014;Relationship Structures Questionnaire: a method for assessing attachment orientations across relationships. Psychol Assess. 2011;23(3):615&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira H, Martins T, Gouveia MJ, Canavarro MC. Assessing adult attachment across different contexts: validation of the Portuguese version of the Experiences in Close Relationships-Relationship Structures Questionnaire. J Pers Assess. 2015Jan 2;97(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidin R. Parenting stress index: Manual. 3rd ed. Odessa, FL.: Psychological Assessment Resources; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidin RR. Parenting Stress Index, Fourth Edition (PSI-4) Professional Manual. 4th ed. Vol. 2012. Lutz, FL: PAR (Psychological Assessment Resources);</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman R. The Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire: a research note. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 1997;38(5):581&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman R. The extended version of the Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire as a guide to child psychiatric caseness and consequent burden. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 1999;40(5):791&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman R. Psychometric properties of the Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2001;40(11):1337&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niclasen J, Teasdale TW, Andersen AMN, Skovgaard AM, Elberling H, Obel C. Psychometric properties of the Danish Strength and Difficulties Questionnaire: the SDQ assessed for more than 70,000 raters in four different cohorts. Scott JG, editor. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(2):e32025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trompenaars FJ, Masthoff ED, Van Heck GL, Hodiamont PP, De Vries J. Content validity, construct validity, and reliability of the WHOQOL-Bref in a population of Dutch adult psychiatric outpatients. Qual Life Res. 2005;14(1):151&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein NB, Baldwin LM, Bishop DS. The McMaster Family Assessment Device*. J Marital Fam Ther. 1983;9(2):171&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller IW, Ryan CE, Keitner GI, Bishop DS, Epstein NB. The McMaster approach to families: theory, assessment, treatment and research. J Fam Ther. 2000;22(2):168&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boterhoven De Haan KL, Hafekost J, Lawrence D, Sawyer MG, Zubrick SR. Reliability and validity of a short version of the general functioning subscale of the McMaster Family Assessment Device. Fam Process. 2015;54(1):116&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koita K, Long D, Hessler D, Benson M, Daley K, Bucci M, et al. Development and implementation of a pediatric adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) and other determinants of health questionnaire in the pediatric medical home: A pilot study. Tu WJ, editor. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(12):e0208088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucci M, Wang LG, Koita K, Purewal S, Marques SS, Harris NB. Center for Youth Wellness ACE-Questionnaire User Guide. San Fransisco, CA: Center for Youth Wellness; 2015. Available from: https://www.nursing.umaryland.edu/media/son/academics/professional-education/religion-and-ethics/CYW-ACE-Q-USer-Guide-copy.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndjatou T, Qiu Y, Gerber LM, Chang J. How do differences in adolescent and caregiver reports of adolescent adverse childhood experiences relate to adolescent depression? The Journal of Pediatrics: Clinical Practice. 2024;13:200113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston C, Mash EJ. A measure of parenting satisfaction and efficacy. J Clin Child Psychol. 1989;18(2):167&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes C, Ayala-Nunes L, Ferreira LI, Pechorro P, Freitas D, Martins C, et al. Parenting sense of competence: psychometrics and invariance among a community and an at-risk samples of Portuguese parents. Healthcare. 2022Dec 21;11(1):15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis LR, Lazarus, L. SCL-90&#x2014;R, Brief Symptom Inventory, and matching clinical rating scales. In: The use of psychological testing for treatment planning and outcome assessment. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Inc.; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis LR. Brief Symptom Inventory: administration, scoring, and procedures manual. 1st ed. Vol. 1993. Minneapolis, MN: National Computer Systems;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis LR, Melisaratos N. The brief symptom inventory: an introductory report. Psychol Med. 1983;13(3):595&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen KHR. Gender-stratified national mental health norms of BSI-53, BSI-18, SCL-10, ADHD-9, and ADHD-6 for Denmark. Nord J Psychiatry. 2025Jan 2;79(1):96&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare F, Ameri H, Madadizadeh F, Aghaei MR. Validity and reliability of the EQ-5D-3L (a generic preference-based instrument used for calculating quality-adjusted life -years) for patients with type 2 diabetes in Iran. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews. 2021;15(1):319&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders JB, Aasland OG, Babor TF, De La Fuente JR, Grant M. Development of the alcohol use disorders identification test (AUDIT): WHO collaborative project on early detection of persons with harmful alcohol consumption&#x2010;II. Addiction. 1993;88(6):791&#x2013;804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman AH, Palmstierna T, K&#xe4;llm&#xe9;n H, Bergman H. The self-report Drug Use Disorders Identification Test&#x2014;Extended (DUDIT-E): reliability, validity, and motivational index. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2007;32(4):357&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyten P, Mayes LC, Nijssens L, Fonagy P. The parental reflective functioning questionnaire: development and preliminary validation. Eapen V, editor. PLoS ONE. 2017:12(5):e0176218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anis L, Perez G, Benzies KM, Ewashen C, Hart M, Letourneau N. Convergent validity of three measures of reflective function: parent development interview, parental reflective function questionnaire, and reflective function questionnaire. Front Psychol. 2020Dec;16(11):574719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meins E, Fernyhough C, Wainwright R, Clark&#x2010;Carter D, Gupta MD, Fradley E, et al. Pathways to understanding mind: construct validity and predictive validity of maternal mind-mindedness. Child Dev. 2003;74(4):1194&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell C, Tanzer M, Saunders R, Booker T, Allison E, Li E, et al. Development and validation of a self-report measure of epistemic trust. PLoS ONE. 2021Apr 16;16(4):e0250264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonagy P, Luyten P, Allison E, Campbell C. What we have changed our minds about: part 2. Borderline personality disorder, epistemic trust and the developmental significance of social communication. Borderline Personal Disord Emot Dysregul. 2017;4(1):9&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprecher EA, Li E, Sleed M, Midgley N. &#x2018;Trust me, we can sort this out&#x2019;: a theory-testing case study of the role of epistemic trust in fostering relationships. Qual Res Psychol. 2022Feb;12:1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonagy P, Luyten P, Allison E. Epistemic petrification and the restoration of epistemic trust: a new conceptualization of borderline personality disorder and its psychosocial treatment. J Pers Disord. 2015Sep 22;29(5):575&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;gels SM, Hellemans J, van Deursen S, R&#xf6;mer M, van der Meulen R. Mindful parenting in mental health care: effects on parental and child psychopathology, parental stress, parenting, coparenting, and marital functioning. Mindfulness. 2014;5(5):536&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericksen J, Loughlin E, Holt C, Rose N, Hartley E, Buultjens M, et al. A therapeutic playgroup for depressed mothers and their infants: feasibility study and pilot randomized trial of community hugs. Infant Ment Health J. 2018;39(4):396&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potharst ES, Aktar E, Rexwinkel M, Rigterink M, B&#xf6;gels SM. Mindful with your baby: feasibility, acceptability, and effects of a mindful parenting group training for mothers and their babies in a mental health context. Mindfulness. 2017;8(5):1236&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonagy P, Sleed M, Baradon T. Randomized controlled trial of parent-infant psychotherapy for parents with mental health problems and young infants: parent-infant psychotherapy randomized controlled trial. Infant Ment Health J. 2016;37(2):97&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juul S, Gluud C, Simonsen S, Frandsen FW, Kirsch I, Jakobsen JC. Blinding in randomised clinical trials of psychological interventions: a retrospective study of published trial reports. BMJ EBM. 2021;26(3):109&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen JC, Gluud C, Wetterslev J, Winkel P. When and how should multiple imputation be used for handling missing data in randomised clinical trials &#x2013; a practical guide with flowcharts. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2017Dec 6;17(1):162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA. European Medicines Agency. 2018 [cited 2022 Feb 16]. ICH E6 (R2) Good clinical practice. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/ich-e6-r2-good-clinical-practice.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen JC, Gluud C, Winkel P, Lange T, Wetterslev J. The thresholds for statistical and clinical significance - a five-step procedure for evaluation of intervention effects in randomised clinical trials. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014Mar;4(14):34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki. ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013Nov 27;310(20):2191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). [cited 2022 Feb 21]. General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) &#x2013; Official Legal Text. Available from: https://gdpr-info.eu/.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>