<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41320898</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preoperative High-Intensity Strength Training and Outcomes After Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19417381251388638</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19417381251388638</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381251388638</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381251388638</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Preoperative and postoperative strength training is beneficial for outcomes of total knee arthroplasty (TKA). However, the effect of high-intensity strength training is not well understood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to determine the effects of preoperative high-intensity strength training on TKA outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">PubMed, EMBASE, and Cochrane CENTRAL were searched up to December 18, 2023.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY SELECTION" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized controlled trials and cohort studies evaluating the effect of preoperative high-intensity strength training after TKA were eligible.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic review and meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level II, systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials and cohort studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA EXTRACTION" NlmCategory="METHODS">Evaluated outcomes consisted of Timed Up and Go (TUG) test, the 6-minute walk test (6MWT), stair test, range of motion (ROM) flexion, Short Form Health Survey (SF-36) scores, Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index (WOMAC) scores, and the Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score for Activities of Daily Living (KOOS-ADL). These were compared between the intervention and control groups using pooled standardized mean differences. The quality of the studies was appraised using the Risk of Bias in Nonrandomized Studies by Interventions (ROBINS-I) and the Cochrane Collaboration tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Seven studies, comprising 419 patients in total, were included. The meta-analysis showed that the preoperative high-intensity strength training group (intervention group) exhibited statistically significant improvements compared with the control group in 6MWT (pooled standardized mean difference [pSMD] = 0.73; 95% CI, 0.04 to 1.41), ROM flexion (pSMD = 0.40; 95% CI, 0.08 to 0.72), SF-36 (pSMD = 1.54; 95% CI, 0.32 to 2.75), and WOMAC (pSMD = -0.78, 95% CI, -1.22 to -0.34).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Preoperative high-intensity strength training as the prehabilitation programs for patients scheduled for TKA lead to better postoperative recovery, enhanced physical function, and improved quality of life.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shan-Tso</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-8564-4927</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Shan-Wei</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9924-0703</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Fooyin University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Leisure and Sports Management, Cheng Shiu University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-intensity strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total knee arthroplasty (TKA)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41320898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12668991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381251388638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adebero T, Omana H, Somerville L, Lanting B, Hunter SW. Effectiveness of prehabilitation on outcomes following total knee and hip arthroplasty for osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Disabil Rehabil. 2024;46(24):5771-5790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38349251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buvanendran A, Valle CJD, Kroin JS, et al. Acute postoperative pain is an independent predictor of chronic postsurgical pain following total knee arthroplasty at 6 months: a prospective cohort study. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2019;44(3):e100036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calatayud J, Casa&#xf1;a J, Ezzatvar Y, Jakobsen MD, Sundstrup E, Andersen LL. High-intensity preoperative training improves physical and functional recovery in the early post-operative periods after total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25(9):2864-2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CY, Chiu CH, Wu IW, et al. Micronutrients and renal outcomes: a prospective cohort study. Nutrients. 2022;14(15):3063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9370256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35893916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zwart AH, Dekker J, Roorda LD, et al. High-intensity versus low-intensity resistance training in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2022;36(7):952-967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35331018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Navarro F, Silvestre-Mu&#xf1;oz A, Igual-Camacho C, et al. A randomized controlled trial assessing the effects of preoperative strengthening plus balance training on balance and functional outcome up to 1 year following total knee replacement. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(3):838-848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furon Y, Dang Van S, Blanchard S, Saulnier P, Baufreton C. Effects of high-intensity inspiratory muscle training on systemic inflammatory response in cardiac surgery - a randomized clinical trial. Physiother Theory Pract. 2024;40(4):778-788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36637368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;nicher P, Mulder L, Lenssen T, Scherr J, Swanenburg J, de Bie R. Prehabilitation improves knee functioning before and within the first year after total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52(11):709-725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36125444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336(7650):924-926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Cochrane Collaboration. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2nd ed. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley-Blackwell; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden MA, Button K, Collins NJ, et al. Guidance for implementing best practice therapeutic exercise for patients with knee and hip osteoarthritis: what does the current evidence base tell us? Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2021;73(12):1746-1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holsgaard-Larsen A, Hermann A, Zerahn B, Mejdahl S, Overgaard S. Effects of progressive resistance training prior to total HIP arthroplasty - a secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2020;28(8):1038-1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao S, Feng Z, Dai T, Huang J, Liu R, Meng Q. High-intensity progressive rehabilitation versus routine rehabilitation after total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial. J Arthroplasty. 2024;39(3):665-671.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37634879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Cong H, Chen L, Wu H, Yang X, Cao Y. Efficacy and safety of lower limb progressive resistance exercise for patients with total knee arthroplasty: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(3):488-501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H-B, Wang Y-Q, Liu X, et al. Effects of preoperative high-intensity interval training combined with team empowerment education in lung cancer patients with surgery: a quasi-experimental trial. Cancer Nursing. 2024;47(6):E368-E375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37430424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maharaj Z. A team based approach is essential to optimize total knee arthroplasty outcomes. Int J Orthop Sports Med (IJOSM). 2020;1(1):1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster Arthroplasty Collaborative (MAC). Incidence and predictors of prosthetic joint infection following primary total knee arthroplasty: a 15-year population-based cohort study. J Arthroplasty. 2022;37(2):367-372.e361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34678445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Mihalko SL, Beavers DP, et al. Effect of high-intensity strength training on knee pain and knee joint compressive forces among adults with knee osteoarthritis: the START randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2021;325(7):646-657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7887656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33591346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutzouri M, Gleeson N, Billis E, Tsepis E, Panoutsopoulou I, Gliatis J. The effect of total knee arthroplasty on patients&#x2019; balance and incidence of falls: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25(11):3439-3451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27761627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzuolo M, Antoniadis A, Mahlouly J, Wegrzyn J. Total knee arthroplasty improves the quality-adjusted life years in patients who exceeded their estimated life expectancy. Int Orthop. 2021;45(3):635-641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33447874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plantz MA, Sherman AE, Miller CH, Hardt KD, Lee YC. Outcomes of total knee arthroplasty in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Orthopedics. 2021;44(5):e626-e632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34590960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punnoose A, Claydon-Mueller LS, Weiss O, Zhang J, Rushton A, Khanduja V. Prehabilitation for patients undergoing orthopedic surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(4):e238050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10102876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roxburgh BH, Campbell HA, Cotter JD, et al. Upper-Limb high-intensity interval training or passive heat therapy to optimize cardiorespiratory fitness prior to total hip or knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2024;76(3):393-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skoffer B, Maribo T, Mechlenburg I, Korsgaard CG, S&#xf8;balle K, Dalgas U. Efficacy of preoperative progressive resistance training in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty: 12-month follow-up data from a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2020;34(1):82-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su W, Zhou Y, Qiu H, Wu H. The effects of preoperative rehabilitation on pain and functional outcome after total knee arthroplasty: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Orthop Surg Res. 2022;17(1):175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35313897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun JN, Shan YZ, Wu LX, et al. Preoperative high-intensity strength training combined with balance training can improve early outcomes after total knee arthroplasty. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10504716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37715204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuva M, Theodora PMVV, Simone B, et al. EULAR recommendations for the non-pharmacological core management of hip and knee osteoarthritis: 2023 update. Ann Rheum Dis. 2024;83(6):730-740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11103326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen DM, de Ruiter CJ, Nolte PA, de Haan A. Preoperative strength training for elderly patients awaiting total knee arthroplasty. Rehabil Res Pract. 2014;2014:462750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3945933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24693435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasileiadis D, Drosos G, Charitoudis G, Dontas IA, Vlamis J. The efficacy of high-intensity preoperative physiotherapy training on postoperative outcomes in Greek patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty: a quasi-experimental study. Cureus. 2022;14(3):e23191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9010031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35444879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vervullens S, Meert L, Baert I, et al. Prehabilitation before total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review on the use and efficacy of stratified care. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2023;66(4):101705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishavpreet S, Galen B, Akshay G, Alisina S, Ali O. Stiffness after primary total knee arthroplasty. In: Jo&#xe3;o Bosco Sales N, Jos&#xe9; Alberto Dias L, Leonardo Her&#xe1;clio Do Carmo A, Marcelo Cortez B, eds. Knee Surgery. Rijeka: IntechOpen; 2019. Ch. 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HY, Losina E, Lange JK, Katz JN, Collins JE. Longitudinal trajectories of pain and function improvement following total knee replacement. ACR Open Rheumatol. 2019;1(5):308-317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31777807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>