<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41700149</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0915-5287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of physical therapy science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Phys Ther Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and validation of prediction models for one-repetition maximum based on bioelectrical impedance analysis in adults of all ages.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>63</StartPage><EndPage>71</EndPage><MedlinePgn>63-71</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1589/jpts.38.63</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>[Purpose] This study aimed to develop and internally validate one-repetition maximum prediction models based on skeletal muscle mass or skeletal muscle mass index measured using bioelectrical impedance analysis in adults across all ages and both sexes. [Participants and Methods] Eighty-two participants (40 males, 42 females, aged 20-84 years) completed measurement of dominant leg skeletal muscle mass and skeletal muscle mass index using multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis. Unilateral leg press one-repetition maximum was measured. Two multiple linear regressions that incorporated age and sex were fitted and internally validated through bootstrap resampling. [Results] The model using skeletal muscle mass produced an adjusted R<sup>2</sup> of 0.701 and a standard error of estimate of 16.01 kg. The model using skeletal muscle mass index demonstrated higher accuracy (adjusted R<sup>2</sup>=0.737; standard error of estimate=15.0 kg). Internal validation indicated minimal overfitting, with optimism-corrected adjusted R<sup>2</sup> values of 0.677 and 0.715 and standard error of estimate values of 16.82 and 15.81 kg, respectively. [Conclusion] The developed and internally validated models can reasonably predict unilateral leg press one-repetition maximum in adults across a broad age range. However, caution is warranted owing to the magnitude of the prediction error.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2026&#xa9;by the Society of Physical Therapy Science. Published by IPEC Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukushima</LastName><ForeName>Kio</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Graduate School of Medicine, Science and Technology, Shinshu University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Kamijo Memorial Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sue</LastName><ForeName>Keita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Health Sciences, Shinshu University: 3-1-1 Asahi, Matsumoto-shi, Nagano 390-8621, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, JA Nagano Kakeyu-Misayama Rehabilitation Center Kakeyu Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oyake</LastName><ForeName>Kazuaki</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Health Sciences, Shinshu University: 3-1-1 Asahi, Matsumoto-shi, Nagano 390-8621, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurobe</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Fujimi Kogen Medical Center, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akashi</LastName><ForeName>Yuto</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Shinshu University Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endo</LastName><ForeName>Taiga</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Morioka Yuai Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Momose</LastName><ForeName>Kimito</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Health Sciences, Shinshu University: 3-1-1 Asahi, Matsumoto-shi, Nagano 390-8621, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>J Phys Ther Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105359</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0915-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bioelectrical impedance analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41700149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12906961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.38.63</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2025-114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liguori G: ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription, 11th ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer Health, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning, 4th ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics Publishers, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernier-Jean A, Beruni NA, Bondonno NP, et al. : Exercise training for adults undergoing maintenance dialysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev, 2022, 1: CD014653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35018639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kotob R, Ponzano M, Chaput JP, et al. : Resistance training and health in adults: an overview of systematic reviews. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab, 2020, 45: S165&#x2013;S179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Mao L, Feng Y, et al. : Effects of different exercise training modes on muscle strength and physical performance in older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr, 2021, 21: 708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazur LJ, Yetman RJ, Risser WL: Weight-training injuries. Common injuries and preventative methods. Sports Med, 1993, 16: 57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8356377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock ML, Carroll JF, Graves JE, et al. : Injuries and adherence to walk/jog and resistance training programs in the elderly. Med Sci Sports Exerc, 1991, 23: 1194&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1758297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewiadomski W, Laskowska D, Gasiorowska A, et al. : Determination and prediction of one repetition maximum (1RM): safety considerations. J Hum Kinet, 2008, 19: 109&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyward VH: Advanced Fitness Assessment and Exercise Prescription, 6th ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics Publishers, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds JM, Gordon TJ, Robergs RA: Prediction of one repetition maximum strength from multiple repetition maximum testing and anthropometry. J Strength Cond Res, 2006, 20: 584&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macht JW, Abel MG, Mullineaux DR, et al. : Development of 1RM prediction equations for bench press in moderately trained men. J Strength Cond Res, 2016, 30: 2901&#x2013;2906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26913865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes JF, Dingley AF, Garcia-Ramos A, et al. : Prediction of one repetition maximum using reference minimum velocity threshold values in young and middle-aged resistance-trained males. Behav Sci (Basel), 2021, 11: 71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo J, Kim J, Hwang B, et al. : Estimation of 1-repetition maximum using a hydraulic bench press machine based on user&#x2019;s lifting speed and load weight. Sensors (Basel), 2022, 22: 698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mur&#xfa;a JA, Romero-P&#xe9;rez EM, Guajardo-Cruztitla JL, et al. : Intra-session reliability and predictive value of maximum voluntary isometric contraction for estimating one-repetition maximum in older women: a randomised split-sample study. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol, 2025, 10: 160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12101328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40407444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanada Y, Sakurai H, Sugiura Y, et al. : Estimation of 1RM for knee extension based on the maximal isometric muscle strength and body composition. J Phys Ther Sci, 2017, 29: 2013&#x2013;2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5702837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29200647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Materko W, Santos EL: Prediction model of one repetition maximum (1 RM) based on anthropometrical characteristics on male and female. Braz J Biomotricity, 2013, 7: 43&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavedon V, Milanese C, Zancanaro C: Are body circumferences able to predict strength, muscle mass and bone characteristics in obesity? A preliminary study in women. Int J Med Sci, 2020, 17: 881&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7163357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32308541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EY, Kim SR, Won DD, et al. : Multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis compared with computed tomography for assessment of skeletal muscle mass in primary colorectal malignancy: a predictor of short-term outcome after surgery. Nutr Clin Pract, 2020, 35: 664&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31237032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosy-Westphal A, Jensen B, Braun W, et al. : Quantification of whole-body and segmental skeletal muscle mass using phase-sensitive 8-electrode medical bioelectrical impedance devices. Eur J Clin Nutr, 2017, 71: 1061&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5589975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28327564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Ahn S, Kim YJ, et al. : Comparison between dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry and bioelectrical impedance analyses for accuracy in measuring whole body muscle mass and appendicular skeletal muscle mass. Nutrients, 2018, 10: 738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sue K, Kobayashi Y, Ito M, et al. : Bioelectrical impedance analysis to estimate one-repetition maximum measurement of muscle strength for leg press in healthy young adults. Sci Rep, 2022, 12: 17142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9561610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Watson JS, Weir J: Strength and cross-sectional area of human skeletal muscle. J Physiol, 1983, 338: 37&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1197179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6875963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop P, Cureton K, Collins M: Sex difference in muscular strength in equally-trained men and women. Ergonomics, 1987, 30: 675&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3608972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcazar J, Aagaard P, Haddock B, et al. : Age- and sex-specific changes in lower-limb muscle power throughout the lifespan. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci, 2020, 75: 1369&#x2013;1378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31943003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beliaeff S, Bouchard DR, Hautier C, et al. : Association between muscle mass and isometric muscle strength in well-functioning older men and women. J Aging Phys Act, 2008, 16: 484&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19033607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser EM, Draskovits T, Praschak M, et al. : Association between ultrasound measurements of muscle thickness, pennation angle, echogenicity and skeletal muscle strength in the elderly. Age (Dordr), 2013, 35: 2377&#x2013;2388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3824993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23456136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Reitsma JB, Altman DG, et al. : Transparent reporting of a multivariable prediction model for individual prognosis or diagnosis (TRIPOD): the TRIPOD statement. BMJ, 2015, 350: g7594&#x2013;g7594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrell FE, Jr: Regression modeling strategies: with applications to linear models, logistic and ordinal regression, and survival analysis, 2nd ed. Cham: Springer, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW: Clinical prediction models: a practical approach to development, validation, and updating, 2nd ed. Cham: Springer, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J: A power primer. Psychol Bull, 1992, 112: 155&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perugini M, Gallucci M, Costantini G: A practical primer to power analysis for simple experimental designs. Int. Rev. Soc. Psychol, 2018, 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon I, Kim JS, Shin CH, et al. : Associations between skeletal muscle mass, grip strength, and physical and cognitive functions in elderly women: effect of exercise with resistive Theraband. J Exerc Nutrition Biochem, 2019, 23: 50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6823645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31743974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ideno Y, Takayama M, Hayashi K, et al. : Evaluation of a Japanese version of the Mini-Mental State Examination in elderly persons. Geriatr Gerontol Int, 2012, 12: 310&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22122408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S, Madden AM: Body composition and functional assessment of nutritional status in adults: a narrative review of imaging, impedance, strength and functional techniques. J Hum Nutr Diet, 2016, 29: 714&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27137882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritti-Dias RM, Avelar A, Salvador EP, et al. : Influence of previous experience on resistance training on reliability of one-repetition maximum test. J Strength Cond Res, 2011, 25: 1418&#x2013;1422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Watanabe Y, Ikenaga M, et al. : Comparison of single- or multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis and spectroscopy for assessment of appendicular skeletal muscle in the elderly. J Appl Physiol, 2013, 115: 812&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23813532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester CN, Nickerson BS, Kliszczewicz BM, et al. : Reliability and agreement of various Inbody body composition analyzers as compared to dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry in healthy men and women. J Clin Densitom, 2020, 23: 443&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30472111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii S, Tanaka T, Shibasaki K, et al. : Development of a simple screening test for sarcopenia in older adults. Geriatr Gerontol Int, 2014, 14: 93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CH, Martins BA, Okada K, et al. : A 3-year prospective cohort study of dietary patterns and frailty risk among community-dwelling older adults. Clin Nutr, 2021, 40: 229&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32507582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwase H, Murata S, Nakano H, et al. : Relationship between age-related changes in skeletal muscle mass and physical function: a cross-sectional study of an elderly Japanese population. Cureus, 2022, 14: e24260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9123344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distefano LJ, Blackburn JT, Marshall SW, et al. : Gluteal muscle activation during common therapeutic exercises. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther, 2009, 39: 532&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimer RC, 3rd, Wikstrom EA: Functional fatigue of the hip and ankle musculature cause similar alterations in single leg stance postural control. J Sci Med Sport, 2010, 13: 161&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19342297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller K, Engelhardt M: Strength and muscle mass loss with aging process. Age and strength loss. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J, 2014, 3: 346&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3940510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RM, Freitas ED, Heishman AD, et al. : Muscle performance changes with age in active women. Int J Environ Res Public Health, 2021, 18: 4477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW, Bleeker SE, Moll HA, et al. : Internal and external validation of predictive models: a simulation study of bias and precision in small samples. J Clin Epidemiol, 2003, 56: 441&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12812818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba K, Shinozaki T, Maruo K, et al. : Re-evaluation of the comparative effectiveness of bootstrap-based optimism correction methods in the development of multivariable clinical prediction models. BMC Med Res Methodol, 2021, 21: 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley RD, Ensor J, Snell KI, et al. : Calculating the sample size required for developing a clinical prediction model. BMJ, 2020, 368: m441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein CS, Rice CL, Marsh GD: Normalized force, activation, and coactivation in the arm muscles of young and old men. J Appl Physiol (1985), 2001, 91: 1341&#x2013;1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Newcomer BR, Larson-Meyer DE, et al. : Evaluation of the strength-size relationship in vivo using various muscle size indices. Med Sci Sports Exerc, 2000, 32: 1307&#x2013;1313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10912898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashida I, Tanimoto Y, Takahashi Y, et al. : Correlation between muscle strength and muscle mass, and their association with walking speed, in community-dwelling elderly Japanese individuals. PLoS One, 2014, 9: e111810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4218822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico MJ, Harris TB, Visser M, et al. Health, Aging, and Body: Longitudinal study of muscle strength, quality, and adipose tissue infiltration. Am J Clin Nutr, 2009, 90: 1579&#x2013;1585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan J, Lu YC, Yao MM, et al. : Correlation between hand grip strength and regional muscle mass in older Asian adults: an observational study. BMC Geriatr, 2022, 22: 206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35287584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor RA, Cameron-Smith D, Poppitt SD: It is not just muscle mass: a review of muscle quality, composition and metabolism during ageing as determinants of muscle function and mobility in later life. Longev Healthspan, 2014, 3: 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4268803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distefano G, Standley RA, Zhang X, et al. : Physical activity unveils the relationship between mitochondrial energetics, muscle quality, and physical function in older adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle, 2018, 9: 279&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima FD, Neri SG, Lima RM, et al. : Body fat, but not muscle quality, is related to perceived fatigue in young-adult active and inactive women. Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum, 2019, 21: e56093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusakabe T, Arai H, Yamamoto Y, et al. : Cross-sectional association of skeletal muscle mass and strength with dietary habits and physical activity among first-year university students in Japan: results from the KEIJI-U study. Nutrition, 2024, 118: 112265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37995554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadler SF, Malanga GA, DePrince M, et al. : The relationship between lower extremity injury, low back pain, and hip muscle strength in male and female collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med, 2000, 10: 89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10798789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latey PJ, Burns J, Hiller CE, et al. : Relationship between foot pain, muscle strength and size: a systematic review. Physiotherapy, 2017, 103: 13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lachman ME, Lipsitz L, Lubben J, et al. : When adults don&#x2019;t exercise: behavioral strategies to increase physical activity in sedentary middle-aged and older adults. Innov Aging, 2018, 2: igy007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6037047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30003146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Granacher U, Warneke K, et al. : A. minimalist training: is lower dosage or intensity resistance training effective to improve physical fitness? A narrative review. Sports Med, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Nosaka K, et al. : Maximal number of repetitions at percentages of the one repetition maximum: a meta-regression and moderator analysis of sex, age, training status, and exercise. Sports Med, 2024, 54: 303&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37792272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosicki GJ, Miller ME, Marsh AP: Resistance exercise performance variability at submaximal intensities in older and younger adults. Clin Interv Aging, 2014, 9: 209&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24465127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>