<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41486157</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Supporting the health of working women in midlife: co-designing and testing the acceptability of a digital exercise programme.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>67</StartPage><MedlinePgn>67</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">67</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-025-04244-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Women in midlife (WiML) report a range of physical and psychological challenges, including the transition to perimenopause and menopause. Combined effects of work and life stressors alongside menopause symptoms in working women are reported to increase absenteeism, reduce productivity and work satisfaction and may result in women exiting the labour market earlier than intended. The aim of this study was to co-design and test a novel exercise programme delivered via smartphone app for working women in midlife. The findings aim to inform targeted support to facilitate exercise for working women in midlife, that could be offered virtually and at scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A two-phase process was used to co-design and test a digital exercise programme for WiML, to be delivered via smartphone app. In phase one, participants (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;12) joined four co-design workshops where collected data was mapped against the Behaviour Change Wheel (BCW). A tailored exercise programme was designed by an exercise physiologist and physiotherapist to meet user needs with a focus on increasing muscle strength. In phase two, a prototype app was developed to deliver the programme digitally. The app was tested for acceptability by a cohort of working women from the education and private sectors (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) using the Theoretical Framework of Acceptability as a reference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Creating opportunities, both physical and social, were identified as the strongest enablers for improving engagement with strength training exercises for WiML, while automatic motivation was identified as a barrier. The app-based exercise programme was found to be low effort to engage with, but affective attitude towards the app was neutral and perceived effectiveness of the programme was low.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">A digital intervention was co-designed and tested by WiML. Findings suggest that combining a flexible programme of aerobic exercise, strength training and pelvic floor exercise via a smartphone application may be an acceptable way to support the health and wellbeing of working women in midlife. Optimisation of the app usability and functionality are needed prior to assessments of effectiveness. Digital workplace interventions are a potentially viable way to address disparities in midlife health and to support healthy ageing in women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-025-04244-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Humphreys</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Behavioural Science and Applied Psychology, Sheffield Hallam University, Collegiate Crescent, Sheffield, S10 2BP, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Platts</LastName><ForeName>Katharine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Wellbeing Research Centre, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield Olympic Park, Sheffield, S9 3TU, UK. Katharine.platts@shu.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kudiersky</LastName><ForeName>Nik</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Wellbeing Research Centre, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield Olympic Park, Sheffield, S9 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ankeny</LastName><ForeName>Ursula</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Hallam University, 153 Arundel Street, Lab4Living, Sheffield, S1 2NU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Copeland</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Wellbeing Research Centre, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield Olympic Park, Sheffield, S9 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowe</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Wellbeing Research Centre, Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield Olympic Park, Sheffield, S9 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ES/W00660X/1 and ES/Y001427/1</GrantID><Agency>UK Research and Innovation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acceptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health intervention.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Midlife</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">User-centred design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women&#x2019;s health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Workplace health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations: For the purpose of open access, the author has applied a Creative Commons Attribution (CC BY) licence to any Author Accepted Manuscript version arising from this submission. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by Sheffield Hallam University Research Ethics Committee (REC IDs: 37050211 and 55467001). All participants gave informed, written consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41486157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12869935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-04244-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-025-04244-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Thomas AJ, Mitchell ES, Woods NF. The challenges of midlife women: themes from the Seattle midlife Women&#x2019;s health study. Women&#x2019;s Midlife Health. 2018;4:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6298022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30766718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. El Khoudary SR, Greendale G, Crawford SL, Avis NE, Brooks MM, Thurston RC, et al. The menopause transition and women&#x2019;s health at midlife: a progress report from the Study of Women&#x2019;s Health Across the Nation (SWAN). Menopause. 2019;26:1213&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000001424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31568098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>3.Lerner UH. Bone remodeling in post-menopausal osteoporosis. J Dent Res. 2006;85:584&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/154405910608500703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16798857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>4.Sternfeld B, Dugan S. Physical Activity and Health During the Menopausal Transition. Obstet Gynecol Clin N Am. 2011;38:537&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ogc.2011.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3270074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21961719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>5. Everybody active, every day: framework for physical activity. GOV.UK. 2021. https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/everybody-active-every-day-a-framework-to-embed-physical-activity-into-daily-life. Accessed 13 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>6.Juppi H-K, Sipil&#xe4; S, Cronin NJ, Karvinen S, Karppinen JE, Tammelin TH, et al. Role of Menopausal Transition and Physical Activity in Loss of Lean and Muscle Mass: A Follow-Up Study in Middle-Aged Finnish Women. J Clin Med. 2020;9:1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9051588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32456169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>7.G&#xf3;mez-Cabello A, Ara I, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ag&#xfc;ero A, Casaj&#xfa;s JA, Vicente-Rodr&#xed;guez G. Effects of Training on Bone Mass in Older Adults. Sports Med. 2012;42:301&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11597670-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22376192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>8.White RL, Vella S, Biddle S, Sutcliffe J, Guagliano JM, Uddin R, et al. Physical activity and mental health: a systematic review and best-evidence synthesis of mediation and moderation studies. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2024;21:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-024-01676-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11603721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39609855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>9.Mansikkam&#xe4;ki K, Raitanen J, Malila N, Sarkeala T, M&#xe4;nnist&#xf6; S, Fredman J, et al. Physical activity and menopause-related quality of life - a population-based cross-sectional study. Maturitas. 2015;80:69&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2014.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25449820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>10.Bernard P, Ninot G, Bernard PL, Picot MC, Jaussent A, Tallon G, et al. Effects of a six-month walking intervention on depression in inactive post-menopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. Aging Ment Health. 2015;19:485&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13607863.2014.948806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25133492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>11.Cho ST, Kim KH, Cho ST, Kim KH. Pelvic floor muscle exercise and training for coping with urinary incontinence. J Exerc Rehabil. 2021;17:379&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2142666.333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35036386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. Wang Y, Liu L, Chen Q, Gao K, Wang H, Xu N, et al. Modified lumbo-pelvic exercise to alleviate mild stress urinary incontinence in middle-aged females. Sci Rep. 2023;13:7142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10153777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37130891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>13.Stimson AM, Anderson C, Holt A-M, Henderson AJ. Why don&#x2019;t women engage in muscle strength exercise? An integrative review. Health Prom J Aust. 2024;35:911&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hpja.857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38566279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>14.Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31825dabb8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>15.Vasudevan A, Ford E. Motivational Factors and Barriers Towards Initiating and Maintaining Strength Training in Women: a Systematic Review and Meta-synthesis. Prev Sci. 2022;23:674&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-021-01328-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34800250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>16.McArthur D, Dumas A, Woodend K, Beach S, Stacey D. Factors influencing adherence to regular exercise in middle-aged women: a qualitative study to inform clinical practice. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health. 2014;14:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6874-14-49</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24666887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>17.O&#x2019;Neill MT, Jones V, Reid A. Impact of menopausal symptoms on work and careers: a cross-sectional study. Occup Med. 2023;73:332-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/occmed/kqad078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10540666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>18.Griffiths A, MacLennan SJ, Hassard J. Menopause and work: An electronic survey of employees&#x2019; attitudes in the UK. Maturitas. 2013;76:155&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2013.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23973049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>19. Equality &amp; Human Rights Commission. Menopause in the workplace: Guidance for employers. 2024. https://www.equalityhumanrights.com/guidance/menopause-workplace-guidance-employers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>20. Managing the menopause - Menopause at work. Acas. 2024. https://www.acas.org.uk/menopause-at-work. Accessed 13 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>21.Cronin C, Hungerford C, Wilson RL. Using Digital Health Technologies to Manage the Psychosocial Symptoms of Menopause in the Workplace: A Narrative Literature Review. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2021;42:541&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01612840.2020.1827101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33027594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>22.Riches S, Taylor L, Jeyarajaguru P, Veling W, Valmaggia L. Virtual reality and immersive technologies to promote workplace wellbeing: a systematic review. J Mental Health. 2024;33:253&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638237.2023.2182428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36919828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>23.Deady M, Johnston D, Milne D, Glozier N, Peters D, Calvo R, et al. Preliminary Effectiveness of a Smartphone App to Reduce Depressive Symptoms in the Workplace: Feasibility and Acceptability Study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018;6:e11661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30514694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>24.Scheutzow J, Attoe C, Harwood J. Acceptability of Web-Based Mental Health Interventions in the Workplace: Systematic Review. JMIR Ment Health. 2022;9:e34655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/34655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9133994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35544305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>25. Michie S, Atkins L, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a guide to designing interventions. London: Silverback Publishing; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>26. West R, Michie S. A brief introduction to the COM-B Model of behaviour and the PRIME Theory of motivation. Qeios. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>27.Warburton DER, Jamnik VK, Bredin SSD, Gledhill N. The Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire for Everyone (PAR-Q+) and Electronic Physical Activity Readiness Medical Examination (ePARmed-X+). Health Fit J Can. 2011;4:3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>28.Sekhon M, Cartwright M, Francis JJ. Acceptability of healthcare interventions: an overview of reviews and development of a theoretical framework. BMC Health Serv Res. 2017;17:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-017-2031-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5267473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28126032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>29.Buckingham SA, Williams AJ, Morrissey K, Price L, Harrison J. Mobile health interventions to promote physical activity and reduce sedentary behaviour in the workplace: A systematic review. Digit Health. 2019;5:2055207619839883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055207619839883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>30.Rowe-Roberts D, Cercos R, Mueller F. Floyd. Preliminary results from a study of the impact of digital activity trackers on health risk status. Stud Health Technol Inf. 2014;204:143-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>31.AlSwayied G, Guo H, Rookes T, Frost R, Hamilton FL. Assessing the Acceptability and Effectiveness of Mobile-Based Physical Activity Interventions for Midlife Women During Menopause: Systematic Review of the Literature. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2022;10:e40271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/40271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36485026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>32.Sawettikamporn W, Sarit-apirak S, Manonai J. Attitudes and barriers to pelvic floor muscle exercises of women with stress urinary incontinence. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health. 2022;22:477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-022-02067-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9701389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36435776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>33.McNulty KL, Lane A, Kealy R, Heavey P. Experience of the menopause transition in Irish women and how it impacts motivators, facilitators, and barriers to physical activity engagement. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health. 2024;24:666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-024-03524-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11673553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39725981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>34.Cowley ES, Schneider J. I sometimes feel like I can&#x2019;t win! An exploratory mixed-methods study of women&#x2019;s body image and experiences of exercising in gym settings. PLoS ONE. 2025;20:e0316756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0316756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11778772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39879151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>35. Physical activity guidelines: UK Chief Medical Officers&#x2019; report. GOV.UK. 2020. https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/physical-activity-guidelines-uk-chief-medical-officers-report. Accessed 14 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>36.Adams EJ, Musson H, Watson A, Mason L. Bright spots, physical activity investments that work: Workplace Challenge. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1026&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29079583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>37.Watanabe K, Sato M, Okusa S, Tsutsumi A. Effectiveness and Implementation Outcomes of an mHealth App Aimed at Promoting Physical Activity and Improving Psychological Distress in the Workplace Setting: Cluster-Level Nonrandomized Controlled Trial. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2025;13:e70473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/70473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12071197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40327360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>38.Jim&#xe9;nez-M&#xe9;rida MR, Romero-Salda&#xf1;a M, Molina-Luque R, Molina-Recio G, Meneses-Monroy A, De Diego-Cordero R, et al. Women-centred workplace health promotion interventions: a systematic review. Int Nurs Rev. 2021;68:90&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inr.12637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>39.Fasero M, Coronado PJ. Cardiovascular Disease Risk in Women with Menopause. J Clin Med. 2025;14:3663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14113663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12156203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40507425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>40. Recommendations | Pelvic floor dysfunction: prevention and non-surgical management | Guidance | NICE. 2021. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng210/chapter/recommendations#preventing-pelvic-floor-dysfunction. Accessed 22 Sep 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>41. NHS England. Health Survey for England, 2021 part 2. 16 May 2023. Adult physical activity - NHS England Digital. https://digital.nhs.uk/data-and-information/publications/statistical/health-survey-for-england/2021-part-2/physical-activity. Accessed 22 Sep 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>42. Women in Sport. Inspiring Women to be Active During Midlife and Menopause. 2021. Inspiring Women to be Active During Midlife and Menopause - Women in Sport. https://womeninsport.org/resource/inspiring-women-to-be-active-during-midlife-and-menopause/Accessed 22 Sep 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>43.Dumoulin C, Cacciari LP, Hay-Smith EJC. Pelvic floor muscle training versus no treatment, or inactive control treatments, for urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;10:CD005654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6516955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>44.Wei W, Zhu J, Ren S, Jan YK, Zhang W, Su R, He L. Effects of progressive body-weight versus barbell back squat training on strength, hypertrophy and body fat among sedentary young women. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):13505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-40319-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10439966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37598268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>45.Cho ST, Kim KH. Pelvic floor muscle exercise and training for coping with urinary incontinence. J Exerc rehabilitation. 2021;17(6):379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2142666.333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35036386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>46.Dickinson B, Briscoe L. Why is education for pelvic floor muscle exercises a neglected public health issue? Br J Midwifery. 2017;25:724&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/bjom.2017.25.11.724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>47.Tsoli S, Fancourt D, Sullivan A, Hamer M, Ploubidis GB, Kawachi I. Life-course social participation and physical activity in midlife: longitudinal associations in the 1970 British Cohort Study (BCS70). Eur J Epidemiol. 2024;39:643&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-024-01107-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11249713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38492116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>48.Joshi SP, Dahal RK, Sharma DR, Karki D, Ghimire B. Impact of Fitness App Experiences on Users&#x2019; Overall Well-Being through Joy, Usefulness and Social Connectivity. J Logistics Inf Service Sci. 2025;12(4):235&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>49.Hu J, He W, Zhang J, Song J. Examining the impacts of fitness app features on user well-being. Inf Manag. 2023;60:103796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.im.2023.103796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>