<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841084</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices of Infection Prevention and Control Among Healthcare Workers in a Tertiary Hospital in Mauritius.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103455</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103455</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Many hospitalized patients suffer from healthcare-associated infections (HAIs), especially in low- and middle-income countries (LMIC), particularly drug-resistant infections. Infection prevention and control (IPC) is one of the most cost-effective healthcare investments since most HAIs can be prevented by the implementation of effective IPC interventions. This study aims to examine the knowledge, attitudes, and practices (KAP) of healthcare workers (HCW) regarding IPC, given that these factors may shape their compliance with IPC guidelines. Methodology A cross-sectional study was conducted at Dr Bruno Cheong Hospital in Mauritius, from March 2024 to April 2024. Demographic information and KAP scores were collected through a self-administered questionnaire. Results A total of 58 responses were analyzed; 69% of participants scored more than 70% on the IPC knowledge questionnaire. The mean knowledge score was 12.5 with a total score of 17. The mean attitude score was 48.4 over a total score of 60. Mean knowledge was higher among nurses (p = 0.001) compared to other personnel, and HCWs with five to 10 years of experience (p = 0.05). A total of 86.2% of participants scored more than 70% on the attitude questionnaire. The mean attitude score was 48.4 out of 60. The highest attitude scores were observed again among those with five to 10 years of experience (p = 0.05);84.5% of participants scored more than 70% on the practice questionnaire. The mean practice score was 48.64 out of 60. There was no significant association between knowledge and attitude (p = 0.69). There was a strongly significant association between a positive attitude leading to better practice (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 25.1, p = 0.001). Conclusion Healthcare professionals, especially nurses, showed adequate knowledge, but they could not predict their attitude toward IPC. However, an adequate attitude strongly predicted better practice. Thus, targeted interventions to improve attitude are necessary to promote better engagement. Pathways, such as fostering a positive IPC culture via leadership, managerial support, more focused training, and better staffing ratios, could be explored to improve the attitude of HCW toward IPC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Bhugun-Aumeerbocus et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhugun-Aumeerbocus</LastName><ForeName>Bibi Noor Afzah</ForeName><Initials>BNA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Prevention and Control Unit, Sir Anerood Jugnauth Hospital, Flacq, MUS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nuckchady</LastName><ForeName>Dooshanveer C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases, Victoria Hospital, Quatre Bornes, MUS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hospital acquired infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infection prevention and control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">practice</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Launch of WHO handbook and case definitions for health care-associated infections (HAI) surveillance. WHO.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2024. https://www.who.int/news-room/events/detail/2024/10/16/default-calendar/launch-of-who-handbook-and-case-definitions-for-hai-surveillance https://www.who.int/news-room/events/detail/2024/10/16/default-calendar/launch-of-who-handbook-and-case-definitions-for-hai-surveillance</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>About International Infection Control Branch - Healthcare-Associated Infections.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/international-infection-control/hcp/about/iicb-hai.html. https://www.cdc.gov/international-infection-control/hcp/about/iicb-hai.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitude, and practices toward infection prevention and control among undergraduate pharmacy students in Zambia: findings and implications. Mudenda S, Chizimu J, Chabalenge B, et al. Antimicrob Steward Healthc Epidemiol. 2023;3:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37771733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO launches first ever global report on infection prevention and control.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2022. https://www.who.int/news/item/06-05-2022-who-launches-first-ever-global-report-on-infection-prevention-and-control https://www.who.int/news/item/06-05-2022-who-launches-first-ever-global-report-on-infection-prevention-and-control</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>First-ever WHO research agenda on hand hygiene in health care to improve quality and safety of care.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2023. https://www.who.int/news/item/12-05-2023-first-ever-who-research-agenda-on-hand-hygiene-in-health-care-to-improve-quality-and-safety-of-care https://www.who.int/news/item/12-05-2023-first-ever-who-research-agenda-on-hand-hygiene-in-health-care-to-improve-quality-and-safety-of-care</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety of patients and healthcare professionals at heart of second national Infection Prevention and Control action plan.  [
Jul;
2025 
]. 2024. https://www.afro.who.int/countries/mauritius/news/safety-patients-and-healthcare-professionals-heart-second-national-infection-prevention-and-control. https://www.afro.who.int/countries/mauritius/news/safety-patients-and-healthcare-professionals-heart-second-national-infection-prevention-and-control.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of multi-drug resistant organisms and their outcomes in an ICU in Mauritius: an observational study. Nuckchady DC, Boolaky SH. Asian J Med Health. 2020;18:71&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health Wellness: National Guidelines on Infection Prevention and Control.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2025. https://health.govmu.org/health/ https://health.govmu.org/health/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Progress on theory of planned behavior research: advances in research synthesis and agenda for future research. Hagger MS, Hamilton K. J Behav Med. 2025;48:43&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11893630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39833388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monta&#xf1;o DE, Kasprzyk D. Health Behavior: Theory, Research, and Practice. Hoboken, NJ: Jossey-Bass/Wiley; 2015. Theory of reasoned action, theory of planned behavior, and the integrated behavioral model.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitude, and practice of healthcare professionals toward sarcopenia. Liang B, Wang B, Liang J, Sun X. Sci Rep. 2025;15:19826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12141720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40473813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge and determinants of infection prevention and control compliance among nurses in Yendi municipality, Ghana. Mutaru AM, Balegha AN, Kunsu R, Gbeti C. PLoS One. 2022;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35857742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitudes and practice of infection prevention and control in the CT suite. Abu Awwad D, Hill S, Lewis S, Jimenez Y. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23:741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10329788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37422620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitudes and practices towards infection prevention control among healthcare workers in selected hospitals located in Karongi district, Rwanda. Haguminshuti JC, Safari E, Mochama M, Rutayisire E. J Public Health Int. 2022;6:11&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers to healthcare workers to adhere to infection prevention and control guidelines. Ishaq M. J Saidu Med Coll Swat. 2022;12:55&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitudes, and practices on infection prevention and control among healthcare workers in Rohingya refugee camp. Mondol MA, Shimul MM, Raihan SM, Pantho SA, Khandker S. IJID Reg. 2025;17:100750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12514522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41081036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors associated with infection prevention and control (IPC) practices among primary healthcare nurses in Saudi Arabia. Villareal S, Alruwaili A. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/395450437_Factors_Associated_with_Infection_Prevention_And_Control_IPC_Practices_among_Primary_Healthcare_Nurses_in_Saudi_Arabia NURSE Educ Pract J. 2025;1:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infection prevention and control awareness, attitudes, and practices among healthcare professionals in South India. Thazha SK, Cruz JP, Alquwez N, Scaria B, Rengan SS, Almazan JU. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2022;16:659&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35544628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infection prevention and control knowledge, attitudes, and practices of healthcare workers in tertiary care hospitals in Bangladesh during COVID-19: a multicenter cross-sectional survey. Harun MG, Sumon SA, Anwar MM, et al. Clin Infect Dis. 2025;81:49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12314486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40558090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowledge, attitudes, and practices of infection prevention and control nurses in public hospitals in the Limpopo Province: a qualitative study. Ranoto LQ, Ntimana CB, Mamogobo P, Maimela E. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2025;22:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11764878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39857569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>