<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41857089</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SiaCon-DetNet with HySHO: a cutting-edge transformer-based deep learning framework for emotion-aware facial recognition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41890-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Facial emotion recognition (FER) plays a critical role in most applications in human-computer interaction, psychological analysis, and affective computing to make intelligent systems capable of effectively perceiving the emotions of humans. Current approaches lack sufficient strength against problems like poor feature representation, robustness of facial expression variation, and model generalization. In order to counter such shortcomings, this paper presents a new FER model that integrates the SiaCon-DetNet and HySHO algorithm. The most striking novelty of SiaCon-DetNet is its capacity to combine convolutional feature learning with transformer attention mechanisms in order to make strong detection of fine-grained facial features. Also, the suggested framework are based on its intelligent combination of bio-inspired top optimization and deep learning, resulting in an adaptive and efficient emotion detector. Meanwhile, HySHO dynamically adjusts model parameters to enhance learning convergence and reduce computation overhead. This method in the paper presumes an organized working process with the initial step being face region detection by a Siamese convolutional network and feature enhancement by multi-head self-attention in the detection transformer network. Comparative analysis of its performance indicates the new model shows better performance as compared to all other FER methods with up to 99.20% accuracy on JAFFE database and having very short training periods. Emotion-wise correlation and performance testing also validate the reliability of the proposed framework, with precision, recall, and F1-score consistently between 98-99%.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Sumithra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, School of Computing, Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Avadi, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600062, India. blessfulsumi@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Ulagammai</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science Emerging Technologies, SRM Institute of Science and Technology Vadapalani, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600026, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K</LastName><ForeName>Tamilarasi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of IT, Panimalar Engineering College, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600123, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>V</LastName><ForeName>Deepa</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence &amp; Data Science, Rajalakshmi Institute of Technology, Chembarambakkam, Tamil Nadu, 600124, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C</LastName><ForeName>Mahesh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science Emerging Technologies, SRM Institute of Science and Technology Vadapalani, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600026, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Face emotion recognition (FER)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimization and classification</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41857089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41890-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41890-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Huang, S. &amp; Xu, Y. UA-FER: Uncertainty-aware representation learning for facial expression recognition. Neurocomputing 621, 129261 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halkiopoulos, C., Gkintoni, E., Aroutzidis, A. &amp; Antonopoulou, H. Advances in neuroimaging and deep learning for emotion detection: A systematic review of cognitive neuroscience and algorithmic innovations. Diagnostics 15, 456 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madni, S. H. H., Pathmanatan, L. A. /L., Faheem, M., Shahzad, H. M. F. &amp; Shah, S. Exploring optimizer efficiency for facial expression recognition with convolutional neural networks. J. Eng. 2025, e70060 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, F. et al. Towards facial micro-expression detection and classification using modified multimodal ensemble learning approach. Inf. Fusion 115, 102735 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A. &amp; Kumar, A. Human emotion recognition using machine learning techniques based on the physiological signal. Biomed. Signal Process. Control 100, 107039 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akrout, B. Deep facial emotion recognition model using optimal feature extraction and dual-attention residual U-Net classifier. Expert Syst. 42, e13314 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran, G., Ranjith, S., Chenthil, T. &amp; Jagan, G. Facial expression-based emotion recognition across diverse age groups: A multi-scale vision transformer with contrastive learning approach. J. Comb. Optim. 49, 1&#x2013;39 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima, N. S. et al. Enhanced facial emotion recognition using vision transformer models. J. Electr. Eng. Technol. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42835-024-02118-w (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Luzio, F., Rosato, A. &amp; Panella, M. An explainable fast deep neural network for emotion recognition. Biomed. Signal Process. Control 100, 107177 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A., Kumar, A. &amp; Gupta, S. Machine learning-driven emotion recognition through facial landmark analysis. SN Comput. Sci. 6, 1&#x2013;10 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. et al. A video-based cognitive emotion recognition method using an active learning algorithm based on complexity and uncertainty. Appl. Sci. 15, 462 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi, B. &amp; Preetha, M. M. S. J. Facial emotion recognition using convolutional neural network based krill head optimisation. Expert Syst. 42, e13376 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Liu, Z., Zhang, Z., Wang, Q. &amp; Ma, M. Decoding group emotional dynamics in a web-based collaborative environment: A novel framework utilizing multi-person facial expression recognition. Int. J. Hum. Comput. Interact. 41, 3455&#x2013;3473 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, Y., Xia, H. &amp; Song, S. Mining label-free consistency regularization for noisy facial expression recognition. Complex Intell. Syst. 11, 105 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gursesli, M. C. et al. Facial emotion recognition (FER) through custom lightweight CNN model: Performance evaluation in public datasets. IEEE Access https://doi.org/10.1109/access.2024.3380847 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballesteros, J. A., Ram&#xed;rez V, G. M., Moreira, F., Solano, A. &amp; Pelaez, C. A. Facial emotion recognition through artificial intelligence. Front. Comput. Sci. 6, 1359471 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury, J. H., Liu, Q. &amp; Ramanna, S. Simple histogram equalization technique improves performance of VGG models on facial emotion recognition datasets. Algorithms 17, 238 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. H., Poulose, A. &amp; Han, D. S. Cvgg-19: Customized visual geometry group deep learning architecture for facial emotion recognition. IEEE Access 12, 41557&#x2013;41578 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezquerra, A., Agen, F., Toma, R. B. &amp; Ezquerra-Romano, I. Using facial emotion recognition to research emotional phases in an inquiry-based science activity. Res. Sci. Technol. Educ. 43, 62&#x2013;85 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari, N. &amp; Bhatia, R. Saliency map and deep learning based efficient facial emotion recognition technique for facial images. Multim. Tools Appl. 83, 36841&#x2013;36864 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupan, B. &amp; Eskritt, M. Facial and vocal emotion recognition in adolescence: A systematic review. Adolesc. Res. Rev. 9, 253&#x2013;277 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X., Zhang, Y., Lu, S. &amp; Lu, Z. Facial expression recognition: A review. Multim. Tools Appl. 83, 23689&#x2013;23735 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younis, E. M., Mohsen, S., Houssein, E. H. &amp; Ibrahim, O. A. S. Machine learning for human emotion recognition: A comprehensive review. Neural Comput. Appl. 36, 8901&#x2013;8947 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S. et al. CSE-GResNet: A simple and highly efficient network for facial expression recognition. IEEE Trans. Affect. Comput. https://doi.org/10.1109/taffc.2025.3535811 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X. Emotional recognition and feedback of students in English e-learning based on computer vision and face recognition algorithms. Entertain. Comput. 52, 100847 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong, S. C., Tang, Y. M., Lai, C. H. &amp; Lee, C. K. M. Facial expression and body gesture emotion recognition: A systematic review on the use of visual data in affective computing. Comput. Sci. Rev. 48, 100545 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. H. Yip and J. Hu, Enhanced Multi-scale Hierarchical Network for Micro-expression Recognition, In International Conference on Image and Graphics, 2025, pp. 40&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari, N. &amp; Bhatia, R. Deep learning based efficient emotion recognition technique for facial images. Int. J. Syst. Assur. Eng. Manag. 14, 1421&#x2013;1436 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dujaili, M. J. Survey on facial expressions recognition: Databases, features and classification schemes. Multimed. Tools Appl. 83, 7457&#x2013;7478 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Aghabeigi, S. Nazari, and N. Osati Eraghi, An efficient facial emotion recognition using convolutional neural network with local sorting binary pattern and whale optimization algorithm, Int. J. Data Sci. Anal., 2024/07/08 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider, I., Yang, H.-J., Lee, G.-S. &amp; Kim, S.-H. Robust human face emotion classification using Triplet-loss-based deep CNN features and SVM. Sensors 23, 4770 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Wang, J., Tian, L., Wang, J. &amp; Huang, Y. A fine-grained human facial key feature extraction and fusion method for emotion recognition. Sci. Rep. 15, 6153 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>