<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41866518</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-709X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chiropractic &amp; manual therapies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chiropr Man Therap</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mobilization with movement enhances early rehabilitation outcomes in knee osteoarthritis: a six-week randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12998-026-00636-0</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasan</LastName><ForeName>Shahnaz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Health Rehabilitation, College of Applied Medical Sciences, Majmaah University, Al-Majmaah, 11952, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Amir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Research Chair, Department of Rehabilitation Health Sciences, College of Applied Medical Sciences, King Saud University, P.O. Box. 10219, Riyadh, 11433, Saudi Arabia. physioamir@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Abeer Ramadan</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Rehabilitation Sciences Department, Faculty of Applied Medical Sciences, Umm Al-Qura University, Mecca, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diab</LastName><ForeName>Reham H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Medical Rehabilitation Science, Taibah University, Madina, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Zaheen A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, School of Allied Health Sciences, Manav Rachna International Institute and Studies (MRIIRS), Faridabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasan</LastName><ForeName>Tabinda</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences, College of Medicine, Princess Nourah Bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box. 84428, Riyadh, 11671, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anwer</LastName><ForeName>Shahnawaz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghadir</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Research Chair, Department of Rehabilitation Health Sciences, College of Applied Medical Sciences, King Saud University, P.O. Box. 10219, Riyadh, 11433, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ORF-RC-2025-1000</GrantID><Agency>Ongoing Research Funding program - Research Chairs (ORF-RC-2025-1000), King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Chiropr Man Therap</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101551481</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-709X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Manual therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobilization with movement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethics Sub-Committee, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia (approval ID: RRC-2021-17). The trial was prospectively registered with the ClinicalTrials.gov Protocol Registration and Results System (PRS) under the identifier: NCT05577403, dated: 12/07/2021 (initial release), and the record was subsequently updated on 14/09/2025 (https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05577403). The study adhered to the ethical standards of the World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki (2010). All participants provided written informed consent prior to study enrolment. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41866518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12998-026-00636-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12998-026-00636-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cross M, et al. The global burden of hip and knee osteoarthritis: estimates from the global burden of disease 2010 study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73(7):1323&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, et al. The epidemiology and burden of global osteoarthritis: a systematic analysis based on the Global Burden of Disease database. Aging Adv. 2025;2:104103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenei-Lanzl Z, Zaucke F. Osteoarthritis year in review 2024: biology. Osteoarthr Cartil. 2025;33(1):58&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandt KD, Dieppe P, Radin EL. Etiopathogenesis of osteoarthritis. Rheumatic Disease Clin North Am. 2008;34(3):531&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;iestad BE, et al. Knee extensor muscle weakness is a risk factor for development of knee osteoarthritis. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoarthr Cartil. 2015;23(2):171&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlindon TE, et al. OARSI guidelines for the non-surgical management of knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthr Cartil. 2014;22(3):363&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, et al. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee. Cochr Datab Syst Rev. 2015. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD004376.pub3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell K, Hinman R. Exercise as a treatment for osteoarthritis. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2005;17(5):634&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raposo F, Ramos M, L&#xfa;cia Cruz A. Effects of exercise on knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review. Musculoskelet Care. 2021;19(4):399&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan S. Effects of plyometric vs. strength training on strength, sprint, and functional performance in soccer players: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):4256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardoloi B, et al. Knee osteoarthritis: an overview of recent interventions. J Biomed Eng Biosci. 2017;4(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad Z. Powering the knee: impact of targeted hamstring and quadriceps strengthening on pain and function in osteoarthritis&#x2014;a randomized controlled trial. Int J Soc Sci Bull. 2025;3(7):750&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan S. Quadriceps femoris strength training: effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation vs isometric exercise in osteoarthritis of knee. Indian J Physiother Occup Ther. 2015;9(3):129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott J, et al. Manual therapy, exercise therapy, or both, in addition to usual care, for osteoarthritis of the hip or knee: a randomized controlled trial. 1: clinical effectiveness. Osteoarthr Cartil. 2013;21(4):525&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulligan BR. Manual therapy: NAGS, SNAGS, MWMs etc. 2010. 6th edition. Plane View Services, Wellington 6241, New Zealand.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicenzino B, Paungmali A, Teys P. Mulligan&#x2019;s mobilization-with-movement, positional faults and pain relief: current concepts from a critical review of literature. Man Therap. 2007;12(2):98&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdi&#x307;n&#xe7;ler DAR, Mutlu EK, Mulli&#x307;gan tekni&#x307;&#x11f;i&#x307;, pasi&#x307;f eklem mobi&#x307;li&#x307;zasyonu, geleneksel fi&#x307;zyoterapi&#x307;ni&#x307;n di&#x307;z osteoartri&#x307;t tedavi&#x307;si&#x307;ndeki&#x307; etki&#x307;leri&#x307;ni&#x307;n kar&#x15f;ila&#x15f;tirilmasi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiran A, et al. Comparison of efficacy of mulligan&#x2019;s mobilization with movement with maitland mobilization along with conventional therapy in the patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Libyan Int Med Univ J. 2018;3(01):26&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teys P, Bisset L, Vicenzino B. The initial effects of a Mulligan&#x2019;s mobilization with movement technique on range of movement and pressure pain threshold in pain-limited shoulders. Man Therap. 2008;13(1):37&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diracoglu D, et al. Effects of kinesthesia and balance exercises in knee osteoarthritis. JCR: J Clin Rheumatol. 2005;11(6):303&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huskisson EC. Measurement of pain. Lancet. 1974;304(7889):1127&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyle GD, et al. Effectiveness of manual physical therapy and exercise in osteoarthritis of the knee: a randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2000;132(3):173&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwer S, Alghadir A. Effect of isometric quadriceps exercise on muscle strength, pain, and function in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled study. J Phys Ther Sci. 2014;26(5):745&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan S. Effects of plyometric vs. strength training on strength, sprint, and functional performance in soccer players: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2023;13:4256. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-31375-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan S, Alonazi A, Anwer S, Jamal A, Parvez S, Alfaiz FA, Li H. Efficacy of patellar taping and electromyographic biofeedback training at various knee angles on quadriceps strength and functional performance in young adult male athletes with patellofemoral pain syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Res Manage. 2022;2022(1):8717932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan S, et al. Efficacy of patellar taping and electromyographic biofeedback training at various knee angles on quadriceps strength and functional performance in young adult male athletes with patellofemoral pain syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Res Manage. 2022;2022(1):8717932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsabbahi SA et al. Mulligan mobilization vs. instrument-assisted soft tissue mobilization in the treatment of chronic lateral epicondylitis: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Front Health Inf. 2025. 14(1): p. 485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Cervera FV, et al. Influence of expectations plus mobilization with movement in patient with lateral epicondylalgia: a pilot randomized controlled trial. J Exerc Rehabil 2017;13(1):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice WE. Joint mobilization and traction techniques in rehabilitation. Rehabilitation techniques for sports medicine and athletic training. London: Routledge; 2024. pp. 329&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafez AR, et al. Treatment of knee osteoarthritis in relation to hamstring and quadriceps strength. J Phys Ther Sci. 2013;25(11):1401&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>