<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41823357</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vagus nerve stimulation to improve post-stroke motor function and activity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD015859</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD015859</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD015859</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD015859.pub2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="RATIONALE">After a stroke, many people experience persistent upper extremity (UE) motor impairments (that is, deficits in strength, coordination, and muscle tone), which can limit activities such as reaching, grasping, and manipulation. Despite conventional rehabilitation, recovery of UE function often remains limited. Vagus nerve stimulation (VNS), applied invasively or non-invasively (transcutaneously), has been proposed as an adjunct to rehabilitation to enhance neuroplasticity and improve motor outcomes after stroke. While early trials have reported mixed findings, the overall effectiveness and safety of VNS interventions in this context are uncertain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To assess the potential benefits and harms of vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) as an add-on treatment to rehabilitate people who have post-stroke UE motor function impairments and activity limitations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">We searched for published trials in the Cochrane Library, MEDLINE, Embase, Scopus, PsycINFO, CINAHL and PEDro. We also handsearched for reference lists and looked for other relevant studies on Google Scholar. We performed the searches up to May 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA">We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) that assessed the effect of VNS paired with conventional rehabilitation, compared to conventional rehabilitation alone (or paired with sham VNS) in adults (&#x2265; 18 years) with a first-ever ischaemic or haemorrhagic stroke, at any post-stroke phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES">Our critical outcomes were UE motor function and the number of participants with at least one serious adverse event (SAE). Our main important outcomes were UE activity and quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RISK OF BIAS">Two review authors independently screened references, selected studies based on eligibility criteria, extracted data, and assessed the risk of bias in each included study using the Cochrane RoB 2 tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYNTHESIS METHODS">When the studies were sufficiently similar, we synthesised VNS benefits and harms using a fixed-effects model meta-analysis for dichotomous outcomes and a random-effects model for continuous outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INCLUDED STUDIES">We included 10 studies with a total of 547 participants that met our inclusion criteria. The included studies took place in China, the UK, the USA, and Italy. All studies were published in peer-reviewed journals. Nine were written in English, and one in Chinese. Three studies applied VNS invasively and seven non-invasively (transcutaneously). All interventions were paired with rehabilitation (motor training) and compared with rehabilitation alone. All studies included both men and women. Most treatments were given in outpatient hospital services or health centres. All studies measured outcomes at short-term (six to 12 weeks after treatment), three studies at medium-term (six months after treatment), and one study at long-term (12 months after treatment). We also identified 23 ongoing studies and 14 studies are awaiting classification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYNTHESIS OF RESULTS">Compared with conventional rehabilitation alone, the evidence is very uncertain about the effect of VNS paired with rehabilitation on UE motor function in the short-term (SMD 1.22, 95% CI 0.68 to 1.77; 10 studies, 499 participants; very low-certainty evidence). VNS paired with rehabilitation may result in little to no increased risk of SAEs compared to rehabilitation alone (RR 2.38, 95% CI 0.77 to 7.30; 8 studies, 416 participants; low-certainty evidence). The evidence is very uncertain about the effect of VNS plus rehabilitation on UE activity (SMD 0.88, 95% CI -0.09 to 1.86; 6 studies; 186 participants; very low-certainty of evidence) and quality of life (SMD 0.04, 95% CI -0.30 to 0.37; 3 studies, 180 participants; very low-certainty of evidence) compared to rehabilitation alone in the short-term. For the critical and main important outcomes, most studies had an overall high risk of bias. Few included studies took long-term follow-up measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Comparing VNS paired with rehabilitation to rehabilitation alone, we found very uncertain evidence for the effects on UE motor function, UE activity, and quality of life in the short-term. VNS may result in little to no increased risk of SAEs. The body of evidence on the benefits and harms of VNS is limited by the risk of bias in the included studies, the small number of included studies, and the relatively small sample sizes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING">This Cochrane review did not receive any specific funding.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION">Protocol (2024) DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD015859.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Everard</LastName><ForeName>Gauthier</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5029-5693</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Secteur des Sciences de la Sant&#xe9;, Institut de Recherche Exp&#xe9;rimentale et Clinique, Neuro Musculo Skeletal Lab (NMSK), Universit&#xe9; Catholique de Louvain, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre interdisciplinaire de recherche en r&#xe9;adaptation et int&#xe9;gration sociale, Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, Laval University, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saragih</LastName><ForeName>Ita Daryanti</ForeName><Initials>ID</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Sciences and Technology, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dawson</LastName><ForeName>Jesse</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarihoran</LastName><ForeName>Dame Elysabeth</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universitas Kristen Krida Wacana (UKRIDA), Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Advani</LastName><ForeName>Shailesh M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Social Epidemiology Research Unit, Social Behavioral Research Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tzeng</LastName><ForeName>Huey-Ming</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston, Galveston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Bih-O</ForeName><Initials>BO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bekkering</LastName><ForeName>Geertruida E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Academic Center for General Practice, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Evidence-Based Medicine, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cochrane Belgium, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD015859</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071939" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Rehabilitation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055536" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vagus Nerve Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034941" MajorTopicYN="Y">Upper Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015982" MajorTopicYN="N">Bias</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Gauthier Everard: none known. Ita Daryanti Saragih: none known. Jesse Dawson: works as a stroke consultant, and received funding from MicroTransponder Inc since January 2012 for costs of enrolment for clinical trials and travel expenses. He is an investigator of several RCTs included in this review [49, 60, 61], and therefore was not involved in the selection of studies, data extraction and management, risk of bias assessments, and certainty of the evidence assessments. No other relevant conflict of interest. Dame Elysabeth Tarihoran: none known. Shailesh Advani: none known. Huey&#x2010;Ming Tzeng: registered nurse (by training) at the University of Texas Medical Branch (Galveston, TX, USA) but does provide direct patient care. Bih&#x2010;O Lee: works as health professional in Kaohsiung Medical University (Taiwan). Geertruida E Bekkering: none known.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41823357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12984006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD015859.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Copenhagen Trial Unit&#x2019;s Trial Sequential Analysis Software (TSA Software). Version 0.9.5.10 Beta. Copenhagen Trial Unit, 2017. Available at ctu.dk/tsa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankey GJ. Stroke. Lancet 2017;389(10069):641-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco RL, Kasner SE, Broderick JP, Caplan LR, Connors JJ, Culebras A, et al. An updated definition of stroke for the 21st century: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke 2013;44(7):2064-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Stroke Collaborators. Global, regional, and national burden of stroke and its risk factors, 1990-2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet. Neurology 2021;20(10):795-820. [DOI: 10.1016/S1474-4422(21)00252-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(21)00252-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorelick PB. The global burden of stroke: persistent and disabling. Lancet. Neurology 2019;18(5):417-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fekadu G, Chelkeba L, Kebede A. Risk factors, clinical presentations and predictors of stroke among adult patients admitted to stroke unit of Jimma University Medical Center, South West Ethiopia: prospective observational study. BMC Neurology 2019;19(1):187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil-Salcedo A, Dugravot A, Fayosse A, Landr&#xe9; B, Jacob L, Bloomberg M, et al. Pre-stroke disability and long-term functional limitations in stroke survivors: findings from more of 12 years of follow-up across three international surveys of aging. Frontiers in Neurology 2022;13:888119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mead GE, Sposato LA, Sampaio Silva G, Yperzeele L, Wu S, Kutlubaev M, et al. A systematic review and synthesis of global stroke guidelines on behalf of the World Stroke Organization. International Journal of Stroke 2023;18(5):499-531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran S, Gonzalez NR, Zachrison KS, Adeoye O, Alexandrov AW, Ansari SA, et al. 2026 guideline for the early management of patients with acute ischemic stroke: a guideline from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke 2026 Jan 26 [Epub ahead of print]. [DOI: 10.1161/STR.0000000000000513]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STR.0000000000000513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teasell R, Salbach NM, Foley N, Mountain A, Cameron JI, Jong A, et al. Canadian Stroke Best Practice recommendations: rehabilitation, recovery, and community participation following stroke. Part one: rehabilitation and recovery following stroke; 6th edition update 2019. International Journal of Stroke 2020;15(7):763-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alt Murphy M, Munoz-Novoa M, Heremans C, Branscheidt M, Cabanas-Vald&#xe9;s R, Engelter ST, et al. European Stroke Organisation (ESO) guideline on motor rehabilitation. European Stroke Journal 2025;10(4):1160-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KB, Lim SH, Kim KH, Kim KJ, Kim YR, Chang WN, et al. Six-month functional recovery of stroke patients: a multi-time-point study. International Journal of Rehabilitation Research. Internationale Zeitschrift fur Rehabilitationsforschung. Revue Internationale de Recherches de Readaptation 2015;38(2):173-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su F, Xu W. Enhancing brain plasticity to promote stroke recovery. Frontiers in Neurology 2020;11:554089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinear C. Prediction of recovery of motor function after stroke. Lancet. Neurology 2010;9(12):1228-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland RH. Vagus nerve stimulation. Current Behavioral Neuroscience Reports 2014;1(2):64-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afra P, Adamolekun B, Aydemir S, Watson GD. Evolution of the vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) therapy system technology for drug-resistant epilepsy. Frontiers in Medical Technology 2021;3:696543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheless JW, Gienapp AJ, Ryvlin P. Vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) therapy update. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2018;88S:2-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arsava EM, Topcuoglu MA, Ay I, Ozdemir AO, Gungor IL, Togay Isikay C, et al. Assessment of safety and feasibility of non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation for treatment of acute stroke. Brain Stimulation 2022;15(6):1467-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JN, Xie CC, Li CQ, Zhang GF, Tang H, Jin CN, et al. Efficacy and safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation combined with conventional rehabilitation training in acute stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial conducted for 1 year involving 60 patients. Neural Regeneration Research 2022;17(8):1809-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redgrave J, Day D, Leung H, Laud PJ, Ali A, Lindert R, et al. Safety and tolerability of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation in humans: a systematic review. Brain Stimulation 2018;11(6):1225-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malakouti N, Serruya MD, Cramer SC, Kimberley TJ, Rosenwasser RH. Making sense of vagus nerve stimulationfor stroke. Stroke 2024;55:519-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt MF, Albusoda A, Farmer AD, Aziz Q. The anatomical basis for transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation. Journal of Anatomy 2020;236(4):588-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Zhang X, Zhou M, Kendrick KM, Zhao W. Therapeutic applications of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation with potential for application in neurodevelopmental or other pediatric disorders. Frontiers in Endocrinology 2022;13:1000758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadeyne S, Mertens A, Carrette E, Van den Bossche F, Boon P, Raedt R, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation cannot modulate the P3b event-related potential in healthy volunteers. Clinical Neurophysiology 2022;135:22-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraudier M, Ventura-Bort C, Burger AM, Claes N, D'Agostini M, Fischer R. Evidence for a modulating effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) on salivary alpha-amylase as indirect noradrenergic marker: a pooled mega-analysis. Brain Stimulation 2022;15(6):1378-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharon O, Fahoum F, Nir Y. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation in humans induces pupil dilation and attenuates alpha oscillations. Journal of Neuroscience 2021;41(2):320-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engineer ND, Kimberley TJ, Prudente CN, Dawson J, Tarver WB, Hays SA. Targeted vagus nerve stimulation for rehabilitation after stroke. Frontiers in Neuroscience 2019;13:280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakauer JW. Functional imaging of motor recovery after stroke: remaining challenges. Current Neurology and Neuroscience Reports 2004;4(1):42-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nudo RJ. Mechanisms for recovery of motor function following cortical damage. Current Opinion in Neurobiology 2006;16(6):638-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen LK, Solis JE, McIntire LK, Hatcher-Solis CN. Vagus nerve stimulation: mechanisms and factors involved in memory enhancement. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience 2023;17:1152064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen H, Fuchino Y, Miyamoto D, Nomura H, Matsuki N. Vagus nerve stimulation enhances perforant path-CA3 synaptic transmission via the activation of &#x3b2;-adrenergic receptors and the locus coeruleus. International Journal of Neuropsychopharmacology 2012;15(4):523-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen LK, Moore RJ, Bechmann NA, Ethridge VT, Gargas NM, Cunningham SD, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation-induced cognitive enhancement: hippocampal neuroplasticity in healthy male rats. Brain Stimulation 2022;15(5):1101-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furmaga H, Carreno FR, Frazer A. Vagal nerve stimulation rapidly activates brain-derived neurotrophic factor receptor TrkB in rat brain. PLOS One 2012;7(5):e34844. [DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0034844]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0034844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Q. Neuromodulatory transmitter systems in the cortex and their role in cortical plasticity. Neuroscience 2002;111(4):815-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manta S, Dong J, Debonnel G, Blier P. Enhancement of the function of rat serotonin and norepinephrine neurons by sustained vagus nerve stimulation. Journal of Psychiatry Neuroscience 2009;34(4):272-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Qiao P, Li Q, Wang Y, Zhang L, Yan LJ, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation as a promising adjunctive treatment for ischemic stroke. Neurochemistry International 2019;131:104539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandel ER, Dudai Y, Mayford MR. The molecular and systems biology of memory. Cell 2014;157(1):163-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ay I, Lu J, Ay H, Gregory Sorensen A. Vagus nerve stimulation reduces infarct size in rat focal cerebral ischemia. Neuroscience Letters 2009;459(3):147-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biggio F, Gorini G, Utzeri C, Olla P, Marrosu F, Mocchetti I, et al. Chronic vagus nerve stimulation induces neuronal plasticity in the rat hippocampus. International Journal of Neuropsychopharmacology 2009;12(9):1209-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers EC, Solorzano BR, James J, Ganzer PD, Lai ES, Rennaker RL, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation enhances stable plasticity and generalization of stroke recovery. Stroke 2018;49(3):710-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng K, Wang Z, Bai J, Xiong J, Chen J, Ni J. Research advances in the application of vagus nerve electrical stimulation in ischemic stroke. Frontiers in Neuroscience 2022;16:1043446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindemann J, Rakers C, Matuskova H, Simon BJ, Kinfe T, Petzold GC. Vagus nerve stimulation reduces spreading depolarization burden and cortical infarct volume in a rat model of stroke. PLOS One 2020;15(7):e0236444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreier JP. The role of spreading depression, spreading depolarization and spreading ischemia in neurological disease. Nature Medicine 2011;17(4):439-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartings JA, Shuttleworth CW, Kirov SA, Ayata C, Hinzman JM, Foreman B, et al. The continuum of spreading depolarizations in acute cortical lesion development: examining Leao&#x2019;s legacy. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism 2017;37(5):1571-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura H, Strong AJ, Dohmen C, Sakowitz OW, Vollmar S, Sue M, et al. Spreading depolarizations cycle around and enlarge focal ischaemic brain lesions. Brain: Broad Research in Artificial Intelligence and Neuroscience 2010;133(7):1994-2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodaparast N, Kilgard MP, Casavant R, Ruiz A, Qureshi I, Ganzer PD, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation during rehabilitative training improves forelimb recovery after chronic ischemic stroke in rats. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2016;30(7):676-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnellan C, Hickey A, Hevey D, O'Neill D. Effect of mood symptoms on recovery one year after stroke. International Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry 2010;25(12):1288-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CT, Brougher J, Gaulding SJ, Hassan BS, Thorn CA. Vagus nerve stimulation promotes cortical reorganization and reduces task-dependent calorie intake in male and female rats. Brain Research 2020;1748:147099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Liu CY, Francisco GE, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, Dixit A, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb motor function after ischaemic stroke (VNS-REHAB): a randomised, blinded, pivotal, device trial. Lancet 2021;397(10284):1545-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhang L, Zhang X, Ma J, Jia G. Effect of combined vagus nerve stimulation on recovery of upper extremity function in patients with stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Stroke and Cerebrovascular Diseases 2022;31(6):106390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Castaneda JA, Barreto-Cortes CF, Losada-Floriano D, Sanabria-Barrera SM, Silva-Sieger FA, Garcia RG. Efficacy and safety of vagus nerve stimulation on upper limb motor recovery after stroke. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Frontiers in Neurology 2022;13:889953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie YL, Wang S, Wu Q, Chen X. Vagus nerve stimulation for upper limb motor impairment after ischemic stroke: a meta-analysis. Medicine 2021;100(46):e27871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Wang JX, Sun FH, Xie YJ, Ou X, Yang SB. The effect of VNS on the rehabilitation of stroke: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies. Journal of Clinical Neuroscience 2020;81:421-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, Yang J, Huang J, Zhao Z, Qu Y. Effect of vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb function improvement after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. International Journal of Rehabilitation Research. Internationale Zeitschrift fur Rehabilitationsforschung. Revue Internationale de Recherches de Readaptation 2021;45(2):99-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Wong&#x200a;TW, Ng SS. Effects and safety of vagus nerve stimulation on upper limb function in patients with stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scientific Reports 2023;13(1):15415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei T, Ge X, Lu L, Li J, Xu P, Wu Q. Efficacy and safety of vagus nerve stimulation on upper extremity motor function in patients with stroke: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. NeuroRehabilitation 2023;53(3):253-67. [DOI: 10.3233/NRE-230106]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NRE-230106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Xing Y, Du W, Liu L, Di X. Analysis of the effect of combined rehabilitation training and transcutaneous vagus nerve electrical stimulation on promoting central nervous system remodeling in stroke patients. Brain Research 2025;1851:149460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liu Y, Jin Z. Effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation combined with bilateral arm training on upper limbmotor function of stroke patients. Chinese Journal of Rehabilitation Theory and Practice 2023;29(3):280-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MH, Wang YX, Xie M, Chen LY, He MF, Lin F, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation with task-oriented training improves upper extremity function in patients with subacute stroke: a randomized clinical trial. Frontiers in Neuroscience 2024;18:1346634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Pierce D, Dixit A, Kimberley TJ, Robertson M, Tarver B, et al. Safety, feasibility, and efficacy of vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after ischemic stroke. Stroke 2016;47(1):143-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Pierce D, Prudente CN, Francisco GE, Yozbatiran N, Smith P, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper limb rehabilitation after chronic stroke. Stroke 2018;49(11):2789-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F, Miccinilli S, Pellegrino G, Zollo L, Simonetti D, Bressi F, et al. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation combined with robotic rehabilitation improves upper limb function after stroke. Neural Plasticity 2017;2017:876507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Ma J, Zhang L, Wang S, Tan B, Jia G. Effect and safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on recovery of upper limb motor function in subacute ischemic stroke patients: a randomized pilot study. Neural Plasticity 2020;2020:8841752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JL, Coggins AN, Saul M, Paget-Blanc A, Straka M, Wright J, et al. Transcutaneous Auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tAVNS) delivered during upper limb interactive robotic training demonstrates novel antagonist control for reaching movements following stroke. Frontiers in Neuroscience 2021;15:767302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwakkel G, Dobkin BH. Vagus nerve stimulation for upper limb function: significant difference, but clinically important? Stroke 2021;52(10):3407-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Lasserson T, Thomas J, Flemyng E, Churchill R. Methodological Expectations of Cochrane Intervention Reviews. Version August 2023. Cochrane, London. https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/mecir-manual.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everard G, Saragih ID, Dawson J, Tarihoran DE, Advani SM, Tzeng HM, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation to improve post-stroke motor function and activity. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2024, Issue 2. Art. No: CD015859. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD015859]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD015859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JE, Brennan SE, Ryan RE, Thomson HJ, Johnston RV, Thomas J. Chapter 3: Defining the criteria for including studies and how they will be grouped for the synthesis. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhardt J, Hayward KS, Kwakkel G, Ward NS, Wolf SL, Borschmann K, et al. Agreed definitions and a shared vision for new standards in stroke recovery research: the Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable Taskforce. International Journal of Stroke 2017;12(5):444-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugl-Meyer AR, J&#xe4;&#xe4;sk&#xf6; L, Leyman I, Olsson S, Steglind S. The post-stroke hemiplegic patient. 1. A method for evaluation of physical performance. Scandinavian Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine 1975;7(1):13-31. [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1135616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook D, Lauzier F, Rocha MG, Sayles MJ, Finfer S. Serious adverse events in academic critical care research. CMAJ: Canadian Medical Association Journal 2008;178(9):1181-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwakkel G, Lannin NA, Borschmann K, English C, Ali M, Churilov L, et al. Standardized measurement of sensorimotor recovery in stroke trials: consensus-based core recommendations from the Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable. International Journal of Stroke 2017;12(5):451-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanct&#xf4;t KL, Lindsay MP, Smith EE, Sahlas DJ, Foley N, Gubitz G, et al. Canadian Stroke Best Practice recommendations: mood, cognition and fatigue following stroke; update 2019. International Journal of Stroke 2020;15(6):668-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohl J, Held JP, Verheyden G, Alt Murphy M, Engelter S, Fl&#xf6;el A, et al. Consensus-based core set of outcome measures for clinical motor rehabilitation after stroke - a Delphi study. Frontiers in Neurology 2020;11:875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prange-Lasonder GB, Alt Murphy M, Lamers I, Hughes AM, Buurke JH, Feys P, et al. European evidence-based recommendations for clinical assessment of upper limb in neurorehabilitation (CAULIN): data synthesis from systematic reviews, clinical practice guidelines and expert consensus. Journal of Neuroengineering and Rehabilitation 2021;18(1):162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Criekinge T, Heremans C, Burridge J, Deutsch JE, Hammerbeck U, Hollands K, et al. Standardized measurement of balance and mobility post-stroke: consensus-based core recommendations from the third Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2023;19(2):158-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winstein CJ, Stein J, Arena R, Bates B, Cherney LR, Cramer SC, et al. Guidelines for adult stroke rehabilitation and recovery: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke 2016;47(6):e98-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yozbatiran N, Der-Yeghiaian L, Cramer SC. A standardized approach to performing the Action Research Arm test. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2008;22(1):78-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin KC, Hsieh YW, Wu CY, Chen CL, Jang Y, Liu JS. Minimal detectable change and clinically important difference of the Wolf Motor Function Test in stroke patients. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2009;23(5):429-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf SL, Catlin PA, Ellis M, Archer AL, Morgan B, Piacentino A. Assessing Wolf Motor Function test as outcome measure for research in patients after stroke. Stroke 2001;32(7):1635-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregson JM, Leathley M, Moore AP, Sharma AK, Smith TL, Watkins CL. Reliability of the Tone Assessment Scale and the modified Ashworth scale as clinical tools for assessing poststroke spasticity. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 1999;80(9):1013-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris S. Ashworth and Tardieu scales: their clinical relevance for measuring spasticity in adult and paediatric neurological populations. Physical Therapy Reviews 2002;7(1):53-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunnstrom S. Motor testing procedures in hemiplegia: based on sequential recovery stages. Physical Therapy 1966;46(4):357-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiowetz V, Volland G, Kashman N, Weber K. Adult norms for the Box and Block test of manual dexterity. American Journal of Occupational Therapy 1985;39(6):386-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiowetz V, Weber K, Kashman N, Volland G. Adult norms for the Nine-Hole Peg test of finger dexterity. Occupational Therapy Journal of Research 1985;5(1):24-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan PW, Wallace D, Lai SM, Johnson D, Embretson S, Laster LJ. The Stroke Impact Scale version 2.0. Evaluation of reliability, validity, and sensitivity to change. Stroke 1999;30(10):2131-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin R, Charro F. EQ-5D: a measure of health status from the EuroQol Group. Annals of Medicine 2001;33(5):337-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica 1983;67(6):361-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Archives of Internal Medicine 2006;166(10):1092-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brott T, Adams HP Jr, Olinger CP, Marler JR, Barsan WG, Biller J, et al. Measurements of acute cerebral infarction: a clinical examination scale. Stroke 1989;20(7):864-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe1;valos A, Blanco M, Pedraza S, Leira R, Castellanos M, Pumar JM, et al. The clinical-DWI mismatch: a new diagnostic approach to the brain tissue at risk of infarction. Neurology 2004;62(12):2187-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre C, Glanville J, Briscoe S, Featherstone R, Littlewood A, Metzendorf M-I, et al. Chapter 4: Searching for and selecting studies. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Intervention</i>s Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence. Melbourne, Australia: Veritas Health Innovation, accessed 14 November 2023. Available at covidence.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Higgins JP, Deeks JJ, editor(s). Chapter 5: Collecting data. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review Manager (RevMan). Version 10.0.0. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2026. Available at revman.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutron I, Page MJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG, Lundh A, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A. Chapter 7: Considering bias and conflicts of interest among the included studies. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ, editor(s). Chapter 6: Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd edition. Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Inc, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Vist GE, Higgins JPT, Santesso N, Deeks JJ, Glasziou P, et al. Chapter 15: Interpreting results and drawing conclusions. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.5. Cochrane, 2024. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Eldridge S, Li T, editor(s). Chapter 23: Including variants on randomized trials. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;cker G, Cates CJ, Schwarzer G. Methods for including information from multi-arm trials in pairwise meta-analysis. Research Synthesis Methods 2017;8(4):392-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch VA, Petkovic J, Jull J, Hartling L, Klassen T, Kristjansson E, et al. Chapter 16: Equity and specific populations. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X, Wang W, Liu J, Tong T. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from the sample size, median, range and/or interquartile range. BMC Medical Research Methodology 2014;14(1):135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PlotDigitizer. Version 3.1.6. PORBITAL, 2001. Available from https://plotdigitizer.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ 1997;315(7109):629-34. [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Version 4.3.2. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing, 2017. Available at www.R-project.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthimiou O. Practical guide to the meta-analysis of rare events. BMJ Mental Health 2018;21(2):72-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG, editor(s). Chapter 10: Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell M, McKenzie JE, Sowden A, Katikireddi SV, Brennan SE, Ellis S, et al. Synthesis without meta-analysis (SWiM) in systematic reviews: reporting guideline. BMJ 2020;368:l6890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Statistics in Medicine 2002;21(11):1539-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woytowicz E, Rietschel J, Goodman R, Conroy S, Sorkin J, Whitall J, et al. Determining levels of upper extremity movement impairment by applying a cluster analysis to the Fugl-Meyer Assessment of the upper extremity in chronic stroke. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2017;98(3):456-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawe P, Shiell A, Riley T. Complex interventions: how "out of control" can a randomised controlled trial be? BMJ 2004;328(7455):1561-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope C, Mays N, Popay J. Synthesising Qualitative and Quantitative Health Evidence: A Guide to Methods. Buckingam (UK): Open University Press, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Higgins JP, Vist GE, Glasziou P, Akl EA, Skoetz N, et al. Chapter 14: Completing &#x2018;Summary of findings&#x2019; tables and grading the certainty of the evidence. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). <i>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</i> Version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Cochrane, 2023. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRADEpro GDT. Version accessed 24 November 2023. Hamilton (ON): McMaster University (developed by Evidence Prime), 2023. Available at gradepro.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bro&#x17c;ek JL, Akl EA, Jaeschke R, Lang DM, Bossuyt P, Glasziou P, et al. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations in clinical practice guidelines: Part 2 of 3. The GRADE approach to grading quality of evidence about diagnostic tests and strategies. Allergy 2009;64(8):1109-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F, Miccinilli S, Pellegrino G, Zollo L, Simonetti D, Bressi F, et al. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation combined with robotic rehabilitation improves upper limb function after stroke. Neural Plasticity 2017;2017:876507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02878720. Combining non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation and robotic training in upper limb-impaired chronic stroke patients. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02878720 (first received 16 August 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F, Miccininilli S, Pellegrino G, Zollo L, Guglielmelli E, Sterzi S, et al. Combining transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation and upper-limb robotic rehabilitation in chronic stroke patients. Brain Stimulation 2019;12(2):413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F, Miccinilli S, Pellegrino G, Zollo L, Simonetti D, Bressi F, et al. Safety, feasibility, and efficacy of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation combined with upper-limb robotic rehabilitation after stroke. Clinical Neurophysiology 2019;130(1):e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JL, Coggins AN, Saul M, Paget-Blanc A, Straka M, Wright J, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (tAVNS) delivered during upper limb interactive robotic training demonstrates novel antagonist control for reaching movements following stroke. Frontiers in Neuroscience 2021;15:767302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03592745. Evaluating the use of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (tVNS) and robotic training to improve upper limb motor recovery after stroke [Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (tVNS) and robotic training to improve arm function after stroke]. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03592745 (first received 05 July 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Pierce D, Dixit A, Kimberley TJ, Robertson M, Tarver B, et al. Safety, feasibility, and efficacy of vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after ischemic stroke. Stroke 2016;47(1):143-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, McLean J, Forbes K, Dixit A, Tarver B, Walters M, et al. Paired vagus nerve stimulation for arm weakness after stroke-analysis of baseline MRI data (10288). Neuromodulation 2016;19(3):e27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson JD, Engineer N, Pierce D, Kimberley T, Tarver B, Dixit A, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation improves upper limb recovery after chronic ischemic stroke. Neuromodulation Technology at the Neural Interface 2015;18(6):e107-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT01669161. A proof-of-concept pilot study assessing vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) paired with rehabilitation for improved upper limb function after stroke (MicroTransponder's Vivistim System) [Paired vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) with rehabilitation for upper limb function improvement after stroke]. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01669161 (first received 15 August 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Liu CY, Francisco GE, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, Dixit A, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb motor function after ischaemic stroke (VNS-REHAB): a randomised, blinded, pivotal, device trial. Lancet 2021;397(10284):1545-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Prudente CN, Engineer ND, Pierce D, Tarver B, Cramer SC, et al. Study protocol for a pivotal randomised study assessing vagus nerve stimulation during rehabilitation for improved upper limb motor function after stroke. European Stroke Journal 2019;4(4):363&#x2010;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CY, Russin J, Adelson DP, Jenkins A, Hilmi O, Brown B, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for stroke: implantation experience from the VNS-REHAB trial. Journal of Clinical Neuroscience 2022;105:122&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco GE, Kimberley TJ, Engineer N, Prudente C, Tarver WB, Pierce D, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation decreases impairment and improves upper limb function after ischemic stroke: results of a randomized, controlled, multi-center, Phase III trial. 2021 AAPM&amp;R annual assembly abstracts. PM&amp;R 2021;13:S17-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Dawson J, Liu C, Francisco G, Wolf S, O'Dell M, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper limb rehabilitation after chronic stroke: cross-over results from the VNS-REHAB pivotal trial. WSO congress supplement. International Journal of Stroke 2021;16(25):3-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISRCTN14280559. Paired vagus nerve stimulation for improved upper limb function after stroke. https://www.isrctn.com/ISRCTN14280559 (first received 14 August 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Engineer ND, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, Ali R, O'Dell MW, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb motor impairment and function after chronic ischemic stroke: subgroup analysis of the randomized, blinded, pivotal, VNS-REHAB device trial. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2023;37(6):367-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Liu C, Francisco GE, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, Dixit A, et al. Abstract 1: Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb motor function after ischaemic stroke: sub-group analysis of the randomised, blinded, pivotal, vns-rehab device trial. Abstracts from the American Stroke Association 2022 International Stroke Conference and State-of-the-Science Stroke Nursing Symposium 2022. Stroke 2022;53(Number Suppl 1):no pagination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley T, Liu C, Francisco G, Wolf S, O'Dell M, Bell K, et al. Effects of VNS paired with rehabilitation for chronic upper limb recovery post stroke: cross-over response. Brain Stimulation 2021;14(6):1715&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03131960. A pivotal randomized study assessing vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) during rehabilitation for improved upper limb motor function after stroke (VNS-REHAB) [Pivotal study of VNS during rehab after stroke (VNS-REHAB)]. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03131960 (first received 24 April 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03945851. Functional MRI and DTI analysis of post VNS therapy rehab changes. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03945851 (first received 29 April 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beovich A, Boose J, Patel R, Wolf SL. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for chronic stroke: characterizing responders. Journal of Neurologic Physical Therapy 2024;48(4):217-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CY, Achrol A, Adelson D, Hilmi O, Williams Z, Russin J, et al. Abstract 305: Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb motor function after ischemic stroke. Oral presentations 2022 AANS annual scientific meeting. Journal of Neurosurgery 2022;136:No pagination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, Liu C, Gochyyev P, Dawson J; VNS-REHAB Trial Group. Long-term outcomes of vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper extremity rehabilitation after stroke. Stroke 2025;56(8):2255-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Pierce D, Prudente CN, Francisco GE, Yozbatiran N, Smith P, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper limb rehabilitation after chronic stroke. Stroke 2018;49(11):2789&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley T, Engineer N, Prudente C, Pierce D, Francisco G, Yozbatiran N, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for upper limb recovery after stroke: 1-year follow up. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2019;33(12):1095&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco GE, Prudente C, Van de Winckel A, Alexander J, Engineer N, Pierce D, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper limb rehabilitation after stroke: long-term outcomes. 2020 AAPM&amp;R annual assembly abstracts. PM&amp;R 2020;12:S50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Engineer ND, Prudente CN, Pierce D, Francisco G, Yozbatiran N, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after stroke: one-year follow-up. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2020;34(7):609&#x2010;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco GE, Dawson J, Kimberly TJ, Yozbatiran N, Cramer SC, Wolf SL, et al. A randomized double-blind study assessing the effect of vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) during rehabilitation on post-stroke upper limb recovery. WCNR 2018 oral abstracts. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 2018;32(4&#x2010;5):317-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco GE, Engineer ND, Dawson J, Kimberley TJ, Cramer SC, Prudente CN, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after stroke: 2- and 3-year follow-up from the pilot study. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2023;104(8):1180-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Kimberley TJ, Francisco GE, Smith P, Cramer SC, Wigginton J, et al. Abstracts from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association 2017 international stroke conference and state-of-the-science stroke sursing symposium. In: Stroke. Vol. 48. 2017:S146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02243020. Study MT-St-02 - stroke - A randomized pilot study assessing vagus nerve stimulation (VNS) during rehabilitation for improved upper limb motor function after stroke (MicroTransponder's Vivistim System) [VNS during rehabilitation for improved upper limb motor function after stroke]. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02243020 (first received 15 September 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JN, Xie CC, Li CQ, Zhang GF, Tang H, Jin CN, et al. Efficacy and safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation combined with conventional rehabilitation training in acute stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial conducted for 1 year involving 60 patients. Neural Regeneration Research 2022;17(8):1809&#x2010;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChiCTR1800018962. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation promotes functional recovery after stroke in clinical patients. https://www.chictr.org.cn/showprojEN.html?proj=31434 (first received 19 October 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Ma J, Zhang L, Wang S, Tan B, Jia G. Effect and safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on recovery of upper limb motor function in subacute ischemic stroke patients: a randomized pilot study. Neural Plasticity 2020;2020:8841752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChiCTR1800019635. Effect of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation on the recovery of upper limb motor function in patients with ischemic stroke. https://www.chictr.org.cn/showprojEN.html?proj=32961 (first received 20 November 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Yu M, Whang S. Effects of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation on the recovery of upper limb motor function in patients with ischemic stroke. Chinese Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine 2020;35(11):1316-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACTRN12623000376640. The effect of non invasive auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) combined with physiotherapy on mobility and balance impairment after stroke [The effect of non invasive auricular vagus nerve stimulation paired with physiotherapy on gait and balance impairments in chronic stroke: a randomised controlled feasibility study]. https://trialsearch.who.int/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=ACTRN12623000376640 (first received 13 April 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ananda R, Roslan MH, Wong LL, Botross NP, Ngim CF, Mariapun J. Efficacy and safety of vagus nerve stimulation in stroke rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cerebrovascular Diseases (Basel, Switzerland) 2023;52(3):239-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Ding Q, Li T, Li W, Yin J, Li Y, et al. Application of vagus nerve stimulation on the rehabilitation of upper limb dysfunction after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Frontiers in Neurology 2023;14:1189034. [DOI: 10.3389/fneur.2023.1189034]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1189034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Zhu Y, Lu X, Wang N, Zhu S, Gong J, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with rehabilitation for motor function, mental health and activities of daily living after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry 2023;94(4):257-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei-Jiang, Zhang C, Wang JX, Sun FH, Xie YJ, Ou X, et al. The effect of VNS on the rehabilitation of stroke: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies. Journal of Clinical Neuroscience 2020;81:421-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Qian Y, Li H. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation combined with rehabilitation training in the intervention of upper limb movement disorders after stroke: a systematic review. Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment 2022;18:2095-106.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>