<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41198072</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-2031</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feasibility of Multimodal Physical Therapy Intervention on Pelvic Floor Symptoms and Function in Adults With Constipation: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCG.0000000000002278</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="GOALS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the feasibility and effectiveness of an 8-week multimodal physical therapy program for adults with constipation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Constipation is a common multifactorial digestive disease in adults. A multimodal intervention program may better improve pelvic floor muscle (PFM) function and alleviate symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY" NlmCategory="METHODS">This pilot randomized controlled trial was conducted at a Tertiary Medical Center in Taiwan. Adults with functional constipation were recruited and randomly assigned to either the intervention group (IG) or the control group (CG). The IG received a multimodal physical therapy intervention, including therapist-guided lifestyle modification education, twice-weekly physical exercise, and pelvic floor muscle training for 8 weeks. The CG received only 1 session of lifestyle modification education after baseline assessment. Assessments were conducted at baseline and after the 8-week program. Primary outcomes included feasibility measures. Secondary outcomes comprised symptom severity, PFM function, health-related quality of life (HRQOL), and physical activity levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 27 participants were recruited (IG: n=14, CG: n=13). The consent rate was 65.2%, with an overall withdrawal rate of 14.8%. No adverse events were reported, and treatment satisfaction was moderate to high. After the 8-week intervention, significant improvements were observed in symptom severity (P=0.003), PFM coordination (P=0.011), PFM strength (P=0.007), HRQOL (P=0.013), and physical activity levels (P=0.037) in the IG, whereas no significant changes were observed in the CG.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">An 8-week multimodal physical therapy intervention program appears feasible and potentially effective in improving constipation symptoms, PFM function, HRQOL, and physical activity levels in adults with constipation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Fang</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Far Eastern Memorial Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Po-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Colorectal Surgery, Department of Surgery, National Cheng Kung University Hospital, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Yin</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School and Graduate Institute of Physical Therapy, National Taiwan University, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7910017</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0192-0790</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adult</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">constipation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pelvic floor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41198072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCG.0000000000002278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004836-990000000-00537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rao SS, Rattanakovit K, Patcharatrakul T. Diagnosis and management of chronic constipation in adults. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;13:295&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barberio B, Judge C, Savarino EV, et al. Global prevalence of functional constipation according to the Rome criteria: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6:638&#x2013;648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werth BL, Christopher S-A. Potential risk factors for constipation in the community. World J Gastroenterol. 2021;27:2795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amselem C, Puigdollers A, Azpiroz F, et al. Constipation: a potential cause of pelvic floor damage? Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2010;22:150&#x2013;e148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahmani A, Arab AM, Khorasany B, et al. 2015 Systematic review: the role of pelvic floor muscles dysfunction in constipation. JGH Open, 4:177&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald A, Scarpignato C, Kamm MA, et al. The burden of constipation on quality of life: results of a multinational survey. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;26:227&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x142;odarczyk J, Wa&#x15b;niewska A, Fichna J, et al. Current overview on clinical management of chronic constipation. J Clin Med. 2021;10:1738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SS, Beaty J, Chamberlain M, et al. Effects of acute graded exercise on human colonic motility. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 1999;276:G1221&#x2013;G1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J, Xie F, Yue H, et al. Physical activity and constipation: a systematic review of cohort studies. J Glob Health. 2024;14:04197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Tao Y, Zhou C, et al. Exercise therapy in patients with constipation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2019;54:169&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8; K. Pelvic floor muscle training is effective in treatment of female stress urinary incontinence, but how does it work? Int Urogynecol J. 2004;15:76&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessoku T, Misawa N, Ohkubo H, et al. Current treatment practices for adult patients with constipation in Japan. Digestion. 2024;105:40&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaCross JA, Borello-France D, Marchetti GF, et al. Physical therapy management of functional constipation in adults: A 2021 Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guideline From the American Physical Therapy Association&#x2019;s Academy of Pelvic Health Physical Therapy. J Women Health Phys Ther. 2022;46:E59&#x2013;E84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johanson J, Kralstein J. Chronic constipation: a survey of the patient perspective. Aliment pharmacol Ther. 2007;25:599&#x2013;608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiarioni G, Whitehead WE, Pezza V, et al. Biofeedback is superior to laxatives for normal transit constipation due to pelvic floor dyssynergia. Gastroenterology. 2006;130:657&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ersoy O. Constipation and Biofeedback; Important Gastrointestinal Symptom but Ignored Initial Management. Adv Res Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;4:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y-J, Ting SW-H, Hsiao S-M, et al. Efficacy of bio-assisted pelvic floor muscle training in women with pelvic floor dysfunction. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2020;251:206&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George SE, Borello-France DF. Perspective on physical therapist management of functional constipation. Phys Ther. 2017;97:478&#x2013;493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Mearin F, Chang L, et al. Bowel disorders. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1393&#x2013;1407. e1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocchini R, Chiarioni G, Corazziari E, et al. Pelvic floor rehabilitation for defecation disorders. Tech Coloproctol. 2019;23:101&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes M, Garber CE. General Principles of Exercise Prescription. In: Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G. ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Wolters Kluwer Health; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day ML, McGuigan MR, Brice G, et al. Monitoring exercise intensity during resistance training using the session RPE scale. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:353&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva C, Motta M. The use of abdominal muscle training, breathing exercises and abdominal massage to treat paediatric chronic functional constipation. Colorectal Dis. 2013;15:e250&#x2013;e255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanai A, Ishiguro H, Sozu T, et al. Effects of a self-management program on antiemetic-induced constipation during chemotherapy among breast cancer patients: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2016;155:99&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy KL, Troiano RP, Ballard RM, et al. The physical activity guidelines for Americans. JAMA. 2018;320:2020&#x2013;2028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kotob R, Giangregorio LM. Pilot and feasibility studies in exercise, physical activity, or rehabilitation research. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2018;4:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teresi JA, Yu X, Stewart AL, et al. Guidelines for designing and evaluating feasibility pilot studies. Med Care. 2022;60:95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton C, Bannister S, Booth L, et al. Habit training versus habit training with direct visual biofeedback in adults with chronic constipation: a randomized controlled trial. Colorectal Dis. 2023;25:2243&#x2013;2256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyr MP, Dumoulin C, Bessette P, et al. Feasibility, acceptability and effects of multimodal pelvic floor physical therapy for gynecological cancer survivors suffering from painful sexual intercourse: a multicenter prospective interventional study. Gynecol Oncol. 2020;159:778&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank L, Kleinman L, Farup C, et al. Psychometric validation of a constipation symptom assessment questionnaire. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1999;34:870&#x2013;877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yiannakou Y, Tack J, Piessevaux H, et al. The PAC-SYM questionnaire for chronic constipation: defining the minimal important difference. Aliment Pharmacol Therap. 2017;46:1103&#x2013;1111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadowy AM, Brouwer HL, Finseth DL, et al. Development of a pelvic floor muscle coordination scale. J Women Health Phys Ther. 2010;34:81&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M, Ford AC, Mawe GM, et al. Chronic constipation. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantiphlachiva K, Rao P, Attaluri A, et al. Digital rectal examination is a useful tool for identifying patients with dyssynergia. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2010;8:955&#x2013;960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frawley H, Shelly B, Morin M, et al. An International Continence Society (ICS) report on the terminology for pelvic floor muscle assessment. Neurourol Urodyn. 2021;40:1217&#x2013;1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messelink B, Benson T, Berghmans B, et al. Standardization of terminology of pelvic floor muscle function and dysfunction: report from the pelvic floor clinical assessment group of the International Continence Society. Neurourol Urodyn. 2005;24:374&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushal JN, Goldner F. Validation of the digital rectal examination as an estimate of anal sphincter squeeze pressure. Am J Gastroenterol. 1991;86:886&#x2013;887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosling J, Plumb A, Taylor SA, et al. High-resolution anal manometry: repeatability, validation, and comparison with conventional manometry. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2019;31:e13591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquis P, De La Loge C, Dubois D, et al. Development and validation of the Patient Assessment of Constipation Quality of Life questionnaire. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2005;40:540&#x2013;551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, et al. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exercise. 2003;35:1381&#x2013;1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead AL, Julious SA, Cooper CL, et al. Estimating the sample size for a pilot randomised trial to minimise the overall trial sample size for the external pilot and main trial for a continuous outcome variable. Stat Methods Med Res. 2016;25:1057&#x2013;1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitz FF, St&#xfc;pp L, da Costa TF, et al. Outpatient biofeedback in addition to home pelvic floor muscle training for stress urinary incontinence: a randomized controlled trial. Neurourol Urodyn. 2017;36:2034&#x2013;2043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y-T, Tsai Y-J, Wang L-Y, et al. The feasibility of a multimodal exercise program for sedentary postmenopausal women with urinary incontinence: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Maturitas. 2023;167:90&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lausen A, Marsland L, Head S, et al. Modified Pilates as an adjunct to standard physiotherapy care for urinary incontinence: a mixed methods pilot for a randomised controlled trial. BMC Women Health. 2018;18:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SS. Biofeedback therapy for constipation in adults. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2011;25:159&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves MLC, Fernandes S, de Sousa JB. Do moderate aerobic exercise and strength training influence electromyographic biofeedback of the pelvic floor muscles in female non-athletes? J Phys Ther Sci. 2018;30:313&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesel PH, Dorta G, Cuypers P, et al. Patient satisfaction after biofeedback for constipation and pelvic floor dyssynergia. Swiss Med Wkly. 2001;131:152&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fennell C, Peroutky K, Glickman E. Effects of supervised training compared to unsupervised training on physical activity, muscular endurance, and cardiovascular parameters. MOJ Orthop Rheumatol. 2016;5:00184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrington EV, Brokjaer A, Craven H, et al. Traditional measures of normal anal sphincter function using high-resolution anorectal manometry (HRAM) in 115 healthy volunteers. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2014;26:625&#x2013;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noelting J, Ratuapli SK, Bharucha AE, et al. Normal values for high-resolution anorectal manometry in healthy women: effects of age and significance of rectoanal gradient. Am J Gastroenterol. 2012;107:1530&#x2013;1536.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>