<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41423031</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-2201</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of allergy and clinical immunology. In practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel Approaches to Ambulatory Antibiotic Allergic Clinics.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-2198(25)01183-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaip.2025.12.013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antibiotic allergy labels, especially to penicillins, are common but often inaccurate, with more than 90% disproven on formal evaluation. These unverified labels lead to suboptimal antibiotic use, increased health care costs, and worse clinical outcomes. Traditional allergist-led assessment models are not scalable due to global shortages of allergy specialists. Recent evidence supports a shift toward proactive, ambulatory, multidisciplinary delabeling strategies that integrate risk-stratified direct oral drug provocation testing into routine care. Validated point-of-care tools now enable nonallergists, including pharmacists, nurses, and physicians, to safely identify low-risk patients suitable for delabeling without skin testing. Successful programs in hospitals, outpatient clinics, and community settings demonstrate that ambulatory delabeling is safe, cost-effective, and scalable. High-yield populations such as pregnant women, immunocompromised individuals, and older adults benefit significantly from timely evaluation. Effective implementation requires structured training, standardized protocols, integration into electronic health records, and a Hub-and-Spoke model linking nonspecialist "spokes" to allergist-led "hubs" for oversight. Clear documentation, patient education, and postchallenge follow-up are essential to prevent relabeling. Future efforts must focus on equitable access, workforce development, and research to validate tools in underrepresented populations and quantify long-term antimicrobial stewardship benefits. Ambulatory delabeling is no longer the sole domain of allergists but a shared responsibility across health care systems to improve prescribing, patient safety, and global antimicrobial resistance outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 American Academy of Allergy, Asthma &amp; Immunology. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cox</LastName><ForeName>Fionnuala</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Beaumont Hospital, Dublin, Ireland; Department of Pathology, Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dowden</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Immunology, University of Iowa Health Care, Iowa City, Iowa; Department of Internal Medicine, University of Iowa Carver College of Medicine, Iowa City, Iowa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sousa-Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MEDCIDS-Department of Community Medicine, Information and Health Decision Sciences, Faculty of Medicine, University of Porto, Porto, Portugal; CINTESIS@RISE-Health Research Network, Faculty of Medicine, University of Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Philip H</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Department of Medicine, Queen Mary Hospital, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, SAR, China; Division of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Department of Medicine, University of Hong Kong-Shenzhen Hospital, Shenzhen, China. Electronic address: liphilip@hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597220</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ambulatory care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delabeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Direct oral challenge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug provocation test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low-risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Penicillin allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Point-of-care</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41423031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2025.12.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-2198(25)01183-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>