<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41931963</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1760-4788</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of nutrition, health &amp; aging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nutr Health Aging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of a protein intervention during resistance training with varying training intensities on muscle outcomes in frail community-dwelling older adults: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100838</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100838</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jnha.2026.100838</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1279-7707(26)00069-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Optimising nutritional and exercise strategies is essential to preserve muscle health and physical function in frail older adults. This study aims to investigate the effects of a protein intervention during progressive resistance training (PRT) with varying training intensities on muscle strength, muscle mass, and physical performance in frail community-dwelling older adults. We were particularly interested in whether these effects differed according to variations in habitual protein intake and resistance training intensity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This 12-week RCT randomized 295 frail community-dwelling older adults into PRT-only or PRT with a protein intervention (PRT-Pro). Frailty was defined by receipt of in-home care services or a Tilburg Frailty Indicator score &#x2265;5.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION" NlmCategory="METHODS">All participants performed under one-to-one supervision, twice-weekly full-body resistance training performed until muscle failure with varying training intensities (20-80% of one-repetition maximum (1RM)). Participants in the protein intervention group received dietary counselling and tailored daily provision of whey protein supplements (20 g) to support achieving a protein intake of 1.2-1.5 g/kg/day. To prevent over-feeding, for participants with a BMI &gt; 30 kg/m<sup>2</sup>, bodyweight was adjusted using a BMI of 27.5 kg/m<sup>2</sup>.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MEASUREMENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Primary outcome was leg press muscle strength (1RM). Secondary outcomes included appendicular lean mass and physical performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants had a mean age of 73.9 &#xb1; 6.0, with 69% being female. Protein intake increased in PRT-Pro compared to PRT-only (0.4 g/kg, 95%CI: 0.3-0.5, p &lt; 0.001). Overall, the protein intervention did not result in significantly greater gains in leg press muscle strength, appendicular lean mass, or physical performance compared to PRT-only (p &gt; 0.05). In exploratory subgroup analyses, participants with baseline habitual protein intake &lt;1.2 g/kg showed greater improvements in leg press strength with protein intervention (6.4 kg, 95% CI: 1.3-11.4, p = 0.013), with the largest effect observed in those &lt;0.8 g/kg (10.9 kg, 95% CI: 1.5-20.4, p = 0.025) compared with PRT-only. Training intensity did not modify the effects of the protein intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A protein intervention during resistance training did not enhance overall muscle strength, muscle mass, or physical performance in frail older adults. The protein intervention was associated with greater strength gains in exploratory analyses among participants with lower baseline protein intake (&lt;1.2 g/kg/day), with the most pronounced associations observed in those consuming &lt;0.8 g/kg/day. These findings highlight the potential importance of baseline protein status, although they require confirmation in larger trials involving frail older populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY ID" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">NL-OMON54919 (at ICTRP Search Portal), date of registration: 09-02-2021.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biersteker</LastName><ForeName>Esm&#xe9;e J M</ForeName><Initials>EJM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Movement Sciences Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands. Electronic address: e.j.m.biersteker@hva.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benali</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Movement Sciences Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>den Helder</LastName><ForeName>Jantine van</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Movement Sciences Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Twisk</LastName><ForeName>Jos</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam Public Health Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Department of Epidemiology and Data Sciences, Amsterdam University Medical Center, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tieland</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands; Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weijs</LastName><ForeName>Peter J M</ForeName><Initials>PJM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Movement Sciences Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Public Health Research Institute, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Amsterdam University Medical Center, VU University, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoufour</LastName><ForeName>Josje D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Dokter Meurerlaan 8, Amsterdam, 1067 SM, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>J Nutr Health Aging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100893366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1279-7707</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41931963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnha.2026.100838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1279-7707(26)00069-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>