<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41182897</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coronary Artery Calcium Status, Body Composition, Blood Lipids, and Fitness Among Firefighters Participating in a Health and Wellness Program.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95</StartPage><EndPage>e103</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e95-e103</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005262</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sanchez, KJ, Baruch, T, Ross, KA, Coburn, JW, Costa, PB, Orr, RM, Dawes, JJ, and Lockie, RG. Coronary artery calcium status, body composition, blood lipids, and fitness among firefighters participating in a health and wellness program. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): e95-e103, 2026-Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is prevalent among firefighters. Coronary artery calcium (CAC) can contribute to the identification of CVD risk, but there has been limited analysis in firefighters. This study investigated body composition, blood lipid, and fitness test differences in firefighters with normal (CAC-N) and abnormal (CAC-A) CAC. Relationships between these health and fitness variables and CAC status were also derived. Archival data from 45 male firefighters were examined. Data included age, height, body mass, body mass index, body fat mass, lean body mass, waist-to-hip ratio, blood lipids (triglycerides, low-density lipoproteins, high-density lipoproteins, total cholesterol), grip strength, vertical jump (VJ), plank, push-ups, resting heart rate, systolic and diastolic blood pressure (BP), and estimated maximal aerobic capacity (V&#x307; o2 max). Firefighters were screened and grouped as CAC-N (CAC = 0; n = 35) and CAC-A (CAC &gt; 0; n = 10). Independent samples t-tests or Mann-Whitney U -tests determined between-group differences. Pearson's correlations determined relationships between the binary variable of CAC status with the other variables. There were no significant between-group differences in any variable. The CAC-N group had a lower systolic BP than the CAC-A group, with a moderate effect ( p = 0.080, d = 0.893). Systolic BP also correlated with CAC status ( r = 0.355; p = 0.017). The CAC-N group had 9-14% better VJ and V&#x307; o2 max than the CAC-A group, which had small effects ( p = 0.050-0.110, d = 0.555-0.584). Body composition, blood lipids, and fitness generally did not differentiate or relate to CAC status. Apparently fit and healthy firefighters may have underlying CVD risk factors such as higher CAC. Health and wellness programs should be multifaceted, including exercise and medical screening.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanchez</LastName><ForeName>Kristine J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tactical Fitness and Nutrition Lab, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baruch</LastName><ForeName>Terrence</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foothill Cardiology Medical Group, Inc., Arcadia, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Kristina A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fire Technology Department, Santa Ana College, Santa Ana, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coburn</LastName><ForeName>Jared W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University, Fullerton, Fullerton, California; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Pablo B</ForeName><Initials>PB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University, Fullerton, Fullerton, California; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orr</LastName><ForeName>Robin M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tactical Research Unit, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dawes</LastName><ForeName>J Jay</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tactical Fitness and Nutrition Lab, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lockie</LastName><ForeName>Robert G</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University, Fullerton, Fullerton, California; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>SY7Q814VUP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002118">Calcium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061388" MajorTopicYN="Y">Firefighters</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Promotion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003331" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Vessels</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Calcium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003324" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Artery Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">first responder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tactical</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41182897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aandstad A, Holtberget K, Hageberg R, Holme I, Anderssen SA. Validity and reliability of bioelectrical impedance analysis and skinfold thickness in predicting body fat in military personnel. Mil Med 179: 208&#x2013;217, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agatston AS, Janowitz WR, Hildner FJ, Zusmer NR, Viamonte M Jr, Detrano R. Quantification of coronary artery calcium using ultrafast computed tomography. J Am Coll Cardiol 15: 827&#x2013;832, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association. Coronary artery calcium test. Available at: https://www.heart.org/en/health-topics/heart-attack/diagnosing-a-heart-attack/cac-test . Accessed June 13, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angerer P, Kadlez-Gebhardt S, Delius M, Raluca P, Nowak D. Comparison of cardiocirculatory and thermal strain of male firefighters during fire suppression to exercise stress test and aerobic exercise testing. Am J Cardiol 102: 1551&#x2013;1556, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleman AJ, Van Hasselt VB, Schuhmann BB. Relationship between posttraumatic stress symptoms and cardiovascular disease risk in firefighters. Behav Modif 46: 321&#x2013;351, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashen MD, Carson KA, Ratchford EV. Coronary calcium scanning and cardiovascular risk assessment among firefighters. Am J Prev Med 62: 18&#x2013;25, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badby AJ, Mundy PD, Comfort P, Lake JP, McMahon JJ. The validity of Hawkin Dynamics wireless dual force plates for measuring countermovement jump and drop jump variables. Sensors 23: 4820, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrios P, Martin-Biggers J, Quick V, Byrd-Bredbenner C. Reliability and criterion validity of self-measured waist, hip, and neck circumferences. BMC Med Res Methodol 16: 49, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billings J, Focht W. Firefighter shift schedules affect sleep quality. J Occup Environ Med 58: 294&#x2013;298, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rkegren JLM, Lusis AJ. Atherosclerosis: Recent developments. Cell 185: 1630&#x2013;1645, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. About Cholesterol. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/cholesterol/about/index.html . Accessed November 18, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland Clinic. Calcium Score Test. Available at: https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diagnostics/16824-calcium-score-screening-heart-scan . Accessed June 20, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins KS, Christensen B, Orr RM, Dulla JM, Dawes JJ, Lockie RG. Analysis of total and segmental body composition relative to fitness performance measures in law enforcement recruits. Int J Exerc Sci 15: 245&#x2013;260, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig SR, Amin RV, Russell DW, Paradise NF. Blood cholesterol screening influence of fasting state on cholesterol results and management decisions. J Gen Intern Med 15: 395&#x2013;399, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl&#xf6;f B. Cardiovascular disease risk factors: Epidemiology and risk assessment. Am J Cardiol 105: 3A&#x2013;9A, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darras P, Mattman A, Francis GA. Nonfasting lipid testing: The new standard for cardiovascular risk assessment. Can Med Assoc J 190: E1317&#x2013;E1318, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Koning L, Merchant AT, Pogue J, Anand SS. Waist circumference and waist-to-hip ratio as predictors of cardiovascular events: Meta-regression analysis of prospective studies. Eur Heart J 28: 850&#x2013;856, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolezal BA, Barr D, Boland DM, Smith DL, Cooper CB. Validation of the firefighter WFI treadmill protocol for predicting VO2 max. Occup Med 65: 143&#x2013;146, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellulu MS, Patimah I, Khaza&#x2019;ai H, Rahmat A, Abed Y, Ali F. Atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: A review of initiators and protective factors. Inflammopharmacology 24: 1&#x2013;10, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firefighter Candidate Testing Center. Candidate Physical Ability Test. Available at: https://www.fctconline.org/cpat/ . Accessed March 20, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geluk CA, Dikkers R, Kors JA, et al. Measurement of coronary calcium scores or exercise testing as initial screening tool in asymptomatic subjects with ST-T changes on the resting ECG: An evaluation study. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 7: 19, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin SC, Regan TL, Harber P, et al. Evaluation of a fitness intervention for new firefighters: Injury reduction and economic benefits. Inj Prev 22: 181&#x2013;188, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. How to interpret changes in an athletic performance test. Sportscience 8: 1&#x2013;7, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A Scale of Magnitudes for Effect Statistics. Available at: http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html . Accessed January 18, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innes E. Handgrip strength testing: A review of the literature. Aust Occup Ther J 46: 120&#x2013;140, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahnke SA, Poston WS, Jitnarin N, Haddock CK. Health concerns of the US fire service: Perspectives from the firehouse. Am J Health Promot 27: 111&#x2013;118, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Chang Y, Kim S, Sung KC, Shin H, Ryu S. Increased burden of coronary artery calcium from elevated blood pressure in low-risk young adults. Atherosclerosis 282: 188&#x2013;195, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimley KE, Van Hasselt VB, Stripling AM. Posttraumatic stress disorder in police, firefighters, and emergency dispatchers. Aggress Violent Behav 43: 33&#x2013;44, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama S, Saito K, Tanaka S, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness as a quantitative predictor of all-cause mortality and cardiovascular events in healthy men and women: A meta-analysis. JAMA 301: 2024&#x2013;2035, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Dawes JJ, Dulla JM, Orr RM, Hernandez E. Physical fitness, sex considerations, and academy graduation for law enforcement recruits. J Strength Cond Res 34: 3356&#x2013;3363, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Dawes JJ, Orr RM. Health and fitness data for police officers within a health and wellness program: Implications for occupational performance and career longevity. Work 73: 1059&#x2013;1074, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Dulla JM, Higuera D, et al. Body composition and fitness characteristics of firefighters participating in a health and wellness program: Relationships and descriptive data. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 15758, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Orr RM, Dawes JJ. Fit (and healthy) for duty: Blood lipid profiles and physical fitness test relationships from police officers in a health and wellness program. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 5408, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Orr RM, Montes F, Ruvalcaba TJ, Dawes JJ. Differences in fitness between firefighter trainee academy classes and normative percentile rankings. Sustainability 14: 6548, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockie RG, Dulla JM, Higuera D, et al. Age-related differences in body fat and fitness of firefighters participating in a health and wellness program. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1127&#x2013;1135, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin ZT, Schlaff RA, Hemenway JK, et al. Cardiovascular disease risk factors and physical fitness in volunteer firefighters. Int J Exerc Sci 12: 764&#x2013;776, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaelides MA, Parpa KM, Henry LJ, Thompson GB, Brown BS. Assessment of physical fitness aspects and their relationship to firefighters' job abilities. J Strength Cond Res 25: 956&#x2013;965, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miedema MD, Dardari ZA, Nasir K, et al. Association of coronary artery calcium with long-term, cause-specific mortality among young adults. JAMA Netw Open 2: e197440, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno MR, Dawes JJ, Orr RM, Dulla JM, Lockie RG. Relationships between strength and power with the 74.84-kg (165-lb) and 90.72-kg (200-lb) body drags. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1305&#x2013;1313, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntner P, Shimbo D, Carey RM, et al. Measurement of blood pressure in humans: A scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hypertension 73: e35&#x2013;e66, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Cholesterol Education Program. Third Report of the National Cholesterol Education Program (NCEP) Expert Panel on Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol in Adults (Adult Treatment Panel III). Available at: https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/files/docs/guidelines/atp3xsum.pdf . Accessed September 27, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Fire Protection Association. NFPA 1582: Standard on Comprehensive Occupational Medical Program for Fire Departments. Available at: https://www.princegeorgescountymd.gov/sites/default/files/Appendix-L.pdf . Accessed June 20, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesto RW. Beyond low-density lipoprotein: Addressing the atherogenic lipid triad in type 2 diabetes mellitus and the metabolic syndrome. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs 5: 379&#x2013;387, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan V, Dean E. Submaximal exercise testing: Clinical application and interpretation. Phys Ther 80: 782&#x2013;807, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr R, Pope R, Peterson S, Hinton B, Stierli M. Leg power as an indicator of risk of injury or illness in police recruits. Int J Environ Res Public Health 13: 237, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford NB, DeFina LF, Leonard D, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness, coronary artery calcium, and cardiovascular disease events in a cohort of generally healthy middle-age men: Results from the Cooper Center Longitudinal Study. Circulation 137: 1888&#x2013;1895, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G, Magal M. ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription (10th ed.). Philadelphia, PA: Wolters Kluwer, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Mora-Custodio R, Franco-M&#xe1;rquez F, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Traditional vs. sport-specific vertical jump tests: Reliability, validity, and relationship with the legs strength and sprint performance in adult and teen soccer and basketball players. J Strength Cond Res 31: 196&#x2013;206, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero Cabrera JL, Sotos-Prieto M, Garc&#xed;a R&#xed;os A, et al. Sleep and association with cardiovascular risk among Midwestern US firefighters. Front Endocrinol 12: 772848, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryman Augustsson S, Bers&#xe5;s E, Magnusson Thomas E, Sahlberg M, Augustsson J, Svantesson U. Gender differences and reliability of selected physical performance tests in young women and men. Adv Physiother 11: 64&#x2013;70, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyedmehdi SM, Attarchi M, Cherati AS, Hajsadeghi S, Tofighi R, Jamaati H. Relationship of aerobic fitness with cardiovascular risk factors in firefighters. Work 55: 155&#x2013;161, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shreya D, Zamora DI, Patel GS, et al. Coronary artery calcium score&#x2014;A reliable indicator of coronary artery disease? Cureus 13: e20149, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soteriades ES, Smith DL, Tsismenakis AJ, Baur DM, Kales SN. Cardiovascular disease in US firefighters: A systematic review. Cardiol Rev 19: 202&#x2013;215, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone BL, Alvar BA, Orr RM, et al. Impact of an 11-week strength and conditioning program on firefighter trainee fitness. Sustainability 12: 6541, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong TK, Wu S, Nie J. Sport-specific endurance plank test for evaluation of global core muscle function. Phys Ther Sport 15: 58&#x2013;63, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UCLA: Statistical Consulting Group. FAQ: What is dummy coding? Available at: https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/other/mult-pkg/faq/general/faqwhat-is-dummy-coding/ . Accessed July 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaara JP, Kyrolainen H, Niemi J, et al. Associations of maximal strength and muscular endurance test scores with cardiorespiratory fitness and body composition. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2078&#x2013;2086, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker A, Pope R, Schram B, Gorey R, Orr R. The impact of occupational tasks on firefighter hydration during a live structural fire. Saf Now 5: 36, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams-Bell FM, Villar R, Sharratt MT, Hughson RL. Physiological demands of the firefighter Candidate Physical Ability Test. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 653&#x2013;662, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>