<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41518607</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of magnetic resonance imaging : JMRI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Magn Reson Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Subregional Radiomics Analysis on Multiparametric MRI for Evaluating Lymphovascular Invasion and Survival in Gastric Cancer: A Multicenter Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmri.70236</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Accurate preoperative assessment of lymphovascular invasion (LVI) remains challenging due to the high heterogeneity of gastric cancer (GC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the feasibility of a subregion-based radiomics model using multiparametric MRI (mpMRI) for preoperative evaluation of LVI and to further assess its prognostic value.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY TYPE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Retrospective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUBJECTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 878 GC patients from four centers: 313 training, 133 internal test, and 432 external validation cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FIELD STRENGTH/SEQUENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">1.5&#x2009;T and 3&#x2009;T/mpMRI including T2-weighted imaging (FSE/TSE), diffusion-weighted imaging (SS-EPI), and contrast-enhanced T1-weighted imaging (FFE/VIBE).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ASSESSMENT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The fuzzy c-means clustering was applied to subregion generation after manual segmentation. The subregional radiomics model was established using LVI-related features from a four-step extracted pipeline, with logistic regression, random forest, and support vector machine algorithms. The corresponding intra-tumoral subregion (ITS) index for each patient was obtained from the optimal subregional model. Subsequently, a combined model incorporating the ITS index and independent clinical characteristics was developed. Performance was further validated in test and validation cohorts. Additionally, the prognostic utility for overall survival (OS) and disease-free survival (DFS) was assessed in the follow-up cohort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STATISTICAL TESTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Model area under the receiver operating characteristic curves (AUCs) was compared using net reclassification improvement (NRI) and integrated discrimination improvement (IDI). Kaplan-Meier survival analyses were conducted for prognostic evaluation. p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 was considered statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Pathological LVI-positive was detected in 448 (51.0%) patients. The combined model demonstrated satisfactory discrimination of LVI, achieving AUCs of 0.814 (training), 0.769 (test), and 0.758-0.783 (validation), outperforming the optimal subregional model with positive NRI and IDI across all cohorts. Furthermore, the ITS index maintained a significant association with OS (HR 33.50) and DFS (HR 30.00).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The combined model, which integrated the ITS index derived from subregional radiomics with clinical factors, demonstrated robust performance in evaluating both LVI and survival outcomes in GC patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EVIDENCE LEVEL" NlmCategory="METHODS">3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TECHNICAL EFFICACY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Stage 3.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Ruirui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Shanxi Province Cancer Hospital/Shanxi Hospital Affiliated to Cancer Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences/Cancer Hospital Affiliated to Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Graduate Studies, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Qin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Graduate Studies, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Changzhi People's Hospital, Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pei</LastName><ForeName>Erli</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yangpu Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ziang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Graduate Studies, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Xinru</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Graduate Studies, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huo</LastName><ForeName>Yaoliang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Graduate Studies, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Jialiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GE HealthCare, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Yanfen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6631-5687</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Shanxi Province Cancer Hospital/Shanxi Hospital Affiliated to Cancer Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences/Cancer Hospital Affiliated to Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Wujie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou Institute of Medicine (HIM), Chinese Academy of Sciences, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, The First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2233-1404</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Shanxi Province Cancer Hospital/Shanxi Hospital Affiliated to Cancer Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences/Cancer Hospital Affiliated to Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82171923</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82371952</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U24A20757</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024ZL314</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Province Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and technology project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202403021212233</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Program of Shanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202403021222444</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Program of Shanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YDZJSX20231B012</GrantID><Agency>Central Government Guided Local Science and Technology Development Fund Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Magn Reson Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-1807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Medical non&#x2010;invasive assessment for lymphovascular invasion (LVI) of gastric cancer is still challenging. This multicenter study constructed an artificial intelligence (AI) model using routine MRI data for evaluating LVI preoperatively. This result demonstrated that the subregional AI model performed well in evaluating LVI, outperforming the conventional whole&#x2010;tumor analysis. We trained and tested the model using data from four independent institutions. The AI model also facilitated prognostic stratification, which was critically conducive to the clinical therapy of gastric cancer.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastric cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymphovascular invasion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subregion</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41518607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.70236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>F. Bray, M. Laversanne, H. Sung, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Cancer Statistics 2022: Globocan Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 74, no. 3 (2024): 229&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. L. Siegel, A. N. Giaquinto, and A. Jemal, &#x201c;Cancer Statistics, 2024,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 74, no. 1 (2024): 12&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Dicken, K. Graham, S. M. Hamilton, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Lymphovascular Invasion Is Associated With Poor Survival in Gastric Cancer: An Application of Gene&#x2010;Expression and Tissue Array Techniques,&#x201d; Annals of Surgery 243, no. 1 (2006): 64&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. A. Ajani, T. A. D'Amico, D. J. Bentrem, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Gastric Cancer, Version 2.2022, Nccn Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology,&#x201d; Journal of the National Comprehensive Cancer Network 20, no. 2 (2022): 167&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, L. L. Yan, H. K. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Application of Intravoxel Incoherent Motion Diffusion&#x2010;Weighted Imaging for Preoperative Knowledge of Lymphovascular Invasion in Gastric Cancer: A Prospective Study,&#x201d; Abdominal Radiology (New York) 48, no. 7 (2023): 2207&#x2013;2218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. J. Gillies, P. E. Kinahan, and H. Hricak, &#x201c;Radiomics: Images Are More Than Pictures, They Are Data,&#x201d; Radiology 278, no. 2 (2016): 563&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Lambin, R. T. H. Leijenaar, T. M. Deist, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Radiomics: The Bridge Between Medical Imaging and Personalized Medicine,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Clinical Oncology 14, no. 12 (2017): 749&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, G. Wang, J. Ren, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multiparametric Mri&#x2010;Based Radiomics Nomogram for Preoperative Prediction of Lymphovascular Invasion and Clinical Outcomes in Patients With Breast Invasive Ductal Carcinoma,&#x201d; European Radiology 32, no. 6 (2022): 4079&#x2013;4089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Long, J. Sun, L. Jiang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mri&#x2010;Based Traditional Radiomics and Computer&#x2010;Vision Nomogram for Predicting Lymphovascular Space Invasion in Endometrial Carcinoma,&#x201d; Diagnostic and Interventional Imaging 102, no. 7&#x2013;8 (2021): 455&#x2013;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Xu, J. Hong, and X. Wu, &#x201c;An Integrative Clinical and Intra&#x2010; and Peritumoral MRI Radiomics Nomogram for the Preoperative Prediction of Lymphovascular Invasion in Rectal Cancer,&#x201d; Academic Radiology 32, no. 7 (2025): 3989&#x2013;4001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. J. Gillies and Y. Balagurunathan, &#x201c;Perfusion Mr Imaging of Breast Cancer: Insights Using &#x201c;Habitat Imaging&#x201d;,&#x201d; Radiology 288, no. 1 (2018): 36&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Li, Y. Dai, J. Chen, F. Yan, and Y. Yang, &#x201c;MRI&#x2010;Based Habitat Imaging in Cancer Treatment: Current Technology, Applications, and Challenges,&#x201d; Cancer Imaging 24, no. 1 (2024): 107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, Y. Han, S. Zhao, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Spatial Heterogeneity of Edema Region Uncovers Survival&#x2010;Relevant Habitat of Glioblastoma,&#x201d; European Journal of Radiology 154 (2022): 110423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Shi, X. Huang, Z. Cheng, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mri&#x2010;Based Quantification of Intratumoral Heterogeneity for Predicting Treatment Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy in Breast Cancer,&#x201d; Radiology 308, no. 1 (2023): e222830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Cai, Z. Xu, Y. Chen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multiparametric Mri Subregion Radiomics for Preoperative Assessment of High&#x2010;Risk Subregions in Microsatellite Instability of Rectal Cancer Patients: A Multicenter Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Surgery 110, no. 7 (2024): 4310&#x2013;4319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. B. Amin, F. L. Greene, S. B. Edge, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Eighth Edition Ajcc Cancer Staging Manual: Continuing to Build a Bridge From a Population&#x2010;Based to a More &#x201c;Personalized&#x201d; Approach to Cancer Staging,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 67, no. 2 (2017): 93&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. J. Tustison, B. B. Avants, P. A. Cook, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;N4itk: Improved N3 Bias Correction,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging 29, no. 6 (2010): 1310&#x2013;1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. M. van Griethuysen, A. Fedorov, C. Parmar, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Computational Radiomics System to Decode the Radiographic Phenotype,&#x201d; Cancer Research 77, no. 21 (2017): e104&#x2013;e107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Bl&#xfc;thgen, M. Patella, A. Euler, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Computed Tomography Radiomics for the Prediction of Thymic Epithelial Tumor Histology, Tnm Stage and Myasthenia Gravis,&#x201d; PLoS One 16, no. 12 (2021): e0261401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kirkpatrick, &#x201c;Optimization by Simulated Annealing: Quantitative Studies,&#x201d; Journal of Statistical Physics 34, no. 5&#x2013;6 (1984): 975&#x2013;986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Chen, S. Wang, D. Dong, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Evaluation of Lymph Node Metastasis in Advanced Gastric Cancer Using Magnetic Resonance Imaging&#x2010;Based Radiomics,&#x201d; Frontiers in Oncology 9, no. 22 (2019): 1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Song, W. Chen, J. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multiparametric Mri&#x2010;Based Radiomics Analysis for Prediction of Lymph Node Metastasis and Survival Outcome in Gastric Cancer: A Dual&#x2010;Center Study,&#x201d; Academic Radiology 31, no. 12 (2024): 4900&#x2013;4911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, H. Yin, Y. Wang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multiparametric Mri&#x2010;Based Radiomics Nomogram for Early Prediction of Pathological Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy in Locally Advanced Gastric Cancer,&#x201d; European Radiology 33, no. 4 (2023): 2746&#x2013;2756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. F. Liu, M. Wang, Y. J. Lu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cemri&#x2010;Based Quantification of Intratumoral Heterogeneity for Predicting Aggressive Characteristics of Hepatocellular Carcinoma Using Habitat Analysis: Comparison and Combination of Deep Learning,&#x201d; Academic Radiology 31, no. 6 (2024): 2346&#x2013;2355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xie, F. Wang, J. Wei, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Noninvasive Prognostic Classification of Ith in Hcc With Multi&#x2010;Omics Insights and Therapeutic Implications,&#x201d; Science Advances 11, no. 18 (2025): eads8323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, X. Wang, Y. Cao, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Nomogram for Predicting Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy Response in Breast Cancer Using Mri&#x2010;Based Intratumoral Heterogeneity Quantification,&#x201d; Radiology 315, no. 1 (2025): e241805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Althubiti, S. Paul, R. Mohanty, S. N. Mohanty, F. Alenezi, and K. Polat, &#x201c;Ensemble Learning Framework With GLCM Texture Extraction for Early Detection of Lung Cancer on CT Images,&#x201d; Computational and Mathematical Methods in Medicine 2022 (2022): 2733965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Cui, X. Yang, Z. Shi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Radiomics Analysis of Multiparametric Mri for Prediction of Pathological Complete Response to Neoadjuvant Chemoradiotherapy in Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer,&#x201d; European Radiology 29, no. 3 (2019): 1211&#x2013;1220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jin, A. Lan, Y. Dai, L. Jiang, and S. Liu, &#x201c;Development and Testing of a Random Forest&#x2010;Based Machine Learning Model for Predicting Events Among Breast Cancer Patients With a Poor Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy,&#x201d; European Journal of Medical Research 28, no. 1 (2023): 394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yu, R. Chen, J. Yi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Non&#x2010;Invasive Prediction of Axillary Lymph Node Dissection Exemption in Breast Cancer Patients Post&#x2010;Neoadjuvant Therapy: A Radiomics and Deep Learning Analysis on Longitudinal Dce&#x2010;Mri Data,&#x201d; Breast 77 (2024): 103786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liu, X. Qiao, M. Xu, C. Ji, L. Li, and Z. Zhou, &#x201c;Development and Validation of Multivariate Models Integrating Preoperative Clinicopathological Parameters and Radiographic Findings Based on Late Arterial Phase Ct Images for Predicting Lymph Node Metastasis in Gastric Cancer,&#x201d; Academic Radiology 28, no. 1 (2021): S167&#x2013;S178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chen, Z. Yang, J. Yang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Radiomics Analysis of Contrast&#x2010;Enhanced Ct Predicts Lymphovascular Invasion and Disease Outcome in Gastric Cancer: A Preliminary Study,&#x201d; Cancer Imaging 20, no. 1 (2020): 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Guo, Q. Sun, X. Bian, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Development and Validation of a Multiphase Ct Radiomics Nomogram for the Preoperative Prediction of Lymphovascular Invasion in Patients With Gastric Cancer,&#x201d; Clinical Radiology 78, no. 8 (2023): e552&#x2013;e559.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>