<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41275294</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Late-stage anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation in the United Kingdom: an online survey of National Health Service physiotherapists.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>46</StartPage><MedlinePgn>46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">46</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01438-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Late-stage Anterior Cruciate Ligament reconstruction (ACL-R) rehabilitation aims to help patients to return to sports (RTS) and their previous activity levels and minimise reinjury rates. In the United Kingdom, National Health Service (NHS) physiotherapists lead post-ACL-R rehabilitation programs. This survey aimed evaluate NHS physiotherapists&#x2019; perspectives of the resources available, and their confidence to deliver, late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation. The secondary aim was to identify the RTS tests conducted by NHS physiotherapists on ACL-R patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">An online cross-sectional survey of NHS physiotherapists was conducted. Proportions and percentages summarised respondents&#x2019; perspectives of the resources (equipment, space, and time) available, and their confidence, to deliver late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation components (strength testing, Neuromuscular control, movement quality analysis, plyometrics, sports specific drills, and psychological readiness evaluation) and RTS testing. Spearman signed rank test evaluated the strength and direction of any correlation between physiotherapists&#x2019; perspectives of available resources, clinical experience, and their confidence to perform late-stage rehabilitation. The RTS tests used across each component of late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">102 physiotherapists completed the online survey between June-July 2022. Approximately half of respondents (53%) believed most ACL-R patients (&gt;60%) RTS. Approximately half to three quarters of respondents agreed that there were adequate resources available to perform strength (range of 49-60% respondents agreed), neuromuscular control (63-72%), movement quality analysis (53-56%) and plyometric (48-52%) components of late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation. Less than half of respondents agreed there were sufficient resources to perform sports specific drills (18%-38%), psychological readiness evaluation (20-46%), and RTS testing (26%-33%). Most respondents were confident to deliver the exercise-based components of ACL-R late-stage rehabilitation (e.g. strength testing; range 68-92%) and decide when patients were ready to RTS (75%). Conversely, most respondents were not confident to perform psychological readiness evaluation, which was moderately positively correlated with their perspectives of resources. Respondents used a wide variety of non-evidence based RTS tests across all components of late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Targeted training in evidence based late-stage rehabilitation ACL-R protocols and improved access to appropriate resources maybe required to enable NHS physiotherapists to deliver optimal late-stage ACL-R rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">N/A</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01438-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NHS St George's University Hospitals Foundation Trust, London, England, SW17 0QT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NHS University Hospitals of Liverpool, Liverpool, England, L7 8YE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stephens</LastName><ForeName>Gareth</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development, The Royal Orthopaedic Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, Northfield, Birmingham, B31 2AP, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dawes</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre For Musculoskeletal Medicine, Royal Orthopaedic Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, Bristol Road South, Northfield, Birmingham, B31 2AP, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mansfield</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, College of Life and Environmental Sciences, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, Birmingham, B15 2TT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willett</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, College of Life and Environmental Sciences, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, Birmingham, B15 2TT, UK. m.j.willett.1@bham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Precision Rehabilitation for Spinal Pain, University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, Birmingham, B15 2TT, UK. m.j.willett.1@bham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Late-stage rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">National health service</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Return to sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was granted by the Ethics Committee of School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences at the University of Birmingham (ref no. MCR2122_24). Informed consent was taken from all participants prior to survey commencement. This research in this study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41275294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12860011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01438-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01438-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Association BOA, BASK, BOSTAA Elective care standards: best practice for management of Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) Injuries.&#xa0;2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies L, Cook J, Leal J, Areia CM, Shirkey B, Jackson W, et al. Comparison of the clinical and cost effectiveness of two management strategies (rehabilitation versus surgical reconstruction) for non-acute anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury: study protocol for the ACL snnap randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2020;21(1):405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-020-04298-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7222454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, Barbosa O, Maree D, Pantouveris M, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade R, Pereira R, van Cingel R, Staal JB, Espregueira-Mendes J. How should clinicians rehabilitate patients after ACL reconstruction? A systematic review of clinical practice guidelines (CPGs) with a focus on quality appraisal (AGREE II). Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(9):512&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-100310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Dingenen B, Hewett TE. Rehabilitation and return to sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: where are we in 2022? Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(1):e77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2021.10.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F, Della Villa S, Roi GS. On-field rehabilitation part 2: a 5-stage program for the soccer player focused on linear movements, multidirectional movements, soccer-specific skills, soccer-specific movements, and modified practice. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49(8):570&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2019.8952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulver M, Hilfiker R, Bizzini M, Mathieu N, Meyer S, Allet L. Clinical practice and barriers among Swiss physiotherapists treating patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of pre-operative rehabilitation to return to sport. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;65:38&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2023.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38006798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards PK, Leembruggen K, Peers C, Lindahl M, Law YX, Hughes M, et al. Rehabilitation and assessment practices following anterior cruciate ligament injury: a survey of Australian physiotherapists. Phys Ther Sport. 2025;71:69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2024.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39662342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V, Kotsifaki A, Korakaki A, Karanasios S, Whiteley R. Current perspectives and clinical practice of physiotherapists on assessment, rehabilitation, and return to sport criteria after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction. An online survey of 538 physiotherapists. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;52:103&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aquino CF, Ocarino JM, Cardoso VA, Resende RA, Souza TR, Rabelo LM, et al. Current clinical practice and return-to-sport criteria after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of Brazilian physical therapists. Braz J Phys Ther. 2021;25(3):242&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2020.05.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8134775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Grindem H. Evidence-based recommendations for the management of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) rupture. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2019;33(1):33&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2019.01.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31431274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch AD, Logerstedt DS, Grindem H, Eitzen I, Hicks GE, Axe MJ, et al. Consensus criteria for defining &#x2018;successful outcome&#x2019; after ACL injury and reconstruction: a Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort investigation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(5):335&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-092299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23881894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron K, Brown M, Calderon A, Feldman M. Anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation and return to sport: how fast is too fast? Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(1):e175&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2021.10.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrington L, Myer G, Horsley I. Task based rehabilitation protocol for elite athletes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a clinical commentary. Phys Ther Sport. 2013;14(4):188&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2013.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24016398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Du Preez L, Furzer B, Edwards P, Joss B. Which hop tests can best identify functional limb asymmetry in patients 9&#x2013;12 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction employing a hamstrings tendon autograft? Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16(2):393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.21140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meredith SJ, Rauer T, Chmielewski TL, Fink C, Diermeier T, Rothrauff BB, et al. Return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament injury: Panther Symposium ACL injury return to sport consensus group. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(8):2403&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06009-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, Witvrouw E, Clarsen B, Cools A, et al. 2016 consensus statement on return to sport from the first world Congress in sports physical Therapy, Bern. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(14):853&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Korakakis V, Whiteley R, Van Rossom S, Jonkers I. Measuring only hop distance during single leg hop testing is insufficient to detect deficits in knee function after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(3):139&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31142471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moksnes H, Ardern CL, Kvist J, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA, Myklebust G, et al. Assessing implementation, limited efficacy, and acceptability of the BEAST tool: a rehabilitation and return-to-sport decision tool for nonprofessional athletes with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;52:147&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Billiet B, De Baets L, Bellemans J, Truijen J, Gokeler A. Rehabilitation strategies of Flemish physical therapists before and after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: an online survey. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;49:68&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Eitzen I, Moksnes H, Snyder-Mackler L, Risberg MA. A pair-matched comparison of return to pivoting sports at 1 year in anterior cruciate ligament-injured patients after a nonoperative versus an operative treatment course. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(11):2509&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512458424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22962290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty-five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Webster KE, Taylor NF, Feller JA. Return to the preinjury level of competitive sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: two-thirds of patients have not returned by 12 months after surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39(3):538&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510384798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robben BJ, Keuning MC, Zuurmond RG, Stevens M, Bulstra SK. In non-elite athletes, women are more likely to return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25(1):739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-024-07834-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11403877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39285398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keays SL, Mellifont DB, Keays AC, Stuelcken MC, Lovell DI, Sayers MGL. Long-term return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament injury: reconstruction vs no reconstruction-a comparison of 2 case series. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(4):912&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211073152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35148249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson R, Sundberg A, Piussi R, Hogberg J, Senorski C, Thomee R, et al. Questioning the rules of engagement: a critical analysis of the use of limb symmetry index for safe return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(6):376&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2024-108079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11874420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx R, Revision ACL, Reconstruction. Available at:&#xa0;https://www.hss.edu/playbook/revision-acl-reconstruction/. Accessed 8 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health N. 2025.&#xa0;https://www.nuffieldhealth.com/hospitals/oxford/treatments/knee-surgery-acl-repair.&#xa0;Accessed 25 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Krupic F, Sundemo D, Svantesson E, Ivarsson A, Johnson U, et al. &#x201c;I was young, I wanted to return to sport, and re-ruptured my ACL&#x201d; - young active female patients&#x2019; voices on the experience of sustaining an ACL re-rupture, a qualitative study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23(1):760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-022-05708-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9360700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Minh Duc NT, Luu Lam Thang T, Nam NH, Ng SJ, Abbas KS, et al. A consensus-based checklist for reporting of survey studies (CROSS). J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(10):3179&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-021-06737-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8481359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Optimising the late-stage rehabilitation and return-to-sport training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):1043&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01102-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diermeier TA, Rothrauff BB, Engebretsen L, Lynch A, Svantesson E, Hamrin Senorski EA, et al. Treatment after ACL injury: Panther Symposium ACL treatment consensus group. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(1):14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monk AP, Davies LJ, Hopewell S, Harris K, Beard DJ, Price AJ. Surgical versus Conservative interventions for treating anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;4(4):CD011166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27039329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller C, Williams M, Heine P, Williamson E, O&#x2019;Connell N. Current practice in the rehabilitation of complex regional pain syndrome: a survey of practitioners. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41(7):847&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2017.1407968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens G, O&#x2019;Neill S, French HP, Fearon A, Grimaldi A, O&#x2019;Connor L, et al. A survey of physiotherapy practice (2018) in the United Kingdom for patients with greater trochanteric pain syndrome. Musculoskelet Sci Pract. 2019;40:10&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msksp.2019.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30660989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker R, Moffatt F, Timmons S. Austerity on the frontline- a preliminary study of physiotherapists working in the National health service in the UK. Physiother Theory Pract. 2022;38(8):1037&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593985.2020.1812139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32866057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg EM, Greenberg ET, Albaugh J, Storey E, Ganley TJ. Rehabilitation practice patterns following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of physical therapists. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2018;48(10):801&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2018.8264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Hewett TE. What is the evidence for and validity of return-to-sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(6):917&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01093-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustavsson A, Neeter C, Thomee P, Silbernagel KG, Augustsson J, Thomee R, et al. A test battery for evaluating hop performance in patients with an ACL injury and patients who have undergone ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2006;14(8):778&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-006-0045-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16525796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, Korakakis V, Bahr R, Sideris V, et al. Single leg vertical jump performance identifies knee function deficits at return to sport after ACL reconstruction in male athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(9):490&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-104692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9016240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carolan D, King E, Richter C, Franklyn-Miller A, Moran R, Jackson M. Differences in strength, patient-reported outcomes, and return-to-play rates between athletes with primary versus revision ACL reconstruction at 9 months after surgery. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(9):2325967120950037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967120950037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7498981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32984423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. Manual muscle testing: does it meet the standards of an adequate screening test? Clin Rehabil. 2005;19(6):662&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/0269215505cr873oa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, Denderen RV. Isokinetic hamstring and quadriceps strength interpretation guideline for football (soccer) players with ACL reconstruction: a Delphi consensus study in the Netherlands. Sci Med Footb. 2022;6(4):434&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2021.2024592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35089850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Undheim MB, Cosgrave C, King E, Strike S, Marshall B, Falvey E, et al. Isokinetic muscle strength and readiness to return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: is there an association? A systematic review and a protocol recommendation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(20):1305&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26105017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Culvenor AG, Ackerman IN, Russell TG, Crossley KM. Quality of life in anterior cruciate ligament-deficient individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(16):1033&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Osterberg A, Tagesson S, Gauffin H, Webster KE, Kvist J. The impact of psychological readiness to return to sport and recreational activities after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(22):1613&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25293342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toale JP, Hurley ET, Hughes AJ, Withers D, King E, Jackson M, et al. The majority of athletes fail to return to play following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction due to reasons other than the operated knee. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(11):3877&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06407-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tondelli E, Feroldi A, Garcia F, Meza F, Dingenen B. Rehabilitation and return-to-sport after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: exploring physical therapists&#x2019; approaches in Argentina. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;67:131&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2024.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38703448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitaguchi T, Tanaka Y, Takeshita S, Tsujimoto N, Kita K, Amano H, et al. Importance of functional performance and psychological readiness for return to preinjury level of sports 1 year after ACL reconstruction in competitive athletes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(7):2203&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-019-05774-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31679068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Webster KE, Edwards PK, Joss BK, D&#x2019;Alessandro P, Janes G, et al. Current perspectives of Australian therapists on rehabilitation and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A survey. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;35:139&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30557764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>