<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41359927</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating Army Combat Fitness Test Scores: The Influence of Sleep, Nutrition, and Body Composition in Army Reserve Officers' Training Corps Cadets.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>218</StartPage><EndPage>224</EndPage><MedlinePgn>218-224</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005285</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Dicks, ND, Ketterling, JJ, Wooldridge, JD, Shoemaker, ME, and Barry, AM. Evaluating Army Combat Fitness Test scores: The influence of sleep, nutrition, and body composition in army reserve officers' training corps cadets. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): 218-224, 2026-The U.S. Army's Holistic Health and Fitness (H2F) program highlights the importance of physical, mental, nutritional, spiritual, and sleep domains for optimizing soldier readiness. Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC) cadets must meet physical fitness standards, including the Army Combat Fitness Test (ACFT), yet often lack access to H2F resources. This cross-sectional study investigated how lifestyle factors-physical activity (PA), sleep quality, nutritional habits, and fat-free mass (FFM)-influence ACFT performance among Army ROTC cadets. Forty-six cadets (21.6 &#xb1; 2.0 years; women = 7) completed validated questionnaires assessing PA (IPAQ), sleep (PSQI), and nutrition (REAP-S), and underwent anthropometric testing. ACFT scores were obtained from the cadre within 30 days of survey completion. Cadets scoring &#x2265;540 on the ACFT demonstrated significantly better sleep quality (PSQI; p &lt; 0.01) and shorter sleep latency than those scoring &lt;540. Backward linear regression identified PSQI as a significant negative predictor of ACFT scores ( &#x3b2; = -0.42, p = 0.007), with REAP-S and FFM showing marginal significance. Correlation analyses revealed small, significant associations between BF%, MVPA, and PSQI. The final regression model explained 22.4% of the variance in ACFT scores. These results emphasize the importance of sleep quality and body composition in cadet performance, suggesting that targeted education and training strategies could improve readiness in ROTC populations. Future programs should consider holistic approaches to cadet wellness, especially without formal H2F support.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dicks</LastName><ForeName>Nathan D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, North Dakota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ketterling</LastName><ForeName>Joe J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, North Dakota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wooldridge</LastName><ForeName>Joshua D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, North Dakota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Sciences, Moravian University, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoemaker</LastName><ForeName>Marni E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, South Dakota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>Allison M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Sciences, South Dakota State University, Brookings, South Dakota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="N">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat-free mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41359927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acevedo AM, Zeigler Z, Melton B. Body composition as a predictor of performance on the Army Combat Fitness Test total score for ROTC cadets. J Exerc Nutr 7, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alruwaili NW, Alqahtani N, Alanazi MH, Alanazi BS, Aljrbua MS, Gatar OM. The effect of nutrition and physical activity on sleep quality among adults: A scoping review. Sleep Sci Pract 7: 8, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Kohl HW, Gordon NF, Paffenbarger RS. How much physical activity is good for health? Annu Rev Public Health 13: 99&#x2013;126, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boffey D, DiPrima JA, Kendall KL, Hill EC, Stout JR, Fukuda DH. Influence of body composition, load-velocity profiles, and sex-related differences on Army Combat Fitness Test performance. J Strength Cond Res 37: 2467&#x2013;2476, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capaldi VF, Balkin TJ, Mysliwiec V. Optimizing sleep in the military: Challenges and opportunities. Chest 155: 215&#x2013;226, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J, Grandner MA. Sleep and athletic performance: Impacts on physical performance, mental performance, injury risk and recovery, and mental health: An update. Sleep Med Clin 17: 263&#x2013;282, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioural Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of the Army. Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps Program (Army Regulation 145-1). Washington, DC, 2023. Available at: https://armypubs.army.mil/epubs/DR_pubs/DR_a/ARN30751-AR_145-1-000-WEB-1.pdf . Accessed December 22, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of the Army, USACC. Cadet Command Reserve Officers&#x2019; Training Corps Component Selection and Commissioning Regulation 145-9. Department of the Army, https://armyrotc.army.mil/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/USACC_REG_145_9.pdf (2021, Accessed November 3, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels E, Hanson J. Energy-adjusted dietary intakes are associated with perceived barriers to healthy eating but not food insecurity or sports nutrition knowledge in a pilot study of ROTC cadets. Nutrients 13: 3053, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza LC, Lee KM, Chapman-Lopez TJ, et al. Sleep, diet quality, and lipid profile assessment in NCAA division I acrobatics and tumbling student-athletes: A cross-sectional study. J Am Nutr Assoc 43: 464&#x2013;472, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicks ND, Mahoney SJ, Barry AM, Christensen BK, Pettitt RW, Hackney KJ. The impact of critical speed and lean body mass on load carriage performance for Army Reserve officers' training Corps cadets. Mil Med 190: e1799&#x2013;e1805, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efron B. Better bootstrap confidence intervals. J Am Stat Assoc 82: 171, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang AG. Statistical power analyses using G*power 3.1: Tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods 41: 1149&#x2013;1160, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feeney KA, Melton BF, Ryan GA, Bland HW, Butler CR. The association between body composition and performance on military fitness tests. J Strength Cond Res 39: 94&#x2013;98, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garron T, Klein DJ. Male Army ROTC cadets fail to meet military dietary reference intakes and exhibit a high prevalence of low energy availability and poor sleep quality. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 8: 95, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandou C, Wallace L, Fullagar HHK, Duffield R, Burley S. The effects of sleep loss on military physical performance. Sports Med 49: 1159&#x2013;1172, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstr&#xf6;mer M, Oja P, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M. The international physical activity questionnaire (IPAQ): A study of concurrent and construct validity. Public Health Nutr 9: 755&#x2013;762, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrich KM, Streetman AE, Kuki&#x107; F, et al. Baseline physical activity behaviors and relationships with fitness in the Army training at high intensity study. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 7: 27, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston CS, Bliss C, Knurick JR, Scholtz C. Rapid Eating Assessment for Participants [shortened version] scores are associated with Healthy Eating Index-2010 scores and other indices of diet quality in healthy adult omnivores and vegetarians. Nutr J 17: 89, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Patton JF, Gordon SE, et al. Compatibility of high-intensity strength and endurance training on hormonal and skeletal muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol 78: 976&#x2013;989, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim JH, Chung JH. The association between sleep quality and quality of life: A population-based study. Sleep Med 84: 121&#x2013;126, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letzler R, Janoska-Bedi S, Penner A. Marching into the leadership pipeline: Gender, college type, and ROTC participation. Socius Sociological Res a Dynamic World 11: 23780231241297776, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loft M, Cameron L. The importance of sleep: Relationships between sleep quality and work demands, the prioritization of sleep and pre-sleep arousal in day-time employees. Work Stress 28: 289&#x2013;304, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie-Shalders K, Matthews C, Dulla J, Orr R. Law enforcement personnel are willing to change, but report influencing beliefs and barriers to optimised dietary intake. BMC Public Health 20: 1638&#x2013;1639, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensink GBM, Deketh M, Mul MDM, Schuit AJ, Hoffmeister H. Physical activity and its association with cardiovascular risk factors and mortality. Epidemiology 7: 391&#x2013;397, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensink GBM, Loose N, Oomen CM. Physical activity and its association with other lifestyle factors. Eur J Epidemiol 13: 771&#x2013;778, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman A, Armonda A, Braun B. Evaluation of two training programs designed to enhance performance on the Army Combat Fitness Test among ROTC cadets. Mil Med 187: e1030&#x2013;e1036, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AA, Nelson T, Braun B, Graham D, Cooper KB. Development and evaluation of physical and mental readiness training programs for Army Reserve officer training cadets. 2024. Available at: https://hdl.handle.net/10217/239217 . Accessed June 23, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palevo G, Robinson S, Jackson A, Dale K. Sleep metrics, stress score in ruck marching in Corp of cadets. J Exerc Physiol 26: 27&#x2013;35, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posadzki P, Pieper D, Bajpai R, et al. Exercise/physical activity and health outcomes: An overview of cochrane systematic reviews. BMC Public Health 20: 1724, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriquez N, Di Marco N, Langley S. Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 709&#x2013;731, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sax van der Weyden M, Toczko M, Fyock-Martin M, Martin J. Relationship between a maximum plank assessment and fitness, health behaviors, and moods in tactical athletes: An exploratory study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 12832, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Vetter TR. Propensity score matching in observational research. Anesth Analg 130: 1616&#x2013;1617, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secretary of the Army. Army Directive 2023-08: Army Body Fat Assessment Exemption for Army Combat Fitness Test Score. Washington, DC: Headquarters, Department of the Army; 15 March 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal-Isaacson CJ, Wylie-Rosett J, Gans KM. Validation of a short dietary assessment questionnaire: The Rapid eating and activity assessment for participants short version (REAP-S). Diabetes Educ 30: 774&#x2013;781, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Army. FM 7-22: Holistic Health and Fitness. Washington, DC: Headquarters, Department of the Army; i-14&#x2013;58, 2020. Available at: https://armypubs.army.mil/ . Accessed October 7, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson NF, Badr MS, Belenky G, et al. Recommended amount of sleep for a healthy adult: A joint Consensus Statement of the American academy of sleep medicine and sleep research society. J Clin Sleep Med 11: 591&#x2013;592, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>