<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41341117</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2459-4148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of frailty, sarcopenia and falls</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Group-Based Physical Activity Interventions for Fibromyalgia: A Systematic Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>279</StartPage><EndPage>294</EndPage><MedlinePgn>279-294</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22540/JFSF-10-279</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Group-based physical activity interventions improve symptoms, quality of life and function, and are a cost-effective treatment approach for the management for Fibromyalgia Syndrome. Multiple forms of physical activity have been examined in the Fibromyalgia population; however, a comprehensive review of these approaches is lacking. This review aimed to map the current research and descriptively report on attrition data. A scoping review was undertaken searching Medline, CINAHL, SCOPUS, SPORTDiscus and Web-of-Science for studies meeting the following criteria: English language; peer-reviewed; published January 1, 2000 - February 23, 2023; adults (&#x2265;18 years) diagnosed with Fibromyalgia; group-based exercise or group-based physical activity. Study selection and data extraction were performed independently by two reviewers. Data were recorded into spreadsheets, then descriptively analysed and tabulated. 17 studies were included enrolling a total of 893 participants. Most examined multi-component intervention designs. Twelve included resistance exercise, ten included flexibility, eight included aerobic, six included hydrotherapy, four included balance training, three included "mindful movement" (e.g. Qi-Gong), one included Pilates, and one included exergames. Mean attrition was 21%. Current literature on group-based physical activity for Fibromyalgia examines mostly multi-component programmes delivered by multi-disciplinary teams in community settings, matching best-practice guidelines. Future studies should explore attrition further, examining influential variables.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Hylonome Publications.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pursley</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Health, School of Psychological Sciences and Health, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muirhead</LastName><ForeName>Fiona</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Health, School of Psychological Sciences and Health, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donnachie</LastName><ForeName>Craig</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Health, School of Psychological Sciences and Health, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Health, School of Psychological Sciences and Health, University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mavroeidi</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Occupational Therapy and Human Nutrition and Dietetics, School of Health and Life Sciences, Glasgow Caledonian University, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101756655</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2459-4148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Group-based physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41341117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12670220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22540/JFSF-10-279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFSF-010-04-279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gyorfi M, Rupp A, Abd-Elsayed A. Fibromyalgia Pathophysiology. Biomedicines. 2022;10(12):3070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9776089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36551826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doebl S, Hollick RJ, Beasley M, Choy E, Macfarlane GJ. Comparing the Impact of Symptoms and Health Care Experiences of People Who Have and Have Not Received a Diagnosis of Fibromyalgia: A Cross-Sectional Survey Within the PACFiND Study. Arthritis care &amp; research (2010) 2022;74(11):1894&#x2013;1902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34085414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cagnie B, Coppieters I, Denecker S, Six J, Danneels L, Meeus M. Central sensitization in fibromyalgia?A systematic review on structural and functional brain MRI. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2014;44(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs J, Meeus M, Van Oosterwijck J, et al. In the mind or in the brain?Scientific evidence for central sensitisation in chronic fatigue syndrome. Eur J Clin Invest. 2012;42(2):203&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbunt JA, Pernot DH, Smeets RJ. Disability and quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2008;6:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18211701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner A, Malterud K. It is hard work behaving as a credible patient: encounters between women with chronic pain and their doctors. Soc Sci Med. 2003;57(8):1409&#x2013;1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12927471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;user W, Walitt B, Fitzcharles MA, Sommer C. Review of pharmacological therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome. Arthritis Res Ther. 2014;16(1):201&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24433463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macfarlane GJ, Kronisch C, Dean LE, et al. EULAR revised recommendations for the management of fibromyalgia. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76(2):318&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) Chronic pain (primary and secondary) in over 16s: assessment of all chronic pain and management of chronic primary pain. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). [April 7, 2021]  
https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng193/resources/chronic-pain-primaryand-secondary-in-over-16s-assessment-of-all-chronic-pain-andmanagement-of-chronic-primary-pain-pdf-66142080468421. 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams LM, Turk DC. Central sensitization and the biopsychosocial approach to understanding pain. Journal of applied biobehavioral research. 2018;23(2) e12125-n/a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30479469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel GL. The Need for a New Medical Model: A Challenge for Biomedicine. Psychodyn Psychiatry. 2012;40(3):377&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23002701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferro Moura Franco K, Lenoir D, Santos Franco YR, Jandre Reis FJ, Nunes Cabral CM, Meeus M. Prescription of exercises for the treatment of chronic pain along the continuum of nociplastic pain: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Eur J Pain. 2021;25(1):51&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32976664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspersen CJ, Powell KE, Christenson GM. Physical Activity, Exercise, and Physical Fitness: Definitions and Distinctions for Health-Related Research. Public Health Rep. 1985;100(2):126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1424733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3920711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. Dec. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vancampfort D, McGrath RL, Hemmings L, Gillis V, Bernar K, Van Damme T. Physical activity correlates in people with fibromyalgia: a systematic review. Disabil Rehabil. 2023;45(25):4165&#x2013;4174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36398698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholas MK. The pain self-efficacy questionnaire: Taking pain into account. European Journal of Pain. 2006;11(2):153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16446108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannerkorpi K, Gard G. Physiotherapy group treatment for patients with fibromyalgia-an embodied learning process. Disabil Rehabil. 2003;25(24):1372&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14660205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallinen M, Kukkurainen ML, Peltokallio L. Finally heard, believed and accepted &#x2013;Peer support in the narratives of women with fibromyalgia. Patient Educ Couns. 2011;85(2):e126&#x2013;e130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reig-Garcia G, Bosch-Farr&#xe9; C, Su&#xf1;er-Soler R, et al. The impact of a peer social support network from the perspective of women with fibromyalgia: A qualitative study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(23):12801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34886527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis JS, Stokes EK, Gojanovic B, et al. Reframing how we care for people with persistent non-traumatic musculoskeletal pain. Suggestions for the rehabilitation community. Physiotherapy. 2021;112:143&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Onghia M, Ciaffi J, Ruscitti P, et al. The economic burden of fibromyalgia: A systematic literature review. Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism. 2022;56:152060&#x2013;152060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35849890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa EC, Wylde V, Thorn J, et al. Cost-Effectiveness of Group-Based Outpatient Physical Therapy After Total Knee Replacement: Results From the Economic Evaluation Alongside the ARENA Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2022;74(12):1970&#x2013;1977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10087974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35468266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhambra-Borr&#xe1;s T, Dur&#xe1;-Ferrandis E, Ferrando-Garc&#xed;a M. Effectiveness and estimation of cost-effectiveness of a group-based multicomponent physical exercise programme on risk of falling and frailty in community-dwelling older adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(12):2086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6617042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson G, Hawkins N, McCarthy CJ, et al. Cost-effectiveness of a supplementary class-based exercise program in the treatment of knee osteoarthritis. International Journal of Technology Assessment in Health Care. 2006;22(1):84&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16673684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch AJ, Webber SC, Brachaniec M, et al. Exercise Therapy for Fibromyalgia. Current Pain and Headache Reports. 2011;15(5):358&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21725900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Est&#xe9;vez-L&#xf3;pez F, Maestre-Cascales C, Russell D, et al. Effectiveness of Exercise on Fatigue and Sleep Quality in Fibromyalgia: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Trials. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(4):752&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32721388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneen LJ, Martin DJ, Adams N, et al. Effects of education to facilitate knowledge about chronic pain for adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):132&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4591560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26428467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasileios P, Styliani P, Nifon G, Pavlos S, Aris F, Ioannis P. Managing fibromyalgia with complementary and alternative medical exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Rheumatology International. 2022;42(11):1909&#x2013;1923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan J, Straus S, Moher D, et al. Reporting scoping reviews&#x2014;PRISMA ScR extension. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;123:177&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O'Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. International journal of social research methodology. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petticrew M, Roberts H. Systematic reviews in the social sciences: a practical guide. 1st ed. Blackwell Publishing; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock D, Peters MDJ, Khalil H, McInerney P, Alexander L, Tricco AC, et al. Recommendations for the extraction, analysis, and presentation of results in scoping reviews. JBI evidence synthesis. 2023;21(3):520&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36081365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areso-Boveda PB, Mambrillas-Varela J, Garcia-Gomez B, et al. Effectiveness of a group intervention using pain neuroscience education and exercise in women with fibromyalgia: a pragmatic controlled study in primary care. Article. Bmc Musculoskeletal Disorders. 2022 Apr;23(1):323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8978762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Medeiros SA, De Almeida Silva HJ, Do Nascimento RM, Da Silva Maia JB, De Almeida Lins CA, De Souza MC. Mat Pilates is as effective as aquatic aerobic exercise in treating women with fibromyalgia: a clinical, randomized and blind trial. Randomized Controlled Trial. Research Support, Non-U. S. Gov't. Advances in Rheumatology. 04 06. 2020;60(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32252822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericsson A, Bremell T, Cider A, Mannerkorpi K. Effects of exercise on fatigue and physical capacity in men with chronic widespread pain - a pilot study. BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2016;8(1):29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5011845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27602228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson A, Palstam A, L&#xf6;fgren M, et al. Resistance exercise improves muscle strength, health status and pain intensity in fibromyalgia-a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Res Ther. 2015;17(1):161&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin J, Torre F, Padierna A, et al. Six-and 12-month follow-up of an interdisciplinary fibromyalgia treatment programme: results of a randomised trial. Article. Clinical and Experimental Rheumatology. Nov-Dec. 2012;30(6):S103&#x2013;S111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23261008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Zahner L, Cornell M, et al. Benefit of Qigong Exercise in Patients With Fibromyalgia: A Pilot Study. Article. International Journal of Neuroscience. Nov. 2012;122(11):657&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22784212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento CVM, Moon S, Pfeifer T, et al. The therapeutic efficacy of Qigong exercise on the main symptoms of fibromyalgia: A pilot randomized clinical trial. Integrative Medicine Research. Dec. 2020;9(4):100416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrouva S, Sopidou V, Koutsioumpa E, et al. Can Exercise Affect the Pain Characteristics in Patients with Fibromyalgia?A Randomized Controlled Trial. Healthcare. Nov 30. 2022;10(12):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9778432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36553951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonell-Baeza A, Aparicio VA, Chillon P, Femia P, Delgado-Fernandez M, Ruiz JR. Effectiveness of multidisciplinary therapy on symptomatology and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia. Clinical Trial Comparative Study. Research Support, Non-U. S. Gov't. Clinical &amp;Experimental Rheumatology. Nov-Dec. 2011;29(6 Suppl 69):S97&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22243556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonell-Baeza A, Aparicio VA, Ortega FB, et al. Does a 3-month multidisciplinary intervention improve pain, body composition and physical fitness in women with fibromyalgia?Controlled Clinical Trial. Research Support, Non-U. S. Gov't. British Journal of Sports Medicine. Dec. 2011;45(15):1189&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20542976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latorre PA, Santos MA, Heredia-Jimenez JM, et al. Effect of a 24-week physical training programme (in water and on land) on pain, functional capacity, body composition and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia. Controlled Clinical Trial. Clinical &amp; Experimental Rheumatology. Nov-Dec. 2013;31(6 Suppl 79):S72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceballos-Laita L, Mingo-Gomez MT, Estebanez-de-Miguel E, et al. Does the Addition of Pain Neurophysiology Education to a Therapeutic Exercise Program Improve Physical Function in Women with Fibromyalgia Syndrome? Secondary Analysis of a Randomized Controlled Trial. Journal of Clinical Medicine. Jun 07. 2021;10(11):07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8201111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceballos-Laita L, Mingo-Gomez MT, Navas-Camara F, et al. Therapeutic Exercise and Pain Neurophysiology Education in Female Patients with Fibromyalgia Syndrome: A Feasibility Study. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2020;9(11):05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7694507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loftus N, Dobbin N, Crampton JS. The effects of a group exercise and education programme on symptoms and physical fitness in patients with fibromyalgia: a prospective observational cohort study. Disabil Rehabil. 2022;44(15):3860&#x2013;3867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redondo JR, Justo CM, Moraleda FV, et al. Long-term efficacy of therapy in patients with fibromyalgia: A physical exercise-based program and a cognitive-behavioral approach. Article. Arthritis &amp;Rheumatism-Arthritis Care &amp; Research. Apr. 2004;51(2):184&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltran-Carrillo VJ, Tortosa-Martinez J, Jennings G, Sanchez ES. Contributions of a group-based exercise program for coping with fibromyalgia: a qualitative study giving voice to female patients. Women &amp; Health. 2013;53(6):612&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23937732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciardi GB, Dorneles G, Pochmann D, Peres A, Elsner VR. Effects of Qigong practice in quality of life, fatigue, sleep, pain and epigenetic biomarkers in adult women with fibromyalgia. Article. Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2020;16(4):285&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosa-Reina MD, Nunez-Nagy S, Gallego-Izquierdo T, Pecos-Mart&#xed;n D, Monserrat J, &#xc1;lvarez-Mon M. Effectiveness of Therapeutic Exercise in Fibromyalgia Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Clinical Trials. Biomed Res Int 2017. 2017:2356346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5632473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29291206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones KD, Adams D, Winters-Stone K, Burckhardt CS. A comprehensive review of 46 exercise treatment studies in fibromyalgia (1988-2005) Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2006;4(1):67&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1590013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16999856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley JDP, McMillan VMD, Figueroa AMDP. The Effects of 12 Weeks of Resistance Exercise Training on Disease Severity and Autonomic Modulation at Rest and After Acute Leg Resistance Exercise in Women with Fibromyalgia. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010;91(10):1551&#x2013;1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20875513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panton LB, Kingsley JD, Toole T, et al. A Comparison of Physical Functional Performance and Strength in Women With Fibromyalgia, Age- and Weight-Matched Controls, and Older Women Who Are Healthy. Phys Ther. 2006;86(11):1479&#x2013;1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17079747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavi MBRO, Vassalo DV, Amaral FT, et al. Strengthening exercises improve symptoms and quality of life but do not change autonomic modulation in fibromyalgia: A randomized clinical trial. PLoS One. 2014;9(3):e90767&#x2013;e90767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24651512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fergusson D, Aaron SD, Guyatt G, H&#xe9;bert P. Post-randomisation exclusions: the intention to treat principle and excluding patients from analysis. BMJ. Sep 21. 2002;325(7365):652&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1124168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12242181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bee P, McBeth J, MacFarlane GJ, Lovell K. Managing chronic widespread pain in primary care: a qualitative study of patient perspectives and implications for treatment delivery. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders. 2016;17(1):354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4994227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27549811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson S, et al. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ (Online) 2021:374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>