<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41182078</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1527-6473</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Liver transplantation : official publication of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases and the International Liver Transplantation Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Liver Transpl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical exercise improves neurocognition in patients with metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/LVT.0000000000000767</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Physical exercise improves liver and body composition markers in metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease (MASLD), but its effects on cerebral hemodynamics and cognitive function in patients with MASLD remain unexplored. We aimed to evaluate the effect of a monitored 16-week exercise intervention on cerebral hemodynamics and cognitive function in patients with MASLD. In this randomized clinical trial, 40 obese patients with MASLD were randomized to either a control group (n=20) on a caloric restriction diet, or an intervention group (n=20) receiving diet plus exercise. The exercise intervention consisted of gradual increases in daily steps and resistance training. Both groups also received monthly classic literature readings to ensure comparable cognitive engagement throughout the study. Transcranial Doppler ultrasound and neurocognitive tests were assessed as primary outcomes. Secondary outcomes included body composition and liver disease parameters. Participants were 60% female, with a mean age of 47&#xb1;8 years. Intervention adherence was &gt;80%. Daily steps doubled in the intervention group (from 5178 to 10,161; p &lt;0.001) with no changes in controls. The intervention group showed an 8.4% reduction in peripheral arterial stiffness ( p =0.002), 10.4% reduction in resistance index ( p &lt;0.001), and 19.2% decrease in pulsatility index ( p &lt;0.001) with no significant changes in controls. Cognitive function improved in the intervention group, with a 5.9% increase in MoCA score ( p =0.005) and 6.6% increase in Addenbrooke score ( p &lt;0.001). Both groups showed a significant reduction in BMI and body fat percentage (-5.2% and 10.5% intervention, vs. -2.7% and 3.8% in controls). A structured, monitored exercise program improves cerebral hemodynamics, arterial stiffness, and cognitive function in patients with MASLD (NCT05520697).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rom&#xe1;n-Calleja</LastName><ForeName>Berenice Monserrat</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7624-9679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiz-Margain</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2779-8641</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duarte-Rojo</LastName><ForeName>Andres</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Northwestern Medicine, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flores-Silva</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Psychiatry, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez-Cabrera</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Fernando</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8517-0241</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Rosas</LastName><ForeName>Luis Enrique</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valencia-Pe&#xf1;a</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo Alfredo</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cant&#xfa;-Brito</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7494-2015</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Psychiatry, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chalasani</LastName><ForeName>Naga</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4082-3178</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Indiana University, Indianapolis, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguilar-Salinas</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Alberto</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo Ulises</ForeName><Initials>RU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7637-4477</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatology and Liver Transplant Division, Instituto Nacional de Ciencias M&#xe9;dicas y Nutrici&#xf3;n Salvador Zubir&#xe1;n, Mexico City, M&#xe9;xico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05520697</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Liver Transpl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1527-6465</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebral hemodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver steatosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41182078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/LVT.0000000000000767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01445473-990000000-00744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tacke F, Horn P, Wai-Sun Wong V, Ratziu V, Bugianesi E, Francque S, et al. EASL&#x2013;EASD&#x2013;EASO Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of metabolic dysfunction&#x2013;associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD). J Hepatol. 2024;81:492&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platek AE, Szymanska A. Metabolic dysfunction&#x2013;associated steatotic liver disease as a cardiovascular risk factor. Clin Exp Hepatol. 2023;9:187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollace R, Longo S, Nardin M, Tavernese A, Musolino V, Cardamone A, et al. Role of MASLD in CVD: A review of emerging treatment options. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2024;217:111891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazlauskaite R, Janssen I, Wilson RS, Appelhans BM, Evans DA, Arvanitakis Z, et al. Is midlife metabolic syndrome associated with cognitive function change? The study of women&#x2019;s health across the nation. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:E1093&#x2013;E1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooyens ACJ, Baan CA, Spijkerman AMW, Verschuren WMM. Type 2 diabetes and cognitive decline in middle-aged men and women: The Doetinchem Cohort Study. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:1964&#x2013;1969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Flores M, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a E, Cano-Nigenda C, Cant&#xfa;-Brito C. Relationship of obesity and insulin resistance with the cerebrovascular reactivity: A case control study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2014;13:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Julio D, Ram&#xed;rez-Mej&#xed;a MM, Cordova-Gallardo J, Peniche-Luna E, Cant&#xfa;-Brito C, Mendez-Sanchez N. From liver to brain: How MAFLD/MASLD impacts cognitive function. Med Sci Monit. 2024;30:e943417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff SC, Ockenga J, Eshraghian A, Barazzoni R, Busetto L, Campmans-Kuijpers M, et al. Practical guideline on obesity care in patients with gastrointestinal and liver diseases&#x2014;Joint ESPEN/UEG guideline. Clin Nutr. 2023;42:987&#x2013;1024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinella ME, Neuschwander-Tetri BA, Siddiqui MS, Abdelmalek MF, Caldwell S, Barb D, et al. AASLD Practice Guidance on the clinical assessment and management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2023;77:1797&#x2013;1835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Schreibman IR, Faust AJ, Dahmus J, Stern B, Soriano C, et al. NASHFit: A randomized controlled trial of an exercise training program to reduce clotting risk in patients with NASH. Hepatology. 2022;76:172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Dijoseph K, Pattison Z, Harrington A, Chinchilli VM, Schmitz KH, et al. Exercise training is associated with treatment response in liver fat content by magnetic resonance imaging independent of clinically significant body weight loss in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2023;118:1204&#x2013;1213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris SJ, Smith N, Hummer B, Schreibman IR, Faust AJ, Geyer NR, et al. Exercise training improves serum biomarkers of liver fibroinflammation in patients with metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis. Liver Int. 2024;44:532&#x2013;540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez RU, Ruiz-Marg&#xe1;in A, Rom&#xe1;n-Calleja B, Cant&#xfa;-Brito C, Flores-Silva F, Gabutti-Thomas A, et al. Effect of a monitored exercise protocol in cerebral and hepatic hemodynamics in patients with cirrhosis and portal hypertension. Dig Liver Dis. 2024;56:827&#x2013;835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun R, Ge B, Wu S, Li H, Lin L. Optimal cut-off MoCA score for screening for mild cognitive impairment in elderly individuals in China: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Asian J Psychiatr. 2023;87:103691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beishon LC, Batterham AP, Quinn TJ, Nelson CP, Panerai RB, Robinson T, et al. Addenbrooke&#x2019;s Cognitive Examination III (ACE-III) and mini-ACE for the detection of dementia and mild cognitive impairment. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;2019:CD013282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamatsu Y, Kusakabe T, Arai H, Yamamoto Y, Nakao K, Ikeue K, et al. Phase angle from bioelectrical impedance analysis is a useful indicator of muscle quality. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:180&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-G&#xf3;mez M, Escalada J, Noguerol M, P&#xe9;rez A, Carretero J, Crespo J, et al. Gu&#xed;a de pr&#xe1;ctica cl&#xed;nica multidisciplinar de manejo de la esteatosis hep&#xe1;tica metab&#xf3;lica. Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2025;48:502442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan WK, Chuah KH, Rajaram RB, Lim LL, Ratnasingam J, Vethakkan SR. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD): A state-of-the-art review. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2023;32:197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan N, Yki-J&#xe4;rvinen H, Neuschwander-Tetri BA. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease: Heterogeneous pathomechanisms and effectiveness of metabolism-based treatment. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2025;13:134&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Windt DJ, Sud V, Zhang H, Tsung A, Huang H. The effects of physical exercise on fatty liver disease. Gene Expr. 2018;18:89&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Wu S, Gao J, Zhang Y, Zuo Y, Tian X, et al. Association of stroke with metabolic dysfunction&#x2013;associated fatty liver disease with and without CKD. Am J Kidney Dis. 2024;83:477&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers M, Lemstra M, Bird Y, Nwankwo C, Moraros J. Weight loss intervention adherence and factors promoting adherence: A meta-analysis. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2016;10:1547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tincopa MA, Lyden A, Wong J, Jackson EA, Richardson C, Lok AS. Impact of a pilot structured mobile technology based lifestyle intervention for patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Dig Dis Sci. 2022;67:481&#x2013;491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Rivas G, Hummer B, Duarte-Rojo A, May CN, Geyer N, et al. Mobile health lifestyle intervention program leads to clinically significant loss of body weight in patients with NASH. Hepatol Commun. 2023;7:e0052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celikbilek A, Celikbilek M, Bozkurt G. Cognitive assessment of patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;30:944&#x2013;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein G, Davis-Plourde K, Himali JJ, Zelber-Sagi S, Beiser AS, Seshadri S. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, liver fibrosis score and cognitive function in middle-aged adults: The Framingham Study. Liver Int. 2019;39:1713&#x2013;1721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuttolomondo A, Petta S, Casuccio A, Maida C, Corte VD, Daidone M, et al. Reactive hyperemia index (RHI) and cognitive performance indexes are associated with histologic markers of liver disease in subjects with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD): A case control study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2018;17:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez RU, Ruiz-Marg&#xe1;in A, Cant&#xfa;-Brito C, Flores-Silva DF, Garc&#xed;a-Flores OR, Cubero FJ, et al. Changes in cerebral hemodynamics in patients with cirrhosis after liver transplantation. Liver Transpl. 2018;24:1673&#x2013;1679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Xu L, Zheng X, Gu C, Zhou X, Sun Y, et al. Association of pulsatility index with total burden of cerebral small vessel disease and cognitive impairment. Brain Behav. 2024;14:e3526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim EY, Yang DW, Cho AH, Shim YS. Cerebrovascular hemodynamics on transcranial Doppler ultrasonography and cognitive decline in mild cognitive impairment. J Alzheimers Dis. 2018;65:651&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemilar M, Partovi A, Forghani N, Sharifipour E. Comparison of transcranial Doppler ultrasound indices in large and small vessel disease cerebral infarction. Curr J Neurol. 2021;20:229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akazawa N, Tanahashi K, Kosaki K, Ra SG, Matsubara T, Choi Y, et al. Aerobic exercise training enhances cerebrovascular pulsatility response to acute aerobic exercise in older adults. Physiol Rep. 2018;6:e13681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Sechi LA, Navarese EP, Casu G, Vidili G. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease and cardiovascular risk: A comprehensive review. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23:346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhurandhar Y, Tomar S, Das A, Prajapati JL, Singh AP, Bodake SH, et al. Chronic inflammation in obesity and neurodegenerative diseases: Exploring the link in disease onset and progression. Mol Biol Rep. 2025;52:424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Assar M, &#xc1;lvarez-Bustos A, Sosa P, Angulo J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Ma&#xf1;as L. Effect of physical activity/exercise on oxidative stress and inflammation in muscle and vascular aging. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:8713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge X, Wang X, Yan Y, Zhang L, Yu C, Lu J, et al. Behavioural activity pattern, genetic factors, and the risk of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A prospective study in the UK Biobank. Liver Int. 2023;43:1287&#x2013;1297.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>