<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41530375</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-time breath analysis for COPD risk assessment in smokers using a ZnO/SnO&#x2082; heterojunction sensor integrated with support vector machine.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5100</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5100</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35583-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a progressively debilitating and life-threatening respiratory condition that has long been attributed to exposure to airborne toxic substances like carbon monoxide (CO), a reliable biomarker of oxidative stress, especially in smoking individuals. To address the need for a real-time and non-invasive method that can detect this life-threatening condition, a wearable diagnostic device is developed in this work based on a Z/S heterostructure thin-film gas sensor that can detect exhaled CO at a temperature as low as 37 &#xb0;C. This gas sensor was prepared using a hydrothermal synthesis route and characterized by various techniques like X-ray diffraction (XRD), Field Emission Scanning Electron Microscopy (FESEM), and Energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), and packed in a face mask design that enables continuous sampling of breath. Of all the sensing devices prepared with varying concentrations of the active components ZnO (Z), SnO&#x2082; (S), and the combination of both (Z/S), the Z/S structure showed maximum sensitivity with a sensitivity of 264.29% at 12 parts per million (ppm), a response time of 14 seconds, and a recovery time of 3 seconds. The incorporation of a polymer layer of poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene): poly(styrenesulfonate) (PEDOT: PSS) improved the charge carrier mobility through p-n junction formation. A customized gas sensing laboratory chamber enabled accurate calibrations of CO sensing. To derive actual CO levels from the resistance changes in the sensor, a power-law model was used. To classify patient groups further as current smokers, ex-smokers, and non-smokers accurately, a support vector machine (SVM) classification with a training accuracy of 94.2% and testing accuracy of 81.7% was used in this work. By integrating nanostructured gas sensors with wearable technology design concepts and ML diagnostics in a seamless Internet of Things (IoT) network, this scientific development will allow early diagnosis of the life-threatening condition of COPD in a completely non-invasive and non-destructive fashion with high portability. This developed device has unending possibilities in taking up roles in individualized breath medical care and represents a significant milestone in translating on-body disease detection using sensor technology.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chellamuthu</LastName><ForeName>Poundoss</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Energy Systems, Chennai Institute of Technology, Chennai, 600069, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savarimuthu</LastName><ForeName>Kirubaveni</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, College of Engineering, Anna University, Guindy, Chennai, 600025, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsath</LastName><ForeName>M Gulam Nabi</ForeName><Initials>MGN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, College of Engineering, Anna University, Guindy, Chennai, 600025, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishnamoorthy</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Advanced Wireless Integrated Technology, Chennai Institute of Technology, Chennai, 600069, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuvaraj</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Energy Systems, Chennai Institute of Technology, Chennai, 600069, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bajaj</LastName><ForeName>Mohit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Dehradun, 248002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hourani Center for Applied Scientific Research, Al-Ahliyya Amman University, Amman, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, University of Business and Technology, Jeddah, 21448, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabaz</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marwadi University Research Center, Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering and Technology, Marwadi University, Rajkot, 360003, Gujarat, India. bhatsab4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breath analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COPD detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon monoxide sensor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gas sensor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internet of things</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metal oxide heterojunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Support vector machine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interest: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics: The study was approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee, Department of Biomedical Engineering, [Chennai Institute of Technology, Chennai-600069, Tamilnadu, India], under protocol number BME/ECC/2025/00-11, dated 18 June 2025. All research procedures were performed in line with applicable national regulations and the ethical principles described in the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) guidelines for biomedical and health research involving human participants, as well as the Declaration of Helsinki.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41530375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12876945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35583-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35583-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Moger, T. A. et al. Associations between outpatient care and later hospital admissions for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease-a registry study from Norway. <i>BMC Health Serv. Res.</i><b>24</b>(1), 500 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-10975-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11036724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38649963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease across three decades: trends, inequalities, and projections from the global burden of disease study 2021. <i>Front. Med.</i><b>12</b>, 1564878 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1564878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11973060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40196348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Global, regional, and national burden of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and its attributable risk factors from 1990 to 2021: an analysis for the global burden of disease study 2021. <i>Respir. Res.</i><b>26</b>(1), 2 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-024-03051-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11697803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39748260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moger, T. A. et al. The in-and outpatient health care use of patients with COPD before and after initiation of home care: a registry study from Norway. <i>Scand. J. Prim. Health Care</i><b>43</b>(1), 100&#x2013;110 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02813432.2024.2404056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11834786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39282877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronesi, A. et al. Use of carboxyhemoglobin as a biomarker of environmental CO exposure: critical evaluation of the literature. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>24</b>(33), 25798&#x2013;25809 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-017-0270-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29027621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida, K. et al. Updip fluid flow in the crust of the northeastern Noto Peninsula, Japan, triggered the 2023 Mw 6.2 Suzu earthquake during swarm activity. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>50</b>(21), e2023GL106023 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023GL106023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callej&#xf3;n-Leblic, B. et al. Metallomic signatures of lung cancer and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. <i>Int. J. Mol. Sci.</i><b>24</b>(18), 14250 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241814250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10532173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37762552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa, J.V., Branco, P.T., Alvim-Ferraz, M.C., Martins, F.G. and Sousa, S.I., Firefighters&#x2019; occupational exposure to air pollution: impact on COPD and asthma-study protocol. <i>BMJ Open Respiratory Research</i>. 11(1). (2024). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11580236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39572082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C., Feng, W., Yang, X. &amp; Ullah, A. Mach-Zehnder carbon monoxide gas sensor based on tin dioxide coated endlessly single-mode photonic crystal fiber. <i>Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Naturforschung A</i><b>80</b>(2), 81&#x2013;87 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/zna-2024-0202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuperus, L. J., et al Wearable technology for detection of COPD exacerbations: feasibility of the Health Patch. <i>ERJ Open Research</i><i>10</i>(6) (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11587165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39588079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W., Li, Q., Xu, L. &amp; Zeng, W. Gas sensing properties of ZnO-SnO<sub>2</sub> nanostructures. <i>J. Nanosci. Nanotechnol.</i><b>15</b>(2), 1245&#x2013;1252 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1166/jnn.2015.9061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26353640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chellamuthu, P., Savarimuthu, K., Mohammed, G. N. A. &amp; Arumugam, T. Synthesis and fabrication of semiconductor nanoparticles with surfactant-mixed metal oxides for humidity sensing in respiratory monitoring devices. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>74</b>, 1&#x2013;8 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, S. et al. Performance of machine learning models for predicting high-severity symptoms in multiple sclerosis. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 1&#x2013;12 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-63888-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12104369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40414922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejazi, M. A. et al. Correlation of exhaled carbon monoxide level with disease severity in chronic obstruction pulmonary disease. <i>Lung India</i><b>35</b>(5), 401&#x2013;406 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/lungindia.lungindia_11_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30168459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, B. D. &amp; Whichelow, M. J. Carbon monoxide levels in the breath of smokers and nonsmokers: effect of domestic heating systems. <i>J. Epidemiol. &amp; Community Health</i><b>39</b>(1), 75&#x2013;78 (1985).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech.39.1.75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1052406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3989439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst, J. R. et al. Understanding the impact of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbations on patient health and quality of life. <i>Euro. J. Intern. Med.</i><b>73</b>, 1&#x2013;6 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2019.12.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesler, P. et al. Nanostructured SnO<sub>2</sub>-ZnO composite gas sensors for selective detection of carbon monoxide. <i>Beilstein J. Nanotechnol.</i><b>7</b>, 2045&#x2013;2056 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3762/bjnano.7.195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5238679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28144552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pineda-Reyes, A. M., Herrera-Rivera, M. R., Rojas-Ch&#xe1;vez, H., Cruz-Mart&#xed;nez, H. &amp; Medina, D. I. Recent advances in ZnO-based carbon monoxide sensors: role of doping. <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b>(13), 4425 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21134425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. &amp; Jiao, M. A Mini-review on metal oxide semiconductor gas sensors for carbon monoxide detection at room temperature. <i>Chemosensors</i><b>12</b>(4), 55 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/chemosensors12040055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ani, A. et al. Evaluation of spray pyrolysed In: ZnO nanostructures for CO gas sensing at low concentration. <i>J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron.</i><b>32</b>(17), 22599&#x2013;22616 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranthady, C., Shanbhag, G. V. &amp; Sundaram, N. G. Polyaniline/(Ta<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>-SnO<sub>2</sub>) hybrid nanocomposite for efficient room temperature CO gas sensing. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>12</b>(25), 15759&#x2013;15766 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2RA00602B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35685707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari, M. K. et al. Enhancement of CO gas sensing performance by Mn-doped porous ZnSnO<sub>3</sub> microspheres. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>12</b>(50), 32249&#x2013;32261 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2RA06785D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36425716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayed, M. H. et al. Enhanced gas sensing performance of sprayed ZnO&#x2013;ZnWO<sub>4</sub> toward CO gas. <i>Mater. Adv.</i><b>5</b>(12), 5140&#x2013;5147 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4MA00121D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, L. et al. Hydrothermal synthesis and structures of unknown intermediate phase Zn (HCO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> H<sub>2</sub>O nanoflakes and final ZnO nanorods. <i>Inorg. Chemi.</i><b>61</b>(5), 2669&#x2013;2678 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.inorgchem.1c03810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35073051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidi, M., Abrari, M. &amp; Ahmadi, M. Fabrication of dye-sensitized solar cell based on mixed tin and zinc oxide nanoparticles. <i>Appl. Phys. A</i><b>125</b>(6), 409 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00339-019-2697-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. S. &amp; Ahmed, S. Easy and green synthesis of TiO<sub>2</sub> (Anatase and Rutile): estimation of crystallite size using scherrer equation, williamson-hall plot, monshi-scherrer model, size-strain plot, halder-wagner model. <i>Results Mater</i><b>20</b>, 100492 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinma.2023.100492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gultepe, O., Atay, F. &amp; Dikmen, Z. Hydrothermal synthesis of ZnO nanostructures for environmental applications: the role of different supporting ligands. <i>Appl. Phys. A</i><b>129</b>(8), 586 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00339-023-06859-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatimah, I. et al. Synthesis and control of the morphology of SnO2 nanoparticles via various concentrations of tinospora cordifolia stem extract and reduction methods. <i>Arab. J. Chem.</i><b>15</b>(4), 103738 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2022.103738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Synthesis of SnO<sub>2</sub>/ZnO flowerlike composites photocatalyst for enhanced photocatalytic degradation of malachite green. <i>Optical Mater.</i><b>133</b>, 112978 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optmat.2022.112978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng, S., Zhao, M. &amp; Jiang, D. Preparation and performance enhancement study of organic ZnO/Au/PEDOT: PSS heterojunction UV photodetector. <i>J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron.</i><b>33</b>(8), 5161&#x2013;5173 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karmouch, R. et al. PEDOT: PSS/ZnO heterojunctions: resistive switching behavior in memory devices. <i>J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron.</i><b>36</b>(2), 165 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, Z. &amp; Sayyad, M. H. Electrical characteristics of a high rectification ratio organic Schottky diode based on methyl red. <i>Optoelectron. Adv. Mater.-Rapid Commun.</i><b>3</b>(5), 509&#x2013;512 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binowesley, R., Savarimuthu, K. &amp; Emimal, M. Comparative performance analysis of mixed metal oxide sensors for dual-sensing leveraging machine learning. <i>Nanotechnology</i><b>36</b>(9), 095501 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-6528/ad947e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39569864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhusari, R., Thomann, J. S., Guillot, J. &amp; Leturcq, R. Oxygen adsorption and desorption kinetics in CuO nanowire bundle networks: Implications for MOx-based gas sensors. <i>ACS Appl. Nano Mater.</i><b>5</b>(8), 10248&#x2013;10257 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsanm.2c01245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y. H. et al. Stepwise emergence of CO gas sensing response and selectivity on SnO<sub>2</sub> using C supports and PtOx decoration. <i>Front. Chem.</i><b>12</b>, 1469520 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2024.1469520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11484019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39421607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DS, A.K., Chauhan, S.S., Bharathi, K.D., Ravikumar, A. and Rahman, M.R., Flexible and cost effective CNT coated cotton fabric for CO gas sensing application. <i>Sensors and Actuators A: Physical</i>. 362, 114640. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery, D. C., Peck, E. A. &amp; Vining, G. G. <i>Introduction to linear regression analysis</i> (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawad, M. H. M. A., Morsi, M. G. &amp; Fayiad, H. Role of exhaled carbon monoxide in assessment of chronic obstructive airway disease severity. <i>Egypt. J. Bronchol.</i><b>18</b>(1), 41 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43168-024-00295-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsan, N. &amp; Weimar, U. D. O. Conduction model of metal oxide gas sensors. <i>J. Electroceramics</i><b>7</b>(3), 143&#x2013;167 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1014405811371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsan, N. &amp; Weimar, U. Understanding the fundamental principles of metal oxide based gas sensors; the example of CO sensing with SnO<sub>2</sub> sensors in the presence of humidity. <i>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter</i><b>15</b>(20), R813 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, A. et al. The human volatilome: volatile organic compounds (VOCs) in exhaled breath, skin emanations, urine, feces and saliva. <i>J. Breath Res.</i><b>8</b>(3), 034001 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1752-7155/8/3/034001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24946087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J. et al. Formaldehyde gas response and selectivity of ZnO-SnO<sub>2</sub> gas sensors. <i>Sens. Actuators B: Chem.</i><b>425</b>, 136958 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2024.136958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, Y. M. et al. Enhancing selectivity and sensitivity in gas sensors through noble metal-decorated ZnO and machine learning. <i>Appl. Surf. Sci.</i><b>693</b>, 162750 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J., Li, H., Cheng, J., Ma, X. &amp; Fu, Y. Advances in metal oxide semiconductor gas sensor arrays based on machine learning algorithms. <i>J. Mater. Chem. C</i><b>13</b>(9), 4285&#x2013;4303 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4TC05220J</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek, J. W. et al. Present and future of emerging catalysts in gas sensors for breath analysis. <i>ACS Sens.</i><b>10</b>(1), 33&#x2013;53 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssensors.4c02464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39587394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, M. et al. Humidity compensation based on power-law response for MOS sensors to VOCs. <i>Sens. Actuators B: Chem.</i><b>334</b>, 129601 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2021.129601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VA, B., Subramoniam, M. and Mathew, L., Noninvasive detection of COPD and Lung Cancer through breath analysis using MOS Sensor array based e-nose. <i>Expert review of molecular diagnostics</i>. 21(11), 1223-1233. (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34415806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binson, V. A., Subramoniam, M. &amp; Mathew, L. Discrimination of COPD and lung cancer from controls through breath analysis using a self-developed e-nose. <i>J. Breath Res.</i><b>15</b>(4), 046003 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1752-7163/ac1326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34243176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drera, G. et al. Exploring the performance of a functionalized CNT-based sensor array for breathomics through clustering and classification algorithms: from gas sensing of selective biomarkers to discrimination of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>11</b>(48), 30270&#x2013;30282 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1RA03337A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9041100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35480252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Aguilar, M. et al. Identification of breath-prints for the COPD detection associated with smoking and household air pollution by electronic nose. <i>Respir. Med.</i><b>163</b>, 105901 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2020.105901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32125969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>