<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41160036</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predicting a Successful Attempt in Raw Powerlifting. A Nonlinear Mixed Logistic Regression Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e138</StartPage><EndPage>e146</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e138-e146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005276</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Darragh, IAJ, Egan, B, Nolan, D, and Bennett, KE. Predicting a successful attempt in raw powerlifting. A nonlinear mixed logistic regression analysis. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): e138-e146, 2026-This study aimed to predict successful lift attempts in raw powerlifting by examining the influence of jump size (the absolute difference in weight between consecutive attempts) and other factors, using a logistic regression model with nonlinear splines. Data from 93,333 lifters (62,679 males, 30,654 females) across 6,979 International Powerlifting Federation competitions were analyzed. The data set was partitioned into training (80%) and test (20%) sets, with sex-specific models developed to account for class imbalance. Predictors included jump size, lift type (squat, bench press, deadlift), attempt transition (first-to-second or second-to-third), and covariates such as body mass, age, and opening attempt weight. Random effects for lifter identity were included to control for individual performance variability. Significance was set at p &lt; 0.05. Results revealed that jump size significantly influenced success rates, with effects varying by lift type, attempt transition, and sex. For male lifters, moderate jump sizes (5-20 kg) improved squat and deadlift success, but success declined with jumps &gt;20 kg, especially on third attempts. Bench press success increased slightly with jump sizes &lt;10 kg but dropped sharply beyond that-more so in third attempts. For female lifters, squat success improved only with small jumps (&#x2264;8 kg); jumps &gt;10 kg significantly reduced success, particularly on third attempts. In the bench press, female lifters showed an almost linear decline in success with increasing jump size on second attempts, with third-attempt success decreasing sharply beyond 4 kg. Female deadlift success followed a similar pattern to squats but showed slightly greater tolerance, with optimal jumps approximately 9-11 kg. In both sexes, third attempts consistently had lower success rates than second attempts. These findings highlight the nuanced role of jump size in attempt success and provide actionable insights for competition strategy. Coaches and lifters can use these results to optimize attempt selection, particularly in balancing risk and reward across attempts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darragh</LastName><ForeName>Ian A J</ForeName><Initials>IAJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Population Health, RCSI University of Medicine and Health Sciences Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egan</LastName><ForeName>Brendan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florida Institute for Human &amp; Machine Cognition, Pensacola, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nolan</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Population Health, RCSI University of Medicine and Health Sciences Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beaumont RCSI Cancer Centre, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016015" MajorTopicYN="N">Logistic Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competition performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lift success</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight selection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41160036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Statistics notes. The odds ratio. BMJ 320: 1468, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks ME, Kristensen K, Benthem KV, et al. glmmTMB balances speed and flexibility among packages for zero-inflated generalized linear mixed modeling. R J 9: 378&#x2013;400, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coker NA, Varanoske AN, Baker KM, Hahs-Vaughn DL, Wells AJ. Predictors of competitive success of national-level powerlifters: A multilevel analysis. Int J Perform Anal Sport 18: 796&#x2013;805, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferland P-M, Comtois AS. Classic powerlifting performance: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 33: S194&#x2013;S201, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton EN, Lundberg TR. Transgender women in the female category of sport: Perspectives on testosterone suppression and performance advantage. Sports Med 51: 199&#x2013;214, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Powerlifting Federation. International Powerlifting Federation rulebook. 2024. Available at: https://www.powerlifting.sport/fileadmin/ipf/data/rules/technical-rules/english/IPF_Technical_Rules_Book_2024_24_Jan.pdf . Accessed December 12, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, Wang Z, Ross R. Skeletal muscle mass and distribution in 468 men and women aged 18&#x2013;88 yr. J Appl Physiol 89: 81&#x2013;88, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jokipalo I, Khudayarov A. A netnography and a survey on doping use among competitive doping-untested strength-sport athletes. Int J Sports Med 42: 645&#x2013;650, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Van Den Hoek D, Teo W-P. Factors affecting powerlifting performance: An analysis of age- and weight-based determinants of relative strength. Int J Perform Anal Sport 18: 532&#x2013;544, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RC, Wang Z, Heo M, Ross R, Janssen I, Heymsfield SB. Total-body skeletal muscle mass: Development and cross-validation of anthropometric prediction models. Am J Clin Nutr 72: 796&#x2013;803, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mausehund L, Krosshaug T. Understanding bench press biomechanics&#x2014;Training expertise and sex affect lifting technique and net joint moments. J Strength Cond Res 37: 9&#x2013;17, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oommen T, Baise LG, Vogel RM. Sampling bias and class imbalance in maximum-likelihood logistic regression. Math Geosci 43: 99&#x2013;120, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenPowerlifting. OpenPowerlifting.org. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard HJ, Morton RH. Powerlifting: Success and failure at the 2012 and 2013 Oceania and classic world championships. J Aust Strength Cond 23: 67&#x2013;70, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, 2021. Available at: https://www.R-project.org/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd J, Morais DG, Pollack B, Todd T. A historical analysis of the use of supportive apparel in powerlifting. Iron Game Hist 13: 37&#x2013;56, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis SK, Zourdos MC, Bazyler CD. Weight selection attempts of elite classic powerlifters. Percept Mot Skills 128: 507&#x2013;521, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Hoek DJ, Owen PJ, Garrett JM, et al. What are the odds? Identifying factors related to competitive success in powerlifting. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 14: 110, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Hoek D, Garrett J, Travis SK, et al. Analysis of competition performance leading to success at the international powerlifting federation world championships between 2013 and 2019. J Strength Cond Res 37: e555&#x2013;e562, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasdekis VGS, Vlachonikolis IG. On the difference between ML and REML estimators in the modelling of multivariate longitudinal data. J Stat Plann Inference 134: 194&#x2013;205, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warpeha J. A history of Powerlifiting the United States: 50 years after York, 2015. Available at: https://www.usaplmn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/History-of-Powerlifting-Warpeha-9-4-15.pdf . Accessed December 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>