<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41678801</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Uniform Neuromuscular Responses Across Varied Blood Flow Restriction Training Strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>304</StartPage><EndPage>310</EndPage><MedlinePgn>304-310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005311</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Howard, MA, Rivera, PM, Lubiak, SM, Proppe, CE, Schmidt, JT, Rolnick, N, Shobe, ED, Fraifer, TL, and Hill, EC. Uniform neuromuscular responses across varied blood flow restriction training strategies. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): 304-310, 2026-The purpose of this investigation was to assess neuromuscular responses during acute bouts of resistance exercise with low-load blood flow restriction (LLBFR) performed with a 75-repetition protocol (75-rep; 1 &#xd7; 30, 3 &#xd7; 15), 3 sets to failure (3&#xd7;), and 1 set to failure (1&#xd7;). Seventeen recreationally active females randomly completed 75-rep, 3&#xd7;, and 1&#xd7; protocols consisting of unilateral, submaximal (30% of maximal voluntary isometric contraction), isokinetic (90&#xb0;&#xb7;s -1 ), leg extension muscle actions. A greater number of repetitions were performed during set 1 of the 1&#xd7; protocol (59.5 &#xb1; 35.1) compared with the 75-rep protocol (30.0 &#xb1; 0.0), and more total repetitions were performed in the 3&#xd7; protocol (85.2 &#xb1; 42.2) compared with the 1&#xd7; protocol (59.5 &#xb1; 35.1). Surface electromyographic (sEMG) amplitude (AMP) progressively increased and then plateaued after 2 sets for the 75-rep protocol (118.3 &#xb1; 31.4% to 185.9 &#xb1; 85.3%; p = 0.043) and after 1 set of the 3&#xd7; protocol (119.6 &#xb1; 8.6% to 206.3 &#xb1; 84.1%; p = 0.003). In addition, sEMG mean power frequency (MPF) decreased and then plateaued after 3 sets of the 75-rep protocol (99.8 &#xb1; 3.5% to 88.8 &#xb1; 11.7%; p = 0.012) and after 1 set of the 3&#xd7; protocol (101.0 &#xb1; 8.2% to 84.4 &#xb1; 18.9%; p &lt; 0.001). The changes in sEMG AMP and sEMG MPF across multiple sets (i.e., 75-rep and 3&#xd7;) never exceeded the changes observed after the 1&#xd7; protocol. Despite variations in set and repetition schemes, performing just 1 set of LLBFR to failure was sufficient to maximize acute neuromuscular responses. This highlights the efficiency of a single-set LLBFR protocol as a time-effective option for athletes and practitioners.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howard</LastName><ForeName>Mason A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Paola M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Science, Cummings School of Nursing &amp; Health Sciences, Endicott College, Beverly, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lubiak</LastName><ForeName>Sean M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Proppe</LastName><ForeName>Christopher E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory, Department of Human Performance Studies, Wichita State University, Wichita, Kansas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmidt</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AdventHealth Sports Med &amp; Rehab, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rolnick</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The BFR PROS, New York City, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Human Performance Mechanic, New York City, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shobe</LastName><ForeName>Ezra D</ForeName><Initials>ED</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fraifer</LastName><ForeName>Thaila L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Ethan C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5573-3370</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology &amp; Rehabilitation Sciences, Division of Kinesiology, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BFR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusion</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41678801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baguet A, Reyngoudt H, Pottier A, et al. Carnosine loading and washout in human skeletal muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985) 106: 837&#x2013;842, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basmajian J, De Luca C. Description and analysis of EMG signals. In: Muscles Alive: Their Functions Revealed by Electromyography. Butler J, ed. (5th ed). Baltimore, MD: Williams &amp; Wilkins, 1985. pp. 65&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 49: 95&#x2013;108, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira MS, Pereira R, Rocha T, et al. Time to failure and neuromuscular response to intermittent isometric exercise at different levels of vascular occlusion: A randomized crossover study. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol 6: 55&#x2013;70, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colenso-Semple LM, D'Souza AC, Elliott-Sale KJ, Phillips SM. Current evidence shows no influence of women's menstrual cycle phase on acute strength performance or adaptations to resistance exercise training. Front Sports Act Living 5: 1054542, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Murphy BG, Labarbera KE. Neuromuscular function after a bout of low-load blood flow&#x2013;restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 67&#x2013;74, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts BR, Dankel SJ, Barnett BE, et al. Influence of relative blood flow restriction pressure on muscle activation and muscle adaptation. Muscle Nerve 53: 438&#x2013;445, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts BR, Rossow LM, Mattocks KT, et al. Let's talk about sex: Where are the young females in blood flow restriction research? Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 38: 1&#x2013;3, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, LeFever RS, McCue MP, Xenakis AP. Behaviour of human motor units in different muscles during linearly varying contractions. J Physiol 329: 113&#x2013;128, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards RH. Human muscle function and fatigue. In: Human Muscle Fatigue: Physiological Mechanisms. Ciba Foundation Symposium 82. Porter R, Whelan J, eds. London, United Kingdom: Pitman Medical, 1981. pp. 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, et al. Muscular adaptations to fatiguing exercise with and without blood flow restriction. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 167&#x2013;176, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatela P, Mendonca GV, Veloso AP, Avela J, Mil-Homens P. Blood flow restriction alters motor unit behavior during resistance exercise. Int J Sports Med 40: 555&#x2013;562, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatela P, Reis JF, Mendonca GV, Avela J, Mil-Homens P. Acute effects of exercise under different levels of blood-flow restriction on muscle activation and fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 985&#x2013;995, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune E, Lowery MM. Effect of extracellular potassium accumulation on muscle fiber conduction velocity: A simulation study. Ann Biomed Eng 37: 2105&#x2013;2117, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukunaga T, Ichinose Y, Ito M, Kawakami Y, Fukashiro S. Determination of fascicle length and pennation in a contracting human muscle in vivo. J Appl Physiol 82: 354&#x2013;358, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan G, Cotter JA, Reuland W, et al. Effect of blood flow restriction on tissue oxygenation during knee extension. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 185&#x2013;193, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray SM, Cuomo AM, Proppe CE, et al. Effects of sex and cuff pressure on physiological responses during blood flow restriction resistance exercise in young adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 920&#x2013;931, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heald DE. Influence of ammonium ions on mechanical and electrophysiological responses of skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol 229: 1174&#x2013;1179, 1975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 10: 361&#x2013;374, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline JC, De Luca CJ. Synchronization of motor unit firings: An epiphenomenon of firing rate characteristics not common inputs. J Neurophysiol 115: 178&#x2013;192, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labarbera KE, Murphy BG, Laroche DP, Cook SB. Sex differences in blood flow restricted isotonic knee extensions to fatigue. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 53: 444&#x2013;452, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius TR, Scheuermann BW. Acute neuromuscular and microvascular responses to concentric and eccentric exercises with blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2725&#x2013;2733, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Wilson JM, Bemben MG. Blood flow restriction: The metabolite/volume threshold theory. Med Hypotheses 77: 748&#x2013;752, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maclaren DP, Gibson H, Parry-Billings M, Edwards RH. A review of metabolic and physiological factors in fatigue. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 17: 29&#x2013;66, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty KL, Elliott-Sale KJ, Dolan E, et al. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on exercise performance in eumenorrheic women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 50: 1813&#x2013;1827, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merletti R, Knaflitz M, De Luca CJ. Myoelectric manifestations of fatigue in voluntary and electrically elicited contractions. J Appl Physiol 69: 1810&#x2013;1820, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Muro M. Motor unit activity and surface electromyogram power spectrum during increasing force of contraction. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 56: 260&#x2013;265, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol 10: 533, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proppe CE, Aldeghi TM, Rivera PM, Gonzalez-Rojas DH, Hill EC. Neuromuscular responses to failure vs non-failure during blood flow restriction training in untrained females. Int J Exerc Sci 16: 293&#x2013;303, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Persky AM, Price TB, Clarkson PM. Effects of repeated creatine supplementation on muscle, plasma, and urine creatine levels. J Strength Cond Res 18: 162&#x2013;167, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera PM, Hill EC, Proppe CE, Beltran E. Acute effects of fatiguing low-load leg extension muscle actions on maximal strength and neuromuscular function. J Sci Sport Exerc 6: 14&#x2013;21, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolnick N, de Queiros VS, Hill EC, et al. Does protocol matter for repetition volume? A meta-analytic investigation of volitional failure versus the traditionally used 75-repetition blood flow restriction resistance training. Sports Med Open 11: 84, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadoyama T, Masuda T, Miyano H. Relationships between muscle fibre conduction velocity and frequency parameters of surface EMG during sustained contraction. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 51: 247&#x2013;256, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Dose effect on intramuscular metabolic stress during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol 108: 1563&#x2013;1567, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol 8: 985, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir JP. Quantifying test-retest reliability using the intraclass correlation coefficient and the SEM. J Strength Cond Res 19: 231&#x2013;240, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, et al. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J Sports Sci 27: 479&#x2013;489, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>