<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41673572</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SOCAV, a nurse-led program promoting self-direction in nursing homes: a longitudinal mixed-methods pilot study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-026-07100-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study evaluates the impact of the SOCAV program on promoting self-direction of individuals with dementia in nursing homes and examines the behavioral changes in care staff when trained and coached to implement the program. SOCAV is a longitudinal training and coaching intervention designed to enhance person-centered care and support self-direction in individuals with dementia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This mixed-methods longitudinal pilot study was conducted in two long-term care units and one day activity center of a nursing home. Participants included 61 individuals with dementia, 48 caregivers, and 85 care staff members. Qualitative data were collected from reflective coaching diaries, while quantitative data were gathered using the Canadian Occupational Performance Measure (COPM) from the perspectives of individuals with dementia, their caregivers, and care staff.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thematic analysis revealed four positive changes in care staff: acceptance of reflective coaching, focus on self-direction, improvement in communication and interaction, and enhanced team collaboration. Statistically significant improvements in COPM performance and satisfaction were observed in individuals with dementia, as reported by all stakeholders, providing quantitative validation of the observed behavioral changes adopted by the care staff. Initial resistance from staff, linked to fears of criticism and discomfort with change, diminished through supportive peer coaching and emphasis on positive experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The SOCAV program was associated with meaningful improvements in care staff attitudes and behaviors that support self-direction among individuals with dementia. Key facilitators, including peer coaching, team cohesion, and the realization of staff impact on residents' self-direction, were instrumental in establishing these changes. Future research is needed to assess potential benefits of the SOCAV program in other settings and populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Ph&#xe9;be</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, IQ Health, P.O. Box 9101, Nijmegen, 6500 HB, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Douma</LastName><ForeName>Gerbrich</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, IQ Health, P.O. Box 9101, Nijmegen, 6500 HB, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donkers</LastName><ForeName>Hanneke</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Veen</LastName><ForeName>Dinja</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, IQ Health, P.O. Box 9101, Nijmegen, 6500 HB, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HAN University of Applied Sciences, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roets-Merken</LastName><ForeName>Lieve</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, IQ Health, P.O. Box 9101, Nijmegen, 6500 HB, the Netherlands. Lieve.Roets-Merken@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands. Lieve.Roets-Merken@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graff</LastName><ForeName>Maud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud University Medical Center, IQ Health, P.O. Box 9101, Nijmegen, 6500 HB, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radboud Alzheimer Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mixed-Methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Person-Centered</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reflective coaching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-Direction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study adhered to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and the Medical Research Involving Human Subjects Act. Participants were free to withdraw from the study at any time without any consequences. Written informed consent was obtained from the individuals with dementia and/or their caregivers. Caregivers were not direct participants but were involved as respondents related to the intervention. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41673572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-026-07100-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-026-07100-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bunn F, Goodman C, Sworn K, Rait G, Brayne C, Robinson L, et al. Psychosocial factors that shape patient and carer experiences of dementia diagnosis and treatment: a systematic review of qualitative studies. PLoS Med. 2012;9(10):e1001331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Corven CTM, Bielderman A, Wijnen M, Leontjevas R, Lucassen P, Graff MJL, et al. Defining empowerment for older people living with dementia from multiple perspectives: A qualitative study. Int J Nurs Stud. 2021;114:103823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns A. The burden of alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2000;3(Supplement2):S31&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gennip IE, Pasman HR, Oosterveld-Vlug MG, Willems DL, Onwuteaka-Philipsen BD. How dementia affects personal dignity: A qualitative study on the perspective of individuals with mild to moderate dementia. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2016;71(3):491&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummel-Smith K, Butler D, Frieder M, Gibbs N, Henry M, Koons E, et al. American geriatrics society expert panel on Person-Centered care. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2016;64(1):15&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell C, Fitzgerald MH, Williamson P, Manor D, Whybrow S. Independence as a practice issue in occupational therapy: the safety clause. Am J Occup Ther. 2002;56(4):369&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinema T. Wat Werkt Bij Eigen regie [What works to stimulate self-direction]. Movisie [In Dutch]; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Toit SHJ, Shen X, McGrath M. Meaningful engagement and person-centered residential dementia care: A critical interpretive synthesis. Scand J Occup Ther. 2019;26(5):343&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrerink A, Jacobs G, Mulder A, Ten Kate L. From fact to meaning: care practitioners&#x2019; hermeneutic competence development in residential care for persons with dementia. J Aging Stud. 2022;61:101003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan X, Duan AM, Xin GK, Oyebode J, Liu Y. Barriers and facilitators to implementing person-centred dementia care in long-term care facilities in Western and Asian countries: a scoping review. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1523501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TavaresJ, Hwang A, Cohen M. Tracking Progress on Person-Centered Care for Older Adults: How Are We Doing. The Center for Consumer Engagement in Health Innovation. 2021. https://communitycatalyst.org/resource/tracking-progress-on-person-centered-care-for-older-adults-how-are-we-doing/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Care TAGSEPP-C, Person-Centered Care. A definition and essential elements. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2016;64(1):15&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galik E, Resnick B, Hammersla M, Brightwater J. Optimizing function and physical activity among nursing home residents with dementia: testing the impact of function-focused care. Gerontologist. 2014;54(6):930&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corporaal SH, Huijbregts RC, Graff MJ. SOCAV: persoonsgerichte Zorg Bij dementie [SOCAV: person-centred care in dementia] [In Dutch]. Bijblijven. 2019;35(2):40&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budgett J, Sommerlad A, Kupeli N, Zabihi S, Olsen A, Cooper C. Setting individualised goals for people living with dementia and their family carers: A systematic review of goal-setting outcome measures and their psychometric properties. Dement (London). 2024;23(2):312&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Waal MWM, Haaksma ML, Doornebosch AJ, Meijs R, Achterberg WP. Systematic review of measurement properties of the Canadian occupational performance measure in geriatric rehabilitation. Eur Geriatr Med. 2022;13(6):1281&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McColl MA, Denis CB, Douglas KL, Gilmour J, Haveman N, Petersen M, et al. A clinically significant difference on the COPM: A review. Can J Occup Ther. 2023;90(1):92&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturkenboom IH, Graff MJ, Hendriks JC, Veenhuizen Y, Munneke M, Bloem BR, et al. Efficacy of occupational therapy for patients with parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(6):557&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;stlund U, Kidd L, Wengstr&#xf6;m Y, Rowa-Dewar N. Combining qualitative and quantitative research within mixed method research designs: a methodological review. Int J Nurs Stud. 2011;48(3):369&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donkers H, Graff M, Vernooij-Dassen M, Nijhuis-van der Sanden M, Teerenstra S. Reducing sample size by combining superiority and non-inferiority for two primary endpoints in the social fitness study. J Clin Epidemiol. 2017;81:86&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>General Assembly of the World Medical Association. World medical association declaration of helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. J Am Coll Dent. 2014;81(3):14&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Research Involving Human Subjects Act. (WMO, 2022). https://www.government.nl/topics/care-and-support-at-home/social-support-act-wmo. Accessed Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroneman M, de Jong J, Polin K, Webb E. The netherlands: health system summary, 2024. The Netherlands: Health System Summary, 20242025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok R, Verhey F et al. Folstein. Gestandaardiseerde mini-mental state examination. Dutch Translation of the Mini Mental State Examination (1975). 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chingono J, Creavin ST, Fish M, Cullum S, Bayer A, Purdy S, et al. Informant accuracy of IQCODE, AD8 and GPCOGi for diagnosis of dementia: does your friend know best? BMC Prim Care. 2025;26(1):112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff MJ, Vernooij-Dassen MJ, Thijssen M, Dekker J, Hoefnagels WH, Olderikkert MG. Effects of community occupational therapy on quality of life, mood, and health status in dementia patients and their caregivers: a randomized controlled trial. J Gerontol Biol Sci Med Sci. 2007;62(9):1002&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff MJ. Teaching and supporting clients with dementia and their caregivers in daily functioning. In: Soderback I, editor. International Handbook of Occupational Therapy Interventions. New York: Springer; 2015:433&#x2013;&#x2009;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff MJ, Vernooij-Dassen MJ, Thijssen M, Dekker J, Hoefnagels WH, Rikkert MGO. Community based occupational therapy for patients with dementia and their care givers: randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2006;333(7580):1196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff MJ, Vernooij-Dassen MJ, Zajec J, Olde-Rikkert MG, Hoefnagels WH, Dekker J. How can occupational therapy improve the daily performance and communication of an older patient with Dementia and his primary caregiver? A case study. Dementia. 2006;5(4):503&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff M, van Melick M, Thijssen M, Verstraten P, Zajec J. Ergotherapie Bij ouderen Met dementie En Hun mantelzorgers [Occupational therapy for dementia patients and their primary caregivers]. Houten, The Netherlands: Bohn Stafleu van Loghum; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roets-Merken LM, Zuidema SU, Vernooij-Dassen M, Teerenstra S, Hermsen P, Kempen G, et al. Effectiveness of a nurse-supported self-management programme for dual sensory impaired older adults in long-term care: a cluster randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2018;8(1):e016674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roets-Merken LM, Vernooij-Dassen MJ, Zuidema SU, Dees MK, Hermsen PG, Kempen GI, et al. Evaluation of nurses&#x2019; changing perceptions when trained to implement a self-management programme for dual sensory impaired older adults in long-term care: a qualitative study. BMJ Open. 2016;6(11):e013122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: toward a unifying theory of behavioral change. Psychol Rev. 1977;84(2):191&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam KF, Awal A, Mazumder H, Munni UR, Majumder K, Afroz K, et al. Social cognitive theory-based health promotion in primary care practice: A scoping review. Heliyon. 2023;9(4):e14889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry G, Hayfield N, Clarke V, Braun V. Thematic analysis. SAGE Handb Qualitative Res Psychol. 2017;2:17&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic analysis: American Psychological Association; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friese S. Qualitative data analysis with ATLAS. ti. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SPSS I. IBM Corp. Released, statistics for Windows, version 25.0. Armonk. NY: IBM Corp; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grol R, Wensing M, Bosch M, Hulscher M, Eccles M. Theories on implementation of change in healthcare. In: Grol R, Wensing M, Eccles M, Davis D, editors. Improving patient care: the implementation of change in health care. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2013. p. 18&#x2013;39.I mproving Patient Care: Implement Change Health Care. 2013:18&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheraghi R, Ebrahimi H, Kheibar N, Sahebihagh MH. Reasons for resistance to change in nursing: an integrative review. BMC Nurs. 2023;22(1):310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Weide H, Lovink MH, Luijkx KG, Gerritsen DL. Supporting autonomy for people with dementia living in nursing homes: A rapid realist review. Int J Nurs Stud. 2023;137:104382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grol R, Wensing M, Eccles M, Davis D. Improving patient care: the implementation of change in health care. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott WD, Cervone D, Ebiringah OU. The social-cognitive clinician: on the implications of social cognitive theory for psychotherapy and assessment. Int J Psychol. 2024;59(5):616&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motta-Ochoa R, Leibing A, Bresba P, Williams M, Shaffer S, Julien O, et al. You&#x2019;re part of Us and we&#x2019;re happy to have you here: practices of social inclusion for persons with dementia. Clin Gerontol. 2021;44(4):470&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetters MD, Molina-Azorin JF. The journal of mixed methods research starts a new decade: principles for bringing in the new and divesting of the old Language of the field. Los Angeles, CA: Sage Publications Sage CA; 2017. pp. 3&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier S. Functional assessment. In: Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease International, editor. World Alzheimer Report: 2021: Journey through the diagnosis of dementia. London: Alzheimer's Disease International; 2021. Chapter 4. Available from: https://www.altzint.org/resource/world-alzheimer-report-2101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agogo GO, Ramsey CM, Gnjidic D, Moga DC, Allore H. Longitudinal associations between different dementia diagnoses and medication use jointly accounting for dropout. Int Psychogeriatr. 2018;30(10):1477&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke SL, Hu T, Naseh M, Fava NM, O&#x2019;Driscoll J, Alvarez D, et al. Factors influencing attrition in 35 alzheimer&#x2019;s disease centers across the USA: a longitudinal examination of the National alzheimer&#x2019;s coordinating center&#x2019;s uniform data set. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2019;31:1283&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>