<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41359913</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nocturnal Sleep Is Associated With Next-Day Vertical Jump Performance in Collegiate Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>180</StartPage><EndPage>185</EndPage><MedlinePgn>180-185</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005296</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hummel, JW, Miltenberger, MM, Hummer, ET, and Spaeth, AM. Nocturnal sleep is associated with next-day vertical jump performance in collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): 180-185, 2026-This study examined the relationship between nocturnal sleep and next-day vertical jump performance in NCAA Division I male football athletes. We hypothesized that longer sleep would be associated with better vertical jump performance and explored potential mediators of the relationship, including peak concentric force (N), peak concentric velocity (m&#xb7;s -1 ), and countermovement depth (cm). A total of 174 athletes provided 4,049 instances of nocturnal sleep data (measured through photoplethysmography-based smart ring that was worn 5 nights/week) and next-day vertical jump performance. Each week, as part of routine team operations, athletes performed 3 vertical jumps in succession on a force plate and athletic staff calculated maximum and average jump height. A within-subject linear mixed-effects model assessed the relationship between sleep and vertical jump performance, and mediation analysis explored how sleep influenced vertical jump ability. Nocturnal sleep duration averaged 6.2 &#xb1; 1.1 hours per night, maximal jump height averaged 41.8 &#xb1; 7.8 cm, and average jump height averaged 40.2 &#xb1; 7.7 cm. Longer nocturnal sleep duration associated with better next-day vertical jump performance (maximal jump height: SE = 0.062, t = 3.07, 95% confidence interval (CI) [0.07-0.31], p = 0.002; average jump height: SE = 0.063, t = 4.41, 95% CI [0.15-0.40], p &lt; 0.001). Countermovement depth significantly mediated the relationship between sleep and maximal jump performance ( &#x3b2; = -0.18, 95% CI [-0.25 to -0.13], p &lt; 0.001), whereas peak concentric force and peak concentric velocity did not. These findings highlight the importance of prioritizing sufficient nocturnal sleep for optimizing anaerobic performance. Athletic staff should promote sleep hygiene to prevent sleep restriction in student athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hummel</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health, School of Arts and Sciences, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miltenberger</LastName><ForeName>Matthew M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, College of Health Sciences, East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvania, East Stroudsburg, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hummer</LastName><ForeName>Erik T</ForeName><Initials>ET</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health, School of Arts and Sciences, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spaeth</LastName><ForeName>Andrea M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health, School of Arts and Sciences, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="N">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anaerobic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smart ring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">student athletes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41359913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Bevilacqua GG, Casagrande PDO, Brandt R, Coimbra D. Prevalence of poor sleep quality in athletes before competition. Phys Sportsmed 49: 137&#x2013;142, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astridge D, Sommerville A, Verheul M, Turner AP. Training and academic demands are associated with sleep quality in high-performance &#x201c;dual career&#x201d; student swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1675&#x2013;1683, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badr MS, Belenky G, Bliwise DL, et al. Joint consensus statement of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine and Sleep Research Society on the recommended amount of sleep for a healthy adult: Methodology and discussion. J Clin Sleep Med 11: 931&#x2013;952, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevan HR, Bunce PJ, Owen NJ, et al. Optimal loading for the development of peak power output in professional rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 24: 43&#x2013;47, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP. Sleep, recovery, and athletic performance: A brief review and recommendations. Strength Cond J 35: 43&#x2013;47, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: Comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance profiling, neuromuscular fatigue monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Cond J 45: 545&#x2013;553, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumert PA, Crum AJ, Ernsting M, et al. The acute effects of twenty-four hours of sleep loss on the performance of national caliber male collegiate weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res 21: 1146&#x2013;1154, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolin DJ. Sleep deprivation and its contribution to mood and performance deterioration in college athletes. Curr Sports Med Rep 18: 305&#x2013;310, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke TM, Lisman PJ, Maguire K, et al. Examination of sleep and injury among college football athletes. J Strength Cond Res 34: 609&#x2013;616, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Scott TJ, Halson SL, Kelly VG. The influence of sleep hygiene education on sleep in professional rugby league athletes. Sleep Health 4: 364&#x2013;368, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J, Grandner MA. Sleep and athletic performance: Impacts on physical performance, mental performance, injury risk and recovery, and mental health. Sleep Med Clin 15: 41&#x2013;57, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collings TJ, Lima YL, Dutaillis B, Bourne MN. Concurrent validity and test&#x2013;retest reliability of VALD ForceDecks' strength, balance, and movement assessment tests. J Sci Med Sport 27: 572&#x2013;580, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Crewther BT, Kilduff LP, Drawer S, Gaviglio CM. Skill execution and sleep deprivation: Effects of acute caffeine or creatine supplementation&#x2014;a randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 8: 2, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha LA, Costa JA, Marques EA, Brito J, Lastella M, Figueiredo P. The impact of sleep interventions on athletic performance: A systematic review. Sports Med Open 9: 58, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards BJ, Waterhouse J. Effects of one night of partial sleep deprivation upon diurnal rhythms of accuracy and consistency in throwing darts. Chronobiol Int 26: 756&#x2013;768, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrlenspiel F, Erlacher D, Ziegler M. Changes in subjective sleep quality before a competition and their relation to competitive anxiety. Behav Sleep Med 16: 553&#x2013;568, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipas L, Ferioli D, Banfi G, La Torre A, Vitale JA. Single and combined effect of acute sleep restriction and mental fatigue on basketball free-throw performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 415&#x2013;420, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med 47: 1317&#x2013;1333, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HajSalem M, Chtourou H, Aloui A, Hammouda O, Souissi N. Effects of partial sleep deprivation at the end of the night on anaerobic performances in judokas. Biol Rhythm Res 44: 815&#x2013;821, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Hebert JJ, Forsyth PL, Peiffer JJ. Longer sleep durations are positively associated with finishing place during a national multiday netball competition. J Strength Cond Res 32: 189&#x2013;194, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiesel KB, Butler RJ, Plisky PJ. Prediction of injury by limited and asymmetrical fundamental movement patterns in American football players. J Sport Rehabil 23: 88&#x2013;94, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschen GW, Jones JJ, Hale L. The impact of sleep duration on performance among competitive athletes: A systematic literature review. Clin J Sport Med 30: 503&#x2013;512, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles OE, Drinkwater EJ, Roberts SSH, et al. Sustained sleep restriction reduces Resistance exercise quality and quantity in females. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54: 2167&#x2013;2177, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komsta L. Outliers: Tests for Outliers, 2022. Available at: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=outliers . Accessed June, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leduc C, Tee J, Weakley J, Ramirez C, Jones B. The quality, quantity, and intraindividual variability of sleep among students and student-athletes. Sports Health 12: 43&#x2013;50, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Steward CJ, Cullen T, Che K, Zhou Y. Presleep heart-rate variability biofeedback improves mood and sleep quality in Chinese winter Olympic bobsleigh athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 1516&#x2013;1526, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes TR, Pereira HM, Bittencourt LRA, Silva BM. How much does sleep deprivation impair endurance performance? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 1279&#x2013;1292, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep 34: 943&#x2013;950, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Sparks AJ, Samaan MA, Souza RB, Luke A. Sleep restriction impairs maximal jump performance and joint coordination in elite athletes. J Sports Sci 37: 1981&#x2013;1988, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. The role of rate of force development on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res 25: 379&#x2013;385, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Yousfi N, Mhenni T, et al. Does one night of partial sleep deprivation affect the evening performance during intermittent exercise in Taekwondo players? J Exerc Rehabil 12: 47&#x2013;53, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore J, McDonald C, McIntyre A, Carmody K, Donne B. Effects of acute sleep deprivation and caffeine supplementation on anaerobic performance. Sleep Sci 11: 2&#x2013;7, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Bourdin H, Simon-Rigaud ML, Didier JM, Toubin G, Kantelip JP. Effects of a selective sleep deprivation on subsequent anaerobic performance. Int J Sports Med 17: 115&#x2013;119, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, Aloulou A, Duforez F, Meyer T, Dupont G. The variability of sleep among elite athletes. Sports Med Open 4: 34, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Driller MW. Sleep-hygiene education improves sleep indices in elite female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci 10: 522&#x2013;530, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver SJ, Costa RJS, Laing SJ, Bilzon JLJ, Walsh NP. One night of sleep deprivation decreases treadmill endurance performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 107: 155&#x2013;161, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JL, Golkashani HA, Ghorbani S, et al. Selecting a sleep tracker from EEG-based, iteratively improved, low-cost multisensor, and actigraphy-only devices. Sleep Health 10: 9&#x2013;23, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro J, Bates D. Linear and Nonlinear Mixed Effects Models, 2023. Available at: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=nlme . Accessed June, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preacher KJ, Hayes AF. SPSS and SAS procedures for estimating indirect effects in simple mediation models. Behav Research Methods, Instruments, Computers: A Journal Psychon Soc Inc 36: 717&#x2013;731, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing, 2023. Available at: https://www.R-project.org/ . Accessed May, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyner LA, Horne JA. Sleep restriction and serving accuracy in performance tennis players, and effects of caffeine. Physiol Behav 120: 93&#x2013;96, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riegler KE, Guty ET, Thomas GA, Arnett PA. Sleep deprived or concussed? The acute impact of self-reported insufficient sleep in college athletes. J Int Neuropsychological Soc JINS 27: 35&#x2013;46, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritland BM, Simonelli G, Gentili RJ, et al. Effects of sleep extension on cognitive/motor performance and motivation in military tactical athletes. Sleep Med 58: 48&#x2013;55, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samozino P, Morin J-B, Hintzy F, Belli A. Jumping ability: A theoretical integrative approach. J Theor Biol 264: 11&#x2013;18, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schobersberger W, Schobersberger B. The traveling athlete: From jet leg to jet lag. Curr Sports Med Rep 11: 222&#x2013;223, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz J, Simon RD. Sleep extension improves serving accuracy: A study with college varsity tennis players. Physiol Behav 151: 541&#x2013;544, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RS, Efron B, Mah CD, Malhotra A. The impact of circadian misalignment on athletic performance in professional football players. Sleep 36: 1999&#x2013;2001, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B, Gauthier A, Larue J, Davenne D. Effects of one night's sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 359&#x2013;366, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi W, Hammouda O, Ayachi M, et al. Partial sleep deprivation affects endurance performance and psychophysiological responses during 12-minute self-paced running exercise. Physiol Behav 227: 113165, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svensson T, Madhawa K, Nt H, Chung U, Svensson AK. Validity and reliability of the Oura ring generation 3 (Gen3) with Oura sleep staging algorithm 2.0 (OSSA 2.0) when compared to multi-night ambulatory polysomnography: A validation study of 96 participants and 421,045 epochs. Sleep Med 115: 251&#x2013;263, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tingley D, Yamamoto T, Hirose K, Keele L, Imai K. mediation: R package for causal mediation analysis. J Stat Software 59, 2014. https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/91154 . Accessed June, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dongen HPA, Maislin G, Mullington JM, Dinges DF. The cumulative cost of additional wakefulness: Dose-response effects on neurobehavioral functions and sleep physiology from chronic sleep restriction and total sleep deprivation. Sleep 26: 117&#x2013;126, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardar SA, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk L, Kurt C, Bulut E, Sut N, Vardar E. Sleep deprivation induced anxiety and anaerobic performance. J Sports Sci Med 6: 532&#x2013;537, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venter RE. Role of sleep in performance and recovery of athletes: A review article. South Afr J Res Sport Phys Educ Recreat 34: 167&#x2013;184, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale JA, Bonato M, Petrucci L, Zucca G, La Torre A, Banfi G. Acute sleep restriction affects sport-specific but not athletic performance in junior tennis players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 1154&#x2013;1159, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Dai Y, Li X, Yu L. Associations of training and academic stress with sleep in dual-career collegiate badminton athletes: A preliminary study. Nat Sci Sleep 16: 43&#x2013;52, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr Sports Med Rep 16: 413&#x2013;418, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Turner A, Comfort P, et al. A systematic review of the different calculation methods for measuring jump height during the countermovement and drop jump tests. Sports Med 53: 1055&#x2013;1072, 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>