<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41257834</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preventive interventions on ACL injury reduction based on the landing error scoring system evaluation tool: a systematic review and network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1061</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1061</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-025-09290-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) injuries pose a significant risk in sports, often leading to long rehabilitation and re-injury. The Landing Error Scoring System (LESS) has been proposed as a means of assessing the risk of potential ACL damage. This study employed Network meta-analysis to assess the effectiveness of various preventive interventions in reducing ACL injury risk among athletes, utilizing LESS evaluation tool to identify the most effective strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A comprehensive search for related publications in English in databases, such as WOS, Cochrane Library, Embase, PubMed, and Scopus from the establishment of the databases to February 2025. Relevant content in the literature that passed the screening criteria was extracted, including the sample, first author, intervention, intervention duration, and outcome. We compared the Mean Difference (MD) values across studies and used network meta-analysis based on Bayesian modelling.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A Network meta-analysis of 20 studies (<i>N</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1,356) was conducted. After comparison, assessing the impact of eight training interventions on the LESS scores. Dynamic Taping (MD, -1.87, 95% CrI, -3.29 to -0.46), Neuromuscular Training (MD, -1.04, 95% CrI, -2.01 to -0.10), and Feedback Training (MD, -0.86 95% CrI, -1.54 to -0.20) were the most effective in reducing injury risk. The SUCRA rankings from highest to lowest are as follows: Dynamic Taping (79.0), Neuromuscular Training (53.2), and Feedback Training (43.0).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Network meta-analysis simultaneously integrates evidence from both direct comparisons and indirect comparisons. Evidence from Network meta-analysis based on Bayesian models, Dynamic Taping, Neuromuscular Training and Feedback Training are effective intervention training programs for ACL injury prevention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12891-025-09290-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jiakang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Basketball College, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Institute of Sport and Health Science, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Basketball College, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Weihuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Strength and Conditioning, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zirui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Strength and Conditioning, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zezhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Strength and Conditioning, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, 10084, China. chenzezhao2022@bsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Weimo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Plateau Thermal Health Industry Innovation Research Institute, Tengchong, Yunnan, 678100, China. weimozhu@illinois.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Community Health, University of Illinois at Urbana- Champaign, Urbana-Champaign, 61820, USA. weimozhu@illinois.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LESS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: None required. The manuscript does not contain clinical studies or patient data. Consent for publication: All authors had reviewed the final manuscript and give consent for submission and publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41257834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12628533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-025-09290-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-025-09290-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mall NA, Chalmers PN, Moric M, Tanaka MJ, Cole BJ, Bach BR Jr, et al. Incidence and trends of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the United States. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(10):2363&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546514542796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbrojkiewicz D, Vertullo C, Grayson JE. Increasing rates of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in young Australians, 2000&#x2013;2015. Med J Aust. 2018;208(8):354&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja17.00974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29669497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnussen RA, Meschbach NT, Kaeding CC, Wright RW, Spindler KP. ACL graft and contralateral ACL tear risk within ten years following reconstruction: a systematic review. JBJS Rev. 2015;3(1):e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.N.00052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27501023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber-Westin S, Noyes FR. One in 5 athletes sustain reinjury upon return to high-risk sports after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review in 1239 athletes younger than 20 years. Sports Health. 2020;12(6):587&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120912846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty-five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antosh IJ, Svoboda SJ, Peck KY, Garcia ESJ, Cameron KL. Change in KOOS and WOMAC scores in a young athletic population with and without anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(7):1606&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546518768753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29733680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay S, Culvenor A, Ackerman I, Russell T, Crossley K. Quality of life in anterior cruciate ligament deficient individuals: a systematic review. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;19:e38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.12.466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur M, Ribeiro DC, Lamb P, Webster KE, Sole G. Low knee-related quality of life and persistent physical asymmetries in participants up to 10 years post-ACL reconstruction&#x2013;a cross-sectional study. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;48:35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.12.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson B, Culvenor AG, Barton CJ, Guermazi A, Stefanik J, Morris HG, et al. Poor functional performance 1 year after ACL reconstruction increases the risk of early osteoarthritis progression. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(9):546&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32276925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BE, Culvenor AG, Barton CJ, Guermazi A, Stefanik JJ, Crossley KM. Patient-reported outcomes one to five years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the effect of combined injury and associations with osteoarthritis features defined on magnetic resonance imaging. Arthritis Care Res. 2020;72(3):412&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30762314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerts I, Cumps E, Verhagen E, Verschueren J, Meeusen R. A systematic review of different jump-landing variables in relation to injuries. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2013;53(5):509&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23903531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepp&#xe4;nen M, Pasanen K, Kujala UM, Vasankari T, Kannus P, &#xc4;yr&#xe4;m&#xf6; S, et al. Stiff landings are associated with increased ACL injury risk in young female basketball and floorball players. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(2):386&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516665810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27637264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani AM, Alzhrani M, Alshahrani SN, Alghamdi W, Alqahtani M, Alzahrani H. Is hip muscle strength associated with dynamic knee valgus in a healthy adult population? A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(14):7669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18147669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8304771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34300118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Myer GD, Ford KR, Heidt RS Jr., Colosimo AJ, McLean SG, et al. Biomechanical measures of neuromuscular control and valgus loading of the knee predict anterior cruciate ligament injury risk in female athletes: a prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(4):492&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546504269591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15722287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Mart&#xed;nez J, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Capote A, Alarc&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez F, Leicht A, C&#xe1;rdenas-V&#xe9;lez D. Relationship between cognitive demands and biomechanical indicators associated with anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2025;55(1):145&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02124-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39470925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes MA, Probasco MO, Worby TN, Loertscher DE, Soderbeck LK, Huddleston WE. Lower kinetic chain, meet the thinking brain: a scoping review of cognitive function and lower extremity injury risk. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2022;17(5):787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.36814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padua DA, Marshall SW, Boling MC, Thigpen CA, Garrett WE Jr, Beutler AI. The landing error scoring system (LESS) is a valid and reliable clinical assessment tool of jump-landing biomechanics: the JUMP-ACL study. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(10):1996&#x2013;2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509343200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19726623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStefano LJ, Beltz EM, Root HJ, Martinez JC, Houghton A, Taranto N, et al. Sport sampling is associated with improved landing technique in youth athletes. Sports Health. 2018;10(2):160&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738117736056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStefano LJ, Padua DA, DiStefano MJ, Marshall SW. Influence of age, sex, technique, and exercise program on movement patterns after an anterior cruciate ligament injury prevention program in youth soccer players. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(3):495&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546508327542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox A, Bonacci J, McLean S, Saunders N. Efficacy of ACL injury risk screening methods in identifying high-risk landing patterns during a sport&#x2010;specific task. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(5):525&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27292768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus K, Sch&#xfc;tz E, Doyscher R. The relationship between a jump-landing task and functional movement screen items: a validation study. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(7):1855&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28859011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarneo SE, Root HJ, Martinez JC, Denegar C, Casa DJ, Mazerolle SM, et al. Landing technique improvements after an aquatic-based neuromuscular training program in physically active women. J Sport Rehabil. 2017;26(1):8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2015-0052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27632861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DR, Smith MD, Pennuto AP, Stiffler MR, Olson ME. Jump-landing mechanics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a landing error scoring system study. J Athl Train. 2014;49(4):435&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Eppinga P, Dijkstra P, Welling W, Padua D, Otten E, et al. Effect of fatigue on landing performance assessed with the landing error scoring system (LESS) in patients after ACL reconstruction. A pilot study. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2014;9(3):302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4060307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James J, Ambegaonkar JP, Caswell SV, Onate J, Cortes N. Analyses of landing mechanics in division I athletes using the landing error scoring system. Sports Health. 2016;8(2):182&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738115624891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26721287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam KC, McLeod TCV. The impact of sex and knee injury history on jump-landing patterns in collegiate athletes: a clinical evaluation. Clin J Sport Med. 2014;24(5):373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K. Is the landing error scoring system reliable and valid? A systematic review. Sports Health. 2020;12(2):181&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738119886593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7040940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31961778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bathe C, Fennen L, Heering T, Greif A, Dubbeldam R. Training interventions to reduce the risk of injury to the lower extremity joints during landing movements in adult athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9(2):e001508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2022-001508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10254820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-2385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366. 10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthimiou O, Debray TP, van Valkenhoef G, Trelle S, Panayidou K, Moons KG, et al. GetReal in network meta-analysis: a review of the methodology. Res Synth Methods. 2016;7(3):236&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26754852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Sutton AJ, Caldwell DM, Lu G, Ades A. Evidence synthesis for decision making 4: inconsistency in networks of evidence based on randomized controlled trials. Med Decis Making. 2013;33(5):641&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X12455847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23804508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavridis D, Salanti G. A practical introduction to multivariate meta-analysis. Stat Methods Med Res. 2013;22(2):133&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0962280211432219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Valkenhoef G, Lu G, De Brock B, Hillege H, Ades A, Welton NJ. Automating network meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2012;3(4):285&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26053422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks SP, Gelman A. General methods for monitoring convergence of iterative simulations. J Comput Graph Stat. 1998;7(4):434&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10618600.1998.10474787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: A Language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria: Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;liveau A, Boyne DJ, Slater J, Brenner D, Arora P. BUGSnet: an R package to facilitate the conduct and reporting of bayesian network meta-analyses. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0829-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guide AH-O. Doing Meta-Analysis with R. Boca Raton, FL and London: Chapman &amp;; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Ades A, Ioannidis JP. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(2):163&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.03.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root H, Trojian T, Martinez J, Kraemer W, DiStefano LJ. Landing technique and performance in youth athletes after a single injury-prevention program session. J Athl Train. 2015;50(11):1149&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-50.11.01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4732394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Benjaminse A, Gokeler A, Otten B. Enhanced retention of drop vertical jump landing technique: a randomized controlled trial. Hum Mov Sci. 2016;45:84&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2015.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26615475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C-K, Lin Y-C, Chen Y-L, Chao Y-P, Hsieh T-H. The influence of dynamic taping on landing biomechanics after fatigue in young football athletes: a randomized, sham-controlled crossover trial. Bioengineering. 2024;11(6):631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering11060631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11200620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38927867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman DC, Pritchard KA, Cosby NL, Selkow NM. Effect of strength training on jump-landing biomechanics in adolescent females. Sports Health. 2022;14(1):69&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381211056089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8669936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams F, Hadadnezhad M, Letafatkar A, Hogg J. Valgus control feedback and taping improves the effects of plyometric exercises in women with dynamic knee valgus. Sports Health. 2022;14(5):747&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381211049805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34651505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bean J. Effect of Lumbopelvic-Hip complex stability training on clinical measures of postural stability and. Landing Biomechanics: The University of Toledo; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doebel SC. The effect of feedback training on the landing error. Scoring System: University of Toledo; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons JL, Sylvester R, Porter MM. The effect of strength training on the jump-landing biomechanics of young female athletes: results of a randomized controlled trial. Clin J Sport Med. 2017;27(2):127&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafakoriollah A, Daneshmandi H, Samami N. The effect of selected core stability exercises on the jumping-landing pattern and trunk muscular endurance in adolescent volleyball players with trunk defect. Phys Treatments-Spec Phys Ther J. 2020;10(2):89&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahrjerdi S, Mohammadi H, Amiri S. The effect of sports-metrics volleyball training on the landing error scoring system in female volleyball players. Sport Sci Health Res. 2021;13(2):217&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons JL, Carswell J, Nwoba IM, Stenberg H. Athlete perceptions and physical performance effects of the Fifa 11&#x2009;+&#x2009;program in 9&#x2013;11 year-old female soccer players: a cluster randomized trial. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14(5):740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20190740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31598412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukry SA, Justine M, Azidin RMFR, Azhar NI, Zolkafi MAA, Lo CN, et al. Effects of the FIFA 11&#x2009;+&#x2009;injury prevention programme on muscle strength and landing biomechanical markers of ACL injury during fatigue among youth soccer players. Biomed Hum Kinet. 2024;16(1):173&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/bhk-2024-0018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari H, Sahebozamani M, Daneshjoo A, Amiri-Khorasani M, Shimokochi Y. Effect of the FIFA 11&#x2009;+&#x2009;on landing patterns and baseline movement errors in elite male youth soccer players. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;29(6):730&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikora O, Lehnert M, Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, Hughes J. The impact of a novel neuromuscular training program on leg stiffness, reactive strength, and landing biomechanics in amateur female rugby players. Appl Sci. 2023;13(3):1979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13031979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStefano LJ, Marshall SW, Padua DA, Peck KY, Beutler AI, de la Motte SJ, et al. The effects of an injury prevention program on landing biomechanics over time. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(3):767&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515621270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root HJ, Beltz EM, Burland JP, Martinez JC, Bay RC, DiStefano LJ. Preventive training program feedback complexity, movement control, and performance in youth athletes. J Athl Train. 2022;57(9&#x2013;10):894&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-0585.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9842129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36638343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivares-Jabalera J, F&#xed;lter A, Dos&#xb4; Santos T, Ortega-Dom&#xed;nguez J, Soto Hermoso VM, Requena B. The safe landing warm up technique modification programme: an effective anterior cruciate ligament injury mitigation strategy to improve cutting and jump-movement quality in soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(24):2784&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2023.2193451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36958805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryor JL, Root HJ, Vandermark LW, Pryor RR, Martinez JC, Trojian TH, et al. Coach-led preventive training program in youth soccer players improves movement technique. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(9):861&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2017.01.235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28162913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Malley E, Murphy JC, Persson UM, Gissane C, Blake C. The effects of the Gaelic Athletic Association 15 training program on neuromuscular outcomes in Gaelic football and hurling players: a randomized cluster trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(8):2119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27398918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domnick C, Raschke MJ, Herbort M. Biomechanics of the anterior cruciate ligament: physiology, rupture and reconstruction techniques. World J Orthop. 2016;7(2):82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v7.i2.82</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4757662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26925379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koga H, Nakamae A, Shima Y, Bahr R, Krosshaug T. Hip and ankle kinematics in noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injury situations: video analysis using model-based image matching. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(2):333&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546517732750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29024605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron ML, Adams RD, Maher CG. The effect of neoprene shorts on leg proprioception in Australian football players. J Sci Med Sport. 2008;11(3):345&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2007.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17889610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanik KA, Lephart SM, Swanik CB, Lephart SP, Stone DA, Fu FH. The effects of shoulder plyometric training on proprioception and selected muscle performance characteristics. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2002;11(6):579&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mse.2002.127303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12469083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazulak BT, Hewett TE, Reeves NP, Goldberg B, Cholewicki J. Deficits in neuromuscular control of the trunk predict knee injury risk: prospective biomechanical-epidemiologic study. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(7):1123&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546507301585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Ford KR, Palumbo OP, Hewett TE. Neuromuscular training improves performance and lower-extremity biomechanics in female athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanik CB, Covassin T, Stearne DJ, Schatz P. The relationship between neurocognitive function and noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(6):943&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546507299532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17369562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas ZM, Lupowitz L, Ivey M, Wilk KE. Neurocognitive and neuromuscular rehabilitation techniques after ACL injury-Part 2: maximizing performance in the advanced return to sport phase. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(12):1629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.126270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11611477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39628780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Benjaminse A, Della Villa F, Tosarelli F, Verhagen E, Baumeister J. Anterior cruciate ligament injury mechanisms through a neurocognition lens: implications for injury screening. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2021. 10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8130757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34055386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Ford KR, Myer GD. Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes: part 2, a meta-analysis of neuromuscular interventions aimed at injury prevention. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34(3):490&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546505282619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlingermann BE, Lodge CA, Gissane C, Rankin PM. Effects of the Gaelic Athletic Association 15 on lower extremity injury incidence and neuromuscular functional outcomes in collegiate Gaelic games. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(7):1993&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari H, Sahebozamani M, Daneshjoo A, Amiri-Khorasani M, Shimokochi Y. Effect of the FIFA 11&#x2009;+&#x2009;on landing patterns and baseline movement errors in elite male youth soccer players. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;29(6):730&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2018-0374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons JL, Carswell J, Nwoba IM, Stenberg H. Athlete perceptions and physical performance effects of the Fifa 11&#x2009;+&#x2009;program in 9&#x2013;11 year-old female soccer players: a cluster randomized trial. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14(5):740&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20190740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31598412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maga&#xf1;a-Ram&#xed;rez M, Gallardo-G&#xf3;mez D, &#xc1;lvarez-Barbosa F, Corral-Pern&#xed;a JA. What exercise programme is the most appropriate to mitigate anterior cruciate ligament injury risk in football (soccer) players? A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2024;27(4):234&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2024.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto D, Myer GD, McKeon JM, Hewett TE. Evaluation of the effectiveness of neuromuscular training to reduce anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes: a critical review of relative risk reduction and numbers-needed-to-treat analyses. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(14):979&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2011-090895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4164156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Sugimoto D, Thomas S, Hewett TE. The influence of age on the effectiveness of neuromuscular training to reduce anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes: a meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(1):203&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512460637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4160039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23048042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala F, de Baranda PS, Croix MDS, Santonja F. Criterion-related validity of four clinical tests used to measure hamstring flexibility in professional futsal players. Phys Ther Sport. 2011;12(4):175&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2011.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22085711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinyomark A, Osis S, Hettinga B, Leigh R, Ferber R. Gender differences in gait kinematics in runners with iliotibial band syndrome. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(6):744&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25622800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Stroube BW, DiCesare CA, Brent JL, Ford KR, Heidt RS Jr, et al. Augmented feedback supports skill transfer and reduces high-risk injury landing mechanics: a double-blind, randomized controlled laboratory study. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(3):669&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546512472977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23371471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroube BW, Myer GD, Brent JL, Ford KR, Heidt RS, Hewett TE. Effects of task-specific augmented feedback on deficit modification during performance of the tuck-jump exercise. J Sport Rehabil. 2013;22(1):7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.22.1.7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4168972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23238301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pamboris GM, Pavlou K, Paraskevopoulos E, Mohagheghi AA. Effect of open vs. closed kinetic chain exercises in ACL rehabilitation on knee joint pain, laxity, extensor muscles strength, and function: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1416690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2024.1416690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11180725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38887689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, Athens J, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K. Clinical implications of landing error scoring system calculation methods. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;44:61&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.04.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffen K, Emery CA, Romiti M, Kang J, Bizzini M, Dvorak J, et al. High adherence to a neuromuscular injury prevention programme (FIFA 11+) improves functional balance and reduces injury risk in Canadian youth female football players: a cluster randomised trial. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(12):794&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23559666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Konishi D, Welk G, Mahar M, Laurson K, Janz K, et al. Linking vertical jump and standing broad jump tests: a testing equating application. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci. 2022;26(4):335&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1091367X.2022.2112683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>