<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731274</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-4681</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of surgical oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Surg Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in Functional Capacity and Body Composition After a Multimodal Prehabilitation Program in Patients with Cancer undergoing Abdominal Surgery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1245/s10434-026-19173-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Preoperative functional capacity and body composition are associated with postoperative outcomes in patients undergoing abdominal surgery for cancer. Long-term effects of multimodal prehabilitation and exercise dose-response associations remain unclear. This study aimed to investigate changes in functional capacity and body composition during and after prehabilitation and evaluate exercise dose-response associations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data from 816 patients who participated in the monocenter stepped wedge F4S PREHAB trial (March 2021-April 2024) and underwent elective abdominal surgery for gastrointestinal, gynecological, or urological cancers were included. Functional capacity measures included estimated peak oxygen uptake, maximum short exercise capacity, muscle strength (leg press, handgrip), and five-times sit-to-stand test. Body composition measures included weight, fat-free mass, percentage body fat, and phase angle. Assessments occurred at baseline, after prehabilitation, and 3&#xa0;months postoperatively. Changes over time and dose-response associations were evaluated with linear mixed models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Maximum proportions of missing data ranged from 12.9% at preintervention and 24.9% at postintervention to 62.4% after surgery. Significant improvements over time were observed in estimated peak oxygen uptake (&#x3b2;=0.6&#xa0;mL/kg/min, 95% confidence interval [CI] 0.4-0.8), maximum short exercise capacity (&#x3b2;=17.5&#xa0;Watt, 95% CI 13.8-21.2), leg press (&#x3b2;=18.9&#xa0;kg, 95% CI 15.9-21.9), handgrip (&#x3b2;=1.1&#xa0;kg, 95% CI 0.6-1.6), sit-to-stand time (&#x3b2;=0.9&#xa0;seconds, 95% CI -1.1 to -0.6), body weight (&#x3b2;=1.1&#xa0;kg, 95% CI 0.7-1.4), and fat-free mass (&#x3b2;=0.5&#xa0;kg), 95% CI 0.1-0.8). Some exercise dose-response associations were found. Functional capacity measures returned to or declined below baseline value. Sensitivity analyses with complete data at follow-up yielded comparable findings with attenuated associations. Associations varied by tumor type, neoadjuvant therapy, malnutrition risk, and training compliance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Functional capacity and body composition improved after prehabilitation, although gains were generally not sustained postoperatively. Associations may vary between patient subgroups. Future research should focus on targeted approaches and integration with improved postoperative rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The F4S PREHAB trial is registered in the International Clinical Trials Registry Platform, NL8699. Registered on 05-06-2020.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drager</LastName><ForeName>Luuk D</ForeName><Initials>LD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3283-095X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands. Luuk.drager@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Heuvel</LastName><ForeName>Baukje</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strijker</LastName><ForeName>Dieuwke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Laarhoven</LastName><ForeName>Cornelis J H M</ForeName><Initials>CJHM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Buffart</LastName><ForeName>Laurien M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biosciences, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Verlaan</LastName><ForeName>Sjors</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health, Sport and Physical Activity, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Surg Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9420840</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1068-9265</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors confirm that there are no known conflicts of interests associated with this manuscript. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: Ethical approval for this study was granted by the institutional review board of the Radboudumc and local medical ethics committee (METC Oost-Nederland) (NL73777.091.20). The trial has been registered in the International Clinical Trials Registry Platform (NL8699). Participants provided written informed consent prior to study participation. Consent for publication: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-026-19173-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1245/s10434-026-19173-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Helden EV, Kranendonk J, Vermulst A, Boer A, Reuver P, Rosman C, et al. Early postoperative pain and 30-day complications following major abdominal surgery: a retrospective cohort study. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2024;50(8):651&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rapm-2024-105277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tevis SE, Cobian AG, Truong HP, Craven MW, Kennedy GD. Implications of multiple complications on the postoperative recovery of general surgery patients. Ann Surg. 2016;263(6):1213&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27167563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6214627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000001390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy MA, Mullard AJ, Campbell DA Jr, Dimick JB. Hospital and payer costs associated with surgical complications. JAMA Surg. 2016;151(9):823&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2016.0773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack S, West MA, Raw D, Marwood S, Ambler G, Cope TM, et al. The effect of neoadjuvant chemotherapy on physical fitness and survival in patients undergoing oesophagogastric cancer surgery. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2014;40(10):1313&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2014.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallard J, Hucteau E, Schott R, Trensz P, Pflumio C, Kalish-Weindling M, et al. Early skeletal muscle deconditioning and reduced exercise capacity during (neo)adjuvant chemotherapy in patients with breast cancer. Cancer. 2023;129(2):215&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36397290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.34533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heldens AFJM, Bongers BC, Lenssen AF, Stassen LPS, Buhre WF, van Meeteren NLU. The association between performance parameters of physical fitness and postoperative outcomes in patients undergoing colorectal surgery: An evaluation of care data. Eur J Surg Onc. 2017;43(11):2084&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2017.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makker PGS, Koh CE, Solomon MJ, Steffens D. Preoperative functional capacity and postoperative outcomes following abdominal and pelvic cancer surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. ANZ J Surg. 2022;92(7&#x2013;8):1658&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35253333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ans.17577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trejo-Avila M, Bozada-Gutierrez K, Valenzuela-Salazar C, Herrera-Esquivel J, Moreno-Portillo M. Sarcopenia predicts worse postoperative outcomes and decreased survival rates in patients with colorectal cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2021;36(6):1077&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33481108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00384-021-03839-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maria Minnella E, Sender Liberman A, Charlebois P, Stein B, Scheede-Bergdahl C, Awasthi R, et al. The impact of improved functional capacity before surgery on postoperative complications: a study in colorectal cancer. Acta Oncologica. 2019;58(5):573&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0284186X.2018.1557343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen BP, Awasthi R, Sweet SN, Minnella EM, Bergdahl A, Santa Mina D, et al. Four-week prehabilitation program is sufficient to modify exercise behaviors and improve preoperative functional walking capacity in patients with colorectal cancer. Support Care Cancer. 2017;25(1):33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barberan-Garcia A, Ubre M, Roca J, Lacy AM, Burgos F, Risco R, et al. Personalised prehabilitation in high-risk patients undergoing elective major abdominal surgery: a randomized blinded controlled trial. Ann Surg. 2018;267(1):50&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28489682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000002293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkel AEM, Bongers BC, Kotte H, Weltevreden P, de Jongh FHC, Eijsvogel MMM, et al. Effects of community-based exercise prehabilitation for patients scheduled for colorectal surgery with high risk for postoperative complications: results of a randomized clinical trial. Ann Surg. 2022;275(2):e299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8746915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000004702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molenaar CJ, van Rooijen SJ, Fokkenrood HJ, Roumen RM, Janssen L, Slooter GD. Prehabilitation versus no prehabilitation to improve functional capacity, reduce postoperative complications and improve quality of life in colorectal cancer surgery. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;5(5):CD013259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37162250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10171468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterland JL, McCourt O, Edbrooke L, Granger CL, Ismail H, Riedel B, et al. Efficacy of prehabilitation including exercise on postoperative outcomes following abdominal cancer surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Surg. 2021;8:628848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33816546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8017317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsurg.2021.628848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen SN, Morup ST, Mau-Sorensen M, Sillesen M, Lahart I, Christensen JF. Perioperative exercise training for patients with gastrointestinal cancer undergoing surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2021;47(12):3028&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34294466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2021.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raichurkar P, Denehy L, Solomon M, Koh C, Pillinger N, Hogan S, et al. Research Priorities in Prehabilitation for Patients Undergoing Cancer Surgery: An International Delphi Study. Ann Surg Oncol. 2023;30(12):7226&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37620526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10562336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-023-14192-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Cate DWG, Molenaar CJL, Garcia RS, Bojesen RD, Tahasildar BLR, Jansen L, et al. Multimodal prehabilitation in elective oncological colorectal surgery enhances postoperative functional recovery: A secondary analysis of the PREHAB randomized clinical trial. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2024;50(6):108270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38520782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2024.108270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogenbirk RNM, van der Plas WY, Hentzen J, van Wijk L, Wijma AG, Buis CI, et al. Postoperative muscle loss, protein intake, physical activity and outcome associations. Br J Surg. 2023;110(2):183&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36394896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10364506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjs/znac384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoyama T, Kawabe T, Hirohito F, Hayashi T, Yamada T, Tsuchida K, et al. Body composition analysis within 1 month after gastrectomy for gastric cancer. Gastric Cancer. 2016;19(2):645&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25893261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-015-0496-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strijker D, Drager L, van Asseldonk M, Atsma F, van den Berg M, van Daal E, et al. Multimodal prehabilitation (Fit4Surgery) in high-impact surgery to enhance surgical outcomes: Study protocol of F4S PREHAB, a single center stepped wedge trial. Plos One. 2024;19(7):e0303829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38968183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11226070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0303829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, Arena R, Riebe D, Pescatello LS. ACSM&#x2019;s new preparticipation health screening recommendations from ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription, ninth edition. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013;12(4):215&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31829a68cf</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuiver MM, Kampshoff CS, Persoon S, Groen W, van Mechelen W, Chinapaw MJM, et al. Validation and refinement of prediction models to estimate exercise capacity in cancer survivors using the steep ramp test. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;98(11):2167&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2017.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer K, Samek L, Schwaibold M, Westbrook S, Hajric R, Beneke R, et al. Interval training in patients with severe chronic heart failure: analysis and recommendations for exercise procedures. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29(3):306&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9139168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199703000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberger F, Schneider J, Schlueter K, Paratte JL, Wiskemann J. Vertebral fracture during one repetition maximum testing in a breast cancer survivor: A case report. Medicine (Baltimore). 2021;100(20):e25705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8137013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000025705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength Testing&#x2014;Predicting a One-Rep Max from Reps-to-Fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance. 1993;64(1):88&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodermaier A, Millman RD. Accuracy of the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale as a screening tool in cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2011;19(12):1899&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21898134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz-Bermejo L, Adsuar JC, Mendoza-Munoz M, Barrios-Fernandez S, Garcia-Gordillo MA, Perez-Gomez J, et al. Test-retest reliability of five times sit to stand test (FTSST) in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biology (Basel). 2021;10(6):510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34207604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8228261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrico M, Guerreiro CS, Parreira A. The validity of the Patient-Generated Subjective Global Assessment Short-form(c) in cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;43:296&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2021.03.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laza-Cagigas R, Larumbe-Zabala E, Rampal T, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Effect of prehabilitation programmes on functional capacity in patients awaiting oncological resections: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32(10):667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39287834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11408567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molenaar CJL, Minnella EM, Coca-Martinez M, Ten Cate DWG, Regis M, Awasthi R, et al. Effect of multimodal prehabilitation on reducing postoperative complications and enhancing functional capacity following colorectal cancer surgery: the PREHAB randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2023;158(6):572&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10061316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2023.0198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnella EM, Awasthi R, Loiselle SE, Agnihotram RV, Ferri LE, Carli F. Effect of exercise and nutrition prehabilitation on functional capacity in Esophagogastric cancer surgery: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2018;153(12):1081&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30193337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6583009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2018.1645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnella EM, Awasthi R, Bousquet-Dion G, Ferreira V, Austin B, Audi C, et al. Multimodal prehabilitation to enhance functional capacity following radical cystectomy: a randomized controlled trial. Eur Urol Focus. 2021;7(1):132&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31186173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euf.2019.05.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myles PS. More than just morbidity and mortality - quality of recovery and long-term functional recovery after surgery. Anaesthesia. 2020;75(Suppl 1):e143&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31903564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strijker D, Hoogeboom TJ, Meijerink J, Taveirne A, Schreurs WH, van Laarhoven C, et al. Multimodal rehabilitation (Fit4Chemo) before and during adjuvant chemotherapy in patients with colonic cancer. Br J Surg. 2024;111(1):znad354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37941132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10771254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjs/znad354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen SN, Krabek R, Yfanti C, Sjoberg S, Sundberg A, Dalsgaard DM, et al. Postoperative Exercise Training in Patients with Colorectal Liver Metastases A Randomized Controlled Trial. Ann Surg. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0000000000006587 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000006587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39523954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11086676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday LJ, Boshier PR, Doganay E, Wynter-Blyth V, Buckley JP, Moorthy K. The effects of prehabilitation on body composition in patients undergoing multimodal therapy for esophageal cancer. Dis Esophagus. 2023;36(2):doac046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35795994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9885737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/dote/doac046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Erven C, Ten Cate D, van Lieshout R, Beijer S, Dieleman J, Geertsema S, et al. Changes in nutritional status and effectiveness of the dietary intervention of multimodal prehabilitation for patients with colorectal cancer: A secondary analysis of the PREHAB randomized clinical trial. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2025;65:469&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39734017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2024.12.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dronkers J, Witteman B, van Meeteren N. Surgery and functional mobility: doing the right thing at the right time. Tech Coloproctol. 2016;20(6):339&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10151-016-1487-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer M, Bischoff C, Lassing J, Gockel I, Falz R. Effects of postoperative physical exercise rehabilitation on cardiorespiratory fitness, functional capacity and quality of life in patients with colorectal, breast, and prostate cancer - a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol. 2024;151(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39718582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11668849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00432-024-06064-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy EJ, Deane CS, Lund JN, Phillips BE. Loss of muscle mass in the immediate post-operative period is associated with inadequate dietary protein and energy intake. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2023;77(4):503&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10115623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-023-01264-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heger P, Probst P, Wiskemann J, Steindorf K, Diener MK, Mihaljevic AL. A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Physical Exercise Prehabilitation in Major Abdominal Surgery (PROSPERO 2017 CRD42017080366). J Gastrointest Surg. 2020;24(6):1375&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31228083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11605-019-04287-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnella EM, Awasthi R, Gillis C, Fiore JF Jr, Liberman AS, Charlebois P, et al. Patients with poor baseline walking capacity are most likely to improve their functional status with multimodal prehabilitation. Surgery. 2016;160(4):1070&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27476586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surg.2016.05.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>