<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41811121</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Characteristics That Differentiate Playing Levels of Male Rugby Union Players: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1013</StartPage><EndPage>1022</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1013-1022</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005203</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Payne, LKD, Varley, MC, Driller, MW, and James, LP. Physical characteristics that differentiate playing levels of male rugby union players: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 39(9): 1013-1022, 2025-The distinct strength and speed characteristics differentiating Rugby Union athletes by playing level remain unclear, as do their associations with game performance indicators. This review systematically evaluated physical characteristics of adult male Rugby Union athletes across professional, semi-professional, and amateur levels. Five databases (PubMed, CINAHL, SPORTDiscus, Web of Science, Scopus) were searched, yielding 54 eligible studies. Higher-level athletes consistently demonstrated superior heavy dynamic strength (5/5 studies) and fast dynamic strength (3/3 studies). Results were mixed for acceleration (4/5 studies) and maximal sprint speed (3/6 studies), whereas limited evidence supported greater maximal isometric strength (1/1 study) and reactive strength (1/1 study). Explosive strength remains unexplored. Significant associations were observed between strength and speed characteristics and game performance indicators, except for explosive strength because of a lack of investigation. Heavy and fast dynamic strength emerged as key differentiators of playing levels and correlated strongly with game performance metrics. In contrast, findings for sprint speed and acceleration were inconsistent. This review highlights critical gaps in research, particularly regarding maximal isometric, explosive, and reactive strength, providing insights for future studies and practical applications in Rugby Union training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Payne</LastName><ForeName>Leslie K D</ForeName><Initials>LKD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-8991-3119</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varley</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driller</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Lachlan P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="Y">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000054" MajorTopicYN="N">Acceleration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">speed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stratification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41811121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202509000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Argus CK, Gill ND, Keogh JWL. Characterization of the differences in strength and power between different levels of competition in rugby union athletes. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2698&#x2013;2704, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DG, Newton RU. Comparison of lower body strength, power, acceleration, speed, agility, and sprint momentum to describe and compare playing rank among professional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 22: 153&#x2013;158, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr MJ, Sheppard JM, Agar-Newman DJ, Newton RU. Transfer effect of strength and power training to the sprinting kinematics of international rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2585&#x2013;2596, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr MJ, Sheppard JM, Gabbett TJ, Newton RU. Long-term training-induced changes in sprinting speed and sprint momentum in elite rugby union players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2724&#x2013;2731, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady CJ, Harrison AJ, Flanagan EP, Haff GG, Comyns TM. The relationship between isometric strength and sprint acceleration in sprinters. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 38&#x2013;45, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brannigan J. Training Strength and Power in Rugby Union. Strength and Conditioning for Rugby Union. Crowood Lane, Marlborough, United Kingdom: Crowood, 2016. p. 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Antrobus M, Stebbings GK, et al. Anthropometric and physiological characteristics of elite male rugby athletes. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1790&#x2013;1801, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahill N, Lamb K, Worsfold P, Headey R, Murray S. The movement characteristics of English premiership rugby union players. J Sports Sci 31: 229&#x2013;237, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Doyle TLA, Benson AC. A cross-sectional lower-body power profile of elite and sub-elite Australian football players. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2836&#x2013;2841, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavda S, Hill M, Martin S, et al. Weightlifting: An applied method of technical analysis. Strength Cond J 43: 32&#x2013;42, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coghetto G, Zanrosso EM, Rabello R, da Ros JL, Rodrigues R. Association between success and unsuccess rates on technical skills and physical qualities in rugby players. Res Q Exerc Sport 94: 254&#x2013;262, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Haigh A, Matthews MJ. Are changes in maximal squat strength during preseason training reflected in changes in sprint performance in rugby league players? J Strength Cond Res 26: 772&#x2013;776, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham D, West D, Owen N, et al. Strength and power predictors of sprinting performance in professional rugby players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 53: 105&#x2013;111, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham DJ, Shearer DA, Drawer S, et al. Relationships between physical qualities and key performance indicators during match-play in senior international rugby union players. PLoS One 13: e0202811, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Hollander S, Brown J, Lambert M, Treu P, Hendricks S. Skills associated with line breaks in elite rugby union. J Sports Sci Med 15: 501&#x2013;508, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimundo F, Cole M, Blagrove R, et al. Talent identification and development in male rugby union: A systematic review. J Expertise 4: 33&#x2013;55, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duthie GM, Pyne DB, Marsh DJ, Hooper SL. Sprint patterns in rugby union players during competition. J Strength Cond Res 20: 208&#x2013;214, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duthie GM. A framework for the physical development of elite rugby union players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 1: 2&#x2013;13, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dymond C, Flanagan E, Turner A. The relationship between maximal strength and plyometric ability in rugby players. Portuguese J Sport Sci 11: 77&#x2013;80, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgueta-Cancino E, Evans E, Martinez-Valdes E, Falla D. The effect of resistance training on motor unit firing properties: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 13: 817631, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Influence of fatigue on tackling ability in rugby league players: Role of muscular strength, endurance, and aerobic qualities. PLoS One 11: e0163161, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin MJ, Deuchrass RW, Elliot CE, Manimmanakorn N. Short and long-term differences in anthropometric characteristics and physical performance between male rugby players that became professional or remained amateur. J Exerc Sci Fitness 19: 143&#x2013;149, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen KT, Cronin JB, Pickering SL, Douglas L. Do force-time and power-time measures in a loaded jump squat differentiate between speed performance and playing level in elite and elite junior rugby union players? J Strength Cond Res 25: 2382&#x2013;2391, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart AS, Erskine RM, McLaughlin TJ, Clark DR. Physical characteristics explain ball-carrying capability in sub-elite rugby union players. J Sci Sport Exerc 5: 244&#x2013;253, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heather O, Lander P, Rayner R. Practice to pitch: The relationship between force-velocity profiles and match-day performance of semi-professional rugby union players. Front Sports Active Living 5: 1066767, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannis G. Comparison of physical capacities strength and speed of different competition level football players. J Phys Educ Sport 13: 255&#x2013;259, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Young WB, Newton RU, Gastin PB. Strength classification and diagnosis not all strength is created equal. J Strength Cond Res 45(3): 333&#x2013;341, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL, Faigenbaum AD, et al. Long-term athletic development, part 2: Barriers to success and potential solutions. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1451&#x2013;1464, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JB, Cowley N, Weakley J. The role of speed, change of direction, and momentum by position and starting status in Division 1 collegiate football players. J Strength Cond Res 10: 519&#x2013;557, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JB, Mayhew JL, Dos Santos ML, Dawes JJ, Signorile JF. Momentum, rather than velocity, is a more effective measure of improvements in Division IA football player performance. J Strength Cond Res 36: 551&#x2013;557, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meir R, Newton R, Curtis E, Fardell M, Butler B. Physical fitness qualities of professional rugby league football players: Determination of positional differences. J Strength Cond Res 15: 450&#x2013;458, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misseldine ND, Blagrove RC, Goodwin JE. Speed demands of women's rugby sevens match play. J Strength Cond Res 35: 183&#x2013;189, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev 4: 1, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters A, Leduc C, Piscione J, Lacome M, Carling C, Babault N. Anthropometric and physical characteristics in U16, U18 and U20 elite French youth rugby union players. PLoS One 18: e0295623, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira LA, Cal Abad CC, Kobal R, et al. Differences in speed and power capacities between female national college team and national Olympic team handball athletes. J Hum Kinet 63: 85&#x2013;94, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarrie KL, Wilson BD. Force production in the rugby union scrum. J Sports Sci 18: 237&#x2013;246, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarrie KL, Hopkins WG, Anthony MJ, Gill ND. Positional demands of international rugby union: Evaluation of player actions and movements. J Sci Med Sport 16: 353&#x2013;359, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Kelly VG, Connick MJ, Beckman EM. Predicting rugby league tackle outcomes using strength and power principal components. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 278&#x2013;285, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Whitley R, et al. The relationship between match tackle outcomes and muscular strength and power in professional rugby league. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2853&#x2013;2861, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan A, Malone S, Walters A, Gabbett T, Collins K. Match-play profile of elite rugby union, with special reference to repeated high-intensity effort activity (RHIE). Sport Sci Health 18: 947&#x2013;956, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart DJ, Hopkins WG, Gill ND. Differences and changes in the physical characteristics of professional and amateur rugby union players. J Strength Cond Res 27: 3033&#x2013;3044, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart D, Hopkins WG, Quarrie KL, Gill N. The relationship between physical fitness and game behaviours in rugby union players. Eur J Sport Sci 14: S8&#x2013;S17, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Styles WJ, Matthews MJ, Comfort P. Effects of strength training on squat and sprint performance in soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1534&#x2013;1539, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins CM, Storey A, McGuigan MR, Downes P, Gill ND. Horizontal force-velocity-power profiling of rugby players: A cross-sectional analysis of competition-level and position-specific movement demands. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1576&#x2013;1585, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Sun Y, Yang C, et al. Biomechanical insights into differences between the mid-acceleration and maximum velocity phases of sprinting. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1906&#x2013;1916, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaloy S, Gir&#xe1;ldez J, Gazzo F, Villaseca-Vicu&#xf1;a R, Gonz&#xe1;lez JG. In-season assessment of sprint speed and sprint momentum in rugby players according to the age category and playing position. J Hum Kinet 77: 274&#x2013;286, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanrosso EM, Coghetto G, Rabello R, et al. Physical and performance indicators between backs and forwards in a subelite Rugby Union Team. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 62: 1435&#x2013;1439, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>