<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41721342</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1757-2215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ovarian research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ovarian Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrative bioinformatics, single-cell and experimental evidence for a BPA-m6A-apoptosis axis in granulosa cell dysfunction in polycystic ovary syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">97</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13048-026-02038-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is increasingly viewed as an environmentally influenced, epigenetically mediated reproductive&#x2013;metabolic disorder. Bisphenol A (BPA) exposure is higher in women with PCOS and has been linked to hyperandrogenism, insulin resistance and ovarian dysfunction, while N6-methyladenosine (m6A) dysregulation contributes to granulosa cells (GCs) proliferation and apoptosis. However, the downstream gene networks that integrate BPA exposure, m6A imbalance and GCs apoptosis in PCOS remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">BPA-related genes were retrieved from the Comparative Toxicogenomics Database and intersected with PCOS differentially expressed genes from four GEO GC datasets (GSE34526, GSE137684, GSE102293, GSE80432) and m6A/apoptosis-related genes from GeneCards. Protein&#x2013;protein interaction, GO/KEGG enrichment, GSEA and immune-cell infiltration (ssGSEA) analyses were performed. A five-gene logistic model and nomogram were built and externally validated in GSE106724 and GSE98595. Single-cell RNA-seq data (GSE268919) were used to map hub-gene expression, m6A and apoptosis signatures across ovarian cell types. Molecular docking (AutoDock Vina) evaluated BPA&#x2013;protein binding. Hub-gene expression and function were verified in primary human GCs and BPA-treated KGN cells by qPCR, Western blot, CCK-8 and flow cytometry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 139 BPA&#x2013;PCOS shared genes and five hub genes&#x2014;LIFR, LMNA, BCL2, ADM, S100P&#x2014;enriched in ovarian steroidogenesis, oxidative-stress and apoptotic pathways. These genes showed distinct expression patterns between PCOS and controls and were associated with altered immune-cell infiltration. A five-gene nomogram achieved an AUC of 0.846 in the training set and 0.791 in an external validation cohort, with good calibration and decision-curve benefit. Single-cell analysis revealed LIFR downregulation and LMNA upregulation in GCs clusters with high m6A and apoptosis scores. Docking predicted moderate-to-strong BPA binding to all five proteins. In vitro, BPA reduced GCs viability, increased apoptosis with BAX/Caspase-3 activation, and reproduced the hub-gene dysregulation observed in PCOS GCs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our integrative data support a BPA&#x2013;m6A&#x2013;apoptosis axis in PCOS and identify a five-gene granulosa-cell signature with potential diagnostic utility, providing mechanistic insight and candidate targets for environmentally driven PCOS; however, its clinical utility requires validation in larger, independent and prospectively recruited cohorts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This work is an observational and experimental laboratory study and not a clinical trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13048-026-02038-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Xiumei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiujuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hailong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Clinical Medicine for Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology and Pediatrics, Fujian Medical University, No. 18, Daoshan Road, Fuzhou, 350001, China. huanghailong@fjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025J01202</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Fujian Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025Y9645</GrantID><Agency>Joint Funds for the Innovation of Science and Technology, Fujian Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Ovarian Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474849</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1757-2215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endocrine disruptors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epigenetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Granulosa cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N6-methyladenosine (m6A)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polycystic ovary syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study involving human participants was approved by the Ethics Committee of Fujian Maternity and Child Health Hospital (Approval No. 2025KY222). All procedures were conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent to participate was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41721342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12980904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-026-02038-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13048-026-02038-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lemogne RA, Oliveira TE, Jota BC. Effects of endocrine disruptive chemicals (EDCs) and therapeutic approaches to the polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS): A current state-of-the-art. Environ Toxicol Pharmacol. 2025;120:104842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.etap.2025.104842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41067401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobar-Morreale HF. Polycystic ovary syndrome: definition, aetiology, diagnosis and treatment. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2018;14(5):270&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrendo.2018.24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruni V, Capozzi A, Lello S. The Role of Genetics, Epigenetics and Lifestyle in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome Development: the State of the Art. Reprod Sci. 2022;29(3):668&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43032-021-00515-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33709373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozga M, Jurewicz J. Environmental exposure to selected non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review. Int J Occup Med Environ Health. 2025;38(2):98&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13075/ijomeh.1896.02551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12064351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40200737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzouma Z, Dourou P, Diamanti A, Harizopoulou V, Papalexis P, Karampas G, et al. Associations Between Endocrine-Disrupting Chemical Exposure and Fertility Outcomes: A Decade of Human Epidemiological Evidence. Life (Basel). 2025;15(7):996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12299029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40724496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan W, Tang W, Shen X, Xu H, Zhang J. Exposure to bisphenol A and its analogs and polycystic ovarian syndrome in women of childbearing age: A multicenter case-control study. Chemosphere. 2023;313:137463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.137463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Zhang N, Zhu Q, Hu Y, Wang X, Weng X, et al. Exposure to Multiple Endocrine-Disrupting Chemicals and Associations with Female Infertility: A Case-Control Study. Environ Health (Wash). 2024;2(12):902&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/envhealth.4c00040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11667288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39722846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossein RB, Amanlou M, Behrouzi LT, Ghazizadeh M, Haghollahi F, Bagheri M, et al. The Association Between Bisphenol A and Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome: A Case-Control Study. Acta Med Iran. 2017;55(12):759&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29373882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandaraki E, Chatzigeorgiou A, Livadas S, Palioura E, Economou F, Koutsilieris M, et al. Endocrine disruptors and polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS): elevated serum levels of bisphenol A in women with PCOS. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011;96(3):E480&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2010-1658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominissini D, Moshitch-Moshkovitz S, Schwartz S, Salmon-Divon M, Ungar L, Osenberg S, et al. Topology of the human and mouse m6A RNA methylomes revealed by m6A-seq. Nature. 2012;485(7397):201&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature11112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22575960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng LJ, Deng WQ, Fan SR, Chen MF, Qi M, Lyu WY, et al. m6A modification: recent advances, anticancer targeted drug discovery and beyond. Mol Cancer. 2022;21(1):52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-022-01510-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8842557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35164788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang Y, Chang HM, Leung PCK, Bai L, Zhu Y. RNA modifications in female reproductive physiology and disease: emerging roles and clinical implications. Hum Reprod Update. 2025;31(4):333&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humupd/dmaf005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40152541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing YX, Li HX, Yue F, Li YM, Yu X, He JJ, et al. N6-methyladenosine demethylase FTO related to hyperandrogenism in PCOS via AKT pathway. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2023;39(1):2276167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09513590.2023.2276167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37931646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao F, Wu L, Wang Q, Zhao X, Chen T, Yin C, et al. Insulin-like growth factor 2 mRNA-binding protein 2-regulated alternative splicing of nuclear factor 1&#xa0;C-type causes excessive granulosa cell proliferation in polycystic ovary syndrome. Cell Prolif. 2022;55(4):e13216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpr.13216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9055906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao YY, Song N, Fang XY, Lu XT, Sun N, Jin HX, et al. YTHDF2 regulates MSS51 expression contributing to mitochondria dysfunction of granulosa cells in polycystic ovarian syndrome patients. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2024;592:112292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mce.2024.112292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabry R, Gallo JF, Rooney C, Scandlan OLM, Davis OS, Amin S, et al. Genetic and Epigenetic Profiles of Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome and In Vitro Bisphenol Exposure in a Human Granulosa Cell Model. Biomedicines. 2024;12(1):1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines12010237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10813104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38275408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Zhang X, Chen J, Du X, Sun Y, Zhan L, et al. Exploring the molecular mechanisms by which per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances induce polycystic ovary syndrome through in silico toxicogenomic data mining. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf. 2024;275:116251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38537477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M, Yang X, Zhou M, Zhang J, Yu B, Lian H, et al. Integrated single-cell and spatial transcriptomics reveal microenvironment disruptions by androgen in mouse ovary. iScience. 2024;27(10):111028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isci.2024.111028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11490719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39429789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Cui Z, Liu Z, Fan H, Lan Y, Luo J, et al. MiR-204 regulates autophagy and cell viability by targeting BDNF and inhibiting the NTRK2-dependent PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway in a human granulosa cell line exposed to bisphenol A. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf. 2024;287:117304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.117304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39520743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Du K, Luo K, Wang L, Hua F. Mitigating bisphenol A-induced apoptosis in KGN cells: the therapeutic role of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) through upregulation of PGC-1alpha expression and inhibition of the mitochondrial cytochrome c pathway. Horm (Athens). 2024;23(3):363&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42000-024-00539-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38421590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celar SD, Rezen T, Jancar N, Virant-Klun I. Bisphenol a Disrupts Steroidogenesis and Induces Apoptosis in Human Granulosa Cells Cultured In Vitro. Int J Mol Sci. 2025;26(9):4081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26094081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12071243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40362320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajkumar A, Luu T, Beal MA, Barton-Maclaren TS, Robaire B, Hales BF. Elucidation of the Effects of Bisphenol A and Structural Analogs on Germ and Steroidogenic Cells Using Single Cell High-Content Imaging. Toxicol Sci. 2021;180(2):224&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/toxsci/kfab012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8041462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Jin H, Kim G, Bae J. A low dose of bisphenol A stimulates estradiol production by regulating beta-catenin-FOXL2-CYP19A1 pathway in human ovarian granulosa cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2021;583:192&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2021.10.070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34749236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury EU, Banu H, Morshed MS, Jahan IA, Kharel S, Hasanat MA. Raised Bisphenol A has a Significant Association with Adverse Reproductive Manifestations Rather than Biochemical or Hormonal Aberrations in Women with Polycystic Ovary Syndrome. J ASEAN Fed Endocr Soc. 2025;40(1):26&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12097971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40416478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srnovrsnik T, Virant-Klun I, Pinter B. Polycystic Ovary Syndrome and Endocrine Disruptors (Bisphenols, Parabens, and Triclosan)-A Systematic Review. Life (Basel). 2023;13(1):237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9864804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36676087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbanetz L, Junior JMS, Maciel GAR, Simoes RDS, Baracat MCP, Baracat EC. Does bisphenol A (BPA) participates in the pathogenesis of Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS)? Clin (Sao Paulo). 2023;78:100310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinsp.2023.100310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38008036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed M, Suramya, Mangla A, Jindal G, Bhutto HN, Shahid S, et al. Bisphenol A-induced polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) with hormonal and metabolic implications in rats. Reprod Toxicol. 2025;131:108750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reprotox.2024.108750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39549768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, He C, Xu S, Gao Y, Wang K, Liang M, et al. Bisphenol A triggers apoptosis in mouse pre-antral follicle granulosa cells via oxidative stress. J Ovarian Res. 2024;17(1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-023-01322-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10790560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38229135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin T, Zhang X, Guo T, Yang T, Gao Y, Hao W, et al. Epigenetic Alteration Shaped by the Environmental Chemical Bisphenol A. Front Genet. 2020;11:618966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2020.618966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33505438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombo M, Fernandez-Diez C, Gonzalez-Rojo S, Herraez MP. Genetic and epigenetic alterations induced by bisphenol A exposure during different periods of spermatogenesis: from spermatozoa to the progeny. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):18029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-54368-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31792261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Lu J, Li H, Huang B. The Role of m(6)A on Female Reproduction and Fertility: From Gonad Development to Ovarian Aging. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2022;10:884295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2022.884295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35712673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang E, Chen L. RNA N(6)-methyladenosine modification in female reproductive biology and pathophysiology. Cell Commun Signal. 2023;21(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12964-023-01078-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9996912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36894952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang ZX, Wang YN, Li ZY, Dai ZH, He Y, Chu K, et al. The m6A mRNA demethylase FTO in granulosa cells retards FOS-dependent ovarian aging. Cell Death Dis. 2021;12(8):744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-021-04016-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Fang Y, Xu Y, Sun H. Role of m6A modification in female infertility and reproductive system diseases. Int J Biol Sci. 2022;18(9):3592&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijbs.69771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9254474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Han X, Li W, Wang N, Yao L, Zhao Y, et al. N6-methyladenosine Demethylase FTO Induces the Dysfunctions of Ovarian Granulosa Cells by Upregulating Flotillin 2. Reprod Sci. 2022;29(4):1305&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43032-021-00664-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34254281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Deng W, Liu Q, Wang P, Yang W, Ni W. Altered m(6) A modification is involved in up-regulated expression of FOXO3 in luteinized granulosa cells of non-obese polycystic ovary syndrome patients. J Cell Mol Med. 2020;24(20):11874&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.15807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32869942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Liu C, Chen M, Yan J, Wang C, Zuo Z, et al. The interference effects of bisphenol A on the synthesis of steroid hormones in human ovarian granulosa cells. Environ Toxicol. 2021;36(4):665&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tox.23070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33258555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi J, Liu L, Yang J, Gao X, Zhang W. Bisphenol A decreases progesterone synthesis in human ovarian granulosa cells. Birth Defects Res. 2020;112(20):1843&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bdr2.1817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33073540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M, Huang M, Li X, Liu S, Fu L, Jiang X, et al. Bisphenol A induces apoptosis through GPER-dependent activation of the ROS/Ca(2+)-ASK1-JNK pathway in human granulosa cell line KGN. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf. 2021;208:111429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2020.111429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33039870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoemaker R, Huang MF, Wu YS, Huang CS, Lee DF. Decoding the molecular symphony: interactions between the m(6)A and p53 signaling pathways in cancer. NAR Cancer. 2024;6(3):zcae037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/narcan/zcae037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11426327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39329012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yan C, Xie Q, Wu B, Zhang Y. Exposure to bisphenol A affects transcriptome-wide N6-methyladenine methylation in ovarian granulosa cells. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf. 2024;272:116071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38354435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena S, Rubio M, Vargas C, Alanis C, Paredes AH. Participation of leukaemia inhibitory factor in follicular development and steroidogenesis in rat ovaries. J Endocrinol. 2023;258(1):e220255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/JOE-22-0255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37078922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadoret V, Jarrier-Gaillard P, Papillier P, Monniaux D, Guerif F, Dalbies-Tran R. Leukaemia inhibitory factor modulates the differentiation of granulosa cells during sheep in vitro preantral to antral follicle development and improves oocyte meiotic competence. Mol Hum Reprod. 2021;27(9):gaab051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molehr/gaab051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34411256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao QH, Sun NN, Wang MS, Zhao WX, Liu W, Zhang X, et al. Effect of the LIF gene on the cell cycle and apoptosis of ovarian granulosa cells in white Muscovy ducks. Theriogenology. 2024;230:91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.theriogenology.2024.09.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39278133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai B, Li X, Zhao Z, Cao Y, Liu X, Liu Z, et al. Melatonin Protects the Apoptosis of Sheep Granulosa Cells by Suppressing Oxidative Stress via MAP3K8 and FOS Pathway. Genes (Basel). 2023;14(5):1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes14051067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Dong Y, Wang Z, Ding H, Wang J, Zhao J, et al. Melatonin Attenuates Oxidative Stress-Induced Apoptosis of Bovine Ovarian Granulosa Cells by Promoting Mitophagy via SIRT1/FoxO1 Signaling Pathway. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(16):12854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241612854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10454225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37629033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maynard S, Keijzers G, Akbari M, Ezra MB, Hall A, Morevati M, et al. Lamin A/C promotes DNA base excision repair. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(22):11709&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7145687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31647095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maynard S, Hall A, Galanos P, Rizza S, Yamamoto T, Gram HH, et al. Lamin A/C impairments cause mitochondrial dysfunction by attenuating PGC1alpha and the NAMPT-NAD+ pathway. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50(17):9948&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9508839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36099415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samanta A, Biswas S, Ghosh S, Banerjee S, Dam B, Maitra S. Maternal exposure to chronic, low-dose nonylphenol in zebrafish: Disruption of ovarian health, reproductive function, and embryogenesis. J Environ Manage. 2025;375:124169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39842349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celar SD, Virant KI. Negative effects of endocrine disruptor bisphenol A on ovarian granulosa cells and the protective role of folic acid. Reproduction. 2023;165(5):R117&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/REP-22-0257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36795652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong J, Thi Quynh Mai N, Moon BS, Choi JK. Impact of polystyrene microplastics (PS-MPs) on the entire female mouse reproductive cycle: Assessing reproductive toxicity of microplastics through in vitro follicle culture. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf. 2025;297:118228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2025.118228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40315747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodanch SM, Mukherjee S, Prabhu NB, Kabekkodu SP, Bhat SK, Rai PS. Altered mitochondrial homeostasis on bisphenol-A exposure and its association in developing polycystic ovary syndrome: A comprehensive review. Reprod Toxicol. 2024;130:108700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reprotox.2024.108700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39181417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboulghar M. Role of adrenomedullin in reproduction and endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2018;109(6):1010&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2018.02.133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29935635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CL, Lo WC, Lee TH, Sung JY, Sung YJ. Oocyte-specific disruption of adrenomedullin 2 gene enhances ovarian follicle growth after superovulation. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2022;13:1047498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2022.1047498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9702065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia C, Braunstein Z, Toomey AC, Zhong J, Rao X. S100 Proteins As an Important Regulator of Macrophage Inflammation. Front Immunol. 2017;8:1908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2017.01908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5770888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29379499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Park NR, Park EK, Kim JE. S100P binds to RAGE and activates ERK/NF-kappaB signaling to promote osteoclast differentiation and activity. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2024;738:150536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2024.150536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39146619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M, Yang X, Li L, Li H, Zhang G, Liu W, et al. Integrated transcriptomic and co-expression network analysis identifies immune-metabolic biomarkers of polycystic ovary syndrome in granulosa cells. J Ovarian Res. 2025;18(1):248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-025-01835-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12604246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Xiong D, Yan H, Long F, Zhang G, Zeng J, et al. MMP-9 dysregulation and chronic inflammation in polycystic ovary syndrome: linking ovulatory dysfunction to diagnostic implications. J Ovarian Res. 2025;18(1):247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-025-01851-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12604328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng L, Zhu Q, Xiang Y, Cao T, Cai J, Liang N, et al. METTL3-mediated m(6)A modification of CD36: Implications for glucose metabolism and inflammatory dysregulation in follicles of polycystic ovary syndrome. Int Immunopharmacol. 2024;143(Pt 1):113327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2024.113327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39395382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooda I, Mear L, Hassan J, Damdimopoulou P. The adult ovary at single cell resolution: an expert review. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2025;232(4S):S95.e1-S.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40253085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Hua R, Quan S. N6-methyladenosine regulator-mediated methylation modification patterns and immune infiltration characterization in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS). J Ovarian Res. 2023;16(1):73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-023-01147-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10091541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37046273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Gengxiao Y, Wu Y, Li Y, Hu X, Bie J. Comprehensive analysis of cuproptosis and m6A-Target gene signatures for diagnostic significance and immune microenvironment characterization in polycystic ovary syndrome. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):19996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-03396-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12144264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40481029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kourmaeva E, Sabry R, Favetta LA. Bisphenols A and F, but not S, induce apoptosis in bovine granulosa cells via the intrinsic mitochondrial pathway. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2022;13:1028438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2022.1028438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9650025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36387888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, He X, Huang J, Yu S, Cui M, Gao M, et al. Short-chain fatty acid-butyric acid ameliorates granulosa cells inflammation through regulating METTL3-mediated N6-methyladenosine modification of FOSL2 in polycystic ovarian syndrome. Clin Epigenetics. 2023;15(1):86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13148-023-01487-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10183145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X, Zhang Z, Hou M, Yang X, Cui L. Plasma exosomes and contained MiRNAs affect the reproductive phenotype in polycystic ovary syndrome. FASEB J. 2023;37(7):e22960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202201940RR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzolino M, Herraiz S, Titus S, Roberts L, Romeu M, Peinado I, et al. Transcriptomic landscape of granulosa cells and peripheral blood mononuclear cells in women with PCOS compared to young poor responders and women with normal response. Hum Reprod. 2022;37(6):1274&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/deac069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9156844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Shi X, Xu B, Wang Z, Chen Y, Deng M. Differential expression of plasma&#x2013;derived exosomal miRNAs in polycystic ovary syndrome as a circulating biomarker. Biomed Rep. 2023;19(6):92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/br.2023.1674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10603371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37901874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Pan S, Li Y, Wu X. Exosomal miR-143-3p derived from follicular fluid promotes granulosa cell apoptosis by targeting BMPR1A in polycystic ovary syndrome. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):4359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-08423-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan D, Luo J, Sun Y, Hao L, Zheng J, Yang Z. PCOS follicular fluid derived exosomal miR-424-5p induces granulosa cells senescence by targeting CDCA4 expression. Cell Signal. 2021;85:110030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellsig.2021.110030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui X, Lei X, Huang T, Mao X, Shen Z, Yang X, et al. Follicular fluid-derived extracellular vesicles miR-34a-5p regulates granulosa cell glycolysis in polycystic ovary syndrome by targeting LDHA. J Ovarian Res. 2024;17(1):223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-024-01542-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11562512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39538292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esfandyari S, Elkafas H, Chugh RM, Park HS, Navarro A, Al-Hendy A. Exosomes as Biomarkers for Female Reproductive Diseases Diagnosis and Therapy. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(4):2165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22042165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7926632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montazerian M, Yasari F, Aghaalikhani N. Ovarian extracellular MicroRNAs as the potential non-invasive biomarkers: An update. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;106:1633&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2018.07.073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30119239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>