<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851754</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strength training and detraining in female dancesport athletes: adaptations and retention of lower limb muscle architecture, strength, and dance performance.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01656-2</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Jingting</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Hubei Normal University, Huangshi, China. jingting.lu@hbnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sports Science Programme, School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia. jingting.lu@hbnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Tze-Huan</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Hubei Normal University, Huangshi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zamri</LastName><ForeName>Eva Nabiha Binti</ForeName><Initials>ENB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sports Science Programme, School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaharudin</LastName><ForeName>Shazlin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sports Science Programme, School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia. shazlin@usm.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Science of Learning in Education Centre, National Institute of Education, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Singapore. shazlin@usm.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 2025GB258</GrantID><Agency>Hubei Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Female health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isokinetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports medicine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All recruitment and experimental procedures were approved by the Human Research Ethics Committee of Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM/JEPeM/KK/23040282) and conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The study was registered with ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT07164599). This study adheres to the CONSORT reporting guidelines. Written and oral informed consent were obtained from all participants before enrollment. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01656-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01656-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Monte A, Franchi MV. Regional muscle features and their association with knee extensors force production at a single joint angle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123(10):2239&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-023-05237-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currier BS, Mcleod JC, Banfield L, Beyene J, Welton NJ, D&#x2019;Souza AC, et al. Resistance training prescription for muscle strength and hypertrophy in healthy adults: a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(18):1211&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2023-106807. PubMed PMID: 37414459; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC10579494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arundale AJH, McNulty R, Snyder C, O&#x2019;Brien J, St&#xf6;ggl T. Injury, training, biomechanical, and physiological profiles of professional breakdancers. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18(5):1123&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.87762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong W, Geok SK, Samsudin S, Zhao Y, Ma H, Zhang X. Effects of strength training on neuromuscular adaptations in the development of maximal strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):19315. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-03070-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;vila-Carvalho L, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o F, Escobar-&#xc1;lvarez JA, Gondra B, Leite I, Rama L. The effect of 16 weeks of lower-limb strength training in jumping performance of ballet dancers. Front Physiol. 2022;12:774327. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.774327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown AC, Wells TJ, Schade ML, Smith DL, Fehling PC. Effects of plyometric training versus traditional weight training on strength, power, and aesthetic jumping ability in female collegiate dancers. J Dance Med Sci. 2007;11(2):38&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1177/1089313X0701100202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moita JP, Nunes A, Esteves J, Oliveira R, Xarez L. The relationship between muscular strength and dance injuries: a systematic review. Med Probl Perform Artists. 2017;32(1):40&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.21091/mppa.2017.1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel DA, Kamen G, Frost G. Neural adaptations to resistive exercise: mechanisms and recommendations for training practices. Sports Med. 2006;36(2):133&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200636020-00004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;karabot J, Brownstein CG, Casolo A, Del Vecchio A, Ansdell P. The knowns and unknowns of neural adaptations to resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(3):675&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-020-04567-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysenko EA, Vinogradova OL, Popov DV. The mechanisms of muscle mass and strength increase during strength training. J Evol Biochem Phys. 2021;57(4):862&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1134/S0022093021040104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWeese BH, Hornsby G, Stone M, Stone MH. The training process: planning for strength&#x2013;power training in track and field. Part 1: theoretical aspects. J Sport Health Sci. 2015;4(4):308&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jshs.2015.07.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part I: short term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med. 2000;30(2):79&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200030020-00002. PubMed PMID: 10966148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Muscular characteristics of detraining in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(8):1297&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200108000-00009. PubMed PMID: 11474330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Xu J. Analysis of research progress in dancesport domestically and internationally: a visualization study based on scientific knowledge mapping. J Beijing Sport Univ. 2018;41(4):89&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.19582/j.cnki.11-3785/g8.2018.04.013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Zhang Q. Research on the attributes and characteristics of dancesport under the value orientation of sports competition. J Capital Univ Phys Educ Sports. 2017;29(5):447&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.14036/j.cnki.cn11-4513.2017.05.015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel NA, Vissers D, Kuppens K, Fransen E, Truijen S, Nijs J, et al. Effect of a physical conditioning versus health promotion intervention in dancers: a randomized controlled trial. Man Therap. 2014;19(6):562&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.math.2014.05.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twitchett E. Physiological demands of performance in classical ballet and their relationships with injury and aesthetic components. 2009. Available from: https://wlv.openrepository.com/handle/2436/89157.&#xa0;[cited 2024 Aug 12].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeding JRE, Visser E, Meuffels DE, de Vos RJ. Is training load associated with symptoms of overuse injury in dancers? A prospective observational study. j dance med sci. 2019;23(1):11&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.12678/1089-313X.23.1.11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanke EM, Schreiter J, Groneberg DA, Weisser B. Muscular imbalances and balance capability in dance. J Occup Med Toxicol. 2018;13(1):36. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12995-018-0218-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlovi&#x107; M, Ogrinc N, &#x160;arabon N. Body asymmetries as risk factors for musculoskeletal injuries in dancesport, hip-hop and ballet dancers? Eur J Transl Myol. 2022;32(4):11020. https://doi.org/10.4081/ejtm.2022.11020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs CL, Hincapi&#xe9; CA, Cassidy JD. Musculoskeletal injuries and pain in dancers: a systematic review update. J Dance Med Sci: Off Publ Int Assoc Dance Med Sci. 2012;16(2):74&#x2013;84. PubMed PMID: 22687721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowerman EA, Whatman C, Harris N, Bradshaw E. A review of the risk factors for lower extremity overuse injuries in young elite female ballet dancers. J Dance Med Sci. 2015;19(2):51&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.12678/1089-313X.19.2.51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Seters C, Van Rijn RM, Van Middelkoop M, Stubbe JH. Risk factors for lower-extremity injuries among contemporary dance students. Clin J Sport Med. 2020;30(1):60&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1097/JSM.0000000000000533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalder MA, Noble BJ, Wilkinson JG. The effects of supplemental weight training for ballet dancers. J Strength Cond Res. 1990;4(3):95. [cited 2025 Mar 3].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders DJ, Cardaci TD, McFadden BA, Walker AJ, Bozzini BN, Cintineo HP, et al. The effects of an 8-week resistance training intervention on muscular strength, power, and body composition in collegiate female dancers. Comp Exerc Physiol. 2020;16(4):4. https://doi.org/10.3920/CEP190074. Located at: Scopus.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03193146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(8):1582&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181. d2013a PubMed PMID: 20139780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff G, Triplett NT, National S, Conditioning, Association, editors. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Fourth edition. Market Street, Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2016. p.735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NSCA -National Strength &amp; Conditioning Association. Exercise technique manual for resistance training. Human Kinetics. 2021. Available from: https://books.google.com.my/books?id=rFY_EAAAQBAJ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Milanese C, Longo S, Limonta E, Rampichini S, et al. Specific adaptations in performance and muscle architecture after weighted jump-squat vs. body mass squat jump training in recreational soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):921&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridge A, Brown J, Snider H, Nasato M, Ward WE, Roy BD, et al. Greek yogurt and 12 weeks of exercise training on strength, muscle thickness and body composition in lean, untrained, university-aged males. Front Nutr. 2019;6:55. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2019.00055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa C, LaRoche D, Cadore E, Reischak-Oliveira A, Bottaro M, Kruel LF, et al. 3 different types of strength training in older women. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(12):962&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0032-1312648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso-Fernandez D, Docampo&#x2010;Blanco P, Martinez&#x2010;Fernandez J. Changes in muscle architecture of biceps femoris induced by eccentric strength training with nordic hamstring exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(1):88&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.12877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon TC, Fragala MS, Stout JR, Emerson NS, Beyer KS, Oliveira LP, et al. Muscle architecture and strength: adaptations to short-term resistance training in older adults. Muscle Nerve. 2014;49(4):584&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.23969. PubMed PMID: 23893353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Bertinato L, Milanese C, Venturelli M, Schena F. Including the eccentric phase in resistance training to counteract the effects of detraining in women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(11):3023&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000004039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, McKeever SM, Nolen JD, Comfort P. Muscle architectural and force-velocity curve adaptations following 10 weeks of training with weightlifting catching and pulling derivatives. J Sports Sci Med. 2022;504&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.52082/jssm.2022.504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;r H, Cakin N. Muscle mass, isokinetic torque, and functional capacity in women with osteoarthritis of the knee. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;84(10):1534&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0003-9993(. 03)00288-0 PubMed PMID: 14586923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhite MR, Cohen ER, Wilhite SC. Reliability of concentric and eccentric measurements of quadriceps performance using the KIN-COM dynamometer: the effect of testing order for three different speeds. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1992;15(4):175&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.2519/jospt.1992.15.4.175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY. Statistical notes for clinical researchers: a one-way repeated measures ANOVA for data with repeated observations. Restor Dent Endod. 2015;40(1):91&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.5395/rde.2015.40.1.91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parpucu T, Algun C, Toprak U, T&#xfc;rko&#x11f;lu S. The effects of eccentric-concentric isokinetic muscle strength training on quadriceps femoris muscle architecture, muscle strength and proprioception in healthy young people. Online T&#xfc;rk Sa&#x11f;l&#x131;k Bilim Derg. 2023;8(3):350&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.26453/otjhs.1274774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of plyometric training on muscle-tendon mechanical properties and behavior of fascicles during jumping. Physiol Rep. 2021;9(21):e15073. https://doi.org/10.14814/phy2. 15073 PubMed PMID: 34714597; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC8554776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL, Dyhre-Poulsen P, Leffers AM, Wagner A, Magnusson SP, et al. A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J Physiol. 2001;534(2):613&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.t01-1-00613.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruseghini P, Capelli C, Calabria E, Rossi AP, Tam E. Effects of high-intensity interval training and isoinertial training on leg extensors muscle function, structure, and intermuscular adipose tissue in older adults. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1260. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.01260. PubMed PMID: 31649552; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC6794371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Abe T, Fukunaga T. Muscle-fiber pennation angles are greater in hypertrophied than in normal muscles. J appl physiol (Bethesda Md. 1993;74(6):2741&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1993.74. .6.2740 PubMed PMID: 8365975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson MT, Ryan AMF, Vallance SR, Dias-Dougan A, Dugdale JH, Hunter AM, et al. Tensiomyography derived parameters reflect skeletal muscle architectural adaptations following 6-weeks of lower body resistance training. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1493. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.01493. PubMed PMID: 31920699; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC6914863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-delaCruz M, Bravo-S&#xe1;nchez A, Esteban-Garc&#xed;a P, Jim&#xe9;nez F, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J. Effects of plyometric training on lower body muscle architecture, tendon structure, stiffness and physical performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2022;8(1):40. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-022-00431-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halonen EJ, Gabriel I, Kelahaara MM, Ahtiainen JP, Hulmi JJ. Does taking a break matter-adaptations in muscle strength and size between continuous and periodic resistance training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(10):e14739. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14739. PubMed PMID: 39364857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikne H, Str&#xf8;m V, Pripp AH, Gj&#xf8;vaag T. Human skeletal muscle fiber type percentage and area after reduced muscle use: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(8):1298&#x2013;317. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13675. PubMed PMID: 32281690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. concentric loading: morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol. 2017;8:447. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2017.00447. PubMed PMID: 28725197; PubMed Central PMCID: PMC5495834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Aguado X, Rojas-Mart&#xed;n D, Mart&#xed;n-Garc&#xed;a M, Ara I, Csapo R. Load-controlled moderate and high-intensity resistance training programs provoke similar strength gains in young women. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51(1):92&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.24271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seaborne RA, Strauss J, Cocks M, Shepherd S, O&#x2019;Brien TD, van Someren KA, et al. Human skeletal muscle possesses an epigenetic memory of hypertrophy. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1898. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-20287-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part II: long term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med. 2000;30(3):145&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200030030-00001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutedakis Y, Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Metsios G. The significance of muscular strength in dance. J Dance Med Sci. 2005;9(1):29&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1177/1089313X0500900106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajic S, Legg HS, Maurus P, Nigg SR, Cleather DJ. The effects of a 9-week hip focused weight training program on hip and knee kinematics and kinetics in experienced female dancers. J Hum Kinet. 2020;75(1):29&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.2478/hukin-2020-0035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Hu R. Effects of physical training on the morphology of the main muscles in the lower limbs of sports dancers. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2023;29:e20220307. https://doi.org/10.1590/1517-8692202329012022_0307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psilander N, Eftest&#xf8;l E, Cumming KT, Juvkam I, Ekblom MM, Sunding K, et al. Effects of training, detraining, and retraining on strength, hypertrophy, and myonuclear number in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126(6):1636&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00917.2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Marcus R. Dynamic muscle strength alterations to detraining and retraining in elderly men. Clin Physiol. 1997;17(3):311&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2281.1997.tb00010.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Chen SC, Chen CN, Hsu CW, Zhou WS, Chien KY. Training session and detraining duration affect lower limb muscle strength maintenance in middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Aging Phys Act. 2022;30(3):552&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1123/japa.2020-0493. PubMed PMID: 34510028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharples AP, Turner DC. Skeletal muscle memory. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2023;324(6):C1274&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpcell.00099.2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103(5):1565&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00578.2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angioi M, Metsios G, Twitchett EA, Koutedakis Y, Wyon M. Effects of supplemental training on fitness and aesthetic competence parameters in contemporary dance: a randomised controlled trial. Med Probl Perform Art. 2012;27(1):3&#x2013;8. PubMed PMID: 22543316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardis MD, Greco G. Effects of a plyometric supplemental training on vertical jump height and aesthetic jumping ability in adolescent female dancers. Eur J Phys Educ Sport Sci. 2020;010.46827/ejpe.v0i0.2890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuthill JC, Azim E, Proprioception. Curr Biol. 2018;28(5):R194&#x2013;203. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2018.01.064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xe4;sing B, Calvo-Merino B, Cross ES, Jola C, Honisch J, Stevens CJ. Neurocognitive control in dance perception and performance. Acta Psychol (Amst). 2012;139(2):300&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2011.12.005. PubMed PMID: 22305351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burzynska AZ, Finc K, Taylor BK, Knecht AM, Kramer AF. The dancing brain: structural and functional signatures of expert dance training. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017;11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2017.00566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Elst O, Foster NHD, Vuust P, Keller PE, Kringelbach ML. The neuroscience of dance: a conceptual framework and systematic review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2023;150:105197. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2023.105197.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>