<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41619029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7339</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Supportive care in cancer : official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Support Care Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of aerobic and resistance training across eight cancer types: a systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>149</StartPage><MedlinePgn>149</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00520-026-10363-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patients with cancer&#xa0;often experience declines in quality of life (QoL), functional capacity, psychosocial health, and body composition, alongside cancer-related fatigue. Aerobic and resistance exercise interventions have shown potential in mitigating these effects. This review evaluated the impact of such interventions on QoL, fatigue, body composition, functional capacity, and psychosocial health across both the&#xa0;commonly studied cancers such as breast, prostate, lung, and colorectal, as well as the less-studied types, including&#xa0;lymphoma, ovarian, multiple myeloma and head and neck cancers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic searches were conducted across PubMed, Cochrane, ScienceDirect, Scopus, and EBSCOhost, identified 25 randomised controlled trials (RCTs) from an initial 18,116 studies. The 25 RCTs were&#xa0;assessed using the TESTEX scale and PRISMA guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Aerobic and/or resistance training showed to provide beneficial improvements in a number of measures&#xa0;during and after cancer treatment across&#xa0; cancer types. Qulity of&#xa0;life improved in 12 (of 13) trials&#xa0;that&#xa0;reported QoL.&#xa0;, There was a reported reduction in cancer-related fatigue&#xa0;in 9 (out of 10 ) studies that reported this measure. Significant enhancements in lean body mass and fat mass, were found in 6 of 8 trials&#xa0;that reported body composition. Functional capacity improved in 7 of 12 trials&#xa0;that reported this variable. Psychosocial outcomes showed mixed results, with significant improvements&#xa0;reported in 2 out of 7 trials that measured depression and anxiety. Moderate-intensity exercise, performed three times per week, demonstrated the most consistent benefits. Specific improvements from exercise were found in patients suffering from breast, prostate, lymphoma, multiple myeloma, colorectal, lung, and head and neck cancer. There was a notable lack of trials meeting the inclusion/exclusion criteria that&#xa0;specifically focused on ovarian cancer&#xa0;patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Structured aerobic and resistance exercise showed to&#xa0;significantly improve QoL, fatigue, body composition, and functional capacity in cancer patients. Integrating tailored exercise into cancer rehabilitation can enhance recovery. Future trials should aim to standardise outcome measures and improve adherence across diverse cancer populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oppong</LastName><ForeName>Isaac</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Staffordshire, School of Health, Education, Policing and Science, College Rd, Stoke-on-Trent, ST4 2DE, United Kingdom. Isaac.oppong@research.staffs.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naemi</LastName><ForeName>Roozbeh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Human Movement and Rehabilitation, School of Health and Society, University of Salford, Frederick Road Campus, Manchester, M6 6PU, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gossett</LastName><ForeName>Roger T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Support Care Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9302957</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0941-4355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Informed consent: Not applicable. Use of AI tools: No generative AI tools were used to create review content, data extraction, or analysis. AI-assisted grammar tools were used only for language editing. Ethical approval: This article is a systematic review and does not involve human or animal participants. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41619029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-026-10363-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00520-026-10363-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cancer Research UK(n.d.) Cancer incidence for common cancers. Cancer Research UK. Retrieved April 15, 2025, from https://www.cancerresearchuk.org/health-professional/cancer-statistics/incidence/common-cancers-compared</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddams J, Brewster D, Gavin A, Steward J, Elliott J, Utley M, M&#xf8;ller H (2009) Cancer prevalence in the United Kingdom: estimates for 2008. Br J Cancer 101(3):541&#x2013;547. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.bjc.6605148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bjc.6605148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2720244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya KS, Friedenreich CM, Quinney HA, Fields AL, Jones LW, Fairey AS (2003) A randomized trial of exercise and quality of life in colorectal cancer survivors. Eur J Cancer Care 12(4):347&#x2013;357. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2354.2003.00437.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2354.2003.00437.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azim HA Jr., de Azambuja E, Colozza M, Bines J, Piccart MJ (2011) Long-term toxic effects of adjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer. Ann Oncol 22(9):1939&#x2013;1947. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdq683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdq683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demark-Wahnefried W, Aziz NM, Rowland JH, Pinto BM (2005) Riding the crest of the teachable moment: promoting long-term health after the diagnosis of cancer. J Clin Oncol 23(24):5814&#x2013;5830. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2005.01.230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2005.01.230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1550285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knols R, Aaronson NK, Uebelhart D, Fransen J, Aufdemkampe G (2005) Physical exercise in cancer patients during and after medical treatment: a systematic review of randomized and controlled clinical trials. J Clin Oncol 23(16):3830&#x2013;3842. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2005.02.148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2005.02.148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Campbell AM, Stuiver MM, Pinto BM, Schwartz AL, Morris GS, Ligibel JA, Cheville A, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Alfano CM, Patel AV, Hue T, Gerber LH, Sallis R, Gusani NJ, Stout NL, Chan L, Flowers F, Doyle C, Helmrich S, Bain W, Sokolof J, Winters-Stone KM, Campbell KL, Matthews CE (2019) Exercise is medicine in oncology: engaging clinicians to help patients move through cancer. CA Cancer J Clin 69(6):468&#x2013;484. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7896280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra SI, Scherer RW, Snyder C, Geigle P, Gotay C (2014) Are exercise programs effective for improving health-related quality of life among cancer survivors? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Oncol Nurs Forum 41(6):E326&#x2013;E342. https://doi.org/10.1188/14.ONF.E326-E342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1188/14.ONF.E326-E342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4332787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffart LM, Kalter J, Sweegers MG, Courneya KS, Newton RU, Aaronson NK, Jacobsen PB, May AM, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Chinapaw MJ, Steindorf K, Irwin ML, Stuiver MM, Hayes S, Griffith KA, Lucia A, Mesters I, van Weert E, Knoop H, Goedendorp MM, Mutrie N, Daley AJ, McConnachie A, Bohus M, Thorsen L, Schulz K-H, Short CE, James EL, Plotnikoff RC, Arbane G, Schmidt ME, Potthoff K, van Beurden M, Oldenburg HS, Sonke GS, van Harten WH, Garrod R, Schmitz KH, Winters-Stone KM, Velthuis MJ, Taaffe DR, van Mechelen W, Kersten M-J, Nollet F, Wenzel J, Wiskemann J, de Verdonck- Leeuw IM, Brug J (2017) Effects and moderators of exercise on quality of life and physical function in patients with cancer: an individual patient data meta-analysis of 34 RCTs. Cancer Treat Rev 52:91&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ctrv.2016.11.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2016.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heale R, Twycross A (2015) Validity and reliability in quantitative research. Evid Based Nurs 18(3):66&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1136/eb-2015-102129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/eb-2015-102129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, Giallauria F, Vigorito C, Cornelissen V, Dieberg G (2015) Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. Int J Evid Based Healthc 13(1):9&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mardani A, Pedram Razi S, Mazaheri R, Haghani S, Vaismoradi M (2020) Effect of the exercise programme on the quality of life of prostate cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. International Journal of Nursing Practice, 27(2),e12883&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.1111/ijn.12883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijn.12883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam TL, Sze WK, Yip PS, Pang MY (2020) Androgen deprivation in prostate cancer: benefits of home-based resistance training. Support Care Cancer 28(9):4281&#x2013;4289. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-020-05350-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone K, Wiskemann J, May AM, Schwartz AL, Courneya KS, Zucker D, Matthews C, Ligibel J, Gerber L, Morris S, Patel A, Hue T, Perna F, Schmitz KH (2019) Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51(11):2375&#x2013;2390. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000002116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8576825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su T-L, Chen A-N,Leong C-P, Huang Y-C, Chiang C-W, Chen I-H, Lee Y-Y(2017) The effect of home-based program and outpatient physical therapy in patients with head and neck cancer: a randomized, controlled trial. Oral Oncol 74:130&#x2013;134. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oraloncology.2017.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oraloncology.2017.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia Roca M, Catala- Vilaplana I, Hernando C,Balino P, Salas-Medina M, Suarez-Alcazar P, Folch-Ayora A, Collado Boira E (2024) Effect of a long-term online home-based supervised exercise program on physical fitness and adherence in breast cancer patients: a randomized clinical trial. Cancers, 16(10),1912&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16101912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers16101912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Paulo TRS, Winters-Stone KM, Viezel J, Rossi FE, Sim&#xf5;es RR, Tosello G, Freitas Junior IF (2018) Effects of resistance plus aerobic training on body composition and metabolic markers in older breast cancer survivors undergoing aromatase inhibitor therapy. Exp Gerontol 111:210&#x2013;217. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exger.2018.07.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2018.07.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos WDN, Vieira A, de Lira CAB, Mota JF, Gentil P, de Freitas J&#xfa;nior R, Battaglini CL, Bottaro, M,Vieira CA (2019) Once a week resistance training improves muscular strength in breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Integr Cancer Ther 18:1534735419879748. https://doi.org/10.1177/1534735419879748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furzer BJ, Ackland TR, Wallman KE, Petterson AS, Gordon SM, Wright KE, Joske DJL (2016) A randomised controlled trial comparing the effects of a 12-week supervised exercise versus usual care on outcomes in haematological cancer patients. Support Care Cancer 24(4):1697&#x2013;1707. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-015-2955-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-015-2955-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen TS, Thorsen L, Kirkegaard C, Skovlund E, Raastad T, Foss&#xe5; SD (2015) Effects of strength training on body composition, physical functioning, and quality of life in prostate cancer patients during androgen deprivation therapy. Acta Oncol 54(10):1805&#x2013;1813. https://doi.org/10.3109/0284186X.2015.1037008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/0284186X.2015.1037008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satish P, Gupta A, Pujary K, Nambiar P (2019) Effectiveness of structured exercise intervention in cancer-related fatigue among oral cavity cancer patients. Int J Nurs Educ Res 7(2):181&#x2013;185.&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0043-1766134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuel SR, Maiya AG, Fernandes DJ, Guddattu V, Saxena PUP, Kurian JR, Lin P-J, Mustian KM (2019) Effectiveness of exercise-based rehabilitation on functional capacity and quality of life in head and neck cancer patients receiving chemo-radiotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Support Care Cancer 27(10):3913&#x2013;3920. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-019-04750-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-04750-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6728220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Spry N,Joseph D, Gardiner RA, Wall BA, Cormie P, KA Bolam Galv&#xe3;o DA (2017) Effects of different exercise modalities on fatigue in prostate cancer patients undergoing androgen deprivation therapy: a year-long randomised controlled trial. Eur Urol 72(2):293&#x2013;299. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2017.02.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2017.02.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd, M. J., Cho, M. H., Miaskowski, C., Painter, P. L., Paul, S. M., Cooper, B. A., Duda, J., Krasnoff, J., &amp; Bank, K. A. (2010). A randomized controlled trial of home-based exercise for cancer-related fatigue in women during and after chemotherapy with or without radiation therapy. Cancer nursing, 33(4), 245&#x2013;257. https://doi.org/10.1097/NCC.0b013e3181ddc58c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0b013e3181ddc58c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2891044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Paulo TRS, Rossi FE, Viezel J, Tosello GT, Seidinger SC, Sim&#xf5;es RR, de Freitas R Jr, Freitas IF Jr (2019) The impact of an exercise program on quality of life in older breast cancer survivors undergoing aromatase inhibitor therapy: a randomized controlled trial. Health Qual Life Outcomes 17(1):17. https://doi.org/10.1186/s129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceseiko R, Eglitis J, Srebnijs A, Timofejevs M, Purmalis E, Erts R, Vetra A, Tomsone S (2019). The impact of maximal strength training on quality of life among women with breast cancer undergoing treatment .&#xa0;Experimental oncology, 41(2), 166&#x2013;172. https://doi.org/10.32471/exp-oncology.2312-8852.vol-41-no-2.13249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijwel S, Backman M, Bolam KA, Jervaeus A, Sundberg CJ, Margolin S, Browall M, Rundqvist H, Wengstr&#xf6;m Y (2018) Adding high-intensity interval training to conventional training modalities: optimizing health-related outcomes during chemotherapy for breast cancer: the OptiTrain randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 168(1):79&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-017-4571-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-017-4571-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Huedo-Medina TB, Pescatello LS, Pescatello SM, Ferrer RA, Johnson BT (2017) Dose&#x2013;response effects of aerobic exercise on body composition among colon cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial.&#xa0;British journal of cancer, 117(11), 1614&#x2013; https://doi.org/10.1038/bjc.2017.339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H-M, Tsai C-M, Wu Y-C, Lin K-C, Lin C-C (2015) Randomized controlled trial on the effectiveness of home-based walking exercise on anxiety, depression, and cancer-related symptoms in patients with lung cancer. Psychooncology 24(11):1552&#x2013;1560. https://doi.org/10.1002/pon.3791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.3791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader S, Massoud A, Al-Obeidat F, Mohamed WF, Hafez W, Rashid A, Yousef OAE, Gador M, Ahmed S, Jose M, Abdelrahman A, Abdelshakour M, Fathey S, Osorio MF, Robles-Velasco K, Cherrez-Ojeda I (2024) Impact of aerobic and resistance training on fatigue, quality of life, and physical activity in prostate cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Surg 110:6170&#x2013;6181. https://doi.org/10.1097/JS9.0000000000000982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000000982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11487001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ficarra S, Thomas E, Bianco A, Gentile A, Thaller P, Grassadonio F, Papakonstantinou S, Schulz T, Olson N, Martin A, Wagner C, Nordstr&#xf6;m A, Hofmann H (2022) Impact of exercise interventions on physical fitness in breast cancer patients and survivors: a systematic review. Breast Cancer 29(3):402&#x2013;418. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12282-022-01347-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12282-022-01347-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9021138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Batrakoulis A, Norhayati MN, Mohamed M, Drenowatz C, Irekeola AA, Afolabi HA, G&#xfc;l&#xfc; M, Alkhamees NH, Wan Ghazali WS (2024) Combined aerobic and resistance training improves body composition, alters cardiometabolic risk, and ameliorates cancer-related indicators in breast cancer patients and survivors with overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Sports Sci Med 23(2):366&#x2013;395. https://doi.org/10.52082/jssm.2024.366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11149074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh JWL, MacLeod RD (2012) Body composition, physical fitness, functional performance, quality of life, and fatigue benefits of exercise for prostate cancer patients: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage 43(1):96&#x2013;110. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2011.03.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2011.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos-Mansilla B, Galiano-Castillo N, Lozano-Lozano M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Lao C, Lopez-Garzon M, Arroyo-Morales M (2021) Effect of physical therapy modalities on quality of life of head and neck cancer survivors: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Clin Med 10(20):4696. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10204696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10204696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8539984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Ca&#xf1;amero S, Cobo&#x2010;Cuenca AI, Carmona&#x2010;Torres JM, Pozuelo&#x2010;Carrascosa DP, Santacruz&#x2010;Salas E, Rabanales&#x2010;Sotos JA, Cuesta&#x2010;Mateos T, Laredo&#x2010;Aguilera JA (2022) Impact of physical exercise in advanced&#x2010;stage cancer patients: systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Cancer Med 11(19):3714&#x2013;3727. https://doi.org/10.1002/cam4.4746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.4746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9554454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneses-Ech&#xe1;vez JF, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Jim&#xe9;nez E, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R (2015) Supervised exercise reduces cancer-related fatigue: a systematic review. J Physiother 61(1):3&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphys.2014.08.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2014.08.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalfe JW, Orange ST, Madden LA, Marshall P, Vince RV (2024) Effects of resistance training on quality of life, fatigue, physical function, and muscular strength during chemotherapy treatment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer 32(9):593. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-024-08766-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-024-08766-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11330399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Davis K, Breitbart W, Curt G, Fatigue Coalition (2001) Cancer-related fatigue: prevalence of proposed diagnostic criteria in a United States sample of cancer survivors. J Clin Oncol 19(14):3385&#x2013;3391. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2001.19.14.3385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2001.19.14.3385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE (2014) Cancer-related fatigue&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and treatments. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 11(10):597&#x2013;609. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4664449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mast IH, Bongers CCWG, Gootjes EC, de Wilt JHW, Hopman MTE, Buffart LM (2024) Potential mechanisms underlying the effect of walking exercise on cancer-related fatigue in cancer survivors. J Cancer Surviv. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11764-024-01537-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-024-01537-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12283887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessels E, Husson O, van der Feltz-Cornelis CM (2018) The effect of exercise on cancer-related fatigue in cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat 14:479&#x2013;494. https://doi.org/10.2147/NDT.S150464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S150464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5810532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson D, Diorio C, Beyene J, Sung L (2014) Effect of exercise on cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 93(8):675&#x2013;686. https://doi.org/10.1097/PHM.0000000000000083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000000083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juvet LK, Thune I, &#xd8;. Elvsaas IK, Fors EA, Lundgren S, Bertheussen G, Leivseth G, Oldervoll LM (2017) The effect of exercise on fatigue and physical functioning in breast cancer patients during and after treatment and at 6 months follow-up: a meta-analysis. Breast 33:166&#x2013;177. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.breast.2017.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.breast.2017.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herranz-G&#xf3;mez A, Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez F, Suso-Mart&#xed; L, Varangot-Reille C, Prades-Monfort M, Calatayud J, Casa&#xf1;a J (2023) Effectiveness of therapeutic exercise models on cancer-related fatigue in patients with cancer undergoing chemotherapy: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 104(6):1105&#x2013;1116. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2023.01.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2023.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palesh O, Kamen C, Sharp S, Golden A, Neri E, Spiegel D, Koopman C (2018) Physical activity and survival in women with advanced breast cancer. Cancer Nurs 41(4):E31&#x2013;E38. https://doi.org/10.1097/NCC.0000000000000525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0000000000000525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5775062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salam A, Woodman A, Chu A, Al-Jamea LH, Islam M, Sagher M, Sager M, Akhtar M (2022) Effect of post-diagnosis exercise on depression symptoms, physical functioning and mortality in breast cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Cancer Epidemiol 77:102111. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.canep.2022.102111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canep.2022.102111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H-P, Wen F-H, Yang T-Y, Lin Y-C, Tsai J-C, Shun S-C, Chen M-L (2019) The effect of a 12-week home-based walking program on reducing fatigue in women with breast cancer undergoing chemotherapy: a randomized controlled study. Int J Nurs Stud 99:103376. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pin F, Couch ME, Bonetto A (2018) Preservation of muscle mass as a strategy to reduce the toxic effects of cancer chemotherapy on body composition. Curr Opin Support Palliat Care 12(4):420&#x2013;426. https://doi.org/10.1097/SPC.0000000000000382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6221433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojman P, Gehl J, Christensen JF, Pedersen BK (2018) Molecular mechanisms linking exercise to cancer prevention and treatment. Cell Metab 27(1):10&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2017.09.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2017.09.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwase T, Wang X, Shrimanker TV, Kolonin MG, Ueno NT (2021) Body composition and breast cancer risk and treatment: mechanisms and impact. Breast Cancer Res Treat 186(2):273&#x2013;283. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10549-020-06092-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-020-06092-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser SF, Gardner JR, Dalla Via J, Daly RM (2022) The effect of exercise training on lean body mass in breast cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54(2):211&#x2013;219. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000002792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen C-J, Hung C-H, Kao C-L, Tsai W-M, Chan S-H, Cheng H-C, Jheng W-T, Lu Y-J, Tsai K-L (2019) Multimodal exercise ameliorates exercise responses and body composition in head and neck cancer patients receiving chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer 27:4687&#x2013;4695. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-019-04786-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-04786-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battaglini C, Bottaro M, Dennehy C,Rae L, Shields E, Kirk D, Hackney AC (2007) The effects of an individualized exercise intervention on body composition in breast cancer patients undergoing treatment.Sao Paulo medical journal, Revista paulista de medicina, 125(1), 22&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.1590/s1516-31802007000100005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-31802007000100005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malveiro C, Correia IR, Cargaleiro C, Magalh&#xe3;es JP, de Vasconcelos Matos L, Hil&#xe1;rio S, Sardinha LB, Cardoso MJ (2023) Effects of exercise training on cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant treatment: a systematic review. J Sci Med Sport 26(11):586&#x2013;592. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2023.08.178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2023.08.178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shobeiri F, Masoumi SZ, Nikravesh A, Moghadam RH, Karami M (2016) The Impact of Aerobic Exercise on Quality of Life in Women with Breast Cancer: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Journal of Research in Health Sciences.&#xa0;6(3), 127&#x2013;132.&#xa0;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27840340/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7191023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtezani A, Ibraimi Z, Bakalli A, Krasniqi S, Devolli Disha E, Kurtishi I (2014) The effect of aerobic exercise on quality of life among breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. J Cancer Res Ther 10(3):658&#x2013;664. https://doi.org/10.4103/0973-1482.137985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-1482.137985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dittus KL, Gramling RE, Ades PA (2017) Exercise interventions for individuals with advanced cancer: a systematic review. Prev Med 104:124&#x2013;132. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2017.07.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2017.07.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman EA, Hall-Barrow J, Beckstead JW, Wampler NS, Piper BF (2012) Effects of exercise on fatigue, sleep, and performance: a randomized trial. Oncol Nurs Forum 39(5):468&#x2013;477. https://doi.org/10.1188/12.ONF.468-477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1188/12.ONF.468-477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6417884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocki BC, Andreasen J, Nielsen LR, Nekrasas V, Gorst-Rasmussen A, Westerdahl E (2014) Short and long-term effects of supervised versus unsupervised exercise training on health-related quality of life and functional outcomes following lung cancer surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Lung Cancer 83(1):102&#x2013;108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lungcan.2013.10.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2013.10.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Courneya KS, Matthews C, Demark-Wahnefried W, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Pinto BM, Irwin ML, Wolin KY, Segal RJ, Lucia A, Schneider CM, von Gruenigen VE, Schwartz AL (2010) American College of Sports Medicine roundtable on exercise guidelines for cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42(7):1409&#x2013;1426. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181e0c112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181e0c112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tock WL, Maheu C, Johnson NA (2022) Considerations of control conditions designs in randomized controlled trials of exercise interventions for cancer survivors. Can J Nurs Res 54(4):377&#x2013;391. https://doi.org/10.1177/08445621211062467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08445621211062467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9596954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott SA, Brown JSL (2002) What are we doing to waiting list controls? Behav Res Ther 40(9):1047&#x2013;1052. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0005-7967(01)00082-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-7967(01)00082-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street LL, Luoma JB (2002) Control groups in psychosocial intervention research: ethical and methodological issues. Ethics Behav 12(1):1&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1207/S15327019EB1201_1</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>