<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41287061</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of TRX suspension training versus traditional balance training on balance performance in elite surfers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>352</StartPage><MedlinePgn>352</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">352</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01411-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Traditional balance training (TB) may have certain limitations in replicating surfing's unstable conditions, which may somewhat restrict its sport-specific efficacy. Total Resistance Exercise (TRX) suspension training uses controllable instability to better enhance key balance abilities. This study compared TRX and TB effects on static, dynamic, and surfing-specific balance in elite surfers, and explored correlations between these dimensions to inform targeted training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">32 surfers from the current Chinese National Surfing Team were randomized to TRX or TB groups (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;16 each). Both groups completed 30-minute training sessions &#xd7;3/week for 8 weeks. Static balance (eyes-closed single-leg stand), dynamic balance (Star Excursion Balance Test (SEBT), Linear travel deviation test), and surfing-specific balance (Indo board lateral squat) were assessed pre- and post-intervention. Pearson correlations examined relationships between balance dimensions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">(1) Both methods improved static balance (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), but TRX group exhibited greater improvements (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). (2) Dynamic balance improved significantly in both groups (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), but TRX outperformed TB (SEBT: p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.034 for left leg, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.043 for right leg; Linear travel deviation: p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.000). (3) Surfing-specific balance improved significantly in both groups (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01), with TRX superior to TB (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01); (4) Surfing-specific balance changes correlated significantly with static balance (moderate positive: r&#x2009;=&#x2009;+&#x2009;0.487 for left leg, r&#x2009;=&#x2009;+&#x2009;0.457 for right leg), multidirectional dynamic balance (weak positive: r&#x2009;=&#x2009;+&#x2009;0.395 for left leg, r&#x2009;=&#x2009;+&#x2009;0.363 for right leg), and directional control (moderate negative: r=-0.515).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">TRX suspension training is more effective than TB in enhancing static, dynamic, and surfing-specific balance in elite surfers. Thus, TRX suspension training can serve as a preferred sport-specific training method for improving balance ability in elite surfers, providing practical support for them to cope with complex wave conditions in competitions and enhance competitive performance. TRX suspension training can be integrated into elite surfers' programs, aiding injury prevention and competitive performance optimization. Correlations support a hierarchical model where static balance provides a foundation, dynamic balance enables adaptation, and directional control reflects surfing's uniqueness-findings that inform scientific design of surfing-specific training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Retrospectively registered. Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (https//www.chictr.org.cn/). Registration number ChiCTR2500102873. State Successful. Reg Date 20,250,521 000000.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoyi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China. mayong@whsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China. mayong@whsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Specialised Research Centre for High-Quality Development of Competitive Sports, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China. mayong@whsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Sports Health Intelligent Equipment of Hubei Province, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China. mayong@whsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Zhihao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Mengyao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China. jmy15737132785@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China. jmy15737132785@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Weitao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Sports Engineering, Wuhan Sports University, No. 461 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province, 430079, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Engineering of General Administration of Sport of China, Wuhan Sports University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>21KT02</GrantID><Agency>the Science and Technology Team Foundation of Wuhan Sports University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021-05</GrantID><Agency>the 14th Five Year-Plan Advantageous and Characteristic Disciplines (Groups) of Colleges and Universities in Hubei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indo board lateral squat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Static balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surfing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Suspension training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The studies involving humans conform to the Declaration of Helsinki concerning studies involving human subjects and the study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Wuhan Sports University (No. 2021030). The studies were conducted in accordance with the local legislation and institutional requirements. Written informed consent for participation in this study was provided by the participants&#x2019; legal guardians/next of kin. Participants gave written informed consent to participate in the present study and to its publication. Consent for publication: Consent to publish. We confirmed that adult participants had signed a written informed consent form for the publication of their personal or clinical details and recognizable images in this study. We explained to them about the study and its publication.&#xa0; For minors (&lt;&#x2009;18 years of age) in the study, we obtained written informed consent for publication of clinical details and/or clinical images from their parents or legal guardians. They were informed and they gave their consent by signing a consent form. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41287061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12642247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01411-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01411-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Chen HQ, Liu L, Lin SJ, Jia MY, Zheng WT. Construction and demonstration of a comprehensive evaluation system of factors influencing the performance for competitive short-board surfing. China Sport Sci. 2023;43(5):60&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsyth JR, Tsai MC, Sheppard JM, Whitting JW, Steele JR. Can we predict the landing performance of simulated aerials in surfing? J Sports Sci. 2021;39(22):2567&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco JT, Boergers R, Cappaert T, Miller M, Nelson J, Schoenberger M. A comprehensive needs analysis on surfing performance factors and training methodologies. Strength Conditioning J. 2022;16(3):10&#x2013;1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony CC, Brown LE, Coburn JW, Galpin AJ, Tran TT, Meir R, Farley O. Stance affects balance in surfers. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2016a;11(3):446&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadpoor M, Maedeh, Bragazzi NL. The effects of strength training on motor control and functional performance in older adults: A narrative review. Int J Sport Stud Health. 2025;8(1):12&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z, Wang H. Influence of core training on the ability of control and balance in surfers. Revista Brasileira De Med Do Esporte. 2022;28(6):723&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labata LN, Rodr&#xed;guez RS, L&#xf3;pez-de-Celis C, Rodr&#xed;guez SJ, Canet VM, R-Oviedo G, Gonz&#xe1;lez RV, P&#xe9;rez BA. Effectiveness of different training modalities on static balance in older adults: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Life (Basel). 2023;13(5):1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10222379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony CC, Brown LE. Resistance training considerations for female surfers. Strength Conditioning J. 2016b;38(2):64&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axel TA, Crussemeyer JA, Dean K, Young DE. Field test performance of junior competitive surf athletes following a core strength training program. Int J Exerc Sci. 2018;11(6):696&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6033504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29997737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson T, Scantlebury M, Furness J, Kemp SK, Newcomer S, Climstein M. Training methods in the sport of surfing: A scoping review. Strength Conditioning J. 2022;44(3):21&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejuto G, G&#xf3;mez-Carmona CD, Gracia J, Rico-Gonz&#xe1;lez M. Surfing Time&#x2013;Motion characteristics possible to gain using global navigation satellite systems: A systematic review. Sensors. 2024;24(11):3455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11174645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38894246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei YJ, Zhao HB, Song XF, Sun YL. The function and application of sling exercise training. J Tianjin Univ Sport. 2009;24(4):358&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YM, Yu HJ, Zi W, Cao CM, Chen XP. Discussion on core strength and training in competitive sports&#x2014;origin, problem, development. China Sport Sci. 2008;28(4):19&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Z, Yuan WN. Effect of S-E-T suspension training method on balance ability of track and field athletes. J Shenyang Sport Univ. 2010;29(5):85&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang ZJ, Zhou ZR, Lu Q. Effects of suspension training(S-E-T) on the application of physical training for swimmers aged 15&#x2009;~&#x2009;17 in Jiangsu Province. J Shandong Inst Phys Educ Sports. 2012;28(3):82&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Sun WX. The S-E-T training influence on football player&#x2019;s ability of control movement under instable state. J Beijing Sport Univ. 2014;37(1):124&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, Kraemer WJ, Blimkie CJ, Jeffreys I, Micheli LJ, Nitka M, Rowland TW. Youth resistance training: updated position statement paper from the National strength and conditioning association. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2017;31(3):601&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banister EW. Modeling elite athletic performance. Physiol Behav. 1991;50(5):633&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu HM, Li CW, Yu M. The original of size principle and its influence on strength training. China Sport Sci. 2016;36(11):56&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X. Experimental study on the influence of TRX suspension training on hurdle technique. [Dissertation, Shandong Normal University]; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WX, Li HX. Competitive athletes&#x2019; core strength training. J Beijing Sport Univ. 2007;30(8):1119&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun QZ, Hao WF, Hong F. Sports measurement and evaluation. Beijing: Higher Education Press; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu P. Application of SEBT on core training measurement on elite fin swimming athletes. J Wuhan Sports Univ. 2011;45(9):74&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Zhu XQ, Bi Q. Application of star excursion balance test in evaluating the effects of neuromuscular training for women&#x2019;s volleyball players. J Tianjin Univ Sport. 2018;33(1):86&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng WT, Qu P. Core stability and strength training of windsurfing. J Wuhan Inst Phys Educ. 2011;45(2):78&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao JC. An experimental study on the influence of Total Resistance Exercise on students&#x2019; balance ability in the general course of gymnastics. [Dissertation, Yangzhou University]; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu QC, Xu SS, Zhang ZP. The S-E-T training influence on curling player&#x2019;s ability of of special skills. China Winter Sports. 2018;1(5):29&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang ZY, Ma Y, Guo ZH, Jia MY, Zheng WT. The effect of suspension training on dynamic balance of excellent elite surfers. J Xi&#x2019;an Phys Educ Univ. 2024;41(6):829&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco JT, Boergers R, Cappaert T. The effects of a land - based home exercise program on surfing performance in recreational surfers. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(4):358&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37167547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard B, Johnston M, Dixon D. Theoretical framework and methodological development of common subjective health outcome measures in osteoarthritis: a critical review. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2007;5(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1832179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17343739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MG, Zhai D, Zhang HJ. Research on training for rapidly improving the balance control ability of surfers. Youth Sport. 2020;8(9):90&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez VA, Bishop D. Physiological aspects of surfboard riding performance. Sports Med. 2005;35(1):55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15651913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu CX, Li P. The experimental research of set on the ability of balance control and trunk core stability for male tennis players. J Beijing Sport Univ. 2014;37(2):138&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Zhou SH, Zhang QY, et al. A force-sensitive adhesion GPCR is required for equilibrioception. Cell Res. 2025;2(35):243&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11958651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39966628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JC, Zhou KL, Shi YT, Feng GQ, Yuan H. Suspension training in core strength training of skill dominated performing event&#x2014;In view of diving events. J Wuhan Inst Phys Educ. 2010;44(2):53&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeraj PM, Gaurav KM, Aseem GM. Effect of wobble board balance training program on static balance, dynamic balance &amp; triple hop distance in male collegiate basketball athlete. Int J Physiotherapy Res. 2014;2(4):657&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng CZ, Li HQ. Effects of multimodal functional training on lower limb muscle strength, proprioception and dynamic balance ability of female college students with functional ankle instability. J Shandong Sport Univ. 2020;36(1):66&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Young WB. Agility literature review: Classifications, training and testing. Sports Med. 2006;36(11):919&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler S, Skaanes PT, Kirkesola G, Katch FI. Effects of sling exercise training on maximal clubhead velocity in junior golfers: 1781: Board# 154 2: 00 PM&#x2013;3: 00 PM. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(5):S286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez GM, Castanedo JM, Cobo C. Implementation of surfing in physical education. J Phys Educ Recreation Dance. 2023;94(4):51&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Materne O, Chamari K. Rethinking knee injury prevention strategies: joint-by-joint training approach paradigm versus traditional focused knee strengthening. Biology Sport. 2025;42(4):59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12490306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furness J, Warrington GS. Acute injuries in recreational and competitive surfers: Incidence, Severity, Location, Type, and mechanism. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(5):1203&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Padulo J, Be&#x161;lija T, Cheze L. Dynamic posture change in Non-Specific low back pain management: A paradigm shift utilizing the Joint-by-Joint training approach. New Asian J Med. 2024;2(3):17&#x2013;23. (17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpert DM, Ghahramani Z. Computational principles of movement neuroscience. Nat Neurosci. 2000;3(11):1212&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11127840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farley ORL, et al. Five weeks of sprint and high-intensity interval training improves paddling performance in adolescent surfers. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2016;30(9):2471&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26849794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe9;vin M, Bonneton P, Mouragues A, Castelle B. Non-hydrostatic, non&#x2010;linear processes in the surf zone. J Geophys Research: Oceans. 2020;125(2):1&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horak FB. Postural orientation and equilibrium: what do we need to know about neural control of balance to prevent falls? Age Ageing. 2006;35(2):7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterka RJ. Sensorimotor integration in human balance. J Neurophysiol. 2002;88(3):1097&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12205132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>