<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41333731</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0972-8988</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary world</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet World</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phenotypic resistance and virulence gene profiles of non-typhoidal <i>Salmonella</i> in retail poultry products in Arusha, Tanzania: A One Health perspective.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2991</StartPage><EndPage>3001</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2991-3001</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14202/vetworld.2025.2991-3001</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Non-typhoidal <i>Salmonella</i> (NTS) is a leading cause of foodborne illness, with poultry products serving as major transmission routes. In sub-Saharan Africa, surveillance of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) and virulence determinants remains limited. This study investigated the prevalence, AMR, and virulence gene profiles of NTS isolated from poultry products retailed in Arusha, Tanzania.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional study was conducted between August and October 2023. A total of 240 samples (layer eggs and broiler meat) were collected from two wards in Arusha City using systematic random sampling. NTS isolates were confirmed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and tested for susceptibility to 11 antimicrobial agents using the Kirby-Bauer method. Virulence (<i>invA</i> and <i>stn</i>) and resistance genes (<i>tetA, tetB, bla<sub>TEM</sub>, bla<sub>CTXM</sub></i> , and <i>bla<sub>SHV</sub></i> ) were screened by PCR. Statistical associations were analyzed using odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The overall prevalence of NTS was 23.3% (56/240). Layer eggs showed significantly higher contamination (20%) compared with broiler meat (3.3%) (OR = 10.0, 95% CI: 4.4-22.6, p &lt; 0.001). <i>Salmonella</i> Typhimurium was the predominant serotype. All isolates carried <i>invA</i> and <i>stn</i> genes. Alarmingly, 100% of isolates were resistant to imipenem (IMI), while resistance to ampicillin (58.9%) and tetracycline (41.1%) was also common. Multidrug resistance patterns were frequent, although resistance genes were detected at a low prevalence (<i>tetA</i>, 5.3%; <i>bla<sub>TEM</sub></i> , 3.5%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings demonstrate a high prevalence of virulent and IMI-resistant <i>S</i>. Typhimurium in retail poultry products in Arusha, particularly in eggs. These results highlight critical gaps in food safety regulation and antimicrobial stewardship within the Tanzanian One Health framework. Further genomic studies are warranted to elucidate underlying resistance mechanisms and inform effective surveillance strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Ahmed, et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Salum</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Research and Clinical Trial, Ifakara Health Institute (IHI), P.O. Box 74, Bagamoyo, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Bioengineering (LiSBE), The Nelson Mandela African Institution of Science, Technology (NM-AIST), P.O. Box 447, Arusha, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Livestock Training Agency (LITA), The Ministry of Livestock and Fisheries, P.O. Box 3101, Arusha, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Research and Clinical Trial, Ifakara Health Institute (IHI), P.O. Box 74, Bagamoyo, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyimo</LastName><ForeName>Beatus</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Bioengineering (LiSBE), The Nelson Mandela African Institution of Science, Technology (NM-AIST), P.O. Box 447, Arusha, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimaro</LastName><ForeName>Esther Gwae</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Bioengineering (LiSBE), The Nelson Mandela African Institution of Science, Technology (NM-AIST), P.O. Box 447, Arusha, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Vet World</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101504872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0972-8988</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">One Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tanzania</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-typhoidal Salmonella</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poultry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virulence genes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41333731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12668727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2025.2991-3001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">Vetworld-18-2991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Plumb I Fields, Patricia and Bruce B (CDC) In CDC Yellow Book 2024:Health Information for International Travel. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2024th ed. USA: Atlanta, Georgia; 2024. Salmonellosis, Nontyphoidal.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO and WHO. Measures for the Control of Non-typhoidal Salmonella spp. Poultry Meat. Meas Control non-Typhoidal Salmonella spp Poult Meat. FAO, Rome. 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James S.L, Abate D, Abate K.H, Abay T, Murray C.J.L. Global, regional, and national incidence, prevalence, and years lived with disability for 354 diseases and injuries for 195 countries and territories, 1990-2017:A systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet. 2018;392(10159):1789&#x2013;1858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanaway J.D, Parisi A, Sarkar K, Blacker B.F, Reiner B.X, Ullah I, Yimer E.M, Zaidi Z, Murray C.J.L, Crump J.A. The global burden of non-typhoidal Salmonella invasive disease:A systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2019;19(12):1312&#x2013;1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFSA and ECDC. Multi-country outbreak of Salmonella Enteritidis infections linked to eggs, third update &#x2013;6 February 2020. EFSA Support Publ. 2020;17((2)):1799e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heredia N, Garc&#xed;a S. Animals as sources of food-borne pathogens:A review. Anim. Nutr. 2018;4(3):250&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30175252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services. One Health Zoonotic Disease Prioritization for Multisectoral Engagement in Tanzania. United States: Department of Health and Human Services; 2017. CDC, USAID and FAO; pp. 1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngogo F.A, Joachim A, Abade A.M, Rumisha S.F, Mizinduko M.M, Majigo M.V. Factors associated with Salmonella infection in patients with gastrointestinal complaints seeking health care at Regional Hospital in Southern Highland of Tanzania. BMC Infect. Dis. 2020;20(1):135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7017463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32050928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonola V.S, Katakweba A, Misinzo G, Matee M.I. Molecular epidemiology of antibiotic resistance genes and virulence factors in multidrug-resistant Escherichia coli isolated from rodents, humans, chicken, and household soils in Karatu, Northern Tanzania. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2022;191((9)):5388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escher N.A, Muhummed A.M, Hattendorf J, Vonaesch P, Zinsstag J. Systematic review and meta-analysis of integrated studies on antimicrobial resistance genes in Africa-A One Health perspective. Trop. Med. Int. Health. 2021;26(10):1153&#x2013;1163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8597124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertagnolio S, Dobreva Z, Centner C.M, Olaru I.D, Don&#xe0; D, Burzo S, Huttner B.D, Chaillon A, Gebreselassie N, Wi T, Hasso-Agopsowicz M, Allegranzi B, Sati H, Ivanovska V, Kothari K.U, Balkhy H.H, Cassini A, Hamers R.L, Weezenbeek K.V WHO Research Agenda for AMR in Human Health Collaborators. WHO global research priorities for antimicrobial resistance in human health. Lancet Microbe. 2024;5(11):100902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39146948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2022. Global Antimicrobial Resistance and Use Surveillance System (GLASS)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M.S, Sobur M.A, Rahman S, Ballah F.M, Ievy S, Siddique M.P, Rahman M, Kafi M.A, Rahman M.T. Detection of blaTEM, blaCTX-M, blaCMY, and blaSHV genes among extended-spectrum beta-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolated from migratory birds travelling to Bangladesh. Microb. Ecol. 2022;83(4):942&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiula A.H, Makene V.A. Molecular epidemiology of antibiotic resistance among Escherichia coli isolated from broiler chickens sold at selected markets in dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Tanzania J. Sci. 2023;49(2):422&#x2013;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessy D, Kiage O, Kiprutto N. Multiplier effects of tourism in selected areas of Arusha, Tanzania. African J. Hosp. Tour. Leis. 2018;7(3):1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lwanga S.K, Lemeshow S. WHO, Geneva: A Practical Manual; 1991. Sample Size Determination in Health Studies; pp. 175&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindiyo E, Missanga J. Common diseases affecting poultry production in Arusha Peri-urban, Northern Tanzania. J. Appl. Life Sci. Int. 2018;15:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique A, Azim S, Ali A, Andleeb S, Ahsan A, Imran M, Rahman A. Antimicrobial resistance profiling of biofilm forming non typhoidal Salmonella enterica isolates from poultry and its associated food products from Pakistan. Antibiotics (Basel) 2021;10(7):785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzyzanowski F, Zappelini L, Martone-Rocha S, Dropa M, Matt&#xe9; M.H, Nacache F, Razzolini M.T.P. Quantification and characterization of Salmonella spp. Isolates in sewage sludge with potential usage in agriculture. BMC Microbiol. 2014;14:263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4207900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25927729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendybayeva A, Abilova Z, Bulashev A, Rychshanova R. Prevalence and resistance to antibacterial agents in Salmonella enterica strains isolated from poultry products in Northern Kazakhstan. Vet. World. 2023;16(3):657&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10082744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37041849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CLSI. Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing. 28th ed. Wayne: CLSI Supplement M100; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diab M.S, Thabet A.S, Elsalam M.A, Ewida R.M, Sotohy S.A. lactamase resistance genes of non-typhoidal Salmonella isolates from human and animal origin in Egypt &#x201c;one health concern&#x201d;. Gut Pathog. 2023;15(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10061834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36998086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M.Y, Geng J.L, Chen Y.J, Song Y, Sun M, Liu H.Z, Hu C.J. Direct detection of mecA, blaSHV, blaCTX-M, blaTEM and blaOXA genes from positive blood culture bottles by multiplex-touchdown PCR assay. Lett. Appl. Microbiol. 2017;64(2):138&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27699804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong-Ngoen T, Santajit S, Tunyong W, Pumirat P, Sookrung N, Chaicumpa W, Indrawattana N. Antimicrobial resistance and virulence of non-typhoidal Salmonella from retail foods marketed in Bangkok, Thailand. Foods. 2022;11(5):661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8909193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tack B, Vanaenrode J, Verbakel J.Y, Toelen J, Jacobs J. Invasive non-typhoidal Salmonella infections in sub-Saharan Africa:A systematic review on antimicrobial resistance and treatment. BMC Med. 2020;18(1):212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32677939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher R, Currie P. Towards a safe, nourishing, economic and inclusive food system for Arusha, based on Partnering. 2019 2018&#x2013;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mramba R.P, Mwantambo P.A. The impact of management practices on the disease and mortality rates of broilers and layers kept by small-scale farmers in Dodoma urban district, Tanzania. Heliyon. 2024;10(8):29624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11035043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38655291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer E.W, Chisnall T, Tano-Debrah K, Card R.M, Duodu S, Kunadu A.P.H. Prevalence and genomic characterization of Salmonella isolates from commercial chicken eggs retailed in traditional markets in Ghana. Front. Microbiol. 2023;2023:1283835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10646427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38029182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crump J.A, Thomas K.M, Benschop J, Knox M.A, Wilkinson D.A, Midwinter A.C, Munyua P.C, Ochieng J.B, Bigogo G.M, Verani J.R, Widdowson M.A, Prinsen G, Cleaveland S, Karimuribo E.D, Kazwala R.R, Mmbaga B.T, Swai E.S, French N.P, Zadoks R.N. Investigating the meat pathway as a source of human nontyphoidal Salmonella bloodstream infections and diarrhea in East Africa. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2021;73(7):1570&#x2013;1578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamboj S, Gupta N, Bandral J.D, Gandotra G, Anjum N. Food safety and hygiene:A review. Int. J. Chem. Stud. 2020;8(2):358&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivali V, Roesel K, Dohoo I, Alinaitwe L, Bugeza J.K, Hoona J.J, Mugizi D.R, Kankya C, Dang-Xuan S, Szabo I, R&#xf6;sler U, Friese A, Cook E.A.J. Non-typhoidal Salmonella among slaughterhouse workers and in the pork value chain in selected districts of Uganda. Front. Vet. Sci. 2024;11:1427773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11472856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39403216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moffatt C.R.M, Musto J, Pingault N, Miller M, Stafford R, Gregory J, Polkinghorne B.G, Kirk M.D. Salmonella Typhimurium and outbreaks of egg-associated disease in Australia, 2001 2011. Foodborne Pathog. Dis. 2016;13(7):379&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27028267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Olivas E, Mu&#xf1;oz-Pina S, Andr&#xe9;s A, Heredia A. Impact of cooking preparation on in vitro digestion of eggs simulating some gastrointestinal alterations in elders. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2021;69:4402&#x2013;4411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianou A, Panagou E.Z, Nychas G.J.E. 8th ed. United Kingdom: Woodhead Publishing; 2017. Meat safety-I foodborne pathogens and other biological issues. In:Lawrie's Meat Science.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garridogamarro E, Svanevik C.S, Lundebye A.K, Sanden M, D'Agostino E, Kjellevold M, Pincus L, Pucher J. Challenges in the implementation of food safety and quality assurance systems in small-scale fisheries. Food Qual. Saf. 2023;7(3):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aga A.M, Mulugeta D, Muleta D, Woldesemayat A.A, Motuma A, Kelel M, Wakitole B, Tadesse S, Teferi Z, Woldemariyam F.T, Oljira S, Ferede H, Berihun N, Girma S, Nigussie D, Gemeda M.T. Antibiotic susceptibility patterns of Salmonella isolates from clinical, food, and environmental sources in Addis Ababa and surrounding towns, Ethiopia. Microbiol. Spectr. 2025;13((8)):0097025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12323349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40642986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoud S.S, Njakoi G.N, Sholla S, Renatus D, Majigo M, Gangji R.R, Nyawale H, Mawazo A, Ntukula A, Kamori D. Carbapenem resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Acinetobacter baumannii in Tanzania. Ger. J. Microbiol. 2024;4(3):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutua F, Kihara A, Rogena J, Ngwili N, Aboge G, Wabacha J, Bett B. Piloting a livestock identification and traceability system in the northern Tanzania-Narok-Nairobi trade route. Trop. Anim. Health Prod. 2018;50(2):299&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ssekatawa K, Byarugaba D.K, Wampande E, Ejobi F. A systematic review:The current status of carbapenem resistance in East Africa. BMC Res. Notes. 2018;11((1)):629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6119249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30170613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katale B.Z, Misinzo G, Mshana S.E, Chiyangi H, Campino S, Clark T.G, Good L, Rweyemamu M.M, Matee M.I. Genetic diversity and risk factors for the transmission of antimicrobial resistance across human, animals and environmental compartments in East Africa:A review. Antimicrob. Resist. Infect. Control. 2020;9(1):127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalal S.H, Jaber N.N, Hussein K.R. Molecular identification of virulence genes Salmonella enterica isolated of animal and human diarrheal. J. Med. Chem. Sci. 2023;6(2):1302&#x2013;1309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalefa H.S, Ahmed Z.S, Abdel-Kader F, Ismail E.M, Elshafiee E.A. Sequencing and phylogenetic analysis of the stn gene of Salmonella species isolated from different environmental sources at Lake Qarun protectorate:The role of migratory birds and public health importance. Vet. World. 2021;14(10):2764&#x2013;2772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8654765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onduru O.G, Mkakosya R.S, Aboud S, Rumisha S.F. Genetic determinants of resistance among ESBL-producing Enterobacteriaceae in community and hospital settings in East, Central, and Southern Africa:A systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence. Can. J. Infect. Dis. Med. Microbiol. 2021;2021:5153237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8192179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34122680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund D, Parras-Molt&#xf3; M, Inda-D&#xed;az J.S, Ebmeyer S, Larsson D.G.J, Johnning A, Kristiansson E. Genetic compatibility and ecological connectivity drive the dissemination of antibiotic resistance genes. Nat. Commun. 2025;16:2595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11911422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40090954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>