<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41384801</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of Sport Representation and Attitudes Toward Strength Training on Neuromuscular Performance Profiles in University Athletes: Part II Male Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>324</StartPage><EndPage>336</EndPage><MedlinePgn>324-336</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005310</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>McClean, ZJ, da Silva Torres, R, Herzog, W, Pasanen, K, Lun, V, and Jordan, MJ. The influence of sport representation and attitudes toward strength training on neuromuscular performance profiles in university athletes: Part I-Male athletes. J Strength Cond Res 40(3): 324-336, 2026-Strength, power, and plyometric testing are essential to evaluate neuromuscular performance in athletes. However, this approach creates datasets with numerous outcome measures that can lead to challenges for interpretation and establishing relevant performance benchmarks for preseason testing and performance-readiness after injury. The idea that athlete performance profiles exist within a larger population has been suggested, but limited research has explored this concept or suggested methodologies for delineating relevant profiles. Exploring the existence of neuromuscular performance profiles in university athletes while accounting for the influence of the sport environment and psychosocial factors, such as attitudes toward strength training, may support more athlete-specific neuromuscular benchmarks. Healthy male university athletes ( n = 272) from 5 sports completed a comprehensive neuromuscular performance testing battery and a questionnaire that included assessment of attitudes toward strength training. Unsupervised machine learning applied to the body weight-normalized neuromuscular performance dataset, along with Fisher's exact tests, was used to examine differences in attitudes toward strength training across clusters (alpha = 0.05). Five profiles were identified, including a high strength/high power/braking-dominant jump strategy cluster with a large ice hockey representation and a high strength/high power/fast jump strategy cluster consisting mostly of field-sport athletes. Differences in attitudes toward training were noted across profiles ( p &lt; 0.05); for instance, athletes in a low-strength/low-power profile tended to prefer training in a more private training environment ( p = 0.023). These results may help inform neuromuscular performance benchmarks in male university athletes, while the psychosocial characteristics of these profiles may provide insight into increasing strength training engagement in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClean</LastName><ForeName>Zachary J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7219-9448</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva Torres</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Group, Wageningen University &amp; Research, Wageningen, the Netherlands ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herzog</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasanen</LastName><ForeName>Kati</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lun</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Medicine Center, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Neuromuscular Sport Performance Lab, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Medicine Center, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CGS D-589477-2024</GrantID><Agency>Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete profiling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">countermovement jump testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unsupervised machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41384801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Wahl MJ, Button DC, Power KE, Anderson KG. Relationship between hockey skating speed and selected performance measures. J Strength Cond Res 19: 326&#x2013;331, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: Comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance profiling, neuromuscular fatigue monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Cond J 45: 545&#x2013;553, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Read P, Chavda S, Turner A. Asymmetries of the lower limb: The calculation conundrum in strength training and conditioning. Strength Cond J 38: 27&#x2013;32, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. An applied research model for the sport sciences. Sports Med 38: 253&#x2013;263, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittencourt NFN, Meeuwisse WH, Mendon&#xe7;a LD, Nettel-Aguirre A, Ocarino JM, Fonseca ST. Complex systems approach for sports injuries: Moving from risk factor identification to injury pattern recognition&#x2014;narrative review and new concept. Br J Sports Med 50: 1309&#x2013;1314, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Magnusson SP, Rasmussen LR, Kjaer M, Aagaard P. Muscle performance during maximal isometric and dynamic contractions is influenced by the stiffness of the tendinous structures. J Appl Physiol 99: 986&#x2013;994, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casimiro-Art&#xe9;s M&#xc1;, Hileno R, Garcia-de-Alcaraz A. Applying unsupervised machine learning models to identify serve performance related indicators in women's volleyball. Res Q Exerc Sport 95: 47&#x2013;53, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chander B, Gopalakrishnan K. Data clustering using unsupervised machine learning. In: Statistical Modeling in Machine Learning. Goswami T, Sinha GR, eds. Academic Press, 2023. pp. 179&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin J, McNair PJ, Marshall RN. Velocity specificity, combination training and sport specific tasks. J Sci Med Sport 4: 168&#x2013;178, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui M. Introduction to the K-Means clustering algorithm based on the elbow method. Account Audit Finance 1: 5&#x2013;8, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B, Layer J, Vertz C, et al. Baseline assessments of strength and balance performance and bilateral asymmetries in collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res 33: 3015&#x2013;3029, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworkin SL. &#x201c;Holding back&#x201d;: Negotiating a glass ceiling on women's muscular strength. Sociol Perspect 44: 333&#x2013;350, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fidos-Czuba O, Rutkowski L, et al. Predicting competitive swimming performance. Cent Eur J Sport Sci Med 9, 2015. Accessed November 15, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli N, Petrie T, Chatterton J. Team weigh-ins and self-weighing: Relations to body-related perceptions and disordered eating in collegiate male athletes. Psychol Sport Exerc 29: 51&#x2013;55, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JE, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exerc Sci 11: 226&#x2013;238, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. Lower limb asymmetry in mechanical muscle function: A comparison between ski racers with and without ACL reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: e301&#x2013;e309, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. A comparison of lower limb stiffness and mechanical muscle function in ACL-reconstructed, elite, and adolescent alpine ski racers/ski cross athletes. J Sport Health Sci 7: 416&#x2013;424, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Morris N, Lane M, et al. Monitoring the return to sport transition after ACL injury: An alpine ski racing case study. Front Sports Act Living 2: 12, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kauffmann J, Esders M, Ruff L, Montavon G, Samek W, Muller KR. From clustering to cluster explanations via neural networks. IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst 35: 1926&#x2013;1940, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopka T. umap: Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection, 2023. Available from https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/umap/index.html . Accessed November 13, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RK, Wastvedt S, Pareek A, et al. Unsupervised machine learning of the combined Danish and Norwegian knee ligament registers: Identification of 5 distinct patient groups with differing ACL revision rates. Am J Sports Med 52: 881&#x2013;891, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean Z, Mossel NBv, McKenzie M, et al. Lower extremity asymmetry values derived from multiple strength testing modes are associated with perceived functional capabilities among university athletes. Transl Sports Med 2024: 5589056, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean ZJ, McKenzie M, Zukowski M, et al. Predicting multijoint maximal eccentric and concentric strength with force-velocity jump mechanics in collegiate athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 20: 399&#x2013;410, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean ZJ, Pasanen K, Lun V, et al. A biopsychosocial model for understanding training load, fatigue, and musculoskeletal sport injury in university athletes: A scoping review. J Strength Cond Res 38: 1177&#x2013;1188, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean ZJ, da Silva Torres R, Herzog W, et al. Establishing population-specific neuromuscular strength benchmarks using an unsupervised machine learning approach in female university athletes. J Strength Cond Res, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes J&#xfa;nior PR, De Souza RM, Werneck RDO, et al. Nearest neighbors distance ratio open-set classifier. Mach Learn 106: 359&#x2013;386, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf8;ller M, Zebis MK, Myklebust G, Lind M, Wedderkopp N, Bekker S. &#x201c;Is it fun and does it enhance my performance?&#x201d;&#x2014;Key implementation considerations for injury prevention programs in youth handball. J Sci Med Sport 24: 1136&#x2013;1142, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosenthal W, Kim M, Holzshu R, Hanypsiak B, Athiviraham A. Common ice hockey injuries and treatment: A current concepts review. Curr Sports Med Rep 16: 357&#x2013;362, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevill AM, Bate S, Holder RL. Modeling physiological and anthropometric variables known to vary with body size and other confounding variables. Am J Phys Anthropol 128: 141&#x2013;153, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios D, Barco R. Unsupervised technique for automatic selection of performance indicators in self-organizing networks. IEEE Commun Lett 21: 2198&#x2013;2201, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasanen K, Sepp&#xe4;nen A, Lepp&#xe4;nen M, et al. Knee laxity, joint hypermobility, femoral anteversion, hamstring extensibility and navicular drop as risk factors for non-contact ACL injury in female athletes: A 4.5-year prospective cohort study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc: ksa.12625, 2025. Accessed April 4, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, et al. Scikit-learn: Machine learning in python. J Mach Learn Res 12: 2825&#x2013;2830, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivi&#xe8;re JR, Rossi J, Jimenez-Reyes P, Morin J-B, Samozino P. Where does the one-repetition maximum exist on the force-velocity relationship in squat? Int J Sports Med 38: 1035&#x2013;1043, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins DW. Positional physical characteristics of players drafted into the National Football League. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2661&#x2013;2667, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DJ. A framework for understanding the training process leading to elite performance. Sports Med 33: 1103&#x2013;1126, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyanskaya O, Cantor M, Sherlock G, et al. Missing value estimation methods for DNA microarrays. Bioinformatics 17: 520&#x2013;525, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigh-Larsen JF, Mohr M. The physiology of ice hockey performance: An update. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14284, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellsandt E, Failla MJ, Snyder-Mackler L. Limb symmetry indexes can overestimate knee function after anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 47: 334&#x2013;338, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkerson GB, Colston MA, Baker CS. A sport fitness index for assessment of sport-related injury risk. Clin J Sport Med 26: 423&#x2013;428, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>