<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41209072</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2056-5909</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of aerobic and inspiratory strength muscle training on exaggerated blood pressure response during exercise in hypertensive patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e35</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e35</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e35</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5646/ch.2025.31.e35</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An exaggerated blood pressure response (EBPR) to exercise predicts future hypertension and cardiovascular disease. Although aerobic exercise (AE) and inspiratory muscle strength training (IMST) lower resting blood pressure (BP), their capacity to attenuate EBPR has not been compared. This study examined the effects of AE and IMST on EBPR during maximal exercise testing in hypertensive patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-four participants were randomly assigned to AE (<i>n</i> = 12, 40-70% of heart rate reserve, 30 minutes) or IMST (<i>n</i> = 12, 55-75% of maximal inspiratory pressure, 30 breaths/day), 5 days/week for 8 weeks. Brachial BP and heart rate were measured at rest, during each stage of a graded cycle-ergometer test, and during recovery. EBPR was defined as peak systolic BP (SBP) &#x2265; 210 mmHg (men) or &#x2265; 190 mmHg (women). Primary outcomes were changes in SBP across exercise stages and prevalence of EBPR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Both interventions reduced resting SBP (-8.0 mmHg) and diastolic BP (-4.2 mmHg). The prevalence of EBPR declined from 62.5% to 45.8%, though this did not reach statistical significance (&#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> = 1.34, <i>P</i> = 0.25). Subgroup analysis showed greater SBP attenuation at moderate intensity with AE (-9.2 mmHg, <i>P</i> = 0.020) and at higher intensity with IMST (-8.8 mmHg, <i>P</i> = 0.042).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Both AE and IMST attenuated SBP responses during submaximal exercise in hypertensive individuals. These findings highlight a potential for exercise training to mitigate EBPR in hypertension.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Korean Society of Hypertension.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Ho Jeong</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1903-4291</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Tae Gu</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0422-9692</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyun Jeong</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5159-9525</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunutsor</LastName><ForeName>Setor K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2625-0273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Rady Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jae</LastName><ForeName>Sae Young</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0358-7866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Urban Social Health, Graduate School of Urban Public Health, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101669508</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2056-5909</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inspiratory muscle strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maximal exercise testing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interest: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41209072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12591863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5646/ch.2025.31.e35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schultz MG, Sharman JE. Exercise hypertension. Pulse (Basel) 2014;1:161&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26587435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuspidi C, Gherbesi E, Faggiano A, Sala C, Carugo S, Grassi G, et al. Masked hypertension and exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise: a review and meta-analysis. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023;13:1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10047162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36980313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayrak M, Bacaksiz A, Vatankulu MA, Ayhan SS, Kaya Z, Ari H, et al. Exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise--a new portent of masked hypertension. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2010;32:560&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21091361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharman JE, Hare JL, Thomas S, Davies JE, Leano R, Jenkins C, et al. Association of masked hypertension and left ventricular remodeling with the hypertensive response to exercise. Am J Hypertens. 2011;24:898&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuspidi C, Faggiano A, Gherbesi E, Sala C, Grassi G, Tadic M. Clinical and prognostic value of exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise. Rev Cardiovasc Med. 2023;24:64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11263987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39077480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae SY, Fernhall B, Heffernan KS, Kang M, Lee MK, Choi YH, et al. Exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise is associated with carotid atherosclerosis in apparently healthy men. J Hypertens. 2006;24:881&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16612250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae SY, Franklin BA, Choo J, Choi YH, Fernhall B. Exaggerated exercise blood pressure response during treadmill testing as a predictor of future hypertension in men: a longitudinal study. Am J Hypertens. 2015;28:1362&#x2013;1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25824452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae SY, Kim HJ, Kurl S, Kunutsor SK, Laukkanen JA. Independent and joint associations of exercise blood pressure and cardiorespiratory fitness with the risk of cardiovascular mortality. Am J Hypertens. 2023;36:148&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36520452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller K, Stelzer K, Ostad MA, Post F. Impact of exaggerated blood pressure response in normotensive individuals on future hypertension and prognosis: systematic review according to PRISMA guideline. Adv Med Sci. 2017;62:317&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyai N, Arita M, Morioka I, Miyashita K, Nishio I, Takeda S. Exercise BP response in subjects with high-normal BP: exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise and risk of future hypertension in subjects with high-normal blood pressure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2000;36:1626&#x2013;1631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Hashizume T, Wanaka Y, Handa S, Nakamura C, Fujiwara S, et al. Effects of antihypertensive agents on blood pressure during exercise. Hypertens Res. 2001;24:671&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11768726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidiville J, Nussberger J, Waeber G, Porchet M, Waeber B, Brunner HR. Individual responses to converting enzyme inhibitors and calcium antagonists. Hypertension. 1988;11:166&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2830189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mert KU, &#x15e;ener E, Y&#x131;lmaz AS, Mert G&#xd6;, Yetmi&#x15f; F, Dural M, et al. The association of exaggerated hypertensive response to exercise and beta-blockers use in hypertensives. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2020;42:707&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32543272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babcock MC, Robinson AT, Migdal KU, Watso JC, Martens CR, Edwards DG, et al. High salt intake augments blood pressure responses during submaximal aerobic exercise. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:e015633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7660875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bommarito JC, Stapleton RK, Murray NS, Burr JF, Millar PJ. Acute partial sleep deprivation attenuates blood pressure responses to cycling exercise. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2024;327:H947&#x2013;H955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JT, Sutterfield SL, Post HK, Lovoy GM, Banister HR, Turpin VG, et al. Impact of high sodium intake on blood pressure and functional sympatholysis during rhythmic handgrip exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2020;45:613&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31725319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green M, Ken-Dror G, Fluck D, Sada C, Sharma P, Fry CH, et al. Meta-analysis of changes in the levels of catecholamines and blood pressure with continuous positive airway pressure therapy in obstructive sleep apnea. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2021;23:12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8030100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Franklin BA, Fagard R, Farquhar WB, Kelley GA, Ray CA, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and hypertension. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:533&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craighead DH, Freeberg KA, McCarty NP, Rossman MJ, Moreau KL, You Z, et al. Inspiratory muscle strength training for lowering blood pressure and improving endothelial function in postmenopausal women: comparison with &#x201c;standard of care&#x201d; aerobic exercise. Front Physiol. 2022;13:967478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jae SY, Choi TG, Kim HJ, Kunutsor SK. Comparison of inspiratory muscle strength and aerobic exercise training and detraining on blood pressure in hypertensive patients. Clin Hypertens. 2025;31:e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11975636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40201315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HY, Shin J, Kim GH, Park S, Ihm SH, Kim HC, et al. 2018 Korean Society of Hypertension guidelines for the management of hypertension: part II-diagnosis and treatment of hypertension. Clin Hypertens. 2019;25:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Ades PA, Kligfield P, Arena R, Balady GJ, Bittner VA, et al. Exercise standards for testing and training: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013;128:873&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craighead DH, Heinbockel TC, Freeberg KA, Rossman MJ, Jackman RA, Jankowski LR, et al. Time-efficient inspiratory muscle strength training lowers blood pressure and improves endothelial function, NO bioavailability, and oxidative stress in midlife/older adults with above-normal blood pressure. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:e020980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34184544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz MG, La Gerche A, Sharman JE. Cardiorespiratory fitness, workload, and the blood pressure response to exercise testing. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2022;50:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34669623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone BB, Wang NY, Bacher AC, Stewart KJ. Decreased exercise blood pressure in older adults after exercise training: contributions of increased fitness and decreased fatness. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43:52&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18728054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijkman MO, Sandberg K, Kleist M, Falk L, Enthoven P. The exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise in the sub-acute phase after stroke is not affected by aerobic exercise. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2018;20:56&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29338111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Verheyden B, Aubert AE, Fagard RH. Effects of aerobic training intensity on resting, exercise and post-exercise blood pressure, heart rate and heart-rate variability. J Hum Hypertens. 2010;24:175&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19554028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubolsakka-Jones C, Tongdee P, Jones DA. The effects of slow loaded breathing training on exercise blood pressure in isolated systolic hypertension. Physiother Res Int. 2019;24:e1785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31141288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keadle SK, Conroy DE, Buman MP, Dunstan DW, Matthews CE. Targeting reductions in sitting time to increase physical activity and improve health. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:1572&#x2013;1582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5511092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28272267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Maiorana A, O&#x2019;Driscoll G, Taylor R. Effect of exercise training on endothelium-derived nitric oxide function in humans. J Physiol. 2004;561:1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15375191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Hopman MTE, Padilla J, Laughlin MH, Thijssen DHJ. Vascular adaptation to exercise in humans: role of hemodynamic stimuli. Physiol Rev. 2017;97:495&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28151424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monahan KD. Effect of aging on baroreflex function in humans. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2007;293:R3&#x2013;R12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLucia CM, Tavoian D, Debonis DR, Wyatt Snell E, Schwyhart SM, Bailey EF. A short course of high-resistance, low-volume breathing exercise extends respiratory endurance and blunts cardiovascular responsiveness to constant load respiratory testing in healthy young adults. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2023;307:103974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10136372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36180018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranish JR, Bailey EF. Daily respiratory training with large intrathoracic pressures, but not large lung volumes, lowers blood pressure in normotensive adults. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2015;216:63&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le VV, Mitiku T, Sungar G, Myers J, Froelicher V. The blood pressure response to dynamic exercise testing: a systematic review. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2008;51:135&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18774013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghidoni C, Kruzik M, Rossi VA, Caselli S, Schmied CM, Niederseer D. Definitions for hypertensive response to exercise. Cardiol Rev. 2024;32:273&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36729898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>