<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41380037</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-7312</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of developmental and behavioral pediatrics : JDBP</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Dev Behav Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pediatric Resident Participation in Primary Care Autism Evaluations: A Novel Continuity Clinic Training Opportunity.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/DBP.0000000000001442</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">There is a growing need for autism evaluations in young children. Wait times to evaluation are long due to the limited specialty workforce. Primary care autism evaluations are 1 solution, but many providers lack training and confidence in autism care. Literature highlights the need for improvement in developmental and behavioral pediatrics training among pediatric residents. This study evaluates resident confidence in autism care after participation in a novel autism evaluation pathway in a primary care pediatric resident continuity clinic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Pediatric residents led a primary care autism evaluation with a trained pediatrician in their continuity clinic. Residents were provided with enhanced autism education which included neurodiversity-affirming strategies and training on the use of an autism assessment tool. Presurveys and postsurveys were used to assess resident confidence in autism care before and after the educational intervention. Survey data were compared using Mann-Whitney U tests appropriate for ordinal, nonpaired data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty resident-led autism evaluations were conducted during the study period. There was statistically significant improvement in resident confidence in autism screening, use of assessment tools, evaluation, diagnosis, treatment recommendations, sharing resources, understanding of neurodiversity, and use of a strength-based approach after participation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Providing autism education and hands-on primary care autism evaluation training opportunities for residents in pediatric continuity clinic improves confidence in autism care. This model is 1 way to enhance autism education and training during pediatric residency which may have a positive impact on the care provided to autistic patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Brittany</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-3538-200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Academic Pediatrics, Department of Pediatrics, Nemours Children's Health, Wilmington, DE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sidney Kimmel Medical College at Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Informatics Center, Nemours Children's Health, Wilmington, DE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrison</LastName><ForeName>Meghan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Academic Pediatrics, Department of Pediatrics, Nemours Children's Health, Wilmington, DE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U54 GM104941</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CARE T37</GrantID><Agency>Weill Cornell Career Advancement for Research in Health Equity</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U54-GM104941</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Dev Behav Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8006933</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0196-206X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resident education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41380037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2138717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12928545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DBP.0000000000001442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004703-990000000-00328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shaw KA, Williams S, Patrick ME, et al. Prevalence and early identification of autism spectrum disorder among children aged 4 and 8 years &#x2014; autism and developmental disabilities monitoring network, 16 sites, United States, 2022. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2025;74:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12011386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40232988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwaigenbaum L, Bauman ML, Fein D, et al. Early screening of autism spectrum disorder: recommendations for practice and research. Pediatrics. 2015;136 (Suppl 1):S41&#x2013;S59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26430169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie LK, Orr CJ, Turner AL, et al. Child health and the US pediatric subspecialty workforce: planning for the future. Pediatrics. 2024;153:e2023063678B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38299999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YH, Drye M, Chen Q, et al. Delay from screening to diagnosis in autism spectrum disorder: results from a large national health research network. J Pediatr. 2023;260:113514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10805541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37244580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthrie W, Wallis K, Bennett A, et al. Accuracy of autism screening in a large pediatric network. Pediatrics. 2019;144:e20183963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce K, Gazestani VH, Bacon E, et al. Evaluation of the diagnostic stability of the early autism spectrum disorder phenotype in the general population starting at 12 months. JAMA Pediatr. 2019;173:578&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum RA, Berman BD, Fussell JJ, et al. Child health needs and the developmental-behavioral pediatrics workforce supply: 2020&#x2013;2040. Pediatrics. 2024;153:e2023063678H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38300001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyman SL, Levy SE, Myers SM; et al. Identification, evaluation, and management of children with autism spectrum disorder. Pediatrics. 2020;145:e20193447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31843864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazurek MO, Kuhlthau K, Parker RA, et al. Autism and general developmental screening practices among primary care providers. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2021;42:355&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamp N, DeHaan SL, Cerf CM, et al. Primary care pediatricians&#x2019; perspectives on autism care. Pediatrics. 2023;151:e2022057712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36550067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro SA, Dempsey J, Berry LN, et al. Screening and referral practices for autism spectrum disorder in primary pediatric care. Pediatrics. 2019;144:e20183326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone PS, Murphy NA, Norlin C, et al. Parent and pediatrician perspectives regarding the primary care of children with autism spectrum disorders. J Autism Dev Disord. 2013;43:964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22948548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boreman CD, Thomasgard MC, Fernandez SA, et al. Resident training in developmental/behavioral pediatrics: where do we stand? Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2007;46:135&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17325086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahidullah JD, Kettlewell PW, Palejwala MH, et al. Behavioral health training in pediatric residency programs: a national survey of training directors. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2018;39:292&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29346135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major NE, Peacock G, Ruben W, et al. Autism training in pediatric residency: evaluation of a case-based curriculum. J Autism Dev Disord. 2013;43:1171&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23008057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belzer K, Flake E, Kiger M. Enhancing resident education in autism diagnosis: training on the screening tool for autism in toddlers. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2023;44:e358&#x2013;e364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37216572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hine JF, Wagner L, Goode R, et al. Enhancing developmental-behavioral pediatric rotations by teaching residents how to evaluate autism in primary care. Autism. 2021;25:1492&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8255322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicano E, den Houting J. Annual research review: shifting from &#x2018;normal science&#x2019; to neurodiversity in autism science. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2022;63:381&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9298391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34730840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM-5). 5th ed. Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Publishing; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda-Ojeda R, Wickramasinghe A, Ntolkeras G, et al. The neurodiversity framework in medicine: on the spectrum. Dev Neurobiol. 2025;85:e22960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39874176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saade S, Bockstal-Fieulaine B, Gillespie-Lynch K, et al. Evaluation of an autism training in a much-needed context: the case of France. Autism Adulthood. 2023;5:289&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10468555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37663443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally Keehn R, Swigonski N, Enneking B, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of primary care clinicians across a statewide system of autism evaluation. Pediatrics. 2023;152:e2023061188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37461867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hine J, Foster T, Wagner L, et al. 
ASD-PEDS: An Autism Evaluation Tool for Toddlers and Young Children, User&#x2019;s Manual. Nashville, Tennessee: Vanderbilt Kennedy Center; 2023. Available at: https://vkc.vumc.org/vkc/triad/manual/asd-peds/. Accessed March 25, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schopler E, Van Bourgondien ME, Wellman GJ, et al. 
(CARS<sup>&#xae;</sup>2) Childhood Autism Rating Scale, Second Edition. Los Angeles, CA: Western Psychological Services; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florida State University, Autism Navigator, LLC. Autism Navigator;  [web-based tool]. 2018. Available at: https://resources.autismnavigator.com/. Accessed March 25, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hine JF, Allin J, Allman A et al. Increasing access to autism spectrum disorder diagnostic consultation in rural and underserved communities: streamlined evaluation within primary care. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2020;41:16&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6933088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31490843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>