<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41480326</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>48</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring exercise modalities and their impact on inflammatory bowel disease: A systematic review of rodent colitis models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113243</StartPage><MedlinePgn>113243</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">113243</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v31.i48.113243</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Lifestyle factors are closely associated with the onset and progression of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Studies have demonstrated the positive effects of exercise on clinical outcomes and quality of life in individuals with IBD. Despite the well-documented role of exercise in improving IBD outcomes, the underlying mechanisms remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the efficacy of different exercise modalities and explore their potential physiological mechanisms in rodent models of colitis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a comprehensive search of five databases from inception to September 24, 2024, which yielded 19 animal studies in rodent colitis models. We compared the efficacy of various forms of exercise and explored the possible physiological mechanisms. The effects of different exercise modalities, namely forced treadmill running (FTR), voluntary wheel running (VWR), swimming, climbing, and jumping, on both macroscopic symptoms (<i>e.g.</i>, body weight, disease activity, and colon length) and microscopic parameters (<i>e.g.</i>, histopathology, immune markers, oxidative/antioxidant balance, and gut microbiota) in colitis models were compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">VWR (simulated recreational physical activity), swimming (aerobic exercise), and strength training (climbing and jumping) consistently promoted overall health in animal colitis models. However, evidence for FTR remains inconsistent, with a notable number of studies suggesting potential exacerbation of colitis symptoms, possibly due to stress or fatigue resulting from its coercive nature. Overall, various exercise (<i>e.g.</i>, VWR, swimming, strength training) ameliorates colitis symptoms possibly by suppressing immune hyperactivation, enhancing antioxidant defenses, and modulating gut microbiota composition. In contrast, FTR was inconsistent, with several studies indicating a potential exacerbation of colitis symptoms, possibly due to stress or fatigue induced by its coercive nature.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Exercise modality is critical in influencing colitis outcomes, with voluntary and low-stress forms generally being beneficial, while forced exercise may yield adverse effects. These findings highlight the importance of exercise type and individual tolerance in designing therapeutic exercise interventions for IBD. Further research is warranted to establish a robust therapeutic framework for exercise-based interventions in IBD management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Shao-Peng</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Qing</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Hong</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China. lvbin@medmail.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Animal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003092" MajorTopicYN="Y">Colitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013550" MajorTopicYN="N">Swimming</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Animal study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ulcerative colitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41480326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v31.i48.113243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kaplan GG, Windsor JW. The four epidemiological stages in the global evolution of inflammatory bowel disease. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18:56&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7542092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33033392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamina M, Minozzi S, Warusavitarne J, Buskens CJ, Chaparro M, Verstockt B, Kopylov U, Yanai H, Vavricka SR, Sigall-Boneh R, Sica GS, Reenaers C, Peros G, Papamichael K, Noor N, Moran GW, Maaser C, Luglio G, Kotze PG, Kobayashi T, Karmiris K, Kapizioni C, Iqbal N, Iacucci M, Holubar S, Hanzel J, Sabino JG, Gisbert JP, Fiorino G, Fidalgo C, Ellu P, El-Hussuna A, de Groof J, Czuber-Dochan W, Casanova MJ, Burisch J, Brown SR, Bislenghi G, Bettenworth D, Battat R, Atreya R, Allocca M, Agrawal M, Raine T, Gordon H, Myrelid P. ECCO Guidelines on Therapeutics in Crohn's Disease: Surgical Treatment. J Crohns Colitis. 2024;18:1556&#x2013;1582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38878002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Hur D, Issaschar G, Moshe R, Lebedenko B, Lujan R, Haklai Z, Loewenberg Weisband Y, Ben-Tov A, Lederman N, Matz E, Dotan I, Turner D, Pinto GD, Waterman M. Risk of Age-related and Disease-related Complications and Mortality in Elderly-onset Inflammatory Bowel Disease: A Population-based Study. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2025;23:1982&#x2013;1990.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40089251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buie MJ, Quan J, Windsor JW, Coward S, Hansen TM, King JA, Kotze PG, Gearry RB, Ng SC, Mak JWY, Abreu MT, Rubin DT, Bernstein CN, Banerjee R, Yamamoto-Furusho JK, Panaccione R, Seow CH, Ma C, Underwood FE, Ahuja V, Panaccione N, Shaheen AA, Holroyd-Leduc J, Kaplan GG Global IBD Visualization of Epidemiology Studies in the 21st Century (GIVES-21) Research Group, Balderramo D, Chong VH, Juliao-Ba&#xf1;os F, Dutta U, Simadibrata M, Kaibullayeva J, Sun Y, Hilmi I, Raja Ali RA, Paudel MS, Altuwaijri M, Hartono JL, Wei SC, Limsrivilai J, El Ouali S, Vergara BI, Dao VH, Kelly P, Hodges P, Miao Y, Li M. Global Hospitalization Trends for Crohn's Disease and Ulcerative Colitis in the 21st Century: A Systematic Review With Temporal Analyses. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;21:2211&#x2013;2221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Cheon JH. Incidence and Prevalence of Inflammatory Bowel Disease across Asia. Yonsei Med J. 2021;62:99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piovani D, Danese S, Peyrin-Biroulet L, Nikolopoulos GK, Lytras T, Bonovas S. Environmental Risk Factors for Inflammatory Bowel Diseases: An Umbrella Review of Meta-analyses. Gastroenterology. 2019;157:647&#x2013;659.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31014995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papamichael K, Afif W, Drobne D, Dubinsky MC, Ferrante M, Irving PM, Kamperidis N, Kobayashi T, Kotze PG, Lambert J, Noor NM, Roblin X, Roda G, Vande Casteele N, Yarur AJ, Arebi N, Danese S, Paul S, Sandborn WJ, Vermeire S, Cheifetz AS, Peyrin-Biroulet L International Consortium for Therapeutic Drug Monitoring. Therapeutic drug monitoring of biologics in inflammatory bowel disease: unmet needs and future perspectives. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;7:171&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10187071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Sun S. Unlocking the Power of Physical Activity in Inflammatory Bowel Disease: A Comprehensive Review. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2024;2024:7138811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39759160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun SP, Chen JJ, Zheng MX, Fan YH, Lv B. Progress in research of exercise intervention in inflammatory bowel disease. Shijie Huaren Xiaohua Zazhi. 2024;32:339&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protano C, Gall&#xe8; F, Volpini V, De Giorgi A, Mazzeo E, Ubaldi F, Romano Spica V, Vitali M, Valeriani F. Physical activity in the prevention and management of inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review. J Public Health (Berl) 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivi&#x107; I, Sila S, Mi&#x161;ak Z, Niseteo T, Bato&#x161; AT, Hojsak I, Kola&#x10d;ek S. Impact of an exercise program in children with inflammatory bowel disease in remission. Pediatr Res. 2023;93:1999&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeger WA, Thieringer J, Esters P, Allmendinger B, Stein J, Schulze H, Dignass A. Moderate endurance and muscle training is beneficial and safe in patients with quiescent or mildly active Crohn's disease. United European Gastroenterol J. 2020;8:804&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7434996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32580666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooijmans CR, Rovers MM, de Vries RB, Leenaars M, Ritskes-Hoitinga M, Langendam MW. SYRCLE's risk of bias tool for animal studies. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4230647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24667063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasimay O, G&#xfc;zel E, Gemici A, Abdyli A, Sulovari A, Ercan F, Ye&#x11f;en BC. Colitis-induced oxidative damage of the colon and skeletal muscle is ameliorated by regular exercise in rats: the anxiolytic role of exercise. Exp Physiol. 2006;91:897&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16763006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena A, Fletcher E, Larsen B, Baliga MS, Durstine JL, Fayad R. Effect of exercise on chemically-induced colitis in adiponectin deficient mice. J Inflamm (Lond) 2012;9:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22909126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook MD, Martin SA, Williams C, Whitlock K, Wallig MA, Pence BD, Woods JA. Forced treadmill exercise training exacerbates inflammation and causes mortality while voluntary wheel training is protective in a mouse model of colitis. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;33:46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23707215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilski J, Mazur-Bialy AI, Brzozowski B, Magierowski M, Jasnos K, Krzysiek-Maczka G, Urbanczyk K, Ptak-Belowska A, Zwolinska-Wcislo M, Mach T, Brzozowski T. Moderate exercise training attenuates the severity of experimental rodent colitis: the importance of crosstalk between adipose tissue and skeletal muscles. Mediators Inflamm. 2015;2015:605071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4313673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25684862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilski J, Mazur-Bialy A, Wojcik D, Magierowski M, Surmiak M, Kwiecien S, Magierowska K, Hubalewska-Mazgaj M, Sliwowski Z, Brzozowski T. Effect of Forced Physical Activity on the Severity of Experimental Colitis in Normal Weight and Obese Mice. Involvement of Oxidative Stress and Proinflammatory Biomarkers. Nutrients. 2019;11:1127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6567060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31117199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qonitatillah A, Wigati KW, Irawan R. Physical Exercise Does Not Improve Colon Inflammation in Mice Induced Lambda Carrageenan. J Med Vet. 2020;3:57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Mechelen M, Martens T, Vanden Berghe P, Lories R, Gulino GR. Impact of barrier tissue inflammation and physical activity on joint homeostasis in mice. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2022;61:1690&#x2013;1698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao F, Tian M, Wang H, Li S, Wang X, Jin X, Wang Y, Jiao Y, Tian M. Exercise-induced &#x3b2;-hydroxybutyrate promotes Treg cell differentiation to ameliorate colitis in mice. FASEB J. 2024;38:e23487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38345808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin JJ, Ko IG, Hwang L, Kim SH, Jee YS, Jeon H, Park SB, Jeon JW. Simultaneous Treatment of 5-Aminosalicylic Acid and Treadmill Exercise More Effectively Improves Ulcerative Colitis in Mice. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:5076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11120947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38791116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik-Grzybek D, Sliwowski Z, Kwiecien S, Ginter G, Surmiak M, Hubalewska-Mazgaj M, Chmura A, Wojcik A, Kosciolek T, Danielak A, Targosz A, Strzalka M, Szczyrk U, Ptak-Belowska A, Magierowski M, Bilski J, Brzozowski T. Alkaline Phosphatase Relieves Colitis in Obese Mice Subjected to Forced Exercise via Its Anti-Inflammatory and Intestinal Microbiota-Shaping Properties. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10815191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szalai Z, Sz&#xe1;sz A, Nagy I, Pusk&#xe1;s LG, Kupai K, Kir&#xe1;ly A, Berk&#xf3; AM, P&#xf3;sa A, Strifler G, Bar&#xe1;th Z, Nagy LI, Szab&#xf3; R, P&#xe1;v&#xf3; I, Murlasits Z, Gy&#xf6;ngy&#xf6;si M, Varga C. Anti-inflammatory effect of recreational exercise in TNBS-induced colitis in rats: role of NOS/HO/MPO system. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2014;2014:925981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3941240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24683438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WX, Zhou F, Wang Y, Wang T, Xing JW, Zhang S, Sang LX, Gu SZ, Wang HL. Voluntary exercise protects against ulcerative colitis by up-regulating glucocorticoid-mediated PPAR-&#x3b3; activity in the colon in mice. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2015;215:24&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26031185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazur-Bialy AI, Bilski J, Wojcik D, Brzozowski B, Surmiak M, Hubalewska-Mazgaj M, Chmura A, Magierowski M, Magierowska K, Mach T, Brzozowski T. Beneficial Effect of Voluntary Exercise on Experimental Colitis in Mice Fed a High-Fat Diet: The Role of Irisin, Adiponectin and Proinflammatory Biomarkers. Nutrients. 2017;9:410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5409749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28425943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maillard F, Vazeille E, Sauvanet P, Sirvent P, Bonnet R, Combaret L, Chausse P, Chevarin C, Otero YF, Delcros G, Chavanelle V, Boisseau N, Barnich N. Preventive Effect of Spontaneous Physical Activity on the Gut-Adipose Tissue in a Mouse Model That Mimics Crohn's Disease Susceptibility. Cells. 2019;8:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6356941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30634469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estaki M, Morck DW, Ghosh S, Quin C, Pither J, Barnett JA, Gill SK, Gibson DL. Physical Activity Shapes the Intestinal Microbiome and Immunity of Healthy Mice but Has No Protective Effects against Colitis in MUC2(-/-) Mice. mSystems. 2020;5:e00515&#x2013;e00520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7542559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik-Grzybek D, Hubalewska-Mazgaj M, Surmiak M, Sliwowski Z, Dobrut A, Mlodzinska A, Wojcik A, Kwiecien S, Magierowski M, Mazur-Bialy A, Bilski J, Brzozowski T. The Combination of Intestinal Alkaline Phosphatase Treatment with Moderate Physical Activity Alleviates the Severity of Experimental Colitis in Obese Mice via Modulation of Gut Microbiota, Attenuation of Proinflammatory Cytokines, Oxidative Stress Biomarkers and DNA Oxidative Damage in Colonic Mucosa. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:2964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolahi Z, Yaghoubi A, Rezaeian N, Khazaei M. Exercise Improves Clinical Symptoms, Pathological Changes and Oxidative/Antioxidative Balance in Animal Model of Colitis. Int J Prev Med. 2023;14:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbeyli D, Berberoglu AC, &#xd6;zen A, Erkan O, Ba&#x15f;ar Y, &#x15e;en T, Akak&#x131;n D, Y&#xfc;ksel M, Kas&#x131;may &#xc7;ak&#x131;r &#xd6;. Protective effect of alpha-lipoic acid, aerobic or resistance exercise from colitis in second hand smoke exposed young rats. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2017;44:62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27718277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Santos R, da Silva Cardoso G, da Costa Lima L, de Sousa Cavalcante ML, Silva MS, Cavalcante AKM, Severo JS, de Melo Sousa FB, Pacheco G, Alves EHP, Nobre LMS, Medeiros JVR, Lima-Junior RC, Dos Santos AA, Tolentino M. L-Glutamine and Physical Exercise Prevent Intestinal Inflammation and Oxidative Stress Without Improving Gastric Dysmotility in Rats with Ulcerative Colitis. Inflammation. 2021;44:617&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33128666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace JL, Keenan CM, Gale D, Shoupe TS. Exacerbation of experimental colitis by nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs is not related to elevated leukotriene B4 synthesis. Gastroenterology. 1992;102:18&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1309357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun SP, Lu YF, Li H, Weng CY, Chen JJ, Lou YJ, Lyu D, Lyu B. AMPK activation alleviated dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis by inhibiting ferroptosis. J Dig Dis. 2023;24:213&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37210607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Chen J, Zheng M, Zhou M, Ying X, Shen Y, Hu Y, Ni K, Fan Y, Lv B. Impact of exercise on outcomes among Chinese patients with Crohn's disease: a mixed methods study based on social media and the real world. BMC Gastroenterol. 2024;24:441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11605885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39614151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottoms L, Leighton D, Carpenter R, Anderson S, Langmead L, Ramage J, Faulkner J, Coleman E, Fairhurst C, Seed M, Tew G. Affective and enjoyment responses to 12 weeks of high intensity interval training and moderate continuous training in adults with Crohn's disease. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0222060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6754139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31539378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira BRR, Santos TM, Kilpatrick M, Pires FO, Deslandes AC. Affective and enjoyment responses in high intensity interval training and continuous training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0197124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5991400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29874256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loudon CP, Corroll V, Butcher J, Rawsthorne P, Bernstein CN. The effects of physical exercise on patients with Crohn's disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 1999;94:697&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10086654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng V, Millard W, Lebrun C, Howard J. Exercise and Crohn's disease: speculations on potential benefits. Can J Gastroenterol. 2006;20:657&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17066157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurath MF. Cytokines in inflammatory bowel disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2014;14:329&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24751956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegierska AE, Charitos IA, Topi S, Potenza MA, Montagnani M, Santacroce L. The Connection Between Physical Exercise and Gut Microbiota: Implications for Competitive Sports Athletes. Sports Med. 2022;52:2355&#x2013;2369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klare P, Nigg J, Nold J, Haller B, Krug AB, Mair S, Thoeringer CK, Christle JW, Schmid RM, Halle M, Huber W. The impact of a ten-week physical exercise program on health-related quality of life in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a prospective randomized controlled trial. Digestion. 2015;91:239&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25823689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin O, Barton W, Moran C, Sheehan D, Whiston R, Nugent H, McCarthy Y, Molloy CB, O'Sullivan O, Cotter PD, Molloy MG, Shanahan F. Moderate-intensity aerobic and resistance exercise is safe and favorably influences body composition in patients with quiescent Inflammatory Bowel Disease: a randomized controlled cross-over trial. BMC Gastroenterol. 2019;19:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6373036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30755154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Wang Y, Lin Z, Zhang F, Zhang Y, Ren T, Wang L, Qiao Q, Shen M, Wang J, Song Y, Sun Y, Lin P. Irisin delays the onset of type 1 diabetes in NOD mice by enhancing intestinal barrier. Int J Biol Macromol. 2024;265:130857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38493812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Liang J, Huang J, Wang M, Wu L, Wu T, Chen N. Exerkine irisin mitigates cognitive impairment by suppressing gut-brain axis-mediated inflammation. J Adv Res. 2025;75:843&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39481644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>