<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41359933</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reproducibility of Rate of Perceived Exertion-Based Self-Selected Running Speeds on Indoor Track and Treadmill Conditions in Recreational Runners.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e125</StartPage><EndPage>e130</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e125-e130</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005293</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nguyen, AP, Kisita, V, Van Cant, J, Monnet, T, and Bosquet, L. Reproducibility of rate of perceived exertion-based self-selected running speeds on indoor track and treadmill conditions in recreational runners. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): e125-e130, 2026-This study evaluates the reproducibility of self-selected speeds at a rate of perceived exertion (RPE) of 3/10 in both track and treadmill conditions. It also investigates the differences between 2 conditions: i.e., track versus treadmill and 2 RPE instructions, i.e., 3/10 and 8/10. In addition, it compares spatiotemporal parameters across conditions and RPE levels. Fifty-five recreational runners completed six 1-km runs under randomized conditions: 4 at 3/10 and 2 at 8/10 RPE on both track and treadmill. Spatiotemporal parameters, heart rate, and self-selected speeds were recorded. Reliability was assessed using intraclass correlation coefficients (ICC), standard error of measurement ( SEM ), and minimal detectable change (MDC). Statistical significance for all tests was set at &#x3b1; = 0.05. Self-selected speeds showed excellent reliability on both surfaces (ICC = 0.93-0.97). The track showed lower SEM (0.3 km&#xb7;h -1 ) and MDC (0.7 km&#xb7;h -1 ) values compared with the treadmill ( SEM : 0.6 km&#xb7;h -1 ; MDC: 1.6 km&#xb7;h -1 ). Speeds were 20% slower at 3/10 RPE and 10% slower at 8/10 RPE on the treadmill. Treadmill running exhibited longer contact times (+13%), shorter flight times (-35%), and shorter step lengths (-6%) at 3/10 RPE, with similar trends observed at 8/10 RPE. Rate of perceived exertion appears to be a reliable and practical tool for monitoring and prescribing running intensity levels. The slower treadmill speeds at comparable RPE levels may help reduce biomechanical loading on the lower limb joints, offering advantages for rehabilitation. However, differences in biomechanics and perceived effort between treadmill and track running highlight the need for context-specific applications in training and rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Anh Phong</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Louvain, Institute of Experimental and Clinical Research, Neuromusculoskeletal Laboratory, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Louvain, Faculty of Movement and Rehabilitation Sciences, Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Running Clinic, Lac Beauport, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kisita</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-9222-2813</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Louvain, Institute of Experimental and Clinical Research, Neuromusculoskeletal Laboratory, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Louvain, Faculty of Movement and Rehabilitation Sciences, Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Cant</LastName><ForeName>Joachim</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Running Clinic, Lac Beauport, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Human Motor Sciences, Research Unit in Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Brussels, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monnet</LastName><ForeName>Tony</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute PPrime (UPR 3346), University of Poitiers-ISAE-ENSMA, CNRS, Chasseneuil-du-Poitou, France ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bosquet</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory MOVE (UR 20296), Faculty of Sport Sciences (UFR STAPS), University of Poitiers, Poitiers, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Test</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010465" MajorTopicYN="N">Perception</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">borg scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reliability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">runner</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41359933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexeev SO, Trikha R, Short S, Hunt KJ. The antigravity treadmill as a postoperative and injury rehabilitation tool: Reduction in contact forces and muscle activity with reduced weight running. Clin J Sport Med 35: 45&#x2013;51, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey JP, Dufek JS, Freedman Silvernail J, Navalta J, Mercer J. Understanding the influence of perceived fatigue on coordination during endurance running. Sports Biomech 19: 618&#x2013;632, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berzosa C, Comeras-Chueca C, Bascuas PJ, Guti&#xe9;rrez H, Bataller-Cervero AV. Assessing trail running biomechanics: A comparative analysis of the reliability of StrydTM and GARMINRP wearable devices. Sensors 24: 3570&#x2013;3587, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnaerens S, Fiers P, Galle S, et al. Grounded running reduces musculoskeletal loading. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 708&#x2013;715, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cart&#xf3;n-Llorente A, Roche-Seruendo LE, Ja&#xe9;n-Carrillo D, Marcen-Cinca N, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F. Absolute reliability and agreement between Stryd and RunScribe systems for the assessment of running power. Proc Inst Mech Eng P J Sports Eng Technol 235: 182&#x2013;187, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceci R, Hassmen P. Self-monitored exercise at three different RPE intensities in treadmill vs field running. Med Sci Sports Exerc 23: 732&#x2013;738, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasilva SG, Guidetti L, Buzzachera CF, et al. Psychophysiological responses to self-paced treadmill and overground exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1114&#x2013;1124, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Fontenay BP, Roy JS, Dubois B, Bouyer L, Esculier JF. Validating commercial wearable sensors for running gait parameters estimation. IEEE Sens J 20: 7783&#x2013;7791, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina KA, Wright AA, Ford KR, Wirfel LA, Smoliga JM. Physiological and biomechanical responses to running on lower body positive pressure treadmills in healthy populations. Sports Med 47: 261&#x2013;275, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields KB, Sykes JC, Walker KM, Jackson JC. Prevention of running injuries. Curr Sports Med Rep 9: 176&#x2013;182, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway R, Booker R, Haynes H, Holmes M, Gdovin J. Physiological and perceptual responses to self-selected exercise pace on a track versus treadmill. Int J Strength Cond 1: 1&#x2013;8, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon KE, Ferris DP, Kuo AD. Metabolic and mechanical energy costs of reducing vertical center of mass movement during gait. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 90: 136&#x2013;144, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatchett A, Armstrong K, Parr B, Crews M, Tant C. The effect of a curved non-motorized treadmill on running gait length, imbalance and stride angle. Sports 6: 58&#x2013;66, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heesch MWS, Slivka DR. Running performance, pace strategy, and thermoregulation differ between a treadmill and indoor track. J Strength Cond Res 29: 330&#x2013;335, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iellamo F, Manzi V, Caminiti G, et al. Validation of rate of perceived exertion-based exercise training in patients with heart failure: Insights from autonomic nervous system adaptations. Int J Cardiol 176: 394&#x2013;398, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerdok AE, Biewener AA, McMahon TA, Weyand PG, Herr HM. Energetics and mechanics of human running on surfaces of different stiffnesses. J Appl Physiol 92: 469&#x2013;478, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong PW, Candelaria NG, Tomaka J. Perception of self-selected running speed is influenced by the treadmill but not footwear. Sports Biomech 8: 52&#x2013;59, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropractic Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kranenburg KJ, Smith DJ. Comparison of critical speed determined from track running and treadmill tests in elite runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc 28: 614&#x2013;618, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaCaille RA, Masters KS, Heath EM. Effects of cognitive strategy and exercise setting on running performance, perceived exertion, affect, and satisfaction. Psychol Sport Exerc 5: 461&#x2013;476, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavcanska V, Taylor NF, Schache AG. Familiarization to treadmill running in young unimpaired adults. Hum Mov Sci 24: 544&#x2013;557, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lussiana T, Patoz A, Gindre C, Mourot L, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K. The implications of time on the ground on running economy: Less is not always better. J Exp Biol 222: jeb192047, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JR, Van Hooren B, Bishop C, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of crossover studies comparing physiological, perceptual and performance measures between treadmill and overground running. Sports Med 49: 763&#x2013;782, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama Y, Kudo K, Ohtsuki T. Variability and fluctuation in running gait cycle of trained runners and non-runners. Gait Posture 31: 331&#x2013;335, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs A, Roerdink M, Beek PJ. Exploring running styles in the field through cadence and duty factor modulation. PLoS One 18: e0295423, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orendurff MS, Kobayashi T, Tulchin-Francis K, et al. A little bit faster: Lower extremity joint kinematics and kinetics as recreational runners achieve faster speeds. J Biomech 71: 167&#x2013;175, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton BM, Read P, van Dyk N, et al. London International Consensus and Delphi study on hamstring injuries part 3: Rehabilitation, running and return to sport. Br J Sports Med 57: 278&#x2013;291, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patoz A, Lussiana T, Breine B, Gindre C, Malatesta D. Accurate estimation of peak vertical ground reaction force using the duty factor in level treadmill running. Scand J Med Sci Sports 33: 169&#x2013;177, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnik M, Azrad T, Bondi M, et al. Self-selected gait speed&#x2014;over ground versus self-paced treadmill walking, a solution for a paradox. J NeuroEng Rehabil 12: 20&#x2013;29, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prigent G, Apte S, Paraschiv-Ionescu A, et al. Concurrent evolution of biomechanical and physiological parameters with running-induced acute fatigue. Front Physiol 13: 814172, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schache AG, Blanch PD, Dorn TW, et al. Effect of running speed on lower limb joint kinetics. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1260&#x2013;1271, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shariat A, Cleland JA, Danaee M, et al. Borg CR-10 scale as a new approach to monitoring office exercise training. Work 60: 549&#x2013;554, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MR, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Mental fatigue impairs intermittent running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1682&#x2013;1690, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Monahan KD, Seals DR. Age-predicted maximal heart rate revisited. J Am College Cardiol 37: 153&#x2013;156, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Fuller JT, Buckley JD, et al. Is motorized treadmill running biomechanically comparable to overground running ? A systematic review and meta&#x2014;analysis of cross&#x2014;over studies. Sports Med 50: 785&#x2013;813, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearing SC, Reed LF, Urry SR. Agreement between temporal and spatial gait parameters from an instrumented walkway and treadmill system at matched walking speed. Gait Posture 38: 380&#x2013;384, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh H-P, Stone J, Churchill S, Brymer E, Davids K. Physical and emotional benefits of different exercise environments designed for treadmill running. Int J Environ Res Publ Health 14: 752&#x2013;762, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JH, Chan ZYS, Lau FOY, et al. How do training experience and geographical origin of a runner affect running biomechanics? Gait Posture 84: 209&#x2013;214, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>