<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41111836</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of Point-of-Care C-reactive Protein Testing on Antibiotic Prescription in Febrile Children: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e92646</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e92646</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e92646</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.92646</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Overprescription of antibiotics in febrile children contributes significantly to antimicrobial resistance. Point-of-care testing (POCT) for C-reactive protein (CRP) may help differentiate bacterial from viral infections and support more rational antibiotic use. Objective To assess the effectiveness of POCT CRP testing in reducing antibiotic prescription rates among febrile children in an outpatient pediatric setting. Methods A randomized controlled trial was conducted at a tertiary care hospital in Maharashtra, India, involving 208 children aged one month to 18 years with febrile illness (&#x2264;5 days). Participants were randomized into two groups: Group 1 (n=106) received POCT CRP testing, and Group 2 (n=102) received standard clinical care. CRP was measured using the LumiraDx&#xa0;fluorescence immunoassay (LumiraDx UK Ltd, Alloa, UK). The primary outcome was the rate of antibiotic prescription. Results Antibiotic prescription was significantly higher in Group 1 (59.4%) than in Group 2 (46.1%) (p=0.023). Within the POCT group, 84.2% of children with CRP &gt;20 mg/L were prescribed antibiotics compared to 45.6% with CRP &#x2264;20 mg/L (p=0.0001). Elevated CRP levels were significantly associated with antibiotic prescription, especially in cases of fever and abdominal pain. Conclusion POCT CRP influenced physicians' prescribing decisions, particularly when CRP levels exceeded 20 mg/L. However, without structured integration into clinical algorithms, its use alone did not reduce overall antibiotic use. Physician training and adherence to CRP-based guidance are essential to optimize the benefits of POCT CRP in antimicrobial stewardship.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Khanna et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khanna</LastName><ForeName>Simran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paediatrics, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haseeb</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics and Neonatology, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pania</LastName><ForeName>Akul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Vadde Y</ForeName><Initials>VY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediarics, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nelanuthala</LastName><ForeName>Madhurasree</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sangle</LastName><ForeName>Avinash L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paediatrics, Mahatma Gandhi Mission (MGM) Medical College and Hospital, Aurangabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotics prescription</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crp: c-reactive protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">febrile illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">point-of-care testing (poct)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. MGM-Ethics Committee for Research on Human Subjects (ECRHS) issued approval MGM-ECRCH/2023/40. The meeting of the Ethics Committee for Research on Human Subjects (ECRHS) was held on 27th April, 2023, at 10 am in the Boardroom with Dr. Sachin Bhagwat as Chairperson. At the said meeting, the ECRHS approved the proposal for the clinical study entitled "Role of point of care C-Reactive protein testing on antibiotic prescription in febrile children: A Randomized controlled trial". Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41111836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12535401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.92646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antibiotic overuse: managing uncertainty and mitigating against overtreatment. Tarrant C, Krockow EM. BMJ Qual Saf. 2022;31:163&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-prescription antibiotic use and its predictors among children in low- and middle-income countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zewdie S, Kassa AA, Yayehrad AT, et al. Ital J Pediatr. 2024;50:260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39696454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C-reactive protein as predictor of bacterial infection among patients with an influenza-like illness. Haran JP, Beaudoin FL, Suner S, Lu S. Am J Emerg Med. 2013;31:137&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22944552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum procalcitonin, C-reactive protein and interleukin-6 for distinguishing bacterial and viral pneumonia in children. Toikka P, Irjala K, Juv&#xe9;n T, Virkki R, Mertsola J, Leinonen M, Ruuskanen O. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2000;19:598&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10917215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point-of-care C-reactive protein testing to reduce inappropriate use of antibiotics for non-severe acute respiratory infections in Vietnamese primary health care: a randomised controlled trial. Do NT, Ta NT, Tran NT, et al. Lancet Glob Health. 2016;4:633&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4985565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27495137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute undifferentiated febrile illness in rural Cambodia: a 3-year prospective observational study. Mueller TC, Siv S, Khim N, et al. PLoS One. 2014;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3995936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24755844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C-reactive protein point-of-care testing in primary care-broader implementation needed to combat antimicrobial resistance. Llor C, Plate A, Bjerrum L, et al. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1397096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39100952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point-of-care CRP matters: normal CRP levels reduce immediate antibiotic prescribing for acutely ill children in primary care: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Lemiengre MB, Verbakel JY, Colman R, et al. Scand J Prim Health Care. 2018;36:423&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6381547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotic resistance&#x2014;the need for global solutions. Laxminarayan R, Duse A, Wattal C, et al. The Lancet, Infectious diseases. 2013;13:1057&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24252483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-prescription antimicrobial use worldwide: a systematic review. Morgan DJ, Okeke IN, Laxminarayan R, Perencevich EN, Weisenberg S. Lancet Infect Dis. 2011;11:692&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotics resistance risk associated with antibiotic overuse. Rabat HHA, Mashed FSAAH, Hassoun WSM, et al. journal of medical genetics and clinical biology. 2024;1:244&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidance on C-reactive protein point-of-care testing and complementary strategies to improve antibiotic prescribing for adults with lower respiratory tract infections in primary care. Van Hecke O, Bjerrum L, Gentile I, et al. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1166742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10261980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37324137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point-of-care C-reactive protein testing and antibiotic prescribing for respiratory tract infections: a randomized controlled trial. Cals JW, Schot MJ, de Jong SA, Dinant GJ, Hopstaken RM. Ann Fam Med. 2010;8:124&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2834719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20212299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parents' perceptions of antibiotic use and antibiotic resistance (PAUSE): a qualitative interview study. Van Hecke O, Butler CC, Wang K, Tonkin-Crine S. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2019;74:1741&#x2013;1747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Books: hamburgers in paradise: the stories behind the food we eat: fascinating food. Haslam D. Br J Gen Pract. 2016;66:378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4917041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27364671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decreased acute otitis media with treatment failure after introduction of the ten-valent pneumococcal haemophilus influenzae protein D conjugate vaccine. Eythorsson E, Hrafnkelsson B, Erlendsd&#xf3;ttir H, Gudmundsson SA, Kristinsson KG, Haraldsson &#xc1;. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2018;37:361&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel electronic algorithm using host biomarker point-of-care tests for the management of febrile illnesses in Tanzanian children (e-POCT): a randomized, controlled non-inferiority trial. Keitel K, Kagoro F, Samaka J, et al. PLoS Med. 2017;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5653205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29059253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>One biomarker does not fit all: tailoring anti-infective therapy through utilization of procalcitonin and other specific biomarkers. Essmann L, Wirz Y, Gregoriano C, Schuetz P. Expert Rev Mol Diagn. 2023;23:739&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37505928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>