<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41387838</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A scoping review of virtual clinics in underserved regions: barriers and opportunities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1596</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1596</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1596</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-025-13710-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Universal access to quality healthcare remains a fundamental human right; however, underserved populations in rural and remote areas face persistent barriers to timely and appropriate care. Recent advancements in digital technology, especially virtual clinics, present promising opportunities to bridge these healthcare gaps by enhancing access and continuity of care. This review aims to systematically explore the barriers and facilitators influencing the implementation of virtual clinics in underserved regions to guide future policies and strategic development.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Employing the Joanna Briggs Institute Manual for Evidence Synthesis and adhering to PRISMA-ScR guidelines, comprehensive searches were conducted in PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, Google, and Google Scholar databases, supplemented by gray literature from targeted Google searches and snowballing techniques. A three-phase screening process was independently carried out by multiple reviewers based on predetermined inclusion and exclusion criteria. Data extraction and thematic analysis were conducted through a six-stage process using MAXQDA software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty-six articles were included from an initial 1590 records screened. The body of research has grown steadily since 2002, predominantly originating from Australia, the USA, and Canada. Major challenges identified include inadequate policy support, high startup costs, resistance from healthcare providers, limited internet infrastructure, privacy and security concerns regarding data, and restrictions in performing physical examinations remotely. Key facilitators encompass strong government policy backing, active stakeholder engagement, sustainable financial models, targeted workforce training (notably indigenous-focused), investment in infrastructure, and the adoption of hybrid care models combining in-person and virtual services. Notably, the nature and severity of these challenges and facilitators vary across countries of different income levels, underscoring the necessity of tailored, context-sensitive strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Implementing virtual clinics in underserved areas faces multifaceted challenges, but strategic facilitators can significantly advance their adoption and sustainability. Context-specific approaches considering economic capacities, infrastructural strengths, and workforce readiness are essential. Strengthening infrastructure, enhancing digital literacy, supporting human resource development, and formulating enabling policies form the cornerstone for equitable and enduring virtual healthcare access in marginalized regions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazi</LastName><ForeName>Aliyeh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy, School of Pharmacy, Zabol University of Medical Sciences, Zabol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emadi</LastName><ForeName>Vahideh</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Master of Health Services Management, Central, Zahedan University of Medical Sciences, Zahedan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isfahani</LastName><ForeName>Parvaneh</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Management, School of Public Health, Zabol University of Medical Sciences, Zabol, Iran. p.isfehani@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarani</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, School of Public Health, Zabol University of Medical Sciences, Zabol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moghadam</LastName><ForeName>Mahdieh Poodineh</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, School of Nursing and Midwifery, Zabol University of Medical Sciences, Zabol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008507" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medically Underserved Area</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019035" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rural Health Services</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medically underserved area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scoping review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual clinics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41387838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12699901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-13710-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-025-13710-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lazo-Porras M, Penniecook T. Health equity: access to quality services and caring for underserved populations. Health Policy Plan. 2023;38(Supplement2):ii1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czad073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10666925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37995262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanijahani A, Iezadi S, Gholipour K, Azami-Aghdash S, Naghibi D. A systematic review of racial/ethnic and socioeconomic disparities in COVID-19. Int J Equity Health. 2021;20(1):248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-021-01582-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8611382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34819081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk ME, Gage AD, Arsenault C, Jordan K, Leslie HH, Roder-DeWan S, et al. High-quality health systems in the sustainable development goals era: time for a revolution. Lancet Global Health. 2018;6(11):e1196&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30386-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millman M. Access to health care in America. 1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliot Jost M, Barker A, Kemper L, Ullrich F, Mueller K, McBride T. RUPRI center for rural health policy analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SL, Wakerman J, Humphreys JS. Ensuring equity of access to primary health care in rural and remote Australia-what core services should be locally available? Int J Equity Health. 2015;14(1):111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-015-0228-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4625941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26510998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsaei Z, Jangi M, Tahmasebian S, Ehteshami A. Functional and nonfunctional requirements of virtual clinic mobile applications: a systematic review. Int J Telemedicine Appl. 2024;2024(1):7800321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/7800321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11186682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38899062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AS, Adamson WC, DeVries AR. Virtual visits for acute, nonurgent care: a claims analysis of episode-level utilization. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(2):e35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5336603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu KK, Lopez C, Nichols M. Virtual visits in prenatal care: an integrative review. J Midwifery Women&#x2019;s Health. 2022;67(1):39&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jmwh.13284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan EM, Rogers AC, Hanly AM, McCawley N, Deasy J, McNamara DA. A virtual outpatient department provides a satisfactory patient experience following endoscopy. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2014;29(3):359&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00384-013-1801-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24309978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford E, Noray R, HEarr&#xe1;in C&#xd3;, Quinlan K, Hegarty A, Ekpotu L, et al. Potential benefits and drawbacks of virtual clinics in general surgery: pilot cross-sectional questionnaire study. JMIR Perioperative Med. 2020;3(1):e12491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7728406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dictionary ISD. Virtual Clinic. Scotland PH 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtual NHC. Clinic England: NHS; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MD, Godfrey C, McInerney P, Munn Z, Tricco AC, Khalil H. Scoping reviews. JBI manual for evidence synthesis. 2020;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagram PF. PRISMA 2020 flow diagram for new systematic reviews which included searches of databases and registers only. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accelerator SR. 2025 [Available from: https://sr-accelerator.com/#/polyglot</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1364557032000119616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlDossary S, Martin-Khan MG, Bradford NK, Armfield NR, Smith AC. The development of a telemedicine planning framework based on needs assessment. J Med Syst. 2017;41(5):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10916-017-0709-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28321589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari AA, Wani TA, Liem M, Boyd J, Khan UR. Advancing regional and remote health care with virtual hospital implementation: rapid review. JMIR Hum Factors. 2025;12:e64582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/64582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12174879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40460425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig LR, Ko J, Upadhyay UD. Virtual clinic telehealth abortion services in the united States one year after dobbs: landscape review. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11333862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39102679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jetty A, Moore MA, Coffman M, Petterson S, Bazemore A. Rural family physicians are twice as likely to use telehealth as urban family physicians. Telemedicine e-Health. 2018;24(4):268&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2017.0161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uscher-Pines L, Sousa JL, Zachrison KS, Schwamm L, Mehrotra A. Financial impact of telehealth: rural chief financial officer perspectives. Am J Manag Care. 2022;28(12):e436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37765/ajmc.2022.89279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36525663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland M, Tennant M, Bowen DJ, Bauer AM, Fortney JC, Pyne JM, et al. Psychiatrist and psychologist experiences with telehealth and remote collaborative care in primary care: a qualitative study. J Rural Health. 2021;37(4):780&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jrh.12523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8518862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33022079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston K, Smith D, Preston R, Evans R, Carlisle K, Lengren J, et al. From the technology came the idea: safe implementation and operation of a high quality teleradiology model increasing access to timely breast cancer assessment services for women in rural Australia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05922-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7708244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33256724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini SM, Boushehri SA, Alimohammadzadeh K. Challenges and solutions for implementing telemedicine in Iran from health policymakers&#x2019; perspective. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24(1):50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-10488-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10782789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38200535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifehsoltani SN, Gerami MR, editors. E-health challenges, opportunities and experiences of developing countries. 2010 International Conference on e-Education, e-Business, e-Management and e-Learning; 2010, IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornwell L, Hawley SR, Romain TS. Implementation of a coordinated school health program in a rural, low-income community. J Sch Health. 2007;77(9):601&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1746-1561.2007.00239.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17970863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilenski SM, Ang PM, Greenberg MT, Feinberg ME, Spoth R. The impact of a prevention delivery system on perceived social capital: the PROSPER project. Prev Sci. 2014;15(2):125&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-012-0347-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3718867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23404665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semansky R, Willging C, Ley DJ, Rylko-Bauer B. Lost in the rush to National reform: recommendations to improve impact on behavioral health providers in rural areas. J Health Care Poor Underserved. 2012;23(2):842&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/hpu.2012.0059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3415203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22643628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka JK, Budhwani S, Thomas-Jacques T, De Vera K, Challa P, Fuller K, et al. Challenges and strategies for promoting health equity in virtual care: protocol for a scoping review of reviews. JMIR Res Protocols. 2020;9(12):e22847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/22847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore MA, Coffman M, Jetty A, Klink K, Petterson S, Bazemore A. Family physicians report considerable interest in, but limited use of, telehealth services. J Am Board Family Med. 2017;30(3):320&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3122/jabfm.2017.03.160201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28484064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De La Torre A, Diaz P, Perdomo R. Analysis of the virtual healthcare model in Latin america: a systematic review of current challenges and barriers. mHealth. 2024;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11058594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haleem A, Javaid M, Singh RP, Suman R. Telemedicine for healthcare: Capabilities, features, barriers, and applications. Sens Int. 2021;2:100117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sintl.2021.100117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34806053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dooley J, Kelly L, St Pierre-Hansen N, Antone I, Guilfoyle J, O&#x2019;Driscoll T. Rural and remote obstetric care close to home: program description, evaluation and discussion of Sioux lookout Meno Ya win health centre obstetrics. Can J Rural Med. 2009;14(2):75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19379632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haggarty JM, Ryan-Nicholls KD, Jarva JA. Mental health collaborative care: a synopsis of the rural and isolated toolkit. Rural Remote Health. 2010;10(3):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20672870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nataliansyah MM, Merchant KA, Croker JA, Zhu X, Mohr NM, Marcin JP, et al. Managing innovation: a qualitative study on the implementation of telehealth services in rural emergency departments. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08271-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Everybody&#x2019;s business: strengthening health systems to improve health outcomes: WHO&#x2019;s framework for action. Everybody&#x2019;s business: strengthening health systems to improve health outcomes: WHO&#x2019;s framework for action. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller M, Stotler C. Telemedicine: a primer. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2018;18(10):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11882-018-0808-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30145709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A, Galea S, Mendez I. Standardizing virtual healthcare deployment: insights from the implementation of telerobotic ultrasound to Bridge healthcare inequities in rural and remote communities across Canada. J Prim Care Community Health. 2025;16:21501319251329314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501319251329314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11952026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40146915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson S. Video-conferencing: under-used by rural general practitioners. Aust Health Rev. 2002;25(6):131&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/AH020131a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12536872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piay-Fern&#xe1;ndez N, Stenbacka E, Jaramillo MC, Guerrero G, Solano Rodriguez AA, Montenegro P, et al. Implementing medical abortion through telemedicine in colombia: a qualitative study. Sex Reproductive Health Matters. 2023;31(4):2236780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26410397.2023.2236780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10424593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37565788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toll K, Moullin JC, Andrew S, Williams A, Varhol R, Carey TA, et al. Enhancing the implementation of provider-to-provider telehealth in rural and remote areas: A mixed methods study protocol. Digit Health. 2024;10:20552076241242790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076241242790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10989039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38571877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Consolidated telemedicine implementation guide. World Health Organization; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Telemedicine: opportunities and developments in Member States: report on the second global survey on eHealth. 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford NK, Caffery LJ, Smith AC. Telehealth services in rural and remote australia: a systematic review of models of care and factors influencing success and sustainability. Rural Remote Health. 2016;16(4):1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snoswell CL, Taylor ML, Comans TA, Smith AC, Gray LC, Caffery LJ. Determining if telehealth can reduce health system costs: scoping review. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(10):e17298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7605980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33074157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootton R. Telehealth in the developing world. IDRC; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan YGX. Telemedicine development in the Asia-Pacific region: network Architecture, capacity and Feasibility. SOM steering committee on economic and technical Cooperation (SCE), telecommunications and information working group. TELWG); 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew S, Fitts MS, Liddle Z, Bourke L, Campbell N, Murakami-Gold L, et al. Telehealth in remote australia: a supplementary tool or an alternative model of care replacing face-to-face consultations? BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23(1):341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-09265-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babatunde AO, Abdulazeez AO, Adeyemo EA, Uche-Orji CI, Saliyu AA. Telemedicine in low and middle income countries: closing or widening the health inequalities gap. Eur J Environ Public Health. 2021;5(2):em0075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21601/ejeph/10777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der L, Fl&#xe4;gel K, Goetz K, Steinh&#xe4;user J. Mobility concepts and access to health care in a rural district in germany: a mixed methods approach. BMC Fam Pract. 2018;19(1):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-018-0733-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arighi A, Fumagalli GG, Carandini T, Pietroboni AM, De Riz MA, Galimberti D, et al. Facing the digital divide into a dementia clinic during COVID-19 pandemic: caregiver age matters. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(4):1247&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-05009-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33459891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam K, Mahumud RA, Alam F, Keramat SA, Erdiaw-Kwasie MO, Sarker AR. Determinants of access to eHealth services in regional Australia. Int J Med Informatics. 2019;131:103960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2019.103960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31518858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis FJ, Fernandes LG, Saragiotto BT. Telehealth in low-and middle-income countries: bridging the gap or exposing health disparities? Health Policy Technol. 2021;10(4):100577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hlpt.2021.100577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34745854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foroudastan SD, Dees O, editors. Solar power and sustainability in developing countries. Proceedings of the international conference on renewable energy for developing countries. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combi C, Pozzani G, Pozzi G. Telemedicine for developing countries. Appl Clin Inf. 2016;7(04):1025&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4338/ACI-2016-06-R-0089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5228142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27803948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barayev E, Shental O, Yaari D, Zloczower E, Shemesh I, Shapiro M, et al. WhatsApp Tele-Medicine&#x2013;usage patterns and physicians views on the platform. Isr J Health Policy Res. 2021;10(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13584-021-00468-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8167384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34074319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirko KA, Kerver JM, Ford S, Szafranski C, Beckett J, Kitchen C, et al. Telehealth in response to the COVID-19 pandemic: implications for rural health disparities. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2020;27(11):1816&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaa156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32589735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocanda L, Fisher K, Brown LJ, May J, Rollo ME, Collins CE, et al. Informing telehealth service delivery for cardiovascular disease management: exploring the perceptions of rural health professionals. Aust Health Rev. 2021;45(2):241&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/AH19231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33715764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshammari OH, Al-towhere HM, Alanazi AB, AlFuhaid AS, AlMoammar KI, Al-Ruwaidi AA, et al. Assessment of the efficiency of virtual clinics in hail Hospitals, Saudi Arabia. J Med Law Public Health. 2023;3(4):289&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani R, Sahebzadeh M, Ehteshami A. Investigating the effective factors on telemedicine in Iran of 2030: A futuristic approach. J Educ Health Promotion. 2025;14(1):168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_2024_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12094456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40400599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBeau K, Varma DS, Kreider CM, Casta&#xf1;eda G, Knecht C, Cowper Ripley D, et al. Whole health coaching to rural veterans through telehealth: Advantages, gaps, and opportunities. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1057586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1057586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10083506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37050942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernsting C, St&#xfc;hmann LM, Dombrowski SU, Voigt-Antons J-N, Kuhlmey A, Gellert P. Associations of health app use and perceived effectiveness in people with cardiovascular diseases and diabetes: population-based survey. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2019;7(3):e12179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30920383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guendelman S, Broderick A, Mlo H, Gemmill A, Lindeman D. Listening to communities: mixed-method study of the engagement of disadvantaged mothers and pregnant women with digital health technologies. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(7):e7736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5517821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuperman EF, Linson EL, Klefstad K, Perry E, Glenn K. The virtual hospitalist: a single-site implementation bringing hospitalist coverage to critical access hospitals. J Hosp Med. 2018;13(11):759&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12788/jhm.3061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30255859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giroux EE, Hagerty M, Shwed A, Pal N, Huynh N, Andersen T, et al. It&#x2019;s not one size fits all: a case for how equity-based knowledge translation can support rural and remote communities to optimize virtual health care. Rural Remote Health. 2022;22(2):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobburi RK, Olawade DB, Olatunji GD, Kokori E, Aderinto N, David-Olawade AC. Telemedicine use in rural areas of the united Kingdom to improve access to healthcare facilities: A review of current evidence. Inf Health. 2025;2(1):41&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>