<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41887548</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9572</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Harmonizing the stimulation dose of focal transcranial direct current stimulation across target sites.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>121882</StartPage><MedlinePgn>121882</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2026.121882</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1053-8119(26)00198-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Focal transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) using center-surround electrode montages enables region-specific cortical targeting, and holds promise for both cognitive neuroscience and clinical interventions. However, systematic examinations of dose-response relationships and their regional differences are lacking, hampering informed selections of suited stimulation parameters. In this preparatory methodological study, we present a modeling-based framework to support harmonized empirical dose-response studies of focal tDCS across different target areas. It covers three steps: Determining the approximate electric field strength that had led to behavioral and physiological effects in related prior tDCS studies. In our case, this led to a field strength of 0.2 V/m on average across magnetic resonance images (MRIs) from 43 participants and eight target areas related to different cognitive and motor functions. Second, optimizing the radii of center-surround montages for each target area to - on average across participants - achieve the intended field strength while maximizing focality. An additional test of cross-sample generalization in an independent sample confirms that the intended target field strength is achieved on average for new participants. Third, the pre-determined montage radii and a method for the individualized positioning of the center-surround electrode montages are provided for prospective planning in empirical dose-response studies. By harmonizing the electric field strength between different target regions at the group level, but preserving inter-individual variability, our framework will enable systematic analyses to relate the field strength to behavioral and neuroimaging outcomes, and to assess differences of these relations across regions. The described computational tools are open-source, allowing other researchers to tailor our framework to their specific research questions; and are currently used in a multi-center study involving approximately 1,000 datasets.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thielscher</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Technology, Technical University of Denmark, Kongens Lyngby, Denmark; Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark. Electronic address: axthi@dtu.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayek</LastName><ForeName>Dayana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Electronic address: dayana.hayek@med.uni-greifswald.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puonti</LastName><ForeName>Oula</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Technology, Technical University of Denmark, Kongens Lyngby, Denmark; Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, Copenhagen University Hospital Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark. Electronic address: oupu@dtu.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grittner</LastName><ForeName>Ulrike</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Berlin Institute of Health (BIH), 10187 Berlin, Germany; Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, Berlin Institute of Health, Institute of Biometry and Clinical Epidemiology, 10117 Berlin, Germany. Electronic address: ulrike.grittner@charite.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blankenburg</LastName><ForeName>Felix</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurocomputation and Neuroimaging Unit, Freie Universit&#xe4;t Berlin, Berlin, Germany; Berlin School of Mind and Brain, Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, Berlin, Germany. Electronic address: felix.blankenburg@fu-berlin.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fischer</LastName><ForeName>Rico</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Electronic address: rico.fischer@uni-greifswald.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartwigsen</LastName><ForeName>Gesa</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group Cognition and Plasticity, Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences, Leipzig, Germany; Wilhelm Wundt Institute for Psychology, Leipzig University, Leipzig, Germany. Electronic address: hartwigsen@cbs.mpg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Shu-Chen</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Psychology, Chair of Lifespan Developmental Neuroscience, TU Dresden, Dresden, Germany; Centre for Tactile Internet With Human-in-the-Loop, TU Dresden, Dresden, Germany. Electronic address: shu-chen.li@tu-dresden.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meinzer</LastName><ForeName>Marcus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Electronic address: marcus.meinzer@med.uni-greifswald.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nitsche</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leibniz Research Center for Working Environment and Human Factors, Dortmund, Germany; Bielefeld University, University Hospital OWL, Protestant Hospital of Bethel Foundation, University Clinic of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Bielefeld, Germany; German Center for Mental Health (DZPG), Bochum, Germany. Electronic address: nitsche@ifado.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmann</LastName><ForeName>Dagmar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Essen, University of Duisburg-Essen, Essen, Germany; Center for Translational Neuro- &amp; Behavioral Sciences (C-TNBS), University Duisburg Essen, Essen, Germany. Electronic address: dagmar.timmann-braun@uk-essen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fl&#xf6;el</LastName><ForeName>Agnes</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany; German Centre for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE) Standort Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Electronic address: agnes.floeel@med.uni-greifswald.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonenko</LastName><ForeName>Daria</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Electronic address: daria.antonenko@med.uni-greifswald.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9215515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-8119</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-invasive brain stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive enhancement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computational modelling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dose-response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simulation of electric fields</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural imaging</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: MAN is in the scientific advisory board of Neuroelectrics and Pr&#xe9;cis&#x2019;s. All other authors declare no financial or non-financial competing interests. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41887548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2026.121882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1053-8119(26)00198-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>