<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41821917</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2080-4806</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>79</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Central European journal of urology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cent European J Urol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of powerlifting on urinary incontinence in women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><EndPage>22</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15-22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5173/ceju.2025.0184</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Powerlifting is a strength sport that has recently gained popularity among women. It is associated with a high prevalence of stress urinary incontinence, which is known to negatively affect women's quality of life. Therefore, this study aimed to assess the effects of powerlifting on urinary incontinence not only during training but also in daily life. Furthermore, this study aimed to identify risk factors associated with stress urinary incontinence during powerlifting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional study used an anonymous 26-item online questionnaire. Participants were mainly recruited via social media. Responses from 1,072 female powerlifters were analyzed using SPSS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After starting to perform powerlifting, women were 22.7 times more likely to experience stress urinary incontinence overall, 1.6 times more likely to experience stress urinary incontinence in daily life, and 5.2 times more likely to experience urgency urinary incontinence. Among those who experienced changes in the severity of symptoms in daily life after starting to perform powerlifting, a narrow majority indicated an improvement in symptoms. The lifetime prevalence of stress urinary incontinence during powerlifting was 67.3%, whereas the lifetime stress urinary incontinence prevalence in daily life was 31.7%. Risk factors for stress urinary incontinence during powerlifting were older age, years of powerlifting experience, vaginal birth, use of a lifting belt, deadlift stance, and one repetition maximum.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">While powerlifting appears to increase the risk of urinary incontinence in daily life, it also improves symptoms in some participants - likely those able to activate their pelvic floor during lifting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright by Polish Urological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heidorn</LastName><ForeName>Tanja Maria</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Life Sciences, University of Latvia, R&#x12b;ga, Latvia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilsetniece</LastName><ForeName>Zane</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pauls Stradi&#x146;&#x161; Clinical University Hospital, R&#x12b;ga, Latvia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Cent European J Urol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587101</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2080-4806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">daily life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">powerlifting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stress urinary incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urgency urinary incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41821917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12976749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5173/ceju.2025.0184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CEJU-79-01-0184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cholewicki J, Juluru K, Radebold A, Panjabi MM, McGill SM. Lumbar spine stability can be augmented with an abdominal belt and/or increased intra-abdominal pressure. Eur Spine J. 1999; 8: 388-395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3611203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10552322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemack GE, Carmel MC. Urinary Incontinence and Pelvic Prolapse: Epidemiology and Pathophysiology. In: Partin AW, Dmochowski RR, Kavoussi LR, Peters CA (eds.). Campbell-Walsh-Wein Urology, 12th ed. Elsevier, Philadelphia: 2020; 2580&#x2013;2599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel UJ, Godecker AL, Giles DL, Brown HW. Updated Prevalence of Urinary Incontinence in Women: 2015-2018 National Population-Based Survey Data. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2022; 28: 181-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35030139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams P, Smith AP, Cotterill N. The impact of urinary incontinence on health-related quality of life (HRQoL) in a real-world population of women aged 45-60 years: results from a survey in France, Germany, the UK and the USA. BJU Int. 2015; 115: 143-152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24958472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skaug KL, Engh ME, Frawley H, B&#xf8; K. Prevalence of Pelvic Floor Dysfunction, Bother, and Risk Factors and Knowledge of the Pelvic Floor Muscles in Norwegian Male and Female Powerlifters and Olympic Weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2022; 36: 2800-2807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przydacz M, Chlosta P. LUTS POLAND: The first population-based study of prevalence, bother, and treatment-related behaviour for lower urinary tract symptoms and overactive bladder in Eastern Europe. Cent European J Urol. 2024; 77: 658-660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12042399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40313699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney K, Heidel RE, Olewinski L. Prevalence and Normalization of Stress Urinary Incontinence in Female Strength Athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2023; 37: 1877-1881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10448802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36930880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikander L, Cross D, Gahreman DE. Prevalence of urinary incontinence in women powerlifters: a pilot study. Int Urogynecol J. 2019; 30: 2031-2039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30666426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikander L, Kirshbaum MN, Waheed N, Gahreman DE. Urinary Incontinence in Competitive Women Powerlifters: A Cross-Sectional Survey. Sports Med Open. 2021; 7: 89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8651931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34874496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luber KM. The definition, prevalence, and risk factors for stress urinary incontinence. Rev Urol. 2004; 6 (Suppl 3): S3&#x2013;S9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1472862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16985863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsikopoulos I, Lazarou L, Tzelves L, Sakalis V, Papathanasiou C, Samarinas M. The effect of pelvic floor muscle training on urodynamic parameters in women with stress urinary incontinence. Cent European J Urol. 2023; 76: 315-321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xe4;htinen RM, Cartwright R, Tsui JF, et al. Long-term Impact of Mode of Delivery on Stress Urinary Incontinence and Urgency Urinary Incontinence: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Eur Urol. 2016; 70: 148-158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5009182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26874810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazek D, Stastny P, Maszczyk A, Krawczyk M, Matykiewicz P, Petr M. Systematic review of intra-abdominal and intrathoracic pressures initiated by the Valsalva manoeuvre during high-intensity resistance exercises. Biol Sport. 2019; 36: 373-386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31938009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Wang X, Gao Z, et al. The Anatomical Pathogenesis of Stress Urinary Incontinence in Women. Medicina (Kaunas). 2022; 59: 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9865065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36676629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paj&#x105;k PM, Wla&#x17a;lak E, Surkont G, Kalinka J. An assessment of the relationship between urethral hypermobility as measured by ultrasound and the symptoms of stress urinary incontinence in primiparous women 9&#x2013;18 months postpartum. J Ultrason. 2024; 24: 20240010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10940277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38496788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>