<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41362309</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1871-4080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cognitive neurodynamics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cogn Neurodyn</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Attention-guided deep learning-machine learning and statistical feature fusion for interpretable mental workload classification from EEG.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18</StartPage><MedlinePgn>18</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">18</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11571-025-10392-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate assessment of mental workload (MWL) from electroencephalography (EEG) signals is crucial for real-time cognitive monitoring in safety-critical domains such as aviation and human-computer interaction. Although various computational approaches have been proposed, those mostly suffer from limited robustness, interpretability, or fail to fully exploit both temporal and non-linear neural dynamics. This article introduces a novel hybrid deep learning and XGBoost stacking ensemble framework for reliable and interpretable MWL classification from EEG. The proposed pipeline systematically includes preprocessing of raw EEGs, followed by comprehensive feature extraction (time-domain, frequency-domain, wavelet-based, entropy, and fractal dimension features), and subsequent discriminative feature selection phase using ANOVA F-values, yielding a compact set of 200 highly informative features. The proposed architecture consists of dual processing branches: a CNN-BiLSTM-Attention based deep learning branch for automatic learning of spatiotemporal dynamics, and an XGBoost branch for robust classification from engineered features. Predictions from both branches are integrated using a logistic regression stacking ensemble, maximizing complementary strengths and improving generalization. Experiments are conducted on the STEW (simultaneous workload) and EEGMAT (mental arithmetic task) dataset. Proposed model yields 96.87% and 99.40% of classification accuracy by outperforming 16 and 7 previously published state-of-the-art techniques on STEW and EEGMAT dataset respectively. Attention heatmaps and SHAP value analysis provide intuitive visual explanations and interpretability of the model's decision making, while systematic ablation studies validate the contribution of each architectural module. This work demonstrates that a carefully engineered stacking ensemble, informed by both deep learning and classical machine learning, capable of delivering not only improved performance but also enhanced interpretability for EEG-based MWL assessment in real-world applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature B.V. 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majumder</LastName><ForeName>Sukanta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Kalyani, Kalyani, West Bengal 741235 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03v783k16</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411993.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0688 0940</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Patra</LastName><ForeName>Dibyendu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Kalyani, Kalyani, West Bengal 741235 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03v783k16</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411993.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0688 0940</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Gorai</LastName><ForeName>Subhajit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Kalyani, Kalyani, West Bengal 741235 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03v783k16</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411993.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0688 0940</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halder</LastName><ForeName>Anindya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Application, School of Technology, North-Eastern Hill University, Tura Campus, Tura, Meghalaya 794002 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/055m2tx54</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412227.0</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2173 057X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswas</LastName><ForeName>Utpal</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Kalyani, Kalyani, West Bengal 741235 India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03v783k16</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411993.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0688 0940</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Cogn Neurodyn</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101306907</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1871-4080</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ML-DL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental workload</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SHAP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Statistical&#x2013;entropical&#x2013;wavelet features</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41362309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12681509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11571-025-10392-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bandt C, Pompe B (2002) Permutation entropy: a natural complexity measure for time series. Phys Rev Lett 88(17):174102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.88.174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12005759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baygin N, Aydemir E, Barua PD, Baygin M, Dogan S, Tuncer T, Tan R-S, Acharya UR (2023) Automated mental arithmetic performance detection using quantum pattern-and triangle pooling techniques with eeg signals. Expert Syst Appl 227:120306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.120306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergil E, Oral C, Erg&#xfc;l EU (2023) Classification of arithmetic mental task performances using eeg and ecg signals. J Supercomput 79(14):15535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-023-05294-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakladar DD, Dey S, Roy PP, Dogra DP (2020) EEG-based mental workload estimation using deep BLSTM-LSTM network and evolutionary algorithm. Biomed Signal Process Control 60:101989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2020.101989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles RL, Nixon J (2019) Measuring mental workload using physiological measures: a systematic review. Appl Ergon 74:221&#x2013;232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apergo.2018.08.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30487103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvas F, Mehi&#x107; E, Caler CJ, Ojemann JG, Mourad PD (2016) Toward deep brain monitoring with superficial EEG sensors plus neuromodulatory focused ultrasound. Ultrasound Med Biol 42(8):1834&#x2013;1847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2016.02.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5768413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27181686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehais F, Dupr&#xe8;s A, Blum S, Drougard N, Scannella S, Roy RN, Lotte F (2019) Monitoring pilot&#x2019;s mental workload using erps and spectral power with a six-dry-electrode EEG system in real flight conditions. Sensors 19(6):1324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s19061324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6471557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Cao Y, Duffy VG, Wang Y, Zhang X (2020) Measurement and identification of mental workload during simulated computer tasks with multimodal methods and machine learning. Ergonomics 63(7):896&#x2013;908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140139.2020.1759699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32330080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteller R, Vachtsevanos G, Echauz J, Litt B (2002) A comparison of waveform fractal dimension algorithms. IEEE Trans Circuits Syst I Fund Theory Appl 48(2):177&#x2013;183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/81.904882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galy E, Cariou M, M&#xe9;lan C (2012) What is the relationship between mental workload factors and cognitive load types? Int J Psychophysiol 83(3):269&#x2013;275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2011.09.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez LC, Herv&#xe1;s R, Gonzalez I, Villarreal V (2021) Studying the generalisability of cognitive load measured with EEG. Biomed Signal Process Control 70:103032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2021.103032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow I, Bengio Y, Courville A (2016) Deep learning. http://www.deeplearningbook.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain P, Yedukondalu J, Chhabra H, Chauhan U, Sharma LD (2024) Eeg-based detection of cognitive load using VMD and LightGBM classifier. Int J Mach Learn Cybern 15(9):4193&#x2013;4210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13042-024-02142-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakkos I, Dimitrakopoulos GN, Gao L, Zhang Y, Qi P, Matsopoulos GK, Thakor N, Bezerianos A, Sun Y (2019) Mental workload drives different reorganizations of functional cortical connectivity between 2D and 3D simulated flight experiments. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 27(9):1704&#x2013;1713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2019.2930082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakkos I, Tzavellas E, Feleskoura E, Mourtakos S, Kontopodis E, Vezakis I, Kalamatianos T, Synadinakis E, Matsopoulos GK, Kalatzis I et al (2025) EEG-based assessment of cognitive resilience via interpretable machine learning models. AI 6(6):112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ai6060112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke H, Wang F, Ma H, He Z (2022) ADHD identification and its interpretation of functional connectivity using deep self-attention factorization. Knowl Based Syst 250:109082. 10.1016/j.knosys.2022.109082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2022.109082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke H, Chen D, Yao Q, Tang Y, Wu J, Monaghan J, Sowman P, McAlpine D (2023) Deep factor learning for accurate brain neuroimaging data analysis on discrimination for structural MRI and functional MRI. IEEE/ACM Trans Comput Biol Bioinf 21(4):582&#x2013;595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCBB.2023.3252577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37028037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke H, Wang F, Bi H, Ma H, Wang G, Yin B (2024) Unsupervised deep frequency-channel attention factorization to non-linear feature extraction: a case study of identification and functional connectivity interpretation of parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Expert Syst Appl 243:122853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesi&#x107; S, Spasi&#x107; SZ (2016) Application of higuchi&#x2019;s fractal dimension from basic to clinical neurophysiology: a review. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 133:55&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2016.05.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27393800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanam F, Hossain AA, Ahmad M (2023) Electroencephalogram-based cognitive load level classification using wavelet decomposition and support vector machine. Brain Comput Interfaces 10(1):1&#x2013;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2326263X.2022.2109855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingphai K, Moshfeghi Y (2021) On EEG preprocessing role in deep learning effectiveness for mental workload classification. In: Human mental workload: models and applications: 5th international symposium, H-WORKLOAD 2021, Virtual Event, 24&#x2013;26 November 2021, proceedings, vol 5. Springer, pp 81&#x2013;98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingphai K, Moshfeghi Y (2025) Mental workload assessment using deep learning models from EEG signals: a systematic review. IEEE Trans Cogn Devel Syst 17(1):40&#x2013;60. 10.1109/TCDS.2024.3460750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCDS.2024.3460750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak Y, Kong K, Song W-J, Min B-K, Kim S-E (2020) Multilevel feature fusion with 3d convolutional neural network for EEG-based workload estimation. IEEE Access 8:16009&#x2013;16021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2966834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladekar MY, Gupta SS, Joshi YV, Manthalkar RR (2021) EEG based visual cognitive workload analysis using multirate IIR filters. Biomed Signal Process Control 68:102819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2021.102819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhang R, Zeng Y, Tong L, Lu R, Yan B (2024) MST-Net: a multi-scale swin transformer network for EEG-based cognitive load assessment. Brain Res Bull 206:110834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2023.110834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38049039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim WL, Sourina O, Wang LP (2018) STEW: simultaneous task EEG workload data set. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 26(11):2106&#x2013;2114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2018.2872924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30281467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo L, Wickens CD, Hancock G, Hancock PA (2022) Human mental workload: a survey and a novel inclusive definition. Front Psychol 13:883321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.883321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9201728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Lee S-I (2017) A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst 30:4765&#x2013;4774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luzzani G, Buraioli I, Demarchi D, Guglieri G (2024) A review of physiological measures for mental workload assessment in aviation: a state-of-the-art review of mental workload physiological assessment methods in human&#x2013;machine interaction analysis. Aeronaut J 128(1323):928&#x2013;949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/aer.2023.101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malviya L, Mal S (2022) A novel technique for stress detection from EEG signal using hybrid deep learning model. Neural Comput Appl 34(22):19819&#x2013;19830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-022-07540-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanavelu K, Poonguzhali S, Janani A, Vinutha S (2022) Machine learning-based approach for identifying mental workload of pilots. Biomed Signal Process Control 75:103623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2022.103623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H-H, Iyortsuun NK, Kim S, Yang H-J, Kim S-H (2024) Mental workload estimation with electroencephalogram signals by combining multi-space deep models. Biomed Signal Process Control 94:106284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey V, Choudhary DK, Verma V, Sharma G, Singh R, Chandra S (2020) Mental workload estimation using EEG. In: 2020 Fifth international conference on research in computational intelligence and communication networks (ICRCICN). IEEE, pp 83&#x2013;86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richman JS, Moorman JR (2000) Physiological time-series analysis using approximate entropy and sample entropy. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 278(6):2039&#x2013;2049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.2000.278.6.H2039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10843903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safari M, Shalbaf R, Bagherzadeh S, Shalbaf A (2024a) Classification of mental workload using brain connectivity and machine learning on electroencephalogram data. Sci Rep 14(1):9153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-59652-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11033270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38644365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safari M, Shalbaf R, Bagherzadeh S, Shalbaf A (2024b) Classification of mental workload with EEG analysis by using effective connectivity and a hybrid model of CNN and LSTM. Comput Methods Biomech Biomed Eng. 10.1080/10255842.2024.2386325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39086252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salton G, McGill MJ (1983) Introduction to modern information retrieval. McGraw-Hill Education, New York</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciaraffa N, Aric&#xf2; P, Borghini G, Flumeri GD, Florio AD, Babiloni, F (2019) On the use of machine learning for EEG-based workload assessment: algorithms comparison in a realistic task. In: Human mental workload: models and applications: third international symposium, H-WORKLOAD 2019, Rome, Italy, 14&#x2013;15 November 2019, proceedings, vol 3. springer, pp 170&#x2013;185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddhad G, Gupta A, Dogra DP, Roy PP (2024) Efficacy of transformer networks for classification of EEG data. Biomed Signal Process Control 87:105488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2023.105488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WK, Wong SW, Mak JN, Chan RH (2017) An evaluation of mental workload with frontal EEG. PLoS ONE 12(4):0174949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0174949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28414729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Gao P, Liu P, Wang Y (2025) Memristor-based feature recall neural network circuit with temporal differentiation of emotion and its application in parts inspection. IEEE Trans Industr Inf 21(7):5633&#x2013;5643. 10.1109/TII.2025.3556069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2025.3556069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Gwizdka J, Chaovalitwongse WA (2015) Using wireless EEG signals to assess memory workload in the <i>n</i>-back task. IEEE Trans Hum Mach Syst 46(3):424&#x2013;435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/THMS.2015.2476818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Stevens C, Bennett W, Yu D (2024) Granular estimation of user cognitive workload using multi-modal physiological sensors. Front Neuroergon 5:1292627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnrgo.2024.1292627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10927958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38476759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Ke H, Cai C (2025) Deep wavelet self-attention non-negative tensor factorization for non-linear analysis and classification of fMRI data. Appl Soft Comput 182:113522. 10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Ke H, Ma H, Tang Y (2025) Deep wavelet temporal-frequency attention for nonlinear fmri factorization in asd. Pattern Recogn 165:111543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2025.111543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Ke H, Tang Y (2025) Fusion of generative adversarial networks and non-negative tensor decomposition for depression fmri data analysis. Inform Process Manag 62(2):103961. 10.1016/j.ipm.2024.103961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ipm.2024.103961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Yin Z, Wang Y, Zhang W, Wang Y, Zhang J (2019) Assessing cognitive mental workload via EEG signals and an ensemble deep learning classifier based on denoising autoencoders. Comput Biol Med 109:159&#x2013;170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2019.04.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31059900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yedukondalu J, Sharma LD (2022) Cognitive load detection using binary salp swarm algorithm for feature selection. In: 2022 IEEE 6th Conference on Information and Communication Technology (CICT). IEEE, pp 1&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yedukondalu J, Sharma LD (2023) Cognitive load detection using circulant singular spectrum analysis and binary Harris Hawks optimization based feature selection. Biomed Signal Process Control 79:104006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2022.104006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yedukondalu J, Sunkara K, Radhika V, Kondaveeti S, Anumothu M, Murali Krishna Y (2025) Cognitive load detection through EEG lead wise feature optimization and ensemble classification. Sci Rep 15(1):842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-84429-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11700217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zammouri A, Ait Moussa A, Mebrouk Y (2018) Brain-computer interface for workload estimation: assessment of mental efforts in learning processes. Expert Syst Appl 112:138&#x2013;147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2018.06.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Zhang H, Zhu G, You F, Kuang S, Sun L (2019) A multi-branch 3d convolutional neural network for EEG-based motor imagery classification. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 27(10):2164&#x2013;2177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2019.2938295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Huang S, Xu Z, Wang P, Wu X, Zhang D (2021) Cognitive workload recognition using EEG signals and machine learning: a review. IEEE Trans Cogn Develop Syst 14(3):799&#x2013;818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCDS.2021.3090217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu G, Zong F, Zhang H, Wei B, Liu F (2021) Cognitive load during multitasking can be accurately assessed based on single channel electroencephalography using graph methods. IEEE Access 9:33102&#x2013;33109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3058271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu E, Wang S, Liu C, Wang J (2025) Adaptive tokenization transformer: enhancing irregularly sampled multivariate time-series analysis. IEEE Internet Things J 12(19):39237&#x2013;39246. 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3554249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3554249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zyma I, Tukaev S, Seleznov I, Kiyono K, Popov A, Chernykh M, Shpenkov O (2019) Electroencephalograms during mental arithmetic task performance. Data 4(1):14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/data4010014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>