<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41840396</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cross-border differences in public knowledge, awareness, behaviours and beliefs related to antibiotics and antimicrobial resistance across the island of Ireland.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-026-27024-w</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shields</LastName><ForeName>Caoimhe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, Northern Ireland. cshields11@qub.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queen's University Belfast, University Road, Belfast, BT7 1NN, Northern Ireland. cshields11@qub.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berry</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahm</LastName><ForeName>Laura J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Care Research Group, School of Pharmacy, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleming</LastName><ForeName>Aoife</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Care Research Group, School of Pharmacy, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kandulu</LastName><ForeName>Chikondi C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Care Research Group, School of Pharmacy, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Anne C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biochemistry and Cell Biology, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Bioprocessing Research and Training, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SSPC Pharmaceutical Research Centre, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shorter</LastName><ForeName>Gillian W</ForeName><Initials>GW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Trinity College Dublin, The University of Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>TreAdd Research Group on Treatment and Addictions, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Awareness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behaviour change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behaviours</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Beliefs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was granted by the Faculty of Engineering and Physical Sciences at Queen&#x2019;s University Belfast (03 June 2024, reference EPS 24_68). This study was carried out in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. All participants provided informed consent after reading the study information sheet before survey completion. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41840396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-026-27024-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-026-27024-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Antimicrobial resistance, World Health Organization. World Health Organization [Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/antimicrobial-resistance. Cited 18 Dec 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Protection Surveillance Centre. Antimicrobial Resistance (EARS-Net) Data in Ireland, 2023. Ireland: Centre HPS. 2024. Available from https://www.hpsc.ie/a-z/microbiologyantimicrobialresistance/europeanantimicrobialresistancesurveillancesystemearss/ears-netdataandreports/EARS-Net%20Summary%202023.pdf. Cited 01 Oct 2025.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SK, Hussein S, Qurbani K, Ibrahim RH, Fareeq A, Mahmood KA, et al. Antimicrobial resistance: impacts, challenges, and future prospects. J Med Surg Public Health. 2024;2024(2):100081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri M, Ranucci E, Romagnoli P, Giaccone V. Antimicrobial resistance: A global emerging threat to public health systems. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2017;57(13):2857&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akova M. Epidemiology of antimicrobial resistance in bloodstream infections. Virulence. 2016;7(3):252&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Action Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance. Publications: 2015. Available from https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/193736/9789241509763_eng.pdf?sequence=1. Cited 14 March 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik G, Afseth J, Fagan R, Thomson F, Ring N. Patient and public understanding of antimicrobial resistance: a systematic review and meta-ethnography. JAC-antimicrobial Resist. 2024;6(4):dlae117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullough AR, Parekh S, Rathbone J, Del Mar CB, Hoffmann TC. A systematic review of the public&#x2019;s knowledge and beliefs about antibiotic resistance. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2016;71(1):27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission. Special Eurobarometer 522: Antimicrobial Resistance. Publications Office of the European Union: 2022. Available from https://europa.eu/eurobarometer/surveys/detail/2632. Cited 11 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Antibiotic Resistance: Multi-country public awareness survey. Institutional Repository for Information Sharing: 2015. Available from https://iris.who.int/handle/10665/194460. Cited 11 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams D. Antimicrobial resistance: are we at the dawn of the post-antibiotic era? J Royal Coll Physicians Edinb. 2016;46(3):150&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Meer JW, Fears R, Ter Meulen V. Can we tackle the antibiotic threat? Eur Rev. 2016;24(1):49&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Q, Tang S, Xiao Y. Impact of individual behaviour change on the spread of emerging infectious diseases. Stat Med. 2018;37(6):948&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirota M, Habersaat KB, Betsch C, Bonga DL, Borek A, Buckel A, et al. We must harness the power of social and behavioural science against the growing pandemic of antimicrobial resistance. Nat Hum Behav. 2024;8(1):11&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill J. Tackling drug-resistant infections globally: final report and recommendations. The Review on Antimicrobial Resistance: 2016. Available from https://amr-review.org/sites/default/files/160518_Final%20paper_with%20cover.pdf. Cited 20 Sept 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokharel S, Raut S, Adhikari B. Tackling antimicrobial resistance in low-income and middle-income countries. BMJ Specialist Journals; 2019. p. e002104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulis G, Sayood S, Gandra S. Antimicrobial resistance in low-and middle-income countries: current status and future directions. Expert Rev anti-infective therapy. 2022;20(2):147&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iskandar K, Molinier L, Hallit S, Sartelli M, Hardcastle TC, Haque M, et al. Surveillance of antimicrobial resistance in low-and middle-income countries: a scattered picture. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2021;10:1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne AJ, Chipeta MG, Haines-Woodhouse G, Kumaran EP, Hamadani BHK, Zaraa S, et al. Global antibiotic consumption and usage in humans, 2000&#x2013;18: a spatial modelling study. Lancet Planet Health. 2021;5(12):e893&#x2013;904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health Agency. Surveillance of Antimicrobial Use and Resistance in Northern Ireland Report 2022. Belfast: Public Health Agency: 2024. Available from: https://www.publichealth.hscni.net/publications/surveillance-antimicrobial-use-and-resistance-northern-ireland-annual-reports. Cited 12 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Security Agency. English surveillance programme for antimicrobial utilisation and resistance (ESPAUR) Report 2021&#x2013;2022. The National Archives: 2022. Available from https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/english-surveillance-programme-antimicrobial-utilisation-and-resistance-espaur-report.https://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/ukgwa/20231002172235/UK.&#xa0;Cited 24 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latest surveilance data on antimicrobial consumption. European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control 2023. Available from: https://qap.ecdc.europa.eu/public/extensions/AMC2_Dashboard/AMC2_Dashboard.html#eu-consumption-tab. Cited 24 Jan 2025.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation (IHME). The burden of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in Ireland. Seattle (WA): University of Washington: 2023. Available from https://www.healthdata.org/sites/default/files/2023-09/Ireland.pdf. Cited 04 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonathan McCambridge. Pseudomonas bacteria found in 459 water outlets of new maternity unit &#x2013; Dodds. The Independent. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okeke IN, Edelman R. Dissemination of antibiotic-resistant bacteria across geographic borders. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;33(3):364&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chique C, Cullinan J, Hooban B, Morris D. Mapping and analysing potential sources and transmission routes of antimicrobial resistant organisms in the environment using geographic information systems&#x2014;an exploratory study. Antibiotics. 2019;8(1):16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterlow NR, Cooper BS, Robotham JV, Knight GM. Antimicrobial resistance prevalence in bloodstream infection in 29 European countries by age and sex: An observational study. PLoS Med. 2024;21(3):e1004301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NI Direct. Help with health costs. 2024. Available from: https://www.nidirect.gov.uk/articles/help-health-costs. Cited 10/06/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Service Executive (HSE). Apply for a medical card. Health Service Executive; 2025. Available from: https://www2.hse.ie/services/schemes-allowances/medical-cards/applying/apply/. Cited 01 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Service Executive (HSE). Prescription charges for medical card holders. 2023. Available from: https://www2.hse.ie/services/schemes-allowances/medical-cards/about-the-medical-card/prescription-charges/. Cited 10/06/2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community Pharmacy NI. Pharmacy First Service. Belfast, Northern Ireland: Community Pharmacy NI; 2022. Available from: https://www.communitypharmacyni.co.uk/services/pharmacy-first/. Cited 13 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health. Expert Taskforce to Support the Expansion of the Role of Pharmacy. Dublin, Ireland: 2024. Available from https://assets.gov.ie/static/documents/expert-taskforce-to-support-the-expansion-of-the-role-of-pharmacy-final-report.pdf. Cited 11 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community Development &amp; Health Network (CDHN). Building the Community-Pharmacy Partnership Programme. Newry, Northern Ireland: CDHN; 2025 . Available from: https://www.cdhn.org/bcpp. Cited 13 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health Agency. &#x2018;Keep antibiotics working&#x2019; Living Well campaign launched . Belfast, Northern Ireland: Public Health Agency; 2023. Available from: https://www.publichealth.hscni.net/news/keep-antibiotics-working-living-well-campaign-launched. Cited 01 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Service Executive (HSE). Ordering RESIST publications. Dublin, Ireland: Health Service Executive (HSE); 2025. Available from: https://www.hse.ie/eng/about/who/healthwellbeing/our-priority-programmes/hcai/resources/ordering-resist-publications/. Cited 01 October 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Ireland. Ireland&#x2019;s One Health National Action Plan on Antimicrobial. Resistance 2021&#x2013;2025 (known as iNAP2). Policies: 2021 . Available from https://www.gov.ie/en/publication/d72f1-joint-action-on-antimicrobial-resistance/#irelands-second-one-health-action-plan-on-antimicrobial-resistance-2021-2025-inap2. Cited 08 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Agriculture Environment and Rural Affairs. Confronting antimicrobial resistance 2024 to 2029. Belfast, Northern Ireland: 2024. Available from https://www.daera-ni.gov.uk/sites/default/files/publications/daera/Confronting%20anticnicrobial%20resistance%202024-2029.pdf. Cited 06 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shebehe J, Ottertun E, Carl&#xe9;n K, Gustafson D. Knowledge about infections is associated with antibiotic use: cross-sectional evidence from the health survey Northern Ireland. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todea A. A Study of Consumer Perception of Antibiotic Resistance and Antibiotic Use in Ireland. Arrow@TU Dublin: Technological University Dublin; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healthy Ireland. Healthy Ireland Survey 2023 Summary Report. 2023. Available from https://assets.gov.ie/283794/3ef96218-68fb-4fa3-a0d2-ec687071db38.pdf. Cited 15 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maugeri A, Barchitta M, Basile G, Agodi A. How COVID-19 has influenced public interest in antimicrobials, antimicrobial resistance and related preventive measures: a Google trends analysis of Italian Data. Antibiotics. 2022;11(3):379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusic D, Vilovic M, Bukic J, Leskur D, Seselja Perisin A, Kumric M, et al. Implications of COVID-19 pandemic on the emergence of antimicrobial resistance: Adjusting the response to future outbreaks. Life. 2021;11(3):220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northern Ireland Statistics and Research Agency (NISRA). Census 2021 Population and household estimates for Northern Ireland: Statistical bulletin. Census 2021: 2022. Available from https://www.nisra.gov.uk/system/files/statistics/census-2021-population-and-household-estimates-for-northern-ireland-statistical-bulletin-24-may-2022.pdf. Cited 09 Dec 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistics Office. Census of Population 2022 - Summary Results. Statistics: 2022. Available from https://www.cso.ie/en/releasesandpublications/ep/p-cpsr/censusofpopulation2022-summaryresults/. Cited 23 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran WG. Sampling techniques. New York, NY: Wiley; 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Immunization Agenda 2030: A Global Strategy to Leave No One Behind. WHO website: 2020. Available from https://www.who.int/teams/immunization-vaccines-and-biologicals/strategies/ia2030. Cited 16 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EuroQol Research Foundation. EQ-5D-3L User Guide. User Guides: 2018. Available from https://euroqol.org/publications/user-guides. Cited 15 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan P. Modeling valuations for EuroQol health states. Med Care. 1997;35(11):1095&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson HJ, Jarrett C, Schulz WS, Chaudhuri M, Zhou Y, Dube E, et al. Measuring vaccine hesitancy: the development of a survey tool. Vaccine. 2015;33(34):4165&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadborn T, Williams S, Jorgensen T, Price C, Buckel A, Altieri E. An approach for embedding behavioural science in antimicrobial resistance One Health research. J Infect Public Health. 2023;16:134&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly S, Brick A, O&#x2019;Neill CJ, O&#x2019;Callaghan M. An analysis of the primary care systems of Ireland and Northern Ireland. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northern Ireland Office. The Belfast Agreement: An Agreement Reached at Multi-Party Talks on Northern Ireland. Northern Ireland political stability1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiv TL. When pandemics collide. Lancet HIV. 2020;7(5):e301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger MS, Polet J, Lintunen T. The reasoned action approach applied to health behavior: Role of past behavior and tests of some key moderators using meta-analytic structural equation modeling. Soc Sci Med. 2018;213:85&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health Agency. Antibiotic awareness. Public Health Agency: Public Health Agency; 2025. Available from: https://www.publichealth.hscni.net/directorates/directorate-public-health/health-protection/antibiotic-awareness. Cited 06 June 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Service Executive (HSE). Antibiotics. Health Service Executive (HSE): Health Service Executive (HSE); 2024. Available from: https://www2.hse.ie/medicines/antibiotics/. Cited 15 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health NI. Pharmacy First Pilot Service for Sore Throat: Evaluation Summary. Belfast, Northern Ireland: 2024. Available from https://bso.hscni.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/APPENDIX-1-Sore-throat-Pilot-evaluation-summary-Sept24-002.pdf. Cited 10 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community Development &amp; Health Network (CDHN). BCPP Impact Report 2024. Newry, Northern Ireland: 2024. Available from https://www.cdhn.org/sites/default/files/downloads/FINAL%20BCPP%20Full%20Report%202024_1.pdf. Cited 13 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health, Department of Agriculture Environment and Rural Affairs. Food Standards Agency. Changing the culture 2019&#x2013;2024: One Health. Tackling Antimicrobial Resistance in Northern Ireland. A Five-Year Action Plan. Department of Health: 2019. Available from https://www.health-ni.gov.uk/sites/default/files/publications/health/one-health-antimicrobial.pdf. Cited 11 Nov 2024.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilham EL, Pearce-Smith N, Carter V, Ashiru-Oredope D. Assessment of global antimicrobial resistance campaigns conducted to improve public awareness and antimicrobial use behaviours: a rapid systematic review. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashiru-Oredope D, Hopkins S. Antimicrobial resistance: moving from professional engagement to public action. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2015;70(11):2927&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X, Pang Y, Liu LS, editors. Online health information seeking behavior: a systematic review. Healthcare: MDPI; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afful-Dadzie E, Afful-Dadzie A, Egala SB. Social media in health communication: A literature review of information quality. Health Inform Manage J. 2023;52(1):3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodemer N, M&#xfc;ller SM, Okan Y, Garcia-Retamero R, Neumeyer-Gromen A. Do the media provide transparent health information? A cross-cultural comparison of public information about the HPV vaccine. Vaccine. 2012;30(25):3747&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community Development &amp; Health Network (CDHN). Our Lives, Our Meds, Our Health: Exploring Medication Safety through a Social Lens. Research and Impact: Network CDH; 2023. Available from https://www.cdhn.org/our-lives-our-meds-our-health-exploring-medication-safety-through-social-lens. Cited 14 Aug 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO Bacterial Priority Pathogens List, 2024 [Internet]. 2024 [cited 21/06/2024]. Available from.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller WR, Arias CA. ESKAPE pathogens: antimicrobial resistance, epidemiology, clinical impact and therapeutics. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2024;22(10):598&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denissen J, Reyneke B, Waso-Reyneke M, Havenga B, Barnard T, Khan S, et al. Prevalence of ESKAPE pathogens in the environment: Antibiotic resistance status, community-acquired infection and risk to human health. Int J Hyg Environ Health. 2022;244:114006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krockow EM, Cheng KO, Maltby J, McElroy E. Existing terminology related to antimicrobial resistance fails to evoke risk perceptions and be remembered. Commun Med. 2023;3(1):149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LG, Russell D, Turchioe MR, Myers AC, Vawdrey DK, Creber RMM. Effect of expansion of abbreviations and acronyms on patient comprehension of their health records: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(5):e2212320&#x2013;e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi MT. Three types of conceptual change: Belief revision, mental model transformation, and categorical shift. International handbook of research on conceptual change: Routledge; 2009. pp. 89&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praska C, Pitt MB, Marmet J, Gotlieb R, Charpentier V, Hause E, et al. Laypeople&#x2019;s (mis) understanding of common medical acronyms. Hosp Pediatr. 2023;13(10):e269&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamiel U, Hecht I, Nemet A, Pe&#x2019;er L, Man V, Hilely A, et al. Frequency, comprehension and attitudes of physicians towards abbreviations in the medical record. Postgrad Med J. 2018;94(1111):254&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health, Department of Agriculture Food and the Marine. Ireland One Health Report on Antimicrobial Use &amp; Antimicrobial Resistance. Policies: 2019. Available from https://assets.gov.ie/11418/66ec356a49754ee7a0b53268170b9b9c.pdf. Cited 12 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Bhat A, Ravi K. Antibiotics Misuse and Antimicrobial Resistance Development in Agriculture: A Global Challenge. Environ Health. 2024;2(9):618&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordvall A-C, Ancillotti M, Oljans E, Nilsson E. Antimicrobial resistance and the non-accountability effect on consumers&#x2019; behaviour. Social Responsib J. 2025;21(5):1125&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King AJ, Wald DM, Coberley DD, Dahlstrom MF, Plummer PJ. Science communication challenges about antimicrobial resistance in animal agriculture: insights from stakeholders. JAC-Antimicrobial Resist. 2022;4(2):dlac032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waswa J, Kiggundu R, Joshi MP, Mpagi J, Kasujja H, Murungi M, et al. Addressing gaps in AMR awareness in the public: an evidence-based policy brief to guide school curriculum review in Uganda. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1287523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan &#xc1;, Sweeney S, McKernan C, Benson T, Dean M. Consumer perception and understanding of the risks of antibiotic use and antimicrobial resistance in farming. Agric Hum Values. 2023;40(3):989&#x2013;1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>House of Commons Library. Childhood Immunisation Statistics. 2024 [cited Available from https://researchbriefings.files.parliament.uk/documents/CBP-8556/CBP-8556.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Protection Surveillance Centre. Annual Epidemiological Report [Internet]. 2024 [cited Available from https://www.hpsc.ie/a-z/vaccinepreventable/vaccination/immunisationuptakestatistics/immunisationuptakestatisticsforjuniorinfants/2022-2023%20DTaP-IPV%20&amp;%20MMR%20Vaccine%20Uptake%20in%20Junior%20infants,children%20aged%204-5%20years,%20Ireland_Final.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health Agency. Vaccination coverage. 2024. Available from https://www.publichealth.hscni.net/sites/default/files/2024-10/5%20years%20of%20age%20Jun%202024.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriques-Normark B, Normark S. Bacterial vaccines and antibiotic resistance. Ups J Med Sci. 2014;119(2):205&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Summary, WHO SAGE conclusions and recommendations on Vaccine Hesitancy. Strategic Advisory Group of Experts on Immunization (SAGE). : 2015. Available from https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/immunization/demand/summary-of-sage-vaccinehesitancy-en.pdf?sfvrsn=abbfd5c8_2. Cited 07 Sept 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher A, Morrissey EC, Murphy AW, Molloy GJ. Parents&#x2019; perspectives on childhood antibiotic treatment in Ireland&#x2014;a qualitative study. JAC-Antimicrobial Resist. 2025;7(5):dlaf176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borek AJ, Santillo M, Wanat M, Butler CC, Tonkin-Crine S. How can behavioural science contribute to qualitative research on antimicrobial stewardship in primary care? JAC-Antimicrobial Resist. 2022;4(1):dlac007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>