<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41811270</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuromuscular fatigability with repeated exercise in hypoxia: From single-joint paradigms to sprints.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP288654</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acute hypobaric or normobaric hypoxic exposure (i.e. inspired oxygen pressure &lt;149&#xa0;mmHg) accelerates neuromuscular fatigability. Single-joint exercises and whole-body repeated-sprint efforts offer complementary insights: the former enables detailed exploration of fatigue-related mechanisms, while the latter serves as a functional performance-relevant model. Training with repeated sprints in hypoxia (RSH) has also emerged as a promising ergogenic strategy. This review discusses the aetiology of neuromuscular fatigability during both single-joint exercise and repeated-sprint efforts with mild, moderate and severe hypoxia, and explores how RSH may enhance fatigue resistance. Despite differences in exercise intensity and muscle mass, both paradigms share common features. Regardless of hypoxia severity, maximal force and power during isolated efforts remain largely unaffected, while velocity may improve at terrestrial altitude due to lower air resistance. In contrast, repeated efforts in hypoxia accelerate performance declines, increasing peripheral and cerebral deoxygenation in a hypoxia severity-dependent manner. Above &#x223c;3800&#xa0;m (severe hypoxia), the contribution of central (supraspinal) mechanisms to fatigability increases in single-joint exercise. Differently, the aetiology of fatigability in RSH seems unaffected by hypoxia severity, despite indirect evidence of central limitations. Lastly, we outline the muscular, vascular and molecular mechanisms that may enhance neuromuscular fatigability through RSH training and consider its practical applications. Connecting findings between single-joint and repeated whole-body maximal-intensity exercise is key to translating basic physiology into effective training approaches to improve sport performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruggiero</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1914-9625</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Centre (HPRC), Department of Sports Science, University of Konstanz, Konstanz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brocherie</LastName><ForeName>Franck</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0808-7986</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Sport, Expertise and Performance (EA 7370), French Institute of Sport (INSEP), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girard</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Townsend</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health and Life Sciences, Hamad Bin Khalifa University, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McNeil</LastName><ForeName>Chris J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3681-4404</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Lung and Vascular Health, School of Health and Exercise Sciences, The University of British Columbia, Kelowna, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Millet</LastName><ForeName>Gr&#xe9;goire P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8081-4423</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Sciences, University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Alexander von Humboldt Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deoxygenation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">repeated&#x2010;sprint ability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supraspinal fatigue</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41811270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP288654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Alhammoud, M., Morel, B., Girard, O., Racinais, S., Sevrez, V., Germain, A., Chamu, T., &amp; Hautier, C. (2018). Hypoxia and fatigue impair rapid torque development of knee extensors in elite alpine skiers. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, D. G., Lamb, G. D., &amp; Westerblad, H. (2008). Skeletal muscle fatigue: Cellular mechanisms. Physiological Reviews, 88(1), 287&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., &amp; Calbet, J. A. L. (2008). Convective oxygen transport and fatigue. Journal of Applied Physiology, 104(3), 861&#x2013;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2008). Locomotor muscle fatigue modifies central motor drive in healthy humans and imposes a limitation to exercise performance. The Journal of Physiology, 586(1), 161&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., Goodall, S., Twomey, R., Subudhi, A. W., Lovering, A. T., &amp; Roach, R. C. (2013). AltitudeOmics: On the consequences of high&#x2010;altitude acclimatization for the development of fatigue during locomotor exercise in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 115(5), 634&#x2013;642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., &amp; Kayser, B. (2009). Nervous system function during exercise in hypoxia. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 10(2), 149&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., Romer, L. M., Subudhi, A. W., Pegelow, D. F., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2007). Severity of arterial hypoxaemia affects the relative contributions of peripheral muscle fatigue to exercise performance in healthy humans. The Journal of Physiology, 581(1), 389&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., Wan, H.&#x2010;Y., Thurston, T. S., Georgescu, V. P., &amp; Weavil, J. C. (2020). On the influence of group III/IV muscle afferent feedback on endurance exercise performance. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 48(4), 209&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach, K. B., &amp; Mitchell, G. S. (1996). Hypoxia&#x2010;induced long&#x2010;term facilitation of respiratory activity is serotonin dependent. Respiration Physiology, 104(2&#x2010;3), 251&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, T. L., &amp; Mitchell, G. S. (2000). Episodic but not continuous hypoxia elicits long&#x2010;term facilitation of phrenic motor outputs in rats. The Journal of Physiology, 529(1), 215&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes, W. S. (1980). The relationship between maximum isometric strength and intramuscular circulatory occlusion. Ergonomics, 23(4), 351&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;rtsch, P., Saltin, B., &amp; Dvorak, J. (2008). Consensus statement on playing football at different altitude. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 18(s1), 96&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejder, J., Graae, J., Andersen, J. B., Barbieri, R. A., Campos, E. Z., Bangsbo, J., Nybo, L., &amp; Nordsborg, N. B. (2025). Time&#x2010;course of muscle fatigue development during intense exercise in hypoxia and normoxia. Scientific Reports, 15(1), 14065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland&#x2010;Ritchie, B., Rice, C. L., Garland, S. J., Walsh, M. L. (1995). Task&#x2010;dependent factors in fatigue of human voluntary contractions. In S. C. Gandevia, R. M. Enoka, A. J. McComas, D. G. Stuart, &amp; C. K. Thomas (Eds.), Fatigue: Neural and muscular mechanisms (pp. 361&#x2013;380). Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billaut, F., &amp; Buchheit, M. (2013). Repeated&#x2010;sprint performance and vastus lateralis oxygenation: Effect of limited O2 availability. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 23(3), e185&#x2013;e193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billaut, F., Kerris, J. P., Rodriguez, R. F., Martin, D. T., Gore, C. J., &amp; Bishop, D. J. (2013). Interaction of central and peripheral factors during repeated sprints at different levels of arterial O2 saturation. PLoS ONE, 8(10), e77297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boccia, G., Brustio, P. R., Salvaggio, F., Grossio, L., Calcagno, E., Pintore, A., Rainoldi, A., &amp; Samozino, P. (2025). The rate of torque development as a determinant of the torque&#x2010;velocity relationship. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 35(3), e70035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondi, D., Valli, G., Santangelo, C., Annarumma, S., Pietrangelo, T., Fulle, S., &amp; Verratti, V. (2025). Non&#x2010;invasive motor unit analysis reveals specific responses during maximal muscle contraction under normobaric hypoxia. Pflugers Archiv : European Journal of Physiology, 477(10), 1295&#x2013;1308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouten, J., Brick, M., Saboua, A., Hadjadj, J. L., Piscione, J., Margot, C., Doucende, G., Bourrel, N., Millet, G. P., &amp; Brocherie, F. (2023). Effects of 2 different protocols of repeated&#x2010;sprint training in hypoxia in elite female rugby sevens players, during an altitude training camp. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 18(9), 953&#x2013;959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowtell, J. L., Cooke, K., Turner, R., Mileva, K. N., &amp; Sumners, D. P. (2014). Acute physiological and performance responses to repeated sprints in varying degrees of hypoxia. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 17(4), 399&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Girard, O., Faiss, R., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2017). Effects of repeated&#x2010;sprint training in hypoxia on sea&#x2010;level performance: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 47(8), 1651&#x2013;1660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2020). Hypoxic exercise as an effective nonpharmacological therapeutic intervention. Experimental &amp; Molecular Medicine, 52(3), 529&#x2013;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., Hauser, A., Steiner, T., Rysman, J., Wehrlin, J. P., &amp; Girard, O. (2015). &#x201c;Live high &#x2013; train low and high&#x201d; hypoxic training improves team&#x2010;sport performance. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 47(10), 2140&#x2013;2149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., D'Hulst, G., Van Thienen, R., Deldicque, L., &amp; Girard, O. (2018). Repeated maximal&#x2010;intensity hypoxic exercise superimposed to hypoxic residence boosts skeletal muscle transcriptional responses in elite team&#x2010;sport athletes. Acta Physiologica, 222(1), e12851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., Morin, J. B., &amp; Girard, O. (2016). Mechanical alterations to repeated treadmill sprints in normobaric hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 48(8), 1570&#x2013;1579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Racinais, S., Cocking, S., Townsend, N., Couderc, A., Piscione, J., &amp; Girard, O. (2023). Repeated&#x2010;sprint training at 5000&#x2010;m simulated altitude in preparation for the World Rugby Women's Sevens Series: Too high? Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 55(10), 1923&#x2013;1932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce, C. D., Debenham, M. I. B., Dalton, B. H., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2024). Acute normobaric hypoxia causes a rightward shift in the torque&#x2010;frequency relationship but has no effect on postactivation potentiation. Journal of Applied Physiology, 137(5), 1389&#x2013;1396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit, M., &amp; Laursen, P. B. (2013). High&#x2010;intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle: Part I: cardiopulmonary emphasis. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 43(5), 313&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundle, M. W., &amp; Weyand, P. G. (2012). Sprint exercise performance: Does metabolic power matter? Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 40(3), 174&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnley, M., Vanhatalo, A., &amp; Jones, A. M. (2012). Distinct profiles of neuromuscular fatigue during muscle contractions below and above the critical torque in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 113(2), 215&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher, J., Raberin, A., Brocherie, F., Malatesta, D., Manferdelli, G., Citherlet, T., Krumm, B., Bourdillon, N., Antero, J., Rasica, L., Burtscher, M., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2023). Recommendations for women in mountain sports and hypoxia training/conditioning. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 54(4), 795&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calbet, J. A., &amp; Lundby, C. (2009). Air to muscle O2 delivery during exercise at altitude. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 10(2), 123&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calbet, J. A. L., R&#xe5;degran, G., Boushel, R., &amp; Saltin, B. (2009). On the mechanisms that limit oxygen uptake during exercise in acute and chronic hypoxia: Role of muscle mass. The Journal of Physiology, 587(2), 477&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey, D. P., &amp; Joyner, M. J. (2012). Compensatory vasodilation during hypoxic exercise: Mechanisms responsible for matching oxygen supply to demand. The Journal of Physiology, 590(24), 6321&#x2013;6326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christian, R. J., Bishop, D. J., Billaut, F., &amp; Girard, O. (2014). Peripheral fatigue is not critically regulated during maximal, intermittent, dynamic leg extensions. Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(9), 1063&#x2013;1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland, S. M., Murias, J. M., Kowalchuk, J. M., &amp; Paterson, D. H. (2012). Effects of prior heavy&#x2010;intensity exercise on oxygen uptake and muscle deoxygenation kinetics of a subsequent heavy&#x2010;intensity cycling and knee&#x2010;extension exercise. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 37(1), 138&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins, B. W., Pearcey, G. E. P., Buckle, N. C. M., Power, K. E., &amp; Button, D. C. (2018). Neuromuscular fatigue during repeated sprint exercise: Underlying physiology and methodological considerations. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 43(11), 1166&#x2013;1175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale, E. A., Ben Mabrouk, F., &amp; Mitchell, G. S. (2014). Unexpected benefits of intermittent hypoxia: Enhanced respiratory and nonrespiratory motor function. Physiology, 29(1), 39&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Prampero, P. E., Mognoni, P., &amp; Veicstenas, A. (1982). The effects of hypoxia on maximal anaerobic alactic power in man. In W. Brendel &amp; R. A. Zink (Eds.), High altitude physiology and medicine (pp. 88&#x2013;93). Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debenham, M. I. B., Smuin, J. N., Grantham, T. D. A., Ainslie, P. N., &amp; Dalton, B. H. (2021). Hypoxia and standing balance. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(4), 993&#x2013;1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degens, H., Horneros, J. M. S., &amp; Hopman, M. T. F. (2006). Acute hypoxia limits endurance but does not affect muscle contractile properties. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 33(4), 532&#x2013;537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey, J. A., &amp; Wagner, P. D. (1999). Exercise&#x2010;induced arterial hypoxemia. Journal of Applied Physiology, 87(6), 1997&#x2013;2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devinney, M. J., Nichols, N. L., &amp; Mitchell, G. S. (2016). Sustained hypoxia elicits competing spinal mechanisms of phrenic motor facilitation. Journal of Neuroscience, 36(30), 7877&#x2013;7885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominelli, P. B., Archiza, B., Ramsook, A. H., Mitchell, R. A., Peters, C. M., Molgat&#x2010;Seon, Y., Henderson, W. R., Koehle, M. S., Boushel, R., &amp; Sheel, A. W. (2017). Effects of respiratory muscle work on respiratory and locomotor blood flow during exercise. Experimental Physiology, 102(11), 1535&#x2013;1547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominelli, P. B., Molgat&#x2010;Seon, Y., Griesdale, D. E. G., Peters, C. M., Blouin, J.&#x2010;S., Sekhon, M., Dominelli, G. S., Henderson, W. R., Foster, G. E., Romer, L. M., Koehle, M. S., &amp; Sheel, A. W (2017). Exercise&#x2010;induced quadriceps muscle fatigue in men and women: Effects of arterial oxygen content and respiratory muscle work. The Journal of Physiology, 595(15), 5227&#x2013;5244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dousset, E., Steinberg, J. G., Balon, N., &amp; Jammes, Y. (2001). Effects of acute hypoxemia on force and surface EMG during sustained hand&#x2010;grip. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 24(3), 364&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle&#x2010;Baker, D., Temesi, J., Medysky, M. E., Holash, R. J., &amp; Millet, G. Y. (2018). An innovative ergometer to measure neuromuscular fatigue immediately after cycling. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 50(2), 375&#x2013;387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiken, O., &amp; Tesch, P. A. (1984). Effects of hyperoxia and hypoxia on dynamic and sustained static performance of the human quadriceps muscle. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica, 122(4), 629&#x2013;633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka, R. M., &amp; Duchateau, J. (2016). Translating fatigue to human performance. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 48(11), 2228&#x2013;2238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss, R., L&#xe9;ger, B., Vesin, J.&#x2010;M., Fournier, P.&#x2010;E., Eggel, Y., D&#xe9;riaz, O., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2013). Significant molecular and systemic adaptations after repeated sprint training in hypoxia. PLoS ONE, 8(2), e56522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss, R., Raberin, A., Brocherie, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2025). Repeated&#x2010;sprint training in hypoxia: A review with 10 years of perspective. Journal of Sports Sciences, 43(19), 2164&#x2013;2178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J.&#x2010;L., &amp; Kayser, B. (2016). Fatigue and exhaustion in hypoxia: The role of cerebral oxygenation. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 17(2), 72&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina, D., Merletti, R., &amp; Enoka, R. (2004). The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. Journal of Applied Physiology, 96(4), 1486&#x2013;1495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. C. (2001). Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiological Reviews, 81(4), 1725&#x2013;1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. C., &amp; Butler, J. E. (2024). Acute intermittent hypoxia: Enhancing motoneuronal output or not? Experimental Physiology, 109(9), 1417&#x2013;1419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Brocherie, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2016). High altitude increases alteration in maximal torque but not in rapid torque development in knee extensors after repeated treadmill sprinting. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Brocherie, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2017). Effects of altitude/hypoxia on single&#x2010; and multiple&#x2010;sprint performance: A comprehensive review. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 47(10), 1931&#x2013;1949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Buchheit, M., Goodall, S., &amp; Racinais, S. (2021). Oxygen availability affects exercise capacity, but not neuromuscular fatigue characteristics of knee extensors, during exhaustive intermittent cycling. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(1), 95&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Goods, P. S. R., &amp; Brocherie, F. (2020). Editorial: Elevating sport performance to new heights with innovative &#x201c;Live low &#x2013; Train high&#x201d; altitude training. Front Sports Act Living, 2, 108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Mendez&#x2010;Villanueva, A., &amp; Bishop, D. (2011). Repeated&#x2010;sprint ability &#x2013; Part I: Factors contributing to fatigue. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 41(8), 673&#x2013;694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Peeling, P., Racinais, S., &amp; P&#xe9;riard, J. D. (2024). Combining heat and altitude training to enhance temperate, sea&#x2010;level performance. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 19(3), 322&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., &amp; Racinais, S. (2023). Exhaustive intermittent cycling preferentially decreases explosive over maximal voluntary torque in the knee extensors, with no difference between normoxia and moderate to severe hypoxia. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 18(11), 1352&#x2013;1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall, S., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Alonso, J., Ali, L., Ross, E. Z., &amp; Romer, L. M. (2012). Supraspinal fatigue after normoxic and hypoxic exercise in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 590(11), 2767&#x2013;2782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall, S., Ross, E. Z., &amp; Romer, L. M. (2010). Effect of graded hypoxia on supraspinal contributions to fatigue with unilateral knee&#x2010;extensor contractions. Journal of Applied Physiology, 109(6), 1842&#x2013;1851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall, S., Twomey, R., &amp; Amann, M. (2014). Acute and chronic hypoxia: Implications for cerebral function and exercise tolerance. Fatigue, 2, 73&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall, S., Twomey, R., Amann, M., Ross, E. Z., Lovering, A. T., Romer, L. M., Subudhi, A. W., &amp; Roach, R. C. (2014). AltitudeOmics: Exercise&#x2010;induced supraspinal fatigue is attenuated in healthy humans after acclimatization to high altitude. Acta Physiologica, 210(4), 875&#x2013;888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goods, P. S., Dawson, B. T., Landers, G. J., Gore, C. J., &amp; Peeling, P. (2014). Effect of different simulated altitudes on repeated&#x2010;sprint performance in team&#x2010;sport athletes. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 9(5), 857&#x2013;862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grootenhuis, A., Hiereth, F. C., &#x160;karabot, J., O&#xdf;wald, M., Del Vecchio, A., Gruber, M., &amp; Ruggiero, L. (2025). No differences in motor units discharge rate between females and males in explosive ankle dorsiflexions. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 35(5), e70065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen, C., Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., &amp; Girard, O. (2024). Effects of hypoxia severity on muscle oxygenation kinetics using statistical parametric mapping during repeated treadmill sprints. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 19(4), 417&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haseler, L. J., Hogan, M. C., &amp; Richardson, R. S. (1999). Skeletal muscle phosphocreatine recovery in exercise&#x2010;trained humans is dependent on O2 availability. Journal of Applied Physiology, 86(6), 2013&#x2013;2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan, M. C., Richardson, R. S., &amp; Haseler, L. J. (1999). Human muscle performance and PCr hydrolysis with varied inspired oxygen fractions: A 31P&#x2010;MRS study. Journal of Applied Physiology, 86(4), 1367&#x2013;1373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoiland, R. L., Howe, C. A., Coombs, G. B., &amp; Ainslie, P. A. (2018). Ventilatory and cerebrovascular regulation and integration at high&#x2010;altitude. Clinical Autonomic Research, 28(4), 423&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoiland, R. L., Bain, A. R., Rieger, M. G., Bailey, D. M., &amp; Ainslie, P. N. (2016). Hypoxemia, oxygen content, and the regulation of cerebral blood flow. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 310(5), R398&#x2013;R413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler, H., &amp; Vogt, M. (2001). Muscle tissue adaptations to hypoxia. Journal of Experimental Biology, 204(18), 3133&#x2013;3139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler, H., Vogt, M., Weibel, E. R., &amp; Fl&#xfc;ck, M. (2003). Responses of skeletal muscle mitochondria to hypoxia. Experimental Physiology, 88(1), 109&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlett, R. A., &amp; Hogan, M. C. (2007). Effect of hypoxia on fatigue development in rat muscle composed of different fibre types. Experimental Physiology, 92(5), 887&#x2013;894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hureau, T. J., Ducrocq, G. P., &amp; Blain, G. M. (2016). Peripheral and central fatigue development during all&#x2010;out repeated cycling sprints. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 48(3), 391&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannetta, D., Zhang, J., Murias, J. M., &amp; Aboodarda, S. J. (2022). Neuromuscular and perceptual mechanisms of fatigue accompanying task failure in response to moderate&#x2010;, heavy&#x2010;, severe&#x2010;, and extreme&#x2010;intensity cycling. Journal of Applied Physiology, 133(2), 323&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubeau, M., Rupp, T., Temesi, J., Perrey, S., Wuyam, B., Millet, G. Y., &amp; Verges, S. (2017). Neuromuscular fatigue during prolonged exercise in hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 49(3), 430&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama, K., Amann, M., Pegelow, D. F., Jacques, A. J., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2007). Effect of arterial oxygenation on quadriceps fatigability during isolated muscle exercise. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 292(3), R1279&#x2013;R1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskolou, M. D., Calbet, J. A., R&#xe5;degran, G., &amp; Roach, R. C. (1997). Hypoxia and the cardiovascular response to dynamic knee&#x2010;extensor exercise. American Journal of Physiology, 272, H2655&#x2013;H2663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer, D. L., &amp; McLaughlin, R. L. (2001). The behavioral ecology of intermittent locomotion. American Zoologist, 41, 137&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb, G. D., &amp; Westerblad, H. (2011). Acute effects of reactive oxygen and nitrogen species on the contractile function of skeletal muscle. The Journal of Physiology, 589(9), 2119&#x2013;2127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavier, J., Beaumann, M., Men&#xe9;trey, S., Bouzour&#xe8;ne, K., Rosenblatt&#x2010;Velin, N., Pialoux, V., Mazzolai, L., Peyter, A.&#x2010;C., Pellegrin, M., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2021). High&#x2010;intensity exercise in hypoxia improves endothelial function via increased nitric oxide bioavailability in C57BL/6 mice. Acta Physiologica, 233(2), e13700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, B. D. (2002). Intermittent hypoxic training: Fact and fancy. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 3(2), 177&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linkis, P., Jorgensen, L. G., Olesen, H. L., Madsen, P. L., Lassen, N. A., &amp; Secher, N. H. (1995). Dynamic exercise enhances regional cerebral artery mean flow. Journal of Applied Physiology, 78(1), 12&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciano, F., Pavei, G., &amp; Ruggiero, L. (2022). Bariatric surgery on obese walking: Mass(ive) changes akin to load carrying and hypogravity for normal&#x2010;weight adults. The Journal of Physiology, 600(4), 729&#x2013;731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., Calbet, J. A., &amp; Robach, P. (2009). The response of human skeletal muscle tissue to hypoxia. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 66(22), 3615&#x2013;3623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcolm, R., Cooper, S., Folland, J., Tyler, C., Hannah, R., &amp; Sunderland, C. (2021). Reliability of transcranial magnetic stimulation measurements of maximum activation of the knee extensors in young adult males. Human Movement Science, 78, 102828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marillier, M., Arnal, P. J., Le Roux Mallouf, T., Rupp, T., Millet, G. Y., &amp; Verges, S. (2017). Effects of high&#x2010;altitude exposure on supraspinal fatigue and corticospinal excitability and inhibition. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(8), 1747&#x2013;1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough, P., Behnke, B. J., Padilla, D. J., Musch, T. I., &amp; Poole, D. C. (2005). Control of microvascular oxygen pressures in rat muscles comprised of different fibre types. The Journal of Physiology, 563(3), 903&#x2013;913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeown, D. J., McNeil, C. J., Brotherton, E. J., Simmonds, M. J., &amp; Kavanagh, J. J. (2021). Severe acute hypoxia impairs recovery of voluntary muscle activation after sustained submaximal elbow flexion. The Journal of Physiology, 599(24), 5379&#x2013;5395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeown, D. J., McNeil, C. J., Simmonds, M. J., &amp; Kavanagh, J. J. (2020). Time course of neuromuscular responses to acute hypoxia during voluntary contractions. Experimental Physiology, 105(11), 1855&#x2013;1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeown, D. J., Simmonds, M. J., &amp; Kavanagh, J. J. (2019). Reduced blood oxygen levels induce changes in low&#x2010;threshold motor unit firing that align with the individual's tolerance to hypoxia. Journal of Neurophysiology, 121(5), 1664&#x2013;1671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mckeown, D. J., Mcneil, C. J., Simmonds, M. J., &amp; Kavanagh, J. J. (2022). Post&#x2010;fatigue ability to activate muscle is compromised across a wide range of torques during acute hypoxic exposure. European Journal of Neuroscience, 56(5), 4653&#x2013;4668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon, S., &amp; Jenkins, D. (2002). Factors affecting the rate of phosphocreatine resynthesis following intense exercise. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 32(12), 761&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merton, P. A. (1954). Voluntary strength and fatigue. The Journal of Physiology, 123(3), 553&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Wehrlin, J. P., Peltonen, J. E., Constantini, K., Kumar, V. H. S., Schmidt, W. F. J., Brocherie, F., Girard, O., Troesch, S., Hauser, A., Steiner, T., Rusko, H. K., Fulton, T. J., Hursh, D. G., Noble, T. J., Paris, H. L. R., Wiggins, C. C., Chapman, R. F., &amp; Levine, B. D. (2016). Commentaries on Viewpoint: Time for a new metric for hypoxic dose. Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(1), 356&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Debevec, T., Brocherie, F., Malatesta, D., &amp; Girard, O. (2016). Therapeutic use of exercising in hypoxia: promises and limitations. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Roels, B., Schmitt, L., Woorons, X., &amp; Richalet, J. P. (2010). Combining hypoxic methods for peak performance. Sports Medicine, 40(1), 1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Girard, O., Beard, A. J., &amp; Brocherie, F. (2019). Repeated sprint training in hypoxia &#x2013; An innovative method. Deutsche Zeitschrift Fur Sportmedizin, 2019(5), 115&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. Y., Aubert, D., Favier, F. B., Busso, T., &amp; Beno&#xee;t, H. (2009). Effect of acute hypoxia on central fatigue during repeated isometric leg contractions. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 19(5), 695&#x2013;702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. Y., Muthalib, M., Jubeau, M., Laursen, P. B., &amp; Nosaka, K. (2012). Severe hypoxia affects exercise performance independently of afferent feedback and peripheral fatigue. Journal of Applied Physiology, 112(8), 1335&#x2013;1344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mira, J., Floreani, M., Savoldelli, A., Amery, K., Koral, J., Oranchuk, D. J., Messonnier, L. A., Rupp, T., &amp; Millet, G. Y. (2020). Neuromuscular fatigue of cycling exercise in hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(9), 1888&#x2013;1899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani, T., Nagata, A., deVries, H. A., &amp; Muro, M. (1981). Critical power as a measure of physical work capacity and anaerobic threshold. Ergonomics, 24(5), 339&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo, J. L., Kennedy, D. S., Finn, H. T., &amp; Taylor, J. L. (2021). Voluntary activation of knee extensor muscles with transcranial magnetic stimulation. Journal of Applied Physiology, 130(3), 589&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto, S. R., Borden, C. K., McHail, D. G., &amp; Blacker, K. J. (2025). EEG as a neural measure of hypoxia&#x2010;related impairment. Frontiers in Cognition, 4, 1503028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearcey, G. E. P., Afsharipour, B., Holobar, A., Sandhu, M. S., &amp; Rymer, W. Z. (2024). Acute intermittent hypoxia increases maximal motor unit discharge rates in people with chronic incomplete spinal cord injury. The Journal of Physiology, 602(21), 5699&#x2013;5711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peronnet, F., Thibault, G., &amp; Cousineau, D. L. (1991). A theoretical analysis of the effect of altitude on running performance. Journal of Applied Physiology, 70(1), 399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrey, S., &amp; Rupp, T. (2009). Altitude&#x2010;induced changes in muscle contractile properties. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 10(2), 175&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrard, A., Willis, S. J., Place, N., Millet, G. P., Borrani, F., &amp; Rupp, T. (2019). Neuromuscular evaluation of arm&#x2010;cycling repeated sprints under hypoxia and/or blood flow restriction. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 119(7), 1533&#x2013;1545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raberin, A., Elmer, J., Willis, S. J., Richard, T., Vernillo, G., Iaia, F. M., Girard, O., Malatesta, D., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2023). The oxidative&#x2010;glycolytic balance influenced by sprint duration is key during repeated sprint in hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 55(2), 245&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen, P., Nielsen, J., Overgaard, M., Krogh&#x2010;Madsen, R., Gjedde, A., Secher, N. H., &amp; Petersen, N. C. (2010). Reduced muscle activation during exercise related to brain oxygenation and metabolism in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 588(11), 1985&#x2013;1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, R. S., Knight, D. R., Poole, D. C., Kurdak, S. S., Hogan, M. C., Grassi, B., &amp; Wagner, P. D. (1995). Determinants of maximal exercise VO2 during single leg knee&#x2010;extensor exercise in humans. American Journal of Physiology, 268, 1453&#x2013;1461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roels, B., Thomas, C., Bentley, D. J., Mercier, J., Hayot, M., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2007). Effects of intermittent hypoxic training on amino and fatty acid oxidative combustion in human permeabilized muscle fibers. Journal of Applied Physiology, 102(1), 79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer, L. M., Haverkamp, H. C., Amann, M., Lovering, A. T., Pegelow, D. F., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2007). Effect of acute severe hypoxia on peripheral fatigue and endurance capacity in healthy humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 292(1), R598&#x2013;R606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer, L. M., Haverkamp, H. C., Lovering, A. T., Pegelow, D. F., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2006). Effect of exercise&#x2010;induced arterial hypoxemia on quadriceps muscle fatigue in healthy humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 290(2), R365&#x2013;R375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., Bruce, C. D., Streight, H. B., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2021). Maximal results with minimal stimuli: The fewest high&#x2010;frequency pulses needed to measure or model prolonged low&#x2010;frequency force depression (2021). Journal of Applied Physiology, 131(2), 716&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., &amp; Gruber, M. (2024). Neuromuscular mechanisms for the fast decline in rate of force development with muscle disuse &#x2013; A narrative review. The Journal of Physiology, 604(2), 735&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., Harrison, S. W. D., Rice, C. L., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2022). Neuromuscular fatigability at high altitude: Lowlanders with acute and chronic exposure, and native highlanders. Acta Physiologica, 234(4), e13788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., Hoiland, R. L., Hansen, A. B., Ainslie, P. N., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2018). UBC&#x2010;Nepal expedition: Peripheral fatigue recovers faster in Sherpa than lowlanders at high altitude. The Journal of Physiology, 596(22), 5365&#x2013;5377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., Hoiland, R. L., Hansen, A. B., Ainslie, P. N., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2020). High&#x2010;altitude acclimatization improves recovery from muscle fatigue. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(1), 161&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2023). UBC&#x2010;Nepal expedition: Motor unit characteristics in lowlanders acclimatized to high altitude and Sherpa. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 55(3), 430&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero, L., Yacyshyn, A. F., Nettleton, J., &amp; McNeil, C. J. (2018). UBC&#x2010;Nepal expedition: Acclimatization to high&#x2010;altitude increases spinal motoneurone excitability during fatigue in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 596(15), 3327&#x2013;3339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp, T., Jubeau, M., Wuyam, B., Perrey, S., Levy, P., Millet, G. Y., &amp; Verges, S. (2012). Time&#x2010;dependent effect of acute hypoxia on corticospinal excitability in healthy humans. Journal of Neurophysiology, 108(5), 1270&#x2013;1277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp, T., Le Roux Mallouf, T., Perrey, S., Wuyam, B., Millet, G. Y., &amp; Verges, S. (2015). CO2 clamping, peripheral and central fatigue during knee extensions in men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 47(12), 2513&#x2013;2524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp, T., Racinais, S., Bringard, A., Lapole, T., &amp; Perrey, S. (2015). Modulation of exercise&#x2010;induced spinal loop properties in response to oxygen availability. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 115(3), 471&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, K. J., &amp; Billaut, F. (2010). Influence of cerebral and muscle oxygenation on repeated&#x2010;sprint ability. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 109(5), 989&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solsona, R., D&#xe9;riaz, R., Albert, S., Chamoux, M., Lloria&#x2010;Varella, J., Borrani, F., &amp; Sanchez, A. M. J. (2024). Impact of systemic hypoxia and blood flow restriction on mechanical, cardiorespiratory, and neuromuscular responses to a multiple&#x2010;set repeated sprint exercise. Frontiers in Physiology, 15, 1339284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soo, J., Billaut, F., Bishop, D., Christian, R. J., &amp; Girard, O. (2020). Neuromuscular and perceptual responses during repeated cycling sprints &#x2013; Usefulness of a &#x201c;hypoxic to normoxic&#x201d; recovery approach. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 120(4), 883&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soo, J., Racinais, S., Fairchild, T. J., Ihsan, M., Buchheit, M., &amp; Girard, O. (2021). Effects of graded hypoxia during exhaustive intermittent cycling on subsequent exercise performance and neuromuscular responses. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(12), 3539&#x2013;3549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparing, R., Dafotakis, M., Buelte, D., Meister, I. G., &amp; Noth, J. (2007). Excitability of human motor and visual cortex before, during, and after hyperventilation. Journal of Applied Physiology, 102(1), 406&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szubski, C., Burtscher, M., &amp; L&#xf6;scher, W. N. (2006). The effects of short&#x2010;term hypoxia on motor cortex excitability and neuromuscular activation. Journal of Applied Physiology, 101(6), 1673&#x2013;1677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szubski, C., Burtscher, M., &amp; L&#xf6;scher, W. N. (2007). Neuromuscular fatigue during sustained contractions performed in short&#x2010;term hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 39(6), 948&#x2013;954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd, G., Taylor, J. L., &amp; Gandevia, S. C. (2003). Measurement of voluntary activation of fresh and fatigued muscles using transcranial magnetic stimulation. The Journal of Physiology, 551(2), 661&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres&#x2010;Peralta, R., Losa&#x2010;Reyna, J., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Izal, M., Perez&#x2010;Suarez, I., Calle&#x2010;Herrero, J., Izquierdo, M., &amp; Calbet, J. A. L. (2014). Muscle activation during exercise in severe acute hypoxia: Role of absolute and relative intensity. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 15(4), 472&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres&#x2010;Peralta, R., Losa&#x2010;Reyna, J., Morales&#x2010;Alamo, D., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Izal, M., P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Su&#xe1;rez, I., Ponce&#x2010;Gonz&#xe1;lez, J. G., Izquierdo, M., &amp; Calbet, J. A. L. (2016). Increased PIO2 at exhaustion in hypoxia enhances muscle activation and swiftly relieves fatigue: A placebo or a PIO2 dependent effect? Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend, N. E., Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., &amp; Girard, O. (2021). Central and peripheral muscle fatigue following repeated&#x2010;sprint running in moderate and severe hypoxia. Experimental Physiology, 106(1), 126&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend, N. E., Nichols, D. S., Skiba, P. F., Racinais, S., &amp; P&#xe9;riard, J. D. (2017). Prediction of critical power and in hypoxia: Application to work&#x2010;balance modelling. Frontiers in Physiology, 8, 180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verges, S., Rupp, T., Jubeau, M., Wuyam, B., Esteve, F., Levy, P., Perrey, S., &amp; Millet, G. Y. (2012). Cerebral perturbations during exercise in hypoxia. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 302(8), R903&#x2013;R916.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>