<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41204573</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>45</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the effectiveness of different prescriptions of sit-to-stand training in post-stroke rehabilitation: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45625</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45625</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45625</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000045625</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sit-to-stand (STS) training is essential in post-stroke rehabilitation, yet variations in training prescriptions and outcomes highlight the need for a thorough synthesis to inform clinical practice. The objective of this review is to elucidate the current evidence on the prescription parameters of STS training and its effects on physical and functional outcomes in post-stroke survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This review followed the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines. A comprehensive literature search was conducted across 5 electronic databases: PubMed, Web of Science, EBSCO Medline, Cochrane Library, and Scopus. The preferred keywords were "stroke AND sit-to-stand." Inclusion criteria were: randomized controlled trials assessing STS training effects in post-stroke survivors, reporting on clinical outcomes, published in English, and no restrictions on publication date. Methodological quality was evaluated using the Physiotherapy Evidence Database scale and the Cochrane Risk of Bias Tool, and meta-analysis was performed using Review Manager software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ten randomized controlled trials (published between 2008-2021) involving 384 adults post-stroke were included in the analysis. STS training protocols varied, incorporating task-specific practice, resistance training, and balance exercises, with intensities ranging from low to moderate, and frequencies of 3 to 5 sessions per week over 4 to 12 weeks. Key outcomes assessed included static and dynamic balance, STS performance metrics, functional mobility, and lower limb strength. Most trials reported significant improvements in clinical outcomes following STS training compared to conventional rehabilitation. Meta-analysis revealed significant improvements in balance performance, functional mobility, and STS task duration following STS training compared to conventional rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">STS training significantly enhances balance, functional mobility, and STS performance in post-stroke survivors. Despite variability in protocols, standardizing STS training parameters may further improve therapeutic outcomes and streamline rehabilitation practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Josop</LastName><ForeName>Nancy Anne</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-6251-0726</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Programme &amp; Centre for Rehabilitation and Special Needs Studies (iCaRehab), Faculty of Health Sciences, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Unit, Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Department, Hospital Rehabilitasi Cheras, Ministry of Health, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohd Nordin</LastName><ForeName>Nor Azlin</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0038-1670</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Programme &amp; Centre for Rehabilitation and Special Needs Studies (iCaRehab), Faculty of Health Sciences, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Mohd Azzuan</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2591-8112</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Programme &amp; Centre for Rehabilitation and Special Needs Studies (iCaRehab), Faculty of Health Sciences, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071939" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Rehabilitation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077708" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sitting Position</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078783" MajorTopicYN="N">Standing Position</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrovascular accident</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemiparesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemiplegia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sit-to-stand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">standing up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41204573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12599723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000045625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202511070-00117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Li X, Yu X, et al. Global burden, risk factor analysis, and prediction study of ischemic stroke, 1990-2030. Neurology. 2023;101:e137&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10351546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan KS, Venketasubramanian N. Stroke burden in Malaysia. Cerebrovasc Dis Extra. 2022;12:58&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9149343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donkor ES. Stroke in the 21st century: a snapshot of the burden, epidemiology, and quality of life. Stroke Res Treat. 2018;3238165:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30598741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>eClinicalMedicine. The rising global burden of stroke. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:102028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10225620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37256100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidetti S, Andersson K, Andersson M, Tham K, Von KL. Client-centred self-care intervention after stroke: A feasibility study. Scand J Occup Ther. 2010;17:276&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20187757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan A, Freeman J, Kent B, et al. Standing practice in rehabilitation early after stroke (SPIRES): a functional standing frame programme (prolonged standing and repeated sit to stand) to improve function and quality of life and reduce neuromuscular impairment in people with severe sub-acute stroke &#x2013; a protocol for a feasibility randomised controlled trial. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2018;4:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5865293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29588861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa DG, Harvey LA, Dorsch S, et al. Two weeks of intensive sit-to-stand training in addition to usual care improves sit-to-stand ability in people who are unable to stand up independently after stroke: a randomised trial. J Physiother. 2019;65:152&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31227279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyun SJ, Lee J, Lee BH. The effects of sit-to-stand training combined with real-time visual feedback on strength, balance, gait ability, and quality of life in patients with stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18 :12229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8625418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amala S, Chippala P. Effect of sit-to-stand training on balance, muscle strength, and activities of daily living in patients with stroke: a randomised controlled trial. J Clin Diagn Res. 2024;18:YC05&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock A, Gray C, Culham E, Durward BR, Langhorne P. Interventions for improving sit-to-stand ability following stroke. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014:1&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaovalit S, Taylor NF, Dodd KJ. Sit-to-stand exercise programs improve sit-to-stand performance in people with physical impairments due to health conditions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Disabil Rehabil. 2020;42:1202&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30668164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Morton NA. The PEDro scale is a valid measure of the methodological quality of clinical trials: a demographic study. Aust J Physiother. 2009;55:129&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19463084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik GM, Dila KAS, Mohamed MYF, et al. A step-by-step guide for conducting a systematic review and meta-analysis with simulation data. Trop Med Health. 2019;47:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Kim YM, Kang DY. Repetitive sit-to-stand training with the step-foot position on the non-paretic side, and its effects on the balance and foot pressure of chronic stroke subjects. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:2621&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4563328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26357448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mun BM, Lee YS, Kim TH, et al. Study on the usefulness of sit-to-stand training in self-directed treatment of stroke patients. J Phys Ther Sci. 2014;26:483&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3996404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24764616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton E, Harris N, Turton A. An exploratory randomized controlled trial of assisted practice for improving sit-to-stand in stroke patients in the hospital setting. Clin Rehabil. 2008;22:458&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18441042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joey NCM, Woo KHM. Does self-initiated sit-to-stand training with an assistive device regain the independence of sit-to-stand in stroke patients? A single-blinded randomized controlled trial. J Rehabil Assist Technol Eng. 2020;7:2055668319866053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6971965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farqalit R, Shahnawaz A. Effect of foot position during sit-to-stand training on balance and upright mobility in patients with chronic stroke. Hong Kong Physiother J. 2013;31:75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreca S, Sigouin CS, Lambert C, Ansley B. Effects of extra training on the ability of stroke survivors to perform an independent sit-to-stand: a randomized controlled trial. J Geriatric Phys Ther. 2004;27:59&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung FL, Yang YR, Lee CC, Wang RY. Balance outcomes after additional sit-to-stand training in subjects with stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2010;24:533&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Chen J, Fan W, et al. Effects of modified sit-to-stand training on balance control in hemiplegic stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2016;30 :627&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JE, Eng JJ. Strength training improves upper-limb function in individuals with stroke. Stroke. 2010;41:136&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19940277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winstein CJ, Stein J, Arena R, et al. Guidelines for adult stroke rehabilitation and recovery: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2016;47:e98&#x2013;e169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27145936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vive S, Z&#xfc;gner R, Tranberg R, Bunketorp-K&#xe4;ll L. Effects of enriched task-specific training on sit-to-stand tasks in individuals with chronic stroke. NeuroRehabilitation. 2024;54:297&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10977354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38160369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss A, Suzuki T, Bean J, Fielding RA. High-intensity strength training improves strength and functional performance after stroke. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2000;79:369&#x2013;76; quiz 391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10892623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SL, Dodd KJ, Morris ME. Outcomes of progressive resistance strength training following stroke: a systematic review. Clin Rehabil. 2004;18:27&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14763717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johar MN, Mohd Nordin NA, Mohd Yusoff YA. Effects of game-based task-oriented circuit training on physical functions of stroke survivors: a pilot study in a state hospital in Kelantan, Malaysia. Asian J Med Biomed. 2022;5:5&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johar MN, Mohd Nordin NA. Web-based game-focused exercise in the home setting as an alternative to hospital-based exercise for stroke survivors: a case study. Malaysian Physiother J. 2022;1:62&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pui Kei C, Mohd Nordin NA, Abdul Aziz AF. The effectiveness of home-based therapy on functional outcome, self-efficacy and anxiety among discharged stroke survivors. Medicine (Baltimore). 2020;99:e23296&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7676535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Nordin NA, Yusoff NAH, Singh DKA. Facilitating exercise engagement among community dwelling stroke survivors: is a once per week group session sufficient? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6926925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31783575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Nordin NA, Aziz NA, Sulong S, Aljunid SM. Effectiveness of home-based carer-assisted in comparison to hospital-based therapist-delivered therapy for people with stroke: a randomised controlled trial. NeuroRehabilitation. 2019;45:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31450518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyndman D, Ashburn A, Stack E. Fall events among people with stroke living in the community: circumstances of falls and characteristics of fallers. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;83:165&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11833018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Candan SA, Soysal Tomruk M, Yakasai AM, Truijen S, Saeys W. Constraint-induced movement therapy protocols using the number of repetitions of task practice: a systematic review of feasibility and effects. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:2695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33884528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birkenmeier RL, Prager EM, Lang CE. Translating animal doses of task-specific training to people with chronic stroke in 1-hour therapy sessions: a proof-of-concept study. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2010;24:620&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3235711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20424192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farver PF, Farver TB. Performance of normal older adults on tests designed to measure parietal lobe functions. Am J Occup Ther. 1982;36:444&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7114161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>