<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41666188</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigations of a new EPS-insulated mortar-free reusable interlocking block for sustainable buildings.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0342329</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0342329</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0342329</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0342329</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sustainable, energy-efficient, and reusable construction systems have increasingly been demanded due to the increasing amount of plastics, waste, demolition debris, and the carbon footprints associated with existing traditional materials used in the construction industry. In contribution to this, this study innovates a new enveloped insulated interlocking concrete block (IICB) made of recycled aggregate concrete (RAC) and expanded polystyrene (EPS), which can be shortened to EIICB. This innovation aims to maximize the potential of producing thermally insulated blocks at full scale, focusing on features such as portability, dry assembly, speedy execution, reusability, inventiveness, high compression, low absorption, and sustainability, which cannot be fully achieved by previous concrete blocks. Compared with conventional concrete blocks, the EIICB reduces concrete material usage and achieves an estimated 73.5% reduction in CO&#x2082; emissions. Experimental evaluation showed an average compressive strength of 7.91&#x2009;MPa, water absorption of 4.74%, and a calculated thermal R-value of 15.05, demonstrating improved thermal efficiency and compliance with structural requirements for non-load-bearing and light structural applications. This work has provided key benefits: transforming waste concrete into valuable materials for affordable and sustainable construction, providing energy-efficient solutions for modern construction, protecting the environment, and aligning with sustainable building practices. The results from this study show the EIICB's ability to promote the construction of low-cost, energy-efficient housing and indicate future opportunities for optimization, full-scale thermal validation, and life-cycle performance assessment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Gao et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5125-8528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karani</LastName><ForeName>Moses Mwenda</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-5988-7359</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zhongwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011137">Polystyrenes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>142M471B3J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002245">Carbon Dioxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Construction Materials</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011137" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polystyrenes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059027" MajorTopicYN="Y">Recycling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019245" MajorTopicYN="N">Compressive Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002245" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon Dioxide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest associated with this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41666188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12890158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0342329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-54505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li C, Pradhan P, Chen G, Kropp JP, Schellnhuber HJ. Carbon footprint of the construction sector is projected to double by 2050 globally. Commun Earth Environ. 2025;6(1):831. doi: 10.1038/s43247-025-02840-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43247-025-02840-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12559003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41163641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer R, Jambeck JR, Law KL. Production, use, and fate of all plastics ever made. Sci Adv. 2017;3(7):e1700782. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.1700782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.1700782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5517107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28776036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomponi F, Moncaster A. Embodied carbon mitigation and reduction in the built environment - What does the evidence say? J Environ Manage. 2016;181:687&#x2013;700. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2016.08.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2016.08.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marten B, Hicks A. Expanded polystyrene life cycle analysis literature review: an analysis for different disposal scenarios. Sustain: J Rec. 2018;11(1):29&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1089/sus.2017.0015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/sus.2017.0015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadrack Chukwuebuka U, Chizoba May O. A mini-review on expanded polystyrene waste recycling and its applications. World J Adv Eng Technol Sci. 2023;8(1):315&#x2013;29. doi: 10.30574/wjaets.2023.8.1.0057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjaets.2023.8.1.0057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimpour H, Amini AB, Sharifi F, Fahmi A, Zinatloo-Ajabshir S. Facile fabrication of next-generation sustainable brick and mortar through geopolymerization of construction debris. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):10914. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-61688-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-61688-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38740821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan R, Jambunathan L, Rajendran A. Effect of EPS concrete: &#x201c;structural performance and environmental impact on pollution control: an assessment of expanded polystyrene (EPS) concrete for sustainable construction&#x201d;. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2025;32(31):18919&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1007/s11356-025-36785-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-025-36785-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40760239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duraiswamy S, Neelamegam P, VishnuPriyan M, Alaneme GU. Impact of plastic waste fiber and treated construction demolition waste on the durability and sustainability of concrete. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):27221. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-78107-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-78107-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11549314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39516229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder P, Dewick P, Kusi-Sarpong S, Hofstetter JS. Circular economy and power relations in global value chains: Tensions and trade-offs for lower income countries. Resour Conserv Recycl. 2018;136:77&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2018.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2018.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kylili A, Fokaides PA. Policy trends for the sustainability assessment of construction materials: a review. Sustain Cities Soc. 2017;35:280&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2017.08.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2017.08.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinatloo-Ajabshir S, Morassaei MS, Salavati-Niasari M. Eco-friendly synthesis of Nd2Sn2O7&#x2013;based nanostructure materials using grape juice as green fuel as photocatalyst for the degradation of erythrosine. Composites Part B: Eng. 2019;167:643&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.03.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.03.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinatloo-Ajabshir S, Rakhshani S, Mehrabadi Z, Farsadrooh M, Feizi-Dehnayebi M, Rakhshani S, et al. Novel rod-like [Cu(phen)2(OAc)]&#xb7;PF6 complex for high-performance visible-light-driven photocatalytic degradation of hazardous organic dyes: DFT approach, Hirshfeld and fingerprint plot analysis. J Environ Manage. 2024;350:119545. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.119545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.119545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37995482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Ye X, Cui H. Recycled materials in construction: trends, status, and future of research. Sustainability. 2025;17(6):2636. doi: 10.3390/su17062636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17062636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manu BA. Innovative construction materials: advancing sustainability, durability, efficiency, and cost-effectiveness in modern infrastructure. Int J Res Publ Rev. 2024;5(12):4987&#x2013;99. doi: 10.55248/gengpi.5.1224.0215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55248/gengpi.5.1224.0215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Hu Y, Wang R, Li X, Chen Z, Hua J, et al. Green building practices to integrate renewable energy in the construction sector: a review. Environ Chem Lett. 2023;22(2):751&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1007/s10311-023-01675-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-023-01675-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Huang L, Hua J, Chen Z, Wei L, Osman AI, et al. Green construction for low-carbon cities: a review. Environ Chem Lett. 2023;21(3):1627&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1007/s10311-022-01544-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-022-01544-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips J. Climate change and surface mining: a review of environment-human interactions &amp; their spatial dynamics. Appl Geogr. 2016;74:95&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1016/j.apgeog.2016.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeog.2016.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoon P, Hoon K, Sik Y. A study on the utilization strategy of mining company housing focusing on the company housing in Yangj. J Multimed Serv Converg Art Humanit Soc Sci. 2018;8(6):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saenz S, Walschburger T, Gonz&#xe1;lez JC, Leo J, McKenney B, Kiesecker J. Development by design in Colombia: Making mitigation decisions consistent with conservation outcomes. Mitig Conserv Outcomes Colomb. 2013;8(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3855343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24339972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AF. Comparative study of traditional and modern building techniques in Siwa Oasis, Egypt: Case study: Affordable residential building using appropriate building technique. Case Stud Construc Mater. 2020;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;lmaz MC, Aswad A, Mercimek &#xd6;. An experimental study on innovative concrete block solutions for reconstruction. Buildings. 2023;13(10):2667. doi: 10.3390/buildings13102667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13102667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh SJ, Lokeshwaran N. Experimental investigation on behavior of shear wall assembled with interlocking concrete block. Int J Civ Eng Technol. 2017;8(3):111&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorji S, Derakhshan H, Thambiratnam DP, Zahra T, Mohyeddin A. Behaviour and material properties of versaloc semi-interlocking mortarless masonry. Mater Struct. 2023;56(1). doi: 10.1617/s11527-023-02102-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-023-02102-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan S, Sivalingam I, Rafiudeen MR. Development of interlocking lightweight cement blocks. 2013. Available from: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/281653059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haener. Two piece interlocking block. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Gultom RJ, Chouw N. Capacity of innovative interlocking blocks under monotonic loading. Constr Build Mater. 2012;37:812&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Liu Y, Yang Y, Li Y, Bai M. Bonding performance of 3D printing concrete with self-locking interfaces exposed to compression&#x2013;shear and compression&#x2013;splitting stresses. Addit Manuf. 2021;42:101992. doi: 10.1016/j.addma.2021.101992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addma.2021.101992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taleb HM, AlShuhail K. Thermal performance of insulated concrete block in Sharjah, United Arab Emirates (UAE): continuous monitoring and IR assessment. J Asian Arch Build Eng. 2020;20(1):61&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1080/13467581.2020.1781646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13467581.2020.1781646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Awsh WA, Baghabra Al-Amoudi OS, Al-Osta MA, Ahmad A, Saleh TA. Experimental assessment of the thermal and mechanical performance of insulated concrete blocks. J Clean Prod. 2021;283:124624. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun Kumar B, Ashesh N. Construction using EPS Technology. Int J Adv Res Sci Commun Technol. 2022;:648&#x2013;74. doi: 10.48175/ijarsct-5618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48175/ijarsct-5618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang W, Huang D, Qiang X, Liu W. Preparation of hydrophilic and fire-resistant phytic acid/chitosan/polydopamine-coated expanded polystyrene particles by using coating method. Coatings. 2024;14(5):574. doi: 10.3390/coatings14050574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings14050574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramli Sulong NH, Mustapa SAS, Abdul Rashid MK. Application of expanded polystyrene (EPS) in buildings and constructions: a review. J Appl Polymer Sci. 2019;136(20). doi: 10.1002/app.47529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.47529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrary BH, Kavanaugh SP, Williamson DG. Environmental impacts of surface water heat pump systems. ASHRAE Trans. 2006;112(1):102&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimpour H, Fahmi A, Zinatloo-Ajabshir S. Toward sustainable soda ash production: a critical review on eco-impacts, modifications, and innovative approaches. Results Eng. 2024;23:102399. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanafi MR, Rahimpour H, Zinatloo-Ajabshir S, Moodi F, Fahmi A. Performance enhancement, life cycle assessment, and feature analysis of wheat starch-based NaCl-binder as a sustainable alternative to OPC mortar. Results in Eng. 2024;24:103281. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2024.103281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2024.103281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raja T. Innovative lightweight materials using sugarcane ash and neem fiber epoxy matrix composite for sustainable applications. Results Eng. 2025;25:103720. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2024.103720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2024.103720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahmi A, Zavaragh SR, Hanafi MR, Rahimpour H, Zinatloo-Ajabshir S, Asghari A. Facile preparation, characterization, and investigation of mechanical strength of Starchy NaCl-binder as a lightweight construction material. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):19042. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-46536-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46536-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10624871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37923911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Pan W, Zhang P, Zhang Z, Wang Z, Su D, et al. Characterization and performance evaluation of lightweight thermal insulation recycled concrete. Discov Appl Sci. 2024;6(6). doi: 10.1007/s42452-024-05938-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-024-05938-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Zhang Z, Li P, Zhou Y, Chen C. Study of physical mechanical characteristics, economic viability, and carbon emission impacts of recycled aggregate. Curr Anal Chem. 2025;21(8):1090&#x2013;104. doi: 10.2174/0115734110327991240925112522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0115734110327991240925112522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xf5;es Y, Felipi PF, Fernandes D, Castro LA, Neto JM. Experimental and numerical analysis of the thermal and mechanical behaviour of steel and recycled aggregate concrete composite elements exposed to fire. Fire Mater. 2022;47(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlu T, Fortova K, Divis J, Hajek P. The utilization of recycled masonry aggregate and recycled eps for concrete blocks for mortarless masonry. Mater. 2019;12(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6630574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Yu-Yin W, Wang Q, Geng Y. Experimental study and prediction model for non-uniform shrinkage of recycled aggregate concrete in composite slabs. Constr Build Mater. 2022;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard test methods for sampling and testing concrete masonry units and related units. ASTM C140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard test method for compressive strength of cylindrical concrete specimens 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard specification for rigid, cellular polystyrene thermal insulation 1. Available from: www.astm.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ols&#xf8; BG, Hauk&#xf8; A-M, Risholt B. Experimental study of fire exposed expanded polystyrene (EPS) insulation protected by selected coverings. Heliyon. 2024;10(4):e26309. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10884846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38404805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzawi R. Green Construction And Sustainability Using Modified Expanded Polystyrene (EPS) Insulation. In: 2023 9th International Engineering Conference on Sustainable Technology and Development (IEC). IEEE; 2023. pp. 1&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1109/iec57380.2023.10438799</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iec57380.2023.10438799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayed R, Baddadi S, Dellagi A, Bouadila S, Lazaar M. Thermal behavior improvement of building materials using expanded polystyrene. In: 2022 13th International Renewable Energy Congress (IREC). IEEE; 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1109/irec56325.2022.10002016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/irec56325.2022.10002016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shendy M, Alkhader M, Abu-Nabah BA. Stress Concentration Induced by Synnergisticaly Interacting Geometric Discontinuites. In: 2022 Advances in Science and Engineering Technology International Conferences (ASET). IEEE; 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1109/aset53988.2022.9735055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/aset53988.2022.9735055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohmuller P, Favre J, Piotrowski B, Kenzari S, Laheurte P. Stress concentration and mechanical strength of cubic lattice architectures. Materials (Basel). 2018;11(7):1146. doi: 10.3390/ma11071146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma11071146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29976908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tralli A, Chiozzi A, Grillanda N, Milani G. On Unilateral Contact Between Rigid Masonry Blocks. 2020. pp. 1910&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-41057-5_153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-41057-5_153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maekawa K, Qureshi J. Stress transfer across interfaces in reinforced concrete due to aggregate interlock and dowel action. Doboku Gakkai Ronbunshu. 1997;1997(557):159&#x2013;72. doi: 10.2208/jscej.1997.557_159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2208/jscej.1997.557_159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira LMF, Corr&#xea;a MRS. Numerical and experimental analysis of the shear capacity of interconnected concrete block walls. Ambient constr. 2017;17(3):25&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1590/s1678-86212017000300160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s1678-86212017000300160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi T, Zhang X, Hao H, Xie G. Influences of random imperfection distribution on the compressive properties of interlocking block wall. Structures. 2023;56:104875. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2023.104875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.104875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen GB, Zhang H, Rasmussen KJR, Fan F. Modelling geometric imperfections of spatial latticed structures considering correlations of node imperfections. Appl Mech Mater. 2014;553:576&#x2013;81. doi: 10.4028/www.scientific.net/amm.553.576</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/amm.553.576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiee NA, Jaafar MS, Alwathaf AH, Noorzaei J, Abdulkadir MR. Structural behavior of mortarless interlocking load bearing hollow block wall panel under out-of-plane loading. Adv Struct Eng. 2011;14(6):1185&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1260/1369-4332.14.6.1185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/1369-4332.14.6.1185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie G, Zhang X, Hao H, Bi K, Lin Y. Response of reinforced mortar-less interlocking brick wall under seismic loading. Bull Earthquake Eng. 2022;20(11):6129&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1007/s10518-022-01436-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-022-01436-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiee NA, Jaafar MS, Noorzaei J. Behavior of mortarless wall subjected to in-plane combine loading. Adv Mater Res. 2011;264&#x2013;265:1746&#x2013;51. doi: 10.4028/www.scientific.net/amr.264-265.1746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/amr.264-265.1746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specification for nonloadbearing concrete masonry units. West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International. doi: 10.1520/C0129-22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/C0129-22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specification for loadbearing concrete masonry units. West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International; 2016. doi: 10.1520/C0090-16A</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/C0090-16A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M. Construction thermal insulation building block and method for producing the same. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed MI, Zafar A, Alturki R, Khan MI. Optimization and performance of expanded polystyrene concrete for sustainable infill wall construction using response surface methodology. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):21032. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-07705-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-07705-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12216788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40596473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2021 International Energy Conservation Code (IECC). 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wang X, Ren P, Yang L. Multi-indicator environmental impact assessment of recycled aggregate concrete based on life cycle analysis. Buildings. 2025;15(13):2301. doi: 10.3390/buildings15132301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15132301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertwich EG. Increased carbon footprint of materials production driven by rise in investments. Nat Geosci. 2021;14(3):151&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1038/s41561-021-00690-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41561-021-00690-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W-T, Long Y-L, Huang J, Lin Y. Axial load behavior of structural bamboo filled with concrete and cement mortar. Construction and Building Materials. 2017;148:273&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.05.061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.05.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Sharghi HJ. The Potential of recycling and reusing waste materials in underground construction: A review of sustainable practices and challenges. Sustainability. 2024;16(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi T, Zhang X, Hao H, Chen C. Experimental and numerical investigation on the compressive properties of interlocking blocks. Eng Struct. 2021;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramamurthy K, Kunhanandan Nambiar EK. Accelerated masonry construction review and future prospects. Progress Structural Eng Maths. 2004;6(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1002/pse.162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pse.162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez M, Atamturktur S, Ross B, Thompson J. Assessing the compressive behavior of dry-stacked concrete masonry with experimentally informed numerical models. J Struct Eng. 2018;144(7). doi: 10.1061/(asce)st.1943-541x.0002056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)st.1943-541x.0002056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magrini A, Marenco L, Leoni V, Gamba R. Air cavity building walls: a discussion on the opportunity of filling insulation to support energy performance improvement strategies. Energies. 2022;15(23):8916. doi: 10.3390/en15238916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15238916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaker G, Doshi S. Comparative analysis between ordinary brick masonry and cavity wall. Int J Eng Dev Res. 2016;4(2):282&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summa S, Remia G, Di Perna C, Stazi F. Experimental and numerical study on a new thermal masonry block by comparison with traditional walls. Energy Build. 2023;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue H, Zhang S, Su Y, Wu Z. Capital cost optimization for prefabrication: a factor analysis evaluation model. Sustainability. 2018;10(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jabri KS, Hago AW, Al-Nuaimi AS, Al-Saidy AH. Concrete blocks for thermal insulation in hot climate. Cement Concrete Res. 2005;35(8):1472&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.08.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.08.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Fang G, Liang Z, Li G, Yan T. Design of new green self-insulation block and experimental study on mechanical and thermal properties. Advances in Frontier Research on Engineering Structures. Volume 1. London: CRC Press; 2023. pp. 15&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1201/9781003336631-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781003336631-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown SBWE. Building blocks, and walls comprising building blocks. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpe S, Sangiorgio V, Petrella A, Coppola A, Notarnicola M, Fiorito F. Building Envelope Prefabricated with 3D Printing Technology. Sustainability. 2021;13(16):8923. doi: 10.3390/su13168923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13168923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZM, Kwong KZ, Lee FW, Lim JH. Conceptual design of interlocking block utilizing lightweight expanded polystyrene concrete reinforced with kenaf fiber. E3S Web Conf. 2022;347:02014. doi: 10.1051/e3sconf/202234702014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202234702014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Salloum YA, Morsy MS, Almusallam TH, Abbas H. Interlocking and insulated construction blocks. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro JD. Insulated interlocking superblocks for constructing and supporting structural elements of a building. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaomin L, Biao L, Sigang C, Xianwu L. Building interlocking block and used insulating mortar thereof. 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>