<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41835749</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preliminary Evaluation of Dominant Hand Mimicry Versus Traditional Grip Training for Non-dominant Hand Chopstick Use: A Single-Case Design.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103375</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103375</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103375</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103375</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Many patients with stroke lose functional use of their hands, highlighting the importance of non-dominant hand training as a compensatory strategy in rehabilitation. Chopstick manipulation training is commonly practiced in East Asia; however, it remains unclear whether a traditional grip or a dominant hand-like grip is more effective for training the non-dominant hand.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten right-handed students (five Japanese, five Chinese; eight males, two females; aged 20-26 years) participated in this study. Participants trained with their non-dominant hand for 15 minutes per day over 10 days using an alternating treatments design (ATD), while viewing instructional videos and concurrently practicing chopstick tip alignment exercises with either the traditional grip (Intervention A) or a dominant hand-like grip (Intervention B). Outcomes included the number of bean transfers within two minutes, chopstick tip traction strength, grip style (Yokubo classification), and subjective sense of accomplishment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All 10 participants completed the training with no dropouts. Analysis indicated weak to strong effects of Intervention B on bean transfers (three of five Chinese and all five Japanese) and chopstick tip traction force (three of five Chinese and four of five Japanese). After Intervention A, all participants adopted the "Four Finger" grip, with subjective achievement generally moderate to high. After Intervention B, both groups shifted toward "Three Finger" or "Other" grips, with subjective achievement remaining medium to high.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Grip style plays a critical role in non-dominant hand training. For some tasks, adopting a grip similar to the dominant hand may enhance functional performance and offer practical benefits for stroke rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Fu et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Yuwen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Motor Function Science, Graduate School of Rehabilitation, Niigata University of Rehabilitation, Murakami, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choji</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Allied Health Science, Niigata University of Rehabilitation, Murakami, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chopstick use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dominant hand-mimicking training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fine motor skills</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-dominant hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single-case design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traditional training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ethics Review Committee of Niigata Rehabilitation University issued approval 262. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41835749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12981968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global, regional, and national burden of stroke and its risk factors, 1990-2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. GBD 2019 Stroke Collaborators. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20:795&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34487721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interpretation on the report of global stroke data 2022. Tang CH, Guo L, Li Q, Zhang L. https://www.qk.sjtu.edu.cn/jdcp/EN/10.16150/j.1671-2870.2023.03.06 J Diagn Concepts Pract. 2023;22:238&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arm function after stroke: measurement and recovery over the first three months. Heller A, Wade DT, Wood VA, Sunderland A, Hewer RL, Ward E. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1987;50:714&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1032076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3612152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The hemiplegic arm after stroke: measurement and recovery. Wade DT, Langton-Hewer R, Wood VA, Skilbeck CE, Ismail HM. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1983;46:521&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1027442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6875585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arm function after stroke. An evaluation of grip strength as a measure of recovery and a prognostic indicator. Sunderland A, Tinson D, Bradley L, Hewer RL. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1989;52:1267&#x2013;1272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1031635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2592969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of shape and operation of chopsticks on food-serving performance. Chen YL. Appl Ergon. 1998;29:233&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9701536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pincer chopsticks: the investigation of a new utensil in pinching function. Chang BC, Huang BS, Chen CK, Wang SJ. Appl Ergon. 2007;38:385&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An auxiliary device for chopsticks operation to improve the food-serving performance. Lee YC, Chen YL. Appl Ergon. 2008;39:737&#x2013;742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18177839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What is the significance of the traditional pinching mode of holding chopsticks? Shimomura Y, Ohsawa T, Shimura M, Xia Y, Iwanaga K, Katsuura T. J Physiol Anthropol. 2020;39:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32366321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An investigation for determining the optimum length of chopsticks. Hsu SH, Wu SP. Appl Ergon. 1991;22:395&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15676839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mode of grasp, materials, and grooved chopstick tip on gripping performance and evaluation. Ho CP, Wu SP. Percept Mot Skills. 2006;102:93&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16671604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukai Y, Hashimoto K. Tokyo: Hosei University Press; 2001. Cultural History of Things and Humans 102: Chopsticks [Book in Japanese]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isshiki H. Ochanomizu Shobo, Tokyo. Tokyo: Ochanomizu Shobo; 1990. A Cultural History of Chopsticks [Book in Japanese]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcosticks: classification of chopstick grips.  [
Aug;
2024 
]. 2020. https://marcosticks.org/classification-of-chopstick-grips https://marcosticks.org/classification-of-chopstick-grips</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handwriting kinematics during learning to write with the dominant left hand in converted left-handers. Stetter L, Sattler JB, Marquardt C, Hermsd&#xf6;rfer J. Sci Rep. 2023;13:2171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9905490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A literature review on chopstick trainings with non-dominant hand [Article in Japanese] Choji Y, Kadohata T, Yoshihara Y, Watanabe M, Kobayashi R. https://jglobal.jst.go.jp/detail?JGLOBAL_ID=202002230519384995 Jpn J Clin Occup Ther. 2019;6:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relationship between operating patterns of each hand in using chopsticks for normal right hand subjects: with special reference to treatment plan for changing the dominant hand [Article in Japanese] Yamada K, Shimizu H, Yamada H. https://webview.isho.jp/journal/detail/abs/10.11477/mf.6003900312 Occup Ther. 1995;14:128&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining empirically supported therapies. Chambless DL, Hollon SD. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1998;66:7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9489259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The assessment and analysis of handedness: the Edinburgh inventory. Oldfield RC. Neuropsychologia. 1971;9:97&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5146491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What Works Clearinghouse: What Works Clearinghouse procedures and standards handbook, version 5.0.  [
Sep;
2025 
]. 2022. https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/Docs/referenceresources/Final_WWC-HandbookVer5.0-0-508.pdf https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/Docs/referenceresources/Final_WWC-HandbookVer5.0-0-508.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in chopstick-handling speed through chopstick-use training (interim report) [Article in Japanese] Takagi A, Yamamoto Y, Sato T, et al.  https://mol.medicalonline.jp/journal/abstract?GoodsID=dr0aomot/1992/000101/005&amp;name=0009-0013j Aomori J Occup Ther Res. 1992;1:9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Networks associated with short-term motor learning of chopstick-use with the non-dominant hand in order adults [Article in Japanese] Takeda S, Miyamoto R. Jpn J Clin Neurophysiol. 2024;52:85&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between chopstick manipulation and cross-sectional shape in the developmental stages from infancy to early school age. Yokubo YK, Ota T, Shibata K. Appl Ergon. 2021;97:103507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34214755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford JR, Gast DL. London: Routledge; 2010. Single Subject Research Methodology in Behavioral Sciences: Applications in Special Education and Behavioral Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analyzing data from single-case alternating treatments designs. Manolov R, Onghena P. Psychol Methods. 2018;23:480&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28301199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PND at 25: past, present, and future trends in summarizing single-subject research. Scruggs TE, Mastropieri MA. https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0741932512440730 Remedial Spec Educ. 2013;34:9&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manolov R. Data analysis techniques for alternating treatment designs.  [
Jul;
2025 
]. 2018. https://manolov.shinyapps.io/ATDesign/ https://manolov.shinyapps.io/ATDesign/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of the self-help chopsticks (Hashizo-kun) - using the rank Rn test and the narrow KJ method [Article in Japanese] Choji Y, Kadohata T, Yoshihara Y. https://webview.isho.jp/journal/detail/abs/10.11477/mf.5001201761 Occup Ther J. 2019;53:691&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of manipulation on different chopstick materials to age and gender of school-aged children. Yang B, Song B, Han M. Indian J Public Health Res Dev. 2018;9:560&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>