<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41883900</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mapping the Evidence on Abdominal Weight Training for Respiratory Muscle Strength: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104028</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104028</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104028</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104028</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This scoping review synthesized evidence on abdominal weight training (AWT), a non-invasive method for respiratory muscle rehabilitation that increases diaphragmatic load, to evaluate its clinical significance. We specifically summarized its effects on respiratory muscle strength, measured by maximal inspiratory pressure (MIP) and maximal expiratory pressure (MEP), diaphragmatic function, and patient outcomes, including ventilator weaning. A systematic search of MEDLINE, CENTRAL, and Web of Science databases conducted on March 13, 2025, identified five studies meeting the inclusion criteria: one randomized trial, two comparative trials, one crossover trial, and one experimental study. Participants included patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation or chronic respiratory failure as well as healthy adults. The findings indicated that AWT is associated with improved MIP and MEP and enhanced diaphragmatic function in patients with compromised respiratory health. Furthermore, clinical benefits such as improved ventilator weaning rates have been reported, with evidence suggesting that AWT can effectively retrain diaphragmatic breathing patterns. Although AWT appears to be a promising intervention for improving respiratory muscle strength and function in specific populations, the limited number of studies and heterogeneous protocols underscore the need for well-designed trials to standardize training regimens and confirm clinical efficacy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Matsuda et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuda</LastName><ForeName>Keita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation, Kawasaki University of Medical Welfare, Kurashiki, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Hiroki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation, Kawasaki University of Medical Welfare, Kurashiki, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikeda</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Okayama University Hospital, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katayama</LastName><ForeName>Syo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Okayama University Hospital, Okayama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal weight training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breathing exercises</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diaphragm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scoping review &#x2003;</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41883900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13010238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The use of respiratory muscle training in patients with pulmonary dysfunction, internal diseases or central nervous system disorders: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Cacciante L, Turolla A, Pregnolato G, Federico S, Baldan F, Rutkowska A, Rutkowski S. Qual Life Res. 2023;32:1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35460472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of respiratory muscle training on performance in athletes. HajGhanbari B, Yamabayashi C, Buna TR, et al. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:1643&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22836606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle training in weaning from prolonged mechanical ventilation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Andrade-Rebolledo FA, Villagra-Morales G, P&#xe9;rez LA. Front Med (Lausanne) 2025;12:1719837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12835378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41608455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Respiratory muscle rehabilitation in patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation: a targeted approach. Bissett B, Gosselink R, van Haren FM. Crit Care. 2020;24:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32204719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of inspiratory muscle training in critically ill adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Farley C, Oliveira A, Brooks D, Newman AN. J Intensive Care Med. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39924923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle rehabilitation in critically ill adults. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Vorona S, Sabatini U, Al-Maqbali S, et al. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2018;15:735&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29584447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of abdominal weight training with and without cough machine assistance on lung function in the patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation: a randomized trial. Hung TY, Wu WL, Kuo HC, et al. Crit Care. 2022;26:153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current status and problems of respiratory muscle training in Japan | CiNii Research. Takako Tanaka, Ryo Kozu. https://cir.nii.ac.jp/crid/1390282763127917056 Journal of the Japan Society for Respiratory Care and Rehabilitation. 2019;28:79&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of abdominal sandbag training in enhancing diaphragm muscle function and exercise tolerance in patients with chronic respiratory failure. Lin TK, Chen MY, Cheng HH, Chow J, Chen CM, Chou W. J Formos Med Assoc. 2024;123:1087&#x2013;1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38302365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Godfrey C, McInerney P, Munn Z, Tricco AC, Khalil H. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. Joanna Briggs Institute; 2020. Scoping reviews.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. BMJ. 2011;343:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. BMJ. 2016;355:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moola S, Munn Z, Tufunaru C, et al. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. Joanna Briggs Institute; 2024. Systematic reviews of aetiology and risk.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study of diaphragmatic muscle function during abdominal weight in normal subjects. Monteiro SG, Pessolano FA, Su&#xe1;rez AA, De Vito EL. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22522848/ Medicina (B Aires) 2012;72:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22522848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdominal weight and inspiratory resistance: their immediate effects on inspiratory muscle functions during maximal voluntary breathing in chronic tetraplegic patients. Lin K-H, Chuang C-C, Wu H-D, Chang C-W, Kou YR. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1999;80:741&#x2013;745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10414755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle function following abdominal weight exercises in healthy subjects. Merrick J, Axen K. Phys Ther. 1981;61:651&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7232502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contraction of the abdominal muscles associated with movement of the lower limb. Hodges PW, Richardson CA. Phys Ther. 1997;77:132&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9037214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postural function of the diaphragm in persons with and without chronic low back pain. Kolar P, Sulc J, Kyncl M, et al. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42:352&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22236541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Troyer A, Boriek AM. Comprehensive Physiology. Wiley; 2011. Mechanics of the respiratory muscles; pp. 1273&#x2013;1300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postural-respiratory function of the diaphragm assessed by M-mode ultrasonography. Sembera M, Busch A, Kobesova A, Hanychova B, Sulc J, Kolar P. PLoS One. 2022;17:275389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9550028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in intra-abdominal pressure during postural and respiratory activation of the human diaphragm. Hodges PW, Gandevia SC. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:967&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of diaphragm breathing exercise and feedback breathing exercise on pulmonary function in healthy adults. Yong MS, Lee HY, Lee YS. J Phys Ther Sci. 2017;29:85&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5300812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28210046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle training during pulmonary rehabilitation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Beaumont M, Mialon P, Ber-Moy C Le, et al. Chron Respir Dis. 2015;12:305&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26170421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromuscular ultrasound for evaluation of the diaphragm. Sarwal A, Walker FO, Cartwright MS. Muscle Nerve. 2013;47:319&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>