<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796752</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8304</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>222</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Appetite</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appetite</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Estimating the UK population prevalence of eating in response to exercise, and exploring what factors are associated with eating in response to exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108534</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.appet.2026.108534</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0195-6663(26)00096-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Some individuals consume food before or after exercise to compensate for energy expended. If this behaviour is prevalent, it could have implications for population-level health. We estimated the prevalence of eating in response to exercise (before and after exercise) and explored associated factors using an online questionnaire. A nationally representative sample of UK adults engaging in weekly exercise (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;1054) reported how their eating behaviours (portion size, frequency, perceived healthiness) change on exercise days compared to non-exercise days. Other measures included demographics (e.g., sex, dieting status), exercise characteristics (frequency, intensity, duration, mode), exercise motivation and enjoyment, the Three-Factor Eating Questionnaire (dietary restraint and disinhibition), and the Diet-Related Beliefs of Exercisers Scale (DBES) (sub-scales: food as reward, nutritional replenishment, healthy eating and refrain from eating). Associations with eating in response to exercise were examined using multiple logistic regression. Eating in response to exercise was reported by 24% (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;251) of the sample, and occurred most often after exercise (17%, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;178). The DBES food as reward sub-scale (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;2.26, 95% CI 1.91, 2.67) and the DBES nutritional replenishment sub-scale (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.42, 95% 1.13, 1.79) were strongly and positively associated with eating in response to exercise. Internal motivation for exercise (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.53, 95% CI 1.21, 1.93), strength training (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.74, 95% CI 1.28, 2.36), and disinhibition (OR&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.12, 95% CI 1.07, 1.17) were also positively associated with eating in response to exercise. We conclude that nearly a quarter of regular exercisers report consuming more food on exercise days and that reducing this behaviour has the potential to improve population-level health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salton</LastName><ForeName>Jody</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Bristol Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust and University of Bristol, UK; Nutrition and Behaviour Unit, School of Psychological Science, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. Electronic address: jody.salton@bristol.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porter</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Bristol Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust and University of Bristol, UK; Population Health Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, UK. Electronic address: alice.porter@bristol.ac.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jago</LastName><ForeName>Russell</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Bristol Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust and University of Bristol, UK; Population Health Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, UK. Electronic address: russ.jago@bristol.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brunstrom</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Bristol Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust and University of Bristol, UK; Nutrition and Behaviour Unit, School of Psychological Science, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. Electronic address: jeff.brunstrom@bristol.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferriday</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Bristol Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust and University of Bristol, UK; Nutrition and Behaviour Unit, School of Psychological Science, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK. Electronic address: danielle.ferriday@bristol.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Appetite</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8006808</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-6663</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compensatory eating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eating behaviours</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Licensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Online survey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Portion size</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Snacking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest related to this research.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2026.108534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0195-6663(26)00096-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>