<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41178988</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of different types of core training on pain and functional status in patients with chronic nonspecific low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1672010</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1672010</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1672010</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1672010</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chronic non-specific low back pain (CNSLBP) represents a leading cause of global disability, with core training emerging as a promising non-pharmacological intervention. However, the comparative effectiveness of different core training modalities remains unclear. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to comprehensively compare the differential effects of three core training approaches-Pilates training, core stability training, and core resistance training-on pain intensity, functional status, and quality of life in adults with CNSLBP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A comprehensive systematic search was conducted across four electronic databases (Web of Science, PubMed, Cochrane Library, and Scopus) from inception to May 2025, following PRISMA guidelines. We included randomized controlled trials comparing Pilates training, core stability training, or core resistance training with control conditions in adults aged 18-65 years with CNSLBP &#x2265;12 weeks. Primary outcomes included pain intensity (assessed using Visual Analog Scale [VAS] or Numerical Rating Scale [NRS]) and functional disability (measured by Oswestry Disability Index [ODI] or Roland-Morris Disability Questionnaire [RMDQ]). Secondary outcomes encompassed quality of life measures (SF-36). Risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2.0 tool. Random-effects meta-analysis was performed, with standardized mean differences (SMD) calculated for effect sizes. Meta-regression analysis was conducted to identify optimal training parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 57 randomized controlled trials involving 7,705 participants were included. All three core training modalities demonstrated significant improvements in pain relief compared to controls (SMD = 0.70; 95% CI: 0.58-0.82; p &lt; 0.00001; I<sup>2</sup> = 47%). Subgroup analysis revealed differential effects: Pilates training showed optimal pain relief effects (SMD = 0.75; 95% CI: 0.58-0.92), followed by core resistance training (SMD = 0.68; 95% CI: 0.56-0.80) and core stability training (SMD = 0.53; 95% CI: 0.34-0.73). For functional status improvement, core resistance training demonstrated the most significant and stable effects (SMD = 0.76; 95% CI: 0.55-0.97; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), while Pilates training (SMD = 0.71; 95% CI: 0.13-1.56) and core stability training (SMD = 0.52; 95% CI: 0.33-0.70; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%) showed moderate improvements. Although the effect sizes for Pilates, core stability training, and core resistance training showed numerical differences, the statistical comparison did not reach significance (P = 0.24) for improving pain and functional status. Meta-regression analysis identified optimal training parameters: core resistance training 3-4 sessions per week (30-45 min per session), Pilates training 2-3 sessions per week (50 min per session, 8-12 weeks duration), and core stability training 3-4 sessions per week (40-60 min per session, 6-8 weeks duration). Training frequency emerged as the strongest predictor of pain improvement in core resistance training (&#x3b2; = 0.48; p = 0.007). All three modalities showed limited effects on mental health components of quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study provides the first comprehensive evidence-based comparison of core training modalities for CNSLBP management. Pilates training demonstrates superior effectiveness for pain relief, while core resistance training shows optimal benefits for functional improvement. The identification of specific dose-response relationships and optimal training parameters offers precise clinical guidance for individualized exercise prescription. Core training represents a safe, effective, evidence-based non-pharmacological treatment approach, with clinical application requiring tailored selection based on patient-specific symptoms and treatment objectives. Future research should focus on long-term efficacy evaluation and development of personalized intervention protocols.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYSTEMATIC REVIEW REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PROSPERO CRD420251054431.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Guo, Lan, Ding, Tang and Yang.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Xu Bin</ForeName><Initials>XB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Physical Education, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Qiuxi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Yulin University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Junyi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Physical Education, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Physical Education, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Aviation Sports, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated sports medicine innovation hub for pilots, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aerospace Medicine, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Mingliang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Physical Education, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Aviation Sports, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated sports medicine innovation hub for pilots, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">core stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise movement techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41178988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12571568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1672010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1672010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Airaksinen O., Brox J. I., Cedraschi C., Hildebrandt J., Klaber&#x2010;Moffett J., Kovacs F., et al. (2006). Chapter 4. European guidelines for the management of chronic nonspecific low back pain. Eur. Spine J. 15 (2), 192&#x2013;300. 10.1007/s00586-006-1072-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00586-006-1072-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3454542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16550448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alp A., Mengi G., Avsaroglu A. H., Mert M., Sigirli D. (2014). Efficacy of core-stabilization exercise and its comparison with home-based conventional exercise in low back pain patients. Turk J. Phys. Med. Rehab. 10.5152/tftrd.2014.26817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/tftrd.2014.26817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqhtani R. S., Ahmed H., Ghulam H. S. H., Alyami A. M., Al Sharyah Y. H. H., et al. (2024). Efficacy of core-strengthening and intensive dynamic back exercises on pain, core muscle endurance, and functional disability in patients with chronic non-specific low back pain: a randomized comparative study. J. Clin. Med. 13, 475. 10.3390/jcm13020475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13020475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10816614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38256609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aluko A., DeSouza L., Peacock J. (2013). The effect of core stability exercises on variations in acceleration of trunk movement, pain, and disability during an episode of acute nonspecific low back pain: a pilot clinical trial. J. Manip. Physiological Ther. 36, 497&#x2013;504. 10.1016/j.jmpt.2012.12.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmpt.2012.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23948426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves M. C., De Souza Neto R. J., Barbosa R. I., Marcolino A. M., Kuriki H. U. (2020). Effects of a pilates protocol in individuals with non-specific low back pain compared with healthy individuals: clinical and electromyographic analysis. Clin. Biomech. 72, 172&#x2013;178. 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2019.12.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2019.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androulakis-Korakakis P., Fisher J. P., Steele J. (2020). The minimum effective training dose required to increase 1RM strength in resistance-trained men: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 50, 751&#x2013;765. 10.1007/s40279-019-01236-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01236-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31797219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aparecido Magalh&#xe3;es R., Gabriel Bertoletti J., Lu&#xed;sa Morais Amancio A., Borges da Cruz G., Delbim L., Martelli A. (2024). Effects of strength training program in the treatment of chronic non-specific low back pain. ISJHR 3, 34&#x2013;48. 10.56238/isevjhv3n1-006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56238/isevjhv3n1-006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa A. W. C., Guedes C. A., Bonif&#xe1;cio D. N., De F&#xe1;tima Silva A., Martins F. L. M., Almeida Barbosa M. C. S. (2015). The pilates breathing technique increases the electromyographic amplitude level of the deep abdominal muscles in untrained people. J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther. 19, 57&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.jbmt.2014.05.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2014.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behera S., Pattnaik G., Behera C. (2023). Chronic nonspecific low back pain: a diagnostic enigma. Int. J. Orthop. Sci. 9, 01&#x2013;07. 10.22271/ortho.2023.v9.i3a.3397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/ortho.2023.v9.i3a.3397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernier E., Driscoll M. (2023). Numerical investigation of intra-abdominal pressure and spinal load-sharing upon the application of an abdominal belt. J. Biomech. 161, 111863. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2023.111863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2023.111863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37977959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boguszewski D., St&#x119;pie&#x144; M., Adamczyk J. G. (2023). The influence of core stability exercises programme on the functional limitations of the musculoskeletal system in girls practising volleyball. Phys. Act. Rev. 11, 24&#x2013;30. 10.16926/par.2023.11.04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16926/par.2023.11.04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Carta G., Gambarotta G., Fornasari B. E., Muratori L., El Soury M., Geuna S., et al.  (2021). The neurodynamic treatment induces biological changes in sensory and motor neurons <i>in vitro</i>
. Sci. Rep.
11, 13277. 10.1038/s41598-021-92682-2

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-92682-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8225768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Nakagawa S. (2023). Physical activity for cognitive health promotion: an overview of the underlying neurobiological mechanisms. Ageing Res. Rev. 86, 101868. 10.1016/j.arr.2023.101868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2023.101868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36736379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortell-Tormo J. M., S&#xe1;nchez P. T., Chulvi-Medrano I., Tortosa-Mart&#xed;nez J., Manchado-L&#xf3;pez C., Llana-Belloch S., et al. (2018). Effects of functional resistance training on fitness and quality of life in females with chronic nonspecific low-back pain. J. Back Musculoskelet. Rehabilitation 31, 95&#x2013;105. 10.3233/BMR-169684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-169684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28826168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozacov R., Minerbi A., Haddad M., Vulfsons S. (2022). Differential sensitization of muscle versus fascia in individuals with low back pain. Bioengineering 9, 440. 10.3390/bioengineering9090440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering9090440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36134986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-D&#xed;az D., Bergamin M., Gobbo S., Mart&#xed;nez-Amat A., Hita-Contreras F. (2017). Comparative effects of 12 weeks of equipment based and mat pilates in patients with chronic low back pain on pain, function and transversus abdominis activation. A randomized controlled trial. Complementary Ther. Med. 33, 72&#x2013;77. 10.1016/j.ctim.2017.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2017.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-D&#xed;az D., Romeu M., Velasco-Gonz&#xe1;lez C., Mart&#xed;nez-Amat A., Hita-Contreras F. (2018). The effectiveness of 12 weeks of pilates intervention on disability, pain and kinesiophobia in patients with chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Clin. Rehabil. 10.1177/0269215518768393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215518768393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29651872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira C. T., Kanas M., Wajchenberg M. (2021). Treatment of non-specific chronic low back pain: resistance training with or without using weights? Rev. Bras. Med. Esporte 27, 603&#x2013;609. 10.1590/1517-8692202127062020_0121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-8692202127062020_0121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A., Casolo A., Negro F., Scorcelletti M., Bazzucchi I., Enoka R., et al. (2019). The increase in muscle force after 4 weeks of strength training is mediated by adaptations in motor unit recruitment and rate coding. J. Physiol. 597, 1873&#x2013;1887. 10.1113/JP277250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP277250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30727028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endleman I., Critchley D. J. (2008). Transversus abdominis and obliquus internus activity during pilates exercises: measurement with ultrasound scanning. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 89, 2205&#x2013;2212. 10.1016/j.apmr.2008.04.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2008.04.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18996251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farragher J. B., Pranata A., Williams G. P., El-Ansary D., Parry S. M., Clark R. A., et al. (2024). Neuromuscular control and resistance training for people with chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. J. Orthop. and Sports Phys. Ther. 54, 350&#x2013;359. 10.2519/jospt.2024.12349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2024.12349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38497906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez R., &#xc1;lvarez-Bueno C., Cavero-Redondo I., Torres-Costoso A., Pozuelo-Carrascosa D. P., Reina-Guti&#xe9;rrez S., et al. (2022). Best exercise options for reducing pain and disability in adults with chronic low back pain: pilates, strength, core-based, and mind-body. A network meta-analysis. J. Orthop. and Sports Phys. Ther. 10.2519/jospt.2022.10671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2022.10671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35722759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira M. L., De Luca K., Haile L. M., Steinmetz J. D., Culbreth G. T., Cross M., et al. (2023). Global, regional, and national burden of low back pain, 1990&#x2013;2020, its attributable risk factors, and projections to 2050: a systematic analysis of the global burden of disease study 2021. Lancet Rheumatol. 5, e316&#x2013;e329. 10.1016/S2665-9913(23)00098-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(23)00098-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10234592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37273833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana Carvalho A. P., Dufresne S. S., Rogerio De Oliveira M., Couto Furlanetto K., Dubois M., Dallaire M., et al. (2020). Effects of lumbar stabilization and muscular stretching on pain, disabilities, postural control and muscle activation in pregnant woman with low back pain. Eur. J. Phys. Rehabil. Med. 56, 297&#x2013;306. 10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06086-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06086-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32072792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French S., Cameron M., Clarke R., Esterman A., Reggars J., Walker B. (2004). Superficial heat or cold for low-back pain. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2006, CD004750. 10.1002/14651858.CD004750.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004750.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8846312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16437495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladwell V., Head S., Haggar M., Beneke R. (2006). Does a program of pilates improve chronic non-specific low back pain? J. Sport Rehabilitation 15, 338&#x2013;350. 10.1123/jsr.15.4.338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.15.4.338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes G. K., Franco C. M., Nunes P. R. P., Orsatti F. L. (2019). High-frequency resistance training is not more effective than low-frequency resistance training in increasing muscle mass and strength in well-trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res. 33, S130&#x2013;S139. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottschall J. S., Mills J., Hastings B. (2013). Integration core exercises elicit greater muscle activation than isolation exercises. J. Strength Cond. Res. 27, 590&#x2013;596. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2cc7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2cc7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22580983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X. B., Tang L. (2024). Effects of different exercise types on balance function in healthy older adults and parkinson&#x2019;s patients: a systematic review. Front. Aging Neurosci. 16, 1411584. 10.3389/fnagi.2024.1411584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2024.1411584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39777047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartvigsen J., Hancock M. J., Kongsted A., Louw Q., Ferreira M. L., Genevay S., et al. (2018). What low back pain is and why we need to pay attention. Lancet 391, 2356&#x2013;2367. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30480-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30480-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29573870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Higgins J., Thomas J., Chandler J., et al.  (2021). Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 6.2. London, United Kingdom: Cochrane. Available online at: https://www.training.cochrane.org/handbook (Accessed June 10, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B., Salanti G., Caldwell D. M., Chaimani A., Schmid C. H., Cameron C., et al. (2015). The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann. Intern. Med. 162, 777&#x2013;784. 10.7326/M14-2385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-2385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen V. M., Vasseljen O., Mork P. J., Berthelsen I. R., B&#xf8;rke J.-B. B., Berheussen G. F., et al. (2017). Resistance training in addition to multidisciplinary rehabilitation for patients with chronic pain in the low back: study protocol. Contemp. Clin. Trials Commun. 6, 115&#x2013;121. 10.1016/j.conctc.2017.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2017.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5936860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson J. K., Shepherd T. R., Kell R. T. (2011). The influence of periodized resistance training on recreationally active males with chronic nonspecific low back pain. J. Strength Cond. Res. 25, 242&#x2013;251. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b2c83d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b2c83d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20093971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong U.-C., Sim J., Kim C.-Y., Hwang-Bo G., Nam C. W. (2015). The effects of gluteus muscle strengthening exercise and lumbar stabilization exercise on lumbar muscle strength and balance in chronic low back pain patients. J. Phys. Ther. Sci. 27, 3813&#x2013;3816. 10.1589/jpts.27.3813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.27.3813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz J. N. (2006). Lumbar disc disorders and low-back pain: socioeconomic factors and consequences. J. Bone Jt. Surg. 88, 21&#x2013;24. 10.2106/JBJS.E.01273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.E.01273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell R. T., Asmundson G. J. G. (2009). A comparison of two forms of periodized exercise rehabilitation programs in the management of chronic nonspecific low-back pain. J. Strength and Cond. Res. 23, 513&#x2013;523. 10.1519/jsc.0b013e3181918a6e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0b013e3181918a6e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19209082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar T., Kumar S., Nezamuddin M., Sharma V. P. (2015). Efficacy of core muscle strengthening exercise in chronic low back pain patients. BMR 28, 699&#x2013;707. 10.3233/BMR-140572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-140572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25467999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalitha B., Salih M. M. N., Patil S. P., Medidi R. C. (2021). Effect of core stabilization exercises versus general back exercises in reducing chronic low back pain. Natl. J. Clin. Orthop. 5, 38&#x2013;45. 10.33545/orthor.2021.v5.i3a.290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/orthor.2021.v5.i3a.290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Zhang H., Lo W. L. A., Ge L., Miao P., Liu H., et al. (2022). Sling exercise can drive cortical representation of the transversus abdominis and multifidus muscles in patients with chronic low back pain. Front. Neurol. 13, 904002. 10.3389/fneur.2022.904002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2022.904002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9315065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35903113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhang X., Xu X., Xie S., Sun C., Dong J. (2025). The morphology and composition of paravertebral muscles evaluated by MRI technology are used to predict low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acad. Radiol. 32, 4750&#x2013;4766. 10.1016/j.acra.2025.04.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acra.2025.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40348711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J., Wang J., Jia S., Cai Z., Liu H. (2024). Correlation of muscle strength, working memory, and activities of daily living in older adults. Front. Aging Neurosci. 16, 1453527. 10.3389/fnagi.2024.1453527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2024.1453527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11449751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39372646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majeed A S., Ts A., Sugunan A., Ms A. (2019). The effectiveness of a simplified core stabilization program (TRICCS&#x2014;Trivandrum Community-based core stabilisation) for community-based intervention in chronic non-specific low back pain. J. Orthop. Surg. Res. 14, 86. 10.1186/s13018-019-1131-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-019-1131-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6431028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30902095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall P. W. M., Kennedy S., Brooks C., Lonsdale C. (2013). Pilates exercise or stationary cycling for chronic nonspecific low back pain: does it matter? A randomized controlled trial with 6-month follow-up. Spine 38, E952&#x2013;E959. 10.1097/BRS.0b013e318297c1e5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BRS.0b013e318297c1e5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23615384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes P. R. F., Gomes S. R. A., Liguori A. D. A. L., Bulh&#xf5;es L. C. C., Brasileiro J. S. (2024). Core stabilisation exercises reduce chronic low back pain in air Force fighter pilots: a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Mil. Health 170, 31&#x2013;36. 10.1136/bmjmilitary-2021-002005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjmilitary-2021-002005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto G. C., Franco K. F. M., Van Dongen J. M., Franco Y. R. D. S., De Oliveira N. T. B., Amaral D. D. V., et al. (2018). Different doses of pilates-based exercise therapy for chronic low back pain: a randomised controlled trial with economic evaluation. Br. J. Sports Med. 52, 859&#x2013;868. 10.1136/bjsports-2017-098825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamad E. W., Hafiz E., Othman Z., A. Hamid M. S. (2020). The short-term effects of progressive vs conventional core stability exercise in rehabilitation of nonspecific chronic low back pain. Sains Malays. 49, 2527&#x2013;2537. 10.17576/jsm-2020-4910-18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17576/jsm-2020-4910-18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller J., Niederer D. (2020). Training dose and effect-response relationship of motor control stabilization exercises on pain and disability in chronic non-specific low back pain patients: a systematic review with meta-regression. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 52, 791. 10.1249/01.mss.0000683844.61408.4c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000683844.61408.4c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negaresh R., Ranjbar R., Baker J., Habibi A., Mokhtarzade M., Gharibvand M. M., et al. (2017). Skeletal muscle hypertrophy, insulin-like growth factor 1, myostatin and follistatin in healthy and sarcopenic elderly men: the effect of whole-body resistance training. Int. J. Prev. Med. 10. 10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_310_17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_310_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijs J., George S. Z., Clauw D. J., Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C., Kosek E., Ickmans K., et al. (2021). Central sensitisation in chronic pain conditions: latest discoveries and their potential for precision medicine. Lancet Rheumatol. 3, e383&#x2013;e392. 10.1016/S2665-9913(21)00032-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(21)00032-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38279393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noormohammadpour P., Kordi M., Mansournia M. A., Akbari-Fakhrabadi M., Kordi R. (2018). The role of a multi-step core stability exercise program in the treatment of nurses with chronic low back pain: a single-blinded randomized controlled trial. Asian Spine J. 12, 490&#x2013;502. 10.4184/asj.2018.12.3.490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4184/asj.2018.12.3.490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6002169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nowotny A. H., Calderon M. G., De Souza P. A., Aguiar A. F., L&#xe9;onard G., Alves B. M. O., et al.  (2018). Lumbar stabilisation exercises <i>versus</i> back endurance-resistance exercise training in athletes with chronic low back pain: protocol of a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open Sport Exerc. Med.
4, e000452. 10.1136/bmjsem-2018-000452

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2018-000452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6267311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30555717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver G. D., Dwelly P. M., Sarantis N. D., Helmer R. A., Bonacci J. A. (2010). Muscle activation of different core exercises. J. Strength Cond. Res. 24, 3069&#x2013;3074. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d321da</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d321da</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20733527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M. J., McKenzie J. E., Bossuyt P. M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T. C., Mulrow C. D., et al. (2021). The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ n71, n71. 10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panjabi M. M. (1992). The stabilizing system of the spine. Part I. Function, dysfunction, adaptation, and enhancement. J. Spinal Disord. 5, 383&#x2013;389. 10.1097/00002517-199212000-00001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00002517-199212000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1490034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh D., Arora P. (2016). Role of pilates in rehabilitation: a literature review. Int. J. Ther. Rehabil. Res. 5, 77. 10.5455/ijtrr.000000148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/ijtrr.000000148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pat R. W., Lord K., Lamb J., Yamato T. P., Maher C. G., Saragiotto B. T., et al. (2014). Pilates for low back pain. Cochrane database syst rev 2015;7:CD010265. J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther. 18, 361&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8078578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26133923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pata R. W., Lord K., Lamb J. (2014). The effect of pilates based exercise on mobility, postural stability, and balance in order to decrease fall risk in older adults. J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther. 18, 361&#x2013;367. 10.1016/j.jbmt.2013.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2013.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25042305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peebles A. T., Van Der Veen S., Stamenkovic A., Thomas J. S. (2022). Patients with chronic non-specific low back pain have altered movement coordination during functional reaching tasks. Gait Posture 91, 30&#x2013;34. 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2021.10.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2021.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34634613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaseem A., Wilt T. J., McLean R. M., Forciea M. A., Denberg T. D., et al. Clinical Guidelines Committee of the American College of Physicians (2017). Noninvasive treatments for acute, subacute, and chronic low back pain: a clinical practice guideline from the American college of physicians. Ann. Intern. Med. 166, 514&#x2013;530. 10.7326/M16-2367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M16-2367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaseem A., McLean R. M., O&#x2019;Gurek D., Batur P., Lin K., Kansagara D. L. (2020). Nonpharmacologic and pharmacologic management of acute pain from non&#x2013;low back, musculoskeletal injuries in adults: a clinical guideline from the American college of physicians and American academy of family physicians. Ann. Intern. Med. 173, 739&#x2013;748. 10.7326/M19-3602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M19-3602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queiroz B. C., Cagliari M. F., Amorim C. F., Sacco I. C. (2010). Muscle activation during four pilates core stability exercises in quadruped position. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 91, 86&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.apmr.2009.09.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2009.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20103401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson Z. P., Pelland J. C., Remmert J. F., Refalo M. C., Jukic I., Steele J., et al. (2024). Exploring the dose&#x2013;response relationship between estimated resistance training proximity to failure, strength gain, and muscle hypertrophy: a series of meta-regressions. Sports Med. 54, 2209&#x2013;2231. 10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydeard R., Leger A., Smith D. (2006). Pilates-based therapeutic exercise: effect on subjects with nonspecific chronic low back pain and functional disability: a randomized controlled trial. Res. Rep. 36, 472&#x2013;484. 10.2519/jospt.2006.2144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2006.2144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16881464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryum T., Stiles T. C. (2023). Changes in pain catastrophizing, fear-avoidance beliefs, and pain self-efficacy mediate changes in pain intensity on disability in the treatment of chronic low back pain. PAIN Rep. 8, e1092. 10.1097/PR9.0000000000001092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10501475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37719924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos I. R., Mousinho R. R., Parizotto N. A., Coutinho C. C. (2023). Pilates method in low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. Fisioter. Bras. 24, 564&#x2013;579. 10.33233/fb.v24i5.5430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33233/fb.v24i5.5430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savigny P., Watson P., Underwood M. on behalf of the Guideline Development Group (2009). Early management of persistent non-specific low back pain: summary of NICE guidance. BMJ 338, b1805. 10.1136/bmj.b1805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.b1805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19502217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkow N. M., Eck M. R., Rivas S. (2017). Transversus abdominis activation and timing improves following core stability training: a randomized trial. Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther. 12, 1048&#x2013;1056. 10.26603/ijspt20171048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20171048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29234556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyedhoseinpoor T., Taghipour M., Dadgoo M., Sanjari M. A., Takamjani I. E., Kazemnejad A., et al. (2022). Alteration of lumbar muscle morphology and composition in relation to low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Spine J. 22, 660&#x2013;676. 10.1016/j.spinee.2021.10.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2021.10.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34718177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silfies S. P., Mehta R., Smith S. S., Karduna A. R. (2009). Differences in feedforward trunk muscle activity in subgroups of patients with mechanical low back pain. Archives Phys. Med. Rehabilitation 90, 1159&#x2013;1169. 10.1016/j.apmr.2008.10.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2008.10.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19501348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva M. L., Miyamoto G. C., Franco K. F. M., Franco Y. R. D. S., Cabral C. M. N. (2020). Different weekly frequencies of pilates did not accelerate pain improvement in patients with chronic low back pain. Braz. J. Phys. Ther. 24, 287&#x2013;292. 10.1016/j.bjpt.2019.05.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2019.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31153789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tottoli C. R., Ben &#xc2;. J., da Silva E. N., Bosmans J. E., van Tulder M., Carregaro R. L. (2024). Effectiveness of pilates compared with home-based exercises in individuals with chronic non-specific low back pain: randomised controlled trial. Clin. Rehabil. 38, 1495&#x2013;1505. 10.1177/02692155241277041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02692155241277041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11528976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39275840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dillen L. R., Lanier V. M., Steger-May K., Wallendorf M., Norton B. J., Civello J. M., et al. (2021). Effect of motor skill training in functional activities vs strength and flexibility exercise on function in people with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 78, 385&#x2013;395. 10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4821</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33369625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volovyk N., Pidvalna O. (2023). &#x201c;The principles of pilates and their role in the effective application of this system of physical exercises,&#x201d; in Scientific journal of national pedagogical dragomanov university. Series 15. Scientific and pedagogical problems of physical culture (physical culture and sports), 89&#x2013;94. 10.31392/NPU-nc.series15.2023.3K(162).18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31392/NPU-nc.series15.2023.3K(162).18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wafaa A. (2024). Effect of core stability exercises on pain in chronic non-specific low back pain. Med. J. Cairo Univ. 92, 113&#x2013;118. 10.21608/mjcu.2024.353093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/mjcu.2024.353093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahyuni W., Kurnia N. E. (2023). The effectiveness of core stability exercises on pain in patients with low back pain: a meta-analysis. Phys. Ther. J. Indones. 4, 85&#x2013;90. 10.51559/ptji.v4i1.86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51559/ptji.v4i1.86</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wajswelner H., Metcalf B., Bennell K. (2012). Clinical pilates <i>versus</i> general exercise for chronic low back pain: randomized trial. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc.
44, 1197&#x2013;1205. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318248f665

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318248f665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22246216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walcott B. P., Nahed B. V., Redjal N., Stein T. D., Kahle K. T., Coumans J.-V. (2011). Pathological mechanism of lumbar disc herniation resulting in neurogenic muscle hypertrophy. J. Clin. Neurosci. 18, 1682&#x2013;1684. 10.1016/j.jocn.2011.03.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2011.03.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Fan Z., Liu X., Zheng J., Zhang S., Zhang S., et al. (2022). Effect of progressive postural control exercise versus core stability exercise in young adults with chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Ther. 12, 293&#x2013;308. 10.1007/s40122-022-00458-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40122-022-00458-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Wang R., Ma S., He B. (2024). Interventional effect of core stability training on pain and muscle function of youth with chronic non-specific lower back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Heliyon 10, e32818. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e32818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e32818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11226851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38975134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Chang M. C. (2019). Chronic pain: structural and functional changes in brain structures and associated negative affective states. IJMS 20, 3130. 10.3390/ijms20133130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20133130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6650904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31248061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Yin Y., Wang J., Zhang X., Cai H., Peng F. (2023). Efficacy of pilates on pain, functional disorders and quality of life in patients with chronic low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 20, 2850. 10.3390/ijerph20042850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20042850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9956295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Wang Y., Li T., Ma J., He R., Han X., et al. (2024). Relation between abnormal spontaneous brain activity and altered neuromuscular activation of lumbar paraspinal muscles in chronic low back pain. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 105, 2107&#x2013;2117. 10.1016/j.apmr.2024.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2024.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38969254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>