<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41201787</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Maximal Strength or Speed-Strength Have Stronger Associations with Performance Indicators in the Rugby Football Codes? A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>215</StartPage><EndPage>227</EndPage><MedlinePgn>215-227</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02342-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Both maximal strength and speed-strength are considered key aspects of rugby league and rugby union match-play yet represent distinct physical qualities. Establishing whether maximal strength or speed-strength has a greater association with game performance in these sports can help direct resistance training interventions towards the physical quality most likely to transfer to the outcome of interest. It is therefore important to develop a clearer understanding of whether it is maximal strength or speed-strength that has stronger links to key aspects of rugby union and rugby league competition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematically review and meta-analyse the literature to compare maximal strength versus speed-strength measures in their associations with within-game key performance indicators (KPIs) in rugby union and rugby league. Further, sub-group analysis was undertaken to determine whether the type of KPI (tackles, rucks, line breaks, carries/hit-ups, errors, and miscellaneous) moderated the extent to which the observed effect favoured maximal strength or speed-strength for a given KPI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search, conducted in accordance with PRISMA guidelines, of Web of Science, PubMed, and SportDiscus was conducted up to December 2024. Studies meeting the inclusion criteria provided correlation coefficients that were converted into Fisher's z-transformed effect sizes to standardise the measures and allow for consistent comparison across studies. These effect sizes were analysed using a multivariate meta-analysis framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Six studies containing 41 maximal strength versus speed-strength comparisons and 134 players were included in the final analysis. Of the 786 studies initially identified, 28 underwent full-text screening, with 22 ultimately excluded. The overall pooled effect was 0.24 [0.11: 0.37] in favour of strength; however, the prediction interval ranged from g&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.58 to g&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.06. The moderator analysis revealed a statistically significant effect of type (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.038), indicating stronger associations for maximal strength compared to speed-strength. Residual heterogeneity (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005) suggested substantial variability in effect sizes across studies that was not fully explained by the model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Within-game rugby union and rugby league KPIs typically have stronger links to maximal strength than to speed-strength. However, the wide prediction interval underscores that the observed maximal strength advantage may not generalise across all types of KPIs or predictably translate to all future settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Lachlan P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0598-5502</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, Department of Dietetics, Nutrition and Sport, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia. l.james@latrobe.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelly</LastName><ForeName>Vincent G</ForeName><Initials>VG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Faculty of Health, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weakley</LastName><ForeName>Jonathon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research (CARR) Centre, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>Rich D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research (CARR) Centre, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huynh</LastName><ForeName>Minh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, Department of Dietetics, Nutrition and Sport, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="Y">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of Interest: The authors have no conflicts of interest to report in relation to this work. Data Availability: The following link provides the R code to run the analysis: https://github.com/m2huynh/SPOA-D-25-00240/blob/main/Maximal%20Strength%20or%20Speed-Strength/Scripts/Script.R . Author Contributions: Conceptualisation and study design: LJ and MH. Literature search and screen: LJ and VK. Data extraction: LJ. Statistical analysis: MH. Data interpretation: LJ, MH, JW, RJ, VK. Manuscript drafting: LJ, MH. Manuscript revision and critical review: VK, JW, RJ. Figure and table preparation: LJ and MH. All authors read and approved the final version.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41201787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02342-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02342-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan M, Newton R. Developing maximal neuromuscular power: part 2&#x2014;raining considerations for improving maximal power production. Sports Med. 2011;41(2):125&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21244105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Talpey SW, Young WB, Geneau MC, Newton RU, Gastin PB. Strength classification and diagnosis: not all strength is created equal. Strength Cond J. 2023;45(3):333&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneau MC, Carey DL, Gastin PB, Robertson S, James LP. Classification of force-time metrics into lower-body strength domains. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(9):1561&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38976311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Influence of strength on magnitude and mechanisms of adaptation to power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(8):1566&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20639724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Haff G, Kelly VG, Connick M, Hoffman B, Beckman EM. The impact of strength level on adaptations to combined weightlifting, plyometric, and ballistic training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(5):1494&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29281133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer CM, Pyne DB, Mooney M, McKune A, Serpell BG. Performance analysis in rugby union: a critical systematic review. Sports Medicine-Open. 2020;6:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG. Applied sport science of Rugby League. Sports Med. 2014;44:1087&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24748460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods CT, Sinclair W, Robertson S. Explaining match outcome and ladder position in the National Rugby League using team performance indicators. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(12):1107&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28479281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett M, Bezodis NE, Shearer DA, Kilduff LP. Predicting performance at the group-phase and knockout-phase of the 2015 Rugby World Cup. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(3):312&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32174244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes MD, Bartlett RM. The use of performance indicators in performance analysis. J Sports Sci. 2002;20(10):739&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12363292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes A, Barnes A, Churchill SM, Stone JA. Performance indicators that discriminate winning and losing in elite men&#x2019;s and women&#x2019;s Rugby Union. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2017;17(4):534&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson N, Durbach I, Hendricks S, Stewart T. On the validity of team performance indicators in rugby union. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2017;17(4):609&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhouse LN, Bennett M, Tallent J, Patterson SD, Waldron M. The relationship between physical characteristics and match collision performance among elite international female rugby union players. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23(9):1849&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36336974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham DJ, Shearer DA, Drawer S, Pollard B, Cook CJ, Bennett M, et al. Relationships between physical qualities and key performance indicators during match-play in senior international rugby union players. PLoS ONE. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0202811 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0202811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6218024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza MJA, Gabbett TJ, Greene DA, Johnston RD, Townshend AD. Tackle characteristics and outcomes in match-play rugby league: the relationship with tackle ability and physical qualities. Sci Med Footb. 2017;1(3):265&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohn LD, Becker BJ. How meta-analysis increases statistical power. Psychol Methods. 2003;8(3):243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14596489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrer M, Cuijpers P, Furukawa T, Ebert D. Doing meta-analysis with R: a hands-on guide. Boca Raton: Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Haycraft JA, Carey DL, Robertson SJ. A framework for test measurement selection in athlete physical preparation. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1406997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39011346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11246953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1998;52(6):377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1756728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox AS, Bonacci J, McLean SG, Spittle M, Saunders N. What is normal? Female lower limb kinematic profiles during athletic tasks used to examine anterior cruciate ligament injury risk: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2014;44:815&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24682949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bujalance-Moreno P, Latorre-Rom&#xe1;n P&#xc1;, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F. A systematic review on small-sided games in football players: acute and chronic adaptations. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(8):921&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvis P, Turner A, Read P, Bishop C. Reactive strength index and its associations with measures of physical and sports performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52(2):301&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34606061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36(3):1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustejovsky JE. clubSandwich (Version 0.5.11) [R package]. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coghetto G, Zanrosso EM, Rabello R, Da Ros JL, Rodrigues R. Association between success and unsuccess rates on technical skills and physical qualities in rugby players. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2023;94(1):254&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35323103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart AS, Erskine RM, McLaughlin TJ, Clark DR. Physical characteristics explain ball-carrying capability in sub-elite Rugby Union players. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2023;5(3):244&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Whitley R, Connick MJ, Kelly VG, Beckman EM. The relationship between match tackle outcomes and muscular strength and power in professional rugby league. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(10):2853&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD. Influence of physical characteristics and match outcome on technical errors during Rugby League match play. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(8):1043&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30676143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duthie G, Pyne D, Hooper S. Applied physiology and game analysis of rugby union. Sports Med. 2003;33(13):973&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14606925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimundo F, Cole M, Blagrove R, Till K, McAuley A, Hall M, et al. Talent identification and development in male rugby union: A systematic review. Journal of Expertise. 2021;4(1):33&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Antrobus M, Stebbings GK, Day SH, Callus P, Erskine RM, et al. Anthropometric and physiological characteristics of elite male rugby athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(6):1790&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Newton R. Comparison of lower body strength, power, acceleration, speed, agility, and sprint momentum to describe and compare playing rank among professional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(1):153&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 4th ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon JJ, Murphy S, Rej SJ, Comfort P. Countermovement-jump-phase characteristics of senior and academy rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(6):803&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Kelly VG, Connick MJ, Beckman EM. Predicting rugby league tackle outcomes using strength and power principal components. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(2):278&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34853184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman K, Wade L, Whitley R, Connick M, Kelly VG, Beckman E. Relationship between match playing performance and muscular strength and power in professional rugby league. J Aust Strength Cond. 2019;27(6):38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce LA, Sinclair WH, Leicht AS, Woods CT. Passing and tackling qualities discriminate developmental level in a rugby league talent pathway. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2019;19(6):985&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rooyen M, Yasin N, Viljoen W. Characteristics of an &#x2018;effective&#x2019;tackle outcome in Six Nations rugby. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24533518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron M, Worsfold PR, Twist C, Lamb K. The relationship between physical abilities, ball-carrying and tackling among elite youth rugby league players. J Sports Sci. 2014;32(6):542&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24070519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza MJ, Gabbett TJ, Johnston RD, Sheppard JM. Relationship between a standardized tackling proficiency test and match-play tackle performance in semiprofessional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(6):754&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26115181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza MJ, Gabbett TJ, Johnston RD, Sheppard JM. Muscular strength and power correlates of tackling ability in semiprofessional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(8):2071&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26200016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza MJ, Gabbett TJ, Johnston RD, Sheppard JM. Effect of strength and power training on tackling ability in semiprofessional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(2):336&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26813629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Developing explosive muscular power: implications for a mixed methods training strategy. Strength Cond J. 1994;16:20&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards S, Lee R, Fuller G, Buchanan M, Tahu T, Tucker R, et al. 3D biomechanics of Rugby tackle techniques to inform future rugby research practice: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2021;7(1):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34097146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8184906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Influence of fatigue on tackling ability in rugby league players: role of muscular strength, endurance, and aerobic qualities. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(10):e0163161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27798634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5087954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone S, Hughes B, Doran DA, Collins K, Gabbett TJ. Can the workload&#x2013;injury relationship be moderated by improved strength, speed and repeated-sprint qualities? J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaney JA, Scott TJ, Ballard DA, Duthie GM, Hickmans JA, Lockie RG, et al. Contributing factors to change-of-direction ability in professional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2688&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas C, Comfort P, Jones PA, Dos&#x2019;Santos T. A comparison of isometric midthigh-pull strength, vertical jump, sprint speed, and change-of-direction speed in academy netball players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(7):916&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Miller IR, Talpey SW. Physical qualities predict change-of-direction speed but not defensive agility in Australian rules football. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(1):206&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Hollander S, Brown J, Lambert M, Treu P, Hendricks S. Skills Associated With Line Breaks In Elite Rugby Union. J Sports Sci Med. 2016;15(3):501&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygaard Falch H, Guldteig R&#xe6;derg&#xe5;rd H, van den Tillaar R. Effect of different physical training forms on change of direction ability: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2019;5:1&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Newton RU, Binetti M, Hart NH, Sheppard JM, Nimphius S. Mechanical determinants of faster change of direction and agility performance in female basketball athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(8):2205&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Nimphius S, Hart NH, Specos C, Sheppard JM, Newton RU. Contribution of strength characteristics to change of direction and agility performance in female basketball athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(9):2415&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24875426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry GJ, Dawson B, Lay BS, Young WB. Relationships between reactive agility movement time and unilateral vertical, horizontal, and lateral jumps. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(9):2514&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23820562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matl&#xe1;k J, Tihanyi J, R&#xe1;cz L. Relationship between reactive agility and change of direction speed in amateur soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(6):1547&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Weakley J, Comfort P, Huynh M. The relationship between isometric and dynamic strength following resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and level of agreement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;1(aop):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W, Wilson G, Byrne C. Relationship between strength qualities and performance in standing and run-up vertical jumps. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1999;39(4):285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10726428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>