<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41857636</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-0003</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroengineering and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroeng Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feasibility of AI-driven multichannel FES-assisted gait and cycling training in chronic neurological disorders: a case series.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12984-026-01953-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Gait impairments following chronic neurological conditions, such as spinal cord injury (SCI), represent a major challenge for rehabilitation, with limited options to sustain functional recovery and patient engagement. Functional electrical stimulation (FES) has shown potential to enhance gait performance, but its integration into routine rehabilitation requires clinically feasible and acceptable solutions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the feasibility, safety, and acceptability of integrating NeuroSkin&#xae;, a wearable AI-powered multichannel FES system, into walking rehabilitation programs for individuals with chronic neurological gait impairments, and to explore its potential to improve functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective case series included four individuals (three males, one female; aged 54-78&#xa0;years) with chronic neurological gait impairments of diverse etiologies (acute disseminated encephalomyelitis, idiopathic transverse myelitis, incomplete spinal cord injury, and polyradiculoneuritis). Participants underwent 20 rehabilitation sessions over 6&#xa0;weeks, which combined FES-assisted cycling and ambulation with the NeuroSkin device. The system integrates inertial measurement units and plantar pressure sensors to deliver phase-specific stimulation across multiple lower limb muscle groups. Feasibility was assessed through completion rates and adherence to the study protocol. Gait, balance, and spasticity outcomes were recorded before (PRE) and after the intervention (POST) with standardized assessments (10-Meter Walk Test, 2-Minute Walk Test, Berg Balance Scale, Stand Chair Test, Modified Ashworth Scale, SCATS, and Neuropathic Pain Diagnostic Questionnaire).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All participants completed the intervention, demonstrating good feasibility, tolerance, and adherence. Improvements were observed in walking speed and distance (10mWT and 2MWT), with concomitant improvement in lower limb strength and reductions in spasticity for three patients. These findings support the potential integration of AI-driven multichannel FES into long-term gait rehabilitation programs for individuals with chronic neurological conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The integration of the NeuroSkin AI-driven FES system into rehabilitation programs for individuals with chronic neurological gait impairments was feasible, well accepted by patients, and safe. Furthermore, while improvements in gait performance were observed, these findings should be interpreted as exploratory and require confirmation in controlled studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Babi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Nikola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kurage, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo Fernandes</ForeName><Initials>BF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pour La Recherche Sur La Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re (IRME), Station Debout, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levy</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pour La Recherche Sur La Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re (IRME), Station Debout, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de M&#xe9;decine Physique Et de R&#xe9;adaptation, H&#xf4;pital Raymond Poincar&#xe9; (AP-HP Saclay), Garches, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Touzard</LastName><ForeName>Fleur</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pour La Recherche Sur La Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re (IRME), Station Debout, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire Sur Les Interactions, Cognition, Action, &#xc9;motion (LICAE), Universit&#xe9; Paris Nanterre, Garches, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blancho</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pour La Recherche Sur La Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re (IRME), Station Debout, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe9;guin</LastName><ForeName>Perrine</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kurage, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metani</LastName><ForeName>Amine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kurage, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique, Universit&#xe9; de Lyon, &#xc9;cole Normale Sup&#xe9;rieure de Lyon (ENS Lyon), Centre National de La Recherche Scientifique (CNRS), Garches, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Descollonges</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#xeb;l</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kurage, Lyon, France. descollonges.mael@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroeng Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101232233</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-0003</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic impairments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gait rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NeuroSkin&#xae;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Authorization to use the data was granted by the National Commission for Data Protection and Privacy (CNIL: 2227969 v 0, MR-004). All procedures related to ethics, data collection, and analysis complied with the MR-004 reference methodology. Participants were informed that data collected through the NeuroSkin&#xae; system and standardized assessments would be used for research purposes, and that they could withdraw their consent at any time. Consent for publication: Not applicable as all participants have been de-identified. Competing interests: This research was supported by the Institut pour la Recherche sur la Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re et l&#x2019;Enc&#xe9;phale (IRME), Station Debout, and Kurage (Lyon, France). The study was conducted in Station Debout Research Center, IRME, Paris. Conflicts of Interest: N.B., P.S., A.M. &amp; M.D. declare conflict of interest via research funding by the Kurage Company.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41857636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-026-01953-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12984-026-01953-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wirz M, van Hedel HJA. Balance, gait, and falls in spinal cord injury. Handbook Clin Neurol. 2018;159:367&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-444-63916-5.00024-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willison HJ, Jacobs BC, Van DPA. Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome. BMJ. 2016;23:717&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KD. Targeting recovery: priorities of the spinal cord-injured population. J Neurotrauma. 2004;21(10):1371&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkelmans S, Dominici N, Afschrift M, Bruijn S, Janssen TWJ. Feasibility and safety of automated multi-channel FES-assisted gait training in incomplete spinal cord injury. J Rehabil Med. 2025;57:jrm42638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson LA, Eng JJ, Hsieh JTC, Wolfe DL. The health and life priorities of individuals with spinal cord injury: a systematic review. J Neurotrauma. 2012;29(8):1548&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein RB, Everaert DG, Thompson AK, SuLing C, Whittaker M, Robertson J, et al. Long-term therapeutic and orthotic effects of a foot drop stimulator on walking performance in progressive and nonprogressive neurological disorders. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2010;24(2):152&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nightingale EJ, Raymond J, Middleton JW, Crosbie J, Davis GM. Benefits of FES gait in a spinal cord injured population. Spinal Cord. 2007;45(10):646&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Marmier P, Mater A, Di Marco J, Descollonges M, Marmier P, et al. FES-rowing&#x202f;: a well-tolerated and highly beneficial exercise for a patient with Brown- Sequard syndrome. J Spinal Cord Med. 2023;0(0):1&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1080/10790268.2023.2165369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Chaney R, Garnier P, Pirgent-Tessier A, Brugniaux JV, Deley G. Electrical stimulation: a potential alternative to positively impact cerebral health? Front Physiol. 2024;15:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosini E, Ferrante S, Pedrocchi A, Ferrigno G, Molteni F. Cycling induced by electrical stimulation improves motor recovery in postacute hemiparetic patients: a randomized controlled trial. Stroke. 2011;42(4):1068&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Di Marco J, Jafari E, Pouillart PH, Brugniaux VJ, Pageaux B, et al. Positive effects of functional electrical stimulation-assisted cycling on perception of effort, cerebral blood flow, and cognition in post-stroke patients. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-025-01800-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosini E, Ferrante S, Ferrigno G, Molteni F, Pedrocchi A. Cycling induced by electrical stimulation improves muscle activation and symmetry during pedaling in hemiparetic patients. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2012;20(3):320&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metani A, Popovi&#x107;-Maneski L, Seguin P, Di Marco J. NeuroSkin&#xae;: AI-driven wearable functional electrical stimulation for post-stroke gait recovery&#x2014;a multicenter feasibility study. Sensors. 2025;25(18):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David R, Billot M, Ojardias E, Parratte B, Roulaud M, Ounajim A, et al. A 6-month home-based functional electrical stimulation program for foot drop in a post-stroke patient&#x202f;: considerations on a time course analysis of walking performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19159204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Moreau B, Feppon N, Abdoun O, S&#xe9;guin P, Popovic-maneski L, et al. Evaluation of the validity and reliability of NeuroSkin&#x2019;s wearable sensor gait analysis device in healthy individuals. Bioengineering Basel. 2025. https://doi.org/10.3390/bioengineering12090960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doucet BM, Lam A, Griffin L. Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation for Skeletal Muscle Function. 2012;85:201&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Marmier P, Jafari E, Marillier M. Acute Impact of FES- &#xad; Assisted Cycling on Cerebrovascular and Cognitive Function in Healthy Young Adults. 2026;1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descollonges M, Marmier P, Marillier M, Jafari E, Brugniaux JV, Deley G. Effect of electrical muscle stimulation on cerebrovascular function and cognitive performance. Am J Physiol - Hear Circ Physiol. 2024;326(4):H923&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari E, Descollonges M, Deley G, Di Marco J, Popovic-maneski L, Metani A. Comfort, consistency, and efficiency of garments with textile electrodes versus hydrogel electrodes for neuromuscular electrical stimulation in a randomized crossover trial. Sci Rep. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-91452-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chantraine F, Filipetti P, Schreiber C, Remacle A. Proposition of a classification of adult patients with hemiparesis in chronic phase. 2016;1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi R, Widmer M, Merz N, Bastiaenen CHG, Z&#xf6;rner B, Bolliger M. Validity and reliability of the 2-minute walk test in individuals with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2023;61(1):15&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta S, Lorenz DJ, Harkema SJ. Dynamic longitudinal evaluation of the utility of the Berg Cord Injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2012;93(9):1565&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2012.01.026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs S, Marquez J, Chiarelli P. The Berg Balance Scale has high intra- and inter-rater reliability but absolute reliability varies across the scale: A systematic review. J Physiother. 2013;59(2):93&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1836-9553(13)70161-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CJ, Rikli RE, Beam WC. A 30-s chair-stand test as a measure of lower body strength in community-residing older adults. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1999;70(2):113&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meseguer-Henarejos AB, S&#x1ce;NCHEZ-MECA J, L&#xf3;pez-Pina JA, CARLES-HERN&#x1ce;NDEZ R. Inter-and intra-rater reliability of the Modified Ashworth Scale: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54(4):576&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpinar P, Atici A, Ozkan FU, Aktas I, Kulcu DG, Kurt KN. Reliability of the spinal cord assessment tool for spastic reflexes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;98(6):1113&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2016.09.119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madani SP, Bagherzadeh Cham M, Sajadi S, Mansouri K, Samadaeian N, Zare N. Assessing the validity and reliability of the DN4 neuropathic pain questionnaire: a systematic review. Ann Mil Health Sci Res. 2025;23(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam T, Noonan VK, Eng JJ. A systematic review of functional ambulation outcome measures in spinal cord injury. 2011;46(4):246&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest GF, Hutchinson K, Lorenz DJ, Buehner JJ, Vanhiel LR, Sisto A, et al. Are the 10 Meter and 6 Minute Walk Tests Redundant in Patients with Spinal Cord Injury&#x202f;? Walk. 2014;9(5):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street T, Singleton C. A clinically meaningful training effect in walking speed using functional electrical stimulation for motor-incomplete spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. 2018;41(3):361&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapadia N, Masani K, Craven C, Giangregorio L, Hitzig SL, Richards K, et al. A randomized trial of functional electrical stimulation for walking in incomplete spinal cord injury: Effects on walking competency Naaz. J Spinal Cord Med. 2014. https://doi.org/10.1179/2045772314y.0000000263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field-Fote EC, Roach KE. Influence of a locomotor training approach on walking speed and distance in people with chronic spinal cord injury: a randomized clinical trial. Phys Ther. 2011;91(1):48&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Crouch R. Minimal clinically important difference for change in 6 - minute walk test distance of adults with pathology. Syst Rev. 2016;6:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morawietz C, Moffat F. Effects of locomotor training after incomplete spinal cord injury: A systematic review. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(11):2297&#x2013;308. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2013.06.023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang CY, Lien ASY, Tsai JL, Yang HC, Chan HL, Chen RS, et al. The effect and dose-response of functional electrical stimulation cycling training on spasticity in individuals with spinal cord injury: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawcett JW, Curt A, Steeves JD, Coleman WP, Tuszynski MH, Lammertse D, et al. Guidelines for the conduct of clinical trials for spinal cord injury as developed by the ICCP panel. Ther Clin Trials. 2006;2007:190&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>