<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Prog</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Prog</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">4462</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">sciprog</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">SCI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Science Progress</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0036-8504</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2047-7163</issn><publisher><publisher-name>SAGE Publications</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13009636</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13009636.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13009636</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13009636</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41834701</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/00368504261432840</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">10.1177_00368504261432840</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Research Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Beyond aggregate volume—Accelerometer-derived activity phenotypes reveal a decoupling of lean mass and function: A cross-sectional study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9436-6630</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="X">Xiangyu</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0009-0008-4571-7108</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names initials="X">Xiaoming</given-names></name><xref rid="corresp1-00368504261432840" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><aff id="aff1-00368504261432840">Department of Physical Education, <institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="Ringgold">12379</institution-id><institution content-type="university">Capital Normal University</institution></institution-wrap>, Beijing, China</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="corresp1-00368504261432840">XiaoMing Wu, Department of Physical Education, Capital Normal University, Beijing 100048, China. 
Email: <email>wuxiaomingcnu@163.com</email>
</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>16</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><season>Jan-Mar</season><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>109</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503713</issue-id><elocation-id>00368504261432840</elocation-id><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>16</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>25</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-03-25 00:25:12.400"><day>25</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><copyright-holder content-type="sage">SAGE Publications</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>) which permits non-commercial use, reproduction and distribution of the work without further permission provided the original work is attributed as specified on the SAGE and Open Access page (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/open-access-at-sage">https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/open-access-at-sage</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Objective</title><p>Lean mass preservation does not guarantee sustained muscle strength in aging populations. Aggregate physical activity metrics obscure temporal movement patterns and fail to explain this mass-function dissociation. Unsupervised machine learning is required to identify multidimensional activity phenotypes and clarify their specific neuromuscular impacts. This study examined the associations of accelerometer-derived activity phenotypes with lean mass versus function, comparing phenotypic models against aggregate volume metrics.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p>This cross-sectional study analyzed National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2011–2014 data from United States adults aged analyzed. K-Means clustering derived activity phenotypes from wrist-accelerometry features representing rhythm and fragmentation. Survey-weighted linear regression assessed independent associations with appendicular lean mass (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 1756) and grip strength (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3890), adjusting for covariates. The Akaike information criterion compared the explanatory power of phenotype-based versus traditional volume-based models.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p>Two phenotypes emerged: high-volume/consolidated (HVC: higher MIMS volume, longer sedentary bouts) and low-volume/fragmented (LVF: lower MIMS volume, shorter sedentary bouts). Compared to LVF, HVC exhibited significantly higher appendicular lean mass index (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 0.11; 95% CI, 0.03 to 0.18), equivalent to offsetting five years of age-related decline. It demonstrated no significant advantage in grip strength (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = −0.07; 95% CI, −0.70 to 0.56). Phenotype-based models demonstrated statistical equivalence to traditional volume-based models (ΔAIC &lt; 1.0) for both outcomes.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p>High activity volume accumulated via structured patterns is associated with preserved appendicular lean mass. However, this structural advantage does not translate to improved grip strength. This dissociation implies that total activity volume is insufficient to ensure generalized neuromuscular performance in the presence of prolonged sedentary time. This decoupling implies that consolidated sedentary behavior compromises neuromuscular performance despite adequate total movement. Consequently, sarcopenia guidelines must integrate sedentary fragmentation targets rather than relying solely on aggregate volume.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>Sarcopenia</kwd><kwd>accelerometry</kwd><kwd>sedentary fragmentation</kwd><kwd>unsupervised machine learning</kwd><kwd>dynapenia</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>typesetter</meta-name><meta-value>ts19</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>cover-date</meta-name><meta-value>January-March 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="section1-00368504261432840"><title>Introduction</title><p>Skeletal muscle integrity determines functional independence in aging populations.<sup><xref rid="bibr1-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">1</xref><xref rid="bibr2-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr"/>–<xref rid="bibr3-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> Sarcopenia encompasses the simultaneous loss of lean mass and contractile function.<sup><xref rid="bibr4-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">4</xref><xref rid="bibr5-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr"/>–<xref rid="bibr6-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> However, distinct non-linear trajectories frequently emerge between muscle size and muscle strength. Individuals often maintain muscle volume despite significant deficits in force production.<sup><xref rid="bibr7-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">7</xref><xref rid="bibr8-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr"/>–<xref rid="bibr9-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup> Aggregate physical activity volume metrics fail to fully explain this mass-function dissociation.<sup><xref rid="bibr10-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">10</xref><xref rid="bibr11-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr"/>–<xref rid="bibr12-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> Therefore, identifying multidimensional activity accumulation patterns via unsupervised learning is critical to understanding disparate neuromuscular outcomes.<sup><xref rid="bibr13-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">13</xref><xref rid="bibr14-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr"/>–<xref rid="bibr15-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup></p><p>Current epidemiological guidelines emphasize aggregate metrics to maintain musculoskeletal health.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr16-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>
</sup> These indices typically quantify total activity volume or moderate-to-vigorous physical activity duration.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr17-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>
</sup> However, volume-based predictors exhibit inconsistent associations with muscle function outcomes.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr18-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>
</sup> High total activity often fails to mitigate declines in grip strength or gait speed despite the preservation of lean mass.<sup><xref rid="bibr19-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="bibr20-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> This divergence indicates that distinct accumulation patterns mediate specific physiological adaptations. Beyond total volume, the duration of sedentary bouts and the fragmentation of activity intervals appear critical for neuromuscular integrity.<sup><xref rid="bibr21-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,<xref rid="bibr22-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> Consequently, aggregate metrics function as a “black box” that obscures the temporal structure of daily movement.</p><p>Standard analytical approaches frequently reduce high-resolution accelerometry into fixed intensity categories using arbitrary thresholds. Even continuous volume summation obscures critical temporal dynamics. Identical daily accumulation totals often arise from fundamentally different behavioral structures, such as consolidated exercise versus fragmented intermittent movement.<sup><xref rid="bibr23-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="bibr24-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> Unsupervised machine learning methodologies overcome these limitations by identifying multidimensional phenotypes without reliance on subjective assumptions.<sup><xref rid="bibr25-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,<xref rid="bibr26-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">26</xref></sup> Data-driven clustering techniques effectively capture the complex interplay between activity intensity, sedentary bout duration, and fragmentation.<sup><xref rid="bibr27-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="bibr28-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup></p><p>This study aimed to evaluate the divergent associations of accelerometer-derived physical activity phenotypes with lean mass versus muscle function. Data were analyzed from the 2011–2014 National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Unsupervised K-Means clustering was utilized to classify participants based on five features representing activity rhythm, inequality, and sedentary fragmentation. Multivariable regression models subsequently assessed independent associations between derived phenotypes and both appendicular lean mass index (ALMI) and handgrip strength. Additionally, the explanatory quality of these phenotypic models was statistically compared against traditional volume-based models. This analytical framework moves beyond aggregate summation to isolate the specific physiological relevance of activity accumulation patterns. Mechanical loading drives muscle hypertrophy. Total activity volume preserves architectural structure.<sup><xref rid="bibr29-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,<xref rid="bibr30-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">30</xref></sup> Conversely, neuromuscular performance demands frequent activation. Prolonged sedentary bouts compromise motor unit recruitment.<sup><xref rid="bibr31-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="bibr32-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">32</xref></sup> This impairment persists despite adequate volume. It was hypothesized that a high-volume yet sedentary-structured phenotype would predict preserved lean mass but compromised muscle function. Clarifying these relationships provides necessary evidence to refine sarcopenia prevention strategies from simple volume targets to specific behavioral architectures.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods" id="section2-00368504261432840"><title>Methods</title><sec id="section2A-00368504261432840"><title>Data and sample sources</title><p>Data were obtained from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES). The National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) conducts this national cross-sectional survey. NHANES assesses the health and nutritional status of the US non-institutionalized civilian population. A complex, stratified, multistage probability design is used to select a nationally representative sample. Participants completed in-home interviews and underwent physical and laboratory examinations in a mobile examination center (MEC). The NCHS Research Ethics Review Board approved all study protocols. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki of 1975, as revised in 2024. All participants provided written informed consent. Detailed study information and data are publicly available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/" ext-link-type="uri">www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/</ext-link>.<sup><xref rid="bibr33-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="bibr34-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">34</xref></sup> All participant data were de-identified by the National Center for Health Statistics prior to public release.</p><p>This retrospective cross-sectional study utilized data from two NHANES cycles (2011–2012 and 2013–2014). These specific survey cycles were selected because they represent the most recent NHANES data containing objective wrist-worn accelerometry measurements. These cycles uniquely contain concurrent accelerometer (ACC) and dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) data. The initial dataset included 19,931 participants. Participants were first excluded for missing survey weights (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 780), leaving 19,151 participants. Individuals aged &lt; 40 years (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 12,002) were then excluded. This resulted in a master cohort of 7149 adults. This master cohort formed the starting point for two separate analytical cohorts (Cohort A for ALMI; Cohort B for Grip Strength). Following all exclusions, the final analytical cohorts included 1756 participants (Cohort A, ALMI) and 3890 participants (Cohort B, Grip Strength). A detailed flow diagram of the complete participant selection process is presented in <xref rid="fig1-00368504261432840" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>.</p><fig position="float" id="fig1-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Flow diagram of participant inclusion and exclusion for the two-cohort analysis. DXA denotes dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry. ALMI denotes appendicular lean mass index. PA denotes physical activity. BMI denotes body mass index. PIR denotes poverty income ratio. VitD denotes vitamin D.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-fig1.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="section2B-00368504261432840"><title>Outcome measures</title><p>The primary outcome for lean mass was ALMI. ALMI was derived from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA). Appendicular lean mass (ALM) was calculated as the sum of lean mass from both arms (DXDLALE, DXDRALE) and both legs (DXDLLLE, DXDRLLE). This total, provided in grams, was converted to kilograms. Standing height (BMXHT, in centimeters) was converted to meters. ALMI was defined as ALM (kg) divided by height squared (m<sup>2</sup>).<sup>
<xref rid="bibr35-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>
</sup></p><p>The outcome for muscle function was maximal handgrip strength. Grip strength (kg) was assessed using a hand dynamometer. Up to six measurements were recorded, representing three trials for each hand. The final outcome variable was the single highest value from all valid trials.<sup><xref rid="bibr36-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>,<xref rid="bibr37-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">37</xref></sup></p></sec><sec id="section2C-00368504261432840"><title>Exposure assessment</title><p>The primary exposure was physical activity phenotype. Phenotypes were derived from minute-level accelerometer data (PAXMIN). Accelerometer data were first processed to identify valid wear. Wear time included minutes flagged as “Wake wear” (PAXPREDM = 1) or “Sleep wear” (PAXPREDM = 2). A “Valid Day” was defined as ≥ 600 wear minutes. Participants required ≥ 4 Valid Days for inclusion.</p><p>Five features were engineered from valid day data. Three functional features (fPC1, fPC2, fPC3) were extracted via functional principal component analysis (fPCA).<sup><xref rid="bibr38-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>,<xref rid="bibr39-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">39</xref></sup> The fPCA was applied to the 1440-minute mean daily activity profile. This profile consisted of MIMS activity units (PAXMTSM) for wake-wear minutes and zero for all other minutes.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr40-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>
</sup></p><p>Two structural features were calculated from wake-wear minutes. The Gini Index quantified inequality in MIMS values. Average Sedentary Bout Length was the mean duration of continuous minutes with MIMS values &lt; 100.<sup><xref rid="bibr41-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>,<xref rid="bibr42-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">42</xref></sup></p><p>These five features were standardized (<italic toggle="yes">Z</italic>-scores). K-Means clustering was applied to this 5-feature matrix. This process was used to derive distinct PA phenotypes.</p><p>A traditional physical activity metric, average daily MIMS volume (Avg_Daily_MIMS), was also calculated to represent the total volume of physical activity. This metric was derived by summing the MIMS triaxial values (PAXMTSM) for all “Wake wear” (PAXPREDM = 1) minutes on valid days. The total accumulated MIMS units across all valid days were summed and divided by the total number of valid days.</p></sec><sec id="section2D-00368504261432840"><title>Covariates</title><p>Covariates were selected based on prior literature. Sociodemographic variables included age (continuous), sex (Male, Female), and race/ethnicity (Mexican American, Other Hispanic, Non-Hispanic White, Non-Hispanic Black, Other Race/Multi-Racial). Socioeconomic status was quantified using the family income to poverty ratio (PIR). This calculated variable divides annual family income by the Department of Health and Human Services poverty guidelines specific to family size. Ratios below 1.0 indicate income below the official poverty threshold. This continuous metric serves as a standardized proxy for socioeconomic status in NHANES analyses.</p><p>Anthropometric and lifestyle variables were included. Body mass index (BMI, kg/m<sup>2</sup>) was used as a continuous variable. Smoking status was classified (never, former, current) using self-reported history. Daily alcohol intake (g/day) was calculated from self-reported frequency and quantity.</p><p>Dietary covariates included total energy intake (kcal/day) and total protein intake (g/day). These values represented the mean of two 24-hour dietary recall interviews. Single-day data were utilized when the second interview was unavailable. Laboratory assessment quantified serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations (nmol/L).</p><p>A comorbidity count (ranging 0–5) was computed. This count summed five conditions: hypertension, diabetes, arthritis, cardiovascular disease, and cancer. Hypertension was defined by self-report, medication use, or an average systolic blood pressure ≥ 130 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥80 mmHg. Diabetes was defined by self-report, medication use, HbA1c ≥ 6.5%, or fasting plasma glucose ≥126 mg/dL (with ≥ 8-hour fast). Arthritis, cardiovascular disease (congestive heart failure, coronary heart disease, heart attack, or stroke), and cancer were defined by self-reported physician diagnoses.</p><p>All detailed measurement processes of these variables are publicly available at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/</ext-link>.</p></sec><sec id="section2E-00368504261432840"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>The final 4-year MEC weight (WTMEC4YR) was computed by halving the provided 2-year MEC weight (WTMEC2YR). Two separate analytical cohorts were used. Cohort A was defined for the ALMI. It included 1756 participants aged 40 to 59 years. Cohort B was defined for the muscle function analysis (Grip Strength). It included 3890 participants aged 40 to 80 years.</p><p>All statistical analyses were performed using R with the “survey” package. The complex, multistage probability design of NHANES was incorporated in all analyses by specifying stratum (SDMVSTRA), primary sampling units (SDMVPSU), and the 4-year MEC weights (WTMEC4YR).</p><p>Baseline characteristics for both Cohort A and Cohort B were described, stratified by the derived PA phenotype. Continuous variables were presented as weighted means ± standard deviations, and categorical variables as weighted percentages. Weighted independent <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-tests (for continuous) and weighted Chi-squared tests (for categorical) were used to assess differences between phenotype groups.</p><p>Weighted multivariable linear regression models (svyglm) were used to examine the independent associations between PA phenotypes and the primary outcomes (ALMI in Cohort A; Grip Strength in Cohort B). The phenotype identified as the least active cluster was set as the reference group.</p><p>Three sequential models were constructed for each outcome:
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p><bold>Model 1:</bold> An unadjusted crude model.</p></list-item><list-item><p><bold>Model 2:</bold> Adjusted for age, sex, race/ethnicity, and BMI.</p></list-item><list-item><p><bold>Model 3:</bold> Adjusted for all variables in Model 2 plus total energy intake, protein intake, serum vitamin D, smoking status, daily alcohol intake, and the chronic disease count.</p></list-item></list></p><p>Results from these models were reported as <italic toggle="yes">β</italic> coefficients with 95% confidence intervals (CIs).</p><p>Finally, a model comparison was conducted to evaluate the explanatory utility of the phenotype-based model against a traditional volume-based metric. The Akaike information criterion (AIC) of the fully adjusted phenotype model (Model 3) was compared to an identical model where the PA_Phenotype variable was replaced by continuous Avg_Daily_MIMS. Statistical significance for all analyses was set at a two-sided <italic toggle="yes">p</italic>-value &lt; 0.05. To evaluate the robustness of the findings, we performed sensitivity analyses to test for potential effect modification by obesity status. An interaction term between PA phenotype and binary BMI categories (&lt;30 vs. ≥30 kg/m<sup>2</sup>) was entered into the fully adjusted Model 3 for the ALMI outcome. The reporting of this study follows the Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) guidelines.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr43-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>
</sup></p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="section3-00368504261432840"><title>Results</title><sec id="section3A-00368504261432840"><title>Derivation and characteristics of PA phenotypes</title><p>K-Means clustering was applied to the five standardized features (fPC1, fPC2, fPC3, Gini Index, Avg_Sed_Bout_Len) for 6045 eligible participants. Both the Elbow Method (Within Sum of Squares) and the Average Silhouette Width method indicated that <italic toggle="yes">K</italic> = 2 was the optimal cluster solution (<xref rid="fig2-00368504261432840" ref-type="fig">Figure 2A</xref>, B). A principal component analysis plot visually confirmed the distinct separation of the two clusters (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/suppl/10.1177/00368504261432840" ext-link-type="uri">Supplementary Figure S1</ext-link>).</p><fig position="float" id="fig2-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p>Derivation of optimal cluster solution. (A) The Elbow (WSS) method, showing the total within sum of squares relative to the number of clusters (k). (B) The Average Silhouette Width method, indicating a peak at k = 2, which represents the most stable two-cluster solution.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-fig2.jpg"/></fig><p>The identified clusters represent two distinct behavioral architectures (<xref rid="fig3-00368504261432840" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>). The first phenotype is low-volume/fragmented (LVF: lower MIMS volume, shorter sedentary bouts). This group accumulates minimal total activity volume. Sedentary time occurs in frequent and brief intervals. The pattern reflects constant low-intensity interruption without sustained movement. The second phenotype is high-volume/consolidated (HVC: higher MIMS volume, longer sedentary bouts). This group achieves high total physical activity volume. Sedentary behavior accumulates in prolonged and uninterrupted bouts. This profile combines structured exercise intervals with extended periods of immobilization. These descriptions rely on absolute behavioral patterns rather than relative statistical scores.</p><fig position="float" id="fig3-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Physical activity phenotype profiles (N = 6045). This plot shows the mean standardized Z-scores for the five features used in clustering for Phenotype 1 (“HVC”, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3245) and Phenotype 2 (LVF, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2800). The dashed line at 0 represents the population mean. Features included: Avg_Sed_Bout_Len (Average Sedentary Bout Length), fPC1_Score (Functional Principal Component 1), fPC2_Score, fPC3_Score, and Gini_Index. HVC denotes the high-volume consolidated phenotype. LVF denotes the low-volume fragmented phenotype. PA denotes physical activity.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-fig3.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="section3B-00368504261432840"><title>Baseline participant characteristics</title><sec id="section3B1-00368504261432840"><title>Cohort A: lean mass analysis sample</title><p>Cohort A comprised 1756 participants aged 40 to 59 years (<xref rid="table1-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). The HVC and LVF phenotypes exhibited similar baseline distributions for age, sex, and BMI. However, racial/ethnic composition differed significantly between groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">=</italic> 0.002). Socioeconomic status also varied, with the LVF group reporting a higher mean poverty income ratio compared to the HVC group (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">&lt;</italic> 0.001). As expected by the phenotype definitions, the HVC group accumulated significantly higher daily AVG_DAILY_MIMS volume. No significant differences existed for total energy intake, protein consumption, smoking status, alcohol intake, or chronic disease burden. The primary outcome for this cohort, ALMI, was comparable between phenotypes at baseline.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="table1-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Baseline characteristics of participants in Cohort A (age 40–59, N = 1756) stratified by physical activity phenotype.</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table1.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Level</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">HVC</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">LVF</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SMD</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>
<italic toggle="yes">N</italic>
</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1038</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">718</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Age (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">49.22 (5.66)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">49.29 (5.59)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.521</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.047</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">
<bold>Sex (%)</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">513 (48.40)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">387 (55.10)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.052</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.134</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">525 (51.60)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">331 (44.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">
<bold>Race (%)</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mexican American</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">143 (8.00)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">61 (4.30)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.002</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.244</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other Hispanic</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">103 (5.40)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">47 (3.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Non-Hispanic White</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">437 (70.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">350 (76.70)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Non-Hispanic Black</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">250 (10.60)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">138 (7.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other Race/Multi-Racial</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">105 (5.00)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">122 (7.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>PIR (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.69 (1.65)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.06 (1.73)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.209</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>BMI (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.33 (6.51)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.63 (6.75)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.355</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.064</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Energy (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2181.92 (812.71)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2097.01 (810.54)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.118</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.109</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Protein (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.19 (36.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">84.15 (37.33)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.459</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.057</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>VitaminD (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">64.17 (26.87)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">64.95 (25.22)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.701</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.024</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">
<bold>Smoking (%)</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Never Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">516 (47.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">363 (51.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.123</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.127</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Former Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">228 (25.10)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">189 (26.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Current Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">294 (27.30)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">166 (21.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Alcohol_g (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.82 (20.16)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.14 (15.18)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.651</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.035</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Chronic_Count (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.06 (0.95)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.06 (0.98)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.346</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.064</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>ALMI (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.00 (1.70)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.01 (1.64)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.445</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.055</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>Grip_Strength (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">38.96 (10.60)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">39.60 (10.54)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.055</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.128</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<bold>AVG_DAILY_MIMS (mean (SD))</bold>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">14,499.10 (2767.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9943.35 (2683.45)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.575</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn1-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> Data presented as weighted mean (SD) for continuous variables and weighted frequency (%) for categorical variables. <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-values derived from weighted <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-tests or Chi-squared tests. SD: standard deviation; SMD: standardized mean difference; PIR: poverty income ratio; BMI: body mass index; ALMI: appendicular lean mass index; Avg_Daily_MIMS: average daily Monitor-Independent Movement Summary units.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="section3B2-00368504261432840"><title>Cohort B: muscle function analysis sample</title><p>Cohort B included 3890 participants aged 40 to 80 years (<xref rid="table2-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). In contrast to Cohort A, the phenotype groups in this wider age range demonstrated distinct demographic and health profiles. The LVF group was significantly older (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">&lt;</italic> 0.001) and possessed a higher proportion of males (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">&lt;</italic> 0.001) compared to the HVC group. The LVF group also presented a less favorable clinical profile, characterized by a significantly higher mean BMI (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">=</italic> 0.018) and a greater number of comorbidities (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> <italic toggle="yes">&lt;</italic> 0.001). Furthermore, the LVF group reported lower mean intakes of total energy and protein. Consistent with Cohort A, the HVC group maintained substantially higher AVG_DAILY_MIMS levels. Baseline grip strength did not differ statistically between the two phenotypes.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="table2-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Baseline characteristics of participants in Cohort B (age 40–80, N = 3890) stratified by physical activity phenotype.</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table2.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Level</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">HVC</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">LVF</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SMD</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">N</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2024</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1866</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">57.37 (11.11)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.90 (12.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.228</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sex (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">982 (46.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1069 (54.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.167</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1042 (53.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">797 (45.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Race (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mexican American</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">242 (6.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">133 (3.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.213</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other Hispanic</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">214 (4.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">126 (2.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Non-Hispanic White</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">901 (74.40)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1007 (80.70)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Non-Hispanic Black</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">498 (9.90)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">396 (7.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other Race/Multi-Racial</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">169 (4.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">204 (5.60)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PIR (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.69 (1.64)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.78 (1.65)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.272</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.044</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMI (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.12 (6.63)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">30.10 (7.04)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.018</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.127</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Energy (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2073.36 (779.15)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1945.39 (755.34)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.004</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.17</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Protein (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.65 (34.29)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.96 (33.39)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.034</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.104</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vitamin D (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.57 (28.70)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.74 (30.30)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.901</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.006</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Smoking (%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Never Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">981 (48.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">827 (46.80)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.038</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.12</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Former Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">588 (30.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">705 (35.50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Current Smoker</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">455 (21.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">334 (17.70)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Alcohol_g (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.81 (18.05)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.86 (13.38)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.051</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.095</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chronic_Count (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.41 (1.06)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.69 (1.20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.163</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grip_Strength (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">36.19 (10.74)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">36.10 (11.03)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.063</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">AVG_DAILY_MIMS (mean (SD))</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> 13,685.46 (2809.46)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8848.72 (2575.39)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.692</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn2-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> Data presented as weighted mean (SD) for continuous variables and weighted frequency (%) for categorical variables. <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-values derived from weighted <italic toggle="yes">t</italic>-tests or Chi-squared tests. SD: standard deviation; SMD: standardized mean difference; PIR: poverty income ratio; BMI: body mass index; Avg_Daily_MIMS: average daily Monitor-Independent Movement Summary units.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec id="section3C-00368504261432840"><title>Associations of PA phenotypes with muscle health outcomes</title><sec id="section3C1-00368504261432840"><title>Cohort A: lean mass (ALMI)</title><p><xref rid="table3-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref> presents the weighted linear regression analyses for ALMI. In the unadjusted Model 1, ALMI did not differ significantly between the HVC and the reference group (LVF) (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = −0.09; 95% CI, −0.32 to 0.15). Adjustment for demographic covariates in Model 2 revealed a significant positive association. HVC exhibited significantly higher ALMI compared to LVF (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 0.11; 95% CI, 0.03 to 0.19). This positive association remained robust in Model 3 after further adjustment for dietary and lifestyle factors (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 0.11; 95% CI, 0.03 to 0.18). This difference represents 0.06 standard deviations of the cohort mean. This magnitude is numerically equivalent to offsetting five years of age-related lean mass decline. This finding is visually represented in <xref rid="fig4-00368504261432840" ref-type="fig">Figure 4A</xref>.</p><fig position="float" id="fig4-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Forest plots illustrating the disparate associations of physical activity phenotypes with lean mass versus muscle function. HVC denotes the high-volume consolidated phenotype. LVF denotes the low-volume fragmented phenotype. PA denotes physical activity.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-fig4.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="table3-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>Weighted linear regression analysis of the associations between physical activity phenotypes and ALMI in cohort A (N = 1756).</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table3.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Physical activity 
phenotype</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No. of 
participants</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 1 (Crude)</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 2</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 3</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LVF</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">718</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HVC</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1038</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.09 (−0.32, 0.15)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.11 (0.03, 0.19)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.11 (0.03, 0.18)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">p</italic>-Value</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.445</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.007</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.007</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn3-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> Data are presented as weighted <italic toggle="yes">β</italic> coefficients (95% Confidence Intervals). Bold values indicate statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). Model 1: Unadjusted. Model 2: Adjusted for age, sex, race/ethnicity, and BMI. Model 3: Adjusted for Model 2 covariates plus total energy intake, protein intake, serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, smoking status, alcohol intake, and chronic disease count. Abbreviation: ALMI, appendicular lean mass index.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Sensitivity analyses revealed no significant interaction between PA phenotype and obesity status (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> for interaction &gt; 0.05), indicating that the positive association between the HVC phenotype and lean mass was consistent across both non-obese and obese participants.</p></sec><sec id="section3C2-00368504261432840"><title>Cohort B: muscle function (grip strength)</title><p><xref rid="table4-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 4</xref> summarizes the associations between PA phenotypes and grip strength. In contrast to the results for lean mass, no significant associations emerged for muscle function across all models. The unadjusted Model 1 showed no statistical difference in grip strength between phenotypes (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = −0.70; 95% CI, −1.56 to 0.17). Adjustment for demographic factors in Model 2 did not alter this null result (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 0.01; 95% CI, −0.59 to 0.61). The fully adjusted Model 3 similarly demonstrated no significant relationship between the HVC phenotype and grip strength (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = −0.07; 95% CI, −0.70 to 0.56). This null association is depicted in <xref rid="fig4-00368504261432840" ref-type="fig">Figure 4B</xref>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="table4-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4.</label><caption><p>Weighted linear regression analysis of the associations between physical activity phenotypes and muscle function (grip strength) in Cohort B (N = 3890).</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table4.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Physical activity 
phenotype</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No. of 
participants</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 1 (Crude)</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 2</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model 3</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LVF</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1866</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0 (Reference)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HVC</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2024</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.70 (−1.56, 0.17)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.01 (−0.59, 0.61)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">−0.07 (−0.70, 0.56)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">p</italic>-Value</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.969</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.815</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn4-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> Data are presented as weighted <italic toggle="yes">β</italic> coefficients (95% Confidence Intervals). Model 1: Unadjusted. Model 2: Adjusted for age, sex, race/ethnicity, and BMI. Model 3: Adjusted for Model 2 covariates plus total energy intake, protein intake, serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, smoking status, alcohol intake, and chronic disease count. HVC denotes the high-volume consolidated phenotype. LVF denotes the low-volume fragmented phenotype. PA denotes physical activity.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec id="section3D-00368504261432840"><title>Model comparison with traditional AVG_DAILY_MIMS</title><p>To contextualize the phenotype-based findings, parallel analyses were conducted using the traditional continuous volume metric (Avg_Daily_MIMS). <xref rid="table5-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 5</xref> presents the fully adjusted associations for this volume-based metric in both cohorts. In Cohort A, a significant positive association existed between total activity volume and ALMI (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 3.81 × 10<sup>−5</sup>; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001). Conversely, in Cohort B, total activity volume showed no statistically significant association with grip strength (<italic toggle="yes">β</italic> = 1.42 × 10<sup>−5</sup>; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.732).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="table5-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5.</label><caption><p>Weighted linear regression analysis of the associations between traditional activity volume (Avg_Daily_MIMS) and muscle outcomes (Model 3).</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table5.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Outcome (Cohort)</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">β</italic> (95% CI)</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Standard error</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">p</italic>-Value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">ALMI (Cohort A, N = 1756)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.81 × 10<sup>−5</sup> (1.94 × 10<sup>−6</sup>, 4.95 × 10<sup>−5</sup>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.40 × 10<sup>−6</sup></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grip Strength (Cohort B, N = 3890)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.42 × 10<sup>−5</sup> (−7.18 × 10<sup>−5</sup>, 1.00 × 10<sup>−4</sup>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.08 × 10<sup>−5</sup></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.732</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn5-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> Model 3 is adjusted for age, sex, race/ethnicity, BMI, total energy intake, protein intake, serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, smoking status, alcohol intake, and chronic disease count. <italic toggle="yes">β</italic> coefficients represent the change in outcome per unit increase in daily MIMS. Bold values indicate statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). ALMI: appendicular lean mass index; CI: confidence interval; MIMS: Monitor-Independent Movement Summary.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>The explanatory power of the phenotype-based models (Model 3 from Section 3.3) was compared against these volume-based models using the AIC. As detailed in <xref rid="table6-00368504261432840" ref-type="table">Table 6</xref>, the AIC values for both approaches were substantially equivalent. In Cohort A, the volume-based model yielded an AIC of 21.50, while the phenotype-based model yielded an AIC of 22.16. Similarly, in Cohort B, the AIC was 21.74 for the volume-based model and 22.22 for the phenotype-based model. The difference in AIC (ΔAIC) between the two modeling approaches remained below 1.0 for both muscle health outcomes.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="table6-00368504261432840" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6.</label><caption><p>Comparison of model fit (AIC) between phenotype-based and volume-based models.</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="10.1177_00368504261432840-table6.jpg"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="left" span="1"/><col align="char" char="." span="1"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cohort (outcome)</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Model type</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Main exposure variable</th><th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">AIC</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Cohort A (ALMI)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">New Model</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PA Phenotype (Categorical)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.16</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Old Model</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Avg_Daily_MIMS (Continuous)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.5</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Difference (<italic toggle="yes">Δ</italic>AIC)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.66</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Cohort B (Grip)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">New Model</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PA Phenotype (Categorical)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.22</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Old Model</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Avg_Daily_MIMS (Continuous)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.74</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Difference (<italic toggle="yes">Δ</italic>AIC)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.48</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn6-00368504261432840"><p><italic toggle="yes">Note:</italic> AIC values are derived from the fully adjusted Model 3 for each outcome. A lower AIC indicates a better model fit, though differences &lt; 2.0 generally indicate equivalent explanatory power. AIC: Akaike Information Criterion; PA: physical activity; ALMI: appendicular lean mass index.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="section4-00368504261432840"><title>Discussion</title><p>This cross-sectional analysis identified two distinct accelerometer-derived phenotypes characterized by opposing patterns of activity volume and sedentary fragmentation. The HVC phenotype (higher MIMS volume, longer sedentary bouts) demonstrated a robust positive association with ALMI compared to the LVF phenotype (lower MIMS volume, shorter sedentary bouts). Yet, this structural advantage did not translate into improved muscle function. Grip strength remained statistically indistinguishable between the two groups despite large disparities in total activity volume. Model comparisons indicated that these pattern-based phenotypes offer explanatory utility equivalent to continuous volume metrics. These results highlight a specific decoupling between muscle size and muscle strength linked to daily activity composition.</p><p>This study identifies a distinct decoupling between ALM and grip strength within the HVC phenotype. Historical consensus often assumed a linear, synchronous trajectory for muscle morphology and physical performance.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr44-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>
</sup> Contemporary research challenges this view. Recent longitudinal analyses indicate that muscle strength declines faster than lean mass and serves as a more potent predictor of adverse health outcomes.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr45-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>
</sup> Our data reinforces this non-linear relationship.<sup><xref rid="bibr46-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>,<xref rid="bibr47-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">47</xref></sup> The HVC maintained muscle structural integrity presumably through high daily movement volume. This advantage is numerically equivalent to offsetting 5 years of age-related lean mass decline. However, this volume failed to translate into functional grip strength performance. This discordance aligns with observations that muscle quality and physical capability are distinct constructs from mere muscle size.<sup><xref rid="bibr48-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,<xref rid="bibr49-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">49</xref></sup></p><p>Two potential mechanisms explain the observed functional deficit. The first involves the principle of specificity. The HVC phenotype reflects ambulatory, low-intensity movement. High-intensity resistance stimulus is required to maximize neuromuscular force production.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr44-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>
</sup> Activity volume alone supports muscle maintenance but is insufficient for peak strength development.<sup><xref rid="bibr50-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>,<xref rid="bibr51-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">51</xref></sup> Consequently, the lack of functional advantage may simply reflect insufficient exposure to resistance-type loading. A second possibility involves the deleterious effects of prolonged sedentary behavior. Extended immobilization theoretically impairs motor unit recruitment.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr52-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>
</sup> However, current data cannot definitively distinguish between the toxicity of sedentary structure and the simple absence of training stimulus.</p><p>Statistical equivalence in model fit (AIC) does not imply biological equivalence. Aggregate volume metrics effectively predict lean mass retention.<sup><xref rid="bibr53-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>,<xref rid="bibr54-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">54</xref></sup> However, scalar summation obscures the temporal architecture of movement. The identified HVC phenotype demonstrates that high total volume frequently coexists with consolidated sedentary behavior. This specific “Active Couch Potato” profile preserves muscle size but fails to optimize function. Simple volume metrics aggregate movement into a single scalar value. This summation cannot distinguish pathogenic sedentary consolidation from healthy, fragmented rest.<sup><xref rid="bibr55-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>,<xref rid="bibr56-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">56</xref></sup> Clustering resolves this biological ambiguity.<sup><xref rid="bibr57-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>,<xref rid="bibr58-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">58</xref></sup> It isolates the specific behavioral combination responsible for mass-function decoupling. This approach reveals that prolonged sedentary bouts impair neuromuscular performance even when total volume remains high. Linear volume models obscure this hypothesis-generating clinical utility.</p><p>Conventional classifications rely on arbitrary thresholds. Subjective “high-versus-low” quadrants force artificial boundaries upon continuous behavioral data.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr59-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>
</sup> Unsupervised machine learning eliminates this investigator bias.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr60-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>
</sup> The derived phenotypes confirm that high activity volume naturally co-occurs with prolonged sedentary bouts in this population. This specific combination represents a dominant biological reality rather than a theoretical category.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr61-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>
</sup> Simple descriptors obscure this natural clustering by imposing fixed cut-offs. The phenotype approach validates the existence of this specific “active-sedentary” behavioral architecture. This structural precision explains the observed decoupling between preserved lean mass and compromised function.<sup><xref rid="bibr62-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>,<xref rid="bibr63-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">63</xref></sup></p><p>The HVC phenotype epitomizes the modern “active couch potato” lifestyle. These individuals accumulate high total activity volumes yet engage in prolonged, continuous sedentary bouts. While their high activity volume preserves ALM compared to the LVF, the extended duration of their sedentary episodes introduces a distinct physiological liability. Uninterrupted sitting significantly blunts endothelium-independent vasodilation and reduces resting blood flow to the lower limbs.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr64-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>
</sup> This vascular dysfunction suggests that the protective effects of total activity volume are partially negated by the metabolic toxicity of prolonged immobilization.</p><p>The absence of a grip strength advantage in the HVC despite their greater lean mass points to a neuromuscular deficit driven by this sedentary behavior. Animal models demonstrate that sedentary confinement induces rapid declines in grip strength and mitochondrial enzyme activity even when nutrition is controlled.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr65-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>
</sup> The HVC lack the frequent physical transitions and incidental movements inherent to the fragmented profile. These frequent interruptions likely provide essential neuromuscular maintenance that is absent in the structured pattern. Consequently, preserving muscle function requires more than maintaining activity volume. Public health guidelines for this demographic must prioritize breaking prolonged sedentary bouts and integrating specific resistance training to ensure muscle quality matches muscle size.<sup>
<xref rid="bibr66-00368504261432840" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>
</sup></p><p>These findings present hypothesis-generating clinical utility for sarcopenia prevention. Assessment of physical activity patterns provides distinct insights beyond traditional total volume metrics. Clinicians should evaluate sedentary fragmentation alongside total activity to identify patients at risk of mass-function decoupling. Importantly, the observed associations demonstrated robustness across body composition profiles. The lack of a significant interaction with obesity status suggests that the benefits of a structured physical activity pattern on lean mass maintenance are generalizable, regardless of obesity classification. However, several limitations warrant consideration. The analytical cohorts possessed distinct age ranges. Cohort A included individuals aged 40 to 59 years. Cohort B included individuals aged 40 to 80 years. This discrepancy limits direct comparability. Age variance potentially confounds the interpretation of mass-function decoupling across outcomes. First, the cross-sectional design precludes causal inferences. Phenotypes may reflect existing functional capacities rather than drive them. Second, handgrip strength serves as a limited proxy for neuromuscular function. This isometric upper-body metric may not capture lower-limb power or specific effects of activity fragmentation. Third, comparisons against classical volume-based stratifications were omitted. Clustering was not assessed against volume tertiles or joint volume-sedentary quadrants. Whether unsupervised phenotypes yield superior clinical utility over simple quantile models requires further validation. Finally, wrist-worn accelerometry detects general ambulation but underestimates stationary resistance loads. This instrumentation limitation misclassifies participants executing structured resistance training with minimal wrist displacement. High-tension static loads register as low activity volume or sedentary time. This misclassification directly confounds the evaluation of the resistance stimulus hypothesis.</p></sec><sec id="section5-00368504261432840"><title>Conclusion</title><p>The “high-volume/consolidated” phenotype demonstrated a significant positive association with ALMI compared to the “low-volume/fragmented” group. However, this structural advantage did not extend to muscle function. Grip strength remained equivalent between the two phenotypes. These findings indicate a distinct decoupling between muscle morphology and physical performance linked to activity composition. Consolidated sedentary bouts are associated with an absence of functional gain despite high total volume. This outcome may result from metabolic effects of prolonged immobilization or a lack of resistance stimulus. Cross-sectional design precludes definitive causal assertions regarding sedentary harm. Longitudinal research is required to distinguish between the lack of benefit and active physiological compromise.</p></sec><sec id="section6-00368504261432840" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplemental Material</title><supplementary-material id="suppl1-00368504261432840" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><caption><title>sj-docx-1-sci-10.1177_00368504261432840 - Supplemental material for Beyond aggregate volume—Accelerometer-derived activity phenotypes reveal a decoupling of lean mass and function: A cross-sectional study</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="sj-docx-1-sci-10.1177_00368504261432840.docx" position="float" orientation="portrait"/><p>Supplemental material, sj-docx-1-sci-10.1177_00368504261432840 for Beyond aggregate volume—Accelerometer-derived activity phenotypes reveal a decoupling of lean mass and function: A cross-sectional study by Xiangyu Wang and Xiaoming Wu in Science Progress</p></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>ORCID iDs:</bold> Xiangyu Wang <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9436-6630" ext-link-type="uri">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9436-6630</ext-link></p><p>Xiaoming Wu <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://orcid.org/0009-0008-4571-7108" ext-link-type="uri">https://orcid.org/0009-0008-4571-7108</ext-link></p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Ethics approval and consent to participate:</bold> The National Center for Health Statistics Research Ethics Review Board approved the original survey protocols (Protocol #2011-17). All participants provided written informed consent. This study involved the secondary analysis of de-identified, publicly available data. Consequently, the analysis was deemed exempt from review by the institutional review board of Capital Normal hUniversity.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Consent for publication:</bold> Not applicable.</p></fn><fn fn-type="con"><p><bold>Author contributions:</bold> Xiangyu Wang and Xiaoming Wu conceptualized the study and designed the methodology. Xiangyu Wang performed the data curation, formal analysis, and drafted the original manuscript. Xiaoming Wu contributed to the interpretation of results and critically revised the manuscript. Both authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></fn><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure"><p><bold>Funding:</bold> The authors received no financial support for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Availability of data and code:</bold> This study utilized publicly available data from the NHANES for the 2011–2012 and 2013–2014 cycles. The raw datasets are available for download from the National Center for Health Statistics website (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/" ext-link-type="uri">www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes/</ext-link>). To facilitate the reproducibility of these methods, the complete R analytical code used for data processing, clustering, and statistical modeling has been deposited in a public GitHub repository (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://github.com/Michael1006-dev/NHANES_Activity_Phenotypes_Analysis" ext-link-type="uri">https://github.com/Michael1006-dev/NHANES_Activity_Phenotypes_Analysis</ext-link>).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Supplemental material:</bold> Supplemental material for this article is available online.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="bibr1-00368504261432840"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Antoun</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Watelain</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pinti</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Influence of two strength training modalities (hypertrophy vs. contrast training) on muscular strength, bone health parameters and quality of life in a group of older adults with low skeletal muscle mass index</article-title>. <source>J Clin Densitom</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>28</volume>: <fpage>10</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jocd.2025.101563</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39864269</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr2-00368504261432840"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dechsupa</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yingsakmongkol</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Limthongkul</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Vitamin D supplementation improves muscle mass, physical function, and quality of life in patients with degenerative lumbar disease</article-title>. <source>CTS-Clin Transl Sci</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>18</volume>: <fpage>9</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/cts.70315</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12322578</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40761159</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr3-00368504261432840"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nie</surname><given-names>CZ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>QW</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Long-term consumption of highland barley tea promotes healthy aging of skeletal muscle</article-title>. <source>Food Sci Human Wellness</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>14</volume>: <fpage>10</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr4-00368504261432840"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Beaudart</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Alcazar</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aprahamian</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Health outcomes of sarcopenia: a consensus report by the outcome working group of the global leadership initiative in sarcopenia (GLIS)</article-title>. <source>Aging Clin Exp Res</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>37</volume>: <fpage>13</fpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40520-025-02995-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11929733</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40120052</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr5-00368504261432840"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cardoso</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Santos</surname><given-names>TV</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ramon-Krauel</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Impact of bariatric and metabolic surgery on sarcopenia-related parameters according to the EWGSOP2 consensus criteria in persons living with obesity</article-title>. <source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>35</volume>: <fpage>1900</fpage>–<lpage>1910</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40164918</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11695-025-07816-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12065728</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr6-00368504261432840"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>LK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hsiao</surname><given-names>FY</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Akishita</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>A focus shift from sarcopenia to muscle health in the Asian working group for Sarcopenia 2025 consensus update</article-title>. <source>Nature Aging</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>5</volume>: <fpage>2164</fpage>–<lpage>2175</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41188603</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s43587-025-01004-y</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr7-00368504261432840"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Noda</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kamiya</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hamazaki</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Improved appendicular muscle strength predicts lower mortality in patients with heart failure</article-title>. <source>Nutrition</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>136</volume>: <fpage>7</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nut.2025.112774</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40315559</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr8-00368504261432840"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Uzun</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Heybeli</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>The impact of undernutrition on the association between hypomagnesemia and dynapenia in older women</article-title>. <source>BMC Geriatr</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>25</volume>: <fpage>8</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39910454</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12877-025-05742-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11796258</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr9-00368504261432840"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>XX</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lyu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>The relationship between sleep quality and depressive symptoms in older adults: the mediated role of muscle strength (dynapenia)</article-title>. <source>BMC Public Health</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>24</volume>: <fpage>7</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39725922</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12889-024-21178-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11674542</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr10-00368504261432840"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wiedmaier-Barros</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Higueras-Fresnillo</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sadarangani</surname><given-names>KP</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Associations of pattern-recognition-measured daily activities with sarcopenia and sarcopenic obesity in old age: the IMPACT65 + study</article-title>. <source>Exp Gerontol</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>194</volume>: <fpage>8</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.exger.2024.112511</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38964430</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr11-00368504261432840"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bellettiere</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>LaMonte</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Healy</surname><given-names>GN</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Sedentary behavior and diabetes risk among women over the age of 65 years: the OPACH study</article-title>. <source>Diabetes Care</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>44</volume>: <fpage>563</fpage>–<lpage>570</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33273043</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2337/dc20-0709</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7818329</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr12-00368504261432840"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>WJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hillsdon</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Patterns of accelerometer-measured physical activity and health outcomes in adults: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Med Sci Sports Exercise</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>54</volume>: <fpage>1155</fpage>–<lpage>1166</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002900</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35220369</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr13-00368504261432840"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Letts</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jakubowski</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>King-Dowling</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Accelerometer techniques for capturing human movement validated against direct observation: a scoping review</article-title>. <source>Physiol Meas</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>45</volume>: <fpage>51</fpage>. <comment>Review</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1088/1361-6579/ad45aa</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38688297</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr14-00368504261432840"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pontin</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lomax</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Characterisation of temporal patterns in step count behaviour from smartphone app data: an unsupervised machine learning approach</article-title>. <source>Int J Environ Res Public Health</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>18</volume>: <fpage>27</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/ijerph182111476</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8583116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34769991</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr15-00368504261432840"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Urbanek</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Babiker</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>HIP accelerometry activity patterns improve machine learning prediction of 1-year moca score change</article-title>. <source>Innov Aging</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>5</volume>: <fpage>444</fpage>–<lpage>444</lpage>. <comment>Meeting Abstract</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr16-00368504261432840"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aggio</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sartini</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Papacosta</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Cross-sectional associations of objectively measured physical activity and sedentary time with sarcopenia and sarcopenic obesity in older men</article-title>. <source>Prev Med</source>
<year>2016</year>; <volume>91</volume>: <fpage>264</fpage>–<lpage>272</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27575317</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ypmed.2016.08.040</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5061552</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr17-00368504261432840"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>van der Velde</surname><given-names>JHPM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Savelberg</surname><given-names>HHCM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>van der Berg</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Sedentary behavior is only marginally associated with physical function in adults aged 40–75 years—the Maastricht study</article-title>. <source>Front Physiol</source>
<year>2017</year>: <volume>8</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00242</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5403943</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28487660</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr18-00368504261432840"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stamatakis</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hamer</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Associations of sitting and physical activity with grip strength and balance in mid-life: 1970 British cohort study</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<year>2020</year>; <volume>30</volume>: <fpage>2371</fpage>–<lpage>2381</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32757425</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.13793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8432142</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr19-00368504261432840"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ferrari</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Then</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rottenkolber</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Longitudinal association of type 2 diabetes and insulin therapy with muscle parameters in the KORA-age study</article-title>. <source>Acta Diabetol</source>
<year>2020</year>; <volume>57</volume>: <fpage>1057</fpage>–<lpage>1063</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32246270</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00592-020-01523-7</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr20-00368504261432840"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chao</surname><given-names>Y-P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>W-H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>T-C</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Longitudinal cohort study investigating fall risk across diverse muscle health statuses among older people in the community</article-title>. <source>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>16</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13788</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11955838</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40162590</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr21-00368504261432840"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>RE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Newman</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Using wearable devices to examine the associations of sedentary behavior with perceived and performance fatigability among older adults: The study of muscle, mobility and aging (SOMMA)</article-title>. <source>Sensors</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>25</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/s25092722</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12074308</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40363161</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr22-00368504261432840"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rosenberg</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rillamas-Sun</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bellettiere</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Accelerometer-measured sedentary patterns are associated with incident falls in older women</article-title>. <source>J Am Geriatr Soc</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>69</volume>: <fpage>718</fpage>–<lpage>725</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33252141</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jgs.16923</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8020891</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr23-00368504261432840"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ha</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wakefield</surname><given-names>CE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Diaz</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Patterns of physical activity and sedentary behavior in child and adolescent cancer survivors assessed using wrist accelerometry: a cluster analysis approach</article-title>. <source>Health Informatics J</source>
<year>2023</year>: <fpage>29</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/14604582231212525</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37903362</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr24-00368504261432840"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ensari</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Caceres</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jackman</surname><given-names>KB</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Characterizing daily physical activity patterns with unsupervised learning via functional mixture models</article-title>. <source>J Behav Med</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>48</volume>: <fpage>149</fpage>–<lpage>161</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39306631</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s10865-024-00519-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12967293</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr25-00368504261432840"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>James</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Filterk: a new outlier detection method for k-means clustering of physical activity</article-title>. <source>J Biomed Inform</source>
<year>2020</year>; <volume>104</volume>: <fpage>10</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jbi.2020.103397</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32113005</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr26-00368504261432840"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>PF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ning</surname><given-names>XQ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Association between circadian physical activity patterns and cancer incidence through regulation of inflammation: a UK biobank study</article-title>. <source>Prev Med</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>179</volume>: <fpage>8</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ypmed.2023.107831</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38145876</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr27-00368504261432840"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rovniak</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Saelens</surname><given-names>BE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sallis</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Adults’ physical activity patterns across life domains: cluster analysis with replication</article-title>. <source>Health Psychol</source>
<year>2010</year>; <volume>29</volume>: <fpage>496</fpage>–<lpage>505</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20836604</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1037/a0020428</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3021982</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr28-00368504261432840"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>LT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>JQ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bhadra</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Temporal patterns of diet and physical activity and of diet alone have more numerous relationships with health and disease status indicators compared to temporal patterns of physical activity alone</article-title>. <source>J Acad Nutr Diet</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>123</volume>: <fpage>23</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jand.2023.07.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10789913</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37437807</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr29-00368504261432840"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>BI</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ismaeel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>McCarthy</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>The utility of the rodent synergist ablation model in identifying molecular and cellular mechanisms of skeletal muscle hypertrophy</article-title>. <source>Am J Physiol-Cell Physiol</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>327</volume>: <comment>C601</comment>–<lpage>C606</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpcell.00362.2024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11427019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39069822</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr30-00368504261432840"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Neto</surname><given-names>WK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Silva</surname><given-names>WD</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>de Oliveira</surname><given-names>TVA</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Muscle hypertrophy is correlated with load progression delta, climb volume, and total load volume in rodents undergoing different ladder-based resistance training protocols</article-title>. <source>Tissue Cell</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>75</volume>: <fpage>9</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.tice.2021.101725</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35016105</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr31-00368504261432840"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>RMY</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Exploring motor unit and neuromuscular junction dysfunction in aging and sarcopenia: insights from electromyography in systematic review</article-title>. <source>GeroScience</source>
<year>2025</year>: <fpage>76</fpage>. <comment>Review; Early Access</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11357-025-01760-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40627125</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr32-00368504261432840"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sarto</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Valli</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Monti</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Motor unit alterations with muscle disuse: what's new?</article-title>
<source>J Physiol-London</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>600</volume>: <fpage>4811</fpage>–<lpage>4813</lpage>. <comment>Editorial Material</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36200458</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1113/JP283868</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr33-00368504261432840"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>XM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>PX</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>GZ</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Commentary: association between metallic implants and stroke in US adults from NHANES 2015-2023 a cross-sectional study</article-title>. <source>Front Aging Neurosci</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>17</volume>: <fpage>4</fpage>. <comment>Editorial Material</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fnagi.2025.1586693</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12133842</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40469845</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr34-00368504261432840"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>He</surname><given-names>QW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Overactive bladder and monocyte-to-lymphocyte ratio: a cross-sectional investigation using NHANES data</article-title>. <source>Asian J Surg</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>48</volume>: <fpage>7055</fpage>–<lpage>7056</lpage>. <comment>Letter</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr35-00368504261432840"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tachiki</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kouda</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dongmei</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Muscle strength is associated with bone health independently of muscle mass in postmenopausal women: the Japanese population-based osteoporosis study</article-title>. <source>J Bone Miner Metab</source>
<year>2019</year>; <volume>37</volume>: <fpage>53</fpage>–<lpage>59</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29282553</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00774-017-0895-7</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr36-00368504261432840"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hsieh</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>SI</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hsieh</surname><given-names>HF</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Low muscle strength and mortality: key risk factors in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey retrospective cohort study</article-title>. <source>Medicine (Baltimore)</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>104</volume>: <fpage>11</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/MD.0000000000045284</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12537101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41189181</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr37-00368504261432840"><label>37</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>CY</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>The association between dietary oxidative balance score and muscle strength: NHANES 2011-2014</article-title>. <source>Front Nutr</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>12</volume>: <fpage>10</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fnut.2025.1563451</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12172179</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40529423</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr38-00368504261432840"><label>38</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>GX</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Robust functional principal component analysis via a functional pairwise spatial sign operator</article-title>. <source>Biometrics</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>79</volume>: <fpage>1239</fpage>–<lpage>1253</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/biom.13695</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35583919</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9672141</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr39-00368504261432840"><label>39</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>HC</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Functional principal component analysis estimator for non-Gaussian data</article-title>. <source>J Stat Comput Simul</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>92</volume>: <fpage>2788</fpage>–<lpage>2801</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr40-00368504261432840"><label>40</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aguiar</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Turner</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pleuss</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Daily and peak monitor independent movement summary (MIMS) values associated with metabolic syndrome: NHANES 2011-12 and 2013-14</article-title>. <source>Scand J Med Sci Sports</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>34</volume>: <fpage>9</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/sms.14762</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39535457</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr41-00368504261432840"><label>41</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chastin</surname><given-names>SFM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Granat</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Methods for objective measure, quantification and analysis of sedentary behaviour and inactivity</article-title>. <source>Gait Posture</source>
<year>2010</year>; <volume>31</volume>: <fpage>82</fpage>–<lpage>86</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19854651</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2009.09.002</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr42-00368504261432840"><label>42</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Knaeps</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bourgois</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Charlier</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Associations between physical activity and health-related fitness - volume versus pattern</article-title>. <source>J Sports Sci</source>
<year>2017</year>; <volume>35</volume>: <fpage>539</fpage>–<lpage>546</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27133455</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/02640414.2016.1178393</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr43-00368504261432840"><label>43</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>von Elm</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pocock</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies</article-title>. <source>BMJ-Br Med J</source>
<year>2007</year>; <volume>335</volume>: <fpage>806</fpage>–<lpage>808</lpage>. <comment>Editorial Material</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.39335.541782.AD</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2034723</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17947786</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr44-00368504261432840"><label>44</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Dose–response effects of resistance training on physical function in frail older Chinese adults: a randomized controlled trial</article-title>. <source>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>14</volume>: <fpage>2824</fpage>–<lpage>2834</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37875291</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/jcsm.13359</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10751415</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr45-00368504261432840"><label>45</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Song</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Muscle strength and mass as predictors of pancreatic cancer: insights from the UK biobank</article-title>. <source>BMC Cancer</source>
<year>2025</year>: <fpage>25</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-14766-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12369202</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40836282</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr46-00368504261432840"><label>46</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Association of dietary fat intake with skeletal muscle mass and muscle strength in adults aged 20-59: NHANES 2011-2014</article-title>. <source>Front Nutr</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>10</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1325821</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10827989</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38299186</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr47-00368504261432840"><label>47</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ko</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>YK</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>The prevalence of metabolic syndrome according to grip strength in teenagers</article-title>. <source>Children-Basel</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>8</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/children8020108</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7914943</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33557385</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr48-00368504261432840"><label>48</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mendham</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Goedecke</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Micklesfield</surname><given-names>LK</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Understanding factors associated with sarcopenic obesity in older African women from a low-income setting: a cross-sectional analysis</article-title>. <source>BMC Geriatr</source>
<year>2021</year>: <volume>21</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12877-021-02132-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8048063</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33853546</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr49-00368504261432840"><label>49</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hauger</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Holvik</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bergland</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Physical capability, physical activity, and their association with femoral bone mineral density in adults aged 40 years and older: the Tromso study 2015-2016</article-title>. <source>Osteoporos Int</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>32</volume>: <fpage>2083</fpage>–<lpage>2094</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33864108</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00198-021-05949-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8510966</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr50-00368504261432840"><label>50</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Rawhani</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Adznam</surname><given-names>SNA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Abu Zaid</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Effectiveness of whey protein supplementation on muscle strength and physical performance of older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials</article-title>. <source>Clin Nutr</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>43</volume>: <fpage>2412</fpage>–<lpage>2426</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39303495</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.clnu.2024.08.033</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr51-00368504261432840"><label>51</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kressel</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Matsakas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Current research on Vitamin D supplementation against sarcopenia: a review of clinical trials</article-title>. <source>Int J Sports Med</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>44</volume>: <fpage>843</fpage>–<lpage>856</lpage>. <comment>Review</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37557905</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/a-2116-9240</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr52-00368504261432840"><label>52</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Simulation study on changes of EMG and physiological parameters of athletes under training state based on nano biomechanics analysis</article-title>. <source>Int J Nanotechnol</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>19</volume>: <fpage>1016</fpage>–<lpage>1033</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr53-00368504261432840"><label>53</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Dual cohort insights into accelerometer-derived weekend warrior physical activity and its impact on mortality</article-title>. <source>J Am Heart Assoc</source>
<year>2025</year>: <fpage>14</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1161/jaha.124.039852</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12229127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40417791</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr54-00368504261432840"><label>54</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zelber-Sagi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Paik</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ivancovsky-Wajcmen</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>“Weekend warrior” exercise pattern protects against MASLD and mortality comparable to regular exercise: national cohort study</article-title>. <source>Liver Int</source>
<year>2025</year>: <fpage>45</fpage>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/liv.70226</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40719404</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr55-00368504261432840"><label>55</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cheung</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Wearable device-measured bouted and sporadic physical activity patterns and incident COPD: a prospective cohort study from UK Biobank</article-title>. <source>Public Health</source>
<year>2024</year>; <volume>237</volume>: <fpage>322</fpage>–<lpage>329</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39515216</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.puhe.2024.10.027</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr56-00368504261432840"><label>56</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Millard</surname><given-names>LAC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tilling</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gaunt</surname><given-names>TR</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Association of physical activity intensity and bout length with mortality: an observational study of 79,503 UK Biobank participants</article-title>. <source>PLoS Med</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>18</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003757</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8480840</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34525088</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr57-00368504261432840"><label>57</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wanigatunga</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Daily physical activity patterns as a window on cognitive diagnosis in the Baltimore longitudinal study of aging (BLSA)</article-title>. <source>J Alzheimers Dis</source>
<year>2022</year>; <volume>88</volume>: <fpage>459</fpage>–<lpage>469</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35599480</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3233/JAD-215544</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12276952</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr58-00368504261432840"><label>58</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Greenwood-Hickman</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bellettiere</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Associations between physical function and device-based measures of physical activity and sedentary behavior patterns in older adults: moving beyond moderate-to-vigorous intensity physical activity</article-title>. <source>BMC Geriatr</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>21</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12877-021-02163-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8011072</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33789584</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr59-00368504261432840"><label>59</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>You</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Accelerometer-measured physical activity patterns are associated with phenotypic age: isotemporal substitution effects</article-title>. <source>Heliyon</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>9</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19158</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10558316</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37810111</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr60-00368504261432840"><label>60</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Accelerometer-measured multidimensional physical activity patterns and physical functional decline: a prospective national cohort study of aging</article-title>. <source>J Gerontol Ser a-Biol Sci Med Sci</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>80</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/gerona/glaf158</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40680230</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr61-00368504261432840"><label>61</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wanigatunga</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Urbanek</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Wrist-worn accelerometry, aging, and gait speed in the Baltimore longitudinal study of aging</article-title>. <source>J Aging Phys Act</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>31</volume>: <fpage>408</fpage>–<lpage>416</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36241170</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/japa.2022-0156</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11955955</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr62-00368504261432840"><label>62</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>McKenna</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Uncovering relationships between 24-h rest-activity patterns and immune-metabolic dysfunction in young people with mood disorders</article-title>. <source>J Psychiatr Res</source>
<year>2025</year>; <volume>191</volume>: <fpage>691</fpage>–<lpage>699</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41086524</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2025.10.009</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr63-00368504261432840"><label>63</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hetherington-Rauth</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Magalhaes</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Judice</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Physical activity moderates the effect of sedentary time on an older adult's physical independence</article-title>. <source>J Am Geriatr Soc</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>69</volume>: <fpage>1964</fpage>–<lpage>1970</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33780003</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jgs.17141</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr64-00368504261432840"><label>64</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>O'Brien</surname><given-names>MW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>An acute bout of prolonged sitting blunts popliteal endothelium-independent dilation in young, healthy adults</article-title>. <source>J Appl Physiol</source>
<year>2023</year>; <volume>134</volume>: <fpage>521</fpage>–<lpage>528</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36656984</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/japplphysiol.00712.2022</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr65-00368504261432840"><label>65</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Anwar</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mallick</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Paliwal</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Impact of physical activity on mitochondrial enzymes, muscle stem cell and anti-oxidant protein Sestrins in Sarcopenic mice</article-title>. <source>Exp Gerontol</source>
<year>2021</year>; <volume>150</volume>. <comment>Article</comment>. DOI: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2021.111358</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33872736</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr66-00368504261432840"><label>66</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Eliakim</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Falk</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Armstrong</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
</person-group>, <etal>et al.</etal>
<article-title>Expert's choice: 2018's most exciting research in the field of pediatric exercise science</article-title>. <source>Pediatr Exerc Sci</source>
<year>2019</year>; <volume>31</volume>: <fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>27</lpage>. <comment>Article</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30760123</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/pes.2019-0010</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>