<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Health Serv Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Health Serv Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">34</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmchsr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Health Services Research</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1472-6963</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12967010</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12967010.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12967010</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12967010</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41462460</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-13832-0</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13832</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Public attitudes and practices toward using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance: a multinational cross-sectional study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdelwahed</surname><given-names initials="AE">Aya Elsayed</given-names></name><address><email>aya1elsayed1@gmail.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abd El-Nasser</surname><given-names initials="M">Mahmoud </given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heih</surname><given-names initials="OQ">Omar Qasem</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Suleiman</surname><given-names initials="AM">Aya Muhammed</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Khader</surname><given-names initials="AM">Ahmed Mithqal</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names initials="RA">Rahma AbdElfattah</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdelnaby Fathalla Hamad</surname><given-names initials="MR">Mohamed Rabiea</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Radwan</surname><given-names initials="E">Eslam</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Srour</surname><given-names initials="AM">Azza Magdy</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><collab>HealthTech Alliance</collab></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim Ghallab</surname><given-names initials="MM">Marwa Mohammed</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04a97mm30</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411978.2</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0578 3577</institution-id><institution>Faculty of Medicine, </institution><institution>Kafrelsheikh University, </institution></institution-wrap>Kafr ash Shaykh, Egypt </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03wwspn40</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.440591.d</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0444 686X</institution-id><institution>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, </institution><institution>Palestine Polytechnic University, </institution></institution-wrap>Hebron, Palestine </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04a97mm30</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411978.2</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0578 3577</institution-id><institution>Internship student, Faculty of Medicine, </institution><institution>KafrELShiek University, </institution></institution-wrap>Kafr ash Shaykh, Egypt </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04a97mm30</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411978.2</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0578 3577</institution-id><institution>Department of Medical Parasitology, Faculty of Medicine, </institution><institution>Kafrelsheikh University, </institution></institution-wrap>Kafr ash Shaykh, Egypt </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>30</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>26</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503724</issue-id><elocation-id>335</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>19</day><month>9</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>27</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>30</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>08</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-03-08 10:25:12.333"><day>08</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2025</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12913_2025_Article_13832.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="structured"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Using artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots in healthcare can enhance patient care. However, misuse may lead to negative outcomes. Our study’s aim is to evaluate the practices and attitudes related to AI chatbots for healthcare assistance within the general population in the Arab region.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">A population of 12 years old and above from 21 Arab countries was invited to complete a validated web-based questionnaire from 1 May to 1 June 2024. The survey consisted of four sections: demographics, identification, attitudes, and practices related to AI chatbots in healthcare assistance. We utilized Microsoft Excel and SPSS software for data entry and analysis. Descriptive statistics, chi-square tests, and binary logistic regression were used to analyze demographic associations and usage predictors for healthcare</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Among the 12,886 valid responses, the median age was 24 years (IQR: 21–31), with a female-to-male ratio of 2:1. Most were single (66.8%), from Egypt (11.2%), urban residents (81.2%), students (43.6%), university-educated (73.2%), or healthcare-affiliated (40.2%). While 72.5% were aware of AI chatbots, only 26.4% used them, primarily for health coaching (67.5%), self-medication (54.5%), self-diagnosis (44.1%), and mental support (48%). ChatGPT was the most used chatbot (22.65%) for healthcare assistance. Individuals with psychological or mental health issues had greater odds of chatbot use (Exp(B) = 1.343, 95% CI: 1.189–1.516, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001), while the strongest predictor was participation in AI-related training courses, which was associated with more than a threefold increase in odds (Exp(B) = 3.109, 95% CI: 2.715–3.559, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001).</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par4">This study highlighted varying attitudes and patterns regarding the use of AI-powered chatbots for healthcare assistance, from consultation to self-diagnosis and medication. The insights from this study can help policymakers, researchers, developers and healthcare professionals integrate AI chatbots more effectively into the existing healthcare system.</p></sec><sec><title>Clinical trial number</title><p id="Par5">Not applicable.</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12913-025-13832-0.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Artificial intelligence</kwd><kwd>Chatbots</kwd><kwd>Healthcare</kwd><kwd>Attitude</kwd><kwd>Practice</kwd><kwd>ChatGPT</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Kafr El Shiekh University</institution></funding-source></award-group><open-access><p>Open access funding provided by The Science, Technology &amp; Innovation Funding Authority (STDF) in cooperation with The Egyptian Knowledge Bank (EKB).</p></open-access></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par7">
<disp-quote><p id="Par8">Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.</p><p id="Par9">       Arthur C. Clarke [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]</p></disp-quote>
</p><p id="Par10">Technology plays a vital role in our daily lives [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. One of the most rapidly evolving technologies is artificial intelligence (AI) powered chatbots. These computer programs use natural language processing (NLP), machine learning (ML), and deep learning (DL) to simulate human conversation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Users can interact with these chatbots through various formats, including text, voice, and images [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>].</p><p id="Par11">Since Eliza -the first chatbot- was introduced in 1966, AI chatbots have evolved remarkably [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Advanced versions are now widely accessible, including ChatGPT, Siri, Alexa, Gemini, Copilot, and IBM Watson [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Factors that contributed to its widespread use include the launch of ChatGPT in 2022 and the integration of these chatbots into social media platforms such as Snapchat, Telegram, and Meta [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. They have become essential to our daily lives, playing significant roles in education, research, business, tourism, and even the healthcare system [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p id="Par12">In healthcare systems, AI chatbots have been shown to assist providers in decision-making related to diagnosis, treatment, health promotion, and patient monitoring [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Research highlights the potential for integrating AI chatbots into public healthcare as valuable tools. These chatbots can facilitate health consultations and patient education, offer psychological support, manage appointments, oversee medication adherence, and provide guidance on healthy lifestyle choices [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. The integration of an AI chatbot in healthcare has the potential to ease the financial burden on both patients and the healthcare system [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. It can also help reduce energy consumption and lower the carbon footprint associated with healthcare services [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. AI chatbots are available 24/7, offering patients access to support [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>].</p><p id="Par13">Within the Arab region, several national initiatives reflect a growing governmental commitment to digital health transformation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Countries such as the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia have incorporated healthcare-related AI applications into their national AI strategies—such as the UAE Strategy for Artificial Intelligence 2031 and Saudi Arabia’s National Strategy for Data and AI (NSDAI)—which encourage the integration of AI-supported health services [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>].</p><p id="Par14">While chatbots can offer several benefits, depending solely on them without consulting human healthcare providers can be detrimental [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. Errors, hallucinations, and misinformation are major concerns, especially when dealing with complex health conditions that require human expertise for accurate diagnosis and treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. AI chatbot adoption faces challenges, including algorithmic limitations, regulatory constraints, data reliance, and transparency issues that reduce trust [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. AI-generated solutions can be flawed, and algorithmic bias presents risks, while data security and privacy remain major concerns. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. Limited access to clinical data, time constraints in research, and the complexity of data collection further hinder integration [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Recent comparative analyses highlight that healthcare AI has progressed from rule-based expert systems to machine-learning models and now to large language models, revealing persistent gaps in unified evaluation and governance across these technological eras [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>].</p><p id="Par15">Evaluating public attitudes and practices regarding the use of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance has become essential. However, research exploring these issues is still limited in the Arab region. Existing studies have focused primarily on healthcare professionals and medical students, who can critically assess the accuracy of chatbot-generated information [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. In contrast, public attitudes toward AI chatbots in healthcare have not been adequately studied in the Arab region. This raises important questions about their perceived effectiveness in health consultations, cost efficiency, and potential to support or replace human healthcare professionals. Understanding public trust and comfort with AI chatbots is crucial for their effective and healthy integration into healthcare systems [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>].</p><p id="Par16">Additionally, the extent and nature of AI chatbot usage for health purposes among the public require further investigation. While some individuals may use chatbots for general health advice, such as lifestyle coaching, others might rely on them for high-risk applications such as self-diagnosis and self-treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. Distinguishing between specialized medical chatbots and general-purpose models (e.g., ChatGPT) is also essential, as the latter may lack training on high-quality, peer-reviewed medical data, increasing the risk of misinformation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Examining these usage patterns can help improve chatbot training, raise awareness about potential risks, and guide interventions to promote safe and effective use.</p><p id="Par17">Demographic factors and prior AI-related training may influence chatbot adoption for healthcare. Hence, identifying whether specific demographics are strong predictors of chatbot reliance—or whether other factors play a more significant role—can inform future research and policy decisions. Investigating these relationships will provide insights into how AI chatbots can be tailored to meet user needs while minimizing potential risks in healthcare applications.</p><p id="Par18">This study bridges these gaps by assessing public attitudes and practices regarding the use of general chatbots in healthcare assistance in the Arab regions. It also explored the influence of some demographic factors on AI usage in healthcare. The findings provide valuable insights to guide future research and inform policymakers, healthcare providers, and technology developers, supporting effective AI chatbot integration to enhance patient engagement and health outcomes.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Study design and setting</title><p id="Par19">A multinational online descriptive cross-sectional study was implemented among the population of 21 Arab nations (Algeria, Bahrain, Comoros, Egypt, Iraq, Jordan, Kuwait, Lebanon, Libya, Mauritania, Morocco, Oman, Palestine, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Sudan, Somalia, Syria, Tunisia, the United Arab Emirates, and Yemen).</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Study populations</title><p id="Par20">We included participants who resided in an Arab country, had internet access, and consented to participate in either English or Arabic. Adolescents are active users of social media and AI chatbots, making their inclusion essential for capturing real-world interactions with this technology, particularly in accessing digital health information [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. Hence, we included participants above than 12 years old. The exclusion criteria are those who do not fulfill the inclusion criteria.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Data collection tool</title><p id="Par21">The questionnaire was developed based on previously established literature [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]. It was initially developed in English and then translated into Arabic, and we performed back-translation into English again for verification and accuracy. Content validity was evaluated by six experts, construct validity was assessed using exploratory and confirmatory factor analyses of the scales, face validity was examined through feedback from pilot participants, and reliability was tested using Cronbach’s alpha (see Additional File <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par22">The final tool versions (see Additional File <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>, Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref> &amp; <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref>) consisted of four parts, which are detailed below:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p id="Par23"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Demographics -</italic></bold> This part consists of 10 questions that address age, sex, country, education, residence, occupation, specialties, and history of chronic and mental health diseases.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par24"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Identifying AI Chatbots</italic></bold> - This part has three questions, in particular:<list list-type="alpha-lower"><list-item><p id="Par25">Hearing about AI chatbots.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par26">Definition of AI chatbots.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par27">Previous training in artificial intelligence.</p></list-item></list></p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par28"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Attitudes and confidence in the use of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance:</italic></bold> This section consists of 13 items with a five-point Likert scale.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par29"><bold><italic toggle="yes">Practice of AI Chatbots in Healthcare Assistance:</italic></bold> This domain consists of 4 questions. The first question aims to investigate the usage of AI chatbots in fields other than healthcare, with ten possible options. The second question concerns the prevalence of using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance. The participants who answered that they did not use these chatbots for healthcare assistance would submit the form, whereas those who did would transform it into the next question. The third question asks which AI chatbots are used most frequently. The fourth question evaluated the common applications of AI chatbots in healthcare assistance. This question includes 10 options in the Arabic version and only six in the validated English version.</p></list-item></list></p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Sample size and sampling</title><p id="Par30">We calculated the sample size to be 386 respondents from each country via version 7.2.4.0 of the Epi Info software at a confidence level of 95% (α = 0.05) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. To account for a 10% nonresponse rate, we aimed to collect at least 423 responses from each country. We utilized a convenience sampling approach for data collection.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Data collection</title><p id="Par31">We recruited collaborators from each country. They collected data online via Google Forms by sharing questionnaires through various platforms of social media from 1 May to 1 June 2024. The online questionnaire required responses for all applicable items and employed filtering logic to guide completion, resulting in a dataset with no missing values</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par32">We organized the data via a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet, which was then imported into the 29th version of the IBM SPSS software to obtain the descriptive statistics for all the variables [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>] (see Additional file <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref> for item coding).</p><p id="Par33">The only numerical variable was “Age,” so tests for normality were conducted, including the Shapiro test and a boxplot. Both highlighted its skewness and warranted its description in the median (minimum-maximum) form.</p><p id="Par34">For the attitude section, we changed the original 5-point scale to a simpler 3-point scale for easier interpretation (see Additional file <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>, Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3</xref>). “Strongly Disagree” and “Disagree” were combined and labeled “Disagree”. The “Neutral” option remains unchanged, whereas “Agree” and “Strongly Agree” are merged into a single category labeled “Agree”.</p><p id="Par35">We conducted chi-square tests with effect size to explore associations between demographic factors and AI chatbot usage for healthcare assistance. To account for multiple comparisons in the Chi-square analyses, we applied the Benjamini-Hochberg False Discovery Rate (FDR) correction for Type I error inflation (see Additional file <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>, Table <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>). Raw p-values from each test were ranked, and an adjusted significance threshold was calculated using the B-H procedure. Variables with p-values below the adjusted threshold were considered statistically significant. This adjustment ensured a more robust interpretation of the findings while minimizing false-positive results. The comparisons remained significant after correction.</p><p id="Par36">Additionally, binary logistic regression, with the Hosmer–Lemeshow test for model fit, was performed to explore the influence of demographic variables (independent variables), on AI chatbot use (dependent variable). To ensure a meaningful and stable comparison, we selected the reference group as the category with the highest frequency in each variable.</p><p id="Par37">The model fit statistics indicated explanatory power (Nagelkerke R<sup>2</sup> = 0.106), with a non-significant Hosmer–Lemeshow test (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.807), suggesting a good fit.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec14"><title>Demographic characteristics</title><p id="Par38">As shown in Tables <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> of the 12911 completed questionnaires, 12886 were included after inconsistent data were removed. The highest percentages of the collected samples were from Egypt (11.2%) and Palestine (10%). The median age of the participants was 24 years old. The female-to-male ratio was 2:1 (65%:33.5%). Nearly two-thirds of the participants were single (66.8%). The majority resided in urban areas (81.2%), had a university education (73.2%), were still students (43.6%), had specialties in the healthcare system (40.2%), and had heard about AI chatbots (72.5%). Almost 14.7% of the participants were diagnosed with a chronic disease, and 18.6% had a mental illness.<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Socio-demographic characteristics of participants</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 12886)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">English version</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Arabic</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10660</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">82 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">English</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2226</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age (years)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Median (IQR)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">24 (21–31)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Gender</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">204</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8370</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">65 × 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4312</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33 × 5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">Marital status</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">279</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Married</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3755</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Single</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8609</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">66 × 8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Widow</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">93</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Divorced</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">150</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Residence</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rural</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2418</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18 × 8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Urban</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10468</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="22" colspan="1">Country</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Algeria</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">332</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Bahrain</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1051</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Comoros</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Djibouti</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Egypt</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1440</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Iraq</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1120</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Jordan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1169</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Kuwait</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">310</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 × 4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lebanon</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">350</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Libya</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">810</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mauritania</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> &lt; 0.01</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Morocco</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Oman</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">994</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Palestine</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1295</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10 × 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Qatar</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">484</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 × 8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Saudi Arabia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">525</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Somalia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sudan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">659</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Syria</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">751</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 × 8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Tunisia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">251</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 × 9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">United Arab Emirates</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">529</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yemen</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">716</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-educated·</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">141</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-university education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1882</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">University education (undergraduate/postgraduate)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9431</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-graduate degrees (Master’s/Doctorate) ·</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1432</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1">Main occupation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Unemployed</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1676</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13 × 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Governmental employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2078</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Private employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1624</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Freelancer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">800</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Artisan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">87</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Housewife</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">848</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Student</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5614</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retired</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">124</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 × 0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Others</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1">Your Specialty (current or future)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1902</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14 × 8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Engineering</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1469</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11 × 4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Health care system</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5183</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IT/computer science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">957</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 × 4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Business</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1183</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9 × 2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Arts/Humanities</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">661</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 × 1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Natural science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">719</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Other</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">812</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 × 3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Diagnosed with chronic disease·</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1898</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14 × 7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Have any psychological or mental health issues</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2400</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18 × 6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Have you heard about AI-powered chatbots (like Chat GPT, Gemini, Poe)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3549</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27 × 5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9337</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72 × 5</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Previous training and correct identification</title><p id="Par39">Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref> shows that 6.7% of the people who heard about AI chatbots identified the correct definition and had previously attended training courses about AI-powered chatbots.<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Identification of AI power chatbots by the public and previous training about AI-powered chatbots·</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="2"/><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">I have participated in training courses or workshops about AI-powered chatbots or similar content online·<break/><italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 9337</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Total<break/>100%</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 8170, 87 × 5%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 1167, 12 × 5%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Identified AI-powered chatbots as:</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chatbots that are powered by human intelligence·</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3562 (38 × 1%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">476 (5 × 1%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>4038</p><p>(43 × 2%)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chatbots that are programmed to make phone calls·</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">162 (1 × 7%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41 (0 × 4%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">203 (2 × 2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chatbots that rely on natural language processing and machine learning to mimic human conversation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4329 (46 × 4%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">630 (6 × 7%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4959 (53 × 1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Chatbots that are only used for audio</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">117 (1 × 3%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20 (0 × 2%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">137 (1 × 5%)</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Public attitudes and confidence</title><p id="Par40">Regarding the attitude toward using AI chatbots for health care assistance (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>), Most agreed that chatbots improve access to health information (54.8%), assist with medication management (45.4%), and support initial symptom assessment (44.1%). A clear majority (46.2%) strongly rejected the idea that chatbots could replace human healthcare professionals.<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>The attitude toward using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 9337)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent %</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="50" colspan="1">I think AI chatbots are effective to:</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">1. Contribute to health care assistance.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">I strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">699</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1400</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2755</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3827</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">656</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">2.Provide accurate and trustworthy sources of health-related information.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">621</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2011</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3170</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3013</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">522</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">3. Facilitate the accessibility of health-related information and resources</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">370</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">725</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1955</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5120</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">54.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1167</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">4. Be used for identifying the initial symptoms assessment for health-related issues</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">606</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1360</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2555</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4119</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">697</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">5. Assist in medication management and reminders.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">500</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">971</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2012</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4237</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1617</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">6. Offer psychological and mental support and resources.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">814</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1773</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2993</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3145</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">612</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">7. Contribute to remote monitoring of health issues</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">931</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2021</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2905</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2926</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">554</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">8. Offer cost-effective solutions for healthcare assistance.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1028</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2048</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2921</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2782</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">558</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">9. Replace the human health care professionals.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">259</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">942</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1389</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2429</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4318</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">46.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">10. Help the human health care professionals.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1276</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1577</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2548</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3156</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">780</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="15" colspan="1">Regarding using AI chatbots for health care assistance:</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">1. I feel comfortable when discussing health issues with AI chatbots (or imagining the situation if I haven’t done it before).</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1273</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2330</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3047</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2231</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">456</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">2. I consider it transparent.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">901</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1989</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3569</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2449</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">429</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">3. I consider it to be trustworthy.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1451</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Disagree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2712</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.0</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Neutral</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3245</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Agree</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1616</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Strongly agree.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">313</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.4</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>The use of AI chatbots for non-healthcare services</title><p id="Par41">The participants reported using AI chatbots for non-healthcare services such as education and learning (74.9%) and scientific research (62.9%) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Using AI chatbots for non-healthcare services</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12913_2025_13832_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Prevalence of using AI chatbots for healthcare services</title><p id="Par42">On the other hand, we found that 26.4% of the participants used AI chatbots for health care assistance services. The highest prevalence rates were detected in Jordan (13.4%), Palestine (12.12%), and Egypt (12.1%) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Country-wise prevalence of using AI-powered chatbots for health care assistance</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO2" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12913_2025_13832_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par43">The common AI chatbots used for healthcare assistance were ChatGPT (22.6%), Google Assistant (8.8%), and Siri (8.3%) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>).<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>AI-powered chatbots used for healthcare assistance</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO3" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12913_2025_13832_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec23"><title>The purpose of using AI chatbots for healthcare services</title><p id="Par44">As presented in Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>, the commonest uses of AI chatbots for health care assistance were offering personalized health coaching (67.5%), identifying the initial symptoms of the disease (58.2%), and obtaining information about self-medication (54.5%).<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Using AI chatbots for health care assistance</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency<break/>(<italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 2461)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent %</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1. Medication management (and/or) Reminders</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">920</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2. Assisting with appointment scheduling and reminders related to health (such as check-ups, medications, and any health regimen)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">884</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3. Facilitating online health consultations</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1307</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4. Getting information about self-medication (Taking medicines without physician consultation)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1342</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">54.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5. Offering personalized health coaching (such as promoting a healthy lifestyle with exercising, a healthy diet, quitting smoking, and more.)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1660</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">67.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6. Online nursing and monitoring services</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">778</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7. Identifying the initial symptoms of the disease</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1090</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">58.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8. Self-diagnosis</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">826</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9. Psychological and Mental support</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">899</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10. Others</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1014</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">54.2</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p></sec><sec id="Sec25"><title>The association between demographics and the use of AI chatbots for healthcare</title><p id="Par45">The chi-square test (Table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref>) reveals significant but weak differences of using of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance in the following factors: age (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.094), gender (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.076), marital status (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.071), education level (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.050), and employment status (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.079). Additionally, field of specialty (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.135), mental health status (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.055), and prior AI training (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cramer’s V = 0.169) were also significant factors, with prior AI training showing the strongest association, although it remains weak.<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>Chi-square test between using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance and demographic characteristics</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="7" rowspan="1">Chi-square test for using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="5" rowspan="1">Have you ever used AI chatbots for healthcare assistance?</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2461%))</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ<sup>2</sup> Value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">df</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cramer’s V</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">p-value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="7" colspan="1">Age categories</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> &lt; 16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12 (0.5%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="7" colspan="1">82.027</td><td align="left" rowspan="7" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" rowspan="7" colspan="1">0.094</td><td align="left" rowspan="7" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16–24</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1633 (66.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25–34</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">548 (22.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35–44</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">165 (6.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45–54</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72 (2.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">55–64</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24 (1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> &gt; 64</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 (0.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Gender</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28 (1.1%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">53.434</td><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">0.076</td><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1420 (57.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1013 (41.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">Marital Status</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35 (1.4%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">47.671</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">0.071</td><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Married</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">454 (18.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Single</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1948 (79.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Widow</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6 (0.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Divorced</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18 (0.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Residence</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rural</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">434 (17.6%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.965</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0,010</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.326</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Urban</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2027 (82.4)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-educated.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14 (0.6%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">23.141</td><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">0.050</td><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-university education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">228 (9.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">University education (undergraduate/postgraduate)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1944 (79%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-graduate degrees (Master’s/Doctorate).</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">275 (11.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1">Main occupation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Unemployed</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">304 (12.4%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1">57.745</td><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1">0.079</td><td align="left" rowspan="9" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Governmental employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">276 (11.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Private employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">291 (11.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Freelancer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">146 (5.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Artisan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10 (0.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Housewife</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">68 (2.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Student</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1350 (54.9%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retired</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7 (0.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Others</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9 (0.4%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1">Your Specialty (current or future)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">244 (9.9%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1">170.312</td><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1">0.135</td><td align="left" rowspan="8" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Engineering</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">249 (10.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Health care system</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1344 (54.6%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IT/computer science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">199 (8.1%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Business</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">162 (6.6%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Arts/Humanities</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">82 (3.3%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Natural science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">119 (4.8%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Other</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">62 (2.5%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Diagnosed with chronic disease.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2123 (86.3%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.247</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.005</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.619</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">338 (13.7%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">“Do you have any psychological or mental health issues?”</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1890 (76.8%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">27.874</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.055</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">571 (23.2%)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">I have participated in training courses or workshops about AI-powered chatbots or similar content online.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1923 (78.1%)</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">267.841</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">0.169</td><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">538 (21.9%)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>χ<sup>2</sup> Value – Chi-square Value. df – Degrees of Freedom. The table shows weak but significant associations between AI chatbot use and age, specialty, gender, mental health, and AI training, while residence and chronic disease have no impact</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p id="Par46">As shown in Table <xref rid="Tab6" ref-type="table">6</xref>, logistic regression analysis revealed several significant predictors of AI chatbot usage for healthcare assistance. Compared with those with university education, individuals with no education (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001, Exp(B) = 0.222, 95% CI: 0.090–0.547), pre-university education (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001, Exp(B) = 0.230, 95% CI: 0.094–0.560), and postgraduate degrees (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.006, Exp(B) = 0.281, 95% CI: 0.114–0.694) were significantly less likely to use AI chatbots.<table-wrap id="Tab6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6</label><caption><p>Binary logistic regression test between using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance and demographic predictors</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="9" rowspan="1">Have you ever used AI chatbots for healthcare assistance (yes/No)</th></tr><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 9337</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">B</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">S.E.</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Wald</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Df</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Sig.</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Exp(B)</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">95% C.I.for EXP(B)</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lower</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Upper</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Age categories (Reference: 16–24)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.727</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> &lt; 16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.572</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.341</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.807</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.094</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.771</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.907</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.457</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25–34</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.419</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.350</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.435</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.231</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.521</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.766</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.021</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35–44</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.179</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.365</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.239</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.625</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.196</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.584</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.445</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45–54</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.086</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.380</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.051</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.821</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.918</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.436</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.933</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">55–64</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.029</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.433</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.005</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.946</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.971</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.416</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.269</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> &gt; 64</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.933</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.609</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.347</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.125</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.542</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.771</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.383</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Gender (Reference: Female)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60.758</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.028</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.233</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.014</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.905</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.028</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.652</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.623</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.451</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.234</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.696</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.055</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.569</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.991</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.485</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Marital Status (Reference: Single)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.296</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.862</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prefer not to answer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.168</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.224</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.562</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.453</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.183</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.763</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.835</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Married</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.132</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.211</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.392</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.531</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.141</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.755</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.724</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Widow</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.143</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.540</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.070</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.791</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.867</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.301</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.499</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Divorced</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.023</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.352</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.004</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.947</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.977</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.490</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.948</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Country (Reference: Egypt)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">83.254</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Algeria</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.478</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.174</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.521</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.006</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.612</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.146</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.268</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Bahrain</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.173</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.077</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.186</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.276</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.231</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.391</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.675</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Comoros</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.069</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.158</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.194</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.660</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.072</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.787</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.460</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Iraq</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.240</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.165</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.103</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.147</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.271</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.919</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.758</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Jordan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.568</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.159</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.724</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.764</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.292</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.411</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Kuwait</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.380</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.220</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.990</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.084</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.462</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.951</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.248</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lebanon</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.207</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.000</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.997</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.999</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.666</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.499</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Libya</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.011</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.181</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.004</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.953</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.011</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.709</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.441</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Morocco</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.322</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.414</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.603</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.437</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.380</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.612</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.108</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Oman</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.037</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.176</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.045</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.833</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.038</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.736</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.464</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Palestine</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.311</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.160</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.769</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.052</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.364</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.997</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.867</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Qatar</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.043</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.190</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.050</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.822</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.958</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.661</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.390</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Saudi Arabia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.153</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.195</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.618</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.432</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.166</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.795</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.709</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Somalia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.514</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.452</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.218</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.543</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.874</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.014</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sudan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.095</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.176</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.289</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.591</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.099</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.778</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.553</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Syria</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.173</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.177</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.951</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.329</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.841</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.594</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.191</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Tunisia</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.088</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.221</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.160</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.689</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.916</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.594</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.411</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">United Arab Emirates</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.290</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.189</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.346</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.126</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.336</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.922</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.937</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yemen</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.445</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.179</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.168</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.013</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.560</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.098</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.215</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Residence (Reference: Urban) Rural</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.056</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.068</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.672</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.413</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.946</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.828</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.080</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Education (Reference: University education (undergraduate/postgraduate))</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15.657</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-educated.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−1.504</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.460</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.708</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.222</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.090</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.547</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-university education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−1.470</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.455</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.457</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.230</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.094</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.560</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-graduate degrees (Master’s/Doctorate).</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−1.268</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.461</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.567</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.006</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.281</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.114</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.694</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Main occupation (Reference: Student)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.981</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.082</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Unemployed</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.210</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.114</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.398</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.065</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.811</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.649</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.013</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Government employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.046</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.107</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.182</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.670</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.955</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.774</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.179</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Private employee</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.139</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.128</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.191</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.275</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.149</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.895</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.476</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Freelancer</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.216</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.408</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.281</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.596</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.805</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.362</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.793</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Artisan</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.224</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.173</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.681</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.195</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.251</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.892</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.754</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Housewife</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.027</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.081</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.111</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.739</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.027</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.876</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.205</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Retired</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.434</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.434</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.999</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.318</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.648</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.277</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.517</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Others</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.463</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.426</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.180</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.277</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.589</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.689</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.664</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Your Specialty (current or future) (Reference: Health care system)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">152.093</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.263</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.110</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.751</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.016</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.769</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.620</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.953</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Engineering</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.462</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.089</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.109</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.587</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.334</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.888</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IT/computer science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.202</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.118</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.934</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.087</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.817</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.648</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.030</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Business</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.187</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.122</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.362</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.124</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.829</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.653</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.053</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Arts/Humanities</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.295</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.148</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.972</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.046</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.744</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.557</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.995</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Natural science</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.062</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.134</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.211</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.646</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.940</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.723</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.223</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Other</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">−0.540</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.161</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.177</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.583</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.425</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.800</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Diagnosed with chronic disease. (Reference: No)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.106</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.075</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.978</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.160</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.112</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.959</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.288</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>Have psychological or mental health issues (Reference: No)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.295</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.062</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">22.515</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.343</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.189</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.516</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>I have participated in training courses or workshops about AI-powered chatbots or similar online content (Reference: No)</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.134</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.069</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">269.557</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold> &lt; 0.001</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.109</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.715</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.559</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>B – Beta coefficient. S.E. – Standard Error. df – Degrees of Freedom. Sig. – Significance level. Exp(B) – Exponentiated Beta coefficient. 95% C.I. for Exp(B) − 95% Confidence Interval for Exp(B). Lower – Lower bound of the confidence interval. Upper – Upper bound of the confidence interval. AI chatbot use is weakly predicted by age, gender, education, specialty, mental health, and AI training, with training being the strongest predictor. Model fit: Nagelkerke R<sup>2</sup> = 0.106, Hosmer-Lemeshow χ<sup>2</sup> = 4.525, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.807 (good fit)</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p id="Par47">Regarding specialty, individuals in engineering (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Exp(B) = 1.587, 95% CI: 1.334–1.888) were more likely to use AI chatbots than those in healthcare. Conversely, those in education (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.016, Exp(B) = 0.769, 95% CI: 0.620–0.953), arts/humanities (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.046, Exp(B) = 0.744, 95% CI: 0.557–0.995), and other specialties (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001, Exp(B) = 0.583, 95% CI: 0.425–0.800) were significantly less likely to use AI chatbots.</p><p id="Par48">Having psychological or mental health issues was a significant predictor, with affected individuals being more likely to use AI chatbots (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Exp(B) = 1.343, 95% CI: 1.189–1.516). Finally, participation in AI-related training courses or workshops was the strongest predictor, significantly increasing the likelihood of chatbot usage (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Exp(B) = 3.109, 95% CI: 2.715–3.559).</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec26"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par49">In the digital age, remarkable technological innovations have transformed human-computer interactions. An impressive advancement is the emergence of AI-powered chatbots, particularly after ChatGPT launched in 2022 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Previous studies have shown the impact of AI chatbots on various daily activities, including planning, time management, task completion, education, psychological support, and research [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. However, there is a lack of research focusing on the public’s use of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance. Implementing these chatbots in healthcare without the involvement of healthcare providers may result in malpractice. Therefore, this study aims to evaluate the use of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance by the public in the Arab region.</p><p id="Par50">Our study revealed that more than two-thirds (72.5%) of the participants were familiar with AI-powered chatbots. This finding is consistent with those of previous studies, which reported familiarity rates ranging from 60.5% among medical researchers to 78.6% among Lebanese university students [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]. Almost half of our respondents (53.1%) correctly identified AI chatbots, only 6.7% had previously received training about them, and 46.4% had not. This aligns with earlier research regarding acceptable knowledge and familiarity with AI chatbots, even though most participants lacked prior training [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>]. One possible explanation for the widespread awareness of AI chatbots without prior training may be their user-friendly interfaces, which simplify technology and enhance user engagement [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>]. Another leading factor may be the reach of social media [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>]. Users frequently share their experiences with AI chatbots on various platforms, which helps disseminate information about them [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>]. Additionally, AI chatbots have been integrated into several social media platforms, such as Snapchat, increasing exposure to this technology for 383 million daily users [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>].</p><p id="Par51">We found that 26.4% of the participants reported using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance in the Arab region. The prevalence varies by country, with the highest rates observed in Jordan (13.4%), Palestine (12.2%), and Egypt (12.1%). Conversely, the lowest rates are observed in Morocco (0.4%), Somalia (0.6%), Tunisia (2%), and Kuwait (2.3%). An earlier study revealed that 18.4% of Saudi healthcare workers used AI-powered chatbots to deliver health assistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>]. While we found that Saudi Arabia had a 3.3% prevalence rate of using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance, this rate was derived from a broader population that included the public, not just healthcare workers. The variations in prevalence rates may be explained by national factors affecting digital health adoption, such as government policies, healthcare systems, internet access, economic conditions, and public trust in technology [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>].</p><p id="Par52">Nearly two-thirds of the participants (67.5%) reported using AI chatbots for health assistance to receive personalized health coaching that promotes a healthy lifestyle through exercise, diet, and the cessation of bad habits. This finding aligns with previous systematic reviews highlighting similar studies that used AI chatbots for effective behavioral changes and healthy lifestyle modification, which included smoking cessation, medication and diet adherence, exercise compliance, and reducing substance misuse [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>]. However, AI chatbots rely on user input, which may be inaccurate, leading to misleading recommendations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>].</p><p id="Par53">Almost one-third of the respondents utilized these chatbots for medication management (37.4%), appointment scheduling and reminders related to health events (35.9%), and online nursing and monitoring services (31.6%). Previous studies have also shown promising results for chatbots used in these areas [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. Specifically, the study noted a 47% increase in appointments booked via AI chatbots [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. Additionally, other studies reported that chatbots used for online nursing and monitoring services achieved a satisfaction rate of approximately 85% in terms of quality [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>]. We can explain these findings by highlighting that AI chatbots provide 24/7 availability, reduce wait times, and streamline scheduling [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Online nursing offers instant responses and remote monitoring, enhancing patient support without the need for in-person visits [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. For medication management, chatbots help with reminders, dosage tracking, and adherence monitoring, decreasing the risk of missed doses [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>]. This may guide future efforts to enhance these tasks through continuous training and improvement. Regular evaluations of user satisfaction and performance are crucial for ensuring effectiveness, addressing technical issues, and optimizing healthcare implementation.</p><p id="Par54">Approximately half of the participants employed AI chatbots to facilitate online health consultations (53.1%), provide mental health support (48%), and identify initial symptoms of diseases (58.2%). Relying on AI chatbots carries risks of misdiagnosis, misinformation, and a lack of personalized care, emphasizing the need for human oversight [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>]. To mitigate these risks, users should verify AI-generated advice with healthcare professionals, use chatbots as a supplementary tool rather than a primary source, and ensure the chatbot is from a reputable, medically validated source. These patterns further highlight the ethical challenges emphasized in recent reviews, which underscore the critical importance of safeguarding privacy, preventing bias, ensuring transparency, and maintaining human oversight when AI tools are used for mental health support [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>]. in this context, it is important to recognize that many general-purpose chatbots are trained predominantly on western datasets, which may limit cultural sensitivity and introduce biased or culturally inappropriate responses for Arab users. Additionally, given the sensitive nature of mental health information, users may not be fully aware of how their data is collected, stored, or shared, raising significant privacy and confidentiality concerns [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>]. Our findings are consistent with reports from the National Health Service (NHS). It is noted that approximately 1.2 million people used chatbots for consultations instead of calling the NHS for nonemergency issues [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>]. Various studies have also documented the use of AI chatbots to address mental health conditions and identify initial symptoms [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>]. Some studies have addressed the fear of developing an emotional relationship with AI-powered chatbots after they receive some form of mental support [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>]. This observation could suggest a direction for future research regarding this phenomenon.</p><p id="Par55">Surprisingly, 54.5% of the participants reported using AI chatbots to obtain information about self-medication, whereas 44.1% used them for self-diagnosis. These findings correspond with previous research indicating that 78.4% of the participants intended to use chatbots for self-diagnosis and treatment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. The results may reflect a growing dependence on these tools for personal health decisions. The accessibility and cost-effectiveness of these chatbots are likely contributing factors to their popularity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. However, relying solely on AI chatbots is potentially dangerous. AI chatbots rely on large datasets and pattern recognition rather than deep clinical reasoning [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>]. They are trained in general health information and may not account for individual patient comorbidities or nuanced symptom presentations. Because they lack real-time access to a patient’s full medical context and cannot perform physical examinations or diagnostic tests, they may oversimplify symptoms or miss serious underlying conditions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>]. Additionally, their recommendations are often based on statistical likelihoods and may not reflect the latest clinical guidelines or be adapted to specific patient needs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. This can lead to delayed diagnoses, inappropriate use of medications, adverse drug interactions, and even the masking of critical warning signs. Moreover, users may develop a false sense of security, opting to skip necessary medical consultations. Therefore, while chatbots can serve as initial sources of information, they should not replace professional medical evaluation and guidance.</p><p id="Par56">Research has shown that the public tends to trust AI chatbots for health-related information more when individuals are experiencing mild disease symptoms than when they are experiencing severe symptoms [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>]. This may be due to the lower perceived risk in mild cases, whereas severe symptoms prompt a preference for human experts for reassurance. However, Meyrowitsch DW and colleagues discussed the dangers of health misinformation caused by algorithms used in public AI chatbots [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>]. Therefore, it is advisable not to rely solely on these chatbots for health-related information, particularly for self-diagnosis and medication.</p><p id="Par57">In our study, we found that the most used AI chatbots for healthcare assistance are ChatGPT (22.6%), Google Assistant (8.8%), Siri (8.3%), and AI-powered chatbots on social media platforms such as Snapchat (7%). These findings align with those of previous studies, indicating that ChatGPT is among the most frequently utilized AI chatbots across various populations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>]. Furthermore, the availability of Siri and Google Assistant on mobile devices contributes to their higher usage. Similarly, integrating AI chatbots into social media platforms with large user bases encourages more people to use these technologies. The user-friendly interfaces of these chatbots have made it easier for individuals to understand and engage with technology [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>]. Additionally, continuous improvements and updates have helped familiarize the public with these tools and ensure the delivery of high-quality services [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR70">70</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR71">71</xref>]. These factors likely contribute to building and gaining people’s trust in using these technologies for healthcare assistance. General AI chatbots, like ChatGPT, can offer general health information but may not provide the precise, evidence-based advice needed for personal healthcare [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR72">72</xref>]. They are designed to provide broad, conversational information across a wide range of topics, including health. While they can offer useful general knowledge, symptom explanations, or lifestyle tips, they are not equipped to deliver precise, evidence-based medical advice tailored to an individual’s unique health profile [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. These chatbots lack access to a patient’s full medical history, current medications, diagnostic test results, and other critical contextual information necessary for accurate clinical decision-making. As a result, they may unintentionally provide incomplete, outdated, or nonspecific guidance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Therefore, users should take practical steps when using these tools for health issues. These include checking the information with qualified healthcare professionals, comparing it with established clinical guidelines, and ensuring that personal data is handled securely. In contrast, specialized medical chatbots are designed specifically for healthcare. They use carefully selected medical data and follow strict privacy and regulatory rules, making them more reliable and accurate for personalized medical advice [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR73">73</xref>].</p><p id="Par58">Regarding attitudes toward using AI-powered chatbots for healthcare assistance, 37.9% of the participants agreed that AI chatbots could offer accurate and trustworthy sources of health-related information, and 67.3% believed that AI chatbots could increase the accessibility of health-related resources. Moreover, 48% of the respondents considered AI chatbots to be transparent. These findings highlight the public’s confidence in using AI chatbots for health-related issues. These attitudes may explain the use of chatbots for self-medication information, diagnosis, and personalized health coaching.</p><p id="Par59">Conversely, 38.6% of the participants disagreed that they felt comfortable when using AI chatbots for health issues. Low levels of trust and comfort may limit user engagement, decrease adherence to chatbot recommendations, and undermine their effectiveness as tools for health communication during implementation. As a result, chatbots risk being underutilized or misused, especially in sensitive or complex health scenarios. Several factors may contribute to people’s discomfort when they use AI chatbots. Transitioning from human health professionals to AI chatbots for health-related problems can be unsettling. Individuals may have concerns about technological limitations and issues related to trust (28.2%) and transparency (22.5%), which have been reported. To address these challenges, efforts must focus on improving transparency, aligning chatbot responses with evidence-based guidelines, ensuring data security, and integrating chatbots into healthcare settings with oversight from professionals to build user confidence and promote safe adoption.</p><p id="Par60">Many respondents acknowledged the importance of AI chatbots in contributing to healthcare assistance (48%). They agreed on the effectiveness of using them to assess the initial symptoms of health-related issues (51.6%), and in medication management and reminders (62.7%). This aligns with a study of NHS health professionals, which revealed that 79% deemed the importance and effectiveness of using AI chatbots for healthcare assistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR74">74</xref>]. Another cross-sectional study detected the usefulness and satisfaction of AI-assisted symptom checkers and various forms of healthcare assistance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">75</xref>]. Using chatbots among healthcare professionals is promising since they can filter true and false information; however, the public should not rely on chatbots solely to avoid potentially harmful consequences in real-time.</p><p id="Par61">Over one-third of the participants agreed that AI chatbots could contribute to the remote monitoring of health-related issues (37.3%) and provide cost-effective solutions for healthcare assistance (35.8%). This may indicate a growing acceptance of digital health, especially following the COVID-19 pandemic, during which we relied on virtual consultations and remote monitoring [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR76">76</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR77">77</xref>]. In terms of cost-effectiveness, this trend may be attributed to rising healthcare costs and limited resources [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR78">78</xref>]. Telemonitoring can help reduce the financial burden of traditional healthcare delivery, particularly for mild cases. These findings are consistent with previous research, which has predicted the promising effectiveness of using chatbots as part of telemedicine for health monitoring [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR79">79</xref>].</p><p id="Par62">The majority of participants (72.3%) did not believe that AI chatbots can replace human healthcare professionals. However, nearly 13% agree that AI chatbots could take place, which is concerning. Relying solely on AI chatbots without consulting human doctors could lead to harmful health consequences in real-time [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">80</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">81</xref>]. On the other hand, 42.2% of the participants agreed that chatbots are helpful tools for healthcare professionals in delivering effective healthcare. These findings align with previous studies highlighted the preference for integrating human doctors into the diagnosis and treatment process rather than replacing them [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">80</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">82</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">83</xref>].</p><p id="Par63">Our study revealed that 40.2% of the participants believed that AI chatbots could effectively provide psychological and mental support. There is a growing body of research highlighting the benefits of AI-powered chatbots in mental health care [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR84">84</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR85">85</xref>]. However, a study of 971 psychiatrists in 22 countries revealed that 83% of them doubted that AI chatbots could ever deliver empathetic care comparable to that of a psychiatrist [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR86">86</xref>].</p><p id="Par64">In our study, age weakly influenced chatbot adoption, with younger individuals being more likely to use digital tools. However, age alone was not a strong predictor, as differences among older age groups were minimal when considering other factors. This suggests that while younger individuals may be more technologically inclined, age alone does not fully explain chatbot adoption. Our findings supported previous studies indicating that age is a weak factor in digital health and technology adoption [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR87">87</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR88">88</xref>]. Enhancing digital literacy, offering socioeconomic support, and promoting personalized engagement may be more effective strategies for increasing AI chatbot usage beyond the age factor [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR87">87</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR89">89</xref>].</p><p id="Par65">We noticed that education was significantly linked to AI chatbot usage (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001). Individuals with no education, pre-university education, or even postgraduate degrees were less likely to use chatbots for health assistance than those with university education. This trend may stem from differences in digital literacy, technological access, and perceived relevance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR90">90</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR91">91</xref>]. University graduates often have greater exposure to digital tools, while postgraduates may rely on specialized resources instead [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR92">92</xref>]. Meanwhile, those with lower education levels may encounter accessibility barriers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR91">91</xref>]. Additionally, confidence in technology and socioeconomic factors may play crucial roles, highlighting the need for digital training beyond formal education. Notably in our study, the strongest predictor of AI chatbot use was participation in AI training which significantly increased usage, emphasizing the importance of exposure and hands-on engagement in driving technological adoption.</p><p id="Par66">Professionals in engineering fields showed significantly greater usage of AI chatbots compared to health care professionals, likely because of their frequent interaction with digital tools and AI-driven systems, making them more comfortable with chatbot use [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>]. In contrast, individuals in education, arts, and humanities fields demonstrated lower usage compared to heath care filed. This is consistent with previous studies showing that engineering students tend to use AI more than those in medical or humanities disciplines do [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>].</p><p id="Par67">Interestingly, chronic disease history was not significantly associated with chatbot usage, whereas individuals with psychological or mental health issues were more likely to use chatbots. Chronic disease patients hesitate to use chatbots, preferring human interaction to manage their condition, despite studies indicating a promising acceptance rate for future use [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR93">93</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR94">94</xref>]. In contrast, chatbots are more accessible for mental health support, as they rely on conversation-based interactions, which may be sufficient for various forms of mental support [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR95">95</xref>]. Individuals with mental health concerns may favor chatbots for their privacy and non-judgmental nature, which helps reduce the stigma of seeking professional help, a particularly significant factor in Arab countries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR96">96</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR97">97</xref>]. Despite the promising potential of chatbots for mental health support, relying solely on them may have negative consequences due to accuracy concerns [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR95">95</xref>]. We encourage raising awareness about the risks of misuse and the importance of human consultation for proper mental health care.</p><p id="Par68">Importantly, developing and implementing algorithms and devices that ensure high quality and accuracy in data analysis takes time. Healthcare practitioners and medical AI developers must collaborate to improve this process. Additionally, developers should provide doctors with more information about the models, algorithms, and data that AI chatbots utilize. This transparency can help build confidence in AI conclusions and address potential concerns regarding its use in mental health care.</p><sec id="Sec27"><title>Strengths and limitations</title><p id="Par69">This multinational study is addressing a gap in attitudes and practices regarding the use of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance among the public in the Arab region. It includes diverse populations, various demographics, and a large sample size from over 21 countries. We believe that this study can offer valuable insights that can assist researchers, policymakers, healthcare providers, and technology developers in formulating effective strategies for the integration of AI chatbots into healthcare systems, thereby enhancing patient engagement and health outcomes.</p><p id="Par70">This study has some limitations that should be acknowledged. First, a cross-sectional design inherently restricts our ability to infer causality, limiting interpretations to associative relationships. Second, the use of a convenience sampling approach significantly limits the generalizability of the findings. Participants were selected based on accessibility, which introduces selection and sampling biases. This is reflected in the overrepresentation of healthcare-affiliated respondents (40.2%) and university-educated individuals (73.2%), potentially skewing the data toward more informed or technologically engaged perspectives. Third, although data were collected from 21 countries, countries like Egypt contributed disproportionately to the sample (11.2%), while others, such as Djibouti and Mauritania, were minimally represented ( &lt; 0.1%). As such, meaningful cross-country comparison is limited, and caution should be exercised when generalizing findings to broader populations or specific national contexts.</p><p id="Par71">Additionally, the online-only survey format may have excluded individuals without reliable internet access or those with limited digital literacy—an important consideration given the study’s focus on digital health technologies like AI chatbots. The reliance on self-reported responses may introduce recall bias or social desirability bias. The chi-square tests revealed statistically significant but weak associations (Cramer’s V ranging from 0.050–0.169), indicating small effect sizes that may limit the practical significance of these findings. Finally, the binary logistic regression model’s low explanatory power suggests that unmeasured variables may play a significant role in influencing chatbot adoption.</p></sec><sec id="Sec29"><title>Recommendations</title><p id="Par72">Future research should explore additional factors influencing AI chatbot adoption for healthcare via longitudinal studies and qualitative interviews. These factors may include income levels, digital literacy, internet accessibility, and specific health conditions such as chronic diseases or mental health conditions. Future studies should distinguish between general-purpose AI chatbots and medically specialized, validated health chatbots to more accurately evaluate their respective roles, risks, and utility. Conducting more targeted, country-level analyses or comparative studies will help generate deeper, context-sensitive insights into how cultural diversity influences public attitudes and practices toward AI-based healthcare tools.</p><p id="Par73">Policymakers and healthcare professionals must raise awareness about the limitations of relying solely on chatbots without human consultation. Enhancing digital literacy through targeted training campaigns can improve adoption, while developers and stakeholders should focus on refining AI models to address public concerns and ensure effective integration into healthcare systems.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec30"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par74">The majority of the adult population in Arab countries involved in healthcare has heard about AI chatbots. Most participants recognized their capabilities, although few had received prior training in them. Regarding their attitudes towards AI chatbots, participants agreed that these tools are effective in facilitating access to health-related information and resources, as well as assisting with medication management and reminders.</p><p id="Par75">However, there were concerns about the accuracy, transparency, and trustworthiness of the health-related information provided by AI chatbots. Many participants rejected the idea that AI could replace human healthcare professionals. Most reported using AI chatbots in nonhealthcare sectors, particularly in education, scientific research, and personal assistance, with a preference for ChatGPT over other chatbot options.</p><p id="Par76">In healthcare contexts, participants indicated that they use AI chatbots as assistants for personalized health coaching, identifying initial symptoms of diseases, and managing self-medication. However, they were less inclined to use them for online nursing and monitoring services. AI chatbot adoption is significantly influenced by education level, field of specialty, and AI-related training, highlighting the importance of digital literacy and exposure in driving usage. Our findings highlight the need for targeted education and further research for the effective integration of AI chatbots for healthcare assistance.</p></sec><sec id="Sec101" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Electronic supplementary material</title><p>Below is the link to the electronic supplementary material.</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12913_2025_13832_MOESM1_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 1</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><glossary><title>Abbreviation</title><def-list><def-item><term>AI</term><def><p id="Par6">Artificial intelligence</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We want to express our sincere gratitude to the experts who assisted us in validating the questionnaire versions. We thank, <bold>Dr. Ngu Claudia Ngeha</bold>; Ph.D. in public health, PLOS University of Buea, Buea, Southwest, Cameroon, <bold>Dr. Afnan Jobran</bold>; MD in public health and epidemiology, <bold>Dr. Mireille Hanna</bold>; MSc, public health specialist, <bold>Prof. Amany Mokhtar</bold>; Ph.D. in public Health and Epidemiology, <bold>Dr. Ahmed Magdy</bold>; MSc, MPH, National Heart Institute, The American University in Cairo; and <bold>Dr. Loai Zabin</bold>; Norfolk and Norwich University Hospitals NHS Foundation. We are also thankful to the collaborators who helped with data collection but did not fulfill the authorship criteria, Batoul Shokor; Faculty of medical sciences, Lebanese University, Beirut, Lebanon, Fatima S. Eldine; University of Beghazi Faculty of Medicine, Fatima Ajaz; Student in University of Doha for Science and Technology, Sondos S. A. Hassan; Student at Faculty of Medicine Ain Shams University, Egypt, Israa Jaber; Faculty of Medicine, Alquds University, Palestine, Tasneem Alsharabi; Mansoura University Manchester Medical Program, Noura S. Al-Harmali; National University of Science and Technology, Zahraa Shamas; Faculty of Medicine, Lebanese University, Lebanon, Ahmed Saad; Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt, Nouhaila Innan; Faculty of Sciences Ben M’sick, Hassan II University of Casablanca, Morocco, Aseelah Nusair; A final year medical student (practical year), Benghazi Medical University, Mohammad A. Mtairek; Faculty of Medicine, Damascus University, Damascus, Syria, Umalbaneen I. Al-Essa; College of Dentistry, University of Basrah, Iraq, Manel Mili; Faculty of Science of Monastir, Zahra M. Alhoori; Intern Doctor, Internship in Dammam Medical Complex, Saudi Arabia, Leen M. Alhanandeh; Medicine/Yarmouk University/Irbid/Jordan, Salah A. S. Alsheikh; School of Medicine, National University, Sudan, Zaid A. Khalaf; University of Basrah (College of Dentistry), Walaa Ahmed; Medical Student at the National University of Science and Technology, Maimoona M. ur Rahman; B.Sc. Midwifery, College of Health Science, University of Doha for Science and Technology (UDST), Doha, Qatar, Noor F. F. M. Alasfoor; Medical Intern in Mansoura University Hospital in Mansoura, Egypt, Layla Y. Amralla; Currently Intern, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt, Amgad H. H. Obied; Pharmacology Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Omdurman Islamic University, Khartoum, Sudan, Hawwa J. Altaeb; Faculty of Medicine, Tripoli University, Tripoli, Abdullah M. Shaker; College of Dentistry, Basra, Mariam Moselmani; Neuroscience Research Center, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Lebanese University, Sara K. Emghaib; Tobruk University Faculty of Medicine, Manel Ferjani; Faculty of Dental Medicine Monastir, Monastir University, Rania Essouei; IHEC Carthage, Carthage University, Tunis, Tunisia, Souad M. Al Okla; College of Medicine and Health Sciences, National University of Science and Technology, Mostafa Aboheif; Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt, Nawaf M. Hammoud; College of Dentistry, Basra University, Basrah, Iraq, Mazen A. Adam; Intern Doctor at Alexandria Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria, Egypt, Kimia M. Askari; Final year medical student in National University, Hossam Al-Hamidi; <inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e3809" xlink:href="12913_2025_13832_Figa_HTML.gif"/>, Dalia Safwat; Faculty of Science Biochemistry Department, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt, Ayman A. D. Mohamed; Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Omdurman Islamic University, Sudan, Nadia F. Al-Bashtawi; Faculty of Medicine, Yarmouk University, Jordan, Areen Melhem; Medical Student in Yarmouk University, Irbid, Jordan, Fathia G. Elatrash; Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria, Egypt, Sara Y. Aouadi; Mouloud Mammeri University of Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria, Khaled Seggar; Faculty of Medicine, Kasdi Merbah Ouargla, Heba K. Saad; School of Biotechnology, Mayam Mohamed; Faculty of Medicine, Menofia University, Menofia, Egypt, Ehab N. R. Naser; Lecturer, Physical Therapy, Al Salam University, Tanta, Egypt, Mariam B. Baz; Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Egypt, Malaak M. Mashery; Faculty of Medicine, Tobruk University, Asma S. Jama; Faculty of Medicine, Amoud University, Somalia, Alaeldin Ali; Faculty of Medicine, Ibnsina University, Khartoum, Sudan, Siwar B. Salem; Faculty of Medicine, Monastir University, Monastir, Tunisia, Hussain A. H. Abdulber; Faculty of Medicine, University of Science and Technology, Sana’a, Yemen, Heba Alaa; Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Egypt, Hend A. Abdelgawad; Mansoura University Hospitals, Malak A. Ashoory; Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>AEA: leading the team, ideation, idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, data analysis with interpretation, writing in all sections, and final full manuscript editing. MA: idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, writing in introduction, final manuscript editing. OQH: valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, writing in discussion, and final manuscript editing. AMS: Idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, participated in writing. AMK: valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, writing in discussion. RAI: Idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, and writing Methods. MRAFH: Idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, and final editing. IR: Idea validation, valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, data collection management, writing conclusion and abstract. AMS: Valid and reliable questionnaire preparation, statistical planning, and final editing. HTAA: Helped with questionnaire validation and reliability, and data collection from 21 countries. MMIG: Supervising the study.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>Open access funding provided by The Science, Technology &amp; Innovation Funding Authority (STDF) in cooperation with The Egyptian Knowledge Bank (EKB). The authors declare that they have Not received any funding.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>All data generated or analyzed during this study are included in this published article and its supplementary information files.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar21"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par77">This study was carried out following the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki and fully complied with the standards of the Good Clinical Practice (ICH-GCP) Guidelines and applicable local regulatory mandates. Ethical approvals were obtained from ethical committees of the faculty of Medicine at Kafrelshiekh University in Egypt (MKSU51-3–20), the University of Science and Technology in Yemen (2024-E16), Palestine Polytechnic University in Palestine (KA/41/2024), and the Ministry of Health and Prevention in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) (MOHAP/REC/2024/55–2024-f-M). Informed consent was obtained from the participants before they filled out the questionnaire. It clearly outlined the study’s objectives, risks, and benefits. They agreed with this statement: “Filling out this questionnaire constitutes your informed consent to use your answers for research purposes only without revealing your identity or personal data, and you are free to withdraw at any time, without giving a reason. Thank you so much. Confidentiality was emphasized, along with the right of the participant to withdraw from completing the survey at any time. We provided instructions on the first page of the study to ask for parents’ consent before starting the questionnaire if the participant was under 18 years old.</p></notes><notes id="FPar22"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par78">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar23" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par79">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><notes id="FPar223"><title>Consortium</title><p id="Par80">HealthTech Alliance</p><p id="Par81">Jhancy Malay<sup>1</sup>, Sarah A. Haji<sup>2</sup>, Mawada A. H. Taha<sup>3</sup>, Fada S. Alzeidi<sup>4</sup>, Badr A. Al-Tayar<sup>95</sup>, Awlaa Adil<sup>5</sup>, Alaa Mahmoudy<sup>6</sup>, Hiba Y. Yaghmour<sup>7</sup>, Mariam A. Abdulhay<sup>8</sup>, Malak S. Mahdi<sup>9</sup>, Fatema Almadhoob<sup>10</sup>, Djehina Ferhat<sup>11</sup>, Amr Khaled<sup>12</sup>, Omaima Y. A. Al Shehhi<sup>13</sup>, Fatema I. J. Alshakhoori<sup>10</sup>, Eman S. N. Shubbar<sup>15</sup>, Hussam S. Aziz<sup>9</sup>, Younes F. Samara<sup>17</sup>, Noor Alhuda R. Mohammed<sup>18</sup>, Sharouq R. A. Al Rubaiei<sup>19</sup>, Tasnim Tarboush<sup>20</sup>, Mahmoud E. Kamal<sup>21</sup>, Fatma A. Al-shamsi<sup>22</sup>, Ahmad Al Othman<sup>23</sup>, Zohra Bensayah<sup>24</sup>, Danya Ibrahim<sup>25</sup>, Manal Al-Ghafri<sup>26</sup>, Amjd Sobh<sup>27</sup>, Butaina Abdulhafith<sup>28</sup>, Bayan S. M. J. A. Alawi<sup>29</sup>, Alshaima A. H. Koko<sup>30</sup>, Fatema M. Shehab<sup>31</sup>, Aaya E. Ahmed<sup>32</sup>, Fatema S. M. J. Alawi<sup>33</sup>, Shatha Almabrok<sup>34</sup>, Marwan Alqudah<sup>35</sup>, Fada M. H. Al-Ghfeeili<sup>36</sup>, Nagham Alkhateeb<sup>37</sup>, Mohammad H. Awde<sup>38</sup>, Dina E. Abozaid<sup>39</sup>, Taqi M. J. Taher<sup>40</sup>, Alaa Youness<sup>41</sup>, Mahmoud A. M. Albadawi<sup>42</sup>, Mohammad Darwish<sup>43</sup>, Rowayda Hamouda<sup>44</sup>, Mayameen H. Salman<sup>45</sup>, Kareem Ibraheem<sup>46</sup>, Lomass Soliman<sup>47</sup>, Noha Taymour<sup>48</sup>, Hanan A. S. Barbaid<sup>49</sup>, Haidar Kanso<sup>50</sup>, Hanan A. S. Bamatraf<sup>51</sup>, Khalil Smirat<sup>52</sup>, Afia Murshida<sup>53</sup>, Samar Al-Jabri<sup>54</sup>, Ahmed S. Al Sakini<sup>55</sup>, Wadea A. A. A. Abduh<sup>56</sup>, Ruqaia Shoheeduzzaman<sup>57</sup>, Fatima J. S. Bawazeer<sup>58</sup>, Haidy Samy<sup>59</sup>, Ali Alasassi<sup>60</sup>, Shawqi Seder<sup>61</sup>, Ahmad Alkheder<sup>62</sup>, Lina S. A. Alqumairi<sup>63</sup>, Ghadeer A. A. Al-Surabi<sup>64</sup>, Manel Ferjani<sup>14</sup>, Rania Essouei<sup>16</sup>, Ahmed G. Elmenady<sup>65</sup>, Nour Hamed<sup>38</sup>, Dalal J. Saed<sup>66</sup>, Amaal Dier<sup>67</sup>, Shima A. M. Musa<sup>68</sup>, Naris M. Kadoura<sup>69</sup>, Asma Maliha<sup>70</sup>, Juman Muhtaseb<sup>71</sup>, Rama A. Abu Doush<sup>72</sup>, Shahed M. Benghuzi<sup>73</sup>, Sara A. Araed<sup>74</sup>, Abdullah Khalailah<sup>75</sup>, Hind A. Abdulhay<sup>76</sup>, Omar I. Bsharat<sup>77</sup>, Rasha A. A. Salama<sup>78</sup>, Nour Moosa<sup>79</sup>, Baraa M. A. Khader<sup>80</sup>, Mirna F. Mustafa<sup>81</sup>, Husam Abu Dawood<sup>82</sup>, Ghalia Al Turki<sup>83</sup>, Amal Njoom<sup>84</sup>, Habib Alfalah<sup>85</sup>, Abdullah Ayad<sup>86</sup>, Sarah M. Abdelmohsen<sup>87</sup>, Ali Albashiri<sup>88</sup>, Amer O. Girnos<sup>89</sup>, Aya Kawssan<sup>90</sup>, Zoha Rasheed<sup>91</sup>, Rama Alsukhni<sup>92</sup>, Mahmoud N. Bani Hani<sup>93</sup>, Marwan F. Alzboon<sup>95</sup>, Muhammed M. Abdiwahab<sup>96</sup>, Solaima<sup>97</sup>, Nourin N.Sayed<sup>98</sup>, Zainab M. J. Malalla<sup>99</sup>, Abdullah M. Zahran<sup>100</sup>, Anas<sup>101</sup>, Wesam S. A. Elariny<sup>102</sup>, Alanoud AlShahwani<sup>103</sup>, Nooran A.Mohammed<sup>104</sup></p><p id="Par82"><sup>1</sup>Faculty of Pediatrics, RAK Medical and Health Sciences University, Ras Al Khaimah, United Arab Emirates</p><p id="Par83"><sup>2</sup>Lecturer, Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, College of Dentistry, University of Basrah, Basrah, Iraq</p><p id="Par84"><sup>3</sup>Surgery, National Ribat University, Faculty of Medicine, Khartoum, Sudan</p><p id="Par85"><sup>4</sup>Student in the National University of Science and Technology, Sohar, Oman</p><p id="Par86"><sup>5</sup>Faculty of Medicine, National University, Sohar, Sultanate of Oman</p><p id="Par87"><sup>6</sup>Faculty of Science, Zagazig University, Department of Biochemistry, Giza</p><p id="Par88"><sup>7</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par89"><sup>8</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura–Manchester Program, Mansoura, Egypt</p><p id="Par90"><sup>9</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt</p><p id="Par91"><sup>10</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par92"><sup>11</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Ben Youssef Ben Khadda University 1, Algiers, Algeria</p><p id="Par93"><sup>12</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Assiut University, Assiut, Egypt</p><p id="Par94"><sup>13</sup>College of Medicine, National University of Science and Technology</p><p id="Par95"><sup>14</sup>Faculty of Dental Medicine, Monastir University, Monastir, Tunisia</p><p id="Par96"><sup>15</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par97"><sup>16</sup>IHEC Carthage, Carthage University, Tunis, Tunisia</p><p id="Par98"><sup>17</sup>Hashimiyya University</p><p id="Par99"><sup>18</sup>College of Dentistry, University of Basrah, Basrah 61004, Iraq</p><p id="Par100"><sup>19</sup>National University of Science and Technology, College of Medicine and Health Sciences</p><p id="Par101"><sup>20</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt</p><p id="Par102"><sup>21</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Egyptian Russian University, Badr City, Egypt</p><p id="Par103"><sup>22</sup>National University in Medicine, Muscat, Oman</p><p id="Par104"><sup>23</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Near East University, Nicosia, North Cyprus</p><p id="Par105"><sup>24</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Ben Youssef Ben Khadda University 1, Algiers, Algeria</p><p id="Par106"><sup>25</sup>Faculty of Medicine, University of Khartoum, Khartoum, Sudan</p><p id="Par107"><sup>26</sup>Final-year Medical Student, National University, Oman</p><p id="Par108"><sup>27</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Tartous University, Tartous, Syria</p><p id="Par109"><sup>28</sup>Faculty of Medicine, University of Tripoli, Tripoli, Libya</p><p id="Par110"><sup>29</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par111"><sup>30</sup>National Ribat University, Sudan</p><p id="Par112"><sup>31</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par113"><sup>32</sup>Dubai Medical College for Girls, Dubai, United Arab Emirates</p><p id="Par114"><sup>33</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par115"><sup>34</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt</p><p id="Par116"><sup>35</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt</p><p id="Par117"><sup>36</sup>Medical Student, National University of Science and Technology, Sohar, Oman</p><p id="Par118"><sup>37</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par119"><sup>38</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Damascus University, Damascus, Syria</p><p id="Par120"><sup>39</sup>Faculty of Dentistry, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt</p><p id="Par121"><sup>40</sup>Family and Community Medicine Department, College of Medicine, Wasit University, Wasit, Iraq</p><p id="Par122"><sup>41</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Lebanese University, Al Hadath, Lebanon</p><p id="Par123"><sup>42</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafr El-Sheikh, Egypt</p><p id="Par124"><sup>43</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology</p><p id="Par125"><sup>44</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafr El-Sheikh, Egypt</p><p id="Par126"><sup>45</sup>Graduated Medical Doctor, Wasit University</p><p id="Par127"><sup>46</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par128"><sup>47</sup>Institute of Pharmaceutical Technology and Regulatory Affairs, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Szeged, Hungary</p><p id="Par129"><sup>48</sup>Department of Substitutive Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University, Dammam, Saudi Arabia</p><p id="Par130"><sup>49</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Hadhramout University, Yemen</p><p id="Par131"><sup>50</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Damascus University, Damascus, Syria</p><p id="Par132"><sup>51</sup>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hadhramout University, Yemen</p><p id="Par133"><sup>52</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Jordan</p><p id="Par134"><sup>53</sup>Faculty of Health, School of Medicine and Population Health, University of Sheffield, UK</p><p id="Par135"><sup>54</sup>College of Medicine and Health Sciences, National University of Science and Technology, Oman</p><p id="Par136"><sup>55</sup>College of Medicine, University of Baghdad, Iraq</p><p id="Par137"><sup>56</sup>University for Medical and Applied Sciences, Yemen</p><p id="Par138"><sup>57</sup>Department of Biological and Environmental Sciences, Qatar University, Qatar</p><p id="Par139"><sup>58</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Hadhramout University, Al-Mukalla, Yemen</p><p id="Par140"><sup>59</sup>Faculty of Physical Therapy, Modern University for Technology and Information, Egypt</p><p id="Par141"><sup>60</sup>Faculty of Clinical Pharmacy, Egyptian Russian University, Egypt</p><p id="Par142"><sup>61</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par143"><sup>62</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Damascus University &amp; Syrian Private University, Damascus, Syria</p><p id="Par144"><sup>63</sup>Graduate Doctor, National University, Oman</p><p id="Par145"><sup>64</sup>Student, Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Sana’a University, Sana’a City, Yemen</p><p id="Par146"><sup>65</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Dakahlia, Egypt</p><p id="Par147"><sup>66</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Tobruk University, Tobruk, Libya</p><p id="Par148"><sup>67</sup>Faculty of Medicine, University of Tripoli, Libya</p><p id="Par149"><sup>68</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Al-Neelain University, Khartoum, Sudan</p><p id="Par150"><sup>69</sup>Mansoura Manchester Medical Program, Egypt</p><p id="Par151"><sup>70</sup>Qatar University</p><p id="Par152"><sup>71</sup>Faculty of Nursing, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par153"><sup>72</sup>Faculty of Dentistry, University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan</p><p id="Par154"><sup>73</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par155"><sup>74</sup>Faculty of Dentistry, University of Benghazi, Benghazi, Libya</p><p id="Par156"><sup>75</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria university, Alexandria, Egypt</p><p id="Par157"><sup>76</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University – Manchester Program</p><p id="Par158"><sup>77</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Kuwait</p><p id="Par159"><sup>78</sup>Department of Community Medicine, Ras Al kHaimah Medical and Health Science University, Ras Al khaimah, UAE</p><p id="Par160"><sup>79</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par161"><sup>80</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Egypt</p><p id="Par162"><sup>81</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Al-Quds University, Palestine</p><p id="Par163"><sup>82</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par164"><sup>83</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Manchester Program</p><p id="Par165"><sup>84</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Hebron, Palestine</p><p id="Par166"><sup>85</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Jordan</p><p id="Par167"><sup>86</sup>College of Dentistry, University of Basrah, Basrah, Iraq</p><p id="Par168"><sup>87</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Aswan University, Aswan, Egypt</p><p id="Par169"><sup>88</sup>Faculty of Medicine, University of Science and Technology</p><p id="Par170"><sup>89</sup>Faculty of Medicine, University of Duhok, Duhok, Iraq</p><p id="Par171"><sup>90</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Lebanese University, Beirut, Lebanon</p><p id="Par172"><sup>91</sup>University of Doha for Science and Technology</p><p id="Par173"><sup>92</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Hashemite University, Al-Zarqa, Jordan</p><p id="Par174"><sup>93</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology (JUST)</p><p id="Par175"><sup>94</sup>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Science and Technology, Sana’a, Yemen</p><p id="Par176"><sup>95</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Alexandria University, Egypt</p><p id="Par177"><sup>96</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt</p><p id="Par178"><sup>97</sup>Affiliation not available</p><p id="Par179"><sup>98</sup>Master’s in Psychology, University of Kerala, India</p><p id="Par180"><sup>99</sup>Mansoura University, Egypt</p><p id="Par181"><sup>100</sup>College of Medicine, Palestine Polytechnic University, Palestine</p><p id="Par182"><sup>101</sup>Affiliation not available</p><p id="Par183"><sup>102</sup>Faculty of Agriculture, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt</p><p id="Par184"><sup>103</sup>Hayat Universal School (HUBS), Qatar</p><p id="Par185"><sup>104</sup>Faculty of Medicine, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clarke AC. Profiles of the future: an inquiry into the limits of the possible. 1984;251. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://books.google.com/books/about/Profiles_of_the_Future.html?id=pSAhAQAAIAAJ">https://books.google.com/books/about/Profiles_of_the_Future.html?id=pSAhAQAAIAAJ</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alsaleh A. The impact of technological advancement on culture and society. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):1–8. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-83995-z">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-83995-z</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41598-024-83995-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11685575</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39738478</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adamopoulou E, Moussiades L. Chatbots: history, technology, and applications. Mach Learn Appl. 2020;2:100006.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chakraborty C, Pal S, Bhattacharya M, Dash S, Lee SS. Overview of chatbots with special emphasis on artificial intelligence-enabled ChatGPT in medical science. Front Artif Intell. 2023;6:1237704. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10644239/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10644239/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/frai.2023.1237704</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10644239</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38028668</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh J, Sillerud B, Singh A. Artificial intelligence, chatbots and ChatGPT in healthcare-narrative review of historical evolution, current application, and change management approach to increase adoption. J Med Artif Intell. 2023;6 Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://jmai.amegroups.org/article/view/8271/html">https://jmai.amegroups.org/article/view/8271/html</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teubner T, Flath CM, Weinhardt C, van der Aalst W, Hinz O. Welcome to the Era of ChatGPT, et al.: the prospects of large language models. Bus Inf Syst Eng. 2023;65(2):95–101. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12599-023-00795-x">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12599-023-00795-x</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laymouna M, Ma Y, Lessard D, Schuster T, Engler K, Lebouché B. Roles, users, benefits, and limitations of chatbots in health care: rapid review. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26(1):e56930. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.jmir.org/2024/1/e56930">https://www.jmir.org/2024/1/e56930</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/56930</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11303905</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39042446</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bulchand-Gidumal J, William Secin E, O’Connor P, Buhalis D. Artificial intelligence’s impact on hospitality and tourism marketing: exploring key themes and addressing challenges. Curr Issues Tour. 2024;27(14):2345–62. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/13683500.2023.2229480">https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/13683500.2023.2229480</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soni N, Sharma EK, Singh N, Kapoor A. Artificial intelligence in business: from research and innovation to market deployment. Procedia Comput Sci. 2020;1(167):2200–10.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalifa M, Albadawy M. Using artificial intelligence in academic writing and research: an essential productivity tool. Comput Methods Programs Biomed Update. 2024;5:100145.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crompton H, Burke D. Artificial intelligence in higher education: the state of the field. Int J Educ Technol Higher Educ. 2023;20(1):1–22. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://educationaltechnologyjournal.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s41239-023-00392-8">https://educationaltechnologyjournal.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s41239-023-00392-8</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das KP, C J. A survey on artificial intelligence for reducing the climate footprint in healthcare. Energy Nexus. 2023;9:100167.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chakraborty C, Pal S, Bhattacharya M, Islam MA. AI-enabled ChatGPT’s carbon footprint and its use in the healthcare sector: a coin has two sides. Int J Surg. 2023;110(2):1306. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10871565/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10871565/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/JS9.0000000000000905</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10871565</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37994740</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clark M, Bailey S. Chatbots in health care: connecting patients to information. Chatbots in health care: connecting patients to information. Emerg Health Technol. 2024. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK602381/">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK602381/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38564540</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albous MR, Al-Jayyousi OR, Stephens M. AI governance in the GCC States: a comparative analysis of National AI strategies. J Artif Intel Res. 2025;82:2389–422. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.02174">http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.02174</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">UAE-National-Strategy-for-Artificial-Intelligence-2031.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alowais SA, Alghamdi SS, Alsuhebany N, Alqahtani T, Alshaya AI, Almohareb SN, et al. Revolutionizing healthcare: the role of artificial intelligence in clinical practice. BMC Med Educ. 2023;23(1):1–15. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-023-04698-z">https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-023-04698-z</ext-link><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12909-023-04698-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10517477</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37740191</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beheshti M, Toubal IE, Alaboud K, Almalaysha M, Ogundele OB, Turabieh H, et al. Evaluating the reliability of ChatGPT for health-related questions: a systematic review. Informatics. 2025;12(1):9. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9709/12/1/9/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9709/12/1/9/htm</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanna MG, Pantanowitz L, Jackson B, Palmer O, Visweswaran S, Pantanowitz J, et al. Ethical and Bias Considerations in artificial intelligence/machine learning. Mod Pathol. 2025;38(3):100686.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.modpat.2024.100686</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39694331</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker HL, Ghani S, Kuemmerli C, Nebiker CA, Müller BP, Raptis DA, et al. Reliability of Medical information provided by ChatGPT: assessment against clinical guidelines and patient information quality instrument. J Med Internet Res. 2023;25:e47479. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10365578/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10365578/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/47479</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10365578</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37389908</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saeidnia HR, Nilashi M. From MYCIN to MedGemma: a historical and comparative analysis of healthcare AI evolution. Infosci Trends. 2025;2(6):18–28. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.isjtrend.com/article_222739.html">https://www.isjtrend.com/article_222739.html</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdelhafiz AS, Farghly MI, Sultan EA, Abouelmagd ME, Ashmawy Y, Elsebaie EH. Medical students and ChatGPT: analyzing attitudes, practices, and academic perceptions. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):187. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-025-06731-9">https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-025-06731-9</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12909-025-06731-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11800517</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39910593</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Surbaya SH, Khan AA, Surbaya SH, Alzahrani SM. Knowledge, attitude and practice toward artificial intelligence among healthcare workers in private polyclinics in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. Adv Med Educ Pract. 2024;15:269–80. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38596622/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38596622/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/AMEP.S448422</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11001543</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38596622</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wah JNK. Revolutionizing e-health: the transformative role of AI-powered hybrid chatbots in healthcare solutions. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1530799. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11865260/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11865260/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1530799</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11865260</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40017541</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Anezi FM. Exploring the use of ChatGPT as a virtual health coach for chronic disease management. Learn Health Syst. 2024;8(3):e10406. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11257053/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11257053/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/lrh2.10406</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11257053</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39036525</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahsavar Y, Choudhury A. User Intentions to use ChatGPT for self-diagnosis and health-related purposes: cross-sectional survey study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2023;10. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37195756/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37195756/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/47564</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10233444</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37195756</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wong CA, Madanay F, Ozer EM, Harris SK, Moore M, Master SO, et al. Digital health Technology to enhance Adolescent and young adult clinical preventive services: affordances and challenges. J Adolesc Health. 2020;67(2):S24–33. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.jahonline.org/action/showFullText?pii=S1054139X19308675">https://www.jahonline.org/action/showFullText?pii=S1054139X19308675</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2019.10.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11925059</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32718511</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taba M, Allen TB, Caldwell PHY, Skinner SR, Kang M, McCaffery K, et al. Adolescents’ self-efficacy and digital health literacy: a cross-sectional mixed methods study. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):1223. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9207829/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9207829/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12889-022-13599-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9207829</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35725389</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fulmer R, Zhai Y. Artificial intelligence in human growth and development: applications through the lifespan. Fam J. 2024. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10664807241282331?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.1">https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10664807241282331?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.1</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vertsberger D, Naor N, Winsberg M. Adolescents’ Well-being while using a mobile artificial intelligence-powered acceptance commitment Therapy tool: evidence from a longitudinal study. JMIR AI 2022;1(1):e38171. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11041447/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11041447/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/38171</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11041447</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38875600</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brisson J, Bélisle-Pipon JC, Ravitsky V. Investigating the influence of artificial intelligence on adolescent health: an urgent call to action. J Adolesc Health. 2023;73(4):795. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.jahonline.org/action/showFullText?pii=S1054139X23003129">https://www.jahonline.org/action/showFullText?pii=S1054139X23003129</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2023.06.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37716717</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahsavar Y, Choudhury A. User Intentions to use ChatGPT for self-diagnosis and health-related purposes: cross-sectional survey study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2023;10:e47564. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10233444/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10233444/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/47564</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10233444</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37195756</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brauner P, Hick A, Philipsen R, Ziefle M. What does the public think about artificial intelligence?-A criticality map to understand bias in the public perception of AI. Front Comput Sci. 2023;5:1113903.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Altamimi I, Altamimi A, Alhumimidi AS, Altamimi A, Temsah MH. Artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots in Medicine: a supplement, not a substitute. Cureus. 2023;15(6):e40922. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10367431/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10367431/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7759/cureus.40922</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10367431</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37496532</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epi InfoTM | CDC. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.cdc.gov/epiinfo/index.html">https://www.cdc.gov/epiinfo/index.html</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">IBM SPSS Software. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.ibm.com/spss">https://www.ibm.com/spss</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Free online spreadsheet software: excel | microsoft 365. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/excel">https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/excel</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benda N, Desai P, Reza Z, Zheng A, Kumar S, Harkins S, et al. Patient Perspectives on AI for mental health care: cross-sectional survey study. JMIR Ment Health. 2024;11(1):e58462. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39293056">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39293056</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/58462</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11447436</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39293056</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ng JY, Maduranayagam SG, Suthakar N, Li A, Lokker C, Iorio A, et al. Attitudes and perceptions of medical researchers towards the use of artificial intelligence chatbots in the scientific process: an international cross-sectional survey. Lancet Digit Health. 2024;7(1):e94–102. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.thelancet.com/article/S2589750024002024/fulltext">http://www.thelancet.com/article/S2589750024002024/fulltext</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/S2589-7500(24)00202-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39550312</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Labadze L, Grigolia M, Machaidze L. Role of AI chatbots in education: systematic literature review. Available from: 10.1186/s41239-023-00426-1.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swed S, Alibrahim H, Elkalagi NKH, Nasif MN, Rais MA, Nashwan AJ, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practice of artificial intelligence among doctors and medical students in Syria: a cross-sectional online survey. Front Artif Intell. 2022;5:1011524. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9558737/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9558737/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/frai.2022.1011524</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9558737</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36248622</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kharroubi SA, Tannir I, Abu El Hassan R, Ballout R. Knowledge, attitude, and practices toward artificial intelligence among university students in Lebanon. Educ Sci (Basel). 2024;14(8):863. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-7102/14/8/863/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2227-7102/14/8/863/htm</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bodani N, Lal A, Maqsood A, Altamash S, Ahmed N, Heboyan A. Knowledge, attitude, and practices of general population toward utilizing ChatGPT: a cross-sectional study. Sage Open. 2023;13(4). Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/21582440231211079">https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/21582440231211079</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Habib MM, Hoodbhoy Z, Siddiqui MAR. Knowledge, attitudes, and perceptions of healthcare students and professionals on the use of artificial intelligence in healthcare in Pakistan. PLoS Digit Health. 2024;3(5):e0000443. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11086889/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11086889/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pdig.0000443</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11086889</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38728363</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR45" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tandar</surname><given-names>CE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bajaj</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stanford</surname><given-names>FC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Social media and artificial intelligence-understanding medical misinformation through snapchat’s new artificial intelligence chatbot</article-title><source>Mayo Clinic Proc Digit Health</source><year>2024</year><volume>2</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>252</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mcpdig.2024.04.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11221787</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38962215</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR45" publication-type="journal">Tandar CE, Bajaj SS, Stanford FC. Social media and artificial intelligence-understanding medical misinformation through snapchat’s new artificial intelligence chatbot. Mayo Clinic Proc Digit Health. 2024;2(2):252. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11221787/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11221787/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.mcpdig.2024.04.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11221787</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38962215</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Appel G, Grewal L, Hadi R, Stephen AT. The future of social media in marketing. J Acad Mark Sci. 2020;48(1):79–95. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11747-019-00695-1">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11747-019-00695-1</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11747-019-00695-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7222052</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32431463</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR47" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Menon</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shilpa</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>“Chatting with ChatGPT”: analyzing the factors influencing users’ intention to use the Open AI’s ChatGPT using the UTAUT model</article-title><source>Heliyon</source><year>2023</year><volume>9</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>e20962</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20962</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37928033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10623159</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR47" publication-type="journal">Menon D, Shilpa K. “Chatting with ChatGPT”: analyzing the factors influencing users’ intention to use the Open AI’s ChatGPT using the UTAUT model. Heliyon. 2023;9(11):e20962.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37928033</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20962</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10623159</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Temsah MH, Aljamaan F, Malki KH, Alhasan K, Altamimi I, Aljarbou R, et al. ChatGPT and the future of digital health: a study on healthcare workers’ perceptions and expectations. Healthcare Switzerland 2023;11(13):1812. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10340744/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10340744/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/healthcare11131812</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10340744</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37444647</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Del-Valle-Soto C, Briseño RA, López-Pimentel JC, Velázquez R, Valdivia LJ, Varela-Aldás J. Bridging the digital divide in Mexico: a critical analysis of telecommunications infrastructure and predictive models for policy innovation. Telecom. 2024;5(4): Available from: 1076–101. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2673-4001/5/4/55/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2673-4001/5/4/55/htm</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nittas V, Daniore P, Chavez SJ, Wray TB. Challenges in implementing cultural adaptations of digital health interventions. Commun Med. 2024;4(1):1–5. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-023-00426-2">https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-023-00426-2</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s43856-023-00426-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10770150</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38182750</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoque MR, Bao Y. Cultural influence on adoption and use of e-health: evidence in Bangladesh. Telemed J E Health. 2015;21(10):845–51. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26348844/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26348844/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1089/tmj.2014.0128</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26348844</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kwilinski A, Szczepanska-Woszczyna K, Lyulyov O, Pimonenko T. Digital public services: catalysts for healthcare efficiency. J Open Innov: Technol Market Complexity. 2024;10(3):100319.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu L, Sanders L, Li K, Chow JCL. Chatbot for health care and oncology applications using artificial intelligence and machine learning: systematic review. JMIR Cancer. 2021;7(4). Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8669585/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8669585/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/27850</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8669585</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34847056</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oh YJ, Zhang J, Fang ML, Fukuoka Y. A systematic review of artificial intelligence chatbots for promoting physical activity, healthy diet, and weight loss. Int J Behavioral Nutr Phys Activity. 2021;18(1):1–25. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://ijbnpa.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12966-021-01224-6">https://ijbnpa.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12966-021-01224-6</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12966-021-01224-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8665320</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34895247</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR55"><label>55.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ni Z, Peng ML, Balakrishnan V, Tee V, Azwa I, Saifi R, et al. Implementation of chatbot Technology in health care: protocol for a bibliometric analysis. JMIR Res Protoc. 2024;13(1):e54349. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10905346/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10905346/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/54349</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10905346</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38228575</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR56"><label>56.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scerri A, Morin KH. Using chatbots like ChatGPT to support nursing practice. J Clin Nurs. 2023;32(15–16):4211–13. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/jocn.16677">https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/jocn.16677</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jocn.16677</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36880216</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR57"><label>57.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grassini E, Buzzi M, Leporini B, Vozna A. A systematic review of chatbots in inclusive healthcare: insights from the last 5 years. Univers Access Inf Soc. 2024;1–9. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10209-024-01118-x">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10209-024-01118-x</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR58"><label>58.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li YH, Li YL, Wei MY, Li GY. Innovation and challenges of artificial intelligence technology in personalized healthcare. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):18994. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11329630/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11329630/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41598-024-70073-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11329630</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39152194</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR59"><label>59.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyrowitsch DW, Jensen AK, Sørensen JB, Varga T V. AI chatbots and (mis)information in public health: impact on vulnerable communities. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1226776. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10644115/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10644115/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1226776</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10644115</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38026315</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR60"><label>60.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saeidnia HR, Hashemi Fotami SG, Lund B, Ghiasi N. Ethical considerations in artificial intelligence interventions for mental health and well-being: ensuring responsible implementation and impact. Soc Sci. 2024;13(7):381. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2076-0760/13/7/381/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2076-0760/13/7/381/htm</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR61"><label>61.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao Y, Viberg O, Baker RS, Kizilcec RF. Cultural bias and cultural alignment of large language models. PNAS Nexus. 2024;3(9). Available from: 10.1093/pnasnexus/pgae346.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/pnasnexus/pgae346</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11407280</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39290441</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR62"><label>62.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen Q, Jing Y, Gong Y, Tan J. Will users fall in love with ChatGPT? a perspective from the triangular theory of love. J Bus Res. 2025;186:114982.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR63"><label>63.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li H, Zhang R. Finding love in algorithms: deciphering the emotional contexts of close encounters with AI chatbots. J Comput Mediat Commun. 2024;29(5). Available from: 10.1093/jcmc/zmae015.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR64"><label>64.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin B. The AI chatbot always flirts with me, should i flirt back: from the McDonaldization of friendship to the robotization of love. Soc Media Soc. 2024;10(4). Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/20563051241296229?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.32">https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/20563051241296229?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.32</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR65"><label>65.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krishnan G, Singh S, Pathania M, Gosavi S, Abhishek S, Parchani A, et al. Artificial intelligence in clinical medicine: catalyzing a sustainable global healthcare paradigm. Front Artif Intell. 2023;6:1227091. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10497111/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10497111/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/frai.2023.1227091</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10497111</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37705603</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR66"><label>66.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim HK. The effects of artificial intelligence chatbots on women’s health: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare. 2024;12(5):534. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9032/12/5/534/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9032/12/5/534/htm</ext-link>. cited 2025 Apr 19.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/healthcare12050534</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10930454</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38470645</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR67"><label>67.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR67" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mou</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>How does the anthropomorphism of AI chatbots facilitate users’ reuse intention in online health consultation services? The moderating role of disease severity</article-title><source>Technol Forecast Soc Change</source><year>2024</year><volume>203</volume><fpage>123407</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2024.123407</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR67" publication-type="journal">Liu W, Jiang M, Li W, Mou J. How does the anthropomorphism of AI chatbots facilitate users’ reuse intention in online health consultation services? The moderating role of disease severity. Technol Forecast Soc Change. 2024;203:123407.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR68"><label>68.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stöhr C, Ou AW, Malmström H. Perceptions and usage of AI chatbots among students in higher education across genders, academic levels and fields of study. Comput Educ: Artif Intel. 2024;7:100259.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR69"><label>69.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGrath C, Farazouli A, Cerratto-Pargman T. Generative AI chatbots in higher education: a review of an emerging research area. High Educ (dordr). 2024;1–17. Available from<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10734-024-01288-w">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10734-024-01288-w</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR70"><label>70.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adam M, Wessel M, Benlian A. AI-based chatbots in customer service and their effects on user compliance. Electron Mark. 2021;31(2):427–45. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12525-020-00414-7">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12525-020-00414-7</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR71"><label>71.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haugeland IKF, Følstad A, Taylor C, Alexander C. Understanding the user experience of customer service chatbots: an experimental study of chatbot interaction design. Int J Hum Comput Stud. 2022;161:102788.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR72"><label>72.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sparks CA, Fasulo SM, Windsor JT, Bankauskas V, Contrada E V, Kraeutler MJ, et al. ChatGPT is moderately accurate in providing a general overview of orthopaedic conditions. JBJS Open Access. 2024;9(2):e23.00129. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11191019/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11191019/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2106/JBJS.OA.23.00129</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11191019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38912370</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR73"><label>73.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR73" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Babu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boddu</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>BERT-Based Medical chatbot: enhancing healthcare Communication through Natural language Understanding</article-title><source>Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm</source><year>2024</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>100419</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38495953</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.rcsop.2024.100419</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10940906</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR73" publication-type="journal">Babu A, Boddu SB. BERT-Based Medical chatbot: enhancing healthcare communication through natural language understanding. Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm. 2024;13:100419.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38495953</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.rcsop.2024.100419</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10940906</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR74"><label>74.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castagno S, Khalifa M. Perceptions of artificial intelligence among healthcare staff: a qualitative survey study. Front Artif Intell. 2020;3:578983. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.frontiersin.org">https://www.frontiersin.org</ext-link>. cited 2025 Jan 9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/frai.2020.578983</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7861214</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33733219</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR75"><label>75.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer AND, Giardina TD, Spitzmueller C, Shahid U, Scott TMT, Singh H. Patient Perspectives on the usefulness of an artificial intelligence-assisted symptom checker: cross-sectional survey study. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(1). Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32012052/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32012052/</ext-link>. cited 2025 Jan 9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/14679</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7055765</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32012052</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR76"><label>76.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaver J. The state of telehealth before and after the COVID-19 Pandemic. Prim Care. 2022;49(4):517. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9035352/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9035352/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.pop.2022.04.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9035352</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36357058</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR77"><label>77.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shrestha BM. Telemedicine and virtual health care during coronavirus disease Pandemic. JNMA J Nepal Med Assoc. 2020;58(228):547. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7580377/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7580377/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.31729/jnma.5204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7580377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32968285</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR78"><label>78.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoue MG, Cerda AA, García LY, Jakovljevic M. Healthcare system development in the Middle East and North Africa region: challenges, endeavors and prospective opportunities. Front Public Health. 2022;10:1045739. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9815436/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9815436/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1045739</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9815436</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36620278</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR79"><label>79.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsvetanov F. Integrating AI technologies into remote monitoring patient systems. Eng Proc. 2024;70(1):54. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2673-4591/70/1/54/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/2673-4591/70/1/54/htm</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR80"><label>80.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown JEH, Halpern J. AI chatbots cannot replace human interactions in the pursuit of more inclusive mental healthcare. SSM - Ment Health. 2021;1:100017.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR81"><label>81.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amin R, Darwin R, Dey BK, Dhama K, Bin Emran T. Examining the differences between how doctors and artificial intelligence chatbots handle patient symptoms. Int J Surg. 2023;109(10):2892. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10583905/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10583905/</ext-link>. cited 2025 Jan 9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/JS9.0000000000000565</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10583905</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37352516</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR82"><label>82.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Palanica A, Flaschner P, Thommandram A, Li M, Fossat Y. Physicians’ perceptions of chatbots in health care: cross-sectional web-based survey. J Med Internet Res. 2019;21(4):e12887. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6473203/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6473203/</ext-link>. cited 2025 Jan 9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/12887</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6473203</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30950796</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR83"><label>83.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Loh E. ChatGPT and generative AI chatbots: challenges and opportunities for science, medicine and medical leaders. BMJ Lead. 2024;8(1):51–54. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://bmjleader.bmj.com/content/8/1/51">https://bmjleader.bmj.com/content/8/1/51</ext-link>. cited 2025 Jan 9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/leader-2023-000797</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12038121</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37192124</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR84"><label>84.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts LW, Chan S, Torous J. New tests, new tools: mobile and connected technologies in advancing psychiatric diagnosis. npj digital Medicine. 2018;1(1):1–4. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-017-0006-0">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-017-0006-0</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41746-017-0006-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6550288</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31304350</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR85"><label>85.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Islam MR, Urmi TJ, Mosharrafa R, Rahman MS, Kadir MF. Role of ChatGPT in health science and research: a correspondence addressing potential application. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6(10):e1625. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10568002/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10568002/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/hsr2.1625</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10568002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37841943</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR86"><label>86.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR86" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Doraiswamy</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blease</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bodner</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Artificial intelligence and the future of psychiatry: insights from a global physician survey</article-title><source>Artif Intell Med</source><year>2020</year><volume>102</volume><fpage>101753</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.artmed.2019.101753</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31980092</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR86" publication-type="journal">Doraiswamy PM, Blease C, Bodner K. Artificial intelligence and the future of psychiatry: insights from a global physician survey. Artif Intell Med. 2020;102:101753.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31980092</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.artmed.2019.101753</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR87"><label>87.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR87" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jokisch</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>LI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Doh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Acceptance of digital health services among older adults: findings on perceived usefulness, self-efficacy, privacy concerns, ICT knowledge, and support seeking</article-title><source>Front Public Health</source><year>2022</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1073756</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1073756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36582385</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9792847</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR87" publication-type="journal">Jokisch MR, Schmidt LI, Doh M. Acceptance of digital health services among older adults: findings on perceived usefulness, self-efficacy, privacy concerns, ICT knowledge, and support seeking. Front Public Health. 2022;10:1073756.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36582385</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1073756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9792847</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR88"><label>88.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertolazzi A, Quaglia V, Bongelli R. Barriers and facilitators to health technology adoption by older adults with chronic diseases: an integrative systematic review. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):506. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10873991/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10873991/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12889-024-18036-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10873991</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38365698</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR89"><label>89.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR89" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Méndez-Suárez</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Monfort</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hervas-Oliver</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Are you adopting artificial intelligence products? social-demographic factors to explain customer acceptance</article-title><source>Eur Res Manag Bus Econ</source><year>2023</year><volume>29</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>100223</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.iedeen.2023.100223</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR89" publication-type="journal">Méndez-Suárez M, Monfort A, Hervas-Oliver JL. Are you adopting artificial intelligence products? social-demographic factors to explain customer acceptance. Eur Res Manag Bus Econ. 2023;29(3):100223.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR90"><label>90.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aydınlar A, Mavi A, Kütükçü E, Kırımlı EE, Alış D, Akın A, et al. Awareness and level of digital literacy among students receiving health-based education. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):1–13. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-024-05025-w">https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-024-05025-w</ext-link>. cited 2025 Mar 17.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12909-024-05025-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10773083</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38191385</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR91"><label>91.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR91" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Zahrani</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Unveiling the shadows: beyond the hype of AI in education</article-title><source>Heliyon</source><year>2024</year><volume>10</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>e30696</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e30696</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38737255</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11087970</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR91" publication-type="journal">Al-Zahrani AM. Unveiling the shadows: beyond the hype of AI in education. Heliyon. 2024;10(9):e30696.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38737255</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e30696</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11087970</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR92"><label>92.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pegalajar Palomino M del C, Rodríguez Torres ÁF. Digital literacy in university students of education degrees in Ecuador. Front Educ (Lausanne). 2023;8:1299059.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR93"><label>93.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu PF, Summers C, Panesar A, Kaura A, Zhang L. AI hesitancy and acceptability-perceptions of AI chatbots for chronic health management and long covid support: survey study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2024;11. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39045815/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39045815/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2196/51086</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11287232</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39045815</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR94"><label>94.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kurniawan MH, Handiyani H, Nuraini T, Hariyati RTS, Sutrisno S. A systematic review of artificial intelligence-powered (AI-powered) chatbot intervention for managing chronic illness. Ann Med. 2024;56(1):2302980. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10930147/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10930147/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/07853890.2024.2302980</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10930147</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38466897</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR95"><label>95.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alanezi F. Assessing the effectiveness of ChatGPT in delivering mental health support: a qualitative study. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2024;17:461. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10838501/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10838501/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/JMDH.S447368</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10838501</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38314011</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR96"><label>96.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fekih-Romdhane F, Jahrami H, Stambouli M, Alhuwailah A, Helmy M, Shuwiekh HAM, et al. Cross-cultural comparison of mental illness stigma and help-seeking attitudes: a multinational population-based study from 16 Arab countries and 10,036 individuals. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2023;58(4):641–56. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00127-022-02403-x">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00127-022-02403-x</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00127-022-02403-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36583767</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR97"><label>97.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khosravi M, Azar G. Factors influencing patient engagement in mental health chatbots: a thematic analysis of findings from a systematic review of reviews. Digit Health. 2024;10:20552076241247984. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11036914/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11036914/</ext-link>.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/20552076241247983</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11036914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38655378</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>