<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41545387</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A modified Dung Beetle optimizer for combined heat and power economic dispatch considering power losses, valve-point effects, and operating constraints.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2278</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2278</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2278</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32060-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Combined Heat and Power Economic Dispatch (CHPED) problem represents a significant optimization challenge in modern power systems due to its inherent complexity arising from multiple operational constraints. This complexity is further exacerbated when considering the effect of power losses (PLs), valve-point loading effect (VPLE), and prohibited operating zones (POZs). Consequently, an efficient and robust optimization algorithm is essential for obtaining a globally optimal solution while satisfying all constraints. To address these challenges, this work evaluates the effectiveness of the Modified Dung Beetle Optimizer (MDBO) for solving the CHPED problem, considering PLs, VPLE, and POZs. The MDBO enhances the search process and mitigates the limitations of the conventional Dung Beetle Optimizer, particularly stagnation and premature convergence to local optima. The novelty in this paper is proposing a modified version of the traditional DBO (MDBO) by integrating three improvement strategies, including the fitness distance balance (FDB), Chaotic mutation (CM), and adaptive local search approach (ALSA), to solve the CHPED problem. The proposed MDBO has the ability to overcome the shortcomings of traditional DBO, such as its premature convergence and tendency to local optima. The effectiveness of the proposed MDBO has been evaluated on CHPED problems involving 4-unit, 7-unit, 24-unit, and 48-unit systems under various operating conditions. Moreover, MDBO performance has been rigorously assessed using standard benchmark test suites, including CEC-2019. The results demonstrate a significant reduction in operating costs, confirming the superior performance of the MDBO in comparison to existing optimization techniques like Sand Cat Swarm Optimizer (SCSO), African vultures optimization algorithm (AVOA), Sine Cosine Algorithm (SCA), Harris Hawks Optimization (HHO), Grey Wolf Optimizer (GWO), Liver cancer algorithm (LCA), Zebra Optimizer Algorithm (ZOA), and Whale Optimization Algorithm (WOA). Furthermore, the proposed algorithm consistently outperforms alternative methods reported in the literature, offering a more efficient and reliable solution for CHPED optimization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rihan</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Qena University, Qena, 83521, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ebeed</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Department, Faculty of Engineering, Sohag University, Sohag, 82524, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, University of Ja&#xe9;n, 23700 EPS Linares, Ja&#xe9;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Noor Habib</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Qingdao Binhai University, Shandong, 266555, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jamal</LastName><ForeName>Raheela</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Qingdao Binhai University, Shandong, 266555, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elnaka</LastName><ForeName>Mosaed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Qena University, Qena, 83521, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nour</LastName><ForeName>Morsy</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Faculty of Energy Engineering, Aswan University, Aswan, 81528, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamid</LastName><ForeName>Amal M Abd El</ForeName><Initials>AMAE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Department, Faculty of Technology and Education, Sohag University, Sohag, 82524, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mansour</LastName><ForeName>Hany S E</ForeName><Initials>HSE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, Suez Canal University, Ismailia, 41522, Egypt. hany_salem@eng.suez.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001517" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coleoptera</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hot Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic dispatch</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modified Dung Beetle optimizer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power losses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prohibited operating zones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Valve-point-loading-effect</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors have no competing interests or other interests that might be perceived to influence the results and/or discussion reported in this paper. Ethical approval: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41545387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12816586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32060-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32060-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu, C., Shahidehpour, M., Li, Z. &amp; Fotuhi-Firuzabad, M. Component and mode models for the short-term scheduling of combined-cycle units. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Syst.</i><b>24</b>(2), 976&#x2013;990 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2009.2016501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginidi, A. R., Elsayed, A. M., Shaheen, A. M., Elattar, E. E. &amp; El-Sehiemy, R. A. A novel heap-based optimizer for scheduling of large-scale combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 83695&#x2013;83708 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3087449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Li, K., Xu, B. &amp; Yang, Z. Biogeography-based learning particle swarm optimization for combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Knowl.-Based Syst.</i><b>208</b>, 106463 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2020.106463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigo-Mariani, R. et al. A combined cycle gas turbine model for heat and power dispatch subject to grid constraints. <i>IEEE Transactions on Sustainable Energy</i><b>11</b>(1), 448&#x2013;456 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2019.2894793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, A., Moghimi, H., Nezhad, A. E., Agelidis, V. G. &amp; Sharaf, A. M. Multi-objective economic emission dispatch considering combined heat and power by normal boundary intersection method. <i>Electric Power Systems Research</i><b>129</b>, 32&#x2013;43 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2015.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong, A. &amp; Lahdelma, R. An efficient envelope-based Branch and Bound algorithm for non-convex combined heat and power production planning. <i>Eur. J. Oper. Res.</i><b>183</b>(1), 412&#x2013;431 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejor.2006.09.072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sashirekha, A., Pasupuleti, J., Moin, N. &amp; Tan, C. S. Combined heat and power (CHP) economic dispatch solved using Lagrangian relaxation with surrogate subgradient multiplier updates. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>44</b>(1), 421&#x2013;430 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2012.07.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, T., Henwood, M. I. &amp; Van Ooijen, M. An algorithm for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Syst.</i><b>11</b>(4), 1778&#x2013;1784 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/59.544642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. G. Chapa and J. V. Galaz, "An economic dispatch algorithm for cogeneration systems," in <i>IEEE Power Engineering Society General Meeting, 2004.</i>, 2004, pp. 989&#x2013;994: IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C., Wu, W., Zhang, B. &amp; Sun, Y. Decentralized solution for combined heat and power dispatch through benders decomposition. <i>IEEE Transactions on Sustainable Energy</i><b>8</b>(4), 1361&#x2013;1372 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2017.2681108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghian, H. &amp; Ardehali, M. A novel approach for optimal economic dispatch scheduling of integrated combined heat and power systems for maximum economic profit and minimum environmental emissions based on Benders decomposition. <i>Energy</i><b>102</b>, 10&#x2013;23 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2016.02.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari-Heris, M., Mohammadi-Ivatloo, B. &amp; Gharehpetian, G. A comprehensive review of heuristic optimization algorithms for optimal combined heat and power dispatch from economic and environmental perspectives. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>81</b>, 2128&#x2013;2143 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.06.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghrah, A., Nazari-Heris, M. &amp; Mohammadi-Ivatloo, B. Solving combined heat and power economic dispatch problem using real coded genetic algorithm with improved M&#xfc;hlenbein mutation. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>99</b>, 465&#x2013;475 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2015.12.136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, D., Li, S., Kong, X., Ouyang, H. &amp; Li, Z. Solving the combined heat and power economic dispatch problems by an improved genetic algorithm and a new constraint handling strategy. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>237</b>, 646&#x2013;670 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.01.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, C., Srinivasan, D. &amp; Reindl, T. Generation and storage scheduling of combined heat and power. <i>Energy</i><b>124</b>, 693&#x2013;705 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2017.02.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi-Ivatloo, B., Moradi-Dalvand, M. &amp; Rabiee, A. Combined heat and power economic dispatch problem solution using particle swarm optimization with time varying acceleration coefficients. <i>Electric Power Systems Research</i><b>95</b>, 9&#x2013;18 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2012.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. ali Shaabani, A. R. Seifi, and M. J. Kouhanjani, "Stochastic multi-objective optimization of combined heat and power economic/emission dispatch," <i>Energy,</i> vol. 141, pp. 1892&#x2013;1904, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M., Wang, S. &amp; Yan, J. Operation scheduling of a coal-fired CHP station integrated with power-to-heat devices with detail CHP unit models by particle swarm optimization algorithm. <i>Energy</i><b>214</b>, 119022 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.119022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaram, A. Combined heat and power economic emission dispatch using hybrid NSGA II-MOPSO algorithm incorporating an effective constraint handling mechanism. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>8</b>, 13748&#x2013;13768 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2963887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, A. M., Ginidi, A. R., El-Sehiemy, R. A. &amp; Elattar, E. E. Optimal economic power and heat dispatch in Cogeneration Systems including wind power. <i>Energy</i><b>225</b>, 120263 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.120263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdinejad, M., Mohammadi-Ivatloo, B. &amp; Dadashzadeh-Bonab, R. Energy production cost minimization in a combined heat and power generation systems using cuckoo optimization algorithm. <i>Energ. Effi.</i><b>10</b>, 81&#x2013;96 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12053-016-9439-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T. T., Nguyen, T. T. &amp; Vo, D. N. An effective cuckoo search algorithm for large-scale combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>30</b>, 3545&#x2013;3564 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-017-2941-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T. T., Vo, D. N. &amp; Dinh, B. H. Cuckoo search algorithm for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>81</b>, 204&#x2013;214 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2016.02.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar, N., Subramanian, S., Ganesan, S. &amp; Elanchezhian, E. Grey wolf optimization for combined heat and power dispatch with cogeneration systems. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>74</b>, 252&#x2013;264 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2015.07.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigvand, S. D., Abdi, H. &amp; La Scala, M. Combined heat and power economic dispatch problem using gravitational search algorithm. <i>Electric Power Systems Research</i><b>133</b>, 160&#x2013;172 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2015.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davoodi, E., Zare, K. &amp; Babaei, E. A GSO-based algorithm for combined heat and power dispatch problem with modified scrounger and ranger operators. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>120</b>, 36&#x2013;48 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2017.03.114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, A. &amp; Das, D. K. A new Kho-Kho optimization Algorithm: An application to solve combined emission economic dispatch and combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>94</b>, 103763 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2020.103763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, A. M. et al. A novel improved marine predators algorithm for combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>61</b>(3), 1834&#x2013;1851 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2021.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolatabadi, S., El-Sehiemy, R. A. &amp; GhassemZadeh, S. Scheduling of combined heat and generation outputs in power systems using a new hybrid multi-objective optimization algorithm. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>32</b>(14), 10741&#x2013;10757 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-019-04610-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanabadi, R. &amp; Sharifzadeh, H. Solving combined heat and power economic dispatch using a mixed integer model. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>444</b>, 141160 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkaya, B., Duman, S., Kahraman, H. T. &amp; Guvenc, U. Optimal solution of the combined heat and power economic dispatch problem by adaptive fitness-distance balance based artificial rabbits optimization algorithm. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>238</b>, 122272 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, A. M., Ginidi, A. R., Alassaf, A. &amp; Alsaleh, I. Developing artificial hummingbird algorithm with linear controlling strategy and diversified territorial foraging tactics for combined heat and power dispatch. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>105</b>, 245&#x2013;260 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2024.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizk-Allah, R. M., Sn&#xe1;&#x161;el, V. &amp; Hassanien, A. E. Multi-orthogonal-oppositional enhanced African vultures optimization for combined heat and power economic dispatch under uncertainty. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>37</b>(8), 6097&#x2013;6123 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-024-10715-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari, A. &amp; Abdi, H. Solving the combined heat and power economic dispatch problem in different scale systems using the imperialist competitive Harris Hawks optimization algorithm. <i>Biomimetics</i><b>8</b>(8), 587 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics8080587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10741563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib, K., Wadood, A., Wei, T., Khan, S. &amp; Xing, X. Optimal coordination of directional overcurrent protection relays using hybrid optimizer. <i>Engineering Research Express</i><b>6</b>(2), 025330 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/ad43be</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib, K., Habib, S., Khan, S., Jafaripournimchahi, A. &amp; Xing, X. A hybrid optimization approach for strategically placing electric vehicle charging stations in a radial distribution IEEE-33 bus system. <i>Engineering Research Express</i><b>6</b>(2), 025344 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/ad507b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib, K., Xu, X., Ling, H. &amp; Khan, S. Optimum control and thermal management of varying operating conditions of variable frequency drives. <i>Int. J. Heat Mass Transf.</i><b>252</b>, 127496 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.127496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Liu and W. Shen, "Data Acquisition of Exercise and Fitness Pressure Measurement Based on Artificial Intelligence Technology," <i>SLAS Technology,</i> p. 100328, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40619065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. H. et al. Optimization of high-speed channel for signal integrity with deep genetic algorithm. <i>IEEE Trans. Electromagn. Compat.</i><b>64</b>(4), 1270&#x2013;1274 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEMC.2022.3161298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Feng, H. Hong, K. Tang, and J. Wang, "Statistical tests for replacing human decision makers with algorithms," <i>Management Science,</i> 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, J. &amp; Shen, B. Dung beetle optimizer: A new meta-heuristic algorithm for global optimization. <i>J. Supercomput.</i><b>79</b>(7), 7305&#x2013;7336 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-022-04959-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, M., Zhou, H., Yang, H., Hu, B. &amp; Wang, X. Multi-strategy improved dung beetle optimization algorithm and its applications. <i>Biomimetics</i><b>9</b>(5), 291 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics9050291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11117942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38786501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, Q., Zhang, D., Xie, M. &amp; He, Q. Multi-strategy enhanced dung beetle optimizer and its application in three-dimensional UAV path planning. <i>Symmetry</i><b>15</b>(7), 1432 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym15071432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, F. et al. Dung beetle optimization algorithm based on quantum computing and multi-strategy fusion for solving engineering problems. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>236</b>, 121219 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.121219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, W., Zhang, Q. &amp; Ye, S. An enhanced dung beetle optimizer with multiple strategies for robot path planning. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 4655 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-88347-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11806072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39920199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, H., Ke, Y., Liao, R. &amp; Sun, Y. Fractional order calculus enhanced dung beetle optimizer for function global optimization and multilevel threshold medical image segmentation. <i>J. Supercomput.</i><b>81</b>(1), 90 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-024-06592-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abo-Khalil, A. G., Eltamaly, A. M., Alsaud, M. S., Sayed, K. &amp; Alghamdi, A. S. Sensorless control for PMSM using model reference adaptive system. <i>International Transactions on Electrical Energy Systems</i><b>31</b>(2), e12733 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2050-7038.12733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahraman, H. T., Aras, S. &amp; Gedikli, E. Fitness-distance balance (FDB): A new selection method for meta-heuristic search algorithms. <i>Knowl.-Based Syst.</i><b>190</b>, 105169 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2019.105169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aras, S., Gedikli, E. &amp; Kahraman, H. T. A novel stochastic fractal search algorithm with fitness-distance balance for global numerical optimization. <i>Swarm Evol. Comput.</i><b>61</b>, 100821 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.swevo.2020.100821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guvenc, U., Duman, S., Kahraman, H. T., Aras, S. &amp; Kat&#x131;, M. Fitness&#x2013;Distance Balance based adaptive guided differential evolution algorithm for security-constrained optimal power flow problem incorporating renewable energy sources. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>108</b>, 107421 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2021.107421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak&#x131;r, H. Dynamic fitness-distance balance-based artificial rabbits optimization algorithm to solve optimal power flow problem. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>240</b>, 122460 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, K. et al. Hybrid particle swarm optimizer with fitness-distance balance and individual self-exploitation strategies for numerical optimization problems. <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>608</b>, 424&#x2013;452 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2022.06.059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Z. et al. Chaotic wind driven optimization with fitness distance balance strategy. <i>International Journal of Computational Intelligence Systems</i><b>15</b>(1), 46 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44196-022-00099-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebeed, M. et al. A modified artificial hummingbird algorithm for solving optimal power flow problem in power systems. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 982&#x2013;1005 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2023.12.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebeed, M. et al. Solving stochastic optimal reactive power dispatch using an Adaptive Beluga Whale optimization considering uncertainties of renewable energy resources and the load growth. <i>Ain Shams Engineering Journal</i><b>15</b>(7), 102762 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asej.2024.102762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, D. et al. An enhanced jellyfish search optimizer for stochastic energy management of multi-microgrids with wind turbines, biomass and PV generation systems considering uncertainty. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>(1), 15558 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-65867-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11226461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38969676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapitaniak, T. Continuous control and synchronization in chaotic systems. <i>Chaos, Solitons Fractals</i><b>6</b>, 237&#x2013;244 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0960-0779(95)80030-K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noman, A. M. et al. Optimum Fractional Tilt Based Cascaded Frequency Stabilization with MLC Algorithm for Multi-Microgrid Assimilating Electric Vehicles. <i>Fractal and Fractional</i><b>8</b>(3), 132 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fractalfract8030132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastawy, M. et al. Optimal day-ahead scheduling in micro-grid with renewable based DGs and smart charging station of EVs using an enhanced manta-ray foraging optimisation. <i>IET Renew. Power Gener.</i><b>16</b>(11), 2413&#x2013;2428 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/rpg2.12531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, X., Liu, Y. &amp; Lin, G. Evolutionary programming made faster. <i>IEEE Trans. Evol. Comput.</i><b>3</b>(2), 82&#x2013;102 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/4235.771163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebeed, M. et al. Optimal energy planning of multi-microgrids at stochastic nature of load demand and renewable energy resources using a modified Capuchin Search Algorithm. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>35</b>(24), 17645&#x2013;17670 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-023-08623-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, B., Giraldo, J. S. &amp; Hoogsteen, G. Dynamic hunting leadership optimization: algorithm and applications. <i>Journal of Computational Science</i><b>69</b>, 102010 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocs.2023.102010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Brest, M. S. Mau&#x10d;ec, and B. Bo&#x161;kovi&#x107;, "The 100-digit challenge: Algorithm jde100," in <i>2019 IEEE congress on evolutionary computation (CEC)</i>, 2019, pp. 19&#x2013;26: IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirjalili, S. &amp; Lewis, A. The whale optimization algorithm. <i>Adv. Eng. Softw.</i><b>95</b>, 51&#x2013;67 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advengsoft.2016.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyyedabbasi, A. &amp; Kiani, F. Sand Cat swarm optimization: A nature-inspired algorithm to solve global optimization problems. <i>Engineering with Computers</i><b>39</b>(4), 2627&#x2013;2651 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-022-01604-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojovsk&#xe1;, E., Dehghani, M. &amp; Trojovsk&#xfd;, P. Zebra optimization algorithm: A new bio-inspired optimization algorithm for solving optimization algorithm. <i>Ieee Access</i><b>10</b>, 49445&#x2013;49473 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3172789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdollahzadeh, B., Gharehchopogh, F. S. &amp; Mirjalili, S. African vultures optimization algorithm: A new nature-inspired metaheuristic algorithm for global optimization problems. <i>Comput. Ind. Eng.</i><b>158</b>, 107408 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cie.2021.107408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirjalili, S., Mirjalili, S. M. &amp; Lewis, A. Grey wolf optimizer. <i>Adv. Eng. Softw.</i><b>69</b>, 46&#x2013;61 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advengsoft.2013.12.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidari, A. A. et al. Harris hawks optimization: Algorithm and applications. <i>Futur. Gener. Comput. Syst.</i><b>97</b>, 849&#x2013;872 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.future.2019.02.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houssein, E. H., Oliva, D., Samee, N. A., Mahmoud, N. F. &amp; Emam, M. M. Liver cancer algorithm: A novel bio-inspired optimizer. <i>Comput. Biol. Med.</i><b>165</b>, 107389 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2023.107389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37678138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ebeed<i> et al.</i>, "An enhanced weighted mean of vectors optimizer: addressing combined heat and power economic dispatch with system losses and valve point loading effect," <i>Neural Computing and Applications,</i> pp. 1&#x2013;33, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sudhakaran and S. M. R. Slochanal, "Integrating genetic algorithms and tabu search for combined heat and power economic dispatch," in <i>TENCON 2003. Conference on Convergent Technologies for Asia-Pacific Region</i>, 2003, vol. 1, pp. 67&#x2013;71: IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y. &amp; Xuan, Q. Combined heat and power economic dispatch using genetic algorithm based penalty function method. <i>Electric machines and power systems</i><b>26</b>(4), 363&#x2013;372 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07313569808955828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y., Chou, C. &amp; Stonham, T. Combined heat and power economic dispatch by improved ant colony search algorithm. <i>Electric Power Systems Research</i><b>52</b>(2), 115&#x2013;121 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-7796(99)00011-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, B., Yan, L.-X. &amp; Wu, W. Multi-objective optimization for combined heat and power economic dispatch with power transmission loss and emission reduction. <i>Energy</i><b>56</b>, 135&#x2013;143 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2013.04.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, A. M., Ginidi, A. R., El-Sehiemy, R. A. &amp; Ghoneim, S. S. Economic power and heat dispatch in cogeneration energy systems using manta ray foraging optimizer. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>8</b>, 208281&#x2013;208295 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3038740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman, S. et al. Improvement of the Fitness-Distance Balance-Based Supply-Demand Optimization Algorithm for Solving the Combined Heat and Power Economic Dispatch Problem. <i>Iranian Journal of Science and Technology, Transactions of Electrical Engineering</i><b>47</b>(2), 513&#x2013;548 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40998-022-00560-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, M. Bee colony optimization for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>38</b>(11), 13527&#x2013;13531 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, M. Artificial immune system for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>43</b>(1), 1&#x2013;5 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2012.05.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, M. Combined heat and power economic dispatch by using differential evolution. <i>Electric Power Components and Systems</i><b>38</b>(8), 996&#x2013;1004 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15325000903571574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi, M. et al. A novel and effective optimization algorithm for global optimization and its engineering applications: Turbulent Flow of Water-based Optimization (TFWO). <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>92</b>, 103666 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2020.103666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D., Hu, Z., Su, Q. &amp; Liu, M. A niching differential evolution algorithm for the large-scale combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>113</b>, 108017 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2021.108017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattanaik, J. K., Basu, M. &amp; Dash, D. P. Heat transfer search algorithm for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Iranian Journal of Science and Technology, Transactions of Electrical Engineering</i><b>44</b>, 963&#x2013;978 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40998-019-00280-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, M. Group search optimization for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>78</b>, 138&#x2013;147 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2015.11.069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellal, M. A. &amp; Williams, E. J. Cuckoo optimization algorithm with penalty function for combined heat and power economic dispatch problem. <i>Energy</i><b>93</b>, 1711&#x2013;1718 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2015.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbaraj, P., Rengaraj, R. &amp; Salivahanan, S. Enhancement of combined heat and power economic dispatch using self adaptive real-coded genetic algorithm. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>86</b>(6), 915&#x2013;921 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2008.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorram, E. &amp; Jaberipour, M. Harmony search algorithm for solving combined heat and power economic dispatch problems. <i>Energy Convers. Manage.</i><b>52</b>(2), 1550&#x2013;1554 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2010.10.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Zou, D. &amp; Kong, Z. A harmony search variant and a useful constraint handling method for the dynamic economic emission dispatch problems considering transmission loss. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>84</b>, 18&#x2013;40 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2019.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini-Hemati, S., Beigvand, S. D., Abdi, H. &amp; Rastgou, A. Society-based Grey Wolf Optimizer for large scale Combined Heat and Power Economic Dispatch problem considering power losses. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>117</b>, 108351 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2021.108351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Q., Liu, P., Zhang, J. &amp; Dong, N. Combined heat and power economic dispatch using an adaptive cuckoo search with differential evolution mutation. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>307</b>, 118057 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2021.118057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, A. M., Elsayed, A. M., Elattar, E. E., El-Sehiemy, R. A. &amp; Ginidi, A. R. An Intelligent Heap-Based Technique With Enhanced Discriminatory Attribute for Large-Scale Combined Heat and Power Economic Dispatch. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>10</b>, 64325&#x2013;64338 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3183562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spea, S. Social network search algorithm for combined heat and power economic dispatch. <i>Electric Power Systems Research</i><b>221</b>, 109400 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, M. Combined heat and power economic dispatch using opposition-based group search optimization. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>73</b>, 819&#x2013;829 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2015.06.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagh, M. T., Teimourzadeh, S., Alipour, M. &amp; Aliasghary, P. Improved group search optimization method for solving CHPED in large scale power systems. <i>Energy Convers. Manage.</i><b>80</b>, 446&#x2013;456 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2014.01.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>