<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41742352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-8137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The New phytologist</Title><ISOAbbreviation>New Phytol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Climate-driven epiphytic bacterial community along a latitudinal&#xa0;gradient and its implications for submerged macrophyte production.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nph.71011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Epiphytic bacterial communities play a regulatory role in biogeochemical carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) cycling and host plant growth. Although their biogeography has been well studied in terrestrial ecosystems, the latitudinal diversity patterns of epiphytic bacterial communities and their implications for cosmopolitan macrophyte production in freshwater ecosystems remain unclear. Here, we conducted a field survey to investigate the latitudinal patterns of bacterial communities colonising the leaf and root surfaces of Myriophyllum spicatum and a surface microbe sterilisation experiment using sediments from high and low latitude regions to verify their causal effects on plant biomass. Distinct diversity patterns were observed across plant compartments. Leaf bacterial community richness increased significantly and linearly with latitude, whereas root bacterial community richness exhibited no significant pattern. Leaf and root bacterial community &#x3b2; diversity significantly decreased with latitude. Mean annual precipitation and temperature emerged as the primary factors influencing the leaf and root community compositions, respectively. The total network edges, total network nodes, and node degree of the leaf bacterial community significantly increased with latitude. Moreover, the network stability peaked at mid-latitudes. The field survey revealed a significant unimodal pattern in host plant biomass along the latitudinal gradient. Significant pathways linking environmental nutrient and leaf bacterial N cycling to host biomass were observed. In the sterilisation experiment, epiphytic bacterial communities significantly increased host biomass in sediment from low latitudes, whereas an opposite pattern was observed in sediment from high latitudes. Sediment source and root bacterial N cycling were identified as significant direct drivers of host biomass. These findings demonstrate the biogeographic patterns of multifaceted epiphytic bacterial matrices (taxonomy, function, and network) of a cosmopolitan macrophyte and highlight the key roles of environmental nutrients and epiphytic bacterial communities in shaping primary production in freshwater ecosystems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). New Phytologist &#xa9; 2026 New Phytologist Foundation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5380-6425</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu Institute of Biology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chengdu, 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Field Station of Freshwater Ecosystem of Liangzi Lake, College of Life Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Siqi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-3848-439X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Field Station of Freshwater Ecosystem of Liangzi Lake, College of Life Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Hongwei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1802-1323</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Environmental Aquatic Chemistry, Research Center for Eco-Environmental Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100085, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Ningfei</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Ecological Environment, Chengdu University of Technology, Chengdu, Sichuan, 610059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Shichu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Guangxi Normal University, Guilin, 541006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yajun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing, 100012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Haiming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Qufu Normal University, Qufu, 273165, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Southern Safety &amp; Environment Technology Institute Co. Ltd, Wuhan, 430071, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoliang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Soil and Water Conservation, Jiangxi University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Nanchang, 330096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chao</LastName><ForeName>Chuanxin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-4910-3708</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Agro-Ecological Processes in Subtropical Region, Institute of Subtropical Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Changsha, 410125, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Huai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7650-289X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu Institute of Biology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chengdu, 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chunhua</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3932-477X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Field Station of Freshwater Ecosystem of Liangzi Lake, College of Life Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025ZNSFSC1032</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2042020kf1025</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024YFF0808703</GrantID><Agency>National Key R &amp; D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GJJ211933</GrantID><Agency>Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>New Phytol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9882884</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-646X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myriophyllum spicatum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N cycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diversity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sterilisation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41742352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.71011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Akbari E, Baldan D, Watzinger A, Weigelhofer G. 2024. Leaves stimulate aquatic phosphorus uptake by dark&#x2010;grown but not by light&#x2010;grown microbial communities in sediments: a laboratory study. Freshwater Biology 69: 321&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahram M, Hildebrand F, Forslund SK, Anderson JL, Soudzilovskaia NA, Bodegom PM, Bengtsson&#x2010;Palme J, Anslan S, Coelho LP, Harend H et&#xa0;al. 2018. Structure and function of the global topsoil microbiome. Nature 560: 233&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S. 2015. Fitting linear mixed&#x2010;effects models using {lme4}. Journal of Statistical Software 67: 1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bestion E, Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Carreras B, Schaum C&#x2010;E, Pawar S, Yvon&#x2010;Durocher G. 2018. Metabolic traits predict the effects of warming on phytoplankton competition. Ecology Letters 21: 655&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchfink B, Xie C, Huson DH. 2015. Fast and sensitive protein alignment using Diamond. Nature Methods 12: 59&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordovez V, Dini&#x2010;Andreote F, Carri&#xf3;n VJ, Raaijmakers JM. 2019. Ecology and evolution of plant microbiomes. Annual Review of Microbiology 73: 69&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyte KZ, Schluter J, Foster KR. 2015. The ecology of the microbiome: networks, competition, and stability. Science 350: 663&#x2013;666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crump BC, Koch EW. 2008. Attached bacterial populations shared by four species of aquatic angiosperms. Applied and Environmental Microbiology 74: 5948&#x2013;5957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csardi G, Nepusz T. 2006. The igraph software package for complex network research. InterJournal Complex Systems 1695: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daumal MM, Oosterhuis D, Verhofstad MJJM, Erkens RHJ, Peeters ETHM. 2024. The impact of drought duration on two Potamogeton species with different growth forms. Aquatic Sciences 86: 73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dray S, Legendre P, Peres&#x2010;Neto PR. 2006. Spatial modelling: a comprehensive framework for principal coordinate analysis of neighbour matrices (PCNM). Ecological Modelling 196: 483&#x2013;493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falasco E, Bona F, Monauni C, Zeni A, Piano E. 2019. Environmental and spatial factors drive diatom species distribution in Alpine streams: Implications for biomonitoring. Ecological Indicators 106: 105441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faust K, Raes J. 2012. Microbial interactions: from networks to models. Nature Reviews Microbiology 10: 538&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flemming HC, Wuertz S. 2019. Bacteria and archaea on Earth and their abundance in biofilms. Nature Reviews Microbiology 17: 247&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flessa H. 1994. Plant&#x2010;induced changes in the redox potential of the rhizospheres of the submerged vascular macrophytes Myriophyllum verticillatum L. and Ranunculus circinatus L. Aquatic Botany 47: 119&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu L, Niu B, Zhu Z, Wu S, Li W. 2012. CD&#x2010;HIT: accelerated for clustering the next&#x2010;generation sequencing data. Bioinformatics 28: 3150&#x2013;3152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Gir&#xf3;n J, Heino J, Baastrup&#x2010;Spohr L, Bove CP, Clayton J, de Winton M, Feldmann T, Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Al&#xe1;ez M, Ecke F, Grillas P et&#xa0;al. 2020. Global patterns and determinants of lake macrophyte taxonomic, functional and phylogenetic beta diversity. Science of the Total Environment 723: 138021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guseva K, Darcy S, Simon E, Alteio LV, Montesinos&#x2010;Navarro A, Kaiser C. 2022. From diversity to complexity: microbial networks in soils. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 169: 108604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair JF, Ringle CM, Sarstedt M. 2011. PLS&#x2010;SEM: indeed a silver bullet. Journal of Marketing Theory and Practice 19: 139&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;rer A, Rennison DJ. 2023. The biogeography of host&#x2010;associated bacterial microbiomes: revisiting classic biodiversity patterns. Global Ecology and Biogeography 32: 931&#x2013;944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He R, Zeng J, Zhao D, Wang S, Wu QL. 2022. Decreased spatial variation and deterministic processes of bacterial community assembly in the rhizosphere of Phragmites australis across the Middle&#x2013;Lower Yangtze plain. Molecular Ecology 31: 1180&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Han B, Geng Y, Shi L, Peng C, Duan L, Shao X. 2025. Unveiling the role of foliar fungi in mediating leaf photosynthesis under global change. Journal of Ecology 113: 3735&#x2013;3747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez DJ, David AS, Menges ES, Searcy CA, Afkhami ME. 2021. Environmental stress destabilizes microbial networks. ISME Journal 15: 1722&#x2013;1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibarbalz FM, Henry N, Brand&#xe3;o MC, Martini S, Busseni G, Byrne H, Coelho LP, Endo H, Gasol JM, Gregory AC et&#xa0;al. 2019. Global trends in marine plankton diversity across Kingdoms of Life. Cell 179: 1084&#x2013;1097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson RB, Mooney HA, Schulze E&#x2010;D. 1997. A global budget for fine root biomass, surface area, and nutrient contents. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA 94: 7362&#x2013;7366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DL, Nguyen C, Finlay RD. 2009. Carbon flow in the rhizosphere: carbon trading at the soil&#x2013;root interface. Plant and Soil 321: 5&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kembel SW, Cowan PD, Helmus MR, Cornwell WK, Morlon H, Ackerly DD, Blomberg SP, Webb CO. 2010. Picante: R tools for integrating phylogenies and ecology. Bioinformatics 26: 1463&#x2013;1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft NJB, Comita LS, Chase JM, Sanders NJ, Swenson NG, Crist TO, Stegen JC, Vellend M, Boyle B, Anderson MJ et&#xa0;al. 2011. Disentangling the drivers of &#x3b2; diversity along latitudinal and elevational gradients. Science 333: 1755&#x2013;1758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuypers MMM, Marchant HK, Kartal B. 2018. The microbial nitrogen&#x2010;cycling network. Nature Reviews Microbiology 16: 263&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J, Zou Y, Zhang J, Peres&#x2010;Neto PR. 2022. Generalizing hierarchical and&#xa0;variation partitioning in multiple regression and canonical analyses using the rdacca.hp R package. Methods in Ecology and Evolution 13: 782&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei C, Zhou SYD, Tissue DT, Neilson R, Lie Z, Wu T, Liu X, Meng C, Li X, Zhu D et&#xa0;al. 2025. Seasonal variation of phyllosphere microbial communities under warming. Global Change Biology 31: e70270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Liu C&#x2010;M, Luo R, Sadakane K, Lam T&#x2010;W. 2015. Megahit: an ultra&#x2010;fast single&#x2010;node solution for large and complex metagenomics assembly via succinct de Bruijn graph. Bioinformatics 31: 1674&#x2013;1676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Petticord DF, Jin M, Huang L, Hui D, Sardans J, Pe&#xf1;uelas J, Yang X, Zhu YG. 2024. From nature to urbanity: exploring phyllosphere microbiome and functional gene responses to the Anthropocene. New Phytologist 245: 591&#x2013;606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Li Y, Kristiansen K, Wang J. 2008. SOAP: short oligonucleotide alignment program. Bioinformatics 24: 713&#x2013;714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chao C, Zuo Z, Hu J, Yu H, Liu C, Yu D. 2023. Effects of dissolved inorganic level and sediment types on the plant traits of Myriophyllum spicatum L. and its exudates input to sediment. Aquatic Sciences 85: 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Chu H, Godoy O, Fan K, Gao GF, Yang T, Ma Y, Delgado&#x2010;Baquerizod M. 2024. Positive associations fuel soil biodiversity and ecological networks worldwide. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA 121: e2308769121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long X, Li J, Liao X, Wang J, Zhang W, Wang K, Zhao J. 2025. Stable soil biota network enhances soil multifunctionality in agroecosystems. Global Change Biology 31: e70041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzinelli EM, Campbell AH, Zozaya Valdes E, Verg&#xe9;s A, Nielsen S, Wernberg T, de Bettignies T, Bennett S, Caporaso JG, Thomas T et&#xa0;al. 2015. Continental&#x2010;scale variation in seaweed host&#x2010;associated bacterial communities is a function of host condition, not geography. Environmental Microbiology 17: 4078&#x2013;4088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei Y, Zhang M, Cao G, Zhu J, Zhang A, Bai H, Dai C, Jia Y. 2024. Endofungal bacteria and ectomycorrhizal fungi synergistically promote the absorption of organic phosphorus in Pinus massoniana. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 47: 600&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikryukov V, Dulya O, Zizka A, Bahram M, Hagh&#x2010;Doust N, Anslan S, Prylutskyi O, Delgado&#x2010;Baquerizo M, Maestre FT, Nilsson H et&#xa0;al. 2023. Connecting the multiple dimensions of global soil fungal diversity. Science Advances 9: 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori H, Maruyama F, Kato H, Toyoda A, Dozono A, Ohtsubo Y, Nagata Y, Fujiyama A, Tsuda M, Kurokawa K. 2014. Design and experimental application of a novel non&#x2010;degenerate universal primer set that amplifies prokaryotic 16S rRNA genes with a low possibility to amplify eukaryotic rRNA genes. DNA Research 21: 217&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K, Efremov A, Davidson TA, Molina&#x2010;Navarro E, Fidanza K, Crivelari Betiol TC, Chambers P, Tapia Grimaldo J, Varandas Martins S, Springuel I et&#xa0;al. 2019. World distribution, diversity and endemism of aquatic macrophytes. Aquatic Botany 158: 103127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolausz M, Kappelmeyer U, Sz&#xe9;kely A, Ruszny&#xe1;k A, M&#xe1;rialigeti K, K&#xe4;stner M. 2008. Diurnal redox fluctuation and microbial activity in the rhizosphere of wetland plants. European Journal of Soil Biology 44: 324&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oksanen J, Simpson GL, Blanchet FG, Kindt R, Legendre P, Minchin PR, O'Hara RB, Solymos P, Stevens MHH, Szoecs E et&#xa0;al. 2022. vegan: community ecology package. [WWW document] URL https://cran.r&#x2010;project.org/package=vegan [accessed 11 October 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontarp M, Bunnefeld L, Cabral JS, Etienne RS, Fritz SA, Gillespie R, Graham CH, Hagen O, Hartig F, Huang S et&#xa0;al. 2019. The latitudinal diversity gradient: novel understanding through mechanistic eco&#x2010;evolutionary models. Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution 34: 211&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y, Wang T, Huang Q, Guo H, Zhang H, Xu Q, Shen Q, Ling N. 2024. Core species impact plant health by enhancing soil microbial cooperation and network complexity during community coalescence. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 188: 109231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raes EJ, Bodrossy L, van de Kamp J, Bissett A, Waite AM. 2018. Marine bacterial richness increases towards higher latitudes in the eastern Indian Ocean. Limnology and Oceanography Letters 3: 10&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva F, Graco&#x2010;Roza C, Daskalova GN, Hudgins EJ, Lewthwaite JMM, Newman EA, Ryo M, Mammola S. 2023. Toward a cohesive understanding of ecological complexity. Science Advances 9: 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez del R&#xed;o &#xc1;, Scheu S, Rillig MC. 2025. Soil microbial responses to multiple global change factors as assessed by metagenomics. Nature Communications 16: 1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh BK, Hu HW, Macdonald CA, Xiong C. 2025. Microbiome&#x2010;facilitated plant nutrient acquisition. Cell Host &amp; Microbe 33: 869&#x2013;881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunagawa S, Coelho LP, Chaffron S, Kultima JR, Labadie K, Salazar G, Djahanschiri B, Zeller G, Mende DR, Alberti A et&#xa0;al. 2015. Structure and function of the global ocean microbiome. Science 348: 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titus J, Goldstein RA, Adams MS, Mankin JB, O'Neill RV, Weiler PR Jr, Shugart HH, Booth RS. 1975. A production model for Myriophyllum spicatum L. Ecology 56: 1129&#x2013;1138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titus JE, Pagano AM. 2017. Carbon dioxide and submersed macrophytes in lakes: linking functional ecology to community composition. Ecology 98: 3096&#x2013;3105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#x11b;trovsk&#xfd; T, Kohout P, Kopeck&#xfd; M, Machac A, Man M, Bahnmann BD, Brabcov&#xe1; V, Choi J, Mesz&#xe1;ro&#x161;ov&#xe1; L, Human ZR et&#xa0;al. 2019. A meta&#x2010;analysis of global fungal distribution reveals climate&#x2010;driven patterns. Nature Communications 10: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vorholt JA. 2012. Microbial life in the phyllosphere. Nature Reviews Microbiology 10: 828&#x2013;840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Wang X, Han X, Deng Y. 2018. Higher precipitation strengthens the microbial interactions in semi&#x2010;arid grassland soils. Global Ecology and Biogeography 27: 570&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Jiang Y, Zhang M, Chu C, Chen Y, Fang S, Jin G, Jiang M, Lian JY, Li Y et&#xa0;al. 2023. Diversity and biogeography of plant phyllosphere bacteria are governed by latitude&#x2010;dependent mechanisms. New Phytologist 240: 1534&#x2013;1547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts SC, Ritchie SC, Inouye M, Holt KE. 2019. FastSpar: rapid and scalable correlation estimation for compositional data. Bioinformatics 35: 1064&#x2013;1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker RH. 1960. Vegetation of the Siskiyou Mountains, Oregon and California. Ecological Monographs 30: 407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright RJ, Langille MGI. 2025. PICRUSt2&#x2010;SC: an update to the reference database used for functional prediction within PICRUSt2. Bioinformatics 41: 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu N, Zhou S, Zhang M, Peng W, Guo K, Qu X, He F. 2021. Spatial and local environmental factors outweigh geo&#x2010;climatic gradients in structuring taxonomically and trait&#x2010;based &#x3b2;&#x2010;diversity of benthic algae. Journal of Biogeography 48: 1842&#x2013;1857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan MM, Guo X, Wu L, Zhang Y, Xiao N, Ning D, Shi Z, Zhou X, Wu L, Yang Y et&#xa0;al. 2021. Climate warming enhances microbial network complexity and stability. Nature Climate Change 11: 343&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Zhang J, Liu Y, Shi P, Wei G. 2018. Co&#x2010;occurrence patterns of soybean rhizosphere microbiome at a continental scale. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 118: 178&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liu S, Wang J, Huang Y, Freedman Z, Fu S, Liu K, Wang H, Li X, Yao M et&#xa0;al. 2020. Local community assembly mechanisms shape soil bacterial &#x3b2; diversity patterns along a latitudinal gradient. Nature Communications 11: 5428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Deng Y, Shen L, Wen C, Yan Q, Ning D, Qin Y, Xue K, Wu L, He Z et&#xa0;al. 2016. Temperature mediates continental&#x2010;scale diversity of microbes in forest soils. Nature Communications 7: 12083.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>