<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41504900</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1615-7605</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioprocess and biosystems engineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioprocess Biosyst Eng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of a psychrotolerant composite microbial agent for nitrogen removal and its nitrogen metabolism pathways.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>603</StartPage><EndPage>620</EndPage><MedlinePgn>603-620</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00449-025-03276-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Low temperature can suppress biological nitrogen removal (BNR) efficiency. Although nitrogen removal (NR) characteristics of single psychrotolerant bacteria have been extensively studied, synergistic interactions between functionally distinct psychrotolerant nitrogen-removing consortia remain unexplored. In this study, a composite microbial agent, designated NDC-6, was generated by coculturing a psychrotolerant nitrifying consortium NC1 (Pseudomonas veronii HN1, P. poae HN2, and P. peli HN3) and an aerobic denitrifying consortium DC1 (Aeromonas sp. AD1, P. extremaustralis AD2, and Serratia liquefaciens AD3) at a 1:1 inoculation ratio, and its NR performance was systematically evaluated. After 3 days of incubation at 10&#xa0;&#xb0;C, NDC-6 achieved removal efficiencies of 89.3%, 88.1%, 85.5%, and 95.3% for NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-N, NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>-N, total nitrogen (TN), and chemical oxygen demand (COD), which were significantly higher than those of individual strains or single-function consortia. Sodium succinate was identified as the optimal carbon source, which simultaneously improved biomass growth and NR efficacy of NDC-6. Optimal culture conditions determined using response surface methodology were as follows: C/N ratio, 6; temperature, 10.2&#xa0;&#xb0;C; pH, 7.2; and shaking speed, 156&#xa0;rpm. Under these conditions, the verification experiment achieved a TN removal efficiency of 89.8%, closely approaching the theoretically predicted maximum of 90.2%. Nitrogen balance and functional gene (hao, napA, nirS, nirK, cnorB, and nosZ) expression analyses revealed that under low-temperature and aerobic conditions, NDC-6 achieved NR primarily through dual pathways of bacterial assimilation and dissimilation, converting NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-N and NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>-N into intracellular nitrogen and N<sub>2</sub>. The dissimilatory mechanism relied on synergistic metabolism and functional complementation between NC1 and DC1, mediated by their respective functional genes. This study provides mechanistic insights into the biological treatment of nitrogen-containing wastewater, particularly under low-temperature conditions, and offers a novel strategy for such treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Yihua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1305-5604</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Restoration of Regional Contaminated Environment, Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Shenyang University, Shenyang, 110044, China. harvesttime@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Restoration of Regional Contaminated Environment, Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Shenyang University, Shenyang, 110044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Huadian Tieling Power Generation Co., Ltd., Tieling, 112008, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Engineering, School of Resources &amp; Civil Engineering, Northeastern University, Shenyang, 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Guangsheng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Restoration of Regional Contaminated Environment, Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Shenyang University, Shenyang, 110044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Datang Environmental Protection Technology Research Institute, Datang Environment Industry Group Co., Ltd., Beijing, 100097, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Huikang Testing and Evaluation Technology Co., Ltd, Shenyang, 110017, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>LJ212411035027</GrantID><Agency>Basic Research Project of Educational Department of Liaoning Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52300023</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Bioprocess Biosyst Eng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088505</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1615-7591</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>N762921K75</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009584">Nitrogen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009584" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nitrogen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001419" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bacteria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological nitrogen removal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Composite microbial agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Denitrification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychrotolerant bacteria</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: All the authors consent to publish this research paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41504900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00449-025-03276-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00449-025-03276-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chamoli A, Karn SK, Kumari M, Sivaramasamy E (2025) Biochar mediated fixation of nitrogen compounds (ammonia and nitrite) in soil: a review. Biodegradation 36:22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10532-025-10116-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10532-025-10116-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40044937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger M, Canty SWJ, Tuholske C, Halpern BS (2022) Sources and discharge of nitrogen pollution from agriculture and wastewater in the Mesoamerican reef region. Ocean Coast Manage 227:106269. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ocecoaman.2022.106269</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ocecoaman.2022.106269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins M, B&#xfc;ngener L, Ronkanen AK, Pirttil&#xe4; AM, Ruotsalainen AL, Lehosmaa K, Ahonen SHK, W&#xe4;li PR, Heiderscheidt E, Postila H (2025) The effectiveness of nature-based hybrid solutions for the removal of nitrogen and emergent pollutants from municipal wastewater in cold climate conditions. Ecol Eng 219:107711. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. ecoleng. 2025. 107711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang TT, Zhao ZY (2025) Deciphering the internal mechanism of nitrogen removal from sludge and biofilm under low temperature from the perspective of microbial function metabolism. Environ Res 267:120688. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. envres. 2024. 120688</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang FR, Feng SY, Liang S, Du WY, Wang LQ, Zhang YW, Ren JY, Gao S, Zhu YJ, Cong YT, Wang L, Gu J, Wang Y, Wang H, Lu YN, Wang LS, Yang GJ (2025) Rapid and efficient nitrogen removal by a novel heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification bacteria Marinobacterium maritimum 5-JS in aquaculture wastewater: Performance and potential applications. Environ Res 276:121500. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. envres. 2025. 121500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu QF, He TX, Chen MP, Zhang MM (2022) Nitrogen removal characterization and functional enzymes identification of a hypothermia bacterium Pseudomonas Fragi EH-H1. Bioresource Technol 365:128156. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2022.128156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2022.128156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma SK, Dogra S, Kumar P, Maurya N, Pandey KK, Bardewa P, Kumar R (2025) Sustainable approaches of microbial-assisted organic waste valorization in colder regions for greener future. Biomass Bioenerg 202:108168. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biombioe. 2025. 108168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Yang T, Shi Y, Xin Y, Zhang L, Gu ZH, Li YR, Ding ZY, Shi GY (2021) The nitrogen removal characterization of a cold-adapted bacterium: Bacillus simplex H-b. Bioresource Technol 323:124554. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2020.124554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2020.124554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu QF, He TX, Chen MP, Zhang MM (2025) Elucidating the mechanisms underlying heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification and cold tolerance in Pseudomonas Fragi EH-H1 under weakly acidic conditions. Int Biodeter Biodegr 200:106046. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ibiod.2025.106046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ibiod.2025.106046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Wang QY, Xu WS, Liu XH, Gao XT, Zhang YX (2017) Stationary phase-dependent accumulation of ectoine is an efficient adaptation strategy in Vibrio anguillarum against cold stress. Microbiol Res 205:8&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. micres. 2017. 08. 005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MP, Tian S, He TX, Qin LK, Liu H, Qifeng W, Zhang MM (2025) Microbial consortium composed of efficient denitrifying strains and bacterial groups from toilet water for enhancing blackwater treatment. J Environ Chem Eng 13:117676. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jece. 2025. 117676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu YL, Ontita NC, Zeng WM, Huang J, Jiang LH, Huang XX, Li Q, Hu P (2025) High-efficiency nitrogen removal by cold-tolerant bacteria consortium at low temperatures. Bioresource Technol 434:132816. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2025. 132816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZY, Zhang TN, Meng JJ, Zhou SL, Zhang ZW, Chen Z, Liu YL, Zhang JF, Cui JS (2022) Efficient nitrate removal of immobilized mixed aerobic denitrifying bacteria and community dynamics response to temperature and low carbon/nitrogen polluted water. Bioresource Technol 362:127873. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2022.127873</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2022.127873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Shi SX, Xie SX, Wang XY, Qu J, Liu F, Liu CS, Zhao CC (2024) Biodegradation kinetics of petroleum hydrocarbons by composite microbial agents combined with slow release agents in groundwater. J Water Process Eng 68:106327. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.106327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.106327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Wang YR, Xu CF, Qiao CL, Chen SQ, Zhao CC, Liu QY, Zhang XX (2023) Reconstruction of Microbiome and functionality accelerated crude oil biodegradation of 2,4-DCP-oil-contaminated soil systems using composite microbial agent B-Cl. J Hazard Mater 447:130808. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.130808</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.130808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36669400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhambri A, Karn SK, Kumar A (2025) Ammonia transformation by potential consortium in the aquatic system. Sci Rep 15:6066. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-90206-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-90206-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39971967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11839903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi F, Liu ZL, Li JL, Gao HW, Qin S, Guo JJ (2022) Alterations in microbial community during the remediation of a black-odorous stream by acclimated composite microorganisms. J Environ Sci 118:181&#x2013;193. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jes. 2021. 12. 034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhambri A, Karn SK, Singh RK (2021) In-situ remediation of nitrogen and phosphorus of beverage industry by potential strains Bacillus sp. (BK1) and Aspergillus sp. (BK2). Sci Rep 11:12243. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-91539-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-91539-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8192750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Zhu DY, Chen YX, Luo J, Zhou YX, Chen F, Zhang YM, Rittmann BE (2025) Differentiating biosynthesis from heterotrophic nitrification/aerobic denitrification for total-nitrogen removal. Environ Res 285:122498. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.122498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.122498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40754282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi HT, Tang J, Feng XC, Xiao ZJ, Jiang CY, Wang WQ, Si QS, Kuang JY, Ren NQ (2025) Aerobic denitrification in different dissolved oxygen conditions: nitrogen metabolism and electron distribution. Environ Int 205:109879. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. envint. 2025. 109879</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Wang HB, Zhang L, Zeng W, Peng YZ (2025) Multi-omics reveals mechanism of hydroxylamine-enhanced ultimate nitrogen removal in pilot-scale anaerobic/aerobic/anoxic system. Water Res 274:123101. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. watres. 2025. 123101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Liu FJ, Yang J, Fan YY, Yu LJ, Li ZH, Jiang N, An J, Jiao ZW, Wang C (2023) Isolation and identification of Bacillus mojavensis YL-RY0310 and its biocontrol potential against penicillium expansum and patulin in apples. Biol Control 182:105239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocontrol.2023.105239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2023.105239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao TT, Chen PP, Zhang LJ, Zhang L, Gao YH, Ai S, Liu H, Liu XY (2021) Heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification by a novel Acinetobacter sp. TAC-1 at low temperature and high ammonia nitrogen. Bioresource Technol 339:125620. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2021. 125620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEPA (2002) Analytical methods for water and wastewater monitoring (4th Edition), Editorial Board of Water and Wastewater Monitoring and Analysis Methods of the State Environmental Protection Administration</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Li XM, Fan WH, Wang JL (2020) Heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification by a novel Acinetobacter sp. ND7 isolated from municipal activated sludge. Bioresource Technol 301:122749. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2020. 122749</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YR, Gui XW, Chen LY, Li HM, Li ZL, Liu TH (2024) Acid-tolerant Pseudomonas citronellolis YN-21 exhibits a high heterotrophic nitrification capacity independent of the Amo and Hao genes. Ecotox Environ Safe 279:116385. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei XY, Li SS, Li C, Liao J, Yang YC, He ZM, Dong K, Lee SS (2025) Characterization and genomic insights into the nitrogen metabolism of heterotrophic nitrifying and aerobic denitrifying bacterium Pseudomonas aeruginosa WS-03. J Environ Manage 376:124405. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39955900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang MQ, Cui YW (2024) Simultaneous aerobic nitrogen and phosphate removal by Pseudomonas aeruginosa SNDPR-01: comprehensive insights on metabolic potential and mechanisms. Chem Eng J 481:148459. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2023.148459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.148459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang L, Wang KJ, Liu XY, Wong MH, Hu ZL, Chen HR, Yang XW, Li SF (2020) A study on the nitrogen removal efficacy of bacterium acinetobacter Tandoii MZ-5 from a contaminated river of Shenzhen, Guangdong Province, China. Bioresource Technol 315:123888. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2020.123888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2020.123888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He TX, Xie DT, Li ZL, Ni JP, Sun Q (2017) Ammonium stimulates nitrate reduction during simultaneous nitrification and denitrification process by Arthrobacter arilaitensis Y-10. Bioresource Technol 239:66&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2017. 04. 125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MX, Wang WC, Feng Y, Zhu XH, Zhou HZ, Tan ZL, Li XD (2014) Impact resistance of different factors on ammonia removal by heterotrophic nitrification&#x2013;aerobic denitrification bacterium Aeromonas sp. HN-02. Bioresource Technol 167:456&#x2013;461. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2014. 06. 001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira ML, Lazzarini Behrmann IC, Daniel MA, Sosa GL, Owusu E, Parkin IP, Candal R, Allan E, Vullo DL (2024) Green synthesis and antibacterial-antibiofilm properties of biogenic silver nanoparticles. Environ Nanotechnol Monit Manag 22:100991. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. enmm. 2024. 100991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara-Moreno A, Vargas-Ord&#xf3;&#xf1;ez A, Villaverde J, Madrid F, Carlier JD, Santos JL, Alonso E, Morillo E (2024) Bacterial bioaugmentation for paracetamol removal from water and sewage sludge. Genomic approaches to elucidate biodegradation pathway. J Hazard Mater 480:136128. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jhazmat. 2024. 136128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B, Jia JL, Gao XL, Zeng MY, Zhang B, Wang WR, Ma YC, Han YX, Zhang S (2025) Optimized solid composite bacterial agents for biodegradation of benzo[a]pyrene contaminated soils: Effects, microbial dynamic changes and mechanisms. Biochem Eng J 223:109875. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. bej. 2025. 109875</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing JW, Wang TT, Guo XY, Huang PF, Li C, Qu YY (2024) Construction and application of petroleum-degrading bacterial agents: community composition, lyophilization technology, and degradation mechanism. J Environ Chem Eng 12:114904. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jece. 2024. 114904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YY, Wang SJ, Geng NF, Wu ZQ, Xiong W, Su HJ (2022) Artificially constructing mixed bacteria system for bioaugmentation of nitrogen removal from saline wastewater at low temperature. J Environ Manage 324:116351. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jenvman. 2022. 116351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Yang RL, Zhang ZJ, Wang XJ, Ye X, Chen SH (2018) Synergy of carbon and nitrogen removal of a co-culture of two aerobic denitrifying bacterial strains, Acinetobacter sp. GA and Pseudomonas sp. GP. RSC Adv 8:21558&#x2013;21565. https://doi.org/10.1039/C8RA02721H</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8RA02721H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35539912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9080916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebadi A, Ghavidel A, Khoshkholgh Sima NA, Heydari G, Ghaffari MR (2021) New strategy to increase oil biodegradation efficiency by selecting isolates with diverse functionality and no antagonistic interactions for bacterial consortia. J Environ Chem Eng 9:106315. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jece. 2021. 106315</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He QL, Song JY, Zhang W, Gao SX, Wang HY, Yu J (2020) Enhanced simultaneous nitrification, denitrification and phosphorus removal through mixed carbon source by aerobic granular sludge. J Hazard Mater 382:121043. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jhazmat. 2019. 121043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Zhang JS, Luo FZ, Shi DH, Liu YC, Liu S, Zhang Q, Sun WZ, Yuan JL, Fan HT, Wang HC, Qi L, Liu GH (2022) Molecular mechanisms through which different carbon sources affect denitrification by Thauera linaloolentis: Electron generation, transfer, and competition. Environ Int 170:107598. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. envint. 2022. 107598</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PP, Zhai TR, Zhang LJ, Zhao TT, Xing ZL, Liu H (2023) Domestication and pilot-scale culture of mixed bacteria HY-1 capable of heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification. Bioresource Technol 384:129285. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2023. 129285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu LH, Ding XY, Lin Y, Lu XS, Lv H, Zhao MP, Yu RH (2022) Nitrogen removal by a novel heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification bacterium Acinetobacter calcoaceticus TY1 under low temperatures. Bioresource Technol 353:127148. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j. biortech. 2022. 127148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HY, Sun Y, Zhou XK, Zhu CY, Wang XJ, Abbasi HN, Geng HY, Zhu GC, Wang XG, Dai HL (2025) Simultaneous removal of nitrogen and phosphorus by aerobic denitrifying Paracoccus versutus JUST-3. Bioresource Technol 428:132457. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j. biortech. 2025. 132457</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei BH, Luo X, Ma WK, Lv PY (2022) Biological nitrogen removal and metabolic characteristics of a novel cold-resistant heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification Rhizobium sp. WS7. Bioresource Technol 362:127756. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2022. 127756</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lungelo Dlamini M, Lesaoana M, Kotz&#xe9; IA, Richards HL (2023) Response surface methodology mediated optimization of diclofenac and norfloxacin biodegradation using laccase immobilized on metal&#x2013;organic frameworks. Sep Purif Technol 326:124709. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. seppur. 2023. 124709</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong YH, Wang ZY, Li L, Zhang XY, Chen F, He JH (2023) Heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification characteristics of the psychrotolerant Pseudomonas Peli NR-5 at low temperatures. Bioproc Biosyst Eng 46:693&#x2013;706. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00449-023-02854-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00449-023-02854-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng XY, Jia TJ, Bai QX, Lang DY, Zhang XH (2024) Development of a composite microbial agent beneficial to improve drought and salt tolerance of Glycyrrhiza uralensis Fisch. Ind Crop Prod 211:118280. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. indcrop. 2024. 118280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan X, Yang YL, Li X, Zhou ZW, Liu CJ, Liu YW, Yin WC, Fan XY (2020) Intensified nitrogen removal by heterotrophic nitrification aerobic denitrification bacteria in two pilot-scale tidal flow constructed wetlands: Influence of influent C/N ratios and tidal strategies. Bioresource Technol 302:122803. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2020. 122803</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu A, Gao DW, Wu WM, Gong XF, Liang H (2025) Enhanced denitrification using iron modified biochar under low carbon source condition: modulating community assembly, allocating carbon metabolism and facilitating electron transfer. J Environ Manage 381:125354. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jenvman. 2025. 125354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai XY, McKnight MM, Neufeld JD, Parker WJ (2022) Nitrogen removal pathways during simultaneous nitrification, denitrification, and phosphorus removal under low temperature and dissolved oxygen conditions. Bioresource Technol 354:127177. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2022. 127177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin ZY, Zhou J, He L, He XJ, Pan ZL, Wang YM, He Q (2022) High-temperature biofilm system based on heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification treating high-strength ammonia wastewater: nitrogen removal performances and temperature-regulated metabolic pathways. Bioresource Technol 344:126184. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2021. 126184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu PY, Li XM, Luo X, Cui JS (2025) Integrated insights into a novel dual-functioning heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification strain Glutamicibacter halophytocola MD1: performance and metabolic mechanisms of synchronous nitrogen and phosphorus removal. Bioresource Technol 433:132714. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2025. 132714</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng XY, Huang JJ, Hua BB, Champagne P (2020) Nitrogen removal bacterial strains, MSNA-1 and MSD4, with wide ranges of salinity and pH resistances. Bioresource Technol 310:123309. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2020. 123309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin RF, Liu TQ, Liu GF, Zhou JT, Huang JY, Wang AJ (2015) Simultaneous heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification by the marine origin bacterium Pseudomonas sp. ADN-42. Appl Biochem Biotechnol 175:2000&#x2013;2011. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12010-014-1406-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12010-014-1406-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25432342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ST, Li L, Tian XL, Gao QF, Dong SL (2025) Spatiotemporal dynamics of ammonium monooxygenase (amoA) genes in sediments of the aquaculture area in the Yellow Sea Cold Water Mass. Reg Stud Mar Sci 89:104298. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. rsma. 2025. 104298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao ZL, Ali A, Ren Y, Su JF, Wang Z (2022) A mechanistic review on aerobic denitrification for nitrogen removal in water treatment. Sci Total Environ 847:157452. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. scitotenv. 2022. 157452</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li WY, Jiang X, Li JY, Li JF (2025) Simultaneous aerobic nitrogen and phosphorous removal characteristics and mechanism by heterotrophic nitrification aerobic denitrification microorganisms: a review. J Water Process Eng 76:108235. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jwpe. 2025. 108235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan XQ, Guo HJ, Ma F, Shan ZL (2023) Enhanced treatment of synthetic wastewater by bioaugmentation with a constructed consortium. Chemosphere 338:139520. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. chemosphere. 2023. 139520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang JK, Lu WH, Lu XH, Yu MR, Chen YH, Liao SA, Ye JM (2025) Nitrogen removal of a coculture of the heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification yeast Kazachstania exigua T14-1 and bacterium Methylobacterium sp. T5-6: Interactions, electron transport, and wastewater treatment. J Water Process Eng 71:107331. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jwpe. 2025. 107331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu JY, Tan Y, Tian SH, Qin YX, Zhou M, Hu H, Zhao XH, Wang ZF, Hu B (2024) Effect of carbon source on carbon and nitrogen metabolism of common heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification pathway. Chemosphere 361:142525. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. chemosphere. 2024. 142525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng JT, Lu JY, Hai C, Liu XY, Wu P, Sun Y, Yuan CB, Zhao JQ, Hu B (2023) Exploring influence mechanism of small-molecule carbon source on heterotrophic nitrification-aerobic denitrification process from carbon metabolism, nitrogen metabolism and electron transport process. Bioresource Technol 387:129681. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. biortech. 2023. 129681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HF, Cheng L, Xia LS, Deng GZ, Zhang YD, Shi XY (2023) Rapid simultaneous removal of nitrogen and phosphorous by a novel isolated Pseudomonas mendocina SCZ-2. Environ Res 231:116062. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. envres. 2023. 116062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu J, Zhao RJ, Chen YY, Li YY, Jin P, Zheng ZW (2022) Enhanced nitrogen removal from low-temperature wastewater by an iterative screening of cold-tolerant denitrifying bacteria. Bioproc Biosyst Eng 45:381&#x2013;390. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00449-021-02668-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00449-021-02668-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Wang YY, Zhang ZJ, Huang FY, Chen SH (2018) Physiological and transcriptomic insights into the cold adaptation mechanism of a novel heterotrophic nitrifying and aerobic denitrifying-like bacterium Pseudomonas indoloxydans YY-1. Int Biodeter Biodegr 134:16&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. ibiod. 2018. 08. 001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng ZJ, Gustavsson DJI, Zheng D, Holmin F, Fal&#xe5;s P, Wil&#xe9;n BM, Modin O, Persson F (2025) Genome-centric metagenomics reveals the effect of organic carbon source on one-stage partial denitrification-anammox in biofilm reactors. J Environ Manage 388:125972. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. jenvman. 2025. 125972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang X, Zhao XX, Song XS, Wang DH, Shi GT, Duan XF, Chen XH, Shen GX (2023) Nitrogen removal by a novel strain Priestia aryabhattai KX-3 from East Antarctica under alkaline pH and low-temperature conditions. Process Biochem 130:674&#x2013;684. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. procbio. 2023. 05. 030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y, Zhang DY, Cao HR, Zhang YL, Zhao DD, Zeng WM, Lei H, Bai Y (2022) Identification of aerobic-denitrifying Psychrobacter cryohalolentis strain F5-6 and its nitrate removal at low temperature. Int Biodeter Biodegr 172:105426. https://doi.org/10. 1016/ j. ibiod. 2022. 105426</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>