<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600485</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>YOLO-UMS: Multi-Scale Feature Fusion Based on YOLO Detector for PCB Surface Defect Detection.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">689</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020689</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Printed circuit boards (PCBs) are critical in the electronics industry. As PCB layouts grow increasingly complex, defect detection processes often encounter challenges such as low image contrast, uneven brightness, minute defect sizes, and irregular shapes, making it difficult to achieve rapid and accurate automated inspection. To address these challenges, this paper proposes a novel object detector, YOLO-UMS, designed to enhance the accuracy and speed of PCB surface defect detection. First, a lightweight plug-and-play Unified Multi-Scale Feature Fusion Pyramid Network (UMSFPN) is proposed to process and fuse multi-scale information across different resolution layers. The UMSFPN uses a Cross-Stage Partial Multi-Scale Module (CSPMS) and an optimized fusion strategy. This approach balances the integration of fine-grained edge information from shallow layers and coarse-grained semantic details from deep layers. Second, the paper introduces a lightweight RG-ELAN module, based on the ELAN network, to enhance feature extraction for small targets in complex scenes. The RG-ELAN module uses low-cost operations to generate redundant feature maps and reduce computational complexity. Finally, the Adaptive Interaction Feature Integration (AIFI) module enriches high-level features by eliminating redundant interactions among shallow-layer features. The channel-priority convolutional attention module (CPCA), deployed in the detection head, strengthens the expressive power of small target features. The experimental results show that the new UMSFPN neck can help improve the AP50 by 3.1% and AP by 2% on the self-collected dataset PCB-M, which is better than the original PAFPN neck. Meanwhile, UMSFPN achieves excellent results across different detectors and datasets, verifying its broad applicability. Without pre-training weights, YOLO-UMS achieves an 84% AP50 on the PCB-M dataset, which is a 6.4% improvement over the baseline YOLO11. Comparing results with existing target detection algorithms shows that the algorithm exhibits good performance in terms of detection accuracy. It provides a feasible solution for efficient and accurate detection of PCB surface defects in the industry.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Huludao 125105, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Wenjie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Huludao 125105, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Baocai</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic and Information Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Huludao 125105, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>24-1097</GrantID><Agency>Education Department of Liaoning Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCB detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">YOLO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-scale features fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network design</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Yang Q. System Design for PCB Defects Detection Based on AOI Technology; Proceedings of the 2011 4th International Congress on Image and Signal Processing; Shanghai, China. 15&#x2013;17 October 2011; pp. 1988&#x2013;1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Chen L., Wu Z., Guo H., Yu W., Du Z., Wang Z.L. 3D Double-Faced Interlock Fabric Triboelectric Nanogenerator for Bio-Motion Energy Harvesting and as Self-Powered Stretching and 3D Tactile Sensors. Mater. Today. 2020;32:84&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.mattod.2019.10.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mattod.2019.10.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girshick R. Fast R-CNN. arXiv. 2015 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1504.08083.1504.08083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1504.08083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girshick R., Donahue J., Darrell T., Malik J. Rich Feature Hierarchies for Accurate Object Detection and Semantic Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Columbus, OH, USA. 23&#x2013;28 June 2014; pp. 580&#x2013;587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., He K., Girshick R., Sun J. Faster R-CNN: Towards Real-Time Object Detection with Region Proposal Networks. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2016;39:1137&#x2013;1149. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K., Gkioxari G., Doll&#xe1;r P., Girshick R. Mask R-CNN; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Venice, Italy. 22&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 2961&#x2013;2969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bochkovskiy A., Wang C.-Y., Liao H.-Y.M. YOLOv4: Optimal Speed and Accuracy of Object Detection. arXiv. 2020 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2004.10934.2004.10934</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2004.10934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Divvala S., Girshick R., Farhadi A. You Only Look Once: Unified, Real-Time Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Las Vegas, NV, USA. 27&#x2013;30 June 2016; pp. 779&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Farhadi A. YOLO9000: Better, Faster, Stronger; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Honolulu, HI, USA. 21&#x2013;26 July 2017; pp. 7263&#x2013;7271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Farhadi A. YOLOv3: An Incremental Improvement. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767.1804.02767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Anguelov D., Erhan D., Szegedy C., Reed S., Fu C.-Y., Berg A.C. Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2016. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2016. SSD: Single Shot MultiBox Detector; pp. 21&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z., Shen C., Chen H., He T. FCOS: Fully Convolutional One-Stage Object Detection. arXiv. 2019 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1904.01355.1904.01355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1904.01355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuan W., Jian-She G., Bo-Jie H., Zong-Shan W., Hong-Wei D., Jie W. A Lightweight Modified YOLOX Network Using Coordinate Attention Mechanism for PCB Surface Defect Detection. IEEE Sens. J. 2022;22:20910&#x2013;20920. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2022.3208580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2022.3208580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Q., Zhou D., Feng J. Coordinate Attention for Efficient Mobile Network Design; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Virtual Conference. 19&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 13713&#x2013;13722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Z., Liu S., Wang F., Li Z., Sun J. YOLOX: Exceeding YOLO Series in 2021. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2107.08430.2107.08430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2107.08430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Dang Z. Fast PCB Defect Detection Method Based on FasterNet Backbone Network and CBAM Attention Mechanism Integrated with Feature Fusion Module in Improved YOLOv7. IEEE Access. 2023;11:95092&#x2013;95103. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3311260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3311260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C.-Y., Bochkovskiy A., Liao H.-Y.M. YOLOv7: Trainable Bag-of-Freebies Sets New State-of-the-Art for Real-Time Object Detectors; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Vancouver, BC, Canada. 17&#x2013;24 June 2023; pp. 7464&#x2013;7475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Kao S.-H., He H., Zhuo W., Wen S., Lee C.-H., Chan S.-H.G. Run, Don&#x2019;t Walk: Chasing Higher FLOPS for Faster Neural Networks; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Vancouver, BC, Canada. 17&#x2013;24 June 2023; pp. 12021&#x2013;12031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo S., Park J., Lee J.-Y., Kweon I.S. CBAM: Convolutional Block Attention Module; Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV); Tel Aviv, Israel. 23&#x2013;27 October 2018; pp. 3&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Chen J., Chen J., Wen Z., Zhou X. LDD-Net: Lightweight Printed Circuit Board Defect Detection Network Fusing Multi-Scale Features. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2024;129:107628. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han K., Wang Y., Tian Q., Guo J., Xu C., Xu C. GhostNet: More Features from Cheap Operations; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 1580&#x2013;1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Lv W., Xu S., Wei J., Wang G., Dang Q., Liu Y., Chen J. DETRs Beat YOLOs on Real-Time Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 16&#x2013;22 June 2024; pp. 16965&#x2013;16974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Chen Z., Zou Y., Lu M., Chen C., Song Y., Zhang H., Yan F. Channel Prior Convolutional Attention for Medical Image Segmentation. Comput. Biol. Med. 2024;178:108784. doi: 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38941900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C.-Y., Liao H.-Y.M., Wu Y.-H., Chen P.-Y., Hsieh J.-W., Yeh I.-H. CSPNet: A New Backbone That Can Enhance Learning Capability of CNN; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops; Seattle, WA, USA. 14&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 390&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K., Zhang X., Ren S., Sun J. Spatial Pyramid Pooling in Deep Convolutional Networks for Visual Recognition. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2015;37:1904&#x2013;1916. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2015.2389824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2015.2389824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26353135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Qi L., Qin H., Shi J., Jia J. Path Aggregation Network for Instance Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;22 June 2018; pp. 8759&#x2013;8768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Li L., Jiang H., Weng K., Geng Y., Li L., Ke Z., Li Q., Cheng M., Nie W., et al. YOLOv6: A Single-Stage Object Detection Framework for Industrial Applications. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2209.02976.2209.02976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2209.02976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding X., Zhang X., Ma N., Han J., Ding G., Sun J. RepVGG: Making VGG-Style ConvNets Great Again; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Nashville, TN, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 13733&#x2013;13742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Jiang J., Chen Y., Sun Z., Tang Y., Lai Q., Zhu H. Rapid Detection of Yunnan Xiaomila Based on Lightweight YOLOv7 Algorithm. Front. Plant Sci. 2023;14:1200144. doi: 10.3389/fpls.2023.1200144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2023.1200144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao G., Hou S., Zhou H. PCB Defect Detection Algorithm Based on CDI-YOLO. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:7351. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-57491-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-57491-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10978831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38548814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu P., Cai Y., Li F., Kan J., Chen K., Dong F. A Deep Learning Method for PCB Defect Detection Based on Improved YOLOv8; Proceedings of the CVDL 2024: The International Conference on Computer Vision and Deep Learning; Changsha, China. 19&#x2013;21 January 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultralytics  YOLOv8. 2024.  [(accessed on 2 October 2024)].  Available online:  https://docs.ultralytics.com/zh/models/yolov8/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Wang S., Zhu L., Shen A., Hu D. A printed circuit board surface defect detection method for long-tail and multi-scale scenarios. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2026;165:113415. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2025.113415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2025.113415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultralytics  YOLO11. 2024.  [(accessed on 2 October 2024)].  Available online:  https://docs.ultralytics.com/zh/models/yolo11/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T.-Y., Doll&#xe1;r P., Girshick R., He K., Hariharan B., Belongie S. Feature Pyramid Networks for Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Honolulu, HI, USA. 21&#x2013;26 July 2017; pp. 2117&#x2013;2125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M., Pang R., Le Q.V. EfficientDet: Scalable and Efficient Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 10781&#x2013;10790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Huang D., Wang Y. Learning Spatial Fusion for Single-Shot Object Detection. arXiv. 2019 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1911.09516.1911.09516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1911.09516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Li L., Geng Y., Jiang H., Cheng M., Zhang B., Ke Z., Xu X., Chu X. YOLOv6 v3.0: A Full-Scale Reloading. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2301.05586.2301.05586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2301.05586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Jiang Y., Chen W., Huang Y., Zhang Y., Sun X. Damo-YOLO: A Report on Real-Time Object Detection Design. arXiv. 20222211.15444</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., He W., Nie Y., Guo J., Liu C., Wang Y., Han K. Gold-YOLO: Efficient Object Detector via Gather-and-Distribute Mechanism. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2024;36:51094&#x2013;51112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G., Lei J., Tian H., Feng Z., Liang R. Asymptotic Feature Pyramid Network for Labeling Pixels and Regions. IEEE Trans. Circuits Syst. Video Technol. 2024;34:7820&#x2013;7829. doi: 10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3376773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3376773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard A.G., Zhu M., Chen B., Kalenichenko D., Wang W., Weyand T., Andreetto M., Adam H. MobileNets: Efficient Convolutional Neural Networks for Mobile Vision Applications. arXiv. 2017 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1704.04861.1704.04861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1704.04861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M.M., Munir M., Marculescu R. EMCAD: Efficient Multi-scale Convolutional Attention Decoding for Medical Image Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 16&#x2013;22 June 2024; pp. 11769&#x2013;11779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y., Xu H., Qian K., Li Z., Yan H. A Window-Based Multi-Scale Attention Model for Slope Collapse Detection. Earth Sci. Inf. 2024;17:181&#x2013;191. doi: 10.1007/s12145-023-01158-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-023-01158-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>