<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715255</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-783X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of medical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Med Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics and risk factors analysis of patients with cN1b papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a retrospective single-center study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40001-026-04101-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Lateral lymph node metastasis (LLNM) increase the risk of local recurrence and secondary surgery, posing a significant physical, psychological and economic burden on patients with papillary thyroid microcarcinoma (PTMC). Therefore, it is necessary to analyze the clinicopathological features and risk factors of recurrence in these cN1b PTMC patients,thereby guiding risk-stratified clinical management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective cohort of 246 patients with cN1b PTMC who underwent primary surgery at Zhejiang Cancer Hospital (January 2008-December 2017) was analyzed. Clinicopathological data and long-term follow-up outcomes were collected. Univariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were used to identify predictors of skip lateral lymph node metastasis (SLNM) and recurrence, while Kaplan-Meier survival analysis with log-rank tests was used to compare recurrence-free survival between subgroups.Sample size calculation was performed to ensure statistical power, and temporal stratification was used to mitigate retrospective bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Multivariate logistic regression identified two independent predictors of SLNM: maximum tumor diameter&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;5&#xa0;mm (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.84) and absence of intrathyroidal dissemination (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;16.19). Notably, SLNM was not associated with recurrence or disease-specific survival (DSS). During follow-up, 14 patients had lymph node recurrence and 6 patients had local recurrence, 2 patients died of thyroid cancer. Multivariate analysis confirmed three independent recurrence predictors: extrathyroidal extension (ETE, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.06, 95% CI 1.14-14.38), upper-pole tumor location (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.58, 95% CI 1.34-9.58), and intrathyroidal dissemination (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.88, 95% CI 1.14-7.28). Kaplan-Meier analysis showed significantly higher recurrence rates in patients with ETE (21.9% vs. 6.1%, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), upper-pole tumors (13.8% vs. 4.6%, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), and intrathyroidal dissemination (18.4% vs. 6.3%, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In cN1b PTMC, SLNM is independently associated with tumor size&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;5&#xa0;mm and absence of intrathyroidal dissemination but not with recurrence or DSS, suggesting it should be a key target for preoperative imaging evaluation rather than a poor prognostic factor. ETE is one of the most important independent recurrence risk factors, alongside upper-pole location and intrathyroidal dissemination-its effect magnitude requires cautious interpretation due to a wide confidence interval. A risk-stratified strategy is supported: patients with these high-risk features may consider more radical treatment and intensified postoperative surveillance. This study provides evidence-based guidance to improve disease-free survival in cN1b PTMC patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xuhang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital of School of Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thyroid Surgery, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Gongshu District, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Yangjian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Head &amp; Neck Cancer Translational Research of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shang</LastName><ForeName>Jinbiao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thyroid Surgery, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Gongshu District, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhejiang Provincial Clinical Research Center for Malignant Tumor, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Chun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thyroid Surgery, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Gongshu District, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaochun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thyroid Surgery, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Gongshu District, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xuefei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Head &amp; Neck Cancer Translational Research of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Huize</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Head &amp; Neck Cancer Translational Research of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Base Alliance, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Weihua</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Second Affiliated Hospital of School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China. weihuagong@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liangzhu Laboratory, Zhejiang University Medical Center, Hangzhou, China. weihuagong@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82305042</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024ZL309</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Province Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and Technology Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021KY086</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Medical Science and Technology Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020KY482</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Medical Science and Technology Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Med Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9517857</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0949-2321</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lateral lymph node metastasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Papillary thyroid microcarcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence-free survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skip metastasis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40001-026-04101-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40001-026-04101-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ito Y, Miyauchi A. Active surveillance of low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinomas. Gland Surg. 2020;9(5):1663&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen BR, Alexander EK, Bible KC, Doherty GM, Mandel SJ, Nikiforov YE, et al. 2015 American Thyroid Association Management guidelines for adult patients with thyroid nodules and differentiated thyroid cancer. Thyroid. 2016;26(1):1&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SY, Li MY, Zhou CP, Ao W, Huang WY, Wang SS, et al. Accurate preoperative prediction of nodal metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: towards optimal management of patients. Head Neck. 2024;46(5):1009&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SK, Park I, Woo JW, Lee JH, Choe JH, Kim JH, et al. Predictive factors for lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Ann Surg Oncol. 2016;23(9):2866&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng JW, Yang XH, Wu BQ, Sun DL, Jiang Y, Qu Z. Predictive factors for central lymph node and lateral cervical lymph node metastases in papillary thyroid carcinoma. Clin Transl Oncol. 2019;21(11):1482&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui S, White MG, Antic T, Grogan RH, Angelos P, Kaplan EL, et al. Clinical and pathologic predictors of lymph node metastasis and recurrence in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Thyroid. 2016;26(6):807&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Yang Z, Ouyang Q. A nomogram to predict skip metastasis in papillary thyroid cancer. World J Surg Oncol. 2020;18(1):167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie X, Tan Z, Ge M. Skip metastasis in papillary thyroid carcinoma is difficult to predict in clinical practice. BMC Cancer. 2017;17(1):702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi FM, Barra MB, Zettler CG. Predictive factors for lymph node metastasis in solitary papillary thyroid carcinomas: a retrospective study. Pathol Oncol Res. 2015;21(1):59&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So YK, Kim MJ, Kim S, Son YI. Lateral lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis for prevalence, risk factors, and location. Int J Surg. 2018;50:94&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goran M, Markovic I, Buta M, Gavrilovic D, Cvetkovic A, Santrac N, et al. The influence of papillary thyroid microcarcinomas size on the occurrence of lymph node metastases. J BUON. 2019;24(5):2120&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallini G, De Leo A, Repaci A, de Biase D, Bacchi Reggiani ML, Di Nanni D, et al. Does the site of origin of the microcarcinoma with respect to the thyroid surface matter? A multicenter pathologic and clinical study for risk stratification. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12(1):246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon JH, Park JY, Hong AR, Kim HK, Kang HC. Predictors of lateral lymph node metastasis and skip metastasis in patients with papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2024;15:1392247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Xin Y, Yang L, Liu Y, Tian Z, Shang X. Risk factors of skip lateral cervical lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid carcinoma. Lin Chuang Er Bi Yan Hou Tou Jing Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2022;36(7):528&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Huang T, Li H. Risk factors for skip metastasis and lateral lymph node metastasis of papillary thyroid cancer. Surgery. 2019;166(1):55&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Feng S, Yu Q, Shen G, Yuan L, Huang W. Conventional papillary thyroid carcinoma with intraglandular lymphatic dissemination shows more aggressive features. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2022;52(11):1311&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Back K, Kim JS, Kim JH, Choe JH. Superior located papillary thyroid microcarcinoma is a risk factor for lateral lymph node metastasis. Ann Surg Oncol. 2019;26(12):3992&#x2013;4001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Chen W, Fang Q, Fan J, Feng L, Guo L. Lateral lymph node metastases in T1a papillary thyroid carcinoma: stratification by tumor location and size. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2021;12:716082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J, Chen Z, Chen S, Xu Z, Wen L, Mao Z, et al. Lateral lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a study of 5241 follow-up patients. Endocrine. 2024;83(2):414&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Deng Y, Zhou M, Wu B, Zhou J. Intraglandular dissemination: a special pathological feature. Front Oncol. 2024;14:1428274.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>