<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41471652</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-Time Zero-Sequence-Voltage Estimation and Fault-Tolerant Control for an Open-Winding Five-Phase Fault-Tolerant Fractional-Slot Concentrated-Winding IPM Motor Under Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7655</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s25247655</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Inter-turn short-circuit (ITSC) faults in motor drives can induce substantial circulating currents and localized thermal stress, ultimately degrading winding insulation and compromising torque stability. To enhance the operational reliability of open-winding (OW) five-phase fault-tolerant fractional-slot concentrated-winding interior permanent-magnet (FTFSCW-IPM) motor drive systems, this paper proposes a real-time fault-tolerant control strategy that provides current suppression and torque stabilization under ITSC conditions. Upon fault detection, the affected phase is actively isolated and connected to an external dissipative resistor, thereby limiting the fault-phase current and inhibiting further propagation of insulation damage. This reconfiguration allows the drive system to uniformly accommodate both open-circuit (OC) and ITSC scenarios without modification of the underlying control architecture. For OC operation, an equal-amplitude modulation scheme based on carrier-based pulse-width modulation (CPWM) is formulated to preserve the required magnetomotive-force distribution. Under ITSC conditions, a feedforward compensation mechanism is introduced to counteract the disturbance generated by the short-circuit loop. A principal contribution of this work is the derivation of a compensation term that can be estimated online using zero-sequence voltage (ZSV) together with measured phase currents, enabling accurate adaptation across varying ITSC severities. Simulation and experimental results demonstrate that the proposed method effectively suppresses fault-phase current, maintains near-sinusoidal current waveforms in the remaining healthy phases, and stabilizes torque production over a wide range of fault and load conditions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Ronghua</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3151-5205</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electrical, Energy and Power Engineering, Yangzhou University, Yangzhou 225127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Qingpeng</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electrical, Energy and Power Engineering, Yangzhou University, Yangzhou 225127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shitao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electrical, Energy and Power Engineering, Yangzhou University, Yangzhou 225127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Huaxin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electrical, Energy and Power Engineering, Yangzhou University, Yangzhou 225127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22KJB470026</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of the Jiangsu Higher Education Institutions of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YZLYJFJH2021YXBS130</GrantID><Agency>Lv Yang Jin Feng Program of Yangzhou</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feedforward compensation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inter-turn short-circuit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zero-sequence voltage</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41471652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12737308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25247655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s25247655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Chau K.T., Wu D., Gao S. Opportunities and Challenges of Vehicle-to-Home, Vehicle-to-Vehicle, and Vehicle-to-Grid Technologies. Proc. IEEE. 2013;101:2409&#x2013;2427. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2013.2271951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2013.2271951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J., Zhang C., Wang Z., Dong Y., Nino C.E., Tariq A.R., Strangas E.G. Thermal Analysis of Permanent Magnet Motor for the Electric Vehicle Application Considering Driving Duty Cycle. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2010;46:2493&#x2013;2496. doi: 10.1109/TMAG.2010.2042043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMAG.2010.2042043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Shang F., Brown I., Krishnamurthy M. Comparative Study of interior permanent magnet, induction, and switched reluctance motor drives for EV and HEV applications. IEEE Trans. Transp. Electrif. 2015;1:245&#x2013;254. doi: 10.1109/TTE.2015.2470092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2015.2470092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Yuan M., Jiang J. A Comprehensive Review of the Multiphase Motor Drive Topologies for High-Power Electric Vehicle: Current Status, Research Challenges, and Future Trends. IEEE Trans. Transp. Electrif. 2024;11:3631&#x2013;3654. doi: 10.1109/TTE.2024.3443926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2024.3443926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves P., Cruz S., Mendes A. Fault-Tolerant Predictive Current Control of Six-Phase PMSMs with Minimal Reconfiguration Requirements. IEEE J. Emerg. Sel. Top. Power Electron. 2023;11:2084&#x2013;2093. doi: 10.1109/JESTPE.2022.3223515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JESTPE.2022.3223515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Guo S., Xu J., Tian X. Power Switch Open-Circuit Fault Diagnosis of Six-Phase Fault Tolerant Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor System Under Normal and Fault-Tolerant Operation Conditions Using the Average Current Park&#x2019;s Vector Approach. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2020;36:2641&#x2013;2660. doi: 10.1109/TPEL.2020.3017637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2020.3017637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki H., Hirata K., Niguchi N., Takahara K. Fault-Tolerant Control for a Six-Phase Two-Controllable-Rotor Motor. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2021;59:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1109/TMAG.2021.3076084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMAG.2021.3076084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsa L., Toliyat H.A., Goodarzi A. Five-Phase Interior Permanent-Magnet Motors with Low Torque Pulsation. IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl. 2007;43:40&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1109/TIA.2006.887235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIA.2006.887235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng S., Zhang L., Shen D. Investigation on Wide-Speed Operation of a New Five-Phase Fault-Tolerant Interior Permanent Magnet Motor from Perspective of Flux-Intensifying Effect. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2023;59:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1109/TMAG.2023.3292918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMAG.2023.3292918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Liu L., Chen Q., Zhao W. Torque Calculation of Five-Phase Interior Permanent Magnet Machine Using Improved Analytical Method. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 2018;34:1023&#x2013;1032. doi: 10.1109/TEC.2018.2880574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2018.2880574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Fan Y., Lorenz R.D., Nied A., Cheng M. Design and Comparison of Three-Phase and Five-Phase FTFSCW-IPM Motor Open-End Winding Drive Systems for Electric Vehicles Applications. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2017;67:385&#x2013;396. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2017.2743246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2017.2743246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priestley M., Fletcher J.E., Tan C. Space-Vector PWM Technique for Five-Phase Open-End Winding PMSM Drive Operating in the Overmodulation Region. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 2018;65:6816&#x2013;6827. doi: 10.1109/TIE.2018.2795527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2018.2795527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levi E., Satiawan I.N.W., Bodo N., Jones M. A Space-Vector Modulation Scheme for Multilevel Open-End Winding Five-Phase Drives. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 2011;27:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1109/TEC.2011.2178074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2011.2178074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Zhu W., Zhang X., Zhang L. Stator Winding Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Faults Severity Detection Controlled by OW-SVPWM Without CMV of a Five-Phase FTFSCW-IPM. IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl. 2017;53:194&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1109/TIA.2016.2609848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIA.2016.2609848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Guan X., Li C., Mou Q., Chen Z. Comprehensive Evaluation of Inter-Turn Short Circuit Faults in PMSM Used for Electric Vehicles. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2020;22:611&#x2013;621. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2020.2987637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2020.2987637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Xiao L., Zou J., Xu Y., Li S. Analysis and Monitoring Method for Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault for PMSM. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2023;59:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berzoy A., Mohamed A.A., Mohammed O. Impact of Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Location on Induction Machines Parameters Through FE Computations. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2017;53:1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1109/TMAG.2017.2665639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMAG.2017.2665639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X., Wang B., Wang Z., Hua W., Cheng M. Detection and Differentiation of Winding Inter-Turn Fault and High-Resistance Fault in PM Machines. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2025;40:12440&#x2013;12451. doi: 10.1109/TPEL.2025.3568022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2025.3568022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C., Yuan C., Wang Y., Qiu H., Chen S., Lian Z., Zhu Z. Analysis of Inter-Turn-Short Fault in High-Speed Permanent Magnet Generators Considering Effect of Structure Windings. IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl. 2025;61:3007&#x2013;3015. doi: 10.1109/TIA.2025.3532403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIA.2025.3532403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L., Kang J., Ke D., Wang F. A Hybrid Model Flux Estimator for Diagnosis of Inter-Turn Short Circuit Fault in Traction Motors Considering Inverter Nonlinearity. IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl. 2025;61:7707&#x2013;7717. doi: 10.1109/TIA.2025.3562513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIA.2025.3562513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Huang W., Pan T., Xu D. Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault Diagnosis and Severity Estimation for Five-Phase PMSM. CES Trans. Electr. Mach. Syst. 2025;9:224&#x2013;233. doi: 10.30941/CESTEMS.2025.00019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30941/CESTEMS.2025.00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo P., Yin Z., Zhang Z., Zhang Y., Zhang P., Liu J. Diversified Diagnosis Strategy for PMSM Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault via Novel Sliding Mode Observer. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2024;39:4149&#x2013;4159. doi: 10.1109/TPEL.2024.3352077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3352077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas-Cornejo J.-J., Almanza-Ojeda D.-L., Gonz&#xe1;alez-Parada A., Hernandez-Ramirez V., Ibarra-Manzano M.-A. Complex Signal Analysis for Inter-Turn Short-Circuits Faults on Induction Motors. IEEE Sens. J. 2025;25:13433&#x2013;13440. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2025.3545030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2025.3545030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiei V., Khoshlessan M., Caicedo-Narvaez C., Fahimi B. Detection of Inter-Turn Short Circuit in Stator Windings of Electric Machines Using Magnetic Symmetry Index and Machine Learning Methods. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 2024;40:642&#x2013;652. doi: 10.1109/TEC.2024.3434395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2024.3434395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei D., Liu K., Huang J., Wang J., Zhou S., Cai H., Chen J. Instantaneous Phase Estimation Based Single-Signal Diagnosis for Inter-Turn Short Circuit Fault in PMSMs. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 2024;40:1350&#x2013;1364. doi: 10.1109/TEC.2024.3480971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2024.3480971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao L., Li S., Liu C., Zou J. Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault Diagnosis Method for Dual Three-Phase PMSM Based on Voltage Demodulation. IEEE Trans. Magn. 2025;61:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1109/TMAG.2025.3528942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMAG.2025.3528942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L., Kang J., Ke D., Wang F. D-Axis High-Frequency Impedance Extraction Method for Online Diagnosis of Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Faults in Traction Motors. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2025;40:17061&#x2013;17072. doi: 10.1109/TPEL.2025.3589369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2025.3589369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen M., Ha D.-H., Mahmoud M.S., Huynh V.K. Robust Fault Classification in Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines Under Dynamic and Noisy Conditions. IEEE Access. 2025;13:115217&#x2013;115225. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3585518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3585518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X., Geng Y., Li M., Wang W., Tu M. Inter-Turn Short Circuit Diagnosis of Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor Based on Siamese Convolutional Neural Network Under Small Fault Samples. IEEE Sens. J. 2024;24:26982&#x2013;26993. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2024.3423751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3423751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Xu Y., Wang R., Cheng M. Advanced Fault Tolerant 3&#xd7;3-Phase PM Drive with Concentric Winding for EV Application. IEEE Trans. Transp. Electrific. 2023;9:2754&#x2013;2764. doi: 10.1109/TTE.2022.3227621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2022.3227621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhan W., Ehsani M. Fault-Tolerant Control of PMSM with Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 2019;34:2267&#x2013;2275. doi: 10.1109/TEC.2019.2936225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2019.2936225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q., Han X., Liu G., Zhao W., Shi H. Inter-Turn Fault Diagnosis and Control for Five-Phase PMSMs by Disturbance Observer. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 2024;71:13901&#x2013;13909. doi: 10.1109/TIE.2024.3374364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2024.3374364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Cui R., Zhang A. Torque Ripple Minimization for Inter-Turn Short-Circuit Fault Based on Open-Winding Five Phase FTFSCW-IPM Motor for Electric Vehicle Application. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2019;69:282&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2019.2953689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2019.2953689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>