<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41880942</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8630</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>404</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of environmental management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Environ Manage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Valorization of waste R227ea refrigerant into fuels and chemicals via supercritical water gasification: A ReaxFF-MD and DFT study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129460</StartPage><MedlinePgn>129460</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jenvman.2026.129460</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0301-4797(26)00920-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Escalating ozone depletion and global warming concerns have positioned the refrigeration and air conditioning sector as a critical arena for climate-change mitigation. High-market-share refrigerants, particularly hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs) recognized as greenhouse gases, are being progressively regulated due to their high global warming potentials, rendering the safe treatment and valorization of end-of-life HFCs an urgent challenge. Supercritical water gasification (SCWG) is capable of efficiently converting organic wastes into value-added products and therefore represents a promising route for HFC abatement. Herein, R227ea (1,1,1,2,3,3,3-heptafluoropropane) was selected as a representative HFC to elucidate its degradation mechanism under SCWG conditions. A combined ReaxFF reactive molecular dynamics and density functional theory framework was employed to resolve elementary pathways and assess the effects of temperature, pressure, and reactant concentration on product formation. The results show that HF, CO, and H<sub>2</sub> are the major products under the investigated conditions, with more than 95% of fluorine atoms converted into HF. Elevated temperature markedly accelerates R227ea decomposition and, within an appropriate range, promotes the formation of HF, CO, and H<sub>2</sub>. Increasing the H<sub>2</sub>O concentration enhances H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> production while suppressing CO formation. Notably, HF formation constitutes the kinetically favored pathway for the R227ea-H<sub>2</sub>O reaction network. Overall, this study advances mechanistic understanding of HFC destruction in supercritical water and supports SCWG as a potential strategy for converting waste HFCs into value-added products.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shukun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, Southwest University, Chongqing, 400715, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Grade Energy Utilization Technologies and Systems, Ministry of Education, School of Energy and Power Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing, 400030, China. Electronic address: liuchao@cqu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Grade Energy Utilization Technologies and Systems, Ministry of Education, School of Energy and Power Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing, 400030, China; College of Aviation Engineering, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Guanghan, 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huo</LastName><ForeName>Erguang</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Efficient Low-carbon Energy Conversion and Utilization of Jiangsu Provincial Higher Education Institutions, School of Physical Science and Technology, Suzhou University of Science and Technology, Suzhou, 215009, China. Electronic address: huoerguang@usts.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Environ Manage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401664</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0301-4797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">R227ea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reaction mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ReaxFF-MD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCWG method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Waste refrigerants treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41880942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2026.129460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0301-4797(26)00920-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>