<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41653288</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-3023</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International urogynecology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Urogynecol J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond the Mesh: PuboUrethral Ligament Plication Versus Transobturator Tape at 6 Months and the Power of Preoperative ICIQ-SF for Risk Stratification.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00192-026-06552-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare short-term outcomes of pubourethral ligament plication (PLP) versus transobturator tape (TOT) for stress urinary incontinence (SUI) and evaluate the prognostic value of the preoperative International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire-Short Form (ICIQ-SF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective, non-randomized cohort study, 140 women underwent PLP (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;48) or TOT (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;92). Success was assessed at 6&#xa0;months using objective (pad count) and subjective criteria. Predictive performance of preoperative ICIQ-SF was analyzed using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Preoperative symptoms were more severe in the TOT group (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003). Objective success rates were 88.0% for TOT and 77.1% for PLP (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05); subjective satisfaction was high and comparable. PLP had significantly shorter operative duration (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and no mesh-related complications, while TOT had an 8.7% complication rate. Preoperative ICIQ-SF score demonstrated excellent discriminative power for predicting failure (AUC 0.98; 95% CI 0.96-1.00), whereas daily pad count was a poor predictor (AUC 0.48). An ICIQ-SF threshold of&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;17 points identified patients at high risk of failure with high sensitivity and specificity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PLP and TOT provide comparable short-term relief. PLP is a faster, mesh-free alternative avoiding synthetic material-related morbidity. Preoperative ICIQ-SF is a robust tool for individualized risk stratification, though the high AUC warrants external validation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive license to International Urogynecological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x130;nceb&#x131;y&#x131;k</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8400-441X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Application Hospital, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Harran University, &#x15e;anl&#x131;urfa, Turkey. drmehmetincebiyik@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adak</LastName><ForeName>&#x130;brahim Halil</ForeName><Initials>&#x130;H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-1602-4165</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Mehmet Akif &#x130;nan Training and Research Hospital, &#x15e;anl&#x131;urfa, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int Urogynecol J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567041</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0937-3462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ICIQ-SF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Native tissue repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective cohort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pubourethral ligament plication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk stratification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress urinary incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transobturator tape</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Statement: This study was approved by the Harran University Clinical Research Ethics Committee (Decision No: HR&#xdc;/25.01.25; Date: 13 January 2025), and was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their inclusion in the study. Conflicts of interest: None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41653288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-026-06552-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00192-026-06552-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Wei WD, Yu H, Yu L. Prevalence and determinants of stress urinary incontinence in middle-aged and older women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Esp Urol. 2025;78(1):46&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.56434/j.arch.esp.urol.20257801.6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56434/j.arch.esp.urol.20257801.6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39943633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West N, Harris K, Chapman M, Moore K. Does urodynamic stress incontinence increase after the menopause? Results from 2,994 urodynamic studies in Australian women. Int Urogynecol J. 2024;35:1789&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-024-05876-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-024-05876-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alquaiz A, Kazi A, Alyousefi N, Alwatban L, AlHabib Y, Turkistani I. Urinary incontinence affects the quality of life and increases psychological distress and low self-esteem. Healthcare. 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare11121772 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11121772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37372891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10297870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravi M, Mohseni M, Oskouie I, Razavi J, Cidranes E, Zolbin M. Exosome therapy in stress urinary incontinence: a comprehensive literature review.&#xa0;Biomedicines. 2025;13. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines13051229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacciari L, Dumoulin C, Hay-Smith E. Pelvic floor muscle training versus no treatment, or inactive control treatments, for urinary incontinence in women: a cochrane systematic review abridged republication. Braz J Phys Ther. 2019;23(2):93&#x2013;107. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjpt.2019.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2019.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30704907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6428911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salo H, Sova H, Laru J, Talvensaari-Mattila A, Nyyss&#xf6;nen V, Santala M, et al. Long-term results of a prospective randomized trial comparing tension-free vaginal tape versus transobturator tape in stress urinary incontinence. Int Urogynecol J. 2023;34:2249&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-023-05527-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-023-05527-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37074367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10506929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambiar A, Cody J, Jeffery S, Aluko P. Single-incision sling operations for urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;7:CD008709. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd008709.pub3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.cd008709.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28746980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6483163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejene S, Funk M, Pate V, Wu J. Long-term outcomes after midurethral mesh sling surgery for stress urinary incontinence. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2021;28:188&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1097/spv.0000000000001094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/spv.0000000000001094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34608036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9169553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pycek M, Zarzecka J, Majkusiak W, Barcz E, Zwierzchowska A. Current approach to the use of transvaginal mesh systems in pelvic organ prolapse. Ginekol Pol. 2025. https://doi.org/10.5603/gpl.101432 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5603/gpl.101432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40145699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivasl&#x131;o&#x11f;lu A, Mirzazada F, Hodgson R, Petros P. Urethral ligament plication operation (ULP) for minimal invasive cure of SUI without tapes. Pelviperineology. 2024. https://doi.org/10.34057/ppj.2024.43.01.2024-3-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brasoveanu S, Ilina R, B&#x103;lulescu L, Pirtea M, Seco&#x219;an C, Grigora&#x219; D, Olaru F, Erdelean D, Balint O, Margan M, Ivan C, Pirtea L. Evaluating patient preferences and clinical outcomes in stress urinary incontinence treatment: a short-term follow-up study of the transobturator tape procedure and pubourethral ligament plication (a minimally invasive technique). J Person Med. 2023;14. https://doi.org/10.3390/jpm14010034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotti F, Rampello S, Terranova C, De Cicco Nardone C, Luvero D, Montera R, et al. The true impact of voiding dysfunctions after transobturator sub-urethral tape procedures: a systematic review of literature. J Clin Med. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13164762 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13164762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39200904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11355201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapple C, Cruz F, Deffieux X, Milani A, Arlandis S, Artibani W, et al. Consensus statement of the European urology Association and the European Urogynaecological Association on the use of implanted materials for treating pelvic organ prolapse and stress urinary incontinence. Eur Urol. 2017;72(3):424&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2017.03.048 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2017.03.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28413126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrar S, Razzak L, Mohsin R. The practice of burch colposuspension versus mid urethral slings for the treatment of stress urinary incontinence in developing country. Pak J Med Sci. 2021;37:1359&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.12669/pjms.37.5.4017 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.37.5.4017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34475912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8377912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petros P, Sivasl&#x131;o&#x11f;lu A, Papadimitriou J, Sekiguchi Y, Hodgson R, Palma P. Further developments of pubourethral ligament surgery for stress urinary incontinence. Ann Trans Med. 2024;12. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-23-1764</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofoudis C, Theodoros S, Panagiotis F. Autologous fascial slings &#x2013; efficacy and future challenges. An analytic review. Obstet Gynecol Int J. 2023. https://doi.org/10.15406/ogij.2023.14.00692</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15406/ogij.2023.14.00692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nipa S, Cooper D, Mostafa A, Hagen S, Abdel-Fattah M. Novel clinically meaningful scores for the ICIQ-UI-SF and ICIQ-FLUTS questionnaires in women with stress incontinence. Int Urogynecol J. 2023;34:3033&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-023-05657-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-023-05657-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37819367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10756866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karmakar D, Mostafa A, Abdel-Fattah M. A new validated score for detecting patient-reported success on postoperative ICIQ-SF: a novel two-stage analysis from two large RCT cohorts. Int Urogynecol J. 2016;28:95&#x2013;100. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-016-3070-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-016-3070-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27379890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5203851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller P, Gurol-Urganci I, Van Der Meulen J, Thakar R, Jha S. Risk of reoperation 10 years after surgical treatment for stress urinary incontinence: a national population-based cohort study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2021.08.059 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2021.08.059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34509439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8135190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, He H, Wang L, Shao H, Liu Y, Yan X, et al. Risk prediction models for stress urinary incontinence after pelvic organ prolapse (POP) surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Womens Health. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-025-03584-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-03584-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41466211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12751348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falah-Hassani K, Reeves J, Shiri R, Hickling D, McLean L. The pathophysiology of stress urinary incontinence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int Urogynecol J. 2021;32:501&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-020-04622-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-020-04622-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33416968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8053188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber M, Brubaker L, Nygaard I, Wheeler T, Schaffer J, Chen Z, et al. Defining success after surgery for pelvic organ prolapse. Obstet Gynecol. 2009;114:600&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/aog.0b013e3181b2b1ae .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/aog.0b013e3181b2b1ae</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19701041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2904469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skorupska K, Grzybowska M, Kubik-Komar A, Rechberger T, Miot&#x142;a P. Identification of the urogenital distress inventory-6 and the incontinence impact questionnaire-7 cutoff scores in urinary incontinent women. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2021;19. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12955-021-01721-z .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur T, Xinyi K, Barnes C, Attarbashi S, Shahid N. Evaluating surgical trends and outcomes in stress urinary incontinence: a clinical audit at a district general hospital.&#xa0;Cureus. 2025;17. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.83815</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>