<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41453969</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A sensor-fused BIM-based &#x131;ntelligent control system for energy-efficient &#x131;ndoor environmental regulation using deep actor-critic reinforcement learning (DACRL).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>957</StartPage><MedlinePgn>957</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">957</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-30460-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rising energy demand of the building sector, coupled with the need for high indoor environmental quality (IEQ), necessitates intelligent control strategies. However, traditional methods like rule-based control (RBC) lack adaptability, while model predictive control (MPC) suffers from model dependency. Hence, this study designed and implemented an intelligent indoor environmental control system based on multi-sensor fusion and Building Information Modeling (BIM). At the algorithmic level, this study employed a deep fusion actor-critic reinforcement learning (DACRL) algorithm to achieve energy-efficient dynamic environmental control. The system employs a four-layer architecture with cloud-edge-end collaboration. Layer 1: The perception layer utilizes a multi-modal sensor network built on an STM32L0 low-power micro-controller and an SX1276 LoRa communication module. This architecture enables distributed collection and pre-processing of parameters such as temperature, humidity, CO<sub>2</sub>, light, and occupancy. Layer 2: The fusion layer proposes a spatio-temporal synchronization mechanism for multi-source asynchronous data based on sliding window dynamic weighting and an extended Kalman filter (EKF). As an optimization, an isolation forest and one-class support vector machine (SVM) are combined to construct a multi-layer anomaly detection process. Layer 3: The decision layer establishes a deep reinforcement learning control model based on the topology of BIM semantic mapping. The key novelty of this model lies in its innovative embedding of the Lieb-Thirring (L-T) inequality, which describes the energy concentration characteristics of spatial fields, as a spectral constraint into both the reward function and the online action projection process of the Actor-Critic algorithm. This model innovatively embeds the Lieb-Thirring (L-T) inequality, which describes the energy concentration characteristics of spatial fields, as a spectral constraint into the reward function and online action projection process of the Actor-Critic algorithm. Layer 4: The execution layer implements real-time closed-loop control of terminal equipment such as HVAC, lighting, and shading through the standard BMS protocol. This study designed large-scale simulation experiments covering six core scenarios: offices, classrooms, residences, hospitals, shopping malls, and data centers. The experimental results demonstrate that the system's annual energy consumption per unit area decreases by up to 63.2% compared to traditional rule-based control (RBC) strategies and by 23.5% compared to model predictive control (MPC) strategies. At the same time, several indoor comfort metrics improved significantly, with CO<sub>2</sub> concentrations falling below 800 ppm 91.5% of the time and the thermal comfort (PMV) index remaining within&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.3 94.2% of the time. The proposed DACRL algorithm demonstrates excellent convergence and generalization capabilities. It achieves stable convergence numerically with an average of only 15,000 training steps. Performance loss in cross-building type transfer testing is only 4.9%.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tong</LastName><ForeName>Libin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Culture and Tourism, Fuzhou Polytechnic, Fuzhou, 350108, Fujian, China. tonglibin@sobeysca.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Building &#x131;nformation modeling (BIM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep actor-critic reinforcement learning (DACRL)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indoor environmental regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sensor fusion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41453969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12783845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-30460-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-30460-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, YunQian, Li, Li., Sadiq, M. &amp; Chien, FengSheng. The impact of non-renewable energy production and energy usage on carbon emissions: Evidence from China. <i>Energy Environ.</i><b>35</b>(4), 2248&#x2013;2269 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0958305X221150432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, J. et al. Global energy use and carbon emissions from irrigated agriculture. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>15</b>(1), 3084 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-47383-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11006866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38600059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Li, Y. &amp; Li, R. Integrating artificial intelligence in energy transition: A comprehensive review. <i>Energ. Strat. Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 101600 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esr.2024.101600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ukoba, K., Olatunji, K. O., Adeoye, E., Jen, T.-C. &amp; Madyira, D. M. Optimizing renewable energy systems through artificial intelligence: Review and future prospects. <i>Energy Environ.</i><b>35</b>(7), 3833&#x2013;3879 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0958305X241256293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, C., Yang, X., Guo, C. &amp; Li, P. Analysis of deformation of deep and large foundation pit support structure and impact on neighbouring buildings in complex environments. <i>Buildings</i><b>15</b>(9), 1435 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15091435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerdali, E., Rivera, M. &amp; Wheeler, P. A review on weighting factor design of finite control set model predictive control strategies for ac electric drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>39</b>(8), 9967&#x2013;9981 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3370550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, Z. &amp; He, H. A data-driven solution for intelligent power allocation of connected hybrid electric vehicles inspired by offline deep reinforcement learning in V2X scenario. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>372</b>, 123861 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayatnia, A., Ghafourian, J., Sepehrzad, R., Al-Durrad, A. &amp; Anvari-Moghaddam, A. Two-stage data-driven optimal energy management and dynamic real-time operation in networked microgrid based on a deep reinforcement learning approach. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>160</b>, 110142 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2024.110142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin, X. et al. A comprehensive review of predictive control strategies in heating, ventilation, and air-conditioning (HVAC): Model-free VS model. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>94</b>, 110013 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, I., Fayaz, M., Aman, M. &amp; Kim, DoHyeun. An optimization scheme for IoT based smart greenhouse climate control with efficient energy consumption. <i>Computing</i><b>104</b>(2), 433&#x2013;457 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00607-021-00963-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakhdari, K., Sriti, L. &amp; Painter, B. Parametric optimization of daylight, thermal and energy performance of middle school classrooms, case of hot and dry regions. <i>Build. Environ.</i><b>204</b>, 108173 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2021.108173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z., Sivaparthipan, C. B. &amp; Muthu, B. A. IoT based smart and intelligent smart city energy optimization. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>49</b>, 101724 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraj, R., Kuthadi, V. M. &amp; Baskar, S. Smart building energy management and monitoring system based on artificial intelligence in smart city. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>56</b>, 103090 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. &amp; Zhang, T. Multi-objective optimization of energy, visual, and thermal performance for building envelopes in China&#x2019;s hot summer and cold winter climate zone. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>59</b>, 105034 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q. &amp; Li, N. Model predictive control for energy-efficient optimization of radiant ceiling cooling systems. <i>Build. Environ.</i><b>205</b>, 108272 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2021.108272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lissa, P. et al. Deep reinforcement learning for home energy management system control. <i>Energy AI</i><b>3</b>, 100043 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2020.100043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman, A. U. et al. An optimal power usage scheduling in smart grid integrated with renewable energy sources for energy management. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 84619&#x2013;84638 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3087321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Huang, J., Feng, Z., Cao, S.-J. &amp; Haghighat, F. Occupant-density-detection based energy efficient ventilation system: Prevention of infection transmission. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>240</b>, 110883 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2021.110883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7940037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hora, S. K., Poongodan, R., De Prado, R. P., Wozniak, M. &amp; Divakarachari, P. B. (2021) Long short-term memory network-based metaheuristic for effective electric energy consumption prediction. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>11</b>(23), 11263 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app112311263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Z., Song, Y. &amp; Chu, Y. Summer performance of a naturally ventilated double-skin facade with adjustable glazed louvers for building energy retrofitting. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>267</b>, 112163 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2022.112163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. A long short-term memory-based model for greenhouse climate prediction. <i>Int. J. Intell. Syst.</i><b>37</b>(1), 135&#x2013;151 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/int.22620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benyezza, H., Bouhedda, M. &amp; Rebouh, S. Zoning irrigation smart system based on fuzzy control technology and IoT for water and energy saving. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>302</b>, 127001 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.127001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arroyo, J., Manna, C., Spiessens, F. &amp; Helsen, L. Reinforced model predictive control (RL-MPC) for building energy management. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>309</b>, 118346 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2021.118346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. &amp; Ying, H. Low carbon urban rail transit station city integration based on building information modeling and sensor fusion. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>110</b>, 108850 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2023.108850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valinejadshoubi, M., Moselhi, O. &amp; Bagchi, A. Integrating BIM into sensor-based facilities management operations. <i>J. Facil. Manag.</i><b>20</b>(3), 385&#x2013;400 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JFM-08-2020-0055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eneyew, D. D., Capretz, M. A. M. &amp; Bitsuamlak, G. T. Toward smart-building digital twins: BIM and IoT data integration. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>10</b>, 130487&#x2013;130506 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3229370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C.-H. et al. Fusion of BIM and SAR for innovative monitoring of urban movement-towards 4D digital twin. <i>Int. Arch. Photogramm. Remote. Sens. Spat. Inf. Sci.</i><b>48</b>, 1627&#x2013;1632 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/isprs-archives-XLVIII-G-2025-1627-2025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavaleta, J. P. A. Using sensors for structural assessment through building &#x131;nformation modeling (BIM) in the life cycle of buildings. <i>J. Adv. Artif. Intell. Eng. Technol.</i> (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xun, X., Zhang, J. &amp; Yuan, Y. Multi-information fusion based on BIM and intuitionistic fuzzy DS evidence theory for safety risk assessment of undersea tunnel construction projects. <i>Buildings</i><b>12</b>(11), 1802 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings12111802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. et al. Deep learning for assessment of environmental satisfaction using BIM big data in energy efficient building digital twins. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>50</b>, 101897 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rached, Ishraq, Rafika Hajji, Tania Landes, and Rashid Haffadi. "Deep Learning Based Semantic Segmentation for BIM Model Generation from RGB-D Sensors." In 19th 3D GeoInfo Conference 2024, vol. 10, pp. 271&#x2013;279. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miky, Y., Alshawabkeh, Y. &amp; Baik, A. Using deep learning for enrichment of heritage BIM: Al Radwan house in historic Jeddah as a case study. <i>Heritage Science</i><b>12</b>(1), 255 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40494-024-01382-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Chonghua, and Jianan Yang. "Develop an Intelligent System of Construction Safety Management Using BIM and Multi-Sensor." In Proceedings of the 2023 International Conference on Computer, Vision and Intelligent Technology, pp. 1&#x2013;12. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niroui, F., Zhang, K., Kashino, Z. &amp; Nejat, G. Deep reinforcement learning robot for search and rescue applications: Exploration in unknown cluttered environments. <i>IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett.</i><b>4</b>(2), 610&#x2013;617 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2019.2891991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, R., Jin, M., Sun, K., Hong, T. &amp; Spanos, C. Advanced building control via deep reinforcement learning. <i>Energy Procedia</i><b>158</b>, 6158&#x2013;6163 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egypro.2019.01.494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, R. et al. Multi-agent deep reinforcement learning optimization framework for building energy system with renewable energy. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>312</b>, 118724 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.118724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Guanyu, Jie Li, and Yonggang Wen. "Energy-efficient thermal comfort control in smart buildings via deep reinforcement learning." arXiv preprint arXiv:1901.04693 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandi, S., Piscitelli, M. S., Martellacci, M. &amp; Capozzoli, A. Deep reinforcement learning to optimise indoor temperature control and heating energy consumption in buildings. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>224</b>, 110225 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2020.110225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang, D., Spangher, L., Nadarajah, S. &amp; Spanos, C. Deep reinforcement learning with planning guardrails for building energy demand response. <i>Energy and AI</i><b>11</b>, 100204 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2022.100204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei, Y. et al. A practical deep reinforcement learning framework for multivariate occupant-centric control in buildings. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>324</b>, 119742 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.119742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valladares, W. et al. Energy optimization associated with thermal comfort and indoor air control via a deep reinforcement learning algorithm. <i>Build. Environ.</i><b>155</b>, 105&#x2013;117 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2019.03.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Qianwen, Lihong Zhao, Henghua Jiang, and Caiyi Wei. "Design of low power LoRa module based on STM32 micro-controller." In Fifth International Conference on Mechatronics and Computer Technology Engineering (MCTE 2022), vol. 12500, pp. 541&#x2013;545. SPIE, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azhar, M., Mhammad, I. Z., Ali, A. M. &amp; Zulkifli, S. A study on LoRa SX1276 performance in IoT health monitoring. <i>Wireless Commun. Mobile Comput.</i><b>1</b>, 6066354 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/6066354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, Y., Yan, B., Zhou, C., Tingli, Su. &amp; Jin, X. State of art on state estimation: Kalman filter driven by machine learning. <i>Annu. Rev. Control.</i><b>56</b>, 100909 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcontrol.2023.100909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodarahmi, M. &amp; Maihami, V. A review on Kalman filter models. <i>Arch. Comput. Methods Eng.</i><b>30</b>(1), 727&#x2013;747 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11831-022-09815-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T., Zhou, Z. &amp; Yang, L. Layered isolation forest: A multi-level subspace algorithm for improving isolation forest. <i>Neurocomputing</i><b>581</b>, 127525 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2024.127525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heigl, M. et al. On the improvement of the isolation forest algorithm for outlier detection with streaming data. <i>Electronics</i><b>10</b>(13), 1534 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics10131534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank, R. L., Gontier, D. &amp; Lewin, M. The nonlinear Schr&#xf6;dinger equation for orthonormal functions II: application to Lieb-Thirring inequalities. <i>Commun. Math. Phys.</i><b>384</b>(3), 1783&#x2013;1828 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00220-021-04039-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Wang, J. &amp; Sun, H. Generalization of the Lieb&#x2013;Thirring&#x2013;Araki inequality and its applications. <i>Mathematics</i><b>9</b>(7), 723 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math9070723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank, R. L. &amp; Kova&#x159;&#xed;k, H. Lieb&#x2013;Thirring inequality for the 2D Pauli operator. <i>Commun. Math. Phys.</i><b>406</b>(2), 23 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00220-024-05177-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Qian, Kane Rodriguez, Nicholas Whetstone, and Steven Habel. "Rapid Internet of Things (IoT) prototype for accurate people counting towards energy efficient buildings." Journal of Information Technology in Construction 24 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anik, S. M., Hassan, X. G., Meng, Na., Agee, P. R. &amp; McCoy, A. P. A cost-effective, scalable, and portable IoT data infrastructure for indoor environment sensing. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>49</b>, 104027 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, H., Sun, Z., Chiba, Y. &amp; Koshizuka, N. Accurate indoor location awareness based on machine learning of environmental sensing data. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>98</b>, 107676 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2021.107676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, Dianyu, Tian Xing, Kailai Sun, Ziyou Zhang, Qianchuan Zhao, and Jian Kang. "Topology-Aware Hypergraph Reinforcement Learning for Indoor Occupant-Centric HVAC Control." Energy and Buildings (2025): 116219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, K., Xinwei Wang, Shaobo Liu, Qianchuan Zhao, Gao Huang, and Chang Liu. "Toward Pedestrian Head Tracking: A Benchmark Dataset and an Information Fusion Network." arXiv preprint arXiv:2408.05877 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>