<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41376749</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Power of Combined Intravenous and Intraventricular Colistin Against Multidrug-Resistant Bacteria in Healthcare-Associated Ventriculitis and Meningitis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e96359</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e96359</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e96359</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.96359</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Healthcare-associated ventriculitis and meningitis (HAVM) caused by multidrug-resistant (MDR) gram-negative organisms represents a major therapeutic challenge, given the limited penetration of most antibiotics into the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). Colistin, although active against MDR strains, exhibits poor CSF distribution when administered intravenously&#xa0;alone. We report a case of a 74-year-old man admitted with a cerebellar hemorrhage complicated by hydrocephalus requiring external ventricular drainage. The patient subsequently developed HAVM due to MDR <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i>. Initial systemic antibiotic regimens, including intravenous (IV) colistin, failed to control the infection. A combined strategy with IV and intraventricular (IVT) colistin was initiated, resulting in rapid improvement of inflammatory biomarkers and microbiological clearance. However, the patient ultimately died from neurological complications related to the primary hemorrhagic stroke. This case illustrates the potential benefit of combined IV and IVT colistin administration in refractory MDR gram-negative HAVM. While clinical outcomes may be limited by underlying neurological severity, adjunct IVT therapy ensures effective CSF antibiotic concentrations and may improve infection control. Further research is needed to optimize dosing and establish standardized treatment protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Azelmat et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azelmat</LastName><ForeName>Sanae</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bacteriology, Mohammed V Military Training Hospital, Rabat, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baadi</LastName><ForeName>Tarik</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology and Critical Care, Mohammed V Military Training Hospital, Rabat, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammadi</LastName><ForeName>Hicham</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology and Critical Care, Mohammed V Military Training Hospital, Rabat, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doghmi</LastName><ForeName>Nawfal</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology and Critical Care, Mohammed V Military Training Hospital, Rabat, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chadli</LastName><ForeName>Mariama</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bacteriology, Mohammed V Military Training Hospital, Rabat, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colistin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare-associated ventriculitis and meningitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intraventricular</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">klebsiella pneumoniae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidrug-resistant</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41376749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.96359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ventriculostomy-related infections: a critical review of the literature. Lozier AP, Sciacca RR, Romagnoli MF, Connolly ES Jr. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12182415/ Neurosurgery. 2002;51:170&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12182415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors and outcomes associated with external ventricular drain infections. Walek KW, Leary OP, Sastry R, Asaad WF, Walsh JM, Horoho J, Mermel LA. https://doi.org/10.1017/ice.2022.23. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2022;43:1859&#x2013;1866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9753061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35471129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infectious risks of external ventriculostomies. (Article in French) Korinek AM. Ann Fr Anesth Reanim. 1999;18:554&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multidrug-resistant, extensively drug-resistant and pandrug-resistant bacteria: an international expert proposal for interim standard definitions for acquired resistance. Magiorakos AP, Srinivasan A, Carey RB, et al. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2012;18:268&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emergence of hypervirulent and carbapenem-resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae from 2014-2021 in Central and Eastern China: a molecular, biological, and epidemiological study. Wu C, Huang Y, Zhou P, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1186/s12866-024-03614-9. BMC Microbiol. 2024;24:465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11552131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39528921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resistance reported from China Antimicrobial Surveillance Network (CHINET) in 2018. Hu F, Guo Y, Yang Y, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1007/s10096-019-03673-1. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2019;38:2275&#x2013;2281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of colistin and polymyxin B: are we there yet? Tran TB, Velkov T, Nation RL, Forrest A, Tsuji BT, Bergen PJ, Li J. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2016.09.010. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2016;48:592&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5154767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27793510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practice guidelines for the management of bacterial meningitis. Tunkel AR, Hartman BJ, Kaplan SL, Kaufman BA, Roos KL, Scheld WM, Whitley RJ. Clin Infect Dis. 2004;39:1267&#x2013;1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15494903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment of central nervous system infection caused by multidrug-resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae with colistin sulfate intravenously and intrathecally: a case report. Lu X, Zhong C, Chen H, Xie X, Lv X. https://doi.org/10.3390/ph15121482. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 2022;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9787966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36558933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intrathecal or intraventricular antimicrobial therapy for post-neurosurgical gram-negative bacillary meningitis or ventriculitis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Li MT, Wu QQ, Li JB, Chen JS. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2023.107033. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2024;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community-acquired bacterial meningitis in adults. van de Beek D, de Gans J, Tunkel AR, Wijdicks EF. N Engl J Med. 2006;354:44&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16394301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment strategies for central nervous system infections: an update. Tan YC, Gill AK, Kim KS. https://doi.org/10.1517/14656566.2015.973851. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2015;16:187&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25328149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosocomial infection. Kollef MH, Torres A, Shorr AF, Martin-Loeches I, Micek ST. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33438970/ Crit Care Med. 2021;49:169&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>