<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731395</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The power of machine learning models in predicting gestational diabetes mellitus.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">348</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-026-08856-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) is associated with various adverse outcomes in pregnancy for the mother and the baby. Precise prediction of GDM trends are crucial for public health. Machine learning (ML) models have emerged as powerful tools for disease prediction, demonstrating superior results compared to traditional methods. As a result, we set out to assess the effectiveness of ML models for predicting GDM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This was a retrospective study that used the clinical and demographic information of all mothers admitted for delivery to a primary referral tertiary center located in Bandar Abbas, Iran, from January 2020 to January 2022. The input data were employed in seven ML models. To evaluate the diagnostic potential of each model, we utilized the accuracy, area under the curve (AUC), precision, recall, and F1 score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The incidence rate of GDM was 20.9%. Models utilizing Boosting techniques, particularly CatBoost and XGBoost, excelled in predicting GDM compared to other models, however the prediction power was not high. These two models yielded the best average AUC (approximately 0.64 to 0.66) and also the top average Recall (approximately 0.43 to 0.52). In terms of all performance metrics, CatBoost demonstrated the best capability in predicting GDM with acceptable accuracy and average recall. BMI, maternal age, gestational age, maternal education, maternal residency, fetal gender, history of abortion, and parity were among the top 10 features that highly predicted GDM. Conversely, factors like intrauterine fetal demise, infertility, cardiovascular issues, COVID-19, substance abuse, multiple births, anemia, and a history of stillbirth exhibited nearly zero significance across nearly all models due to their low prevalence or lack of diversity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">CatBoost model had a higher performance in predicting GDM, however the prediction power was not so high.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehrnoush</LastName><ForeName>Vahid</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mother and Child Welfare Research Center, Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences, Bandar Abbas, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haghighat</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nami</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezaei</LastName><ForeName>Nazanin</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mother and Child Welfare Research Center, Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences, Bandar Abbas, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darsareh</LastName><ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mother and Child Welfare Research Center, Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences, Bandar Abbas, Iran. famadarsareh@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montazeri</LastName><ForeName>Farideh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mother and Child Welfare Research Center, Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences, Bandar Abbas, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saffari</LastName><ForeName>Mozhgan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mother and Child Welfare Research Center, Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences, Bandar Abbas, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gestational diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic models</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study complied with the Declaration of Helsinki and was performed according to ethics committee approval. With authorization from the Hormozgan University of Medical School Research Ethics Board (IR.HUMS.REC.1402.239), we conducted a review of the medical records of every patient who delivered at our facility. The Ethics and Research Committee of Hormozgan University of Medical Sciences exempted the necessity for informed consent for involvement due to the study&#x2019;s retrospective design. Statistical analysis was performed while maintaining patient confidentiality and complying with ethics committee guidelines. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13036927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-026-08856-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-026-08856-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACOG Practice Bulletin No. Gestational Diabetes Mellitus. Obstet Gynecol. 2018;190(2):e49&#x2013;64. 10.1097/AOG.0000000000002501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000002501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartayeva A, Danyarova L, Begalina D, Nurgalieva Z, Baikadamova L, Adilova G. Gestational Diabetes: prevelence and risk for the mother and child (review). Georgian Med News. 2022(328&#x2013;329):47&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36318841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darsareh F, Jahromi M, Ranjbar A, Shekari M, Mehrnoush V, Roozbeh N. Pregnancy and Childbirth Outcomes of Gestational Diabetes Mellitus: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Dis Diagn. 2024;13(4):151&#x2013;6. 10.34172/ddj.1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/ddj.1608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tehrani FR, Naz MSG, Bidhendi-Yarandi R, Behboudi-Gandevani S. Effect of Different Types of Diagnostic Criteria for Gestational Diabetes Mellitus on Adverse Neonatal Outcomes: A Systematic Review, Meta-Analysis, and Meta-Regression. Diabetes Metab J. 2022;46(4):605&#x2013;19. 10.4093/dmj.2021.0178. Epub 2022 Mar 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2021.0178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9353558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir TL, Majumder M, Glastras SJ. A systematic review of the effects of maternal obesity on neonatal outcomes in women with gestational diabetes. Obes Rev. 2024;25(7):e13747. 10.1111/obr.13747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38679418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintanilla Rodriguez BS, Vadakekut ES, Mahdy H, Gestational D. 2024 Jul 14. In: StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025 Jan&#x2013;. PMID: 31424780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sert UY, Ozgu-Erdinc AS. Gestational Diabetes Mellitus Screening and Diagnosis. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2021;1307:231&#x2013;55. 10.1007/5584_2020_512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/5584_2020_512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32314318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliskan R, Atis A, Aydin Y, Acar D, Kiyak H, Topbas F. PAPP-A concentrations change in patients with gestational diabetes. J Obstet Gynaecol. 2020;40(2):190&#x2013;4. 10.1080/01443615.2019.1615041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01443615.2019.1615041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oral S, Celik S, Akpak YK, Golbasi H, Bayraktar B, Unver G, Sahin S, Yurtcu N, Soyer Caliskan C. Prediction of gestational diabetes mellitus and perinatal outcomes by plasma zonulin levels. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2024;309(1):119&#x2013;26. 10.1007/s00404-022-06751-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-022-06751-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35994108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golbasi H, Bayraktar B, Golbasi C, Omeroglu I, Adiyaman D, Sever B, Ekin A. Can sonographic imaging of the fetal pancreas predict perinatal outcomes in gestational diabetes mellitus? J Perinat Med. 2022;50(9):1189&#x2013;97. 10.1515/jpm-2022-0050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jpm-2022-0050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golbasi H, Bayraktar B, Golbasi C, Omeroglu I, Emiralioglu Cakir Z, Tuncer Can S, Pehlivanoglu OC, Ekin A. Splenic Artery Doppler Waveforms in Gestational Diabetes and Association with Fetal Pancreas: A Prospective Case-Control Study. Fetal Diagn Ther. 2024;51(5):500&#x2013;9. 10.1159/000539585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000539585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38815567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayaz L, Joseph R, Ankayarkanni B, Princemary S, Asha P, Student U. Multi-scale and context aware optimized glucose prediction using neural networks. In 2023 7th International Conference on Trends in Electronics and Informatics (ICOEI). 2023:820&#x2013;825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boujarzadeh B, Ranjbar A, Banihashemi F, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Saffari M. Machine learning approach to predict postpartum haemorrhage: a systematic review protocol. BMJ Open. 2023;13(1):e067661. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9853215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banaei M, Roozbeh N, Darsareh F, Mehrnoush V, Farashah MSV, Montazeri F. Utilizing machine learning to predict the risk factors of episiotomy in parturient women. AJOG Glob Rep. 2024;5(1):100420. 10.1016/j.xagr.2024.100420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xagr.2024.100420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11665599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjbar A, Taeidi E, Mehrnoush V, Roozbeh N, Darsareh F. Machine learning models for predicting pre-eclampsia: a systematic review protocol. BMJ Open. 2023;13(9):e074705. 10.1136/bmjopen-2023-074705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-074705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10496701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taeidi E, Ranjbar A, Montazeri F, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F. Machine Learning-Based Approach to Predict Intrauterine Growth Restriction. Cureus. 2023;15(7):e41448. 10.7759/cureus.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10403995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37546140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjbar A, Ghamsari S, Boujarzade B, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F. Predicting risk of postpartum hemorrhage using machine learning approach: A systematic review. GOCM. 2023;3(3):170&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.gocm.2023.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gocm.2023.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malakooti N, Mehrnoush V, Abdi F, Farashah MSV, Darsareh F. Development of a machine learning model to identify the predictors of the neonatal intensive care unit admission. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):20914. 10.1038/s41598-025-06651-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-06651-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12215917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40596456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safarzadeh S, Ardabili NS, Farashah MV, Roozbeh N, Darsareh F. Predicting mother and newborn skin-to-skin contact using a machine learning approach. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2025;25(1):182. 10.1186/s12884-025-07313-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-07313-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11837404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39966775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeilyfard R, Bayati M. Enhancing AI-driven forecasting of diabetes burden: a comparative analysis of deep learning and statistical models. Sci Rep. 2025;15:29137. 10.1038/s41598-025-14599-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-14599-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12335553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40783432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W, Phung D, Tran T, Gupta S, Rana S, Karmakar C, Shilton A, Yearwood J, Dimitrova N, Ho TB, Venkatesh S, Berk M. Guidelines for Developing and Reporting Machine Learning Predictive Models in Biomedical Research: A Multidisciplinary View. J Med Internet Res. 2016;18(12):e323. 10.2196/jmir.5870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.5870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5238707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K P I GK, Hasin AJ, M LFJ, Siluvai S. Support Vector Machines: A Literature Review on Their Application in Analyzing Mass Data for Public Health. Cureus. 2025;17(1):e77169. 10.7759/cureus.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11806959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39925494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Szymczak S. A review on longitudinal data analysis with random forest. Brief Bioinform. 2023;24(2):bbad002. 10.1093/bib/bbad002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbad002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10025446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36653905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldini D, Grisoni F, Kuhn D, Friedrich L, Sieber SA. Practical guidelines for the use of gradient boosting for molecular property prediction. J Cheminform. 2023;15(1):73. 10.1186/s13321-023-00743-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13321-023-00743-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37641120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock JT, Khoshgoftaar TM. CatBoost for big data: an interdisciplinary review. J Big Data. 2020;7(1):94. 10.1186/s40537-020-00369-8. Epub 2020 Nov 4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-020-00369-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei N, Amani M, Asgharpoor H, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Nikmanesh A. Machine Learning Approach to Predict Emergency Cesarean Sections Among Nulliparous Women. Cureus. 2025;17(8):e90501. 10.7759/cureus.90501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12446892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40978894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song YY, Lu Y. Decision tree methods: applications for classification and prediction. Shanghai Arch Psychiatry. 2015;27(2):130&#x2013;5. 10.11919/j.issn.1002-0829.215044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11919/j.issn.1002-0829.215044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4466856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26120265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean MW, Hooker G, Staicu AM, Scheipl F, Ruppert D. Functional Generalized Additive Models. J Comput Graph Stat. 2014;23(1):249&#x2013;69. 10.1080/10618600.2012.729985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10618600.2012.729985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3982924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24729671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, Michel V, Thirion B, Grisel O, Blondel M, Prettenhofer P, Weiss R, Dubourg V, Vanderplas J, Passos A, Cournapeau D, Brucher M, Perrot M, Duchesnay &#xc9;. Scikit-learn: machine learning in Python. J Mach Learn Res. 2011;12:2825&#x2013;30. 10.1145/2786984.2786995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/2786984.2786995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinh Le T, Minh Bui T, Hien Vu T, Phi Thi Nguyen N, Thanh Thi Tran H, Nguyen ST, Ho Thi Nguyen L, Van Ngo M, Huy Duong H, Thanh Vu B, Dinh HT, Nhu Do B, Le DC, Thi Nguyen H. Trung Nguyen K. Insulin Resistance in Gestational Diabetes Mellitus and Its Association With Anthropometric Fetal Indices. Clin Med Insights Endocrinol Diabetes. 2022;15:11795514221098403. 10.1177/11795514221098403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11795514221098403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35601878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjbar A, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Pariafsay F, Shirzadfardjahromi M, Shekari M. The Incidence and Outcomes of Late-Term Pregnancy. Cureus. 2023;15(1):e33550. 10.7759/cureus.33550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.33550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9907390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36779141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrnoush V, Ranjbar A, Banihashemi F, Darsareh F, Shekari M, Jahromi M. Urban-rural differences in the pregnancy-related adverse outcome. Gynecol Obstetr Clin Med. 2023;3(1):51&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.gocm.2022.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gocm.2022.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekari M, Shirzadfardjahromi M, Ranjbar A, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Roozbeh N. Advanced maternal age and adverse obstetrical and neonatal outcomes of singleton pregnancies. Gynecol Obstet Clin Med. 2022;2(4):175&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gocm.2022.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagami K, Iwama N, Hamada H, Tomita H, Kudo R, Kumagai N, Wang H, Izumi S, Watanabe Z, Ishikuro M, Obara T, Metoki H, Miura Y, Ota C, Sugiyama T, Kuriyama S, Arima T, Yaegashi N, Saito M, Japan Environment and Children&#x2019;s Study Group. Advanced maternal age is a risk factor for both early and late gestational diabetes mellitus: The Japan Environment and Children&#x2019;s Study. J Diabetes Investig. 2025;16(4):735&#x2013;43. 10.1111/jdi.14400. Epub 2025 Jan 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdi.14400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11970309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field C, Grobman WA, Yee LM, Johnson J, Wu J, McNeil B, Mercer B, Simhan H, Reddy U, Silver RM, Parry S, Saade G, Chung J, Wapner R, Lynch CD, Venkatesh KK. Community-level social determinants of health and pregestational and gestational diabetes. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2024;6(2):101249. 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2023.101249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajogmf.2023.101249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11184512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38070680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita H, Yasuhi I, Koga M, Sugimi S, Umezaki Y, Fukuoka M, Suga S, Fukuda M, Kusuda N. Fetal sex and maternal insulin resistance during mid-pregnancy: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):560. 10.1186/s12884-020-03242-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-03242-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7513312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Aprile I, Petrillo G, Zonca V, Mazzelli M, De Cillis F, Di Benedetto MG, Riva MA, Cattaneo A. Sex-specific metabolic and inflammatory alterations in adult animals vulnerable to prenatal stress exposure. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2025;138:111344. 10.1016/j.pnpbp.2025.111344. Epub 2025 Mar 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2025.111344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40139340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JH, Lee J, Kim KH, Kim HJ, Kim H, Cha HN, Park J, Lee H, Park SY, Jang HC, Kim H. Multiparity increases the risk of diabetes by impairing the proliferative capacity of pancreatic &#x3b2; cells. Exp Mol Med. 2023;55(10):2269&#x2013;80. 10.1038/s12276-023-01100-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s12276-023-01100-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10618440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37903900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matikainen N, Meri S. Do multiparous women need to work or exercise extra hard to control gestational diabetes? J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11(5):550&#x2013;1. 10.1016/j.jshs.2022.03.006. Epub 2022 Mar 26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2022.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9532586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35346872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livadas S, Anagnostis P, Bosdou JK, Bantouna D, Paparodis R. Polycystic ovary syndrome and type 2 diabetes mellitus: A state-of-the-art review. World J Diabetes. 2022;13(1):5&#x2013;26. 10.4239/wjd.v13.i1.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v13.i1.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8771268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35070056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero R, Espinoza J, Mazor M. Can endometrial infection/inflammation explain implantation failure, spontaneous abortion, and preterm birth after in vitro fertilization? Fertil Steril. 2004;82(4):799&#x2013;804. 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2004.05.076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2004.05.076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roozbeh N, Montazeri F, Farashah MV, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F. Proposing a machine learning-based model for predicting nonreassuring fetal heart. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):7812. 10.1038/s41598-025-92810-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-92810-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11885418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40050357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi F, Roozbeh N, Darsareh F, Mehrnoush V, Vahidi Farashah MS, Montazeri F. Developing a prognostic model for predicting preterm birth using a machine learning algorithm. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2025;25(1):974. 10.1186/s12884-025-08136-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-08136-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12486630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41029225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatankhah Tarbebar M, Mohammadi M, Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F. Prognostic machine learning models for predicting postoperative complications following general surgery in Bandar Abbas, Iran: a study protocol. BMJ Open. 2025;15(10):e108019. 10.1136/bmjopen-2025-108019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2025-108019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12570904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41151946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrnoush V, Darsareh F, Shabana W, Shahrour W. Prediction of Renal Cancer Recurrence using Artificial Intelligence: A Systematic Review. Canc Therapy Oncol Int J. 2025;28(2):556233. 10.19080/CTOIJ.2025.28.556233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19080/CTOIJ.2025.28.556233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>