<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41903302</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>238</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex differences in efficacy and toxicity of first-line treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer: An analysis of 18,041 patients in the ARCAD CRC database.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116694</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116694</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejca.2026.116694</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0959-8049(26)00474-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Greater toxicity of adjuvant chemotherapy in females has been reported previously, but the impact of patients' sex on chemotherapy (CT)+/-targeted therapies for non-resectable, metastatic colorectal cancer (mCRC) has remained unclear. We compared efficacy and toxicity of first-line chemotherapy, with or without targeted therapies, between male and female mCRC patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-seven randomized trials from the ARCAD CRC database were included. Primary endpoint was overall survival (OS); secondary endpoints were progression-free survival (PFS), overall response rate, toxicity (according to NCI-CTCAE). Analyses were performed within three treatment groups: A) CT alone, B) CT+bevacizumab, and C) CT+epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor. OS and PFS were estimated using Kaplan-Meier method. Associations with sex were assessed using study-stratified Cox models adjusted for age, performance status, body mass index, and CT backbone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Baseline data from 18,041 patients were analysed; among 15,271 included in outcome analyses, no sex differences in OS or PFS were observed. Adjusted OS hazard ratios (95% confidence interval) for females versus (vs.) males were: A: 1.01 (0.95-1.08, P&#x202f;=&#x202f;.69), B: 0.96 (0.89-1.04, P&#x202f;=&#x202f;.36), C: 0.97 (0.87-1.10, P&#x202f;=&#x202f;.67). Females experienced higher toxicity, including grade 1-4 and 3-4 nausea (71.8% vs. 60.5% and 7.5% vs. 4.8%), vomiting (47.7% vs. 35.5% and 6.6% vs. 4.4%), and neutropenia (52.4% vs. 44.4% and 29.2% vs. 18.8%) (P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;.001). Conversely, rash (grade 1-4 and 3-4) was more frequent in males (29.6% vs. 24.3% and 5.1% vs. 3.7%, P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Despite higher chemotherapy-related toxicity in females, treatment efficacy was similar between sexes. Rash was more common in males, highlighting that patients' sex modulates toxicity profiles in both directions. Strategies to reduce adverse events in female patients are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wagner</LastName><ForeName>Anna Dorothea</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Division of Medical Oncology, Lausanne University Hospital (CHUV) and University of Lausanne (UNIL), Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raeisi</LastName><ForeName>Morteza</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistical Unit, ARCAD Foundation, Paris, France. Electronic address: morteza.raeisi@fondationarcad.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakez</LastName><ForeName>Manel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistical Unit, ARCAD Foundation, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diasio</LastName><ForeName>Robert D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Cancer Center, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margalit</LastName><ForeName>Ofer</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheba Cancer Research Center and Sheba Medical Center, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zalcberg</LastName><ForeName>John R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venook</LastName><ForeName>Alan P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Douillard</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Yves</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut de Canc&#xe9;rologie de l'Ouest-Ren&#xe9; Gauducheau, Nantes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lenz</LastName><ForeName>Heinz J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Oncology, USC Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heinemann</LastName><ForeName>Volker</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology/Oncology, LMU Klinikum, University of Munich, Comprehensive Cancer Center Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldberg</LastName><ForeName>Richard M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West Virginia University Cancer Institute, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Cutsem</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmoll</LastName><ForeName>Hans-Joachim</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Research in Oncology, Martin-Luther University Halle-Wittenberg, Halle/Saale, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Quantitative Health Sciences, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andr&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Thierry</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Sorbonne University, Saint-Antoine Hospital, AP-HP, France; ARCAD Foundation, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Gramont</LastName><ForeName>Aimery</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ARCAD Foundation, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005373</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Targeted therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Toxicity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: ADW reports consulting or advisory roles for Astellas, Daiichy Sankyo, Dragonfly, Lilly, Merck, MSD, Pierre-Fabre, Servier, BMS, all paid to my institution and reimbursed in part and travel fees from Abbvie, Ipsen, Merck and Sanofi. She is coordinating investigator of EORTC-TRIAL 1203, which is supported by an educational grant from Roche to EORTC. She is co-chair of the gastric cancer task-force of the EORTC GI group, chair of the ESMO Gender Medicine Task Force, and Member of the ASCO scientific committee 2022/2023, all unpaid. QS reports grants or contracts from Celgene/BMS, Roche/Genentech, Janssen, Novartis, all paid to institution, consulting fees from Boehringer Ingelheim Pharmaceuticals, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, and Kronos Bio, all paid to herself, participation on Data Safety Monitoring or Advisory Boards: Yiviva Inc, Hoosier Cancer Research Network, paid to herself. RG reports consulting fees from COMPASS Therapeutics, Abbvie, Innovative Cellular Therapeutics, Eisai, Inspirna, Innovative Chemotherapy Technologies paid to him for drug/device development advice, payment for expert testimony from Taiho in a patent dispute, support for DSMB services fromMerck, Sorrento, Astra Zeneca, GI Therapeutics, Bayer and GI Therapeutics for participation on an advisory board. He is board member in FIGHT Colorectal Cancer and advisory committee member for ASCO PAC. JZ reports consulting fees from MSD, Specialized Therapeutics, CEND, Deciphera, REVOLUTION MEDICINE, FivePHusion, Genorbio, 1Global, Novotech, Lisata, Alloplex Biotherapeutics Inc, Nous Consulting, Honoraria from Specialised Therapeutics, Merck Serono, Targovax, Halozyme, Gilead Sciences, Deciphera, MSD Oncology, Viatris, leadership roles: ICON Group, Lipotec, Stock of other ownership interests: Biomarin, Ophtea, Amarin, Concert harmaceuticaly, Frequency Therapeutics, Gilead, Madrigal Pharmaceuticals, UniQure, Zogenix, Orphazyme, Moderna Therapeutics, TWST, Novovax and research funding from BMS, Astra Zeneca, Pfizer, IQviam Mylan, Ipsen, Eisai, Medtronic, MSD Oncology. VH reports honoraria for talks and advisory roles fro Merck, Amgen, Roche, Sanofi, Servier, Pfizer, Pierre-Fabre, Astra-Zeneca, BMS, MSD, Novartis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Celgene, SIRTEX, Terumo, Oncosil, NORDIC, Seagen and research funding from Merck, Amgen, Roche, Sanofi, Boehringer-Ingelheim, SIRTEX, Servier. TA reports consulting or advisory roles in Aptitude health, Abbvie, Astellas Pharma, Biocartis, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gritstone Bio, GlaxoSmithKline, MSD Oncology, Medicenna, Nimbus, Nordic Bioscience, Seagen, Sanofi, Servier, Pfizer, Takeda/Lundbeck, Tesaro; receiving honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, MSD Oncology, Merck Serono, GlaxoSmithKline, Roche/Genentech, Sanofi, Seagen, Servier DMC member role: Inspirna; and travel and/or accommodation expenses from Bristol Myers Squibb, MSD Oncology, Takeda and Servier.&#xa0;All other authors report no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41903302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2026.116694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0959-8049(26)00474-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>