<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41667544</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A scalable hybrid framework for boosting customer experience and operational efficiency in e-commerce.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8042</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37437-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid growth of e-commerce has highlighted the need for enhanced customised services and operational efficiency. The presented research presents a novel hybrid framework that combines Collaborative Filtering (CF), Matrix Factorisation (MF), and Reinforcement Learning (RL) to enhance the consumer experience and streamline backend operations. By leveraging historical data, this approach provides a dynamic and adaptive system that does not rely on real-time data. While CF and MF are effective at creating personalised recommendations, RL introduces adaptive pricing strategies that take into account market demand and competitor actions, outperforming static models. In addition, Natural Language Processing (NLP) is used to analyse customer feedback, providing sentiment insights that improve customer service. AI-powered automation also optimises supply chain management by improving inventory forecasting, lowering costs, and increasing efficiency. Experimental results on the Retailrocket, Instacart, and Amazon Reviews datasets demonstrate that the hybrid model outperforms traditional approaches. On Retailrocket, the model outperformed baseline models by converting 19.1% and retaining 28.5% of customers. Profitability increased by 6.3%, while the model reduced RMSE to 1.05 and MAE to 0.27 on Retailrocket. These findings show the framework&#x2019;s ability to improve both personalised recommendations and business operations, making it a scalable solution for e-commerce platforms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Haowei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Vocational College of Industry &amp; Engineering , Pingxiang, 337099, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Business , SEGi University , 9, Jalan Teknologi, Pju 5 Kota Damansara, 47810, Petaling Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Farah Raihana</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Business , SEGi University , 9, Jalan Teknologi, Pju 5 Kota Damansara, 47810, Petaling Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia. farahri@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Weihang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Vocational College of Industry &amp; Engineering , Pingxiang, China, 337099.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Vocational College of Industry &amp; Engineering , Pingxiang, China, 337099.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Tarak</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence &amp; Data Science , Koneru Lakshmaiah Education Foundation , Vaddeswaram, Guntur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Yogesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering , Koneru Lakshmaiah Education Foundation , Vaddeswaram, Guntur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lilhore</LastName><ForeName>Umesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>UK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Galgotias University, Greater Noida, UP, India. umeshlilhore@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simaiya</LastName><ForeName>Sarita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Applications, Galgotias University, Greater Noida, UP, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tekeste</LastName><ForeName>Lidia Gosy</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eritrea Institute of Technology Mai-Nefhi College, Himbrti, Mai Nefhi, Eritrea. lidiagosytekeste@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI automation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Collaborative filtering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">E-commerce optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Matrix factorization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Natural language processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reinforcement learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Consent for publication: All authors have reviewed and approved the final manuscript for publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41667544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12957293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37437-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37437-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alti, A. &amp; Lakehal, A. AI-MDD-UX: revolutionizing E-Commerce user experience with generative AI and Model-Driven development. <i>Future Internet</i>. <b>17</b> (4), 180 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fi17040180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos, F. R. et al. Mapping e-commerce trends in the USA: a time series and deep learning approach. <i>J. Market Anal.</i><b>13</b>, 606&#x2013;634. 10.1057/s41270-025-00392-9 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41270-025-00392-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yallamelli, A. R. G., Mamidala, V., Yalla, R. K. M. K. &amp; Mridul, A. H. The optimizing e-commerce behavioral analytics: strategy-driven ensemble blending&#x2014;e-commerce behavioral analytics. <i>Int. J. Adv. Comput. Sci. Eng. Res.</i><b>1</b>(01), 78&#x2013;85 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presskila, X. et al. A Hybrid Learning-Based Q-Commerce Framework Evolving from E-Commerce. In <i>2025 International Conference on Machine Learning and Autonomous Systems</i> (ICMLAS), 295&#x2013;302 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, L. Analysis of product selection strategy for cross-border e-commerce with assistance of artificial intelligence. <i>J. Internet Technol.</i><b>26</b>(1), 111&#x2013;122 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70003/160792642025012601010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, M. K. et al. Recommender Systems in E-Commerce: A Deep Dive into AI-Driven Optimization. In<i> 2025 First International Conference on Advances in Computer Science, Electrical, Electronics, and Communication Technologies</i> (CE2CT), 1392&#x2013;1398 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaji, T. K., Bablani, A., Sreeja, S. R. &amp; Misra, H. TOPS: A framework for trusted opinion analysis of product reviews using hybrid deep learning based D2CL filter. <i>Expert Syst.</i><b>42</b>(2), e13765 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exsy.13765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prova, N. Multilingual Emotion Classification in E-Commerce Customer Reviews Using GPT and Deep Learning-Based Meta-Ensemble Model. Available at SSRN 5161505 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahuja, A. &amp; Gupta, M. A Hybrid Framework for E-Commerce Recommendations in Emerging Markets: Leveraging Sentiment Analysis and LLM Embeddings (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Wasilewski, Y. Chawla and E. Pralat, "Enhanced E-Commerce Personalization Through AI-Powered Content Generation Tools," in IEEE Access, vol. 13, pp. 48083-48095. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3550956 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, A. K., Chaturvedi, V., Yadav, J. &amp; Yadav, D. S. Harnessing marketing intelligence and AI to understand consumer behavior in the education sector in smart cities. In <i>Machine Learning and Robotics in Urban Planning and Management</i>, 25&#x2013;48 (IGI Global Scientific Publishing, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, L. Hybrid collaborative recommendation of cross-border e-commerce products based on multidimensional evaluation. <i>Int. J. Inf. Commun. Technol.</i><b>26</b> (1), 102&#x2013;116 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Patel, N. &amp; Gupta, R. Enhancing customer experience with AI-Powered sales assistants: leveraging natural Language processing and reinforcement learning algorithms. <i>Eur. Adv. AI J.</i><b>10</b>(2) (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvasundaram, K., Trivedi, P., Kasireddy, L. C. &amp; Bhanawat, H. Artificial intelligence in E-commerce and banking: enhancing customer experience and fraud prevention. <i>Artif. Intell.</i><b>5</b>, 1 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. R. et al. Deep Learning for Customer Relationship Management in E-commerce. In <i>2024 International Congress on Human-Computer Interaction, Optimization and Robotic Applications</i> (HORA), 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V. S. &amp; Metta, S. AI-powered Customer Service: The Role of Chatbots in Enhancing E-commerce Interactions. In <i>Navigating Data Science in the Age of AI: Exploring Possibilities of Generative Intelligence</i> 67&#x2013;82 (Emerald Publishing Limited, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomar, N., Sahu, K., Kumar, V. &amp; Srivastava, A. AI Integrated Recommender System for Improving e-commerce Experience. In <i>2025 IEEE 14th International Conference on Communication Systems and Network Technologies</i> (CSNT), 630&#x2013;635 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, A. Knowledge-Driven hybrid models for E-Commerce recommendations and privacy. <i>Ubiquitous Technol. J.</i><b>1</b> (1), 1&#x2013;9 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.71346/utj.v1i1.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si, Z., Ali, D. A., Rosli, R. B., Bhaumik, A. &amp; Ghosh, A. Application of autonomous intelligent customer behavior prediction model based on deep learning in retail marketing strategy optimization. <i>Edelweiss Appl. Sci. Technol.</i><b>9</b> (3), 584&#x2013;598 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55214/25768484.v9i3.5256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Patel, N. &amp; Gupta, R. Optimizing product upselling strategies using reinforcement learning and natural language processing algorithms. <i>Eur. Adv. AI J.</i><b>11</b>(9) (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalusivalingam, A. K., Sharma, A., Patel, N. &amp; Singh, V. Leveraging neural networks and collaborative filtering for enhanced AI-driven personalized marketing campaigns. <i>Int. J. AI ML</i><b>1</b>(2) (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatchalee, P. Coopetition analysis between JD and Tmall in China&#x2019;s e-commerce landscape: A hybrid thematic-latent Dirichlet Allocation Approach. <i>Adv. Artif. Intell. Mach. Learn.</i><b>5</b>(2), 206 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, Q. Deep learning in predicting consumer purchase intentions. In <i>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Signal Processing, Computer Networks and Communications</i>, 525&#x2013;530 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retailrocket recommender system dataset.&#xa0;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/retailrocket/ecommerce-dataset</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Instacart Dataset.&#xa0;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/yasserh/instacart-online-grocery-basket-analysis-dataset</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amazon product reviews dataset. https://jmcauley.ucsd.edu/data/amazon/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan, R. &amp; Sabari, A. Deepsentimodels: A novel hybrid deep learning model for an effective analysis of ensembled sentiments in e-commerce and s-commerce platforms. <i>Cybernetics Syst.</i><b>54</b> (4), 526&#x2013;549 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01969722.2022.2148510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, S., Sharma, A. &amp; Iyer, S. Optimizing sales funnels using reinforcement learning and predictive analytics techniques in AI. <i>Int. J. AI Advancements</i>. <b>10</b>, 1 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer, D., Sharma, D., Singh, N. &amp; Patel, S. Enhancing digital advertising through AI-powered personalization: leveraging reinforcement learning and collaborative filtering algorithms. <i>Int. J. AI ML Innovations</i><b>11</b>, 8 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, P. E-commerce products recognition based on a deep learning architecture: theory and implementation. <i>Future Generation Comput. Syst.</i><b>125</b>, 672&#x2013;676 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.future.2021.06.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabi, N. et al. Unleashing deep learning: transforming E-commerce profit prediction with CNNs. <i>J. Bus. Manage. Stud.</i><b>6</b>(2), 126&#x2013;131 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32996/jbms.2024.6.2.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L. Product advertising recommendation in e-commerce based on deep learning and distributed expression. <i>Electron. Commer. Res.</i><b>20</b> (2), 321&#x2013;342 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10660-020-09411-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Y., Shao, Y. &amp; Zhang, H. Study on early warning of E-commerce enterprise financial risk based on deep learning algorithm. <i>Electron. Commer. Res.</i><b>22</b> (1), 21&#x2013;36 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10660-020-09454-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilhore, U. K., Simaiya, S., Prasad, D. &amp; Verma, D. K. Hybrid weighted random forests method for prediction &amp; classification of online buying customers. <i>J. Inform. Technol. Manage.</i><b>13</b> (2), 245&#x2013;259 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi, N. K., Simaiya, S., Lilhore, U. K. &amp; Sharma, S. K. An efficient credit card fraud detection model based on machine learning methods. <i>Int. J. Adv. Sci. Technol.</i><b>29</b>(5), 3414&#x2013;3424 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, M., Kumar, R., Madhavi, S. &amp; Rani, U. Survey paper on artificial intelligence in retail and e-commerce. <i>Int. J. Emerg. Technol. Eng. Res.</i><b>8</b>(2) (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Learning Self-Growth Maps for Fast and Accurate Imbalanced Streaming Data Clustering, <i>IEEE Trans. Neural Networks Learn. Syst.</i>, <b>36</b>, 9, 16049&#x2013;16061, Sept. 10.1109/TNNLS.2025.3563769 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2025.3563769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40392647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Y. et al. Hierarchical adaptive cross-coupled control of traffic signals and vehicle routes in large&#x2010;scale road network. <i>Comput. -Aided Civ. Infrastruct. Eng.</i><b>40</b>, 5474&#x2013;5493 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/mice.13508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yongsheng, X. Global sustainable supply chain governance, effectiveness of social responsibility, and performance in emergent markets: an exploratory multiple case study. <i>Revista De Administra&#xe7;&#xe3;o De Empresas</i>. <b>65</b> (6), e2024&#x2013;e0587 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s0034-759020250602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin You, S. et al. Comparative hydrologic performance of cascading and distributed green-gray infrastructure: experimental evidence for spatial optimization in urban waterlogging mitigation, <i>J. Hydrol.</i><b>662</b>. 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2025.133979 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B., Zhao, J., Lv, Z. &amp; Yang, P. Diversified personalized recommendation optimization based on mobile data. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>22</b>(4), 2133&#x2013;2139 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2020.3040909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, H., Wang, M., Zhao, P., Xiao, Z. &amp; Dustdar, S. A utility-aware general framework with quantifiable privacy preservation for destination prediction in LBSs. <i>IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw.</i><b>29</b>(5), 2228&#x2013;2241 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNET.2021.3084251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Li, M., Ji, Z., Li, H. &amp; Luo, J. Intelligent productivity transformation: corporate market demand forecasting with the aid of an AI virtual assistant. <i>J. Organ. End. User Comput. (JOEUC)</i><b>36</b>(1), 1&#x2013;27 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van, A. N. T. et al. Exploring work motivation and job effectiveness in Mekong delta&#x2019;s hospitality: A study utilizing partial least squares structural equation modeling. <i>J. Chin. Hum. Resour. Manage.</i><b>15</b>(2), 101&#x2013;112 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>