<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41481444</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interpretable early warnings using machine learning in an online game-experiment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2503493122</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2503493122</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2503493122</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2503493122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Stemming from physics and later applied to other fields such as ecology, the theory of critical transitions suggests that some regime shifts are preceded by statistical early warning signals. Reddit's r/place experiment, a large-scale social game, provides a unique opportunity to test these signals consistently across thousands of subsystems undergoing critical transitions. In r/place, millions of users collaboratively created "compositions", or pixel-art drawings, in which transitions occur when one composition rapidly replaces another. We develop a machine-learning-based early warning system that combines the predictive power of multiple system-specific time series via gradient-boosted decision trees with memory-retaining features. Our method significantly outperforms standard early warning indicators. Trained on the 2022 r/place data, our algorithm detects half of the transitions occurring within 20 min at a false positive rate of just 3.6%. Its performance remains robust when tested on the 2023 r/place event, demonstrating generalizability across different contexts. Using SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) for interpreting the predictions, we investigate the underlying drivers of warnings, which could be relevant to other complex systems, especially online social systems. We reveal an interplay of patterns preceding transitions, such as critical slowing down or speeding up, a lack of innovation or coordination, turbulent histories, and a lack of image complexity. These findings show the potential of machine learning indicators in socio-ecological systems for predicting regime shifts and understanding their dynamics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Falmagne</LastName><ForeName>Guillaume</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6762-3937</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Meadows Environmental Institute, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sociology of Humans and Machines, Research Hubs, Technological University Dublin, Dublin 7 D07 C972, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Stephenson</LastName><ForeName>Anna B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8886-4804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Meadows Environmental Institute, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levin</LastName><ForeName>Simon A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8216-5639</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Meadows Environmental Institute, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collaborative games</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical transitions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early warning signals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">online experiments</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41481444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12773730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2503493122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jackson J. B. C., et al. , Historical overfishing and the recent collapse of coastal ecosystems. Science 293, 629&#x2013;637 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrie B., Frank K. T., Shackell N. L., Leggett W. C., Structure and stability in exploited marine fish communities: Quantifying critical transitions. Fish. Oceanogr. 18, 83&#x2013;101 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagorio C., et al. , Quarantine-generated phase transition in epidemic spreading. Phys. Rev. E 83, 026102 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21405884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orozco-Fuentes S., et al. , Early warning signals in plant disease outbreaks. Ecol. Model. 393, 12&#x2013;19 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandewalle N., Ph Boveroux A., Minguet M Ausloos, The crash of October 1987 seen as a phase transition: Amplitude and universality. Phys. A Stat. Mech. Appl. 255, 201&#x2013;210 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong McKay D. I., et al. , Exceeding 1.5<sup>c</sup><i>irc</i>C global warming could trigger multiple climate tipping points. Science
377, eabn7950 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36074831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place. https://www.reddit.com/r/place/. Accessed 13 December 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Armstrong, &#x201c;Coordination in a peer production platform: A study of Reddit&#x2019;s /r/place experiment,&#x201d; Master&#x2019;s thesis, University of Waterloo (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappaz J., Catasta M., West R., Aberer K., Latent structure in collaboration: The case of reddit r/place. Proc. Int. AAAI Conf. Web Soc. Media 12, 261&#x2013;269 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Vachher, Z. Levonian, H. F. Cheng, S. Yarosh, &#x201c;Understanding community-level conflicts through reddit r/place&#x201d; in <i>Conference Companion Publication of the 2020 on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing, CSCW&#x2019;20 Companion</i> (Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 2020), pp. 401&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litherland K. T., M&#xf8;rch A. I., Instruction vs. emergence on r/place: Understanding the growth and control of evolving artifacts in mass collaboration. Comput. Hum. Behav. 122, 106845 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Israeli, O. Tsur, With Flying Colors: Predicting Community Success in Large-scale Collaborative Campaigns. <i>Proc. ICWSM</i>
<b>18</b>, 691&#x2013;703 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller T. F., Winters J., Compression in cultural evolution: Homogeneity and structure in the emergence and evolution of a large-scale online collaborative art project. PLoS One 13, e0202019 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6124739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30183760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wu, A. Silva, Large-scale collective dynamics in the three iterations of the Reddit r/place experiment. arXiv [Preprint] (2024). 10.48550/arXiv.2408.13236 (Accessed 15 December 2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2408.13236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botelho M. J. C., Oliveira H. C., &#x201c;Art as an expanded field: The case of the r/place social experiment&#x201d; in <i>ArtsIT, Interactivity and Game Creation</i>, A. L. Brooks, Ed. (Springer Nature, Switzerland, Cham, 2024), pp. 123&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wissel C., A universal law of the characteristic return time near thresholds. Oecologia 65, 101&#x2013;107 (1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28312117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Nes E. H., Scheffer M., Slow recovery from perturbations as a generic indicator of a nearby catastrophic shift. Am. Nat. 169, 738&#x2013;747 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer M., et al. , Early-warning signals for critical transitions. Nature 461, 53&#x2013;59 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettiger C., Ross N., Hastings A., Early warning signals: The charted and uncharted territories. Theor. Ecol. 6, 255&#x2013;264 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettiger C., Hastings A., From patterns to predictions. Nature 493, 157&#x2013;158 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter S. R., et al. , Early warnings of regime shifts: A whole-ecosystem experiment. Science 332, 1079&#x2013;1082 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai L., Vorselen D., Korolev K. S., Gore J., Generic indicators for loss of resilience before a tipping point leading to population collapse. Science 336, 1175&#x2013;1177 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22654061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dakos V., et al. , Methods for detecting early warnings of critical transitions in time series illustrated using simulated ecological data. PLoS One 7, e41010 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22815897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Levin, G. I. Hagstrom, &#x201c;Phase transitions and the theory of early warning indicators for critical transitions&#x201d; in <i>How Worlds Collapse</i>, M. Centeno, P. Callahan, P. Larcey, T. Patterson, Eds. (Routledge, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe9;fi S., Dakos V., Scheffer M., Van Nes E. H., Rietkerk M., Early warning signals also precede non-catastrophic transitions. Oikos 122, 641&#x2013;648 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettiger C., Hastings A., No early warning signals for stochastic transitions: Insights from large deviation theory. Proc. R. Soc. B Biol. Sci. 280, 20131372 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3730602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie P., Sieber J., Early-warning indicators for rate-induced tipping. Chaos Interdiscip. J. Nonlinear Sci. 26, 093116 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27781451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titus M., Watson J., Critical speeding up as an early warning signal of stochastic regime shifts. Theor. Ecol. 13, 449&#x2013;457 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Pomeau, M. L. Berre, Critical speed-up vs. critical slow-down: A new kind of relaxation oscillation with application to stick-slip phenomena. arXiv [Preprint] (2011). 10.48550/arXiv.1107.3331 (Accessed 15 December 2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1107.3331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gietka K., Squeezing by critical speeding up: Applications in quantum metrology. Phys. Rev. A 105, 042620 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George S. V., Kachhara S., Ambika G., Early warning signals for critical transitions in complex systems. Phys. Scripta 98, 072002 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunderling N., et al. , How motifs condition critical thresholds for tipping cascades in complex networks: Linking micro- to macro-scales. Chaos Interdiscip. J. Nonlinear Sci. 30, 043129 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32357654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suweis S., D&#x2019;Odorico P., Early warning signs in social-ecological networks. PLoS One 9, e101851 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4094384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25013901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Patterson D., Levin S. A., Wang J., Non-equilibrium early-warning signals for critical transitions in ecological systems. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 120, e2218663120 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36689655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., O&#x2019;Dea E. B., Drake J. M., Epureanu B. I., Eigenvalues of the covariance matrix as early warning signals for critical transitions in ecological systems. Sci. Rep. 9, 2572 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30796264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer M., et al. , Anticipating critical transitions. Science 338, 344&#x2013;348 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23087241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings A., et al. , Transient phenomena in ecology. Science 361, eaat6412 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30190378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien D. A., et al. , EWSmethods: An R package to forecast tipping points at the community level using early warning signals, resilience measures, and machine learning models. Ecography 2023, e06674 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J., Kim P., Choi J., Kim P., Early warning for critical transitions using machine-based predictability. AIMS Math. 7, 20313&#x2013;20327 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi D., Majda A. J., Using machine learning to predict extreme events in complex systems. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 117, 52&#x2013;59 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31871152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett T. S., Rohani P., Dynamical footprints enable detection of disease emergence. PLoS Biol. 18, e3000697 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7239390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32433658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassia M., De Domenico M., Mangioni G., Machine learning dismantling and early-warning signals of disintegration in complex systems. Nat. Commun. 12, 5190 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34465786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bury T. M., et al. , Deep learning for early warning signals of tipping points. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 118, e2106140118 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34544867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb S., Sidheekh S., Clements C. F., Krishnan N. C., Dutta P. S., Machine learning methods trained on simple models can predict critical transitions in complex natural systems. R. Soc. Open Sci. 9, 211475 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35223058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dylewsky D., et al. , Universal early warning signals of phase transitions in climate systems. J. R. Soc. Interface 20, 20220562 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10072946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Miry et al. , Deep learning for disease outbreak prediction: A robust early warning signal for transcritical bifurcations. arXiv [Preprint] (2025). 10.48550/arXiv.2501.07764 (Accessed 15 December 2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2501.07764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., et al. , Early predictor for the onset of critical transitions in networked dynamical systems. Phys. Rev. X 14, 031009 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapak L., Hamidi O., Fathian M., Karami M., Comparative evaluation of time series models for predicting influenza outbreaks: Application of influenza-like illness data from sentinel sites of healthcare centers in Iran. BMC Res. Notes 12, 353 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6591835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31234938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., et al. , Machine learning based early warning system enables accurate mortality risk prediction for COVID-19. Nat. Commun. 11, 5033 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland S. L., et al. , Early prediction of circulatory failure in the intensive care unit using machine learning. Nat. Med. 26, 364&#x2013;373 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Kobylarz Ribeiro <i>et al</i>., &#x201c;A machine learning early warning system: Multicenter validation in Brazilian hospitals in 2020&#x201d; in <i>2020 IEEE 33rd International Symposium on Computer-Based Medical Systems (CBMS)</i> (IEEE, 2020), pp. 321&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samitas A., Kampouris E., Kenourgios D., Machine learning as an early warning system to predict financial crisis. Int. Rev. Financ. Anal. 71, 101507 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my S., Gautier V., Rondeau F., Early warning system for currency crises using long short-term memory and gated recurrent unit neural networks. J. Forecast. 43, 1235&#x2013;1262 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., et al. , &#x201c;Data-driven power system collapse predicting using critical slowing down indicators&#x201d; in <i>2018 International Conference on Power System Technology (POWERCON)</i> (IEEE, Guangzhou, 2018), pp. 1879&#x2013;1884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassetter A., Cotilla-Sanchez E., Kim J., &#x201c;Using critical slowing down features to enhance performance of artificial neural networks for time-domain power system data&#x201d; in <i>2021 IEEE 9th International Conference on Smart Energy Grid Engineering (SEGE)</i> (IEEE, Oshawa, ON, Canada, 2021), pp. 117&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudin C., Stop explaining black box machine learning models for high stakes decisions and use interpretable models instead. Nat. Mach. Intell. 1, 206&#x2013;215 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Lundberg, S. I. Lee, &#x201c;A unified approach to interpreting model predictions&#x201d; in <i>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</i> (Curran Associates, Inc., 2017). vol. 30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Ghadami A., Epureanu B. I., Practical guide to using Kendall&#x2019;s <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mi>&#x3c4;</mml:mi></mml:math> in the context of forecasting critical transitions. R. Soc. Open Sci.
9, 211346 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35911200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Haagmans, Place Atlas Initiative. https://place-atlas.stefanocoding.me/ (Accessed 13 December 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martiniani S., Chaikin P. M., Levine D., Quantifying hidden order out of equilibrium. Phys. Rev. X 9, 011031 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisoi A. K., Mishra J., On calculation of fractal dimension of images. Pattern Recognit. Lett. 22, 631&#x2013;637 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Chen, C. Guestrin, &#x201c;XGBoost: A scalable tree boosting system&#x201d; in <i>Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</i> (Association for Computing Machinery, 2016), pp. 785&#x2013;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;kitie T., Hanson J., Damman S., Wardeberg M., Digital innovation&#x2019;s contribution to sustainability transitions. Technol. Soc. 73, 102255 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tainter J., The Collapse of Complex Societies (Cambridge Univ. Press, 1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascare&#xf1;o A., Critical transitions in ecosystems and society. The contribution of sociological systems theory to the analysis of socio-environmental transformations. Front. Sociol. 6, 763453 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May R. M., Simple mathematical models with very complicated dynamics. Nature 261, 459&#x2013;467 (1976).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">934280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettiger C., Batt R., Bifurcation or state tipping: Assessing transition type in a model trophic cascade. J. Math. Biol. 80, 143&#x2013;155 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake J. M., Early warning signals of stochastic switching. Proc. R. Soc. B Biol. Sci. 280, 20130686 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3730582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettiger C., Hastings A., Early warning signals and the prosecutor&#x2019;s fallacy. Proc. R. Soc. B Biol. Sci. 279, 4734&#x2013;4739 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashwin P., Wieczorek S., Vitolo R., Cox P., Tipping points in open systems: Bifurcation, noise-induced and rate-dependent examples in the climate system. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 370, 1166&#x2013;1184 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22291228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canny J., A computational approach to edge detection. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. PAMI&#x2013;8, 679&#x2013;698 (1986).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21869365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. B. Stephenson, G. Falmagne, S. Levin, Figure data for &#x201c;Interpretable early warnings using machine learning in an online game-experiment.&#x201d; Zenodo. 10.5281/zenodo.14968895. Deposited 4 March 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.14968895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12773730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41481444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Stephenson, r-place-emergence. Github. https://github.com/AnnieStephenson/r-place-emergence/tree/EWSpaper. Deposited 28 November 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>