<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41605848</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-6598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of traumatic stress</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Stress</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Measuring resilience using language modeling: A computational approach to observing resilience.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jts.70046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We developed resilience using language modeling (ReLM) to measure resilience in language through a novel natural language processing approach called archetype analysis. Our model conceptualizes resilience as a process of maintaining healthy functioning after an adverse event. ReLM is theoretically synthesized through nine facets of resilience reviewed from various sources as reflected in language that captures its dynamic capacity: optimism, sense of social support, emotional maturity, uncertainty tolerance, flexible mindset, coping toolkit, cognitive reappraisal, belief in a higher power, and continued activities of daily living. ReLM uses a language model to embed language in a semantic space, with cosine similarity to each facet's prototype statements calculated to quantify a theoretically derived facet score. We applied ReLM to 1,859 voicemails collected from 211 responders to the September 11, 2001, World Trade Center terrorist attacks. Principal component analysis on training and test sets identified a single latent factor from the facet scores, &#x3bb;&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.02 (56% variance explained), and measurement invariance testing confirmed scalar invariance across training and test subsets, &#x394;&#x3c7;<sup>2</sup>(8)&#xa0;=&#xa0;8.89, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;.352, indicating ReLM scores reflected the same underlying construct in both sets. A one-way analysis of variance showed significant differences in posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) symptom trajectories across resilience quartiles, F(3, 169)&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.18, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;.002, with high resilience showing the largest improvements in PTSD after 4 years (M&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.212). Using an archetype-based language model, ReLM offers a theoretically grounded approach to measuring resilience through natural language, capturing psychological processes in narratives, and enabling dynamic assessment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 International Society for Traumatic Stress Studies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahwish</LastName><ForeName>Syeda</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Public Health, Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyd</LastName><ForeName>Ryan L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, School of Behavioral and Brain Sciences, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varadarajan</LastName><ForeName>Vasudha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotov</LastName><ForeName>Roman</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luft</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>H Andrew</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clouston</LastName><ForeName>Sean A P</ForeName><Initials>SAP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6124-0329</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Public Health, Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family, Population, and Preventive Medicine, Renaissance School of Medicine at Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AA028032</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 OH011321</GrantID><Acronym>OH</Acronym><Agency>NIOSH CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG049953</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Trauma Stress</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8809259</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9867</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41605848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.70046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association. (2013). Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders (5th ed.). https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.books.9780890425596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Legion Auxiliary Unit (Fertile, Minnesota)., Aagenes, D. F., &amp; Larson, C. (1942). Personal narrative: Donald Frederick Aagenes collection. Library of Congress. https://www.loc.gov/item/afc2001001.44002/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baby Girl Nay Nay. (2023, June 24). The most emotional moment of my life | Losing my mother [Video]. YouTube. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XKE4_i5DzcQ</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blevins, C. A., Weathers, F. W., Davis, M. T., Witte, T. K., &amp; Domino, J. L. (2015). The Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for DSM&#x2010;5 (PCL&#x2010;5): Development and initial psychometric evaluation. Journal of Traumatic Stress, 28(6), 489&#x2013;498. https://doi.org/10.1002/jts.22059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno, G. A. (2004). Loss, trauma, and human resilience: Have we underestimated the human capacity to thrive after extremely aversive events? The American Psychologist, 59(1), 20&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.1037/0003&#x2010;066X.59.1.20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno, G. A. (2021). The resilience paradox. European Journal of Psychotraumatology, 12(1), Article 1942642. https://doi.org/10.1080/20008198.2021.1942642</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno, G. A., Chen, S., &amp; Galatzer&#x2010;Levy, I. R. (2023). Resilience to potential trauma and adversity through regulatory flexibility. Nature Reviews Psychology, 2(11), 663&#x2013;675. https://doi.org/10.1038/s44159&#x2010;023&#x2010;00233&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno, G. A., Galea, S., Bucciarelli, A., &amp; Vlahov, D. (2006). Psychological resilience after disaster: New York City in the aftermath of the September 11th terrorist attack. Psychological Science, 17(3), 181&#x2013;186. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467&#x2010;9280.2006.01682.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno, G. A., Galea, S., Bucciarelli, A., &amp; Vlahov, D. (2007). What predicts psychological resilience after disaster? The role of demographics, resources, and life stress. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 75(5), 671&#x2013;682. https://doi.org/10.1037/0022&#x2010;006X.75.5.671</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boss, P. (2013). Resilience as tolerance for ambiguity. In D. S. Becvar (Ed.), Handbook of family resilience (pp. 285&#x2013;297). Springer Science + Business Media. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;1&#x2010;4614&#x2010;3917&#x2010;2_17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromet, E. J., Hobbs, M. J., Clouston, S. A., Gonzalez, A., Kotov, R., &amp; Luft, B. J. (2016). DSM&#x2010;IV post&#x2010;traumatic stress disorder among World Trade Center responders 11&#x2013;13 years after the disaster of 11 September 2001 (9/11). Psychological medicine, 46(4), 771&#x2013;783. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291715002184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling, G., Cronhamn, S., Lundgren, O., Bogren Svensson, V., &amp; Frid, J. (2023). The evolution of lexical semantics dynamics, directionality, and drift. Frontiers in Communication, 8, Article 1126249. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcomm.2023.1126249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carver, C., Scheier, M., Miller, C. J., &amp; Fulford, D. (2009). Optimism. In C. Snyder &amp; S. Lopez (Eds.), Oxford handbook of positive psychology (2nd ed., pp. 303&#x2013;311). Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Xiao, S., Zhang, P., Luo, K., Lian, D., &amp; Liu, Z. (2024). BGE M3&#x2010;embedding: multi&#x2010;lingual, multi&#x2010;functionality, multi&#x2010;granularity text embeddings through self&#x2010;knowledge distillation. ArXiv. https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, D. A. (2022). Cognitive reappraisal. Cognitive and Behavioral Practice, 29(3), 564&#x2013;566. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbpra.2022.02.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor, K. M., &amp; Davidson, J. R. (2003). Development of a new resilience scale: The Connor&#x2013;Davidson Resilience Scale (CD&#x2010;RISC). Depression and Anxiety, 18(2), 76&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1002/da.10113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denckla, C. A., Cicchetti, D., Kubzansky, L. D., Seedat, S., Teicher, M. H., Williams, D. R., &amp; Koenen, K. C. (2020). Psychological resilience: an update on definitions, a critical appraisal, and research recommendations. European Journal of Psychotraumatology, 11(1), Article 1822064. https://doi.org/10.1080/20008198.2020.1822064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folkman, S., &amp; Moskowitz, J. T. (2004). Coping: pitfalls and promise. Annual Review of Psychology, 55, 745&#x2013;774. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.55.090902.141456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forgeard, M. J. C., &amp; Seligman, M. E. P. (2012). Seeing the glass half full: A review of the causes and consequences of optimism. Pratiques Psychologiques, 18(2), 107&#x2013;120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prps.2012.02.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friborg, O., Hjemdal, O., Rosenvinge, J. H., &amp; Martinussen, M. (2005). A new rating scale for adult resilience: What are the central protective resources behind healthy adjustment? International Journal of Methods in Psychiatric Research, 14(1), 65&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1002/mpr.15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher, M. W., Long, L. J., &amp; Phillips, C. A. (2020). Hope, optimism, self&#x2010;efficacy, and posttraumatic stress disorder: A meta&#x2010;analytic review of the protective effects of positive expectancies. Journal of Clinical Psychology, 76(3), 329&#x2013;355. https://doi.org/10.1002/jclp.22882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow, I., Bengio, Y., &amp; Courville, A. (2016). Deep learning. MIT Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison, H. R., Scott, K. M., Women in Military Service For America Memorial Foundation, Inc., &amp; Reborchuk, M. (1991). Personal narrative: Holly R. Harrison collection. Library of Congress. https://www.loc.gov/item/afc2001001.46660/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homan, S., Gabi, M., Klee, N., Bachmann, S., Moser, A. M., Duri', M., Michel, S., Bertram, A. M., Maatz, A., Seiler, G., Stark, E., &amp; Kleim, B. (2022). Linguistic features of suicidal thoughts and behaviors: A systematic review. Clinical Psychology Review, 95, Article 102161. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2022.102161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James, G., Witten, D., Hastie, T., &amp; Tibshirani, R. (2013). An introduction to statistical learning (Vol. 112, p. 18). Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobson, M. C. (2020). Emotional maturity among adolescents and its importance. Indian Journal of Mental Health, 7(1), 35&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose, R., Matero, M., Sherman, G., Curtis, B., Giorgi, S., Schwartz, H. A., &amp; Ungar, L. H. (2022). Using Facebook language to predict and describe excessive alcohol use. Alcoholism, Clinical and Experimental Research, 46(5), 836&#x2013;847. https://doi.org/10.1111/acer.14807</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julie Dawn Beauty. (2018, January 18). How I got over my divorce to find love &amp; happiness [Video]. YouTube. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=&#x2010;mHAK8GDAAo</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, Y.&#x2010;B., McCosker, A., Kamstra, P., &amp; Farmer, J. (2022). Resilience in web&#x2010;based mental health communities: Building a resilience dictionary with semiautomatic text analysis. JMIR Formative Research, 6(9), Article e39013. https://doi.org/10.2196/39013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern, M. L., Park, G., Eichstaedt, J. C., Schwartz, H. A., Sap, M., Smith, L. K., &amp; Ungar, L. H. (2016). Gaining insights from social media language: Methodologies and challenges. Psychological Methods, 21(4), 507&#x2013;525. https://doi.org/10.1037/met0000091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjell, O. N., Kjell, K., &amp; Schwartz, H. A. (2024). Beyond rating scales: With targeted evaluation, large language models are poised for psychological assessment. Psychiatry Research, 333, Article 115667. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2023.115667</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs, P., Norcross, J. C., Nicholson, J. M., &amp; Prochaska, J. O. (2018). Stages of change and psychotherapy outcomes: A review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Journal of Clinical Psychology, 74(11), 1964&#x2013;1979. https://doi.org/10.1002/jclp.22683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S., Shakir, A., Koenig, D., &amp; Lipp, J. (2024). Open source strikes bread&#x2014;new fluffy embeddings model. Mixedbread AI. https://www.mixedbread.ai/blog/mxbai&#x2010;embed&#x2010;large&#x2010;v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Ott, M., Goyal, N., Du, J., Joshi, M., Chen, D., Levy, O., Lewis, M., Zettlemoyer, L., &amp; Stoyanov, V. (2019). RoBERTa: A robustly optimized BERT pretraining approach. ArXiv. https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.11692</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen, T., Karstoft, K. I., Bertelsen, M., &amp; Andersen, S. B. (2014). Postdeployment suicidal ideations and trajectories of posttraumatic stress disorder in Danish soldiers: A 3&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up of the USPER study. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry, 75(9), 994&#x2013;1000. https://doi.org/10.4088/JCP.13m08910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangalik, S., Eichstaedt, J. C., Giorgi, S., Mun, J., Ahmed, F., Gill, G., Ganesan, A. V., Clouston, S. A. P., Pinjari, O., Nobles, A. L., Bellisario, G., Fineberg, S., Lee, M., Curtis, B., Ungar, L. H., &amp; Schwartz, H. A. (2024). Robust language&#x2010;based mental health assessments in time and space through social media. NPJ Digital Medicine, 7(1), Article 109. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41746&#x2010;024&#x2010;01100&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann, F. D., Waszczuk, M. A., Clouston, S. A., Feltman, S., Ruggero, C. J., Marx, B. P., Schwartz, J. E., Bromet, E. J., Luft, B. J., &amp; Kotov, R. (2025). A 20&#x2010;year longitudinal cohort study of post&#x2010;traumatic stress disorder in World Trade Center responders. Nature Mental Health, 3(7), 789&#x2013;802. https://doi.org/10.1038/s44220&#x2010;025&#x2010;00419&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masten, A. S. (2014). Global perspectives on resilience in children and youth. Child Development, 85(1), 6&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.12205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matero, M., Giorgi, S., Curtis, B., Ungar, L. H., &amp; Schwartz, H. A. (2023). Opioid death projections with AI&#x2010;based forecasts using social media language. NPJ Digital Medicine, 6(1), Article 35. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41746&#x2010;023&#x2010;00776&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesman, E., Vreeker, A., &amp; Hillegers, M. (2021). Resilience and mental health in children and adolescents: An update of the recent literature and future directions. Current Opinion in Psychiatry, 34(6), 586&#x2013;592. https://doi.org/10.1097/YCO.0000000000000741</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen, J. (2023). Psychological resilience: Connecting contemporary psychology to ancient practical philosophy. Theory &amp; Psychology, 33(3), 366&#x2013;385. https://doi.org/10.1177/09593543231153820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oltmanns, J. R., Schwartz, H. A., Ruggero, C., Son, Y., Miao, J., Waszczuk, M., Clouston, S. A. P., Bromet, E. J., Luft, B. J., &amp; Kotov, R. (2021). Artificial intelligence language predictors of two&#x2010;year trauma&#x2010;related outcomes. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 143, 239&#x2013;245. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2021.09.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennebaker, J. W., Francis, M. E., &amp; Booth, R. J. (2001). Linguistic inquiry and word count: LIWC 2001. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson, C., &amp; Steen, T. (2009). Optimistic explanatory style. In C. Snyder &amp; S. Lopez (Eds.), Oxford handbook of positive psychology (2nd ed., pp. 313&#x2013;321). Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199396511.013.70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzak, R. H., Feder, A., Singh, R., Schechter, C. B., Bromet, E. J., Katz, C. L., Reissman, D. B., Ozbay, F., Sharma, V., Crane, M., Harrison, D., Herbert, R., Levin, S. M., Luft, B. J., Moline, J. M., Stellman, J. M., Udasin, I. G., Landrigan, P. J., &amp; Southwick, S. M. (2013). Trajectories of PTSD risk and resilience in World Trade Center responders: An 8&#x2010;year prospective cohort study. Psychological Medicine, 44(1), 205&#x2013;219. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0033291713000597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenburg, L. J., Velikonja, T., Pietrzak, R. H., DePierro, J., de Haan, L., Todd, A. C., Dasaro, C. R., Feder, A., &amp; Velthorst, E. (2024). Perceived social support and longitudinal trajectories of depression and anxiety in World Trade Center responders. Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology, 59(8), 1413&#x2013;1424. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127&#x2010;023&#x2010;02569&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior, D. F., Dent, Jamie S., Stories of Service&#x2013;San Diego., Smith, C., T, A., &amp; Unknown. (1944). Personal narrative: Donald F. Prior collection. Library of Congress. https://www.loc.gov/item/afc2001001.47925</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimers, N., &amp; Gurevych, I. (2019). Sentence&#x2010;BERT: Sentence embeddings using Siamese BERT&#x2010;networks. Proceedings of the 2019 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and the 9th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&#x2010;IJCNLP; pp. 3980&#x2013;3990). https://doi.org/10.18653/v1/d19&#x2010;1410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutter, M. (2006). Implications of resilience concepts for scientific understanding. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1094(1), 1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1196/annals.1376.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassenberg, K., Winter, K., Becker, D., Ditrich, L., Scholl, A., &amp; Moskowitz, G. B. (2022). Flexibility mindsets: Reducing biases that result from spontaneous processing. European Review of Social Psychology, 33(1), 171&#x2013;213. https://doi.org/10.1080/10463283.2021.1959124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seneca. (2008). Dialogues and essays (J. Davie, Trans.). Oxford University Press. (Original work published ca. 37&#x2013;62).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster, M. A., Stein, B. D., Jaycox, L. H., Collins, R. L., Marshall, G. N., Elliott, M. N., Zhou, A. J., Kanouse, D. E., Morrison, J. L., &amp; Berry, S. H. (2001). A national survey of stress reactions after the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks. New England Journal of Medicine, 345(20), 1507&#x2013;1512. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejm200111153452024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, B. W., Dalen, J., Wiggins, K., Tooley, E., Christopher, P., &amp; Bernard, J. (2008). The Brief Resilience Scale: Assessing the ability to bounce back. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 15(3), 194&#x2013;200. https://doi.org/10.1080/10705500802222972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son, Y., Clouston, S. A. P., Kotov, R., Eichstaedt, J. C., Bromet, E. J., Luft, B. J., &amp; Schwartz, H. A. (2023). World Trade Center responders in their own words: Predicting PTSD symptom trajectories with AI&#x2010;based language analyses of interviews. Psychological Medicine, 53(3), 918&#x2013;926. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291721002294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, K., Tan, X., Qin, T., Lu, J., &amp; Liu, T.&#x2010;Y. (2020). MPNet: Masked and permuted pre&#x2010;training for language understanding. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 33, 16857&#x2013;16867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southwick, S. M., Bonanno, G. A., Masten, A. S., Panter&#x2010;Brick, C., &amp; Yehuda, R. (2014). Resilience definitions, theory, and challenges: Interdisciplinary perspectives. European Journal of Psychotraumatology, 5(1), Article 25338. https://doi.org/10.3402/ejpt.v5.25338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, N. R., Dickstein, B. D., Schuster, J., Litz, B. T., &amp; Resick, P. A. (2012). Trajectories of response to treatment for posttraumatic stress disorder. Behavior Therapy, 43(4), 790&#x2013;800. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.beth.2012.04.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanyi, R. A. (2002). Towards clarification of the meaning of spirituality. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 39(5), 500&#x2013;509. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365&#x2010;2648.2002.02315.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varadarajan, V., Lahnala, A., Ganesan, A. V., Dey, G., Mangalik, S., Bucur, A. M., Soni, N., Rao, R., Lanning, K., Vallejo, I., Flek, L., Schwartz, H. A., Welch, C., &amp; Boyd, R. (2024). Archetypes and entropy: Theory&#x2010;driven extraction of evidence for suicide risk. In A. Yates, B. Desmet, E. Prud'hommeaux, A. Zirikly, S. Bedrick, S. McAvaney, K. Bar, M. Ireland, &amp; Y. Ophir (Eds.), Proceedings of the 9th Workshop on Computational Linguistics and Clinical Psychology (CLPsych 2024; pp. 278&#x2013;291). Association for Computational Linguistics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dijk, W., Schatschneider, C., Al Otaiba, S., &amp; Hart, S. A. (2022). Assessing measurement invariance across multiple groups: When is fit good enough? Educational and Psychological Measurement, 82(3), 482&#x2013;505. https://doi.org/10.1177/00131644211023567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson, P. J., Brymer, M. J., &amp; Bonanno, G. A. (2011). Postdisaster psychological intervention since 9/11. American Psychologist, 66(6), 482&#x2013;494. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0024806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waszczuk, M. A., Ruggero, C., Li, K., Luft, B. J., &amp; Kotov, R. (2019). The role of modifiable health&#x2010;related behaviors in the association between PTSD and respiratory illness. Behaviour Research and Therapy, 115, 64&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brat.2018.10.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weathers, F. W., Litz, B. T., Keane, T. M., Palmier, P. A., Marx, B. P., &amp; Schnurr, P. P. (2013). The PTSD Checklist for DSM&#x2010;5 (PCL&#x2010;5). https://www.ptsd.va.gov/professional/assessment/adult&#x2010;sr/ptsd&#x2010;checklist.asp</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., He, X., Zhang, H., Ma, Y., Bian, J., &amp; Wu, Y. (2020). Measurement of semantic textual similarity in clinical texts: Comparison of transformer&#x2010;based models. JMIR Medical Informatics, 8(11), Article e19735. https://doi.org/10.2196/19735</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>