<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41411971</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-6750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>207</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environment international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MATES: A tool for appraising the completeness with which a meta-analysis has been reported.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>109935</StartPage><MedlinePgn>109935</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.envint.2025.109935</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0160-4120(25)00686-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Meta-analysis is commonly a core component of systematic reviews and has become an important method to reconcile conflicting findings, increase statistical power, and chart new research directions. However, poor reporting practices make it challenging to evaluate the validity of meta-analyses. Despite the existence of reporting checklists, a specifically designed tool has yet to be developed to appraise the completeness with which a meta-analysis has been reported. To bridge this gap, we introduce the Meta-analysis Appraisal Tool for Environmental Sciences (MATES). To develop MATES, we adapted a Delphi process involving experts in meta-analysis methodologies, researchers with experience in guideline/appraisal tool development, and editors of relevant journals. The Delphi process had five steps, including three workshops (11-16 participants), a survey (193 participants), and a validation task (30 participants). This iterative development process resulted in a 14-item appraisal tool that reflects the environmental science and research syntheses community's consensus on essential elements to appraise the completeness with which a meta-analysis has been reported. Validation across 50 meta-analyses demonstrated that the tool is repeatable (average agreement rate: 88.97&#xa0;%) and time-efficient to implement (17.00&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;12.23&#xa0;min). We also outline guidance for interpreting MATES results, describe its potential applications, and reflect on the development process. The authors provide practical implementation guidance for each MATES item, illustrated with real examples in the supplementary material. We also report an extended development methodology to support reproducibility. Finally, we built created a ShinyApp that includes both a training module and an application tool to enhance the usability of MATES (https://kylemorrisonisshiny99.shinyapps.io/MATES_shiny/). Overall, MATES provides authors, readers, stakeholders, and editors with a reliable and accessible tool for appraising the completeness with which a meta-analysis in environmental sciences has been reported.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morrison</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. Electronic address: kyle.morrison@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pottier</LastName><ForeName>Patrice</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Division of Ecology and Evolution, Research School of Biology, The Australian National University, Canberra, Australian Capital Territory, Australia. Electronic address: p.pottier@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pollo</LastName><ForeName>Pietro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. Electronic address: pietro_pollo@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ricolfi</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. Electronic address: l.ricolfi@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Coralie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia. Electronic address: coralie.williams@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yefeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; College of Biosystems Engineering and Food Science, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China. Electronic address: yefeng.yang1@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beillouin</LastName><ForeName>Damien</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HortSys, Univ Montpellier, CIRAD, Montpellier, France. Electronic address: beillouin@cirad.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardoso</LastName><ForeName>Simone Jaqueline</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Plankton Ecology, Department of Zoology, Institute of Biology, Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora 36036-900, Brazil. Electronic address: simone.jcardoso@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Ver&#xf3;nica</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MARE - Marine and Environmental Sciences Centre, ARNET - Aquatic Research Network, Department of Life Sciences, University of Coimbra, Cal&#xe7;ada Martim de Freitas, 3000-456 Coimbra, Portugal. Electronic address: veronica@ci.uc.pt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallagher</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada. Electronic address: brian.kenneth.gallagher@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Jelaine L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Natural and Environmental Sciences, Newcastle University, Newcastle upon Tyne, United Kingdom; Institute of Biology, College of Science, University of the Philippines, Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines. Electronic address: jelainegan21@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Guang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Statistics, School of Public Health, Guangdong Pharmaceutical University, China. Electronic address: haoguang2015@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keikha</LastName><ForeName>Mojtaba</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Social Determinants of Health Research Center, Institute for Futures Studies in Health, Kerman University of Medical Sciences, Kerman, Iran. Electronic address: mr.mojtabakeikha@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozlowsky-Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Betina</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology and Marine Resources, Institute of Biosciences, Federal University of the State of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, RJ 22290-240, Brazi. Electronic address: betinaksuzuki@unirio.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiran Kumara</LastName><ForeName>T M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Agricultural Economics and Policy Research (NIAP), New Delhi 110012, India. Electronic address: kiran.tm@icar.gov.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Latterini</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Dendrology, Polish Academy of Sciences, Parkowa 5, K&#xf3;rnik 62-035, Poland. Electronic address: latterini@man.poznan.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leverkus</LastName><ForeName>Alexandro B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology, University of Granada 18071 Granada, Spain; Laboratory of Ecology (iEcolab), Inter-University Institute for Earth System Research in Andalusia (IISTA), Granada, Spain. Electronic address: leverkus@ugr.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macartney</LastName><ForeName>Erin L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Charles Perkins Centre, School of Life and Environmental Sciences, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia. Electronic address: erin.macartney@sydney.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manrique</LastName><ForeName>Silvina Magdalena</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad de Alcal&#xe1;, Departamento de Geolog&#xed;a, Geograf&#xed;a y Medio Ambiente, A-II km 33.0, 28805 Alcal&#xe1; de Henares, Madrid, Spain. Electronic address: silvina.manrique@uah.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinig</LastName><ForeName>April Robin</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; The Okanagan Institute for Biodiversity, Resilience, and Ecosystem Services, University of British Columbia, Kelowna, British Columbia, Canada. Electronic address: aprilmartinig@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizuno</LastName><ForeName>Ayumi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada. Electronic address: ayumi.mizuno5@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nanayakkara</LastName><ForeName>Shanika</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Dental School, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia; Institute of Dental Research, Westmead Centre for Oral Health, Westmead Hospital, Westmead, Australia. Electronic address: shanika.nanayakkara@sydney.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ntzani</LastName><ForeName>Evangelia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Evidence Synthesis in Health, Brown University School of Public Health, RI, USA; Department of Hygiene and Epidemiology, University of Ioannina School of Medicine, Greece. Electronic address: evangelia_ntzani@brown.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ou&#xe9;draogo</LastName><ForeName>Dakis-Yaoba</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Athens, Greece. Electronic address: dakis.ouedraogo@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pursell</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Medicine and Social Care, Anglia Ruskin University, Chelmsford United Kingdom. Electronic address: edward.purssell@aru.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Department of Agriculture, Agricultural Research Service, Sustainable Water Management Research Unit, Stoneville, MS, USA. Electronic address: zpsimpso@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sleight</LastName><ForeName>Harriet</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environment and Geography, University of York, York, United Kingdom. Electronic address: harriet.sleight@york.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woon</LastName><ForeName>Kok Sin</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carbon Neutrality and Climate Change Thrust, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Guangzhou), China; School of Energy and Chemical Engineering, Xiamen University Malaysia, Malaysia. Electronic address: woonkoksin@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Ziqian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Social Sciences, Stanford University, CA, USA. Electronic address: ziqian.research@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghannad</LastName><ForeName>Mona</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of British Columbia and British Columbia Children's Hospital, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada. Electronic address: mona.ghannad@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grames</LastName><ForeName>Eliza</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Binghamton University, Binghamton, NY, USA. Electronic address: egrames@binghamton.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hennessy</LastName><ForeName>Emily Alden</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Recovery Research Institute, Center for Addiction Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA; Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. Electronic address: ehennessy@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>IntHout</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IQ Health, Radboudumc, Nijmegen, the Netherlands. Electronic address: Joanna.intHout@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moher</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Journalology, Clinical Epidemiology Program, Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa, Canada; School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada. Electronic address: dmoher@ohri.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Dea</LastName><ForeName>Rose E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The School of Agriculture, Food and Ecosystem Sciences, University of Melbourne, Parkville, Melbourne, Australia. Electronic address: rose.eleanor.o.dea@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Page</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methods in Evidence Synthesis Unit, School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia. Electronic address: matthew.page@monash.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whaley</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lancaster Environment Centre, Lancaster University, Lancaster, United Kingdom. Electronic address: p.whaley@lancaster.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lagisz</LastName><ForeName>Malgorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada. Electronic address: m.lagisz@unsw.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Shinichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evolution &amp; Ecology Research Centre and the School of Biological, Earth and Environmental Sciences at the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia; Department of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada. Electronic address: snakagaw@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7807270</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0160-4120</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003697" MajorTopicYN="N">Delphi Technique</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Science</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reliability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk of bias</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transparency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triage</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: YY became Associate Editor of Environmental International after submitting this article. Given role as Associate Editor, YY has no involvement in the peer-review of this article and has no access to information regarding its peer-review. We confirm there are no other conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41411971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2025.109935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0160-4120(25)00686-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>