<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41803167</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reconstructing fine-scale 3D wind fields with terrain-informed machine learning.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70562-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Fine-scale near-surface wind field prediction is essential for a wide range of applications. However, most operational and AI-based weather models operate at kilometer-scale resolution, where terrain-induced wind features such as slope jets, flow deflection, and recirculation are systematically averaged out. Here we introduce FuXi-CFD, a machine learning-based framework designed to generate detailed three-dimensional (3D) near-surface wind fields at 30-meter horizontal resolution, using only coarse-resolution atmospheric inputs and high-resolution terrain information. The model is trained on a large-scale dataset generated via computational fluid dynamics (CFD), encompassing a wide range of terrain types and inflow conditions. Although relying only on horizontal wind inputs, FuXi-CFD infers the full 3D wind fields-including latent variables such as vertical velocity and turbulence-related features. It achieves CFD-comparable accuracy while reducing inference time from hours to seconds. Notably, the model also generalizes well to real-world conditions, as demonstrated by consistent performance against independent wind-tower observations. This capability enables real-time wind field reconstruction for terrain-sensitive applications such as wind turbine siting, power forecasting, and wildfire spread modeling.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chensen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2662-1115</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tie</LastName><ForeName>Ruian</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Innovation Institute, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Shihong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Dongqing</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Meteorological Observatory, Nanjing Meteorological Bureau, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Laboratory for AI-Based Earth System Forecasting, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Zixin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6197-0674</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Incubation Institute, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. lihao_lh@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Innovation Institute, Shanghai, China. lihao_lh@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Laboratory for AI-Based Earth System Forecasting, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. lihao_lh@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Academy of Artificial Intelligence for Science, Shanghai, China. lihao_lh@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41803167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70562-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70562-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barthelmie, R. J. &amp; Pryor, S. C. Automated wind turbine wake characterization in complex terrain. Atmos. Meas. Tech. 12, 3463&#x2013;3484 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Y. &amp; Archer, C. L. A hybrid wind-farm parametrization for mesoscale and climate models. Bound. Layer. Meteorol. 168, 469&#x2013;495 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floors, R., Vincent, C. L., Gryning, S.-E., Pe&#xf1;a, A. &amp; Batchvarova, E. The wind profile in the coastal boundary layer: wind lidar measurements and numerical modelling. Bound. Layer. Meteorol. 147, 469&#x2013;491 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linn, R., Winterkamp, J., Edminster, C., Colman, J. J. &amp; Smith, W. S. Coupled influences of topography and wind on wildland fire behaviour. Int. J. Wildland Fire 16, 183&#x2013;195 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veers, P. et al. Grand challenges in the science of wind energy. Science 366, eaau2027 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifton, A., Barber, S., St&#xf6;kl, A., Frank, H. &amp; Karlsson, T. Research challenges and needs for the deployment of wind energy in hilly and mountainous regions. Wind Energy Sci. 7, 2231&#x2013;2254 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y., Chan, P. &amp; Li, Q. Wind characteristics over different terrains. J. Wind Eng. Ind. Aerodyn. 120, 51&#x2013;69 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haiden, T. et al. Evaluation of ecmwf forecasts, including the 2018 upgrade. Tech. Rep. ECMWF Technical Memorandum 831. (European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts, Reading, UK, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, L., Chen, X., Putman, W., Zhou, L. &amp; Chen, J.-H. A scientific description of the gfdl finite-volume cubed-sphere dynamical core. NOAA Tech. Memo. OAR GFDL 1,109 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, D. et al. New generation of multi-scale NWP system (GRAPES): General scientific design. Chin. Sci. Bull. 53, 3433&#x2013;3445 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, R. et al. Learning skillful medium-range global weather forecasting. Science 382, 1416&#x2013;1421 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak, J. et al. Fourcastnet: a global data-driven high-resolution weather model using adaptive Fourier neural operators. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2202.11214 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi, K. et al. Accurate medium-range global weather forecasting with 3d neural networks. Nature 619, 533&#x2013;538 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. et al. Fuxi: a cascade machine learning forecasting system for 15-day global weather forecast. npj Clim. Atmos. Sci. 6, 190 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. et al. A machine learning model that outperforms conventional global subseasonal forecast models. Nat. Commun. 15, 6425 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espeholt, L. et al. Deep learning for twelve hour precipitation forecasts. Nat. Commun. 13, 1&#x2013;10 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price, I. et al. Gencast: diffusion-based ensemble forecasting for medium-range weather. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2312.15796 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersbach, H. et al. The era5 global reanalysis. Q. J. R. Meteorol. Soc. 146, 1999&#x2013;2049 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoof, J. T. Statistical downscaling in climatology. Geogr. Compass 7, 249&#x2013;265 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Garc&#xed;a, F. P., Contreras-de Villar, A. &amp; Mu&#xf1;oz-Perez, J. J. Review of wind models at a local scale: advantages and disadvantages. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 9, 318 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares, P. M. et al. WRF high-resolution dynamical downscaling of era-interim for Portugal. Clim. Dyn. 39, 2497&#x2013;2522 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez, S. et al. Sensitivity analysis of the wrf model: Wind-resource assessment for complex terrain. J. Appl. Meteorol. Climatol. 57, 733&#x2013;753 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goger, B., Rotach, M. W., Gohm, A., Stiperski, I. &amp; Fuhrer, O. Current challenges for numerical weather prediction in complex terrain: Topography representation and parameterizations. In 2016 international conference on high performance computing &amp; simulation (HPCS), 890&#x2013;894 (IEEE, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy, F., Durand, P. &amp; Hedde, T. Downscaling of surface wind forecasts using convolutional neural networks. Nonlinear Process. Geophys. 30, 553&#x2013;570 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A. et al. Windsr: Improving spatial resolution of satellite wind speed through super-resolution. IEEE Access 11, 69486&#x2013;69494 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian, J. et al. Terrawind: a deep learning-based near-surface winds downscaling model for complex terrain region. Geophys. Res. Lett. 51, e2024GL112124 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buster, G., Benton, B. N., Glaws, A. &amp; King, R. N. High-resolution meteorology with climate change impacts from global climate model data using generative machine learning. Nat. Energy 9, 894&#x2013;906 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, P. et al. Efficient super-resolution of near-surface climate modeling using the Fourier neural operator. J. Adv. Modeling Earth Syst. 15, e2023MS003800 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha, S., Benton, B. &amp; Emami, P. On the effectiveness of neural operators at zero-shot weather downscaling. Environ. Data Sci. 4, e21 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, J.-W. &amp; Hsieh, I.-Y. L. Super-resolution wind mapping with deep learning for scalable renewable energy planning. Commun. Earth Environ. 7, 51 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mardani, M. et al. Residual corrective diffusion modeling for km-scale atmospheric downscaling. Commun. Earth Environ. 6, 124 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasi, E., Franch, G. &amp; Cristoforetti, M. Can AI be enabled to perform dynamical downscaling? a latent diffusion model to mimic kilometer-scale cosmo5. 0_clm9 simulations. Geosci. Model Dev. 18, 2051&#x2013;2078 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Gomez, I. et al. Dynamical-generative downscaling of climate model ensembles. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 122, e2420288122 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Toumelin, L. et al. Emulating the adaptation of wind fields to complex terrain with deep learning. Artif. Intell. Earth Syst. 2, e220034 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferziger, J. H. &amp; Peri&#x107;, M.Computational methods for fluid dynamics. 586 (Springer, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karniadakis, G. E., Israeli, M. &amp; Orszag, S. A. High-order splitting methods for the incompressible Navier-Stokes equations. J. Comput. Phys. 97, 414&#x2013;443 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meteodyn. Meteodyn WT - Wind Resource Assessment Software. https://www.meteodyn.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WindSim AS. WindSim - CFD software for wind energy. https://www.windsim.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Envision Energy. Greenwich - Wind Farm Design Platform. https://www.envision-group.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Icos research infrastructure: Atmospheric tower observations. https://data.icos-cp.eu (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Geological Survey. Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) 1 Arc-Second Global. USGS Earth ResourcesObservation and Science (EROS) Center https://doi.org/10.5066/F7PR7TFT (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanaga, D. et al. ESA WorldCover 10 m 2020 v100. Zenodo https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5571936 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasager, C. B. et al. Effective roughness calculated from satellite-derived land cover maps and hedge-information used in a weather forecasting model. Bound.Layer. Meteorol. 109, 227&#x2013;254 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy, A. et al. An image is worth 16x16 words: transformers for image recognition at scale. Preprint at https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>