<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41624650</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2249-4863</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of family medicine and primary care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Family Med Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessing internal disaster preparedness at Security Forces Hospital, Riyadh.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5122</StartPage><EndPage>5131</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5122-5131</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_843_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hospital safety is very important, particularly in preparing for internal disasters such as fires, power outages, and chemical exposures, which can significantly disrupt hospital functions and endanger patients and staff.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to assess the readiness of the Security Forces Hospital in Riyadh to effectively manage internal disasters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional study was conducted to evaluate hospital staff awareness, perception, knowledge, and preparedness regarding internal disasters. Data were collected through a structured survey. The study analyzed associations between awareness levels, work experience, and participation in disaster training programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Results showed that there is a generally high level of awareness, but gaps remained in disaster response training and knowledge of emergency protocols. Arabic-speaking respondents showed lower awareness compared to English speakers, while employees with less than five years of experience were more aware of internal disasters but lacked knowledge of the hospital's emergency plan, with limited planning courses and evacuation drills.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To enhance disaster preparedness, regular evacuation drills, structured training programs, and multilingual educational materials should be implemented. Standardizing emergency information on staff ID cards, improving accessibility to disaster protocols, and increasing awareness campaigns will strengthen overall readiness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wael</LastName><ForeName>Alotaibi M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Disaster Management (MS), Security Forces Hospital, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alotaibi</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah Aedh</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Medicine College, Shaqra University, Shaqra, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Family Med Prim Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610082</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2249-4863</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disaster</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hospital disaster</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preparedness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interests between the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41624650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12858117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_843_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFMPC-14-5122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qzih ES, Ahmad MM. Hospital-based preparedness measures for CBRNE disasters: A systematic review. Environ Health Insights. 2024;18 11786302241288859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11459511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin Shalhoub AA, Khan AA, Alaska YA. Evaluation of disaster preparedness for mass casualty incidents in private hospitals in Central Saudi Arabia. Saudi Med J. 2017;38:302&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5387908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International JC. JCI Hospital Standards. 6th ed. 2018.  [[Last accessed on 2018 Jan 14]].  Available from: https://store.jointcommissioninternational.org/assets/3/7/JCI_Hosp_Standards_6th_STANDARDS_ONLY_14Jan2018.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International JC. Emergency Management Advisory Services 2025.  [[Last accessed on 2021 Jul 1]].  Available from: https://www.jointcommissioninternational.org/what-we-offer/advisory-services/emergency-management/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency FEM. National Preparedness Goal 2025.  Available from: https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/national-preparedness/goal .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Bakshi H, Banerjee A. Fire safety hazards: How safe are our hospitals? Indian J Community Med. 2020;45:104&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6985949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongiovanni I, Leo E, Ritrovato M, Santoro A, Derrico P. Implementation of best practices for emergency response and recovery at a large hospital: A fire emergency case study. Saf Sci. 2017;96:121&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels JP. Venezuelan migrants &#x201c;struggling to survive&#x201d; amid COVID-19. Lancet (London, England) 2020;395:1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K, Kwon HM, Cho S, Kim J, Moon I. Improvements of safety management system in Korean chemical industry after a large chemical accident. J Loss Prev Process Ind. 2016;42:6&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang T, Nguyen C, Tran PN. Physician beware: Severe cyanide toxicity from amygdalin tablets ingestion. Case Rep Emerg Med 2017. 2017:4289527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5587935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahyuni I, Ismail N, Izziah I, editors. Hospital fire safety improvement effort (study case Rumah Sakit Ibu dan Anak, Banda Aceh) IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering, IOP Publishing. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyerkaufer ML, Lima FS, Gon&#xe7;alves MB. Public and private partnership in disaster risk management. Jamba. 2016;8:277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6014036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29955296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skryabina E, Reedy G, Aml&#xf4;t R, Jaye P, Riley P. What is the value of health emergency preparedness exercises? A scoping review study. Int J Disaster Risk Reduct. 2017;21:274&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achora S, Kamanyire JK. Disaster preparedness: Need for inclusion in undergraduate nursing education. Sultan Qaboos Univ Med J. 2016;16:e15&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4746037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26909207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vugrin ED, Verzi SJ, Finley PD, Turnquist MA, Griffin AR, Ricci KA, et al. Modeling evacuation of a hospital without electric power. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2015;30:279&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25868416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorram-Manesh A, Phattharapornjaroen P, Mortelmans LJ, Goniewicz K, Verheul M, S&#xf6;rensen JL, et al. Current perspectives and concerns facing hospital evacuation: The results of a pilot study and literature review. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2022;16:650&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33531099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohba T, Tanigawa K, Liutsko L. Evacuation after a nuclear accident: Critical reviews of past nuclear accidents and proposal for future planning. Environ Int. 2021;148:106379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowing JR, Walker KN, Elmer SL, Cummings EA. Disaster preparedness among health professionals and support staff: What is effective? An integrative literature review. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2017;32:321&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28300525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman R, Lathabhai H, Mandal S, Kumar C, Nedungadi P. Contribution of business research to sustainable development goals: Bibliometrics and science mapping analysis. Sustainability. 2023;15:12982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naser WN, Saleem HB. Emergency and disaster management training;knowledge and attitude of Yemeni health professionals-A cross-sectional study. BMC Emerg Med. 2018;18:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6091203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ncube A, Chimenya GNT. Hospital disaster emergency preparedness: A study of Onandjokwe Lutheran hospital, Northern Namibia. Afri Saf Promot J Inj Viol Prev. 2016;14:1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nofal A, Alfayyad I, Khan A, Al Aseri Z, Abu-Shaheen A. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices of emergency department staff towards disaster and emergency preparedness at tertiary health care hospital in central Saudi Arabia. Saudi Med J. 2018;39:1123&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6274652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30397712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonneborn O, Miller C, Head L, Cross R. Disaster education and preparedness in the acute care setting: A cross sectional survey of operating theatre nurse's disaster knowledge and education. Nurse Educ Today. 2018;65:23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29524836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alruwaili A, Islam S, Usher K. Disaster Preparedness in hospitals in the middle east: An integrative literature review. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2019;13:806&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30739631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insider B. Surfside Florida Building Collapse Causes: Structural Engineers' Insights 2021.  [[Last accessed on 2021 Jul]].  Available from: https://www.businessinsider.com/surfside-florida-building-collapse-causes-structural-engineers-2021-7 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alotaibi WM. A Quantitative Study to Evaluate the Preparedness for Internal Disasters at Security Forces Hospital in Riyadh. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojat M, Sirati Nir M, Khaghanizade M, Karimizarchi M. A survey of hospital disaster management in medical science universities. Daneshvar Med. 2020;15:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AA, Shaw R, Ye J, Abid M, Amir SM, Kanak Pervez A, et al. Current capacities, preparedness and needs of local institutions in dealing with disaster risk reduction in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Int J Disaster Risk Reduct. 2019;34:165&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wax RS. Preparing the intensive care unit for disaster. Crit Care Clin. 2019;35:551&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31445604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmari AA, Khan AA. Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear preparedness of public hospitals in Riyadh. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2023;17:e401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37264827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajow N, Djalali A, Ingrassia PL, Ragazzoni L, Ageely H, Bani I, et al. Evaluation of a new community-based curriculum in disaster medicine for undergraduates. BMC Med Educ. 2016;16:225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5000399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27562428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi RH, Ghoraba M. Prevalence and patient characteristics of Helicobacter pylori among adult in primary health care of security forces hospital Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, 2018. J Family Med Prim Care. 2019;8:2202&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31463230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Thobaity A, Plummer V, Innes K, Copnell B. Perceptions of knowledge of disaster management among military and civilian nurses in Saudi Arabia. Australas Emerg Nurs J. 2015;18:156&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25864385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlDulijand NA, Al-Wathinani AM, Abahussain MA, Alhallaf MA, Farhat H, Goniewicz K. Sustainable Healthcare resilience: Disaster preparedness in Saudi Arabia's eastern province hospitals. Sustainability. 2023;16:198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsalem MM, Alghanim SA. An Assessment of Saudi Hospitals' disaster preparedness. Eur J Environ Public Health. 2021;5:em0071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajow N, Alesa S, Shaheen FAY, Almalki A, Alshamrani A, Alotaibi R, et al. Assessment of the effectiveness of hospital external disaster functional drills on health care receivers'performance, using standardized patients and mass cards simulation: A pilot study from Saudi Arabia. BMC Emerg Med. 2024;24:175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11438112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39333890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani F, Kyratsis Y. Emergency nurse disaster preparedness during mass gatherings: A cross-sectional survey of emergency nurses' perceptions in hospitals in Mecca, Saudi Arabia. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e013563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klokman VW, Barten DG, Peters NALR, Versteegen MGJ, Wijnands JJJ, van Osch FHM, et al. A scoping review of internal hospital crises and disasters in the Netherlands, 2000-2020. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0250551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8075216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>