<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41922400</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI-driven adaptive vibration control in smart plate systems: a sustainable approach for next-generation sports engineering.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41464-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The current paper proposes an AI-based method for the vibration control of smart plate systems. The application is set for next-generation sports engineering, where performance enhancement is the main goal. The system consists of a core of coarse aggregate ultra-high-performance concrete (CA-UHPA) and piezoelectric face sheets, which are mounted on an elastic foundation. The properties of the material composite are foreseen based on the Halpin-Tsai models and the law of mixtures. Looking into the system's dynamic performance in a very thorough way is done using the quasi-3D theory having four variables. This theory gives the opportunity for the full consideration of the distribution of transverse shear strains and stresses throughout the plate thickness. The governing equations of the resonant response are derived by employing the concept of piezoelectricity together with Hamilton's energy principles. The elastic foundation is analyzed using both Winkler and Pasternak coefficients, thereby allowing the interaction of the plate and its support substrate to be included. The solution is achieved through using the physics-informed neural networks (PINNs) technique, which not only accurately and efficiently replaces the conventional Legendre Polynomial Expansions with deep neural networks (DNNs) for more computational efficiency and accuracy but also doubles the legacy of AI-powered methods in terms of real-time system adaptability and optimal vibration control under changing scenarios. A DNN-based verification process assists in obtaining and confirming the trustworthiness of the results. This research marks above all and the first time as a very promising new direction in the smart systems vibration control area in sports, and it is highly anticipated that the new development will have a positive impact on the performance and durability optimization of advanced sports equipment. The introduced method embodies a patent-driven technology leap in vibration control, where AI and new materials join forces to solve challenging problems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Preschool Education College, Chongqing, 404047, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jinyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Preschool Education College, Chongqing, 404047, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safarpour</LastName><ForeName>Mehran</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran. m_safarpour@modares.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yaylac&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Murat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Recep Tayyip Erdogan University, 53100, Rize, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turgut K&#x131;ran Maritime Faculty, Recep Tayyip Erdogan University, 53900, Rize, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-driven vibration control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coarse aggregate ultra-high-performance concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PINNs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Piezoelectric materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smart plate systems</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41922400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41464-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41464-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dadashi, P., Torbatinejad, K. &amp; Babaei, A. Hybridization as a promising approach to engineering the desired performance of bio-nanocomposites: GO-ZnO hybrid reinforced PCL. Sci. Rep. 15, 17259 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Liu, B. Q., Peng, X. T. &amp; Gao, F. Bending and vibration behavior of functionally graded piezoelectric nanobeams considering dynamic flexoelectric and surface effects. Sci. Rep. 15, 13439 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, P., Wang, Z., Tian, H., Xi, X. &amp; Liu, X. On the magnetically tunable free damped-vibration of L-shaped composite spherical panels made of GPL-reinforced magnetorheological elastomers: an element-based GDQ approach. Thin-Walled Struct. 218, 113987 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari, M., Sadighi, M., Eslami, M. &amp; Kiani, Y. Axisymmetric free vibration analysis of functionally graded sandwich annular plates: A Quasi-3D shear and normal deformable model. Int. J. Struct. Stab. Dyn. 23, 2350086 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei, J., Wu, Z. &amp; Kou, J. Moving-load dynamic analysis of graphene-reinforced metal foam arches covered with titanium alloy layers. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0219455426501737 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. &amp; Peng, J. In-plane vibrations of deep sandwich arches with different end conditions based on a logarithmic shear deformation theory. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. 25, 2550029. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0219455425500294 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, S. F., Xue, N., Ma, W. S., Song, X. J. &amp; Jiang, X. Linear and nonlinear dynamics responses of an axially moving laminated composite plate-reinforced with graphene nanoplatelets. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. 25, 2550036. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0219455425500361 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, S., Gao, J. &amp; Wu, Z. Thermal and mechanical bifurcation stability analyses of clamped hybrid dual-FG composite annular and circular plates. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0219455426501087 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Application of electrorheological fluid cores to improve the vibration response of sandwich toroidal shell elements covered by functionally graded nanocomposite faces. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0219455426501488 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raju, G. H. T., Vembu, V., Raju, P. R., Ganesan, G. &amp; Narendar, S. Influences of external magnetic field on thermo-mechanical vibration analysis of nanocomposite beam using higher-order strain gradient theory. Int. J. Str. Stab. Dyn. 25, 2440008. https://doi.org/10.1142/S021945542440008X (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, G. et al. Study on automatic tracking system of microwave deicing device for railway contact wire. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 73, 1&#x2013;11 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. &amp; Li, B. PDE-based observation and predictor-based control for linear systems with distributed infinite input and output delays. Automatica 170, 111845 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, D. &amp; Zeng, S. Recurrent neural network solver for structural motion differential equations. Int. J. Struct. Stab. Dyn. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Q., Xin, T., Zhenggang, H. &amp; Minghua, H. Measurement and analysis of deformation of underlying tunnel induced by foundation pit excavation. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2023, 8897139 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, C. et al. Coupled vibratory roller and layered unsaturated subgrade model for intelligent compaction. Comput. Geotech. 177, 106827 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, J. &amp; Gao, N. Broadband vibroacoustic reduction for a circular beam coupled with a curved acoustic black hole via nullspace method. Int. J. Mech. Sci. 233, 107641 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, J. et al. Vibration damping by periodic additive acoustic black holes. J. Sound Vib. 574, 118235 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., Zhang, B., Jin, S., Shen, H. &amp; Li, C. Size-dependent dynamics of rotating FG imperfect microplates under in-plane loads using an improved differential quadrature finite element method. Thin-Walled Struct. 212, 113204 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, J. &amp; Chen, Y. RBFNN-based parameter adaptive sliding mode control for an uncertain TQUAV with time-varying mass. Int. J. Robust Nonlinear Control 35, 4658&#x2013;4668 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, D. et al. Calculation methods for the jacking force of a rectangular pipe jacking tunnel: Overview and prospects. J. Pipeline Syst. Eng. Pract. 16, 03125001 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Wu, S., Yu, F., Bi, Y. &amp; Xu, Z. Study on remaining useful life prediction of sliding bearings in nuclear power plant shielded pumps based on nearest similar distance particle filtering. Ann. Nucl. Energy 223, 111625 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Cui, L. Zhao, Y. Ge, K. Xu, A generalized van der Pol nonlinear model of vortex-induced vibrations of bridge decks with multistability. Nonlinear Dyn. 1&#x2013;14 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J., Liu, Y., Lu, X. &amp; Wang, T. An adaptive measurement-based substructure identification framework for dynamic response reconstruction. Available at SSRN 5186270 (n.d.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, J. et al. Robust damping improvement against the vortex-induced vibration in flexible bridges using multiple tuned mass damper inerters. Eng. Struct. 313, 118221 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gai, P.-P., Dai, J., Xu, Z.-D., Bi, Q.-S. &amp; Guan, Q.-S. A novel two-state active tuned mass damper inerter control of high-flexibility long-span bridges. J. Struct. Eng. 151, 05025005 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, R.-B., Lu, Z.-Q., Ding, H. &amp; Chen, L.-Q. A nonlinear vibration isolator supported on a flexible plate: Analysis and experiment. Nonlinear Dyn. 108, 941&#x2013;958 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Z., Brennan, M. J., Yang, T., Li, X. &amp; Liu, Z. An investigation of a two-stage nonlinear vibration isolation system. J. Sound Vib. 332, 1456&#x2013;1464 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, K. et al. Probing to dynamics of a tube-core sandwich enhanced liquid-filled tank subjected to hydrodynamic ram. Thin-Walled Struct 215, 113573 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Puig, V., Wang, X., Wang, S., Sun, C. &amp; Zhang, Y. Dynamic-high-gain-based decentralized optimal fault-tolerant control for a class of interconnected nonlinear systems. IEEE Trans. Autom. Control (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avcar, M., Hadji, L. &amp; Civalek, O. The influence of non-linear carbon nanotube reinforcement on the natural frequencies of composite beams. Adv. Nano Res. 14, 421&#x2013;433 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Z., Liu, Y., Gou, G., Gao, W. &amp; Chen, J. Effect of heat input on interfacial characterization of the butter joint of hot-rolling CP-Ti/Q235 bimetallic sheets by Laser+ CMT. Sci. Rep. 11, 10020 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Xu, Y., Zhou, J., Zhou, Y. &amp; Mahfoud, J. Vibration control of AMB-rotor system under base motions based on disturbance observer. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatron. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, D. et al. Nonlinear vibration and vibration transmission of roll controlled by negative stiffness vibration absorbers. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 245, 113872 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, D. et al. Machine learning&#x2013;finite element mesh optimization-based modeling and prediction of excavation-induced shield tunnel ground settlement. Int. J. Comput. Methods 22, 2450066 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Li, Y.-F., Men, T. &amp; Li, L. Physically interpretable wavelet-guided networks with dynamic frequency decomposition for machine intelligence fault prediction. IEEE Trans. Syst. Man Cybern. Syst. 54, 4863&#x2013;4875 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Weng, X., Hu, D., Tan, Z. &amp; Liu, J. Data-driven method for predicting long-term underground pipeline settlement induced by rectangular pipe jacking tunnel construction. J. Pipeline Syst. Eng. Pract. 16, 04025046 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Cao, J. &amp; Liu, H. Adaptive fuzzy control of nonlinear systems with predefined time and accuracy. IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst. 30, 5152&#x2013;5165 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, L. et al. Machine-learning-driven on-demand design of phononic beams. Sci. China Phys. Mech. Astron. 65, 214612 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, X. et al. Pcastnet: A physics-constrained adaptive style transfer network for sample generation in cross-machine small-sample fault diagnosis. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 74, 1&#x2013;17 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, A. et al. Vibration prediction for abnormal elevator door system faults based on attention mechanism and neural networks with time-frequency domain features. Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. C. J. Mech. Eng. Sci. 239, 7358&#x2013;7372 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, C., Vescovini, R. &amp; Dozio, L. A framework based on physics-informed neural networks and extreme learning for the analysis of composite structures. Comput. Struct. 265, 106761 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. et al. The global industrial robot trade network: Evolution and China&#x2019;s rising international competitiveness. Systems 13, 361 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, N.-T., Hui, D., Lee, J. &amp; Nguyen-Xuan, H. An efficient computational approach for size-dependent analysis of functionally graded nanoplates. Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Eng. 297, 191&#x2013;218 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, J. N. Mechanics of laminated composite plates and shells: theory and analysis (CRC Press, Boca Raton, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandis, N. &amp; Tandis, E. A physics-informed machine learning approach to piezoelectric plate modelling. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 160, 111847 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei, M. Vibration characteristics of sandwich plates with GPLRC core and piezoelectric face sheets with various electrical and mechanical boundary conditions. Mech. Based Des. Struct. Mach. 52, 990&#x2013;1013 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baferani, A. H., Saidi, A. &amp; Ehteshami, H. Accurate solution for free vibration analysis of functionally graded thick rectangular plates resting on elastic foundation. Compos. Struct. 93, 1842&#x2013;1853 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain, M. G. &amp; Stewart, M. Standards for piezoelectric and ferroelectric ceramics. In: Characterisation of Ferroelectric Bulk Materials and Thin Films 267&#x2013;275 (Springer, 2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>