<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41522045</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2223-4292</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Quantitative imaging in medicine and surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Quant Imaging Med Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional connectivity in electroencephalography of brain tumor patients in status epilepticus: a retrospective evaluation of prognostic value.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>87</StartPage><MedlinePgn>87</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">87</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21037/qims-2025-1739</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There is currently no individualized prognostic tool to predict outcomes in patients with brain tumors following status epilepticus (SE), despite its clinical importance for counseling and therapeutic decision-making. This proof-of-principle, retrospective monocentric study investigated whether electroencephalography (EEG)-derived functional connectivity patterns differ in brain tumor patients after SE with respect to survival and tumor type.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">EEG data from 37 brain tumor patients with SE were analyzed. Thirty epochs per frequency band (delta-gamma) were selected using spectral power. Source-space connectivity was measured via weighted Phase Lag Index (wPLI). Permutation tests compared connectivity between survival (&gt;1 <i>vs.</i> &lt;1 year) and tumor subgroups (glioma, meningioma, metastases).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The cohort had a mean age of 68.1 years; 67.6% were female. One-year survival was 32.4%, with a mortality rate of 46.0% and 21.6% lost to follow-up. Tumor diagnoses included 11 adult-type diffuse gliomas, 12 meningiomas, 11 brain metastases, and single cases of primary cerebral lymphoma, schwannoma, and pineal tumor. Higher source connectivity in the alpha and beta bands was observed in patients with longer survival, and higher delta band connectivity in patients with brain metastases compared to those with glioblastoma or meningioma.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Functional connectivity analysis in source space did not reliably differentiate patients by survival or tumor type following SE. These findings suggest that current connectivity metrics are insufficient as standalone prognostic tools in this context. Larger, more homogeneous cohorts and stratification by clinical and tumor characteristics are needed to clarify the potential prognostic value of EEG connectivity in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; AME Publishing Company.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuba</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kr&#xe4;ling</LastName><ForeName>Gunter</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habermehl</LastName><ForeName>Lena</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Center, Neurological Institute, University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Mierlo</LastName><ForeName>Pieter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Information Systems, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menzler</LastName><ForeName>Katja</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagenstecher</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nimsky</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gurschi</LastName><ForeName>Mariana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroradiology, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kemmling</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroradiology, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeiner</LastName><ForeName>Pia S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Senckenberg Institute of Neurooncology, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frankturt Cancer Institute (FCI), Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Goethe University Frankfurt, University Hospital, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Cancer Center (UCT), Goethe University Frankfurt, University Hospital, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Heidelberg, Germany and German Cancer Consortium (DKTK), Partner Site Frankfurt/Mainz, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinbach</LastName><ForeName>Joachim P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Senckenberg Institute of Neurooncology, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frankturt Cancer Institute (FCI), Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Goethe University Frankfurt, University Hospital, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Cancer Center (UCT), Goethe University Frankfurt, University Hospital, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Heidelberg, Germany and German Cancer Consortium (DKTK), Partner Site Frankfurt/Mainz, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmermann</LastName><ForeName>Lars</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strzelczyk</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Cancer Center (UCT), Goethe University Frankfurt, University Hospital, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Epilepsy Center Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt Rhine-Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knake</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xf6;ller</LastName><ForeName>Leona</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Epilepsy Center Hessen, Philipps University Marburg, Marburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Quant Imaging Med Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101577942</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2223-4306</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epilepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebral tumors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional connectivity analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognostic assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">status epilepticus (SE)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: All authors have completed the ICMJE uniform disclosure form (available at https://qims.amegroups.com/article/view/10.21037/qims-2025-1739/coif). P.K. received a &#x20ac;3,000 educational fellowship from Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Neurologie (DGfE) for a 6-week research internship at Epilog (Ghent, Belgium) to learn Python coding applications in epileptology. This grant covered travel and accommodation expenses for training purposes and had no direct relationship to the current study. L.H. received a traveling grant from Jazz Pharma and Angelini Pharma, as well as a clinical fellowship from DGfE. P.v.M. is co-founder and shareholder at Epilog, Clouds of Care NV, Ghent, Belgium. P.v.M. is co-founder and shareholder of Epilog, Clouds of Care NV (Ghent, Belgium), a company developing EEG analysis software and epilepsy-related technologies. This represents both equity interest and leadership role in an entity with potential relevance to epilepsy research. K.M. received speaker honoraria from Jazz pharmaceuticals for educational and consulting activities related to epilepsy treatment. C.N. is consultant for Brainlab and received speaker honoraria from Aesculap, BKmedical, and Brainlab. M.G. declares that she has no competing interest. A.K. received consulting fees from Phenox, Penumbra, and Stryker for medical device-related consulting services in interventional neuroradiology and neurosurgical procedures. P.S.Z. has received a lecture honorarium from Bristol-Myers Squibb. She is funded by the Mildred Scheel Career Center Frankfurt (Deutsche Krebshilfe) and by the Ministry of Higher Education, Research and the Arts of the State of Hesse (HMWK) within the LOEWE Center Frankfurt Cancer Institute (FCI). The Dr. Senckenberg Institute of Neurooncology is supported by the Dr. Senckenberg Foundation. J.P.S. has received honoraria for lectures, advisory board participation, consulting, and travel grants from Abbvie, Roche, Boehringer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Medac, Mundipharma, and UCB. L.T. received consulting fees from Boston Scientific and speaker honoraria from Boston Scientific, AbbVie, Novartis, Neuraxpharm, Teva, Movement Disorders Society, and DIAPLAN (May 2021-May 2023). The author&#x2019;s institution received funding from Boston Scientific, German Research Foundation, German Ministry of Education and Research, Otto-Loewi-Foundation, and Deutsche Parkinson Vereinigung. L.T. serves as unpaid president of the German Neurological Society. The author declares no stock holdings, patents, or financial interests in any mentioned companies or competitors for himself or family members. A.S. reports personal fees and grants from Angelini Pharma, Biocodex, Desitin Arzneimittel, Eisai, Jazz (GW) Pharmaceuticals, Marinus Pharma, Precisis, Takeda, UCB (Zogenix) Pharma, and UNEEG Medical. These relationships included consulting fees, speaker honoraria, and research support for clinical studies and educational activities in epilepsy and neurological disorders. S.K. received speaker honoraria from Arvelle Pharma, Bial, Eisai, Epilog, Desitin, Merck Serono, Precisis AG, UCB Pharma, and Zogenix for educational lectures and presentations on epilepsy and neurological disorders. These payments were for educational activities outside the submitted work and had no direct relationship to the current study. The other authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41522045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12780627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/qims-2025-1739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">qims-16-01-87</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ascoli M, Ferlazzo E, Gasparini S, Mastroianni G, Citraro R, Roberti R, Russo E. Epidemiology and Outcomes of Status Epilepticus. Int J Gen Med 2021;14:2965-73. 10.2147/IJGM.S295855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S295855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser WA, Annegers JF, Kurland LT. Incidence of epilepsy and unprovoked seizures in Rochester, Minnesota: 1935-1984. Epilepsia 1993;34:453-68. 10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb02586.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb02586.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8504780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannini G, Pasini F, Orlandi N, Mirandola L, Meletti S. Tumor-associated status epilepticus in patients with glioma: Clinical characteristics and outcomes. Epilepsy Behav 2019;101:106370. 10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.06.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.06.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saviuk M, Sleptsova E, Redkin T, Turubanova V. Unexplained Causes of Glioma-Associated Epilepsies: A Review of Theories and an Area for Research. Cancers (Basel) 2023;15:5539. 10.3390/cancers15235539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers15235539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10705208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38067243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauletto G, Nilo A, Pez S, Zonta ME, Bagatto D, Isola M, Verriello L, Valente M, Skrap M, Ius T. Meningioma-Related Epilepsy: A Happy Ending? J Pers Med 2023;13:1124. 10.3390/jpm13071124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm13071124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10381126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37511737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenow F, Weber J; on behalf of Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Neurologie (DGN) &amp; &#xd6;sterreichische Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Neurologie (&#xd6;GN). S2k-Leitlinie: Status Epilepticus im Erwachsenenalter. Nervenarzt 2021;92:1002-30. 10.1007/s00115-020-01036-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00115-020-01036-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8484257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33751150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox J, Ajinkya S, Greenblatt A, Houston P, Lekoubou A, Lindhorst S, Cachia D, Olar A, Kutluay E. Clinical characteristics, EEG findings and implications of status epilepticus in patients with brain metastases. J Neurol Sci 2019;407:116538. 10.1016/j.jns.2019.116538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2019.116538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31644990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauff NS, Storstein A. Seizure Management and Prophylaxis Considerations in Patients with Brain Tumors. Curr Oncol Rep 2023;25:787-92. 10.1007/s11912-023-01410-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11912-023-01410-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10256653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37071297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberg LE, Monsson O, Kristensen SB, Dahl SM, Ulvin LB, Heuser K, Taub&#xf8;ll E, Strzelczyk A, Knake S, Bechert L, Rosenow F, Beier D, Beniczky S, Kr&#xf8;ig&#xe5;rd T, Beier CP. Prediction of Long-term Survival After Status Epilepticus Using the ACD Score. JAMA Neurol 2022;79:604-13. 10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.0609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.0609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sairanen JJ, Kantanen AM, Hypp&#xf6;l&#xe4; HT, K&#xe4;lvi&#xe4;inen RK. Outcome of status epilepticus and the predictive value of the EMSE and STESS scores: A prospective study. Seizure 2020;75:115-20. 10.1016/j.seizure.2019.12.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2019.12.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31945716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loddenkemper T. Detect, predict, and prevent acute seizures and status epilepticus. Epilepsy Behav 2023;141:109141. 10.1016/j.yebeh.2023.109141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2023.109141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J, Zhao Y, Shan X, Wei HL, Guo Y, Chen L, Erkoyuncu JA, Sarrigiannis PG. Brain functional and effective connectivity based on electroencephalography recordings: A review. Hum Brain Mapp 2022;43:860-79. 10.1002/hbm.25683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.25683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34668603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjiabadi DH, Pung L, Zhang J, Ward BD, Lim WT, Kalavar M, Thakor NV, Biswal BB, Pathak AP. Brain tumors disrupt the resting-state connectome. Neuroimage Clin 2018;18:279-89. 10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5987800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29876248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladisich B, Rampp S, Trinka E, Weisz N, Schwartz C, Kraus T, Sherif C, Marhold F, Demarchi G. Network topology in brain tumor patients with and without structural epilepsy: a prospective MEG study. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2023;16:17562864231190298. 10.1177/17562864231190298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17562864231190298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37655227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary K, DeCost B, Chen C, Jain A, Tavazza F, Cohn R, Park CW, Choudhary A, Agrawal A, Billinge SJ, Holm E, Ong SP, Wolverton C. Recent advances and applications of deep learning methods in materials science. npj Comput Mater 2022;8:1-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikam RM, Yue X, Kaur G, Kandula V, Khair A, Kecskemethy HH, Averill LW, Langhans SA. Advanced Neuroimaging Approaches to Pediatric Brain Tumors. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14:3401. 10.3390/cancers14143401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14143401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9318188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Noia C, Grist JT, Riemer F, Lyasheva M, Fabozzi M, Castelli M, Lodi R, Tonon C, Rundo L, Zaccagna F. Predicting Survival in Patients with Brain Tumors: Current State-of-the-Art of AI Methods Applied to MRI. Diagnostics (Basel) 2022;12:2125. 10.3390/diagnostics12092125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics12092125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9497964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36140526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai S, Oguri M, Okanishi T, Miyamoto Y, Maeda M, Yazaki K, Matsuura R, Tozawa T, Sakuma S, Chiyonobu T, Hamano SI, Maegaki Y. Predictive modeling based on functional connectivity of interictal scalp EEG for infantile epileptic spasms syndrome. Clin Neurophysiol 2024;167:37-48. 10.1016/j.clinph.2024.08.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2024.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39265289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperatori LS, Betta M, Cecchetti L, Canales-Johnson A, Ricciardi E, Siclari F, Pietrini P, Chennu S, Bernardi G. EEG functional connectivity metrics wPLI and wSMI account for distinct types of brain functional interactions. Sci Rep 2019;9:8894. 10.1038/s41598-019-45289-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-45289-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6586889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31222021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz E, Stingl K, M&#xfc;nssinger J, Braun C, Preissl H, Belardinelli P. Weighted phase lag index and graph analysis: preliminary investigation of functional connectivity during resting state in children. Comput Math Methods Med 2012;2012:186353. 10.1155/2012/186353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/186353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23049617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegg EJ, McKavanagh A, Bracewell RM, Chen Y, Das K, Denby C, Kreilkamp BAK, Laiou P, Marson A, Mohanraj R, Taylor JR, Keller SS. Functional network topology in drug resistant and well-controlled idiopathic generalized epilepsy: a resting state functional MRI study. Brain Commun 2021;3:fcab196. 10.1093/braincomms/fcab196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/braincomms/fcab196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8417840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34514400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegg EJ, Taylor JR, Laiou P, Richardson M, Mohanraj R. Interictal electroencephalographic functional network topology in drug-resistant and well-controlled idiopathic generalized epilepsy. Epilepsia 2021;62:492-503. 10.1111/epi.16811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang C, Li X, Na M, Jiang W, He Y, Wei A, Huang J, Zhou M. Epilepsy lesion localization method based on brain function network. Front Hum Neurosci 2024;18:1431153. 10.3389/fnhum.2024.1431153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2024.1431153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11266299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39050383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinck M, Oostenveld R, van Wingerden M, Battaglia F, Pennartz CM. An improved index of phase-synchronization for electrophysiological data in the presence of volume-conduction, noise and sample-size bias. Neuroimage 2011;55:1548-65. 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2011.01.055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2011.01.055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21276857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The MathWorks Inc. MATLAB version: 9.5.0 (R2018b). Natick, Massachusetts: The MathWorks Inc., 2018. Available online: https://www.mathworks.com/products/matlab.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Python Software Foundation. Python. Available online: https://www.python.org (Computer software).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The jamovi project (2025). jamovi (Version 2.6) [Computer Software]. Available online: https://www.jamovi.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sculier C, Ga&#xed;nza-Lein M, S&#xe1;nchez Fern&#xe1;ndez I, Loddenkemper T. Long-term outcomes of status epilepticus: A critical assessment. Epilepsia 2018;59 Suppl 2:155-69. 10.1111/epi.14515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuppurainen KM, Ritvanen JG, Mustonen H, K&#xe4;mppi LS. Predictors of mortality at one year after generalized convulsive status epilepticus. Epilepsy Behav 2019;101:106411. 10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.07.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31668580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirikarn P, Pattanittum P, Sawanyawisuth K, Tiamkao S. Causes of death in patients with status epilepticus. Epilepsy Behav 2019;101:106372. 10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.06.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.06.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitinger M, Trinka E, Giovannini G, Zimmermann G, Florea C, Rohracher A, Kalss G, Neuray C, Kreidenhuber R, H&#xf6;fler J, Kuchukhidze G, Granbichler C, Dobesberger J, Novak HF, Pilz G, Meletti S, Siebert U. Epidemiology of status epilepticus in adults: A population-based study on incidence, causes, and outcomes. Epilepsia 2019;60:53-62. 10.1111/epi.14607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7380005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannini G, Monti G, Polisi MM, Mirandola L, Marudi A, Pinelli G, Valzania F, Girardis M, Nichelli PF, Meletti S. A one-year prospective study of refractory status epilepticus in Modena, Italy. Epilepsy Behav 2015;49:141-5. 10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.05.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.05.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26074182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantanen AM, Reinikainen M, Parviainen I, K&#xe4;lvi&#xe4;inen R. Long-term outcome of refractory status epilepticus in adults: A retrospective population-based study. Epilepsy Res 2017;133:13-21. 10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2017.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2017.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28402834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaspard N, Foreman BP, Alvarez V, Cabrera Kang C, Probasco JC, Jongeling AC, Meyers E, Espinera A, Haas KF, Schmitt SE, Gerard EE, Gofton T, Kaplan PW, Lee JW, Legros B, Szaflarski JP, Westover BM, LaRoche SM, Hirsch LJ, Critical Care EEG Monitoring Research Consortium (CCEMRC) . New-onset refractory status epilepticus: Etiology, clinical features, and outcome. Neurology 2015;85:1604-13. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4642147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Lee SA, Kim HW, Kim SJ, Jeon SB, Koo YS. The timelines of MRI findings related to outcomes in adult patients with new-onset refractory status epilepticus. Epilepsia 2020;61:1735-48. 10.1111/epi.16620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mad&#x17e;ar D, Knappe RU, Reindl C, Giede-Jeppe A, Spr&#xfc;gel MI, Beuscher V, Gollwitzer S, Hamer HM, Huttner HB. Factors associated with occurrence and outcome of super-refractory status epilepticus. Seizure 2017;52:53-9. 10.1016/j.seizure.2017.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28963934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosma I, Reijneveld JC, Klein M, Douw L, van Dijk BW, Heimans JJ, Stam CJ. Disturbed functional brain networks and neurocognitive function in low-grade glioma patients: a graph theoretical analysis of resting-state MEG. Nonlinear Biomed Phys 2009;3:9. 10.1186/1753-4631-3-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1753-4631-3-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19698149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei F, Bosma I, Klein M, Baayen JC, Reijneveld JC, Postma TJ, Heimans JJ, van Dijk BW, de Munck JC, de Jongh A, Cover KS, Stam CJ. How do brain tumors alter functional connectivity? A magnetoencephalography study. Ann Neurol 2006;59:128-38. 10.1002/ana.20710</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.20710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16278872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Souza S, Hirt L, Ormond DR, Thompson JA. Retrospective analysis of hemispheric structural network change as a function of location and size of glioma. Brain Commun 2021;3:fcaa216. 10.1093/braincomms/fcaa216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/braincomms/fcaa216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmel ES, Quadri TR, King TZ. Correction to: Graph Theoretical Analysis of Brain Network Characteristics in Brain Tumor Patients: A Systematic Review. Neuropsychol Rev 2022;32:676. 10.1007/s11065-021-09512-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11065-021-09512-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34235627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derks J, Kulik S, Wesseling P, Numan T, Hillebrand A, van Dellen E, de Witt Hamer PC, Geurts JJG, Reijneveld JC, Stam CJ, Klein M, Douw L. Understanding cognitive functioning in glioma patients: The relevance of IDH-mutation status and functional connectivity. Brain Behav 2019;9:e01204. 10.1002/brb3.1204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.1204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6456787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30809977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metwali H, Raemaekers M, Ibrahim T, Samii A. Inter-Network Functional Connectivity Changes in Patients With Brain Tumors: A Resting-State Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging Study. World Neurosurg 2020;138:e66-71. 10.1016/j.wneu.2020.01.177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2020.01.177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manglore S, Bharath RD, Panda R, George L, Thamodharan A, Gupta AK. Utility of resting fMRI and connectivity in patients with brain tumor. Neurol India 2013;61:144-51. 10.4103/0028-3886.111120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0028-3886.111120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23644313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dellen E, Douw L, Hillebrand A, Ris-Hilgersom IH, Schoonheim MM, Baayen JC, De Witt Hamer PC, Velis DN, Klein M, Heimans JJ, Stam CJ, Reijneveld JC. MEG network differences between low- and high-grade glioma related to epilepsy and cognition. PLoS One 2012;7:e50122. 10.1371/journal.pone.0050122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0050122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3498183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23166829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douw L, Baayen H, Bosma I, Klein M, Vandertop P, Heimans J, Stam K, de Munck J, Reijneveld J. Treatment-related changes in functional connectivity in brain tumor patients: a magnetoencephalography study. Exp Neurol 2008;212:285-90. 10.1016/j.expneurol.2008.03.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2008.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18534578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickel JK, Zeeb D, Knake S, Urban H, Konczalla J, Weber KJ, et al. Status epilepticus in patients with brain tumors and metastases: A multicenter cohort study of 208 patients and literature review. Neurol Res Pract 2024;6:19. 10.1186/s42466-024-00314-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42466-024-00314-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38570823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei F, Bosma I, Klein M, Baayen JC, Reijneveld JC, Postma TJ, Heimans JJ, van Dijk BW, de Munck JC, de Jongh A, Cover KS, Stam CJ. Disturbed functional connectivity in brain tumour patients: evaluation by graph analysis of synchronization matrices. Clin Neurophysiol 2006;117:2039-49. 10.1016/j.clinph.2006.05.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2006.05.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16859985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann MLM, Breedt LC, Centeno EGZ, Reijneveld JC, Santos FAN, Stam CJ, van Lingen MR, Schoonheim MM, Hillebrand A, Douw L. The relationship between pathological brain activity and functional network connectivity in glioma patients. J Neurooncol 2024;166:523-33. 10.1007/s11060-024-04577-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11060-024-04577-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10876827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38308803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesler SR, Noll K, Cahill DP, Rao G, Wefel JS. The effect of IDH1 mutation on the structural connectome in malignant astrocytoma. J Neurooncol 2017;131:565-74. 10.1007/s11060-016-2328-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11060-016-2328-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27848136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamba N, Catalano PJ, Cagney DN, Haas-Kogan DA, Bubrick EJ, Wen PY, Aizer AA. Seizures Among Patients With Brain Metastases: A Population- and Institutional-Level Analysis. Neurology 2021;96:e1237-50. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000011459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000011459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoga E, Wolff R, Ackermann H, Meissner M, R&#xf6;del C, Tselis N, Chatzikonstantinou G. Factors Associated with Hemorrhage of Melanoma Brain Metastases after Stereotactic Radiosurgery in the Era of Targeted/Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor Therapies. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14:2391. 10.3390/cancers14102391</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14102391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9140160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35625996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrom QT, Cioffi G, Gittleman H, Patil N, Waite K, Kruchko C, Barnholtz-Sloan JS. CBTRUS Statistical Report: Primary Brain and Other Central Nervous System Tumors Diagnosed in the United States in 2012-2016. Neuro Oncol 2019;21:v1-v100. 10.1093/neuonc/noz150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuonc/noz150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6823730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31675094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douw L, van Dellen E, de Groot M, Heimans JJ, Klein M, Stam CJ, Reijneveld JC. Epilepsy is related to theta band brain connectivity and network topology in brain tumor patients. BMC Neurosci 2010;11:103. 10.1186/1471-2202-11-103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2202-11-103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2936439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20731854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>