<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41712139</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-1709</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sleep &amp; breathing = Schlaf &amp; Atmung</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sleep Breath</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Towards automatic home screening of obstructive sleep apnea using combined features from pulse wave amplitude, pulse-to-pulse interval and oxygen desaturation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>57</StartPage><MedlinePgn>57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">57</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11325-026-03592-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Automatic home OSA screening with pulse oximeters often relies on oxygen saturation (SpO2), which may miss hypopneas associated with arousals. Photoplethysmography (PPG) from pulse oximeters can be processed to extract pulse wave amplitude (PWA) and pulse-to-pulse interval (PPI) which reflect autonomic activation during arousals. However, the role of PWA in automated OSA screening remains unexplored. This study evaluated the added value of PWA for detecting OSA segments, and estimating AHI compared with SpO2 and PPI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">From 90 PSG recordings, PWA and PPI were derived from finger PPG. We extracted statistical PWA features to capture amplitude drops, and spectral powers to represent pulse amplitude variability. PPI features included statistics and heart rate variability measures. Support vector machine classifiers with different combinations of PWA, PPI, and SpO2 features were trained to detect 60-second segments with apnea or hypopnea. Performance was assessed at both per-segment and per-subject levels for identifying AHI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;15.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Adding PWA to SpO2 improved sensitivity for arousal-related OSA segments from 61.6% to 65.2% and increased per-subject sensitivity from 61.4% to 64.9%. Adding PPI to SpO2 improved per-segment sensitivity for arousal-related OSA segments to 73.3% and increased per-subject sensitivity to 77.2%. Combining PWA with PPI achieved the highest sensitivity for arousal-related segments (77.1%), and when both were added to SpO2, per-subject sensitivity for detecting AHI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;15 reached 80.7%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Both PWA and PPI improved detection of arousal-related segments and contributed to detecting subjects with AHI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;15. However, PPI consistently outperformed PWA. SpO2 remained particularly important for identifying subjects with AHI&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;15.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thuptimdang</LastName><ForeName>Wanwara</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-3769-5967</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Engineering, Department of Biomedical Sciences and Biomedical Engineering, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Songkhla, Thailand. wanwara.t@psu.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tawaranurak</LastName><ForeName>Krongthong</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Songkhla, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panyarath</LastName><ForeName>Pattaraporn</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory and Respiratory Critical Care Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Songkhla, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakim</LastName><ForeName>Wandee</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Songklanagarind Hospital Sleep Center, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Songkhla, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wae-Asae</LastName><ForeName>Katinee</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Songklanagarind Hospital Sleep Center, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Songkhla, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khoo</LastName><ForeName>Michael C K</ForeName><Initials>MCK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MED6701239S</GrantID><Agency>National Science, Research and Innovation Fund (NSRF) and Prince of Songkla University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Sleep Breath</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804161</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1520-9512</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obstructive sleep apnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen saturation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photoplethysmography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulse wave amplitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory arousal</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: All procedures performed in studies involving human participants were in accordance with the ethical standards of the institutional research committee (the Human Research Ethics Committee, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University (REC 66-019-38-2)) and with the 1964 Helsinki declaration and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards. For this type of study formal consent is not required. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41712139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12920278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11325-026-03592-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11325-026-03592-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AAothers., American Academy of Sleep Medicine (1999) Sleep-related breathing disorders in adults: recommendations for syndrome definition and measurement techniques in clinical research. Sleep 22:667&#x2013;689 The Report of an American Academy of Sleep Medicine Task Force</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/22.5.667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10450601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Veasey SC, Morgan BJ, O&#x2019;Donnell CP (2010) Pathophysiology of sleep apnea. Physiol Rev 90:47&#x2013;112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00043.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3970937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20086074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharia SM, Brown LK (2017) Epidemiology of sleep-disordered breathing and heart failure: what drives what. Curr Heart Fail Rep 14:351&#x2013;364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11897-017-0348-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28808861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzaga C, Bertolami A, Bertolami M, Amodeo C, Calhoun D (2015) Obstructive sleep apnea, hypertension and cardiovascular diseases. J Hum Hypertens 29:705&#x2013;712</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jhh.2015.15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25761667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adult Obstructive Sleep Apnea Task Force of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine (2009) Clinical guideline for the evaluation, management and long-term care of obstructive sleep apnea in adults. J Clin Sleep Med 5:263&#x2013;276</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.27497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19960649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massie F, de Almeida D, Dreesen P, Thijs I, Vranken J, Klerkx S (2018) An evaluation of the NightOwl home sleep apnea testing system. J Clin Sleep Med 14:1791&#x2013;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.7398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30353811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Wang C, Shin H (2024) FDA-cleared home sleep apnea testing devices. NPJ Digit Med 7:123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01112-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38740907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe1;zaro J, Gil E, Vergara JM, Laguna P (2012) OSAS detection in children by using PPG amplitude fluctuation decreases and pulse rate variability. 2012 Comput Cardiol, p. 185&#x2013;188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioan I, Schweitzer C, Touil Y, Da Mota S, Coutier L, Guyon A et al (2025) Respiratory polygraphy combined with pulse wave amplitude drops for the diagnosis of obstructive sleep apnea in pediatric patients. Sleep Med. 10.1016/j.sleep.2025.106618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2025.106618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40483836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaddeo A, Medjahdi N, Fernandez-Bolanos M, Khirani S, Baffet G, Fauroux B (2017) Pulse wave amplitude reduction as a surrogate for cortical arousal during sleep hypopnea in children. Sleep Med 34:64&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2017.02.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hietakoste S, Karhu T, Sillanm&#xe4;ki S, Bail&#xf3;n R, Penzel T, T&#xf6;yr&#xe4;s J et al (2022) Obstructive sleep apnoea-related respiratory events and desaturation severity are associated with the cardiac response. ERJ Open Res. 10.1183/23120541.00121-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00121-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36299363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayano J, Watanabe E, Saito Y, Sasaki F, Fujimoto K, Nomiyama T et al (2011) Screening for obstructive sleep apnea by cyclic variation of heart rate. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol 4:64&#x2013;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCEP.110.958009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papini GB, Fonseca P, van Gilst MM, Bergmans JWM, Vullings R, Overeem S (2020) Wearable monitoring of sleep-disordered breathing: estimation of the apnea&#x2013;hypopnea index using wrist-worn reflective photoplethysmography. Sci Rep 10:13512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-69935-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7421543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deviaene M, L&#xe1;zaro J, Huysmans D, Testelmans D, Buyse B, Van Huffel S et al (2018) Sleep apnea detection using pulse photoplethysmography. Comput Cardiol conf (CinC) 45:1&#x2013;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayano J, Yamamoto H, Nonaka I, Komazawa M, Itao K, Ueda N et al (2020) Quantitative detection of sleep apnea with wearable watch device. PLoS One 15:e0237279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0237279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delessert A, Espa F, Rossetti A, Lavigne G, Tafti M, Heinzer R (2010) Pulse wave amplitude drops during sleep are reliable surrogate markers of changes in cortical activity. Sleep 33:1687&#x2013;1692</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/33.12.1687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2982739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21120131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukinen M, Pitk&#xe4;nen H, Lepp&#xe4;nen T, T&#xf6;yr&#xe4;s J, Islind AS, Kainulainen S et al (2024) Variation in the photoplethysmogram response to arousal from sleep depending on the cause of arousal and the presence of desaturation. IEEE J Transl Eng Health Med 12:328&#x2013;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JTEHM.2024.3349916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10914203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38444399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuptimdang W, Shah P, Khaleel M, Sunwoo J, Veluswamy S, Kato RM et al (2021) Vasoconstriction response to mental stress in sickle cell disease: the role of the cardiac and vascular baroreflexes. Front Physiol 12:698209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.698209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34803725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karavaev AS, Borovik AS, Borovkova EI, Orlova EA, Simonyan MA, Ponomarenko VI et al (2021) Low-frequency component of photoplethysmogram reflects the autonomic control of blood pressure. Biophys J 120:2657&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2021.05.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34087217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Xiang L, Long Y, Xun Q, Kuang J, He L (2023) Cluster analysis of clinical phenotypic heterogeneity in obstructive sleep apnea assessed using photoplethysmography. Sleep Med 102:134&#x2013;141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2022.12.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry RB, Brooks R, Gamaldo CE, Harding SM, Lloyd RM, Marcus CL et al (2020) The AASM manual for the scoring of sleep and associated events: Rules, terminology and technical Specifications. Version 2.6. American Academy of Sleep Medicine, Darien, IL</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task Force (1996) Heart rate variability. Standards of measurement, physiological interpretation, and clinical use. Task force of the European society of cardiology and the North American society for pacing and electrophysiology. Eur Heart J 17:354&#x2013;381. 10.1161/01.CIR.93.5.1043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.93.5.1043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8737210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch P (2003) The use of fast fourier transform for the estimation of power spectra: a method based on time averaging over short, modified periodograms. IEEE Trans Audio Electroacoust 15:70&#x2013;73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAU.1967.1161901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padovano D, Martinez-Rodrigo A, Pastor JM, Rieta JJ, Alcaraz R (2022) On the generalization of sleep apnea detection methods based on heart rate variability and machine learning. IEEE Access 10:92710&#x2013;92725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3201911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-C, Lin C-J (2011) A library for support vector machines. ACM Trans Intell Syst Technol (TIST) 2:1&#x2013;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/1961189.1961199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Chazal P, Heneghan C, Sheridan E, Reilly R, Nolan P, O&#x2019;Malley M (2003) Automated processing of the single-lead electrocardiogram for the detection of obstructive sleep apnoea. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng 50:686&#x2013;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2003.812203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12814235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers DMW (2020) Evaluation: from precision, recall and F-measure to ROC, informedness, markedness and correlation. ArXiv Preprint ArXiv :201016061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen J (2007) Photoplethysmography and its application in clinical physiological measurement. Physiol Meas 28:R1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0967-3334/28/3/R01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17322588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepp&#xe4;nen T, Kulkas A, Oksenberg A, Duce B, Mervaala E, T&#xf6;yr&#xe4;s J (2018) Differences in arousal probability and duration after apnea and hypopnea events in adult obstructive sleep apnea patients. Physiol Meas 39:114004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-6579/aae42c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30251964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salles GF, Ribeiro FM, Guimaraes GM, Muxfeldt ES, Cardoso CRL (2014) A reduced heart rate variability is independently associated with a blunted nocturnal blood pressure fall in patients with resistant hypertension. J Hypertens 32:644&#x2013;651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000000068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Mo Z, Sui H, Qi Y, Xu P, Zheng J et al (2023) Association of baseline and dynamic arterial stiffness status with dyslipidemia: a cohort study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 14:1243673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1243673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10704037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38075050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>