<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41367390</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Web-based high-intensity bodyweight interval training improves metabolic health and physical fitness outcomes in middle-aged men with obesity during the COVID-19 pandemic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1711436</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1711436</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1711436</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1711436</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Reduced opportunities for physical activity during the COVID-19 pandemic have heightened obesity-related health risks, emphasizing the need for effective, scalable, and remotely deliverable exercise interventions. This randomized controlled trial examined the efficacy of an 8-week, real-time, supervised, web-based high-intensity interval training (HIIT) program in improving metabolic health and physical fitness in middle-aged men with obesity. Twenty-two men (age &lt;45 years; BMI &gt;30 kg/m<sup>2</sup>; waist circumference &gt;90 cm) were assigned to a videoconference-based HIIT intervention or a non-exercise control group. The HIIT group completed two supervised sessions per week, each consisting of a standardized warm-up, a 20-min HIIT protocol, and a cool-down, with real-time monitoring and weekly dietary log reviews. Web-based HIIT significantly reduced fat mass by 6.6% (-2.01 kg; <i>d</i> = 1.38) without altering total body weight and improved lipid profiles by increasing HDL cholesterol and decreasing total and LDL cholesterol. Leptin levels decreased, adiponectin increased, and IL-10 rose, whereas IL-6 remained unchanged. Cardiorespiratory fitness improved, with VO<sub>2</sub>max increasing by 3.06 mL&#xb7;kg<sup>-1</sup>&#xb7;min<sup>-1</sup> (&#x223c;8.7%) and minute ventilation increasing, and muscle performance was enhanced, as trunk extensor peak torque and average power increased by 9.7% and 30.2%, respectively, and knee flexor peak torque increased by 31.8% (right) and 19.5% (left), yielding large effect sizes (<i>d</i> = 0.9-1.3). These findings indicate that real-time, non-face-to-face HIIT effectively enhances body composition, lipid metabolism, inflammatory balance, aerobic capacity, and functional muscle performance in men with obesity, supporting this contactless modality as a feasible and deployable strategy for health maintenance during and beyond pandemic-related restrictions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Hwang, Choi and Hyun.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Dong-Joo</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biochemistry Laboratory, Korea National Sport University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Science Institute, Korea National Sport University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Dong-Hun</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Konyang University, Nonsan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hyun</LastName><ForeName>Ah-Hyun</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Military Kinesiology, Korea Military Academy, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-intensity interval training (HIIT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">web-based exercise intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41367390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12682630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1711436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1711436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahl S., Guenther M., Zhao S., James R., Marks J., Szabo A., et al. (2015). Adiponectin levels differentiate metabolically healthy vs unhealthy among obese and Nonobese white individuals. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 100, 4172&#x2013;4180. 10.1210/jc.2015-2765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2015-2765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26401592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreato L. V., Esteves J. V., Coimbra D. R., Moraes A. J. P., De Carvalho T. (2019). The influence of high-intensity interval training on anthropometric variables of adults with overweight or obesity: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Obes. Rev. 20, 142&#x2013;155. 10.1111/obr.12766</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30450794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellissimo G. F., Bailly A., Bourbeau K., Mermier C., Campitelli A., Berkemeier Q., et al. (2025). Impact of exercise video-guided bodyweight interval training on psychophysiological outcomes in inactive adults with obesity. Front. Physiol. 16, 1527171. 10.3389/fphys.2025.1527171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1527171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40247925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies K. A., Sprung V. S., Norman J. A., Thompson A., Mitchell K. L., Halford J. C. G., et al. (2018). Short-term decreased physical activity with increased sedentary behaviour causes metabolic derangements and altered body composition: effects in individuals with and without a first-degree relative with type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia 61, 1282&#x2013;1294. 10.1007/s00125-018-4603-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-018-4603-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casta&#xf1;eda-Babarro A., Arbillaga-Etxarri A., Guti&#xe9;rrez-Santamar&#xed;a B., Coca A. (2020). Physical activity change during COVID-19 confinement. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 17, 6878. 10.3390/ijerph17186878</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17186878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32967091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatfield S. L., Gamble A., Hallam J. S. (2018). Men's preferences for physical activity interventions: an exploratory study using a factorial survey design created with R software. Am. J. Mens. Health 12, 347&#x2013;358. 10.1177/1557988316643316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1557988316643316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5818111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27059629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiappetta S., Sharma A. M., Bottino V., Stier C. (2020). COVID-19 and the role of chronic inflammation in patients with obesity. Int. J. Obes. (Lond) 44, 1790&#x2013;1792. 10.1038/s41366-020-0597-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-020-0597-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codella R., Chirico A., Lucidi F., Ferrulli A., La Torre A., Luzi L. (2021). The immune-modulatory effects of exercise should be favorably harnessed against COVID-19. J. Endocrinol. Invest 44, 1119&#x2013;1122. 10.1007/s40618-020-01403-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40618-020-01403-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva M. a. R., Baptista L. C., Neves R. S., De Fran&#xe7;a E., Loureiro H., Lira F. S., et al. (2020). The effects of concurrent training combining both resistance exercise and high-intensity interval training or moderate-intensity continuous training on metabolic syndrome. Front. Physiol. 11, 572. 10.3389/fphys.2020.00572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silveira M. P., Da Silva Fagundes K. K., Bizuti M. R., Starck &#xc9;., Rossi R. C., De Resende E. S. D. T. (2021). Physical exercise as a tool to help the immune system against COVID-19: an integrative review of the current literature. Clin. Exp. Med. 21, 15&#x2013;28. 10.1007/s10238-020-00650-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10238-020-00650-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashti N., Rezaeian N., Karimi M., Kooroshfard N. (2021). The effect of high intensity interval training on serum levels of osteopontin and insulin resistance index in sedentary overweight and Obese women. J. Sport Exerc. Physiology 14, 115&#x2013;126. 10.52547/joeppa.14.2.115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52547/joeppa.14.2.115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira Neto L., Elsangedy H. M., De Oliveira Tavares V. D., Teixeira C. V. L. S., Behm D. G., Da Silva-Grigoletto M. E. (2020). # traininginhome-home-based training during COVID-19 (SARS-COV2) pandemic: physical exercise and behavior-based approach. Rev. Bras. Fisiol. do Exerc&#xed;cio 19, 9&#x2013;19. 10.33233/rbfe.v19i2.4006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33233/rbfe.v19i2.4006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denay K. L., Breslow R. G., Turner M. N., Nieman D. C., Roberts W. O., Best T. M. (2020). ACSM call to action statement: COVID-19 considerations for sports and physical activity. Curr. Sports Med. Rep. 19, 326&#x2013;328. 10.1249/jsr.0000000000000739</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/jsr.0000000000000739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32769667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey S., Murmu N., Bose M., Ghosh S., Giri B. (2021). Obesity and chronic leptin resistance foster insulin resistance: an analytical overview. BLDE Univ. J. Health Sci. 6, 7&#x2013;21. 10.4103/bjhs.bjhs_29_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/bjhs.bjhs_29_20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Filippo L., De Lorenzo R., Sciorati C., Capobianco A., Lor&#xe8; N. I., Giustina A., et al. (2021). Adiponectin to leptin ratio reflects inflammatory burden and survival in COVID-19. Diabetes Metab. 47, 101268. 10.1016/j.diabet.2021.101268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabet.2021.101268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulin A. J., Dunsiger S., Benitez T., Larsen B., Marcus B. H., Champion G., et al. (2023). The hombres saludables physical activity web-based and Mobile phone intervention: pilot randomized controlled trial with Latino men. J. Med. Internet Res. 25, e39310. 10.2196/39310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/39310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10739242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38060285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favre G., Legueult K., Pradier C., Raffaelli C., Ichai C., Iannelli A., et al. (2021). Visceral fat is associated to the severity of COVID-19. Metabolism 115, 154440. 10.1016/j.metabol.2020.154440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2020.154440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtado G. E., Letieri R. V., Caldo-Silva A., Sard&#xe3;o V. A., Teixeira A. M., De Barros M. P., et al. (2021). Sustaining efficient immune functions with regular physical exercise in the COVID-19 era and beyond. Eur. J. Clin. Invest 51, e13485. 10.1111/eci.13485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33393082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M., Wang Q., Piernas C., Astbury N. M., Jebb S. A., Holmes M. V., et al. (2022). Associations between body composition, fat distribution and metabolic consequences of excess adiposity with severe COVID-19 outcomes: observational study and Mendelian randomisation analysis. Int. J. Obes. (Lond) 46, 943&#x2013;950. 10.1038/s41366-021-01054-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-021-01054-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35031696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gerosa-Neto J., Monteiro P. A., Inoue D. S., Antunes B. M., Batatinha H., Dorneles G. P., et al.  (2020). High- and moderate-intensity training modify LPS-Induced <i>ex-vivo</i> interleukin-10 production in Obese men in response to an acute exercise bout. Cytokine
136, 155249. 10.1016/j.cyto.2020.155249

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2020.155249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32829109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldi L., Miele L., Aleksovska K., Manca F., Leoncini E., Biolato M., et al. (2020). Mediterranean diet and the prevention of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: results from a case-control study. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 24, 7391&#x2013;7398. 10.26355/eurrev_202007_21907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202007_21907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes L. D., Herbert P., Sculthorpe N., Grace F. (2020). High intensity interval training (HIIT) produces small improvements in fasting glucose, insulin, and insulin resistance in sedentary older men but not masters athletes. Exp. Gerontol. 140, 111074. 10.1016/j.exger.2020.111074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2020.111074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand Moghadam B., Golestani F., Bagheri R., Cheraghloo N., Eskandari M., Wong A., et al. (2021). The effects of high-intensity interval training vs. moderate-intensity continuous training on inflammatory markers, body composition, and physical fitness in overweight/Obese survivors of breast cancer: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Cancers (Basel) 13, 4386. 10.3390/cancers13174386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers13174386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8430701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34503198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortmann K., Boutouyrie P., Locatelli J. C., De Oliveira G. H., Sim&#xf5;es C. F., De Souza Mendes V. H., et al. (2021). Acute effects of high-intensity interval training and moderate-intensity continuous training on arterial stiffness in young obese women. Eur. J. Prev. Cardiol. 28, e7&#x2013;e10. 10.1177/2047487320909302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487320909302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34247226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovsepian V., Marandi S. M., Esfarjani F., Zavar R., Sadeghi M. (2021). The effect of all extremity high intensity interval training on athero-protective factors and endothelial function in overweight and Obese women. Int. J. Prev. Med. 12, 141. 10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_248_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_248_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8631139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyun A.-H. (2021). Effect of real-time online high-intensity interval training on physiological and physical parameters for abdominally obese women: a randomized pilot study. Appl. Sci. 11, 12129. 10.3390/app112412129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app112412129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelleyman C., Yates T., O'donovan G., Gray L. J., King J. A., Khunti K., et al. (2015). The effects of high-intensity interval training on glucose regulation and insulin resistance: a meta-analysis. Obes. Rev. 16, 942&#x2013;961. 10.1111/obr.12317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose R. J., Manuel A. (2020). COVID-19 cytokine storm: the interplay between inflammation and coagulation. Lancet Respir. Med. 8, e46&#x2013;e47. 10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30216-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30216-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Keating S. E., Johnson N. A., Mielke G. I., Coombes J. S. (2017). A systematic review and meta-analysis of interval training <i>versus</i> moderate-intensity continuous training on body adiposity. Obes. Rev.
18, 943&#x2013;964. 10.1111/obr.12536

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28513103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshavarz M., S&#xe9;n&#xe9;chal M., Bouchard D. R. (2023). Online circuit training increases adherence to physical activity: a randomized controlled trial of men with obesity. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 55, 2308&#x2013;2315. 10.1249/mss.0000000000003270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000003270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37535330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M., Symonds M. E. (2021). The impact of high intensity interval training on liver fat content in overweight or Obese adults: a meta-analysis. Physiol. Behav. 236, 113416. 10.1016/j.physbeh.2021.113416</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2021.113416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanevari T., Rohani H., Vakili J., Sari Sarraf V. (2021). Effect of high-intensity interval training on leptin, adiponectin, and leptin/adiponectin ratio in overweight adolescent boys. Sci. Mag. yafte 23, 43&#x2013;56. 10.32592/Yafteh.2021.23.3.5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32592/Yafteh.2021.23.3.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompaniyets L., Goodman A. B., Belay B., Freedman D. S., Sucosky M. S., Lange S. J., et al. (2021). Body mass index and risk for COVID-19-Related hospitalization, intensive care unit admission, invasive mechanical ventilation, and death - united States, march-december 2020. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 70, 355&#x2013;361. 10.15585/mmwr.mm7010e4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7010e4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7951819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus W. E., Janz K. F., Powell K. E., Campbell W. W., Jakicic J. M., Troiano R. P., et al. (2019). Daily step counts for measuring physical activity exposure and its relation to health. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 51, 1206&#x2013;1212. 10.1249/mss.0000000000001932</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000001932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok S., Adam S., Ho J. H., Iqbal Z., Turkington P., Razvi S., et al. (2020). Obesity: a critical risk factor in the COVID-19 pandemic. Clin. Obes. 10, e12403. 10.1111/cob.12403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cob.12403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32857454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson A., Lipcsey M., Hultstr&#xf6;m M., Frithiof R., Eriksson M. (2021). Plasma leptin is increased in intensive care patients with COVID-19-An investigation performed in the PronMed-Cohort. Biomedicines 10, 4. 10.3390/biomedicines10010004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10010004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35052684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis B. A., Schuver K., Dunsiger S. (2023). Evaluating the feasibility and efficacy of a home-based combined high intensity interval and moderate intensity training program for increasing physical activity among low-active adults: a randomized pilot trial. PLoS One 18, e0281985. 10.1371/journal.pone.0281985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0281985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9942957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36809292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Li Z., Liu Y., Han X., Zhou Z. (2023). Effects of running-based <i>versus</i> body-weight-based high-intensity interval training on physical fitness in healthy adolescents. Front. Physiol.
14, 1060216. 10.3389/fphys.2023.1060216

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1060216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10036788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P., Taaffe D. R., Galv&#xe3;o D. A., Newton R. U., Nonemacher E. R., Wendt V. M., et al. (2022). Resistance training effectiveness on body composition and body weight outcomes in individuals with overweight and obesity across the lifespan: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes. Rev. 23, e13428. 10.1111/obr.13428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35191588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luzi L., Radaelli M. G. (2020). Influenza and obesity: its odd relationship and the lessons for COVID-19 pandemic. Acta Diabetol. 57, 759&#x2013;764. 10.1007/s00592-020-01522-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00592-020-01522-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7130453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32249357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marterer N., Menz V., Amin S., Faulhaber M. (2020). 6-week high-intensity interval training (HIIT) of the lower extremities improves VO2max of the upper extremities. Int. J. Sports Med. 41, 380&#x2013;390. 10.1055/a-1073-8016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1073-8016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32045953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurya R., Sebastian P., Namdeo M., Devender M., Gertler A. (2021). COVID-19 severity in obesity: Leptin and inflammatory cytokine interplay in the link between high morbidity and mortality. Front. Immunol. 12, 649359. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.649359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.649359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34220807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley A. W., Carroll S. (2009). Emergence of the verification phase procedure for confirming 'true' VO(2max). Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 19, 313&#x2013;322. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.00898.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.00898.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19422662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanovi&#x107; Z., Spori&#x161; G., Weston M. (2015). Effectiveness of high-Intensity Interval training (HIT) and continuous endurance training for VO2max improvements: a systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Sports Med. 45, 1469&#x2013;1481. 10.1007/s40279-015-0365-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0365-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26243014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto-Mikami E., Tsuji K., Horii N., Hasegawa N., Fujie S., Homma T., et al. (2018). Gene expression profile of muscle adaptation to high-intensity intermittent exercise training in young men. Sci. Rep. 8, 16811. 10.1038/s41598-018-35115-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-35115-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6235852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montserrat-De La Paz S., P&#xe9;rez-P&#xe9;rez A., Vilari&#xf1;o-Garc&#xed;a T., Jim&#xe9;nez-Cortegana C., Muriana F. J. G., Mill&#xe1;n-Linares M. C., et al. (2021). Nutritional modulation of leptin expression and leptin action in obesity and obesity-associated complications. J. Nutr. Biochem. 89, 108561. 10.1016/j.jnutbio.2020.108561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnutbio.2020.108561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motiani K. K., Savolainen A. M., Toivanen J., Eskelinen J. J., Yli-Karjanmaa M., Virtanen K. A., et al. (2019). Effects of short-term sprint interval and moderate-intensity continuous training on liver fat content, lipoprotein profile, and substrate uptake: a randomized trial. J. Appl. Physiol. 126, 1756&#x2013;1768. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00900.2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00900.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6620664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30998125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyibo K., Vassileva J. (2020). Gender preference and difference in behavior modeling in fitness applications: a mixed-method approach. Multimodal Technol. Interact. 4, 21. 10.3390/mti4020021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mti4020021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrone M. A., Feola A., Pieri M., Donatucci B., Salimei C., Lombardo M., et al. (2021). The effects of reduced physical activity on the lipid profile in patients with high cardiovascular risk during COVID-19 lockdown. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18, 8858. 10.3390/ijerph18168858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18168858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin B. M., Du S., Green W. D., Beck M. A., Algaith T., Herbst C. H., et al. (2020). Individuals with obesity and COVID-19: a global perspective on the epidemiology and biological relationships. Obes. Rev. 21, e13128. 10.1111/obr.13128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto Gonz&#xe1;lez P., Sedlacek J. (2021). Comparison of the efficacy of three types of strength training: body, weight training machines and free weights. Apunts Educ. F&#xed;sica Deport. 145, 9&#x2013;16. 10.5672/apunts.2014-0983.es</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5672/apunts.2014-0983.es</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricketts T. A., Sui X., Lavie C. J., Blair S. N., Ross R. (2016). Addition of cardiorespiratory fitness within an obesity risk classification model identifies men at increased risk of all-cause mortality. Am. J. Med. 129, 536.e13&#x2013;536.e5.36E20. 10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.11.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26642906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan B. J., Schleh M. W., Ahn C., Ludzki A. C., Gillen J. B., Varshney P., et al. (2020). Moderate-intensity exercise and high-intensity interval training affect insulin sensitivity similarly in Obese adults. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 105, e2941&#x2013;e2959. 10.1210/clinem/dgaa345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgaa345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis R., Young D. R., Tartof S. Y., Sallis J. F., Sall J., Li Q., et al. (2021). Physical inactivity is associated with a higher risk for severe COVID-19 outcomes: a study in 48 440 adult patients. Br. J. Sports Med. 55, 1099&#x2013;1105. 10.1136/bjsports-2021-104080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-104080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33849909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvadori A., Fanari P., Marzullo P., Codecasa F., Tovaglieri I., Cornacchia M., et al. (2021). Playing around the anaerobic threshold during COVID-19 pandemic: advantages and disadvantages of adding bouts of anaerobic work to aerobic activity in physical treatment of individuals with obesity. Acta Diabetol. 58, 1329&#x2013;1341. 10.1007/s00592-021-01747-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00592-021-01747-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8159723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34047810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchis-Gomar F., Lavie C. J., Neeland I. J., Lippi G. (2021). Does abdominal obesity influence immunological response to SARS-CoV-2 infection? Expert Rev. Endocrinol. Metab. 16, 271&#x2013;272. 10.1080/17446651.2021.1979392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17446651.2021.1979392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34533093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaun G. Z., Pinto S. S., Silva M. R., Dolinski D. B., Alberton C. L. (2018). Whole-body high-intensity interval training induce similar cardiorespiratory adaptations compared with traditional high-intensity interval training and moderate-intensity continuous training in healthy men. J. Strength Cond. Res. 32, 2730&#x2013;2742. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000002594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29746386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwendinger F., Pocecco E. (2020). Counteracting physical inactivity during the COVID-19 pandemic: evidence-based recommendations for home-based exercise. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 17, 3909. 10.3390/ijerph17113909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17113909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7311977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stebbing J., Phelan A., Griffin I., Tucker C., Oechsle O., Smith D., et al. (2020). COVID-19: combining antiviral and anti-inflammatory treatments. Lancet Infect. Dis. 20, 400&#x2013;402. 10.1016/s1473-3099(20)30132-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1473-3099(20)30132-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32113509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J., Androulakis-Korakakis P., Carlson L., Williams D., Phillips S., Smith D., et al. (2021). The impact of coronavirus (COVID-19) related public-health measures on training behaviours of individuals previously participating in resistance training: a cross-sectional survey study. Sports Med. 51, 1561&#x2013;1580. 10.1007/s40279-021-01438-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01438-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33871831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson L., Keshavarz M., S&#xe9;n&#xe9;chal M., Bouchard D. R. (2023). Online exercise program for men living with obesity: experiences, barriers, and enablers. Contemp. Clin. Trials Commun. 36, 101226. 10.1016/j.conctc.2023.101226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2023.101226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10681938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38034839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinity J. D., Craig J. C., Fermoyle C. C., Mckenzie A. I., Lewis M. T., Park S. H., et al. (2021). Impact of presymptomatic COVID-19 on vascular and skeletal muscle function: a case study. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 130, 1961&#x2013;1970. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00236.2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00236.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyas N. (2021). Cytokine storm in COVID-19: a thing to worry about or not. Int. Case Rep. Jour 1 (2)&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2020) &#x201c;Considerations for sports federations/sports event organizers when planning mass gatherings in the context of COVID-19: interim guidance, 14 April 2020,&#x201d; in Considerations for sports federations/sports event organizers when planning mass gatherings in the context of COVID-19: interim guidance, 14 April 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Zhong L., Deng J., Peng J., Dan H., Zeng X., et al. (2020). High expression of ACE2 receptor of 2019-nCoV on the epithelial cells of oral mucosa. Int. J. Oral Sci. 12, 8. 10.1038/s41368-020-0074-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41368-020-0074-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32094336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhang B., Gan L., Ke L., Fu Y., Di Q., et al. (2021). Effects of online bodyweight high-intensity interval training intervention and health education on the mental health and cognition of sedentary young females. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18, 302. 10.3390/ijerph18010302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18010302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7795383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>