<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41554896</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resonance suppression method for single-phase LCL Grid-tied inverter based on active damping superposition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5708</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5708</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5708</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36873-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">LCL filters have superior high-frequency harmonic suppression capabilities and have been widely used in grid connected inverters. In order to suppress the inherent resonance peak of LCL filters, active damping method is usually used. Although this control strategy suppresses the resonance peak, the delay of digital control will cause the inherent resonance point to shift. A control strategy based on virtual impedance model and active damping superposition is proposed to address the above issues. It suppresses resonance peaks while avoiding the displacement of the natural resonance point, and expands the effective damping area to (0, <i>f</i><sub><i>s</i></sub>/3). Finally, the correctness of the control strategy is verified by building a simulation system and a hardware in the loop semi physical prototype of an LCL single-phase grid connected inverter. The experimental results show that it has good anti-interference ability, dynamic performance, and steady-state performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-36873-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dongdong</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Electrical Engineering, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, Fujian, China. cdd1911@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Industrial Automation Control Technology and Application of Fujian Higher Education, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, China. cdd1911@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mingwei</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Fujian Electric Power Co.,Ltd, Quanzhou Power Supply Company, Quanzhou, 362011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shengqi</LastName><ForeName>Zhang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Electrical Engineering, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, Fujian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Industrial Automation Control Technology and Application of Fujian Higher Education, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nuan</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Electrical Engineering, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, Fujian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Industrial Automation Control Technology and Application of Fujian Higher Education, Minnan University of Science and Technology, Quanzhou, 362700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024J01208</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Fujian Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024QZC004R</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of Quanzhou City</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Damping superposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Effective damping zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LCL filter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual impedance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41554896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12891644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36873-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36873-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blaabjerg, F. et al. Overview of control and grid synchronization for distributed power generation systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Electron.</i><b>53</b>, 1398&#x2013;1409 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2006.881997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hava, A. M., Lipo, T. A. &amp; Erdman, W. L. Utility interface issues for line connected PWM voltage source converters: a comparative study. <i>Proceedings of IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition-APEC&#x2019;95</i>. Vol. 1. IEEE, 1995. Vol. 1. IEEE, 1995. (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liserre, M., Teodorescu, R. &amp; Blaabjerg, F. Stability of grid-connected PV inverters with large grid impedance variation. <i>IEEE 35th annual power electronics specialists conference (IEEE Cat. No. 04CH37551)</i>. Vol. 6. IEEE, 2004. Vol. 6. IEEE, 2004. (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liserre, M., Blaabjerg, F. &amp; Hansen, S. Design and control of an LCL-filter-based three-phase active rectifier. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl.</i><b>41</b> (5), 1281&#x2013;1291 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIA.2005.853373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahono, P. et al. Damping of transient oscillations on the output LC filter of PWM inverters by using a virtual resistor. <i>4th IEEE International Conference on Power Electronics and Drive Systems. IEEE PEDS 2001-Indonesia. Proceedings (Cat. No. 01TH8594)</i>. Vol. 1. IEEE, (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Capacitor-voltage feedforward with full delay compensation to improve weak grids adaptability of LCL-filtered grid-connected converters for distributed generation systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>33</b> (1), 749&#x2013;764 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2017.2665483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B. et al. Stability analysis of LCL-type grid-connected inverter under single-loop inverter-side current control with capacitor voltage feedforward. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Inf.</i><b>14</b> (2), 691&#x2013;702 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2017.2766890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Hybrid active damping combining capacitor current feedback and point of common coupling voltage feedforward for LCL-type grid-connected inverter. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>36</b> (2), 2373&#x2013;2383 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2020.3008160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez, J., Manuel, C. A., Busada, Jorge, A. &amp; Solsona A robust controller for a grid-tied inverter connected through an LCL filter. <i>IEEE J. Emerg. Sel. Top. Industrial Electron.</i><b>2</b> (1), 82&#x2013;89 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JESTIE.2020.3014834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Unified active damping strategy based on generalized virtual impedance in LCL-type grid-connected inverter. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Electron.</i><b>70</b>, 8129&#x2013;8139 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2022.3232647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, Y. et al. Integrated design of filter and controller parameters for low-switching-frequency grid-connected inverter based on harmonic state-space model. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>38</b>, 6455&#x2013;6473 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2023.3241091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Ruan, X. &amp; Liu, S. Control strategy for grid-connected inverter to suppress current distortion effected by background harmonics in grid voltage. <i>Proceedings of the CSEE</i> 31.6 : 7&#x2013;14. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem, Muhammad, K. Y., Choi &amp; Kim, R. Y. Resonance damping for an LCL filter type grid-connected inverter with active disturbance rejection control under grid impedance uncertainty. <i>International Journal of Power and Energy Systems</i> 109&#xa0;C.JUL.:444&#x2013;454. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, W. et al. Active disturbance rejection control based single current feedback resonance damping strategy for LCL-type Grid-connected inverter. <i>IEEE Trans. Energy Convers.</i><b>36</b> (1), 48&#x2013;62 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2020.3006151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J. et al. Coevolutionary neural dynamics considering multiple strategies for nonconvex optimization. <i>Tsinghua Sci. Technol.</i>10.26599/TST.2025.9010120 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/TST.2025.9010120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M. et al. Activated gradients for deep neural networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Neural Networks Learn. Syst.</i><b>34</b>, 13 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34469312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, L., Wei, L. &amp; Li, S. Gradient-Based differential Neural-Solution to Time-Dependent nonlinear Optimization. <i>Automatic control</i>. <i>IEEE Trans. (T-AC)</i>. <b>68</b>, 8 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. &amp; Lin, H. Passivity enhancement-based general design of capacitor current active damping for LCL-type grid-tied inverter. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>38</b>, 8223&#x2013;8236 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2023.3265630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao, C. et al. Design of grid-connected inverters with LCL filter based on PI regulator and capacitor current feedback active damping. <i>Zhongguo Dianji Gongcheng Xuebao(Proceedings of the Chinese Society of Electrical Engineering)</i>. Vol. 32. No. 25. Chinese Society for Electrical Engineering, (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jikai, C. H. A. N. G. et al. Resonance characteristics and suppression of grid-connected inverter system considering cable distributed capacitance. <i>J. Electr. Power Sci. Technol.</i><b>38</b> (3), 114&#x2013;123 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ming, Y. A. N. G. et al. New type capacittive voltage active damping strategy for LCL grid-connected inverter. <i>Acta Energiae Solaris Sinica</i>. <b>44</b> (2), 399&#x2013;408 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, M., Mizanur, Abdel-Rady, Y. &amp; Mohamed, I. Interaction dynamics and active suppression of instability in parallel photovoltaic voltage-and current-source converters connected to a weak grid. <i>IEEE Open. J. Power Electron.</i><b>4</b>, 395&#x2013;414 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/OJPEL.2023.3275610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M., Cheng, M. &amp; Huafeng Xiao, and An adaptive strategy based on repetitive predictive control for improving adaptability of LCL-type grid-connected inverters under weak grid. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>37</b> (3), 2562&#x2013;2572 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2021.3108878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. E. &amp; Cui, K. Grid-Connected inverter grid voltage feedforward control strategy based on Multi-Objective constraint in weak grid. <i>Energies</i><b>17</b> (13), 3288 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17133288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing, G. et al. Capacitor Voltage Feedforward With Delay Compensation for LCL-Type Grid-Connected Inverter. <i>2024 IEEE 10th International Power Electronics and Motion Control Conference (IPEMC-ECCE Asia)</i>. IEEE, 2024. IEEE, 2024. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Active damping control for LCL filters with inverter-side current feedback only. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>37</b>, 10065&#x2013;10069 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2022.3159229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Z. et al. Full grid voltage feedforward for critical mode LCL-type single-phase grid-tied inverters with physical interpretations. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>38</b> (4), 5283&#x2013;5295 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2023.3236643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, X. &amp; Zhang, H. Quasi-proportional resonant control of the LCL-type grid-connected inverter based on fuzzy control and self-tuning of fuzzy parameters. <i>29th Chinese Control And Decision Conference (CCDC)</i>. IEEE, 2017. IEEE, 2017. (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, R. et al. An H&#x2009;&#x221e;&#x2009;filter based active damping control strategy for grid-connected inverters with LCL filter applied to wind power system. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>144</b>, 108590 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2022.108590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani, H., Abbaszadeh, K., Karimi, M. H. &amp; Gyselinck, J. Adaptive model predictive control for LCL-Filter Grid-Tied inverters. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Electron.</i><b>71.8</b>, 8903&#x2013;8914 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2023.3325574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. et al. An Active Damping Method with Differential Feedback of Filter Capacitance Voltage for LCL Filter Based Grid-connected Inverters. <i>2022 IEEE Transportation Electrification Conference and Expo, Asia-Pacific (ITEC Asia-Pacific)</i>. IEEE, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasekh, N. &amp; Hosseinpour, M. Adequate tuning of LCL filter for robust performance of converter side current feedback control of grid connected modified&#x2013;Y-source inverter. <i>Int. J. Industrial Electron. Control Optim.</i><b>3</b> (3), 365&#x2013;378 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, X. U., Shude, Y. A. N. G. &amp; Xinwen, Z. H. A. N. G. Current-Harmonic-Based active damping strategy. <i>Electr. Power</i>. <b>56</b> (8), 126&#x2013;135 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. &amp; Lin, H. A capacitor-current-feedback positive active damping control strategy for LCL-type grid-connected inverter to achieve high robustness. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>37</b>, 6462&#x2013;6474 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2021.3137845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z. et al. LADRC-based grid-connected control strategy for single-phase LCL-type inverters. <i>Plos One</i>. <b>19</b>, e0303591 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0303591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38748696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab, N., Vahedi, H. &amp; Al-Haddad, K. LQR control of single-phase grid-tied PUC5 inverter with LCL filter. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Electron.</i><b>67</b> (1), 297&#x2013;307 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2019.2897544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhe, W., Ishak, D. &amp; Muhammad Najwan, H. A Grid-Connected Inverter with Grid-Voltage-Weighted Feedforward Control Based on the Quasi-Proportional Resonance Controller for Suppressing Grid Voltage Disturbances. <i>Energies</i> 17.4 : 885. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayalath, S. &amp; Hanif, M. An LCL-filter design with optimum total inductance and capacitance. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>33</b>, 6687&#x2013;6698 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2017.2754100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T. et al. A study of virtual resistor-based active damping alternatives for LCL resonance in grid-connected voltage source inverters. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>35</b> (1), 247&#x2013;262 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2019.2911163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, Y. et al. An active damping method with improved grid current feedback. <i>Proc. CSEE</i> 38 : 5557&#x2013;5567. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi, M. et al. A theoretical concept of decoupled current control scheme for grid-connected inverter with LCL filter. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>11</b>, 6256 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11146256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, D. et al. Active damping of LCL-Filtered Grid-Connected inverter based on parallel feedforward compensation strategy. <i>Ain Shams Eng. J.</i><b>14.3</b>, 101902 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asej.2022.101902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>