<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41665832</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1863-2491</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of robotic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Robot Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Smarter bones: AI &amp; robotics revolutionise orthopedic surgery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>235</StartPage><MedlinePgn>235</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">235</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11701-026-03208-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Artificial intelligence (AI) and robotics are changing the way orthopedic surgery is performed and taught. This review, conducted using a systematic review approach, looks at how these technologies are being used today, what benefits they bring, what challenges remain, and how they may shape the future. The study focuses on two main areas: surgical improvements and medical training. In surgery, tools such as robotic navigation, motion control systems, and smart prediction models help doctors work with greater accuracy. In education, simulation platforms and AI support systems are giving trainees more confidence and helping them learn faster. The review is based on recent research, including large studies and clinical reports. Results show that robotic-assisted procedures, especially knee operations and fracture repairs, can improve accuracy, reduce complications, and make surgical tasks smoother. Training platforms powered by data also help reduce skills gaps. However, there are still concerns. These include the high cost of adopting technology, limited long-term patient data, and difficulties applying AI models to different healthcare settings. Unequal access to advanced tools and a lack of standard training systems are also slow progress. The review suggests more collaboration, better training standards, and stronger ethical guidelines. While AI and robotics show great promise, future success will depend on real-world testing, fair access, and strong teamwork between humans and machines.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wah</LastName><ForeName>Jack Ng Kok</ForeName><Initials>JNK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3055-953X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Management, Multimedia University, Cyberjaya, Cyberjaya, 63100, Selangor, Malaysia. ngkokwah@mmu.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Robot Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101300401</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1863-2483</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI in orthopedic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI predictive analytics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI surgical training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotic orthopedic procedures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotic spine surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Clinical trial number: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41665832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12891097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11701-026-03208-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11701-026-03208-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fan X, Wang Y, Zhang S, Xing Y, Li J, Ma X, Ma J (2025) Orthopedic surgical robotic systems in knee arthroplasty: A comprehensive review. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 13:1523631. 10.3389/fbioe.2025.1523631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2025.1523631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11882601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40051834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhimreddy M, Menta AK, Fuleihan AA, Davidar AD, Kramer P, Jillala R, Theodore N (2025) Beyond pedicle screw placement: future minimally invasive applications of robotics in spine surgery. Neurosurgery 96(3S):S94&#x2013;S102. 10.1227/neu.0000000000003335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000003335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39950789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury AAA, Sultana A, Rafi AH, Tariq M (2024) AI-driven predictive analytics in orthopedic surgery outcomes. Revista Esp De Documentacion Cient 19(2):104&#x2013;124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurmis AP, Lustig S, Zambianchi F, Chen Y (2025) Advances in artificial intelligence and robotics in joint arthroplasty. Arthroplasty 7(1):17. 10.1186/s42836-025-00302-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42836-025-00302-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11966888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40176158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao X, Wang X, Qin J, Wu Q, He Z, Fan X (2024) A Review of the Application of Artificial Intelligence in Orthopedic Diseases. Computers, Materials &amp; Continua 78(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan J, Li Z, Sheng S, Lin Q, Wang S, Wang D, Su J (2025) An artificial intelligence-driven revolution in orthopedic surgery and sports medicine. Int J Surg 111(2):2162&#x2013;2181. 10.1097/JS9.0000000000002187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000002187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39715150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geda MW, Tang YM, Lee CKM (2024) Applications of artificial intelligence in orthopaedic surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eng Appl Artif Intell 133:108326. 10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saadawi A, Tehranchi S, Ahmed S, Nzeako OJ, Ahmed SS (2025) Exploring the current applications of artificial intelligence in orthopaedic surgical training: A systematic. Scoping Rev Cureus 17(4). 10.7759/cureus.81671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12049242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40322353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpal RD (2025) Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in Orthopedic Diagnosis: Applications and Future Directions. Scholar&#x2019;s Digest: Journal of Orthopedics 1(1), 64&#x2013;79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Zhang J, Liu S, Huo T, He J, Xue M, Ye Z (2024) Application of artificial intelligence technology in the field of orthopedics: a narrative review. Artif Intell Rev 57(1):13. 10.1007/s10462-023-10638-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-023-10638-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oettl FC, Zsidai B, Oeding JF, Samuelsson K (2025) Artificial Intelligence and Musculoskeletal Surgical Applications. HSS Journal<sup>&#xae;</sup>. 10.1177/15563316251339596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12092413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40405922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branstetter R, Piedy E, Rajendra R, Bronstone A, Dasa V (2025) Navigating the intersection of technology and surgical education: advancements, challenges, and ethical considerations in orthopedic training. Orthop Clin 56(1):21&#x2013;28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39581642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaishya R, Sibal A, Kar S, Reddy S (2025) Integrating artificial intelligence into orthopedics: Opportunities, Challenges, and future directions. J Hand Microsurgery 100257. 10.1016/j.jham.2025.100257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12088811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40395968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Familiari F, Saithna A, Martinez-Cano JP, Chahla J, Castillo JMD, DePhillipo NN, ISAKOS Young Professionals Task Force (2025) Exploring artificial intelligence in orthopaedics: A collaborative survey from the ISAKOS Young Professional Task Force. J Experimental Orthop 12(1):e70181. 10.1002/jeo2.70181 &#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jeo2.70181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11848192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39996084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang W, Zhou C, Bai J, Zhang H, Jiang B, Wang J, Zhu H (2024) Current advancements in therapeutic approaches in orthopedic surgery: a review of recent trends. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 12. 10.3389/fbioe.2024.1328997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10884185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38405378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Sporn K, Ong J, Waisberg E, Paladugu P, Vaja S, Masalkhi M (2025) Integrating artificial intelligence in orthopedic care: advancements in bone care and future directions. Bioengineering 12(5):513. 10.3390/bioengineering12050513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering12050513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12109427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40428132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul P (2024) The rise of artificial intelligence: implications in orthopedic surgery. J Orthop Case Rep 14(2):1. 10.13107/jocr.2024.v14.i02.4194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13107/jocr.2024.v14.i02.4194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38420225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng P, Luo M, Li T, Wang H, Qin Y, Han J (2025) Duality-Based optimization of occlusion avoidance for active optical navigation system in robotic orthopedic surgeries. IEEE Trans Autom Sci Eng. 10.1109/TASE.2025.3566512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2025.3566512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Jiang Y, He R, Li C, Duan X (2025) Development and validation of a Robot-Assisted Retraction system for orthopedic surgery. IEEE Trans Med Rob Bionics. 10.1109/TMRB.2025.3550648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMRB.2025.3550648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanHendersonAP PR, Economopoulos KJ, Bingham JS, Chhabra A (2024) The use of artificial intelligence for orthopedic surgical backlogs such as the one following the COVID-19 pandemic: A narrative review. JBJS Open Access 9(3):e24 10.2106/JBJS.OA.24.00100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11410334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39301194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budhiparama NC, Kort NP, Kort R, Lumban-Gaol I (2025) The future outlook for data in orthopedic surgery: A new era of real-time innovation. J Orthop Surg 33(1):10225536251331664. 10.1177/10225536251331664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10225536251331664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40172087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian X, Song Y, Liu D, Wang Y, Guo X, Wu B, Zhang N (2025) Motion planning and control of active robot in orthopedic surgery by CDMP-based imitation learning and constrained optimization. IEEE Trans Autom Sci Eng. 10.1109/TASE.2025.3541594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2025.3541594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue W, Awang Z (2025) Application of Orthopedic Robot in the Diagnosis and Treatment of Femoral Neck Fracture. J Theory Practice Eng Technol 2(1):1&#x2013;4. Retrieved from https://woodyinternational.com/index.php/jtpet/article/view/154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun C, Zhang D (2025) Classification and advantages and disadvantages of orthopedic robots in clinical applications. Chin J Tissue Eng Res 29(15):3271. 10.12307/2025.175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12307/2025.175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>