<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41744599</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2313-7673</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomimetics (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomimetics (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Temperature Control of Nonlinear Continuous Stirred Tank Reactors Using an Enhanced Nature-Inspired Optimizer and Fractional-Order Controller.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">153</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/biomimetics11020153</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The temperature regulation of nonlinear continuous stirred tank reactor (CSTR) processes remains a challenging control problem due to strong nonlinearities, time-delay effects, and sensitivity to disturbances and parameter variations. Conventional proportional-integral-derivative (PID)-based control strategies often fail to provide the robustness and precision required under such conditions, motivating the use of more flexible controller structures and advanced optimization techniques. In this study, an enhanced joint-opposition artificial lemming algorithm (JOS-ALA) is proposed for the optimal tuning of a fractional-order PID (FOPID) controller applied to CSTR temperature control. The proposed JOS-ALA incorporates a joint opposite selection mechanism into the original ALA to improve population diversity, convergence stability, and resistance to local optima stagnation. A nonlinear CSTR model is linearized around a stable operating point, and the resulting model is employed for controller design and optimization. The FOPID controller parameters are tuned by minimizing a composite cost function that simultaneously accounts for tracking accuracy, overshoot suppression, and instantaneous error behavior. The effectiveness of the proposed approach is assessed through extensive simulation studies and benchmarked against state-of-the-art and high-performance metaheuristic optimizers, including ALA, electric eel foraging optimization (EEFO), linear population size reduction success-history based adaptive differential evolution (L-SHADE), and the improved artificial electric field algorithm (iAEFA). The benchmarking set is further extended with the success rate-based adaptive differential evolution variant (L-SRTDE) to broaden the comparative evaluation. Simulation results demonstrate that the JOS-ALA-based FOPID controller consistently achieves superior performance across multiple criteria. Specifically, it attains the lowest mean cost function value of 0.1959, eliminates overshoot, and yields a normalized steady-state error of 4.7290 &#xd7; 10<sup>-4</sup>. In addition, faster transient response and improved robustness under external disturbances and measurement noise are observed when compared with competing methods. Statistical reliability of the observed performance differences is additionally examined using a Wilcoxon signed-rank test conducted over 25 independent runs. The resulting <i>p</i>-values confirm that the improvements achieved by the proposed approach are statistically significant at the 5% level across all pairwise algorithm comparisons. These findings indicate that the proposed JOS-ALA provides an effective and reliable optimization framework for high-precision temperature control in nonlinear CSTR systems and offers strong potential for broader application in complex process control problems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekinci</LastName><ForeName>Serdar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Bitlis Eren University, 13100 Bitlis, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izci</LastName><ForeName>Davut</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8359-0875</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Bursa Uludag University, 16059 Bursa, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almeree</LastName><ForeName>Aysha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-9095-2708</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, &#x130;stanbul Ayd&#x131;n University, 34295 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T&#xfc;men</LastName><ForeName>Vedat</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0271-216X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Bitlis Eren University, 13100 Bitlis, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gider</LastName><ForeName>Veysel</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7538-262X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Distance Education Application and Research Center, Batman University, 72100 Batman, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stoyanov</LastName><ForeName>Ivaylo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9824-1504</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Power Engineering, University of Ruse, 7017 Ruse, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabari</LastName><ForeName>Mostafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2169-9802</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Sahand University of Technology, Tabriz 51335, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BG-RRP-2.013-0001</GrantID><Agency>European Union-NextGenerationEU</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Biomimetics (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101719189</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2313-7673</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial lemming algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">continuous stirred tank reactor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fractional-order controller</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">joint opposite selection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">temperature management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41744599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12938556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics11020153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">biomimetics11020153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim H. Mathematical Modeling and Simulation of Control Strategies for Continuous Stirrer Tank Reactor. Bangladesh J. Sci. Ind. Res. 2022;57:149&#x2013;162. doi: 10.3329/bjsir.v57i3.62017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/bjsir.v57i3.62017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha A., Mishra R.K. Control of a Nonlinear Continuous Stirred Tank Reactor via Event Triggered Sliding Modes. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2018;187:52&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2018.04.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2018.04.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui M.A. Design of Parallel Cascade Controller for Nonlinear Continuous Stirred Tank Reactor. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:6210. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-89455-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-89455-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11842819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izci D., Ekinci S., Jabari M., Bajaj M., Blazek V., Prokop L., Yildiz A.R., Mirjalili S. A New Intelligent Control Strategy for CSTH Temperature Regulation Based on the Starfish Optimization Algorithm. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:12327. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-96621-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-96621-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11985496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40210920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavrov D., Nadzinski G., Deskovski S., Stankovski M. Quadratic Model-Based Dynamically Updated PID Control of CSTR System with Varying Parameters. Algorithms. 2021;14:31. doi: 10.3390/a14020031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/a14020031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng W., Chen Y., Wang X., Lin M., Guo J. Robust Fractional Order PID Controller Synthesis for the First Order plus Integral System. Meas. Control. 2023;56:202&#x2013;214. doi: 10.1177/00202940221095564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00202940221095564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajlouni N., Osyavas A., Ajlouni F., Almassri A., Takaoglu F., Takaoglu M. Enhancing PID Control Robustness in CSTRs: A Hybrid Approach to Tuning under External Disturbances with GA, PSO, and Machine Learning. Neural Comput. Appl. 2025;37:12153&#x2013;12177. doi: 10.1007/s00521-025-11170-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-025-11170-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah P., Agashe S. Review of Fractional PID Controller. Mechatronics. 2016;38:29&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.mechatronics.2016.06.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mechatronics.2016.06.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tepljakov A., Petlenkov E., Belikov J. FOMCOM: A MATLAB Toolbox for Fractional-Order System Identification and Control. Int. J. Microelectron. Comput. Sci. 2011;2:51&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y., Cui H., Khurma R.A., Castillo P.A. Artificial Lemming Algorithm: A Novel Bionic Meta-Heuristic Technique for Solving Real-World Engineering Optimization Problems. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2025;58:84. doi: 10.1007/s10462-024-11023-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-11023-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W., Wang L., Zhang Z., Fan H., Zhang J., Mirjalili S., Khodadadi N., Cao Q. Electric Eel Foraging Optimization: A New Bio-Inspired Optimizer for Engineering Applications. Expert Syst. Appl. 2024;238:122200. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanabe R., Fukunaga A.S. 2014 IEEE Congress on Evolutionary Computation (CEC), Beijing, China, 6&#x2013;11 July 2014. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2014. Improving the Search Performance of SHADE Using Linear Population Size Reduction; pp. 1658&#x2013;1665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauhan D., Yadav A. An Adaptive Artificial Electric Field Algorithm for Continuous Optimization Problems. Expert Syst. 2023;40:e13380. doi: 10.1111/exsy.13380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exsy.13380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanovov V., Semenkin E. 2024 IEEE Congress on Evolutionary Computation (CEC), Yokohama, Japan, 30 June&#x2013;5 July 2024. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2024. Success Rate-Based Adaptive Differential Evolution L-SRTDE for CEC 2024 Competition; pp. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brest J., Sepesy Mau&#x10d;ec M. Comparative Study of Modern Differential Evolution Algorithms: Perspectives on Mechanisms and Performance. Mathematics. 2025;13:1556. doi: 10.3390/math13101556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math13101556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabari M., Ekinci S., Izci D., Zitar R.A., Migdady H., Smerat A., Abualigah L. An Advanced PID Tuning Method for Temperature Control in Electric Furnaces Using the Artificial Rabbits Optimization Algorithm. Int. J. Dyn. Control. 2025;13:175. doi: 10.1007/s40435-025-01681-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40435-025-01681-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabari M., Izci D., Ekinci S., Bajaj M., Blazek V., Prokop L. Hybrid Adaptive Ant Lion Optimization with Traditional Controllers for Driving and Controlling Switched Reluctance Motors to Enhance Performance. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:12898. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-97070-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-97070-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12000315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40234547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzakari S.A., Izci D., Ekinci S., Alhussan A.A., Hashim F.A. Nonlinear FOPID Controller Design for Pressure Regulation of Steam Condenser via Improved Metaheuristic Algorithm. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0309211. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0309211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0309211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11412520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39298510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabari M., Botta A., Tagliavini L., Visconte C., Quaglia G. A Safe, High-Precision Reinforcement Learning-Based Optimal Control of Surgical Continuum Robots: A Monotone Tube Boundary Approach with Prescribed-Time Control Capability. Rob. Auton. Syst. 2025;190:104992. doi: 10.1016/j.robot.2025.104992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.robot.2025.104992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabari M., Rad A., Nasab M.A., Zand M., Padmanaban S., Muyeen S.M., Guerrero J.M. Parameter Identification of PV Solar Cells and Modules Using Bio Dynamics Grasshopper Optimization Algorithm. IET Gener. Transm. Distrib. 2024;18:3314&#x2013;3338. doi: 10.1049/gtd2.13279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/gtd2.13279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabari M., Rad A. Optimization of Speed Control and Reduction of Torque Ripple in Switched Reluctance Motors Using Metaheuristic Algorithms Based PID and FOPID Controllers at the Edge. Tsinghua Sci. Technol. 2025;30:1526&#x2013;1538. doi: 10.26599/TST.2024.9010021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/TST.2024.9010021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arini F.Y., Chiewchanwattana S., Soomlek C., Sunat K. Joint Opposite Selection (JOS): A Premiere Joint of Selective Leading Opposition and Dynamic Opposite Enhanced Harris&#x2019; Hawks Optimization for Solving Single-Objective Problems. Expert Syst. Appl. 2022;188:116001. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2021.116001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2021.116001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deepa S.N., Jayalakshmi N.Y. Optimized Fuzzy-Based Wavelet Neural Network Controller for a Non-Linear Process Control System. IETE J. Res. 2023;69:1363&#x2013;1372. doi: 10.1080/03772063.2020.1865212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03772063.2020.1865212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begum K.G. Coot Bird Optimization Algorithm for the Temperature Control of Continuous Stirred Tank Reactor Process. Asia-Pac. J. Chem. Eng. 2023;18:e2787. doi: 10.1002/apj.2787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/apj.2787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bequette B.W. Process Control: Modeling, Design, and Simulation. Prentice Hall Professional; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaresan K.R., Krishnaswamy P.R. Estimation of Time Delay Time Constant Parameters in Time, Frequency, and Laplace Domains. Can. J. Chem. Eng. 1978;56:257&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1002/cjce.5450560215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cjce.5450560215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekinci S., Izci D., Jabari M., &#xc7;elik E., Bajaj M., Vishnuram P., Rubanenko O. A Novel Hyperbolic Tangent-Based PID Controller Tuned by the Artificial Lemming Algorithm for Nonlinear Steam Condenser Pressure Control. Sci. Rep. 2026;16:4600. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-34740-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34740-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12868638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41513948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izci D., Ekinci S., Abualigah L., Salman M., Rashdan M. Parameter Extraction of Photovoltaic Cell Models Using Electric Eel Foraging Optimizer. Front. Energy Res. 2024;12:1407125. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2024.1407125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2024.1407125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izci D., Ekinci S., Mohd Tumari M.Z., Ahmad M.A. A Novel Softsign Fractional-Order Controller Optimized by an Intelligent Nature-Inspired Algorithm for Magnetic Levitation Control. Fractal Fract. 2025;9:801. doi: 10.3390/fractalfract9120801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fractalfract9120801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>