<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41735933</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>One-stage exchange arthroplasty for periprosthetic joint infection following total knee arthroplasty with sinus tract: a mid-to short-term follow-up study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">265</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-026-09648-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">An increasing amount of clinical evidence indicates that one-stage exchange arthroplasty provides outcomes comparable to those of two-stage exchange arthroplasty in the management of chronic periprosthetic joint infection (PJI) following total knee arthroplasty (TKA). However, for cases complicated by a sinus tract, most specialists still advocate a two-stage exchange arthroplasty strategy. This study aims to evaluate the effectiveness of one-stage exchange arthroplasty in treating chronic PJI following TKA with sinus tract formation and to determine the feasibility of this approach in achieving infection control and restoring joint function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was conducted on 23 patients with PJI following TKA accompanied by a sinus tract, who were admitted between January 1, 2019 and December 31, 2023. All patients completed a minimum follow-up of 12 months. During this period, microbiological findings, individualized antimicrobial regimens, and incidences of infection recurrence were meticulously documented. To objectively evaluate infection control, serial measurements of serum inflammatory markers&#x2014;including the erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), C-reactive protein (CRP), interleukin-6 (IL-6), and procalcitonin (PCT)&#x2014;were obtained preoperatively and on postoperative days 3, 7, 10, and 14, allowing for assessment of their dynamic changes. Furthermore, to assess functional recovery, the visual analog scale (VAS) score, knee range of motion (ROM), and Knee Society Score (KSS) were compared preoperatively and at postoperative day 14, 3 months, and the final follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean follow-up duration was 14.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.9 months. At the final follow-up, the infection-free survival rate was 95.65% (22/23) as defined by the International Consensus Meeting (ICM) criteria, with only one case of recurrence at two months postoperatively. All evaluated clinical outcomes&#x2014;including the VAS score, ROM, and KSS&#x2014;demonstrated statistically significant improvements compared to preoperative baseline values (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). By the final follow-up, patients had achieved a nearly pain-free state. The mean knee ROM significantly increased from 64.8&#xb0; &#xb1; 5.0&#xb0; preoperatively to 120.0&#xb0; &#xb1; 4.5&#xb0;, while the mean KSS improved from 33.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.3 points to 87.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.2 points.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">For chronic PJI following TKA with a sinus tract, one-stage exchange arthroplasty, when performed in strict adherence to a standardized protocol, demonstrates favorable potential in infection control and significant functional restoration, with satisfactory medium-term outcomes. Therefore, under strictly standardized surgical protocols, one-stage exchange arthroplasty may be considered a viable treatment option for carefully selected cases of periprosthetic joint infection complicated by a sinus tract following thorough and prudent evaluation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Qiao</LastName><ForeName>Yongjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Qifeng</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Clinical Medical College, Gansu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Xuewen</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, 730000, China. ery_kangxw@lzu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Shenghu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, The 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army, Lanzhou, 730050, China. zhoushenghu120@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>25JRRA812</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Gansu Provincial</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2024-G3-5</GrantID><Agency>The High-Level Talent Training Program of the 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People's Liberation Army</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GSWSKY2024-20</GrantID><Agency>Gansu Provincial Health Industry Scientific Research Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25YFFA064</GrantID><Agency>Key Research and Development Plan of Gansu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">One-stage exchange arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Periprosthetic joint infection(PJI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reimplantation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sinus tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total knee arthroplasty (TKA)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by by the Ethics Committee of the 940th Hospital of the Joint Logistics Support Force of the Chinese People&#x2019;s Liberation Army (Approval No. [2025KYLL209]). Informed consent was obtained from all individuals. The study was performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, as revised in 2008. All patients provided written informed consent prior to participation. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41735933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09648-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-026-09648-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Terhune EB, Carstens MF, Fruth KM, Hannon CP, Bedard NA, Berry DJ, et al. Results of two-stage exchange for periprosthetic joint infection following total knee Arthroplasty: low rates of failure in 463 knees at 10 years. J Arthroplasty. 2025:S0883&#x2013;5403(25)01330-0. 10.1016/j.arth.2025.10.051. 10.1016/j.arth.2025.10.0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41161510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis DC, Blackburn BE, Archibeck J, Archibeck MJ, Anderson LA, Gililland JM, et al. Similar Efficacy and Lower Cost Associated With Ceftazidime Compared to Tobramycin Coupled With Vancomycin in Antibiotic Spacers in the Treatment of Periprosthetic Joint Infection. J Arthroplast. 2024;39:S323&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2024.04.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38631513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaziz H, Schr&#xf6;der M, Shum Tien C, Ibrahim K, Gehrke T, Salber J, et al. Resection of the proximal femur during one-stage revision for infected hip arthroplasty: risk factors and effectiveness. bone joint J. 2021;103&#x2013;b:1678&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.103B11.BJJ-2021-0022.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Li S, Liu S, Li S, Yin Z, Du Y, et al. The presence of a sinus tract is associated with reinfection after two-stage revision surgery for prosthetic hip joint infection: a case-control study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25:721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-024-07840-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11380202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39244574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs MMJ, Heesterbeek PJC, Veerman K, Goosen JHM. One- versus two-stage septic hip and knee revision surgery: a comparative cohort outcome study with short- to mid-term follow-up. J bone joint Infect. 2025;10:185&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/jbji-10-185-2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12163721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40521022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DelliCarpini G, Khury F, Ashkenazi I, Shehadeh K, Schwarzkopf R, Rozell JC, et al. The influence of antibiotic-loaded bone cement spacer type on outcomes of the first stage of a revision total hip Arthroplasty. Antibiotics (Basel). 2025;14(10):1034. 10.3390/antibiotics14101034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12561131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41148726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfraz A, Shichman I, LaPorte ZL, Rozell JC, Schwarzkopf R, Aggarwal VK. Does the Degree of Liner Constraint Increase Risk of Complications in Articulating Spacers in Two-stage Revision After THA? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2025;483:1237&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12190108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40279184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citak M, Friedenstab J, Abdelaziz H, Suero EM, Zahar A, Salber J, et al. Risk Factors for Failure After 1-Stage Exchange Total Knee Arthroplasty in the Management of Periprosthetic Joint Infection. J bone joint Surg Am volume. 2019;101:1061&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.18.00947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31220022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingham JS, Salib CG, McQuivey K, Temkit M, Spangehl MJ. An Evidence-Based Clinical Prediction Algorithm for the Musculoskeletal Infection Society Minor Criteria. J Arthroplast. 2018;33:2993&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2018.04.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29807787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji B, Li G, Zhang X, Wang Y, Mu W, Cao L. Effective treatment of single-stage revision using intra-articular antibiotic infusion for culture-negative prosthetic joint infection. bone joint J. 2020;102&#x2013;b:336&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.102B3.BJJ-2019-0820.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji B, Wahafu T, Li G, Zhang X, Wang Y, Momin M, et al. Single-stage treatment of chronically infected total hip arthroplasty with cementless reconstruction: results in 126 patients with broad inclusion criteria. bone joint J. 2019;101&#x2013;b:396&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.101B4.BJJ-2018-1109.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30929477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson SB, Pinkney JA, Chen AF, Tande AJ. Periprosthetic Joint Infection: Current Clinical Challenges. Clin Infect diseases: official publication Infect Dis Soc Am. 2023;77:e34&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciad360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11004930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Z, Zeng J, Zhang Z, Wu B, Hong Z, Guo Y, et al. Comparison of the efficacy of one-stage revision surgery guided by precise pathogen diagnosis and conventional two-stage revision for chronic knee periprosthetic joint infection. Arthroplasty (London England). 2025;7:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12123842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40448177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehrke T, Citak M, Parvizi J, Budhiparama NC, Akkaya M. Periprosthetic joint infections: state-of-the-art. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;145:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-024-05627-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39694911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suliman J, Warda H, Samaan M. Review of recent advances in the diagnosis and management of periprosthetic joint infection after total knee arthroplasty part 2: single-stage or two-stage surgical technique? J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19:643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-024-05152-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11470652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39395987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lausmann C, Wollny A, Citak M, Gehrke T, Beil FT, Lee MJ, et al. Mid-term Results of 1-stage Revision Total Knee Arthroplasty for Periprosthetic Joint Infection With a Sinus Tract. HSS journal: Musculoskelet J Hosp Special Surg. 2025;21:35&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15563316241228267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11572381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39564405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schenk HM, Sebillotte M, Lomas J, Taylor A, Benavent E, Murillo O, et al. Risk factors for treatment failure in late acute periprosthetic joint infection in patients with rheumatoid arthritis treated with surgical debridement - a case-control study. J bone joint Infect. 2025;10:217&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/jbji-10-217-2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12272950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40688531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McChesney GR, Al Farii H, Singleterry S, Lewis VO, Moon BS, Satcher RL, et al. Can Periprosthetic Joint Infection of Tumor Prostheses Be Controlled With Debridement, Antibiotics, and Implant Retention? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2025;483:49&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38991232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muwanis M, Barimani B, Luo L, Wang CK, Dimentberg R, Albers A. Povidone-iodine irrigation reduces infection after total hip and knee arthroplasty. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2023;143:2175&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-022-04451-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35488919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan JP. Dilute Povidone-Iodine Irrigation: The Science of Molecular Iodine (I2) Kinetics and Its Antimicrobial Activity. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2025;33:65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-24-00471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11661569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39729104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visperas A, Santana D, Klika AK, Higuera-Rueda CA, Piuzzi NS. Current treatments for biofilm-associated periprosthetic joint infection and new potential strategies. J Orthop research: official publication Orthop Res Soc. 2022;40:1477&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35437846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Chen W, Rong R, Pan B, Hu X, Zheng L, et al. Application of the New Irrigation Protocol to Reduce Recurrence Rate in the Management Of Periprosthetic Joint Infection. Orthop Surg. 2024;16:577&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/os.13948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10925507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38238252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poilvache H, Ruiz-Sorribas A, Sakoulas G, Rodriguez-Villalobos H, Cornu O, Van Bambeke F. Synergistic Effects of Pulsed Lavage and Antimicrobial Therapy Against Staphylococcus aureus Biofilms in an in-vitro Model. Front Med. 2020;7:527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.00527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33043028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacqueline C, Caillon J. Impact of bacterial biofilm on the treatment of prosthetic joint infections. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2014;69(Suppl 1):i37&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dku254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25135088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;rquez-G&#xf3;mez M, D&#xed;az-Navarro M, Visedo A, Hafian R, Matas J, Mu&#xf1;oz P, et al. An in vitro study to assess the best strategy for the chemical debridement of periprosthetic joint infection. Antibiotics (Basel). 2023;12(10):1507. 10.3390/antibiotics12101507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10604180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37887208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Fu J, Niu E, Chai W, Xu C, Hao LB, et al. The risk factors of polymicrobial periprosthetic joint infection: a single-center retrospective cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2021;22:780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-021-04664-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34511107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X, Wang Q, Ding H, Li H, Fang X, Zhang W, et al. The Role of Applying Metagenomic Next-Generation Sequencing (mNGS) in Periprosthetic Joint Infection with Sinus Tract: A Retrospective Study. Int J Gen Med. 2025;18:3787&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S531444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12256048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40655305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo UG, De Salvatore S, Bandini B, Lalli A, Barill&#xe0; B, Budhiparama NC, et al. Debridement, antibiotics, and implant retention (DAIR) for the early prosthetic joint infection of total knee and hip arthroplasties: a systematic review. J ISAKOS: joint disorders Orthop sports Med. 2024;9:62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jisako.2023.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37714518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsantes AG, Altsitzioglou P, Papadopoulos DV, Lorenzo D, Roman&#xf2; CL, Benzakour T, et al. Infections of tumor prostheses: an updated review on risk factors, microbiology, diagnosis, and treatment strategies. Biology (Basel). 2023;12(2):314. 10.3390/biology12020314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9953401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36829589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian HY, Li YC, Guo XB, Zhang XG, Cao L. [Intraoperative direct sonication for the diagnostic efficacy of periprosthetic joint infection]. Zhonghua wai ke za zhi [Chinese J surgery]. 2025;63:821&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40734415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao L, Ma Y, Liu R, Li Y, Sun X, Wahafu T, et al. Potential interactions between vancomycin and meropenem in culture-negative periprosthetic joint infection: an in vitro study. BMC Microbiol. 2025;25:197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12866-025-03918-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11969832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40186104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xfc;cel MO, Dalaslan RE, Sa&#x11f;lam S, Ar&#x131;can M, Karaduman ZO, &#xc7;elik M et al. Diabetes, Inflammatory Markers, and Tissue Thickness in Septic and Aseptic Hip Revision Surgeries. Medical science monitor: international medical journal of experimental and clinical research. 2025;31:e949619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12400974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40859616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh GS, Neumann M, Salber J, Gehrke T, Citak M. One-Stage Revision Total Hip Arthroplasty for Polymicrobial Periprosthetic Joint Infection Leads to High Reinfection Rates: A Mean of 5-Year Follow-Up. J Arthroplast. 2026;41:608&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2025.06.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40553944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pioger C, Marmor S, Bouch&#xe9; PA, Kerroumi Y, Lhotellier L, Graff W, et al. One-stage exchange strategy with extensive debridement for chronic periprosthetic joint infection following total knee arthroplasty is associated with a low relapse rate in non-selected patients: a prospective single-center analysis. Orthop Traumatol Surg research: OTSR. 2025;111:104019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.otsr.2024.104019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39393489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>