<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41495851</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of biomedical semantics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Biomed Semantics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Annotating and indexing scientific articles with rare diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13326-025-00346-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Around 30 million people in Europe are affected by a rare (or orphan) disease, defined as a condition occurring in fewer than 1 in 2,000 individuals. The primary challenge is to automatically and efficiently identify scientific articles and guidelines that address a particular rare disease. We present a novel methodology to annotate and index scientific text with taxonomical concepts describing rare diseases from the OrphaNet taxonomy. This task is complicated by several technical challenges, including the lack of sufficiently large, human-annotated datasets for supervised training and the polysemy/synonymy and surface-form variation of rare disease names, which can hinder any annotation engine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We introduce a framework that operationalizes OrphaNet for large-scale literature annotation by integrating the TERMite engine with curated synonym expansion, label normalization (including deprecated/renamed concepts), and fuzzy matching. On benchmark datasets, the approach achieves precision&#x2009;=&#x2009;92%, recall&#x2009;=&#x2009;75%, and F1&#x2009;=&#x2009;83%, outperforming an string-matching baseline. Applying the pipeline to Scopus produces disease-specific corpora suitable for bibliometric and scientometric analyses (e.g., institution, country, and subject-area profiles). These outputs power the Rare Diseases Monitor dashboard for exploring national and global research activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To our knowledge, this is the first systematic, scalable semantic framework for annotating and indexing rare disease literature at scale. By operationalizing OrphaNet in an automated, reproducible pipeline and addressing data scarcity and lexical variability, the work advances biomedical semantics for rare diseases and enables disease-centric monitoring, evaluation, and discovery across the research landscape.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azarbonyad</LastName><ForeName>Hosein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, Noord Holland, The Netherlands. h.azarbonyad@elsevier.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afzal</LastName><ForeName>Zubair</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, Noord Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iping</LastName><ForeName>Rik</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, Zuid Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dumoulin</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, Noord Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nederveen</LastName><ForeName>Ilse</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, Zuid Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Jiangtao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, Noord Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsatsaronis</LastName><ForeName>Georgios</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, Noord Holland, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Biomed Semantics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531992</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035583" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rare Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000043" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abstracting and Indexing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Data Curation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012660" MajorTopicYN="N">Semantics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Annotation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bibliographic databases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health sciences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indexing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Natural language processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rare diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research applications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scientometrics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13326-025-00346-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13326-025-00346-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rath A, Olry A, Dhombres F, Brandt MM, Urbero B, Ayme S. Representation of rare diseases in health information systems: the orphanet approach to serve a wide range of end users. Hum Mutat. 2012;33(5):803&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.22078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowsari K, Jafari Meimandi K, Heidarysafa M, Mendu S, Barnes L, Brown D. Text classification algorithms: a survey. Information. 2019;10(4):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info10040150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M-L, Zhou. Z.-H.: a review on multi-label learning algorithms. IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng. 2013;26(8):1819&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TKDE.2013.39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joachims T. Text categorization with support vector machines: learning with many relevant features. European Conference on Machine Learning. 1998, pp. 137&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott S, Matwin S. Feature engineering for text classification. In: ICML. Vol. 99. 1999. p. 379&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minaee S, Kalchbrenner N, Cambria E, Nikzad N, Chenaghlu M, Gao J. Deep learning&#x2013;based text classification: a comprehensive review. ACM Comput Surv (CSUR). 2021;54(3):1&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3439726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Peng H, Li J, Xia C, Yang R, Sun L, Yu PS, He L. A survey on text classification: from traditional to deep learning. ACM Trans Intell Syst Technol (TIST). 2022;13(2):1&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Chang W-C, Wu Y, Yang Y. Deep learning for extreme multi-label text classification. Proceedings of the 40th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. 2017, pp. 115&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbonyad H, Dehghani M, Marx M, Kamps J. Learning to rank for multi-label text classification: combining different sources of information. Nat Language Eng. 2021;27(1):89&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1351324920000029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipscomb CE. Medical subject headings (mesh). Bull Med Lib Assoc. 2000;88(3):265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC35238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10928714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinreich SS, Mangon R, Sikkens J, Teeuw ME, Cornel M. Orphanet: a european database for rare diseases. Nederlands tijdschrift voor geneeskunde. 2008;152(9):518&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18389888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo F, Silvestri S, Ciampi M, De Pietro G. Deep neural network for hierarchical extreme multi-label text classification. Appl Soft Comput. 2019;79:125&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2019.03.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H, Li J, He Y, Liu Y, Bao M, Wang L, Song Y, Yang Q. Large-scale hierarchical text classification with recursively regularized deep graph-cnn. Proceedings of the 2018 World Wide Web Conference. 2018, pp. 1063&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zangari A, Marcuzzo M, Schiavinato M, Rizzo M, Gasparetto A, Albarelli A, et al. Hierarchical text classification: a review of current research. Expert Syst Appl 224. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;krlj B, Martinc M, Kralj J, Lavra&#x10d; N, Pollak S. tax2vec: constructing interpretable features from taxonomies for short text classification. Comput Speech Lan. 2021;65:101104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csl.2020.101104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T, Wang D, Sun L, Chen Z, Zhuang F, Yang Q. Exploiting global and local hierarchies for hierarchical text classification. arXiv preprint arXiv:2205.02613 (2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharbanda S, Banerjee A, Schultheis E, Babbar R. Cascadexml: rethinking transformers for end-to-end multi-resolution training in extreme multi-label classification. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2022;35:2074&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gururangan S, Dang T, Card D, Smith NA. Variational pretraining for semi-supervised text classification. arXiv preprint arXiv:1906.02242 (2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthelot D, Carlini N, Goodfellow I, Papernot N, Oliver A, Raffel CA. Mixmatch: a holistic approach to semi-supervised learning. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst 32. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen J, Qiu W, Meng Y, Shang J, Ren X, Han J. Taxoclass: hierarchical multi-label text classification using only class names. NAAC&#x2019;21: Proceedings of the 2021 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, {NAACL-HLT} 2021. 2021;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y, Zhang Y, Huang J, Xiong C, Ji H, Zhang C, Han J. Text classification using label names only: a language model self-training approach. Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). 2020, pp. 9006&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pappas N, Henderson J. Gile: a generalized input-label embedding for text classification. Trans Assoc Comput Linguist. 2019;7:139&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/tacl_a_00259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jett&#xe9; N, Quan H, Hemmelgarn B, Drosler S, Maass C, Oec D-G, Moskal L, Paoin W, Sundararajan V, Gao S, et al. The development, evolution, and modifications of icd-10: challenges to the international comparability of morbidity data. Med Care. 2010;1105&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20978452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodenreider O. The unified medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology. Nucleic Acids Res. 2004;32(suppl_1):267&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkh061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC308795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14681409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EG, Wood L, Wood S. The medical dictionary for regulatory activities (meddra). Drug Saf. 1999;20(2):109&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00002018-199920020-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10082069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azam SS, Raju M, Pagidimarri V, Kasivajjala VC. Cascadenet: an lstm based deep learning model for automated icd-10 coding. Advances in Information and Communication: Proceedings of the 2019 Future of Information and Communication Conference (FICC). 2020, pp. 55&#x2013;74, Volume 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaradech N, Khumrin P. Auto-mapping clinical documents to icd-10 using snomed-ct. AMIA Summits Transl Sci Proc. 2021;2021:296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8378640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34457144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M, N&#xe9;v&#xe9;ol A, Lu Z. Recommending mesh terms for annotating biomedical articles. J Am Med Inf Assoc. 2011;18(5):660&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/amiajnl-2010-000055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3168302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Q, Dhingra B, Cohen W, Lu X. Attentionmesh: simple, effective and interpretable automatic mesh indexer. Proceedings of the 6th BioASQ Workshop A Challenge on Large-scale Biomedical Semantic Indexing and Question Answering. 2018, pp. 47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y, Lu Z. Mesh now: automatic mesh indexing at pubmed scale via learning to rank. J Biomed Semant. 2017;8:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13326-017-0123-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5392968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seva J, Kittner M, Roller R, Leser U. Multi-lingual icd-10 coding using a hybrid rule-based and supervised classification approach at clef ehealth 2017. In: CLEF (Working Notes); 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boytcheva S. Automatic matching of icd-10 codes to diagnoses in discharge letters. Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Biomedical Natural Language Processing. 2011, pp. 11&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P-F, Wang S-M, Liao W-C, Kuo L-C, Chen K-C, Lin Y-C, Yang C-Y, Chiu C-H, Chang S-C, Lai F, et al. Automatic icd-10 coding and training system: deep neural network based on supervised learning. JMIR Med Inf. 2021;9(8):23230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/23230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balikas G, Partalas I, Ngomo A-CN, Krithara A, Paliouras G. Results of the bioasq track of the question answering lab at clef 2014. In: CLEF (Working Notes; 2014. p. 1181&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iping R, Nederveen I, Ranjbar-Sahraei B, Azarbonyad H, Dumoulin M, Tsatsaronis G, Mathijssen IM. The development of a research intelligence tool for rare disease research in the Netherlands. Quant Sci Stud. 2024;5(3):704&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/qss_a_00320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>