<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41676321</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2095-4697</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Quantitative biology (Beijing, China)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Quant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A survey of downstream applications of evolutionary scale modeling protein language models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70013</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70013</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70013</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/qub2.70013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The evolutionary scale modeling (ESM) series is promising to revolutionize protein science and engineering through large language models (LLMs), providing a robust framework for understanding the relationships among sequences, structures, and functions of proteins. Trained on a large number of unlabeled protein sequences, ESM models are able to capture intricate patterns of mutation and conservation, yielding insights into the structural and functional properties of proteins. Despite a growing body of literature surrounding ESM, existing surveys often fail to comprehensively describe its advancements or applications in a focused manner. This survey covers the latest developments of ESM, categorizing them into techniques of using ESM and downstream applications. Approximately 100 papers are selected and analyzed, highlighting recognized and innovative studies that exemplify the impact of ESM. Furthermore, we critically discuss the strengths and limitations of ESM to envision future applications. This review provides a valuable resource for researchers seeking to explore the power of ESM models and the emerging applications of LLMs in biology and medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Quantitative Biology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Higher Education Press.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Qingyu</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Science and Technology ShanghaiTech University Shanghai China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Jiale</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Science and Technology ShanghaiTech University Shanghai China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Science and Technology ShanghaiTech University Shanghai China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Vision and Imaging Shanghai China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Quant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101639642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2095-4689</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BERT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transformer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fine&#x2010;tuning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pretraining</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prompting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein language model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41676321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12806033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qub2.70013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">QUB270013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rives A, Meier J, Sercu T, Goyal S, Lin Z, Liu J, et&#xa0;al. Biological structure and function emerge from scaling unsupervised learning to 250 million protein sequences. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2021;118(15):e2016239118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33876751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao RM, Liu J, Verkuil R, Meier J, Canny J, Abbeel P, et&#xa0;al. MSA Transformer. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2021. p. 8844&#x2013;8856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier J, Rao R, Verkuil R, Liu J, Sercu T, Rives A. Language models enable zero&#x2010;shot prediction of the effects of mutations on protein function. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2021;34:29287&#x2013;29303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu C, Verkuil R, Liu J, Lin Z, Hie B, Sercu T, et&#xa0;al. Learning inverse folding from millions of predicted structures. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2022. p. 8946&#x2013;8970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Akin H, Rao R, Hie B, Zhu Z, Lu W, et&#xa0;al. Evolutionary&#x2010;scale prediction of atomic&#x2010;level protein structure with a language model. Science. 2023;379(6637):1123&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36927031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes T, Rao R, Akin H, Sofroniew NJ, Oktay D, Lin Z, et&#xa0;al. Simulating 500 million years of evolution with a language model. 2024. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2024.07.01.600583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39818825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Wei GW. Artificial intelligence&#x2010;aided protein engineering: from topological data analysis to deep protein language models. Briefings Bioinf. 2023;24(5):bbad289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10516362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37580175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, McFee M, Fang Q, Abdin O, Kim PM. Computational and artificial intelligence&#x2010;based methods for antibody development. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2023;44(3):175&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36669976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferruz N, H&#xf6;cker B. Controllable protein design with language models. Nat Mach Intell. 2022;4(6):521&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Xie Q, Pei J, Chen Z, Tiwari P, Li Z, et&#xa0;al. Pre&#x2010;trained language models in biomedical domain: a systematic survey. ACM Comput Surv. 2023;56(3):1&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y, Zhao W, Zhang J, Jin Y, Zhang H, Ren Z. et&#xa0;al. Protein large language models: a comprehensive survey. 2025. Preprint at arXiv:2502.17504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob D, Chang MW, Lee K, Toutanova K. BERT: pre&#x2010;training of deep bidirectional Transformers for language understanding. In: Proceedings of the 2019 conference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics: human language technologies, volume 1 (long and short papers); 2019. p. 4171&#x2013;4186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A, Shazeer N, Parmar N, Uszkoreit J, Jones L, Gomez AN, et&#xa0;al. Attention is all you need. In: Guyon I, Von Luxburg U, Bengio S, Wallach H, Fergus R, Vishwanathan S, et&#xa0;al., editors. Advances in neural information processing systems, 30. Curran Associates, Inc.; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UniProt Consortium . UniProt: a worldwide hub of protein knowledge. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(D1):D506&#x2013;D515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgar RC, Batzoglou S. Multiple sequence alignment. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2006;16(3):368&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing B, Eismann S, Suriana P, Townshend RJL, Dror R. Learning from protein structure with geometric vector perceptrons. 2020. Preprint at arXiv:2009.01411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jumper J, Evans R, Pritzel A, Green T, Figurnov M, Ronneberger O, et&#xa0;al. Highly accurate protein structure prediction with AlphaFold. Nature. 2021;596(7873):583&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ian S, Bordin N, Dawson N, Waman VP, Paul A, Scholes HM, et&#xa0;al. CATH: increased structural coverage of functional space. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(D1):D266&#x2013;D273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protein Data Bank . Protein data bank. Nat New Biol. 1971;233(223):10&#x2013;1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson L, Allen B, Baldi G, Beracochea M, Bileschi ML, Burdett T, et&#xa0;al. MGnify: the microbiome sequence data analysis resource in 2023. Nucleic Acids Res. 2023;51(D1):D753&#x2013;D759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36477304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen IMA, Chu K, Palaniappan K, Ratner A, Huang J, Huntemann&#xa0;M , et&#xa0;al. The IMG/M data management and analysis system v.7: content updates and new features. Nucleic Acids Res. 2023;51(D1):D723&#x2013;D732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36382399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen TH, Boyles F, Deane CM. Observed antibody space: a diverse database of cleaned, annotated, and translated unpaired and paired antibody sequences. Protein Sci. 2022;31(1):141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34655133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandes N, Ofer D, Peleg Y, Rappoport N, Linial M. ProteinBERT: a universal deep&#x2010;learning model of protein sequence and function. Bioinformatics. 2022;38(8):2102&#x2013;2110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9386727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35020807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed E, Heinzinger M, Dallago C, Rehawi G, Wang Y, Jones L, et&#xa0;al. ProtTrans: toward understanding the language of life through self&#x2010;supervised learning. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell. 2021;44(10):7112&#x2013;7127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34232869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, McCann B, Naik N, Keskar NS, Anand N, Eguchi RR, et&#xa0;al. ProGen: language modeling for protein generation. 2020. Preprint at arXiv:2004.03497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijkamp E, Ruffolo JA, Weinstein EN, Naik N, Ali M. ProGen2: exploring the boundaries of protein language models. Cell Syst. 2023;14(11):968&#x2013;978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37909046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Cheng X, Li P, Geng YA, Gong J, Li S, et&#xa0;al. xTrimoPGLM: unified 100B&#x2010;scale pre&#x2010;trained Transformer for deciphering the language of protein. 2024. Preprint at arXiv:2401.06199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Zhang Z, Lu J, Zhu Z, Zhang Y, Chang M, et&#xa0;al. PEER: a comprehensive and multi&#x2010;task benchmark for protein sequence understanding. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2022;35:35156&#x2013;35173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unsal S, Atas H, Albayrak M, Turhan K, Acar AC, Dogan T. Learning functional properties of proteins with language models. Nat Mach Intell. 2022;4(3):227&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livesey BJ, Marsh JA. Updated benchmarking of variant effect predictors using deep mutational scanning. Mol Syst Biol. 2023;19(8):e11474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10407742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37310135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dallago C, Mou J, Johnston KE, Wittmann BJ, Bhattacharya N, Goldman S, et&#xa0;al. FLIP: benchmark tasks in fitness landscape inference for proteins. 2021. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2021.11.09.467890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M, Yuan F, Yang K, Ju F, Su J, Wang H, et&#xa0;al. Exploring evolution&#x2010;aware &amp;&#x2010;free protein language models as protein function predictors. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2022;35:38873&#x2013;38884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Thumuluri V, Martiny HM, Armenteros JJA, Salomon J, 
Nielsen&#xa0;H
, Johansen AR. NetSolP: predicting protein solubility in <i>Escherichia coli</i> using language models. Bioinformatics. 2022;38(4):941&#x2013;946.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Han C, Zhou Y, Shan J, Zhou X, Yuan F. SaProt: protein language modeling with structure&#x2010;aware vocabulary. In: The twelfth international conference on learning representations; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Wang C, Xu M, Chenthamarakshan V, Lozano A, Das P, et&#xa0;al. A systematic study of joint representation learning on protein sequences and structures. 2023. Preprint at arXiv:2303.06275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv L, Lin Z, Li H, Liu Y, Cui J, Yu&#x2010;Chian Chen C, et&#xa0;al. ProLLaMA: a protein large language model for multi&#x2010;task protein language processing. 2024. Preprint at arXiv:2402.16445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala D, Engelberger F, Mchaourab HS, Meiler J. Modeling conformational states of proteins with AlphaFold. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2023;81:102645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37392556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng EC, D Goddard T, Pettersen EF, Couch GS, Pearson ZJ, Morris JH, et&#xa0;al. UCSF ChimeraX: tools for structure building and analysis. Protein Sci. 2023;32(11):e4792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37774136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q, Guo F, Tang J. Improved structure&#x2010;related prediction for insufficient homologous proteins using MSA enhancement and pre&#x2010;trained language model. Briefings Bioinf. 2023;24(4):bbad217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37321965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middendorf L, Eicholt LA. Random, de novo, and conserved&#xa0;proteins: How structure and disorder predictors perform&#xa0;differently. Proteins Struct Funct Bioinf. 2024;92(6):757&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38226524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avraham O, Tsaban T, Ben&#x2010;Aharon Z, Tsaban L, Schueler&#x2010;Furman O. Protein language models can capture protein quaternary state. BMC Bioinf. 2023;24(1):433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10647083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37964216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulmanov M, Guzm&#xe1;n&#x2010;Vega FJ, Duek Roggli P, Lane L, Arold&#xa0;ST , Hoehndorf R. Protein function prediction as approximate semantic entailment. Nat Mach Intell. 2024;6(2):220&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Du Z, Li Y. pLM4CPPs: protein language model&#x2010;based predictor for cell penetrating peptides. J Chem Inf Model. 2024;65(3):1128&#x2013;1139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39878455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovanni Iovino B, Ye Y. Protein embedding based alignment. BMC Bioinf. 2024;25(1):85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10900708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thumuluri V, Armenteros JJA, Johansen AR, Nielsen H, Winther O. DeepLoc 2.0: multi&#x2010;label subcellular localization prediction using protein language models. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50(W1):W228&#x2013;W234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallgren J, Tsirigos KD, Pedersen MD, Armenteros JJA, Marcatili P, Nielsen H, et&#xa0;al. DeepTMHMM predicts alpha and beta transmembrane proteins using deep neural networks. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.04.08.487609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teufel F, Armenteros JJA, Johansen AR, G&#xed;slason MH, Pihl&#xa0;SI , Tsirigos KD, et&#xa0;al. SignalP 6.0 predicts all five types of signal peptides using protein language models. Nat Biotechnol. 2022;40(7):1023&#x2013;1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34980915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Ding X, Hsu W, Munir A, Xu Y, Li Y. pLM4ACE: a protein language model based predictor for antihypertensive peptide screening. Food Chem. 2024;431:137162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37604011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;Mauricio KL, Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Jacas CR, Cordoves&#x2010;Delgado G. Examining evolutionary scale modeling&#x2010;derived different&#x2010;dimensional embeddings in the antimicrobial peptide classification through a KNIME workflow. Protein Sci. 2024;33(4):e4928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38501511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh Rathore A, Choudhury S, Arora A, Tijare P, Raghava GPS. ToxinPred 3.0: an improved method for predicting the toxicity of peptides. Comput Biol Med. 2024;179:108926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39038391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manfredi M, Savojardo C, Martelli PL, Casadio R. E&#x2010;SNPs&amp;GO: embedding of protein sequence and function improves the annotation of human pathogenic variants. Bioinformatics. 2022;38(23):5168&#x2013;5174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9710551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36227117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraldson H&#xf8;ie M, Gade FS, Johansen JM, W&#xfc;rtzen C, Winther O, Nielsen M, et&#xa0;al. DiscoTope&#x2010;3.0: improved B&#x2010;cell epitope prediction using inverse folding latent representations. Front Immunol. 2024;15:1322712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10882062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redl I, Fisicaro C, Dutton O, Hoffmann F, Henderson L, Owens BMJ, et&#xa0;al. ADOPT: intrinsic protein disorder prediction through deep bidirectional Transformers. NAR Genom Bioinform. 2023;5(2):lqad041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10150328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37138579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koleske ML, McInnes G, Brown JEH, Thomas N, Hutchinson K, Chin MY, et&#xa0;al. Functional genomics of OCTN2 variants informs protein&#x2010;specific variant effect predictor for Carnitine Transporter Deficiency. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2022;119(46):e2210247119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9674959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36343260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquet C, Heinzinger M, Olenyi T, Dallago C, Erckert K, Bernhofer M, et&#xa0;al. Embeddings from protein language models predict conservation and variant effects. Hum Genet. 2022;141(10):1629&#x2013;1647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8716573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34967936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z, Wang R, Sun Y, Liu J, Chen Z, Zhang YJ. Interpretable feature extraction and dimensionality reduction in ESM2 for protein localization prediction. Briefings Bioinf. 2024;25(2):bbad534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38279650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraldson H&#xf8;ie M, Kiehl EN, Petersen B, Nielsen M, Winther O, Nielsen H, et&#xa0;al. NetSurfP&#x2010;3.0: accurate and fast prediction of protein structural features by protein language models and deep learning. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50(W1):W510&#x2013;W515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35648435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf8;ddeskov Clifford J, Haraldson H&#xf8;ie M, Deleuran S, Peters B, Nielsen M, Marcatili P. BepiPred&#x2010;3.0: improved B&#x2010;cell epitope prediction using protein language models. Protein Sci. 2022;31(12):e4497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9679979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36366745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong J, Jiang L, Chen Y, Zhang Y, Li X, Ma Z, et&#xa0;al. THPLM: a sequence&#x2010;based deep learning framework for protein stability changes prediction upon point variations using pretrained protein language model. Bioinformatics. 2023;39(11):btad646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10627365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37874953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak MA, Dovidchenko NV, Mishra Sharma S, Ivankov DN. New mega dataset combined with deep neural network makes a progress in predicting impact of mutation on protein stability. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.12.31.522396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villegas&#x2010;Morcillo A, Gomez AM, Sanchez V. An analysis of protein language model embeddings for fold prediction. Briefings Bioinf. 2022;23(3):bbac142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35443054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Sarkizova S, Chen X, Hacohen N, Uhler C. Unsupervised protein&#x2010;ligand binding energy prediction via neural Euler&#x2019;s rotation equation. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;3(6):33514&#x2013;33528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Chen X, Vetticaden A, Sarzikova S, Raychowdhury R, Uhler C, et&#xa0;al. DSMBind: SE (3) denoising score matching for unsupervised binding energy prediction and nanobody design. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.12.10.570461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing B, Berger B, Jaakkola T. AlphaFold meets flow matching for generating protein ensembles. 2024. Preprint at arXiv:2402.04845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipman Y, Chen RTQ, Ben&#x2010;Hamu H, Nickel M, Le M. Flow matching for generative modeling. 2022. Preprint at arXiv:2210.02747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu C, Nisonoff H, Fannjiang C, Listgarten J. Learning protein fitness models from evolutionary and assay&#x2010;labeled data. Nat Biotechnol. 2022;40(7):1114&#x2013;1122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35039677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdine H, Chatzianastasis M, Bouyioukos C, Vazirgiannis M. Prot2Text: multimodal proteins function generation with GNNs and Transformers. Proc AAAI Conf Artif Intell. 2024;38(10):10757&#x2013;10765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmirler R, Heinzinger M, Rost B. Fine&#x2010;tuning protein language models boosts predictions across diverse tasks. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):7407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11358375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39198457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shashkova TI, Umerenkov D, Salnikov M, Strashnov PV, Konstantinova AV, Lebed I, et&#xa0;al. SEMA: antigen B&#x2010;cell conformational epitope prediction using deep transfer learning. Front Immunol. 2022;13:960985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmalkar A, Rao R, Xie YR, Honer J, Deisting W, Anlahr J, et&#xa0;al. Toward generalizable prediction of anti&#x2010;body thermostability using machine learning on sequence and structure features. mAbs. 2023;15(1):2163584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9872953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lialin V, Deshpande V, Rumshisky A. Scaling down to scale up: a guide to parameter&#x2010;efficient fine&#x2010;tuning. 2023. Preprint at arXiv:2303.15647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Z, Gao C, Liu J, Zhang J, Zhang SQ. Parameter&#x2010;efficient fine&#x2010;tuning for large models: a comprehensive survey. 2024. Preprint at arXiv:2403.14608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebuffi S&#x2010;A, Bilen H, Vedaldi A. Learning multiple visual domains with residual adapters. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2017;30:506&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houlsby N, Giurgiu A, Jastrzebski S, Morrone B, De&#xa0;Laroussilhe Q, Gesmundo A, et&#xa0;al. Parameter&#x2010;efficient transfer learning for NLP. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2019. p. 2790&#x2013;2799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester B, Al&#x2010;Rfou R, Constant N. The power of scale for parameter&#x2010;efficient prompt tuning. 2021. Preprint at arXiv:2104.08691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu EJ, Shen Y, Wallis P, Allen&#x2010;Zhu Z, Li Y, Wang S, et&#xa0;al. LoRA: low&#x2010;rank adaptation of large language models. 2021. Preprint arXiv:2106.09685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng S, Wang D, Xu D. PEFT&#x2010;SP: parameter&#x2010;efficient fine&#x2010;tuning on large protein language models improves signal peptide prediction. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.11.04.565642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11529868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Pourmirzaei M, Abbas UL, Zeng S, Manshour N, Esmaili F, et&#xa0;al. S&#x2010;PLM: structure&#x2010;aware protein language model via contrastive learning between sequence and structure. Adv Sci. 2025;12(5):e2404212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11791933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39665266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroll A, Ranjan S, Engqvist MKM, Lercher MJ. A general model to predict small molecule substrates of enzymes based on machine and deep learning. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):2787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37188731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Pertsemlidis S, Watson R, Srikar Kavirayuni V, Hsu A, Vure P, et&#xa0;al. PepMLM: target sequence&#x2010;conditioned generation of peptide binders via masked language modeling. 2023. Preprint at arXiv:2310.03842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Zhang L, Yu Y, Wu B, Li M, Hong L, et&#xa0;al. Enhancing efficiency of protein language models with minimal wet&#x2010;lab data through few&#x2010;shot learning. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):5566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11219809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincoff S, Goel S, Kholina K, Pulugurta R, Vure P, Chatterjee P. FusOn&#x2010;pLM: a fusion oncoprotein&#x2010;specific language model via focused probabilistic masking. 2024. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2024.06.03.597245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;ie M, Hummer A, Olsen T, Nielsen M, Deane C. AntiFold: improved antibody structure design using inverse folding. In: NeurIPS 2023 generative AI and biology (GenBio) workshop; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamali K, K&#xe4;ll L, Zhang R, Brown A, Kimanius D, Scheres SHW. Automated model building and protein identification in cryo&#x2010;EM maps. Nature. 2024;628(8007):450&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11006616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38408488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Bonvin AMJJ. DeepRank&#x2010;GNN&#x2010;esm: a graph neural network for scoring protein&#x2010;protein models using protein language model. Bioinform Adv. 2024;4(1):vbad191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10782804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38213822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Wei Z, Yuan Q, Chen S, Yu W, Lu Y, et&#xa0;al. Identifying B&#x2010;cell epitopes using AlphaFold2 predicted structures and pretrained language model. Bioinformatics. 2023;39(4):btad187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37039829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y, Zhou B, Zheng L, Fan G, Hong L. Semantical and geometrical protein encoding toward enhanced bioactivity and thermostability. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.12.01.569522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12048155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40314227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Zhang Z, Li Z, Li R, Huo R, Chen L, et&#xa0;al. Learning protein fitness landscapes with deep mutational scanning data from multiple sources. Cell Syst. 2023;14(8):706&#x2013;721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37591206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wang Y, Ni X, Yang S. DeepDRP: prediction of intrinsically disordered regions based on integrated view deep learning architecture from Transformer&#x2010;enhanced and protein information. Int J Biol Macromol. 2023;253:127390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37827403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Huo M, Zhang R, Xie P. ProteinChat: towards achieving chatGPT&#x2010;like functionalities on protein 3D structures. 2023. Preprint at arXiv:2402.09649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Xu J. Deep graph learning of inter&#x2010;protein contacts. Bioinformatics. 2022;38(4):947&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8796373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34755837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Kang L, Xiong Y, Wang YG, Fan G, Tan P, et&#xa0;al. SES&#x2010;Net: sequence&#x2010;structure feature&#x2010;integrated deep learning method for data&#x2010;efficient protein engineering. J Cheminf. 2023;15(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanehsazzadeh A, Alverio J, Kasun G, Levine S, Khan JA, Chung C, et&#xa0;al. In vitro validated antibody design against multiple therapeutic antigens using generative inverse folding. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.12.08.570889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Li M, Zhou B, Zhong B, Zheng L, Tan P, et&#xa0;al. Simple,&#xa0;efficient, and scalable structure&#x2010;aware adapter boosts protein language models. J Chem Inf Model. 2024;64(16):6338&#x2013;6349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39110130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Jiang Y, Wei L, Ma Q, Ren Z, Yuan Q, et&#xa0;al. Deep&#x2010;ProSite: structure&#x2010;aware protein binding site prediction using ESMFold and pretrained language model. Bioinformatics. 2023;39(12):btad718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10723037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38015872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Q, Tian C, Song Y, Ou P, Zhu M, Zhao H, et&#xa0;al. GPSFun: geometry&#x2010;aware protein sequence function predictions with language models. Nucleic Acids Res. 2024:gkae381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11223820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38738636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Fan H, Wu Y, Xie S, Girshick R. Momentum contrast for unsupervised visual representation learning. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition; 2020. p. 9729&#x2013;9738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu T, Cui H, Li JC, Luo Y, Jiang G, Zhao H. Enzyme function prediction using contrastive learning. Science. 2023;379(6639):1358&#x2013;1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36996195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Sledzieski S, Bryson B, Cowen L, Berger B. Contrastive learning in protein language space predicts interactions between drugs and protein targets. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2023;120(24):e2220778120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10268324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford A, Kim JW, Hallacy C, Ramesh A, Goh G, Agarwal S, et&#xa0;al. Learning transferable visual models from natural language supervision. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2021. p. 8748&#x2013;8763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B, Qiang B, Tan H, Jia Y, Ren M, Lu M, et&#xa0;al. DrugCLIP: contrasive protein&#x2010;molecule representation learning for virtual screening. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;36:44595&#x2013;44614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat S, Palepu K, Yudistyra V, Hong L, Kavirayuni VS, Chen T, et&#xa0;al. De novo generation and prioritization of target&#x2010;binding peptide motifs from sequence alone. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.06.26.546591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palepu K, Ponnapati M, Bhat S, Tysinger E, Stan T, Brixi G, et&#xa0;al. Design of peptide&#x2010;based protein degraders via contrastive deep learning. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.05.23.493169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton J, Jacob DG, Leem J. Enhancing antibody language models with structural information. 2024. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.12.12.569610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Lu J, Chenthamarakshan V, Lozano A, Das P, Tang J. Structure&#x2010;informed protein language model. 2024. Preprint arXiv:2402.05856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian AM, Thomson M. Unexplored regions of the protein sequence&#x2010;structure map revealed at scale by a library of foldtuned language models. 2025. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.12.22.573145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kempen M, Kim SS, Tumescheit C, Mirdita M, Gilchrist&#xa0;CLM , S&#xf6;ding J, et&#xa0;al. Foldseek: fast and accurate protein structure&#xa0;search. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.02.07.479398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37156916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Deng Y, Xue D, Zhou Y, Ye F, Gu Q. Structure&#x2010;informed language models are protein designers. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2023. p. 42317&#x2013;42338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D, Hartout P, Pellizzoni P, Oliver C, Borgwardt K. Endowing protein language models with structural knowledge. 2024. Preprint at arXiv:2401.14819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12603367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41159381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao R, Meier J, Sercu T, Ovchinnikov S, Rives A. Transformer protein language models are unsupervised structure learners. 2020. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2020.12.15.422761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verkuil R, Kabeli O, Du Y, Wicky BIM, Milles LF, Dauparas J, et&#xa0;al. Language models generalize beyond natural proteins. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.12.21.521521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P, Yan Y, Huang SY. DeepHomo2.0: improved protein&#x2013;protein contact prediction of homodimers by Transformer&#x2010;enhanced deep learning. Briefings Bioinf. 2023;24(1):bbac499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36440949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P, Tao H, Li H, Huang SY. Protein&#x2010;protein contact prediction by geometric triangle&#x2010;aware protein language models. Nat Mach Intell. 2023;5(11):1275&#x2013;1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P, Yan Y, Tao H, Huang SY. Deep transfer learning for inter&#x2010;chain contact predictions of transmembrane protein complexes. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):4935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37582780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittmann BJ, Yue Y, Arnold FH. Informed training set design enables efficient machine learning&#x2010;assisted directed protein evolution. Cell Syst. 2021;12(11):1026&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TVT, Son Hy T. Protein design by directed evolution guided by large language models. IEEE Trans Evol Comput. 2025;29(2):418&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu R, Fu L, Chen Y, Chen J, Qiao Y, Tong S. Protein engineering via Bayesian optimization&#x2010;guided evolutionary algorithm and robotic experiments. Briefings Bioinf. 2023;24(1):bbac570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36562723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren M, Yu C, Bu D, Zhang H. Accurate and robust protein sequence design with CarbonDesign. Nat Mach Intell. 2024;6(5):536&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin A, Berner C, Ovchinnikov S, Vorobieva AA. Validation of de novo designed water&#x2010;soluble and transmembrane proteins by in silico folding and melting. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.06.06.543955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38864690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hie B, Candido S, Lin Z, Kabeli O, Rao R, Smetanin N, et&#xa0;al. A high&#x2010;level programming language for generative protein design. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.12.21.521526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandes N, Goldman G, Wang CH, Ye CJ, Ntranos V. Genome&#x2010;wide prediction of disease variant effects with a deep protein language model. Nat Genet. 2023;55(9):1512&#x2013;1522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10484790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37563329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hie BL, Shanker VR, Xu D, Bruun TUJ, Weidenbacher PA, Tang&#xa0;S , et&#xa0;al. Efficient evolution of human antibodies from general protein language models. Nat Biotechnol. 2024;42(2):275&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagota M, Ye C, Albors C, Rastogi R, Koehl A, Ioannidis N, et&#xa0;al. Cross&#x2010;protein transfer learning substantially improves disease variant prediction. Genome Biol. 2023;24(1):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10408151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37550700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Wei GW. CLADE 2.0: evolution&#x2010;driven cluster learning&#x2010;assisted directed evolution. J Chem Inf Model. 2022;62(19):4629&#x2013;4641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36154171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson SR, Fu X, Viknander S, Goldin C, Monaco S, Zelezniak A, et&#xa0;al. Computational scoring and experimental evaluation of enzymes generated by neural networks. Nat Biotechnol. 2024;43(3):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11919684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38653796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Tang H, Huang L, Pan L, Yang L, Yang H, et&#xa0;al. Self&#x2010;play reinforcement learning guides protein engineering. Nat Mach Intell. 2023;5(8):845&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanker VR, Bruun TUJ, Hie BL, Kim PS. Inverse folding of protein complexes with a structure&#x2010;informed language model enables unsupervised antibody evolution. Science. 2024;385(6704):46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11616794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38963838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamdari S, Thakkar N, van den Berg R, Lu AX, Fusi N, Amini AP, et&#xa0;al. Protein generation with evolutionary diffusion: sequence&#xa0;is&#xa0;all you need. 2023. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2023.09.11.556673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury R, Bouatta N, Biswas S, Floristean C, Kharkar A, Roy K, et&#xa0;al. Single&#x2010;sequence protein structure prediction using a language model and deep learning. Nat Biotechnol. 2022;40(11):1617&#x2013;1623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10440047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffolo JA, Chu LS, Mahajan SP, Gray JJ. Fast, accurate antibody structure prediction from deep learning on massive set of natural antibodies. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):2389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10129313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Yuan X, Miret S, Tang J. ProtST: multi&#x2010;modality learning of protein sequences and biomedical texts. In: International conference on machine learning. PMLR; 2023. p. 38749&#x2013;38767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, You R, Liu Y, Xiong Y, Zhu S. NetGO 3.0: protein language model improves large&#x2010;scale functional annotations. Genom Proteom Bioinform. 2023;21(2):349&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10626176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37075830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilgore HR, Chinn I, Mikhael PG, Mitnikov I, Van Dongen C, Zylberberg G, et&#xa0;al. Protein codes promote selective subcellular compartmentalization. Science. 2025;387:1095&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12034300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39913643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Wang Z, You R, Xie C, Wei H, Xiong Y, et&#xa0;al. PLMSearch: protein language model powers accurate and fast sequence search for remote homology. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):2775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10981738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38555371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang PD, Ma J, Chen T. Escaping the drug&#x2010;bias trap: using debiasing design to improve interpretability and generalization of drug&#x2010;target interaction prediction. 2024. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2024.09.12.612771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40811213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notin P, Kollasch A, Ritter D, Van Niekerk L, Paul S, Han S, et&#xa0;al. ProteinGym: large&#x2010;scale benchmarks for protein fitness prediction and design. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;36:64331&#x2013;64379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou J, Adhikari B, Cheng J. DeepSF: deep convolutional neural network for mapping protein sequences to folds. Bioinformatics. 2018;34(8):1295&#x2013;1303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5905591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valeriani L, Doimo D, Cuturello F, Laio A, Ansuini A, Cazzaniga&#xa0;A . The geometry of hidden representations of large Transformer models. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;36:51234&#x2013;51252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R, Ding F, Wang R, Shen R, Zhang X, Luo S, et&#xa0;al. High&#x2010;resolution de novo structure prediction from primary sequence. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.07.21.500999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Xie Z, Qiu J, Ye Z, Xu J, Tang J. Improved the protein complex prediction with protein language models. 2022. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2022.09.15.508065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Peng Z, Yang J. Single&#x2010;sequence protein structure prediction using supervised Transformer protein language models. Nat Comput Sci. 2022;2(12):804&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38177395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang X, Wang F, Liu L, He J, Lin D, Xiang Y, et&#xa0;al. A method for multiple&#x2010;sequence&#x2010;alignment&#x2010;free protein structure prediction using a protein language model. Nat Mach Intell. 2023;5(10):1087&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek M, DiMaio F, Anishchenko I, Dauparas J, Ovchinnikov S, Lee GR, et&#xa0;al. Accurate prediction of protein structures and interactions using a three&#x2010;track neural network. Science. 2021;373(6557):871&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34282049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubel M, Eicholt L, Bornberg&#x2010;Bauer E. Assessing structure and disorder prediction tools for de novo emerged proteins in the age of machine learning. F1000Research. 2023;12:347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s&#x2010;Tresanco MS, Vald&#xe9;s&#x2010;Tresanco ME, Jim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;Guti&#xe9;rrez&#xa0;DE , Moreno E. Structural modeling of nanobodies: a benchmark of state&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;art artificial intelligence programs. Molecules. 2023;28(10):3991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kshirsagar M, Meller A, Humphreys IR, Sledzieski S, Xu Y, Dodhia R, et&#xa0;al. Rapid and accurate prediction of protein homo&#x2010;oligomer symmetry using Seq2Symm. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11868566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40016259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bairoch A. The ENZYME database in 2000. Nucleic Acids Res. 2000;28(1):304&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC102465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10592255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Xu M, Rokkum Jamasb A, Chenthamarakshan V, Lozano A, Das P, et&#xa0;al. Protein representation learning by geometric structure pretraining. In: The eleventh international conference on learning representations; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner M, Ball CA, Blake JA, Botstein D, Butler H, Cherry JM, et&#xa0;al. Gene ontology: tool for the unification of biology. Nat Genet. 2000;25(1):25&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10802651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si Y, Yan C. Improved inter&#x2010;protein contact prediction using dimensional hybrid residual networks and protein language models. Briefings Bioinf. 2023;24(2):bbad039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbery A, Buttenschoen M, Skyner R, von Delft F, Deane CM. Learnt representations of proteins can be used for accurate prediction of small molecule binding sites on experimentally determined and predicted protein structures. J Cheminf. 2024;16(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10941399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38486231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubach M, Maass T, Nazaretyan L, R&#xf6;ner S, Kircher M. CADD v1.7: using protein language models, regulatory CNNs&#xa0;and other nucleotide&#x2010;level scores to improve genome&#x2010;wide variant predictions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2024;52(D1):D1143&#x2013;D1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10767851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38183205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrum MJ, Lee JM, Benson M, Brown G, Chen C, Chitipiralla&#xa0;S , et&#xa0;al. ClinVar: public archive of interpretations of clinically relevant variants. Nucleic Acids Res. 2016;44(D1):D862&#x2013;D868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26582918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopf TA, Ingraham JB, Poelwijk FJ, Sch&#xe4;rfe CPI, Springer&#xa0;M , Sander C, et&#xa0;al. Mutation effects predicted from&#xa0;sequence co&#x2010;variation. Nat Biotechnol. 2017;35(2):128&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28092658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian H, Wang Y, Zhou X, Gu T, Wang H, Lyu H, et&#xa0;al. ESM&#x2010;Ezy: a deep learning strategy for the mining of novel multicopper oxidases with superior properties. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):3274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11972304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40188191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang KK, Fusi N, Lu AX. Convolutions are competitive with Transformers for protein sequence pretraining. Cell Syst. 2024;15(3):286&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38428432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Wayment&#x2010;Steele HK, Brixi G, Wang H, Peraro MD, Kern D, et&#xa0;al. Protein language models learn evolutionary statistics of interacting sequence motifs. 2024. Preprint at bioRxiv: 2024.01.30.577970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11551344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39467119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>