<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41377606</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1976-1457</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition research and practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Res Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of food literacy on short- and long-term healthy eating intentions among adolescent and adult convenience store users: An application of the extended theory of planned behavior.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>917</StartPage><EndPage>931</EndPage><MedlinePgn>917-931</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4162/nrp.2025.19.6.917</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The present study aimed to analyze the effect of food literacy on the short-term and long-term healthy eating intentions of convenience store consumers using the Extended Theory of Planned Behavior (ETPB) framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUBJECTS/METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional online survey was conducted in South Korea in September 2023. A total of 397 Korean participants were recruited through convenience sampling. The independent variables included food literacy, attitudes, subjective norms, and perceived behavioral control. The &#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> tests, <i>t</i>-tests, correlation analysis, and hierarchical regression were performed, with statistical significance set at <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Adolescents showed significantly higher food literacy than adults (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01). In contrast, adults demonstrated higher scores in attitude (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01), subjective norm (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05), perceived behavioral control (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01), and short-term (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) and long-term healthy eating intentions (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). When food literacy was included as a variable in the hierarchical regression analysis, the explanatory power for short-term and long-term healthy eating intentions increased by 1.7% and 5.3%, respectively (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study highlights the need for customized nutrition education and continuous, systematic education on eating habits to enhance food literacy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2025 The Korean Nutrition Society and the Korean Society of Community Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Wonyeong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-2461-916X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Science and Food Management, Ewha Womans University, Seoul 03760, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Hae Jin</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5145-2232</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Science and Food Management, Ewha Womans University, Seoul 03760, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moon</LastName><ForeName>Suah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3945-407X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Science and Food Management, Ewha Womans University, Seoul 03760, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Jieun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4152-8306</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Science and Industry Convergence, Ewha Womans University, Seoul 03760, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Res Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101311052</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1976-1457</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adult</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eating behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">literacy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: The authors declare no potential conflicts of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41377606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12688001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4162/nrp.2025.19.6.917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alsubhi M, Blake M, Nguyen T, Majmudar I, Moodie M, Ananthapavan J. Consumer willingness to pay for healthier food products: a systematic review. Obes Rev. 2023;24:e13525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10909406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HS, Kim JH. Analysis of food consumption behavior due to COVID-19: focusing on MZ generation. J Digit Converg. 2021;19:47&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Donoso C, Sacks G, Vanderlee L, Hammond D, White CM, Nieto C, Bes-Rastrollo M, Cameron AJ. Public support for healthy supermarket initiatives focused on product placement: a multi-country cross-sectional analysis of the 2018 International Food Policy Study. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2021;18:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8201822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34127002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Food Trust. Healthy Corner Store Initiative: 2013&#x2013;2014 year three report. Philadelphia (PA): The Food Trust; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CL, Minaker LM, Jameson K, Rappaport L, Taylor K, Graham M, Moody N, Cook B. An introduction to the healthy corner store intervention model in Canada. Can J Public Health. 2017;108:e320&#x2013;e324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6972218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28910256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Korea. Convenience store sales trends by item [Internet] Daejeon: Statistics Korea; 2025.  [updated 2025 Aug 8].  [cited 2025 Sep 25].  Available from:  https://kosis.kr/statHtml/statHtml.do?orgId=115&amp;tblId=DT_11523_300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon S, Lim J, Yeo G, Kim Y, Oh J. A study on the consumer behavior and attitude toward low-sodium convenience store foods. Nutr Res Pract. 2024;18:567&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11300112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39109200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Food and Drug Safety. KFDA supports the operation of healthy food sections in convenience stores [Internet] Cheongju: Ministry of Food and Drug Safety address; 2024.  [updated 2024].  [cited 2024 Dec 1].  Available from:  https://impfood.mfds.go.kr/CFBBB02F02/getCntntsDetail?cntntsSn=566353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorbas C, Palermo C, Chung A, Iguacel I, Peeters A, Bennett R, Backholer K. Factors perceived to influence healthy eating: a systematic review and meta-ethnographic synthesis of the literature. Nutr Rev. 2018;76:861&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30202944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truman E, Lane D, Elliott C. Defining food literacy: a scoping review. Appetite. 2017;116:365&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28487244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen T, Hatch J, Martin W, Higgins JW, Sheppard R. Food literacy: definition and framework for action. Can J Diet Pract Res. 2015;76:140&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26280794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Kim EK, Shin MJ, Park DH, Choi MK. Food Information Literacy for Sustainable Diets. Wanju: National Institute of Agricultural Sciences; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo H, Jo E, Lee H, Ko E, Jang E, Sim J, Park S. Who has a high level of food literacy, and who does not?: a qualitative study of college students in South Korea. Nutr Res Pract. 2023;17:1155&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10694421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38053819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko E, Jang E, Sim J, Jeong M, Park S. Evaluating the effectiveness of a food literacy pilot program for university students: using a mixed-methods research approach. Nutr Res Pract. 2024;18:885&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11621428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39651321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manna A, Vidgen H, Gallegos D. Examining the effectiveness of food literacy interventions in improving food literacy behavior and healthy eating among adults belonging to different socioeconomic groups- a systematic scoping review. Syst Rev. 2024;13:221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11350956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39198926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sui D, He J, Liu K, Lv X. Investigating the impact of the Theory of Planned Behavior and food literacy on green food purchasing intentions among Chinese baby boomers, Generation X, and Generation Y. Sustainability (Basel) 2024;16:10467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. The theory of planned behavior. Organ Behav Hum Decis Process. 1991;50:179&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conner M, Armitage CJ. Extending the theory of planned behavior: a review and avenues for further research. J Appl Soc Psychol. 1998;28:1429&#x2013;1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B, Hwang JY. How food literacy levels shape healthy eating intentions: a cross-sectional study of adults in Shandong Province, China, using the theory of planned behavior. Nutr Res Pract. 2025;19:566&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12340098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40809883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Lee S, Hwang JY. Factors related to the intention of healthy eating behaviors based on the theory of planned behavior: focused on adults residing in Beijing, China. J Nutr Health. 2021;54:67&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fila SA, Smith C. Applying the Theory of Planned Behavior to healthy eating behaviors in urban native American youth. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2006;3:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1501033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16734903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwezen MC, Van &#x2019;t Riet J, Dagevos H, Sijtsema SJ, Snoek HM. Snacking now or later? Individual differences in following intentions or habits explained by time perspective. Appetite. 2016;107:144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Povey R, Conner M, Sparks P, James R, Shepherd R. Application of the Theory of Planned Behaviour to two dietary behaviours: roles of perceived control and self-efficacy. Br J Health Psychol. 2000;5:121&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RA, Mueller J, Sharp SJ, Griffin SJ, Ahern AL. Long-term impact of a behavioral weight management program&#xa0;on depression and anxiety symptoms: 5-year follow-up of the WRAP trial. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2022;30:2396&#x2013;2403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9828709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36300839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YA, Yu SR. A study of market segmentation for consumption value about convenience store private brand food. Foodserv Ind J. 2019;15:39&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu A, Lee SW, Hwang JY. Factors related to the short-term and long-term intentions of healthy eating among Chinese adults living in Shanghai and parts of Anhui Province of China using the theory of planned behavior. J Nutr Health. 2022;55:188&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park D, Park YK, Park CY, Choi MK, Shin MJ. Development of a comprehensive food literacy measurement tool integrating the food system and sustainability. Nutrients. 2020;12:3300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salles C. TERIFIQ - Combining technologies to achieve significant binary reductions in sodium, fat and sugar content in everyday foods whilst optimising their nutritional quality &#x2013; FP7 project. Impact (Sydney) 2016;2016:23&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez KJ, Gillis D, Kevany K, Kirk S. Towards a common understanding of food literacy: a pedagogical framework. Can Food Stud. 2021;8:1&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabasakal-Cetin A, Aksaray B, Sen G. The role of food literacy and sustainable and healthy eating behaviors in ultra-processed foods consumption of undergraduate students. Food Qual Prefer. 2024;119:105232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munna AS, Kalam MA. Impact of active learning strategy on the student engagement. Interdiscip J Hum Theor Prax. 2021;4:96&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begley A, Paynter E, Butcher LM, Dhaliwal SS. Effectiveness of an adult food literacy program. Nutrients. 2019;11:797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30959958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Shim E, Kyung MS, Kwon S, Park HS, Kang JH. Application of a living lab model to an evidence-based reduced-sodium healthy eating practice program in Korea: a pre-post study. Korean J Community Nutr. 2025;30:53&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12269036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41030498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain M, Leminen S, Westerlund M. A systematic review of living lab literature. J Clean Prod. 2019;213:976&#x2013;988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SA, Kim JA. Analysis of Dietary Habits of Seoul Citizens and Policy Directions for Food and Nutrition (Policy Report No. 2023-PR-14) Seoul: Seoul Institute; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez F, Brugueras S, Serral G, Valmayor S, Ju&#xe1;rez O, L&#xf3;pez MJ, Ariza C Group OBOTPPE. Three-year follow-up of the POIBA intervention on childhood obesity: a quasi-experimental study. Nutrients. 2021;13:453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7911572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras F, Al-Najim W, le Roux CW. Health benefits beyond the scale: the role of diet and nutrition during weight loss programmes. Nutrients. 2024;16:3585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11547696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39519418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na YS, Oh JE, Lee KW. A qualitative study of changes in adolescent dietary behavior during the COVID-19 pandemic and improvement strategies for school-provided nutrition counseling. Hum Ecol Rev. 2023;61:39&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu KSN, Chen JY, Ng MYC, Yeung MHY, Bedford LE, Lam CLK. How does the family influence adolescent eating habits in terms of knowledge, attitudes and practices? A global systematic review of qualitative studies. Nutrients. 2021;13:3717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8624651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34835973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>