<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41502128</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-6712</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of caring sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Caring Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mothers' Lived Experiences of Participating in Pain Management for Hospitalised Preterm Infants During Invasive Procedures: An Interpretive Phenomenological Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70180</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70180</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/scs.70180</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Preterm infants are subjected to numerous painful procedures during their hospitalisation. Parental involvement, especially mothers, in pain management has been emphasised as one of the most effective approaches for relieving this pain. Understanding mothers' experiences is critical to improving neonatal pain management. This study aimed to explore the lived experiences of mothers from participating in pain management for hospitalised preterm infants during invasive procedures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGICAL DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">This research is a qualitative study with an interpretive phenomenological approach. Data were collected through unstructured interviews with 10 mothers of preterm infants, employing purposeful sampling using a sequential and emergence-driven strategy with a saturation/redundancy approach to select participants. Interviews were initiated with an open-ended question about the mothers' experiences of participating in infants' pain management during invasive procedures, followed by probing questions based on their experiences. Data analysis was conducted through an interpretive phenomenological analysis approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis revealed a constitutive pattern of 'progressive development of capability', comprising three themes: reconstructing the healing role of the mother, maternal growth and transformation, and becoming a healing agent. The subthemes are as follows: 'Sense of helplessness', 'mother on the margin', 'becoming an advocate', 'witnessing pain, discovering responsibility', 'observation and learning', 'laying the groundwork for participation', 'maternal selflessness', 'understanding the maternal healing power' and 'self-confidence'.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of this study revealed that mothers of preterm infants gradually develop the capability to manage their infants' pain with the support and education of healthcare professionals. Empowering mothers as active partners through staff education and attention to family-centred care approaches can improve neonatal pain management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Nordic College of Caring Science.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avazeh</LastName><ForeName>Marzieh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6630-3632</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Nursing, Faculty of Nursing and Midwifery, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahbazi</LastName><ForeName>Shahla</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4146-9425</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Surgical Nursing, Faculty of Nursing and Midwifery, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borimnejad</LastName><ForeName>Leili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7549-0505</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neonatal and Pediatric Nursing Department, Nursing and Midwifery School, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Mohammadbagher</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9067-9392</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Health Research Centre, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabraeili</LastName><ForeName>Mahnaz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6400-0806</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Nursing, Faculty of Nursing and Midwifery, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Tabriz University of Medical Sciences</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Sweden</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Caring Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804206</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0283-9318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009035" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mothers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059408" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pain Management</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007234" MajorTopicYN="Y">Infant, Premature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">experiences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">invasive procedures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mothers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">participation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preterm infants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41502128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/scs.70180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>X. Yu, J. Zhang, and L. Yuan, &#x201c;Chinese Parents' Lived Experiences of Having Preterm Infants in NICU: A Qualitative Study,&#x201d; Journal of Pediatric Nursing 50 (2020): e48&#x2013;e54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Zhao, T. Griffith, Y. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Early&#x2010;Life Factors Associated With Neurobehavioral Outcomes in Preterm Infants During NICU Hospitalization,&#x201d; Pediatric Research 92, no. 6 (2022): 1695&#x2013;1704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ganguly, P. J. Bhadesia, A. G. Phatak, A. S. Nimbalkar, and S. M. Nimbalkar, &#x201c;Pain Profile of Premature Infants During Routine Procedures in Neonatal Intensive Care: An Observational Study,&#x201d; Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care 9, no. 3 (2020): 1517&#x2013;1521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Orovec, T. Disher, K. Caddell, and M. Campbell&#x2010;Yeo, &#x201c;Assessment and Management of Procedural Pain During the Entire Neonatal Intensive Care Unit Hospitalization,&#x201d; Pain Management Nursing 20, no. 5 (2019): 503&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McPherson, S. P. Miller, M. El&#x2010;Dib, A. N. Massaro, and T. E. Inder, &#x201c;The Influence of Pain, Agitation, and Their Management on the Immature Brain,&#x201d; Pediatric Research 88, no. 2 (2020): 168&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. G. Duerden, R. E. Grunau, T. Guo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Early Procedural Pain Is Associated With Regionally&#x2010;Specific Alterations in Thalamic Development in Preterm Neonates,&#x201d; Journal of Neuroscience 38, no. 4 (2018): 878&#x2013;886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Efe, E. Erdem, N. Caner, and T. G&#xfc;ne&#x15f;, &#x201c;The Effect of Gentle Human Touch on Pain, Comfort and Physiological Parameters in Preterm Infants During Heel Lancing,&#x201d; Complementary Therapies in Clinical Practice 48 (2022): 101622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Bucsea and R. P. Riddell, eds., Non&#x2010;Pharmacological Pain Management in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit: Managing Neonatal Pain Without Drugs (Elsevier, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Balice&#x2010;Bourgois, M. Zumstein&#x2010;Shaha, G. D. Simonetti, and C. J. Newman, &#x201c;Interprofessional Collaboration and Involvement of Parents in the Management of Painful Procedures in Newborns,&#x201d; Frontiers in Pediatrics 8 (2020): 394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lee, &#x201c;Neonatal Family&#x2010;Centered Care: Evidence and Practice Models,&#x201d; Clinical and Experimental Pediatrics 67, no. 4 (2023): 171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ullsten, S. Beken, M. Campbell&#x2010;Yeo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Parents in Neonatal Pain Management&#x2014;An International Survey of Parent&#x2010;Delivered Interventions and Parental Pain Assessment,&#x201d; Children 11, no. 9 (2024): 1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. O'Brien, B. J. Stevens, and J. Songok, &#x201c;Mothers' Perceptions About Pain in Hospitalized Newborn Infants in Kenya,&#x201d; Journal of Pediatric Nursing 47 (2019): 51&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. &#xc7;amur, &#x201c;Parental Involvement in Mitigating Procedural Pain for Infants Using Non&#x2010;Pharmacological Approaches,&#x201d; Evidence&#x2010;Based Nursing 27 (2024): e2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ullsten, M. Campbell&#x2010;Yeo, and M. Eriksson, &#x201c;Parent&#x2010;Led Neonatal Pain Management&#x2014;A Narrative Review and Update of Research and Practices,&#x201d; Frontiers in Pain Research 5 (2024): 1375868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Acharya and D. Sethi, &#x201c;Effectiveness of Involving Parents During Minor Invasive Procedures of the Neonates Admitted in Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU): A Review Based on Available Literature,&#x201d; International Journal of Innovative Research in Science, Engineering and Technology 8, no. 7 (2023): 1781&#x2013;1788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Arshadi Bostanabad, S. Alizadeh, H. Namdar Areshtanab, and S. Nemati, &#x201c;The Viewpoint of Mothers on Pain Management in Neonatal Intensive Care Units,&#x201d; Journal of Client&#x2010;Centered Nursing Care 5, no. 2 (2019): 123&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Treiman&#x2010;Kiveste, M. Kangasniemi, R. Kalda, and T. P&#xf6;lkki, &#x201c;Parental Participation in Their Infants' Procedural Pain Alleviation With Nonpharmacologic Methods in Estonia,&#x201d; Pain Management Nursing 24, no. 6 (2023): 641&#x2013;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. van der Vaart, A. G. V. Hauck, R. Mansfield, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Parental Experience of Neonatal Pain Research While Participating in the Parental Touch Trial (Petal),&#x201d; Pain 165, no. 8 (2024): 1727&#x2013;1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Carlsen Misic, E. Olsson, Y. Thernstr&#xf6;m Blomqvist, and A. Ullsten, &#x201c;Preparation Is Key: Parents' and Nurses' Perceptions of Combined Parent&#x2010;Delivered Pain Management in Neonatal Care,&#x201d; Children 11, no. 7 (2024): 781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M&#xe4;ki&#x2010;Asiala, A. Axelin, and T. P&#xf6;lkki, &#x201c;Parents' Experiences With Interprofessional Collaboration in Neonatal Pain Management: A Descriptive Qualitative Study,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Nursing 32, no. 21&#x2013;22 (2023): 7860&#x2013;7872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McNair, M. McAllister, L. S. Franck, B. Stevens, and A. Taddio, &#x201c;Parents' Experiences With Infant Pain Management in the NICU,&#x201d; Journal of Obstetric, Gynecologic, and Neonatal Nursing 53, no. 6 (2024): 648&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.&#x2010;K. Palomaa, A. Korhonen, and T. P&#xf6;lkki, &#x201c;Factors Influencing Parental Participation in Neonatal Pain Alleviation,&#x201d; Journal of Pediatric Nursing 31, no. 5 (2016): 519&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ullsten, M. Andreasson, and M. Eriksson, &#x201c;State of the Art in Parent&#x2010;Delivered Pain&#x2010;Relieving Interventions in Neonatal Care: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; Frontiers in Pediatrics 9 (2021): 651846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Van Manen, Researching Lived Experience: Human Science for an Action Sensitive Pedagogy (Routledge, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Q. Patton, Qualitative Research &amp; Evaluation Methods: Integrating Theory and Practice (Sage publications, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. D. Crist and C. A. Tanner, &#x201c;Interpretation/Analysis Methods in Hermeneutic Interpretive Phenomenology,&#x201d; Nursing Research 52, no. 3 (2003): 202&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. L. Diekelmann, D. Allen, and C. A. Tanner, The NLN Criteria for Appraisal of Baccalaureate Programs: A Critical Hermeneutic Analysis (ABRAMS, 1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Lincoln and E. G. Guba, &#x201c;But Is It Rigorous? Trustworthiness and Authenticity in Naturalistic Evaluation,&#x201d; New Directions for Program Evaluation 1986, no. 30 (1986): 73&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association, &#x201c;World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: Ethical Principles for Medical Research Involving Human Participants,&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 333, no. 1 (2025): 71&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McNair, N. Chirinian, E. Uleryk, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effectiveness of Parental Education About Pain in the Neonatal Period on Knowledge, Attitudes, and Practices: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Paediatrics &amp; Child Health 27, no. 8 (2022): 454&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Benoit, C. Cassidy, J. Van Wijlen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Codevelopment of Implementation Interventions to Support Parent&#x2010;Led Care for Pain in Infants: Protocol for a Qualitative Descriptive Study,&#x201d; JMIR Research Protocols 11, no. 8 (2022): e33770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Feng, J. Jing, M. Shi, B. Tang, and L. Xie, &#x201c;Facilitators and Barriers to Parental Involvement in Neonatal Pain Management in the NICU: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; BMJ Open 15, no. 1 (2025): e085881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McNair, Enhancing Parental Role in Managing Pain in Neonates (University of Toronto (Canada), 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Hughes, R. Martin&#x2010;Misener, M. Latimer, M. Smit, P. McGrath, and M. Campbell&#x2010;Yeo, &#x201c;Parenting Pain Away: Quasi&#x2010;Experimental Study of an eHealth Learning Platform to Evaluate Acceptability, Feasibility, and Utilisation of Parent&#x2010;Led Pain Management,&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Caring Sciences 38, no. 4 (2024): 960&#x2013;972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Gates, K. Shave, R. Featherstone, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Procedural Pain: Systematic Review of Parent Experiences and Information Needs,&#x201d; La Clinica Pediatrica 57, no. 6 (2018): 672&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Tani, H. Ueda, and N. Hott, &#x201c;Feelings of Mothers Who Participated in Pain Management in the NICU,&#x201d; Journal of Japanese Society of Child Health Nursing 31 (2022): 70&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McNair, N. Chinian, V. Shah, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Metasynthesis of Factors That Influence Parents' Participation in Pain Management for Their Infants in the NICU,&#x201d; Journal of Obstetric, Gynecologic, and Neonatal Nursing 49, no. 3 (2020): 263&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Hassankhani, R. Negarandeh, M. Abbaszadeh, and M. Jabraeili, &#x201c;The Role of Mothers During Painful Procedures on Neonates: A Focused Ethnography,&#x201d; Journal of Neonatal Nursing 26, no. 6 (2020): 340&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>