<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41720874</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Agentic AI-driven autonomous decision support system for smart agriculture.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9972</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39472-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Crop productivity is heavily impacted by inefficient fertilizer usage, improper fertilizer handling, and inappropriately chosen crops. To address these issues, this research work proposes an AI-powered Smart Agriculture Prediction System utilizing intelligent agents for carrying out soil classification, estimating soil parameters, crop suggestion, and fertilizer suggestion. The soil classifier module is trained with 1,563 images of black soils, red soils, clay soils, and alluvial soils using MobileNet-V2, ResNet, and Custom CNN, with Custom CNN resulting in a higher accuracy of 92.88%, which performed better in classifying soils based on textures. A soil parameter estimation agent utilizes regression models for estimating pH and NPK content of soils using images. For crop suggestion, a crop dataset with 2,200 samples with parameters such as N, P, K, T, H, pH, and rainfall is used, in which Random Forest model performed better with an accuracy of 92.4% when compared with CNN and DNN models. For fertilizer suggestion, XGBoost performed better with an accuracy of 94.7% in estimating fertilizers such as Urea, DAP, NPK, Potash, and Compost. Real-time climatic parameters are obtained using API in order to make dynamic updates for climatic parameters. Real-time weather data obtained through APIs enables dynamic updates of climatic parameters, while Explainable AI techniques such as SHAP and LIME enhance model transparency and user trust. Additionally, the system incorporates an interactive agent-based framework that processes user inputs, including location, soil images, and nutrient levels, to generate adaptive outputs such as weather alerts, yield potential, and personalized recommendations. The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed system effectively integrates deep learning, ensemble learning, and explainability to deliver a scalable, efficient, and sustainable decision-support solution for precision agriculture, promoting optimized resource utilization and environmental stewardship.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swati</LastName><ForeName>N L Padma</ForeName><Initials>NLP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai Campus, Tamil Nadu, 600127, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>S Vanshita</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai Campus, Tamil Nadu, 600127, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duddela</LastName><ForeName>Navya Sri</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai Campus, Tamil Nadu, 600127, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parvathy</LastName><ForeName>L Rama</ForeName><Initials>LR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai Campus, Tamil Nadu, 600127, India. ramaparvathy.l@vit.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Crop prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data-driven agriculture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fertilizer recommendation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable farming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yield optimization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41720874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13022185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39472-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39472-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tripathi, P., Kumar, N., Rai, M., Shukla, P. K. &amp; Verma, K. N. Applications of Machine Learning in Agriculture, in <i>Smart Village Infrastructure and Sustainable Rural Communities</i>, IGI Global, pp. 99&#x2013;118. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpenpuun, T. D. et al. Review of Temperature Management Strategies and Techniques in the Greenhouse Microenvironment, <i>Adeleke Univ J Eng Technol.</i> 6, 2, 126&#x2013;147, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allouhi, A. et al. Machine learning algorithms to assess the thermal behavior of a Moroccan agriculture greenhouse. <i>Clean. Eng. Technol.</i><b>5</b>, 100346 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clet.2021.100346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayatvarkeshi, M. et al. Modeling soil temperature using air temperature features in diverse Climatic conditions with complementary machine learning models. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>185</b>, 106158 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2021.106158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guill&#xe9;n-Navarro, M. A., Mart&#xed;nez-Espa&#xf1;a, R., Llanes, A., Bueno-Crespo, A. &amp; Cecilia, J. M. A deep learning model to predict lower temperatures in agriculture. <i>J. Ambient Intell. Smart Environ.</i><b>12</b> (1), 21&#x2013;34 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/AIS-200546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mampitiya, L., Pahalawattaarachchi, P. &amp; Abeynayake, S. AI-Based temperature prediction model for soil in agriculture. <i>Sustainability</i><b>16</b> (1), 263 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani, S., Sinha, N. &amp; Prakash, P. A crop recommendation system using optimization algorithms. <i>Ecol. Inf.</i><b>75</b>, 101383 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monjezi, H., Khalilnejad, R. &amp; Yousefi, A. Hybrid intelligent modeling for indoor greenhouse air temperature prediction. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>258</b>, 111876 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Kumar, R. &amp; Yadav, N. Smart farming using Cloud, Satellite, and AI. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>213</b>, 108123 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan, R. J., Rayanoothala, P. S. &amp; Sree, R. P. Next-gen agriculture: integrating AI and XAI for precision crop yield predictions. <i>Front. Plant. Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 1451607 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2024.1451607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11751057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39845494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey, B., Ferdous, J. &amp; Ahmed, R. Machine learning based recommendation of agricultural and horticultural crop farming in India under the regime of NPK, soil pH and three Climatic variables. <i>Heliyon</i>, <b>10</b>, 3, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38322954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, G. V. et al. Precision farming practices with data-driven analysis and machine learning-based crop and fertiliser recommendation system, E3S Web of Conf., 507, 01078, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202450701078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. Y. Artificial intelligence (AI) in agriculture. <i>IT Prof.</i><b>22</b> (3), 14&#x2013;15 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MITP.2020.2986121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suganthi, S. U., Prinslin, L., Selvi, R. &amp; Prabha, R. Generative AI in agri: sustainability in smart precision farming yield prediction mapping system based on GIS using deep learning and GPS. <i>Procedia Comput. Sci.</i><b>252</b>, 365&#x2013;380 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2024.12.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sai, S., Roy, M., Kumari, V. A., Ghosh, R. &amp; Mehta, K. J. Unleashing the power of generative AI in agriculture 4.0 for smart and sustainable farming. <i>Cogn. Comput.</i><b>17</b> (1), 63&#x2013;78 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12559-025-10420-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crop, E. M. L. A. Sustainable food development based on ensemble machine learning assisted crop and fertilizer recommendation system, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandom, S. S., Abe, G. T. &amp; Gambo, I. P. Application of random forest and hierarchical clustering models for crop and fertilizer recommendation to farmers. <i>Nigerian J. Technol.</i><b>44</b> (1), 114&#x2013;122 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/njt.v44i1.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musanase, C., Vodacek, A., Hanyurwimfura, D., Uwitonze, A. &amp; Kabandana, I. Data-driven analysis and machine learning-based crop and fertilizer recommendation system for revolutionizing farming practices. <i>Agriculture</i><b>13</b> (11), 2141 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture13112141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka, T. S., Heuvelink, G. B., Mieno, T. &amp; Bullock, D. S. Can machine learning models provide accurate fertilizer recommendations? <i>Precis Agric.</i><b>25</b> (4), 1839&#x2013;1856 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11119-024-10136-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhilesh, S., Abburi, B. T., Somya, P., Krishna, R. M. S. &amp; Srihari, T. Fertilizer Recommendation for Agriculture using Machine Learning, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A. A., Faheem, M., Bashir, R. N., Wechtaisong, C. &amp; Abbas, M. Z. Internet of things (IoT) assisted context aware fertilizer recommendation. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 129505&#x2013;129519 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3228160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndjuluwa, L. N. P., Adebisi, J. A. &amp; Dayoub, M. Internet of things for crop farming: A review of technologies and applications. <i>Commodities</i><b>2</b> (4), 367&#x2013;381. 10.3390/commodities2040021 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/commodities2040021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar, D., Rais Allauddin Mulla, D. S. H., Shikalgar, S., Jethva, H. B. &amp; Patel, G. A. A novel hybrid AI federated ML/DL models for classification of soil components. <i>Int. J. Recent. Innov. Trends Comput. Commun.</i><b>10</b>, 190&#x2013;199 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17762/ijritcc.v10i1s.5823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godara, S. &amp; Toshniwal, D. Deep Learning-based query-count forecasting using farmers&#x2019; helpline data. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>196</b>, 106875 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2022.106875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folorunso, O. et al. GeaGrow: A mobile tool for soil nutrient prediction and fertilizer optimization using artificial neural networks. <i>Front. Sustainable Food Syst.</i><b>9</b>, 1533423 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2025.1533423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallavi, V. N., Chaitanya, J., Rani, B. S. &amp; Rohan, R. A machine learning-based fertilizer recommendation system for sustainable crop yield, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchbhai, K. G., Lanjewar, M. G. &amp; Naik, A. V. Modified MobileNet with leaky ReLU and LSTM with balancing technique to classify the soil types. <i>Earth Sci. Inf.</i><b>18</b>, 77. 10.1007/s12145-024-01521- (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-024-01521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanjewar, M. G. &amp; Gurav, O. L. Convolutional neural networks based classifications of soil images. <i>Multimed Tools Appl.</i><b>81</b>, 10313&#x2013;10336. 10.1007/s11042-022-12200-y (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-022-12200-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla, A., Chouhan, S. S., Patel, R. K. &amp; Singh, U. P. (2025) AgriCloud: Cloud-Based Framework for Scalable Crop. Monitoring and Intelligent Decision Support. In. Chouhan, S.S., Patel, R.K., Singh, U.P., Jain, S. (eds) AgriTech Revolution Springer, Singapore 10.1007/978-981-95-1268-3_6</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>