<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41361474</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-5908</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Implementation science : IS</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Implement Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Project MIMIC (Maximizing Implementation of Motivational Incentives in Clinics): results of a 28-site cluster-randomized type 3 hybrid trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13012-025-01473-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Contingency management (CM), a behavioral treatment that incentivizes patients for attaining treatment goals, is a highly effective adjunct to medication for opioid use disorder. However, CM is rarely offered in opioid treatment programs in the United States. In a prior pilot trial, the implementation strategy (didactic workshop&#x2009;+&#x2009;feedback&#x2009;+&#x2009;consultation) delivered by the Addiction Technology Transfer Centers (ATTC strategy) promoted CM adoption more effectively than didactic training, but the speed and duration of implementation were sub-optimal. This 28-site type 3 hybrid trial tested the comparative effectiveness of the ATTC strategy versus an Enhanced-ATTC (E-ATTC) strategy that contained two theory-driven techniques targeting implementation climate to improve acceleration and sustainment, respectively: a provider-focused incentivization strategy and a team-focused facilitation strategy. We hypothesized that the E-ATTC strategy would be associated with superior implementation and patient outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-eight opioid treatment programs, 186 providers, and 592 patients were cluster-randomized to receive either the ATTC or E-ATTC strategy. Providers logged their CM sessions in an online CM Tracker and submitted audio-recorded CM sessions, and patients completed surveys about their opioid use at three timepoints. Intention-to-treat analyses examined impacts of the two multi-level strategies on implementation outcomes (CM Exposure, CM Competence, CM Sustainment) and patient outcomes (Opioid Abstinence, Opioid Related Problems).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pattern of results was identical across unadjusted, propensity score-adjusted, and covariate-adjusted general linear mixed models, though significance varied slightly. Relative to providers receiving the ATTC strategy, those receiving the E-ATTC strategy had significantly higher odds of CM Exposure (covariate adjusted OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.21, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and of attaining the Excellent CM Competence benchmark (propensity-adjusted OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.07, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Patients at the E-ATTC sites had significantly greater likelihood of Opioid Abstinence over time (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.04, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). There were no significant conditional differences in CM Sustainment, though data were measured at the program-level, which limited power to detect differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The theory-driven E-ATTC strategy, which targeted implementation climate via facilitation and incentivization, had superior implementation and patient outcomes relative to the ATTC strategy. Results of this study can help inform ongoing CM implementation efforts across the United States.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study was registered in Clinicaltrials.gov (NCT03931174) on April 23, 2019.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Sara J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1827-4662</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Dissemination and Implementation Science, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, 633 N St Clair Street, Chicago, IL, 60611, USA. Sara.Becker@Northwestern.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janssen</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Alcohol and Addiction Studies, Brown University School of Public Health, 121 South Main Street, Providence, RI, 02903, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Alcohol and Addiction Studies, Brown University School of Public Health, 121 South Main Street, Providence, RI, 02903, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartzler</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of Washington, 1107 NE 45Th Street, Suite 120, Seattle, WA, 98105-4631, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rash</LastName><ForeName>Carla J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, UConn Health, 263 Farmington Ave, Farmington, CT, 06030, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DiClemente-Bosco</LastName><ForeName>Kira</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Dissemination and Implementation Science, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, 633 N St Clair Street, Chicago, IL, 60611, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garner</LastName><ForeName>Bryan R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, The Ohio State University, 395 W 12Th Ave 3Rd Floor, Columbus, OH, 43210, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03931174</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P50 DA054072</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DA046941</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01DA046941</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Implement Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101258411</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-5908</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Opioid-Related Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077626" MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation Science</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Behavior Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Addiction technology transfer center</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cluster-randomized</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contingency management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Opioid use disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Substance use treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 3</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was provided by Brown University&#x2019;s Institutional Review Board (Protocol 1811002260). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors have no competing interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41361474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-025-01473-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13012-025-01473-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rawson RA, Erath TG, Chalk M, Clark HW, McDaid C, Wattenberg SA, et al. Contingency management for stimulant use disorder: progress, challenges, and recommendations. J Ambul Care Manage. 2023;46(2):152&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36745163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, DiClemente-Bosco K, Rash CJ, Garner BR. Effective, but underused: lessons learned implementing contingency management in real-world practice settings in the United States. Prev Med. 2023;176:107594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37385413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bol&#xed;var HA, Klemperer EM, Coleman SRM, DeSarno M, Skelly JM, Higgins ST. Contingency management for patients receiving medication for opioid use disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiat. 2021;78(10):1092&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducharme LJ, Knudsen HK, Abraham AJ, Roman PM. Counselor attitudes toward the use of motivational incentives in addiction treatment. Am J Addict. 2010;19(6):496&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2959187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20958844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbeck DM, Hser YI, Teruya C. Empirically supported substance abuse treatment approaches: a survey of treatment providers&#x2019; perspectives and practices. Addict Behav. 2008;33(5):699&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2373985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18207334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGovern MP, Fox TS, Xie H, Drake RE. A survey of clinical practices and readiness to adopt evidence-based practices: dissemination research in an addiction treatment system. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2004;26(4):305&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15182895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park TW, Shuey B, Liebschutz J, Cantor J, Anderson TS. Treatment approaches for opioid use disorder offered in US substance use treatment facilities. JAMA. 2024;332(6):502&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11240225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38990551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rash CJ, Petry NM, Kirby KC, Martino S, Roll J, Stitzer ML. Identifying provider beliefs related to contingency management adoption using the contingency management beliefs questionnaire. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2012;121(3):205&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21925807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rash CJ, Alessi SM, Zajac K. Examining implementation of contingency management in real-world settings. Psychol Addict Behav. 2020;34(1):89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6980876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFulio A. Dissemination of contingency management for the treatment of opioid use disorder. Perspect Behav Sci. 2023;46(1):35&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37006603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowie ME, Hodgins DC. Contingency management in Canadian addiction treatment: provider attitudes and use. J Stud Alcohol Drugs. 2023;84(1):89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36799678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oluwoye O, Weeks DL, McDonell MG. An unexplored equity factor during pre-implementation of contingency management: differential beliefs and attitudes by providers' ethnicity. Res Sq. 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby KC, Benishek LA, Dugosh KL, Kerwin ME. Substance abuse treatment providers&#x2019; beliefs and objections regarding contingency management: implications for dissemination. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2006;85(1):19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aletraris L, Shelton JS, Roman PM. Counselor attitudes toward contingency management for substance use sisorder: effectiveness, acceptability, and endorsement of incentives for treatment attendance and abstinence. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2015;57:41&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4561006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26001821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, Kelly LM, Kang AW, Escobar KI, Squires DD. Factors associated with contingency management adoption among opioid treatment providers receiving a comprehensive implementation strategy. Subst Abus. 2019;40(1):56&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6163086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29595403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams NJ. Multilevel mechanisms of implementation strategies in mental health: integrating theory, research, and practice. Adm Policy Ment Health. 2016;43(5):783&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4834058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hueske A-K, Guenther E. Multilevel barrier and driver analysis to improve sustainability implementation strategies: towards sustainable operations in institutions of higher education. J Clean Prod. 2021;291:125899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCance-Katz EF. The substance abuse and mental health services administration (SAMHSA): new directions. Psychiatr Serv. 2018;69(10):1046&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30099944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squires DD, Gumbley SJ, Storti SA. Training substance abuse treatment organizations to adopt evidence-based practices: the addiction technology transfer center of New England science to service laboratory. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2008;34(3):293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17600652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller WR, Yahne CE, Moyers TB, Martinez J, Pirritano M. A randomized trial of methods to help clinicians learn motivational interviewing. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2004;72(6):1050&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15612851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sholomskas DE, Syracuse-Siewert G, Rounsaville BJ, Ball SA, Nuro KF, Carroll KM. We don&#x2019;t train in vain: a dissemination trial of three strategies of training clinicians in cognitive-behavioral therapy. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2005;73(1):106&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2367057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15709837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, Squires DD, Strong DR, Barnett NP, Monti PM, Petry NM. Training opioid addiction treatment providers to adopt contingency management: a prospective pilot trial of a comprehensive implementation science approach. Subst Abus. 2016;37(1):134&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26682582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helseth SA, Janssen T, Scott K, Squires DD, Becker SJ. Training community-based treatment providers to implement contingency management for opioid addiction: time to and frequency of adoption. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2018;95:26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6209121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30352667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein KJ, Conn AB, Sorra JS. Implementing computerized technology: an organizational analysis. J Appl Psychol. 2001;86(5):811&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11596799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein KJ, Sorra JS. The challenge of innovation implementation. Acad Manage Rev. 1996;21(4):1055&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner BR, Godley SH, Dennis ML, Hunter BD, Bair CM, Godley MD. Using pay for performance to improve treatment implementation for adolescent substance use disorders: results from a cluster randomized trial. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2012;166(10):938&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6746231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22893231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner BR, Lwin AK, Strickler GK, Hunter BD, Shepard DS. Pay-for-performance as a cost-effective implementation strategy: results from a cluster randomized trial. Implement Sci. 2018;13(1):92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6033288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29973280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner BR, Gotham HJ, Chaple M, Martino S, Ford Ii JH, Roosa MR, et al. The implementation and sustainment facilitation strategy improved implementation effectiveness and intervention effectiveness: results from a cluster-randomized, type 2 hybrid trial. Implement Res Pract. 2020;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinde JM, Garner BR, Watson CJ, Ramanan R, Ball EL, Tueller SJ. The implementation &amp; sustainment facilitation (ISF) strategy: cost and cost-effectiveness results from a 39-site cluster randomized trial integrating substance use services in community-based HIV service organizations. Implement Res Pract. 2022;3:26334895221089264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9924275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37091108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran GM, Bauer M, Mittman B, Pyne JM, Stetler C. Effectiveness-implementation hybrid designs: combining elements of clinical effectiveness and implementation research to enhance public health impact. Med Care. 2012;50(3):217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3731143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, Murphy CM, Hartzler B, Rash CJ, Janssen T, Roosa M, et al. Project MIMIC (maximizing implementation of motivational incentives in clinics): a cluster-randomized type 3 hybrid effectiveness-implementation trial. Addict Sci Clin Pract. 2021;16(1):61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout RL, Wirtz PW, Carbonari JP, Del Boca FK. Ensuring balanced distribution of prognostic factors in treatment outcome research. J Stud Alcohol. 1994;12(Suppl):70&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7723001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Tedford J, Austin M, Nich C, Carroll KM, Rounsaville BJ. Prize reinforcement contingency management for treating cocaine users: how low can we go, and with whom? Addiction. 2004;99(3):349&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3709247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prendergast M, Podus D, Finney J, Greenwell L, Roll J. Contingency management for treatment of substance use disorders: a meta-analysis. Addiction. 2006;101(11):1546&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Peirce JM, Stitzer ML, Blaine J, Roll JM, Cohen A, et al. Effect of prize-based incentives on outcomes in stimulant abusers in outpatient psychosocial treatment programs: a national drug abuse treatment clinical trials network study. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005;62(10):1148&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16203960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott K, Jarman S, Moul S, Murphy CM, Yap K, Garner BR, et al. Implementation support for contingency management: preferences of opioid treatment program leaders and staff. Implement Sci Commun. 2021;2(1):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8088083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33931126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, Scott K, Murphy CM, Pielech M, Moul SA, Yap KR, et al. User-centered design of contingency management for implementation in opioid treatment programs: a qualitative study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019;19(1):466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6617614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartzler B, Hinde J, Lang S, Correia N, Yermash J, Yap K, et al. Virtual training is more cost-effective than in-person training for preparing staff to implement contingency management. J Technol Behav Sci. 2022. 10.1007/s41347-022-00283-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41347-022-00283-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36246531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Alessi SM, Ledgerwood DM, Sierra S. Psychometric properties of the contingency management competence scale. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2010;109(1&#x2013;3):167&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20149950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledgerwood DM, Petry NM. Rating contingency management sessions that reinforce abstinence using the contingency management competence scale: University of Connecticut Health Center; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Alessi SM, Ledgerwood DM. A randomized trial of contingency management delivered by community therapists. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2012;80(2):286&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22250852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Weinstock J, Alessi SM. A randomized trial of contingency management delivered in the context of group counseling. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2011;79(5):686&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3722591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21806297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB. Timeline follow-back: a technique for assessing self-reported alcohol consumption. Measuring alcohol consumption: Psychosocial and biochemical methods: Springer; 1992. p. 41&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis ML, Funk R, Godley SH, Godley MD, Waldron H. Cross-validation of the alcohol and cannabis use measures in the Global Appraisal of Individual Needs (GAIN) and Timeline Followback (TLFB; form 90) among adolescents in substance abuse treatment. Addiction. 2004;99(Suppl 2):120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis ML, Titus JC, White MK, Unsicker JI, Hodgkins D. Global appraisal of individual needs: administration guide for the GAIN and related measures. Bloomington, IL: Chestnut Health Systems; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea CM, Jacobs SR, Esserman DA, Bruce K, Weiner BJ. Organizational readiness for implementing change: a psychometric assessment of a new measure. Implement Sci. 2014;9:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24410955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muth&#xe9;n LK, Muth&#xe9;n BO. Mplus User&#x2019;s Guide. Los Angeles, CA: Muth&#xe9;n &amp; Muth&#xe9;n; 1998&#x2013;2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IBM Corp. IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 29.0.1.0. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ. Contingency management needs implementation science. Addiction. 2024;119(9):1522&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11498499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38881151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, Garner BR, Hartzler BJ. Is necessity also the mother of implementation? COVID-19 and the implementation of evidence-based treatments for opioid use disorders. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2021;122:108210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33509413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freese TE, Rutkowski BA, Peck JA, Padwa H, Thompson C, Datrice A, et al. California&#x2019;s recovery incentives program: implementation strategies. J Subst Use Addict Treat. 2024;167:209513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39243980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner BR, Hunter BD, Modisette KC, Ihnes PC, Godley SH. Treatment staff turnover in organizations implementing evidence-based practices: turnover rates and their association with client outcomes. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2012;42(2):134&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3268938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florence C, Luo F, Rice K. The economic burden of opioid use disorder and fatal opioid overdose in the United States, 2017. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2021;218:108350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8091480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rash CJ, Black SI, Parent SC, Erath TG, McDonell MG. Data-driven contingency management incentive magnitudes: a review. JAMA Psychiatr. 2025. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2025.1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2025.1341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40601332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker SJ, DiClemente-Bosco K, Scott K, Janssen T, Salino SM, Hasan FN, et al. Implementing contingency management for stimulant use in opioid treatment programs: protocol of a type III hybrid effectiveness-stepped-wedge trial. Implement Sci. 2023;18(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10498624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37705093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durlak JA, DuPre EP. Implementation matters: a review of research on the influence of implementation on program outcomes and the factors affecting implementation. Am J Community Psychol. 2008;41(3&#x2013;4):327&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontaine G, Vinette B, Weight C, Maheu-Cadotte MA, Lavall&#xe9;e A, Desch&#xea;nes MF, et al. Effects of implementation strategies on nursing practice and patient outcomes: a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis. Implement Sci. 2024;19(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11443951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39350295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasone JR, Kauffeldt KD, Chaudhary R, Brouwers MC. Effectiveness of guideline dissemination and implementation strategies on health care professionals&#x2019; behaviour and patient outcomes in the cancer care context: a systematic review. Implement Sci. 2020;15(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7268663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner BR, Tueller SJ, Bradshaw M, Speck KJ, Satre D, Rash C, et al. Testing the incremental effectiveness of pay-for-performance to improve implementation of a motivational interviewing brief intervention for substance use disorders in HIV settings: results of a parallel cluster-randomized type 3 hybrid trial. Res Sq. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12681604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41362630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Sun L, Yin X, Chen H, Yang L, Yang X. Burden of drug use disorders in the United States from 1990 to 2021 and its projection until 2035: results from the GBD study. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):1639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11188227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38898398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco A. &#x201c;More funerals than weddings:&#x201d; Opioids hit New England hard, devastating families, the economy2023 July 14, 2025. Available from: https://www.bostonfed.org/news-and-events/news/2023/10/more-funerals-than-weddings-opioids-hit-new-england-hard-devastating-families-the-economy.aspx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bebinger M. Instead of sodas, these vending machines offer needles and Narcan to fight overdoses. Shots Health News. 2024 July 14, 2025. Available from: https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2024/11/13/nx-s1-5189599/harm-reduction-opioid-overdoses-vending-machine-narcan-clean-needles-epidemic-fentanyl-xylazine.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodnough A. This addiction treatment works. Why is it so underused?2020. Available from: https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/27/health/meth-addiction-treatment.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein L. Federal government allows program to pay substance abusers for staying clean2022. Available from: https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2022/03/10/cash-payments-addiction/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facher L. Politics is holding back the best tool for treating meth addiction2024. Available from: https://www.statnews.com/2024/08/05/meth-addiction-contingency-management-incentives/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Candy, cash, gifts: how rewards help recovery from addiction2022. Available from: https://apnews.com/article/how-rewards-helps-recovery-from-addiction-6d11673c55fae3a413dcc5f57ca5e104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health Care Services. Recovery incentives program: California&#x2019;s contingency management benefit: DHCS; 2022 [Available from: https://www.dhcs.ca.gov/Pages/DMC-ODS-Contingency-Management.aspx.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37717741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. Using SAMHSA Funds to Implement Evidence-Based Contingency Management Services. Advisory. Publication No. PEP24-06-001. Rockville, MD: Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; 2025. https://library.samhsa.gov/sites/default/files/contingency-management-advisory-pep24-06-001.pdf.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>