<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41444812</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Numerical simulation and experimental research on the oil removal efficiency during the oily wastewater separation by hydrocyclone.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1850</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1850</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1850</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-31480-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Some oil and gas fields in China are located in the north, and in winter, oil fields face technical difficulties in separating oil and water from high viscosity condensate produced fluids. This article proposes a low-temperature oil-water separation scheme using a preheated hydrocyclone, with a focus on studying the separation effect of oil-water mixtures with different oil contents by varying the overflow diversion ratio and inlet flow rate of the hydrocyclone. The structure of the cyclone was optimized using response surface methodology (RSM) through three-dimensional modeling. The Euler multiphase flow model was used to study the distribution characteristics of the flow field and phase volume fraction of the oil-water two-phase medium inside the hydraulic cyclone under different injection parameters. The results show that when the oil content of the mixed liquid is 10% and the viscosity of the oil phase is 27-31mPa&#xb7;s, an increase in the overflow diversion ratio is beneficial for the rapid separation of low-density phase media. If the diversion ratio is too high, it will cause the liquid flowing out of the overflow port to form an oily mixture again. In our experiment, the optimal overflow diversion ratio is 0.2, and the effective oil removal efficiency can reach 92%. The influence of the oil content in the mixed liquid on the oil-water separation efficiency of the cyclone is achieved through the interaction of viscous drag and centrifugal force on the radial partial pressure and tangential flow velocity. As the oil content and viscosity of the mixed liquid increase, the radial flow resistance experienced by the cylindrical and conical sections of the cyclone will increase. The radial partial pressure, pressure gradient, and radial flow velocity of the aqueous medium will also decrease, and the separation efficiency will also decrease accordingly.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shuai</LastName><ForeName>Zhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Labor Vocational and Technical College, Jinan, 250300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weili</LastName><ForeName>Zhou</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Labor Vocational and Technical College, Jinan, 250300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laiyuan</LastName><ForeName>Ding</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Labor Vocational and Technical College, Jinan, 250300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dejun</LastName><ForeName>Kong</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Labor Vocational and Technical College, Jinan, 250300, China. kongdejun@sdlvtc.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wenwen</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Army Engineering University, Shijiazhuang Campus, Shijiazhuang, 050003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZR2024QE216</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Science Foundation of ShanDong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021M693421</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025HX17</GrantID><Agency>Shandong Huayu Pressure Vessel Co., Ltd. entrusts the development project of filter separator</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Euler multiphase flow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrocyclone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oil-water separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oily wastewater</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41444812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12804756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-31480-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-31480-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shiyi, Y. U. A. N. WANG Qiang. New progress and prospect of oilfields development technologies in China. <i>Pet. Explor. Dev.</i><b>45</b> (4), 657&#x2013;668 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiang, Y. A. N. G. et al. Application and research progress of coalescence separation in oily wastewater treatment. <i>Chin. J. Environ. Eng.</i><b>15</b> (3), 767&#x2013;781 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, D. et al. Qiu Xu,Zhang Yuning,. Life cycle analysis of coal based methanol-to-olefins processes in China. Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering, 109: 112&#x2013;118. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietro Rizzo, A. &amp; Bucci Pamela Monaco,et cl. Investigating the potential impact on shallow groundwater quality of oily wastewater injection in deep petroleum reservoirs: A multidisciplinary evaluation at the Val d&#x2019;agri oilfield (Southern Italy). Sustainability.2023,15:9161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Simulation of a large methanol-to-olefins fluidizedbed reactor with consideration of coke distribution. <i>Chem. Eng. Sci.</i><b>189</b>, 212&#x2013;220 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2018.05.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, X., Kuang, J. &amp; Mi, Y. Separation of oily wastewater using titanium modified multi-walled carbon nanotubes as demulsifier. <i>J. Dispersion Sci. Technol. 2021</i>, <b>42</b>(9): 1385&#x2013;1394 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. Evaluation of new hydrophobic association inorganic composite material as coagulant for oilfield wastewater treatment. <i>Sep. Purif. Technol. 2021</i>, <b>275</b>: 119126 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ya-qi, Z. H. O. U. &amp; Gang, W. A. N. G., ZHANG Hang, et al.Removal performance and mechanism of Dithiocarboxyl hydroxymethy&#x2014;poIyacrylamide for Cr(VI)in aqueous solution. China environmental science,2022,42(12): 5658&#x2013;5667 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocaman, E. &amp; Yildiz, M. Investigation of starch as flocculant for removing oil from oily wastewater. <i>J. Water Process. Eng. 2023</i>, <b>56</b>:104499 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting L&#xfc;, C. L. et al. Efficient treatment of emulsified oily wastewater by using amphipathic chitosan-based flocculant. <i>Reactive Funct. Polym.</i><b>139</b>, 133&#x2013;141 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reactfunctpolym.2019.03.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiwen Liu, Q., Guo, S. &amp; Ren Synthesis of starch-based flocculant by multi-component grafting copolymerization and its application in oily wastewater treatment. <i>J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2023</i>, <b>140</b>(4): 53356 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, A. L., Sumathi, S. &amp; Hameed, B. H. Coagulation of residue oil and suspended solid in palm oil mill effluent by chitosan, alum and PAC. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>118</b>, 99&#x2013;105 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2006.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. Guide to rational membrane selection for oily wastewater treatment by membrane distillation. <i>Desalin. 2023</i>, <b>549</b>:116323 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tausif Ahmad, C., Guria, A. &amp; Mandal Optimal synthesis of high fouling-resistant PVC-based ultrafiltration membranes with tunable surface pore size distribution and ultralow water contact angle for the treatment of oily wastewater. <i>Sep. Purif. Technol.</i><b>257</b>, 117829 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2020.117829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, Q. et al. Efficient Preparation of ultrathin ceramic wafer membranes for the high-effective treatment of the oilfield produced water. <i>Sep. Purif. Technol.</i><b>308</b>, 122720 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2022.122720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-badawy Tijjani, O. M. H. et al. Progress in treatment of oilfield produced water using membrane distillation and potentials for beneficial re-use. <i>Sep. Purif. Technol.</i><b>278</b>, 119494 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2021.119494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senlin Shao, D. et al. <i>Unraveling the Kinetics and Mechanism of Surfactant-Induced Wetting in Membrane Distillation: an in Situ Observation with Optical Coherence Tomography</i> Vol. 56, 556&#x2013;563 (Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 2022). 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34928146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Yigang, M. et al. Yaqi Study on the Oil-Water Separation Performance of the Droplet Size Reconstruction Hydrocyclone. CHINA PET&#xf32;OLEUM MACHINERY48(10):90&#x2013;96. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Peng &amp; ChenJiaqing <i>CaiXiaolei,et al.Study on Oil-Water Separation Characteristics of Hydrocyclone Based on CFD PBM Numerical Simulation</i> Vol. 34, 58&#x2013;65 (JOURNAL OF PETROCHEMICAL UNIVERSITIES, 2021). 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, J. et al. Min, Numerical simulation study of offshore heavy oil desanding by hydrocyclones, Separation and Purification Technology,2021,258,118051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judd, S. et al. The size and performance of offshore produced water oil &#x2010; removal technologies forreinjection. <i>Sep. Purif. Technol.</i><b>134</b> (1), 241&#x2013;246 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2014.07.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S. et al. Modeling and numerical simulation of the Inlet velocity on Oil&#x2013;Water Two-Phase vapor separation efficiency by the hydrocyclone. Energies,2022,<b>15</b>(13):4900 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Tao, L. et al. Effect of Temperature on Oil&#x2013;Water Separations Using Membranes in Horizontal Separators. Membranes,2022,12(2): 232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8879186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. <i>Experimental Study on Hydrocyclone Desanding of high-viscosity Oil</i> 341 (Fuel, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, K. W. H. L. et al. Experimental research on pressure fluctuation and vibration in a mixed flow pump. Journal of Mechanical Science &amp; Technology, 30(1):179&#x2013;184. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L. et al. Simulation study on viscosity impacting on the internal flow field and separation efficiency of liquid-liquid cyclone. <i>Fluid Mach.</i><b>38</b> (3), 28&#x2013;32 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, P. et al. Study on Oil-Water separation characteristics of hydrocyclone based on CFD-PBM numerical simulation.<b>34</b>(4):58&#x2013;65. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huixin, Y. et al. Numerical simulation of cyclone extraction element based on population balance model.Petrochemical Technology, 46 (12) : 1500-1506. (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuai Zhao, Z. &amp; Liu, Y. Numerical simulation and experimental study of Inlet velocity on oil water separation effect by a fixed hydrocyclone. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 18024 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02197-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12102358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40410327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>