<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41577809</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hybrid machine learning and Gaussian process for antenna parameter estimation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6076</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6076</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6076</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35564-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper presents a hybrid method of combining the Random Forest (RF) algorithm in machine learning (ML) and the Gaussian process (GP) to design microstrip patch antennas at any frequency from 0.6 to 6.5 GHz. Distinct from many published works, the proposed model is trained and tested with a high quality large dataset obtained from full-wave simulations in CST software, with experimental verification also performed. These factors are vital to assess the ML model's efficacy, but they haven't been thoroughly examined in other studies. In this paper, the GP is employed to seek the optimal hyper-parameters for the ML model using the RF algorithm, leading to superior predictive accuracy, as evaluated by the root mean square error (RMSE) of 0.0056. The advantage of this method is that antenna designers can directly use it to design antennas at any desired frequency within the 0.5-6 GHz range with high accuracy. The proposed method offers a transformative approach to antenna design by significantly reducing the optimization time by up to 99%, thereby improving the overall antenna design process.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thao</LastName><ForeName>Hoang Thi Phuong</ForeName><Initials>HTP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electronics and Telecommunications, Electric Power University, Hanoi, Vietnam. thaohp@epu.edu.vn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kien</LastName><ForeName>Tran Vu</ForeName><Initials>TV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electronics and Telecommunications, Electric Power University, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>102.04-2023.28</GrantID><Agency>Vietnam National Foundation for Science and Technology Development (NAFOSTED)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41577809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12901066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35564-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35564-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Misilmani, H. M.&#xa0;E. &amp; Naous, T. Machine learning in antenna design: An overview on machine learning concept and algorithms. In <i>2019 International Conference on High Performance Computing &amp; Simulation (HPCS)</i>, 600&#x2013;607 (2019). 10.1109/HPCS48598.2019.9188224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohri, M., Rostamizadeh, A. &amp; Talwalkar, A. <i>Foundations of Machine Learning</i> (MIT Press, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker, I.&#xa0;H. Machine learning: Algorithms, real-world applications and research directions. <i>SN Comput. Sci.</i><b>2</b> (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker, N., Podder, P., Mondal, M. R. H., Shafin, S. S. &amp; Kamruzzaman, J. Applications of machine learning and deep learning in antenna design, optimization, and selection: A review. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>11</b>, 103890&#x2013;103915 (2023) https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:262098883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3317371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J., Tian, Y. &amp; Chen, X. Antenna optimization based on co-training algorithm of gaussian process and support vector machine. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>8</b>, 211380&#x2013;211390 (2020) https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:227279818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3039269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, K. &amp; Pandey, G.&#xa0;P. Predicting resonant frequency of annular ring compact microstrip antenna using various machine learning techniques. In <i>2019 IEEE 16th India Council International Conference (INDICON)</i>, 1&#x2013;4 (2019). 10.1109/INDICON47234.2019.9030367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, D., Lian, C., Cui, K., Chen, Y. &amp; Liu, X. An intelligent antenna synthesis method based on machine learning. <i>IEEE Trans. Antennas Propag.</i><b>70</b>, 4965&#x2013;4976. 10.1109/TAP.2022.3182693 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAP.2022.3182693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indharapu, S.&#xa0;S., Caruso, A.&#xa0;N. &amp; Durbhakula, K.&#xa0;C. Supervised machine learning model for accurate output prediction of various antenna designs. In <i>2022 IEEE International Symposium on Antennas and Propagation and USNC-URSI Radio Science Meeting (AP-S/URSI)</i>, 495&#x2013;496 (2022). 10.1109/AP-S/USNC-URSI47032.2022.9886262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsharari, M., Armghan, A. &amp; Aliqab, K. Monopole antenna modeling and optimization for 5g communication system using machine learning. In <i>2023 International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing (IWCMC)</i>, 390&#x2013;393 (2023). 10.1109/IWCMC58020.2023.10183161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuppuswami, S., Mondal, S. &amp; Chahal, P. Design optimization of a 77 ghz antenna array using machine learning. In <i>2021 IEEE 71st Electronic Components and Technology Conference (ECTC)</i>, 1199&#x2013;1204 (2021). 10.1109/ECTC32696.2021.00196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallat, N.&#xa0;K., Jafarieh, A., Nouri, M. &amp; Behroozi, H. A machine learning based design of mmwave compact array antenna for 5g communications. In <i>2022 5th International Conference on Communications, Signal Processing, and their Applications (ICCSPA)</i>, 1&#x2013;4 (2022). 10.1109/ICCSPA55860.2022.10019147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Ka&#x2019;bi, A. Planar mimo antenna model for spectrum sensing applications. <i>Wirel. Pers. Commun.</i><b>135</b>, 919&#x2013;939. 10.1007/s11277-024-11091-6 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11277-024-11091-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gampala, G. &amp; Reddy, C.&#xa0;J. Fast and intelligent antenna design optimization using machine learning. In <i>2020 International Applied Computational Electromagnetics Society Symposium (ACES)</i>, 1&#x2013;2 (2020). 10.23919/ACES49320.2020.9196193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, J. V. &amp; Shaby, S. M. Optimizing inset-fed rectangular micro strip patch antenna by improved particle swarm optimization and simulated annealing. <i>Netw. Comput. Neural Syst.</i><b>36</b>(3), 1282&#x2013;1312 (2024) https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:270067110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0954898X.2024.2358961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38804502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pragya, P. &amp; Sivia, J. S. Design of minkowski curve-based slotted microstrip patch antenna using artificial neural network. <i>J. Inst. Eng. (India) Ser. B</i><b>104</b>, 129&#x2013;139 (2022) https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:253333917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40031-022-00813-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Elsherbeni, A.&#xa0;Z. &amp; Demir, V. Machine learning design of printed patch antenna. In <i>2022 IEEE International Symposium on Antennas and Propagation and USNC-URSI Radio Science Meeting (AP-S/URSI)</i>, 201&#x2013;202 (2022). 10.1109/AP-S/USNC-URSI47032.2022.9887043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs, J. P. Efficient resonant frequency modeling for dual-band microstrip antennas by gaussian process regression. <i>IEEE Antennas Wirel. Propag. Lett.</i><b>14</b>, 337&#x2013;341. 10.1109/LAWP.2014.2362937 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LAWP.2014.2362937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, K. &amp; Pandey, G.&#xa0;P. Prediction of the resonant frequency of square patch microstrip antenna with dgs using machine learning. In <i>2019 IEEE Indian Conference on Antennas and Propogation (InCAP)</i>, 1&#x2013;4 (2019). 10.1109/InCAP47789.2019.9134523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, K. &amp; Pandey, G. P. Efficient modelling of compact microstrip antenna using machine learning. <i>AEU-Int. J. Electron. C.</i><b>135</b>, 153739 (2021) https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1434841121001369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Elsherbeni, A.&#xa0;Z. &amp; Demir, V. Machine learning for microstrip patch antenna design: Observations and recommendations. In <i>2022 United States National Committee of URSI National Radio Science Meeting (USNC-URSI NRSM)</i>, 256&#x2013;257 (2022). 10.23919/USNC-URSINRSM57467.2022.9881476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar, D., Karunakar, P., Rao, S. R. &amp; Srinivas, K. Prediction of microstrip antenna dimension using optimized auto-metric graph neural network. <i>Intell. Syst. Appl.</i><b>21</b>, 200326 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu, K. V. et al. Deep learning assisted fractal slotted substrate mimo antenna with characteristic mode analysis (cma) for sub-6 ghz n78 5 g nr applications: design, optimization and experimental validation. <i>Phys. Scr.</i><b>98</b>, 115526. 10.1088/1402-4896/ad00e6 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu, K. V. &amp; Sree, G. N. J. Design and analysis of four-port mimo system optimization methodology with machine learning approaches of validated antenna parameters. <i>Wirel. Pers. Commun.</i><b>136</b>, 213&#x2013;232. 10.1007/s11277-024-11254-5 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11277-024-11254-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. et al. Deep learning-based inverse design of multi-functional metasurface absorbers. <i>Opt. Lett.</i><b>49</b>, 2733&#x2013;2736 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38748148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ka, AL. &amp; Bi, A. Improvement of energy collection efficiency in mobile sensor networks. <i>Telecommun. Radio Eng.</i><b>82</b>, 43&#x2013;54 (2023). 10.1615/telecomradeng.2023041704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balanis, C.&#xa0;A. <i>Antenna Theory: Analysis and Design</i> (John Wiley &amp; Sons 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faustino, E. <i>et al.</i> Comparison of machine learning algorithms for application in antenna design. In <i>2021 SBMO/IEEE MTT-S International Microwave and Optoelectronics Conference (IMOC)</i>, 1&#x2013;3 (2021). 10.1109/IMOC53012.2021.9624823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Discriminative elastic-net regularized linear regression. <i>IEEE Trans. Image Process.</i><b>26</b>, 1466&#x2013;1481. 10.1109/TIP.2017.2651396 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2017.2651396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28092552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, L., Zhang, Y., Zhang, R. &amp; Liu, Q. H. A modified efficient KNN method for antenna optimization and design. <i>IEEE Trans. Antennas Propag.</i><b>68</b>, 6858&#x2013;6866. 10.1109/TAP.2020.3001743 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAP.2020.3001743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontoura, L. C. M. M., De Castro Lins, H. W., Bertuleza, A. S., D&#x2019;assun&#xe7;&#xe3;o, A. G. &amp; Neto, A. G. Synthesis of multiband frequency selective surfaces using machine learning with the decision tree algorithm. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 85785&#x2013;85794. 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3086777 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3086777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurniawati, N., Novita Nurmala Putri, D. &amp; Kurnia Ningsih, Y. Random forest regression for predicting metamaterial antenna parameters. In <i>2020 2nd International Conference on Industrial Electrical and Electronics (ICIEE)</i>, 174&#x2013;178 (2020). 10.1109/ICIEE49813.2020.9276899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binois, M. &amp; Wycoff, N. A survey on high-dimensional gaussian process modeling with application to bayesian optimization (2022). arXiv:2111.05040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Gehring, C., Kohli, P. &amp; Jegelka, S. Batched large-scale bayesian optimization in high-dimensional spaces (2018). arXiv:1706.01445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetko, I.&#xa0;V., van Deursen, R. &amp; Godin, G. Be aware of overfitting by hyperparameter optimization! (2024). arXiv:2407.20786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11629497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39654058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>