<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41663501</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accurate forecasting of photovoltaic optimal points and efficiency using advanced hybrid machine learning models.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8197</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39031-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate forecasting of photovoltaic performance is essential for improving solar energy management, optimizing operational schedules, and supporting investment decisions. This study proposes a structured data-driven forecasting framework that integrates standalone learners with a hybrid boosting&#x2013;aggregation strategy to predict two critical photovoltaic performance indicators: the optimal peak operating time (NOPT) and the power conversion efficiency (PCE). The methodology involves systematic data preprocessing, feature normalization, model training using both single and hybrid learners, and performance validation under identical experimental conditions. Multiple data-driven algorithms were examined using comprehensive statistical metrics, including R&#xb2;, RMSE, and U95. Among all models, the hybrid XGBA framework demonstrated superior predictive performance, achieving R<sup>2</sup> values of 0.9954 for NOPT and 0.9970 for PCE, and consistently low errors across all evaluation criteria. Model robustness and generalization were further assessed through uncertainty-based evaluation metrics. Sensitivity analyses highlight key influential parameters such as <i>Emin</i> <i>Emax</i>, and <i>Ap</i>, revealing their substantial contributions to model outputs. The proposed hybrid model provides a robust and highly accurate predictive tool that can reduce operational uncertainties, enhance energy yield, and support data-driven decision-making for photovoltaic plant operators and energy sector stakeholders.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Anjan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, GLA University, Mathura, 281406, India. Anjan.kumar@gla.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asif</LastName><ForeName>Md</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Vardhaman College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naji</LastName><ForeName>Malak</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, Applied Science University, Al Eker, Kingdom of Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spoorthi</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, School of Engineering and Technology, JAIN (Deemed to be University), Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahu</LastName><ForeName>Badri Narayan</ForeName><Initials>BN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics &amp; Communication Engineering, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, 751030, Odisha, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radhika</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Hedrewy</LastName><ForeName>Marwea</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Technical Engineering, the Islamic University, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Technical Engineering, the Islamic University of Al Diwaniyah, Al Diwaniyah, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khudaynazarov</LastName><ForeName>Egambergan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Science, Mamun University, Khiva, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nurmatovich</LastName><ForeName>Hayitov Abdulla</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Technology, Urgench State University, Urgench, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimal operating point</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photovoltaic systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power conversion efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy forecasting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solar energy modeling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41663501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12963415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39031-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39031-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. Main Contributions, Applications and Future Prospect of PV, In <i>MATEC Web of Conferences</i>, vol. 386, p. 3012. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellano, N. N., Salvador, R. M. G., Rodriguez, F. P., Fernandez-Ros, M. &amp; Parra, J. A. G. Renewable energy: the future of photovoltaic energy, In Living with Climate Change, Elsevier, 373&#x2013;396. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sheekh, M. M., El-Nagar, A. A., ElKelawy, M. &amp; Bastawissi, H. A. E. Bioethanol from wheat straw hydrolysate solubility and stability in waste cooking oil biodiesel/diesel and gasoline fuel at different blends ratio. <i>Biotechnol. Biofuels Bioprod.</i><b>16</b> (1), 15 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13068-023-02264-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9890877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36726174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Din, H. A., Elkelawy, M. &amp; Yu-Sheng, Z. HCCI engines combustion of CNG fuel with DME and H 2 additives. <i>SAE Tech. Paper</i>, (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Shenawy, E. A., Bastawissi, H. A. E. &amp; Shams, M. M. Enhancement of the performance and emission attributes for the diesel engine using diesel-waste cooking oil biodiesel and graphene oxide nanofluid blends through response surface methodology. <i>Mansoura Eng. J.</i><b>49</b> (5), 8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkelawy, M., El Shenawy, E. A., Bastawissi, H. A. E., Mousa, I. A. &amp; Ibrahim, M. M. A. R. Analyzing the influence of design and operating conditions on combustion and emissions in premixed turbulent flames: A comprehensive review. <i>J. Eng. Res.</i><b>8</b> (1), 34 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboubakr, M. H., Elkelawy, M., Bastawissi, H. A. E. &amp; El-Tohamy, A. R. A technical survey on using oxyhydrogen with biodiesel/diesel blend for homogeneous charge compression ignition engine. <i>J. Eng. Res</i>, <b>8</b>, 1, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbanna, A. M., Cheng, X., Yang, C., Elkelawy, M. &amp; Bastawissi, H. A. E. Investigative research of diesel/ethanol advanced combustion strategies: A comparison of premixed charge compression ignition (PCCI) and direct dual fuel stratification (DDFS). <i>Fuel</i><b>345</b>, 128143 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.128143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, Y. et al. Over 16% efficiency organic photovoltaic cells enabled by a chlorinated acceptor with increased open-circuit voltages. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>10</b> (1), 2515 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-10351-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6555805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, J. et al. Single-junction organic solar cell with over 15% efficiency using fused-ring acceptor with electron-deficient core. <i>Joule</i><b>3</b> (4), 1140&#x2013;1151 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2019.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q. et al. 18% efficiency organic solar cells. <i>Sci. Bull.</i><b>65</b> (4), 272&#x2013;275 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scib.2020.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36659090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuthedath, S. et al. Intrinsic efficiency limits in low-bandgap non-fullerene acceptor organic solar cells. <i>Nat. Mater.</i><b>20</b> (3), 378&#x2013;384 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-020-00835-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33106652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M. et al. Influences of non-fullerene acceptor fluorination on three-dimensional morphology and photovoltaic properties of organic solar cells. <i>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</i>. <b>11</b> (29), 26194&#x2013;26203 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b07317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31283167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Tuning the intermolecular interaction of A2-A1-D-A1-A2 type non-fullerene acceptors by substituent engineering for organic solar cells with ultrahigh V Oc of ~&#x2009;1.2 V. <i>Sci. China Chem.</i><b>63</b> (11), 1666&#x2013;1674 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11426-020-9840-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, X. et al. Efficient polymer solar cells based on non-fullerene acceptors with potential device lifetime approaching 10 years. <i>Joule</i><b>3</b> (1), 215&#x2013;226 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2018.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin, F., I&#x15f;ik, G., &#x15e;ahin, G. &amp; Kara, M. K. Estimation of PM10 levels using feed forward neural networks in Igdir, Turkey. <i>Urban Clim.</i><b>34</b>, 100721 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2020.100721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin, G., Isik, G. &amp; van Sark, W. G. Predictive modeling of PV solar power plant efficiency considering weather conditions: A comparative analysis of artificial neural networks and multiple linear regression. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>10</b>, 2837&#x2013;2849 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2023.09.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamad, S. A., Ghalib, M. A., Munshi, A., Alotaibi, M. &amp; Ebied, M. A. Evaluating machine learning models comprehensively for predicting maximum power from photovoltaic systems. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 10750 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-91044-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11953328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40155411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renold, A. P., Sinha, N. &amp; Gao, X. Z. Hybrid machine learning approach for improved short-term PV power forecasting accuracy. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>28</b>, 107374. 10.1016/j.rineng.2025.107374 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2025.107374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keddouda, A. et al. Solar photovoltaic power prediction using artificial neural network and multiple regression considering ambient and operating conditions. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i>. <b>288</b>, 117186 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2023.117186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari, P. &amp; Toshniwal, D. Extreme gradient boosting and deep neural network based ensemble learning approach to forecast hourly solar irradiance. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>279</b>, 123285 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.123285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg, S. M. &amp; Lee, S. I. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. <i>Adv Neural Inf. Process. Syst.</i>, <b>30</b>, (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro, M. T., Singh, S. &amp; Guestrin, C. &#x2018; Why should i trust you?&#x2019; Explaining the predictions of any classifier, In <i>Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</i>, pp. 1135&#x2013;1144. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z., Xiao, F., Guo, F. &amp; Yan, J. Interpretable machine learning for Building energy management: a state-of-the-art review. <i>Adv. Appl. Energy</i>. <b>9</b>, 100123 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.adapen.2023.100123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, C., Ahsan, M. &amp; Albarbar, A. Machine learning for forecasting a photovoltaic (PV) generation system. <i>Energy</i><b>278</b>, 127807 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutta, M. S. et al. Optimizing solar power efficiency in smart grids using hybrid machine learning models for accurate energy generation prediction. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b> (1), 17101 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-68030-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11269685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39048605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridha, H. M. et al. A novel hybrid photovoltaic current prediction model utilizing singular spectrum analysis, adaptive Beluga Whale optimization, and improved extreme learning machine. <i>Renew. Energy</i>. <b>256</b>, 123878 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2025.123878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. H., Alavi, A. H., Gandomi, M., Gandomi &amp; Sadat Hosseini, S. S. Prediction of maximum dry density and optimum moisture content of stabilised soil using RBF neural networks. <i>IES J. Part. Civ. Struct. Eng.</i><b>2</b> (2), 98&#x2013;106. 10.1080/19373260802659226 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19373260802659226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heshmati, R. A. A., Alavi, A. H., Keramati, M. &amp; Gandomi, A. H. A radial basis function neural network approach for compressive strength prediction of stabilized soil, In <i>Road Pavement Material Characterization and Rehabilitation: Selected Papers from the 2009 GeoHunan International Conference</i>, pp. 147&#x2013;153.10.1061/41043(350)20 (2009). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, G. et al. Lightgbm: A highly efficient gradient boosting decision tree. <i>Adv Neural Inf. Process. Syst</i>, <b>30</b>, (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman, L., Friedman, J., Olshen, R. &amp; Stone, C. Classification and regression trees&#x2013;crc press. <i>Boca Raton Florida</i>, (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman, L. Random forests. <i>Mach. Learn.</i><b>45</b>, 5&#x2013;32 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1010933404324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Galiano, V., Sanchez-Castillo, M., Chica-Olmo, M. &amp; Chica-Rivas, M. Machine learning predictive models for mineral prospectivity: an evaluation of neural networks, random forest, regression trees and support vector machines. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>71</b>, 804&#x2013;818 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2015.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw, A. &amp; Wiener, M. Classification and regression by randomforest. <i>R News</i>. <b>2</b> (3), 18&#x2013;22 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, J. et al. Random forests as a tool for ecohydrological distribution modelling. <i>Ecol. Modell</i>. <b>207</b>, 304&#x2013;318. 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2007.05.011 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. S. A new metaheuristic bat-inspired algorithm, in Nature Inspired Cooperative Strategies for Optimization (NICSO 2010), Springer, 65&#x2013;74. (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. S. Bat algorithm for multi-objective optimisation. <i>Int. J. Bio-Inspired Comput.</i><b>3</b> (5), 267&#x2013;274 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJBIC.2011.042259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bora, T. C., Coelho, L. &amp; Lebensztajn, L. Bat-inspired optimization approach for the brushless DC wheel motor problem, <i>IEEE Trans. Magn.</i>, vol. 48, no. 2, pp. 947&#x2013;950, (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. &amp; Hossein Gandomi, A. Bat algorithm: a novel approach for global engineering optimization. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>29</b> (5), 464&#x2013;483 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/02644401211235834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha, A. M. &amp; Tang, A. Y. C. Bat algorithm for rough set attribute reduction. <i>J. Theor. Appl. Inf. Technol.</i><b>51</b> (1), 1&#x2013;8 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakesh, V., Aruna, S. B. &amp; Raju, T. D. Combined economic load and emission dispatch evaluation using BAT algorithm. <i>Int. J. Eng. Res. Appl.</i><b>3</b> (3), 1224&#x2013;1229 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh, B., Mohan, V. C. J. &amp; Reddy, V. C. V. Application of Bat algorithm for combined economic load and emission dispatch. <i>Int. J. Electr. Eng. Telecommun.</i>. <b>2</b> (1), 1&#x2013;9 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. S. &amp; He, X. Bat algorithm: literature review and applications. <i>Int. J. Bio-inspired Comput.</i><b>5</b> (3), 141&#x2013;149 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJBIC.2013.055093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal, S., Barisal, A. K., Behera, A. &amp; Prakash, T. Optimal power dispatch using BAT algorithm, In <i>2013 International conference on energy efficient technologies for sustainability</i>, pp. 1018&#x2013;1023. (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheirollahi, R. &amp; Namdari, F. Optimal coordination of overcurrent relays based on modified BAT optimization algorithm. <i>Int. Electr. Eng. J.</i><b>5</b> (2), 1273&#x2013;1279 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, R. A. S. et al. Predicting the efficiency of luminescent solar concentrators for solar energy harvesting using machine learning. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b> (1), 4160 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54657-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10879533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38378849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Ji, X. &amp; Zhu, Z. A photovoltaic power forecasting method based on the LSTM-XGBoost-EEDA-SO model. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 30177 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-16368-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12361526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40826278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Zhang, Z., Xu, W., Li, Y. &amp; Niu, G. Short-Term photovoltaic power forecasting using a Bi-LSTM neural network optimized by hybrid algorithms. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b> (12), 5277 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17125277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J., Cao, Q., Chen, Y. &amp; Zhang, D. Cross-variable Linear Integrated ENhanced Transformer for Photovoltaic power forecasting, <i>arXiv Prepr. arXiv2406.03808</i>, (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>