<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600239</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Hybrid Federated Learning Framework for Enhancing Privacy and Robustness in Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">443</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020443</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Non-intrusive load monitoring (NILM), as a key technology in smart-grid advanced metering infrastructure, aims to disaggregate mains power from smart meters into individual load-level power consumption. Traditional NILM methods require centralizing sensitive measurement data from users, which poses significant privacy risks. Federated learning (FL) enables collaborative training without centralized measurement data, effectively preserving privacy. However, FL-based NILM systems face serious threats from attacks such as model inversion and parameter poisoning, and rely heavily on the availability of a central server, whose failure may compromise measurement robustness. This paper proposes a hybrid FL framework that dynamically switches between centralized FL (CFL) and decentralized FL (DFL) modes, enhancing measurement privacy and system robustness simultaneously. In CFL mode, layer-sensitive pruning and robust parameter aggregation methods are developed to defend against model inversion and parameter poisoning attacks; even with 30% malicious clients, the proposed defense limits the increases in key error metrics to under 15.4%. In DFL mode, a graph attention network (GAT)-based dynamic topology adapts to mitigate topology poisoning attacks, achieving an approximately 17.2% reduction in MAE after an attack and rapidly restoring model performance. Extensive evaluations using public datasets demonstrate that the proposed framework significantly enhances the robustness of smart-grid measurements and effectively safeguards measurement privacy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rong</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Communication Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Qiuzhan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Communication Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Huinan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1688-5679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Communication Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">federated learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">model robustness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-intrusive load monitoring (NILM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">privacy preservation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smart-grid advanced metering infrastructure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Armel K.C., Gupta A., Shrimali G., Albert A. Is disaggregation the holy grail of energy efficiency? the case of electricity. Energy Policy. 2013;80:213&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1016/j.enpol.2012.08.062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enpol.2012.08.062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart G.W. Nonintrusive appliance load monitoring. Proc. IEEE. 1992;80:1870&#x2013;1891. doi: 10.1109/5.192069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/5.192069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar I., Khalid S.N., Mustafa M.W., Shareef H., Mustapha M. Application of load monitoring in appliances&#x2019; energy management&#x2014;A review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2017;67:235&#x2013;245. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2016.09.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2016.09.064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L., Kang J.S., Meng F., Yu M. Non-intrusive load identification based on retrainable siamese network. Sensors. 2024;24:2562. doi: 10.3390/s24082562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24082562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11054957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38676180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez &#xc1;., Nieto R., de Diego-Ot&#xf3;n L., P&#xe9;rez-Rubio M.C., Villadangos-Carrizo J.M., Pizarro D., Ure&#xf1;a J. Detection of anomalies in daily activities using data from smart meters. Sensors. 2024;24:515. doi: 10.3390/s24020515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24020515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38257607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Xiang Y., Xu H., Yi Z., Shi D., Wang Z. A novel transfer learning-based intelligent nonintrusive load-monitoring with limited measurements. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2021;70:2500508. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2020.3011335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2020.3011335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykiotis S., Kaselimi M., Doulamis A., Doulamis N. Electricity: An efficient transformer for non-intrusive load monitoring. Sensors. 2022;22:2926. doi: 10.3390/s22082926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22082926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35458907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong J., Wang C., Zhou Q., He Y., Wu H. Enhancing non-intrusive load monitoring through transfer learning with transformer models. Energy Build. 2025;330:115334. doi: 10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.115334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.115334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Lv L., Wang C., Wang H., Wan H., Yang L. Attention-Enhanced Actor&#x2013;Critic Learning for Household Nonintrusive Load Monitoring. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2024;20:14361&#x2013;14370. doi: 10.1109/TII.2024.3451504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2024.3451504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Lv L., Wang C., Li X., Wan H., Li Y., Chen Z. Closed-loop learning for accuracy improvement of nonintrusive load monitoring in smart homes. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2023;72:2524704. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2023.3306823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2023.3306823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athanasiadis C.L., Papadopoulos T.A., Kryonidis G.C., Doukas D.I. A holistic and personalized home energy management system with non-intrusive load monitoring. IEEE Trans. Consum. Electron. 2024;70:6725&#x2013;6737. doi: 10.1109/TCE.2024.3483938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCE.2024.3483938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athanasiadis C.L., Papadopoulos T.A., Kryonidis G.C., Doukas D.I. A review of distribution network applications based on smart meter data analytics. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2024;191:114151. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2023.114151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athanasiadis C.L., Papadopoulos T.A., Kryonidis G.C., Doukas D.I. Multi-objective data-driven framework to support network operation via residential flexibility. Sustain. Energy Grids Netw. 2025;44:102042. doi: 10.1016/j.segan.2025.102042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.segan.2025.102042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong N., Sun K., Wang S., Guitton F., Guo Y. Privacy preservation in federated learning: An insightful survey from the GDPR perspective. Comput. Secur. 2021;110:102402. doi: 10.1016/j.cose.2021.102402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cose.2021.102402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaselimi M., Protopapadakis E., Voulodimos A., Doulamis N., Doulamis A. Towards trustworthy energy disaggregation: A review of challenges, methods, and perspectives for non-intrusive load monitoring. Sensors. 2022;22:5872. doi: 10.3390/s22155872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22155872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9371074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35957428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavorn&#xed;k A., Podrou&#x17e;ek J., Ore&#x161;ko &#x160;., Slosiarov&#xe1; N., Grmanov&#xe1; G. Beyond privacy and security: Exploring ethical issues of smart metering and non-intrusive load monitoring. Telemat. Inform. 2024;90:102132. doi: 10.1016/j.tele.2024.102132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tele.2024.102132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahan B., Moore E., Ramage D., Hampson S., Arcas B.A.y. Communication-efficient learning of deep networks from decentralized data; Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics; Fort Lauderdale, FL, USA. 20&#x2013;22 April 2017; pp. 1273&#x2013;1282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Tang G., Huang Q., Wang Y., Wu K., Yu K., Shao X. Fednilm: Applying federated learning to nilm applications at the edge. IEEE Trans. Green Commun. Netw. 2023;7:857&#x2013;868. doi: 10.1109/TGCN.2022.3167392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGCN.2022.3167392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltr&#xe1;n E.T.M., P&#xe9;rez M.Q., S&#xe1;nchez P.M.S., Bernal S.L., Bovet G., P&#xe9;rez M.G., Celdr&#xe1;n A.H. Decentralized federated learning: Fundamentals, state of the art, frameworks, trends, and challenges. IEEE Commun. Surveys Tuts. 2023;25:2983&#x2013;3013. doi: 10.1109/COMST.2023.3315746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2023.3315746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Si C., Zhao J. A federated learning framework for non-intrusive load monitoring. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2104.01618.2104.01618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2104.01618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Zhang J., Liu L., Liu J. Auditing privacy defenses in federated learning via generative gradient leakage; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); New Orleans, LA, USA. 18&#x2013;24 June 2022; pp. 10132&#x2013;10142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L., Liu Z., Han S. Deep leakage from gradients; Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 8&#x2013;14 December 2019; Red Hook, NY, USA: Curran Associates, Inc.; 2019. pp. 14774&#x2013;14784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagdasaryan E., Veit A., Hua Y., Estrin D., Shmatikov V. How to backdoor federated learning; Proceedings of the Twenty Third International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics; Online. 26&#x2013;28 August 2020; pp. 2938&#x2013;2948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen D.C., Ding M., Pham Q.V., Pathirana P.N., Le L.B., Seneviratne A., Poor H.V. Federated learning meets blockchain in edge computing: Opportunities and challenges. IEEE Internet Things J. 2021;8:12806&#x2013;12825. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2021.3072611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2021.3072611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S., Meng F., Wang Q., Chen X. DP2-NILM: A distributed and privacy-preserving framework for non-intrusive load monitoring. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2024;191:114091. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2023.114091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho H., Mathur A., Kawsar F. Flame: Federated learning across multi-device environments; Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies; Atlanta, GA, USA; Cambridge, UK. 11&#x2013;15 September 2022; New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery; 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Xu J., Vijayakumar P., Sharma P.K., Ghosh U. Homomorphic encryption-based privacy-preserving federated learning in IoT-enabled healthcare system. IEEE Trans. Netw. Sci. Eng. 2022;10:2864&#x2013;2880. doi: 10.1109/TNSE.2022.3185327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2022.3185327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard P., El Mhamdi E.M., Guerraoui R., Stainer J. Machine learning with adversaries: Byzantine tolerant gradient descent; Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems; Long Beach, CA, USA. 4&#x2013;9 December 2017; pp. 118&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang H., Yu M., Wang H., Hua Y., Li J., Yuan X. Backdoor federated learning by poisoning backdoor-critical layers. arXiv. 20232308.04466</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giuseppi A., Manfredi S., Menegatti D., Pietrabissa A., Poli C. Decentralized federated learning for nonintrusive load monitoring in smart energy communities; Proceedings of the 2022 30th Mediterranean Conference on Control and Automation (MED); Vouliagmeni, Greece. 28 June&#x2013;1 July 2022; pp. 312&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Han S., Mao H., Wang Y., Dally W.J. Deep gradient compression: Reducing the communication bandwidth for distributed training. arXiv. 20171712.01887</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin D., Chen Y., Kannan R., Bartlett P. Byzantine-robust distributed learning: Towards optimal statistical rates; Proceedings of the 35th International Conference on Machine Learning; Stockholm, Sweden. 10&#x2013;15 July 2018; pp. 5650&#x2013;5659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Li Y., Wan H., Wang C. Enhancing Byzantine robustness of federated learning via tripartite adaptive authentication. J. Big Data. 2025;12:121. doi: 10.1186/s40537-025-01165-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-025-01165-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Li X., Wan H., Wang C. Byzantine-Robust Federated Learning for Unreliable Environments by Random-Matching Verification and Credibility Table; Proceedings of the International Conference on Security and Privacy in Communication Systems; Dubai, United Arab Emirates. 28&#x2013;30 October 2024; Cham, Switzerland: Springer Nature; 2024. pp. 3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galanis N. Defending against data poisoning attacks in federated learning via user elimination. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2404.12778.2404.12778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2404.12778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Li W., Chang X., Yang T., Sun Y., Zomaya A.Y. On enabling collaborative non-intrusive load monitoring for sustainable smart cities. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:6569. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-33131-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-33131-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10121597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37085586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamport L., Shostak R., Pease M. Concurrency: The Works of Leslie Lamport. 1st ed. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2019. The byzantine generals problem; pp. 203&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veli&#x10d;kovi&#x107; P., Cucurull G., Casanova A., Romero A., Lio P., Bengio Y. Graph attention networks. arXiv. 20171710.10903</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray D., Stankovic L., Stankovic V. An electrical load measurements dataset of united kingdom households from a two-year longitudinal study. Sci. Data. 2017;4:160122. doi: 10.1038/sdata.2016.122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sdata.2016.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5315495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28055033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly J., Knottenbelt W. The uk-dale dataset, domestic appliance-level electricity demand and whole-house demand from five uk homes. Sci. Data. 2015;2:150007. doi: 10.1038/sdata.2015.7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sdata.2015.7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4432654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25984347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Incecco M., Squartini S., Zhong M. Transfer learning for non-intrusive load monitoring. IEEE Trans. Smart Grid. 2020;11:1419&#x2013;1429. doi: 10.1109/TSG.2019.2938068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSG.2019.2938068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemenjak C., Faustine A., Makonin S., Elmenreich W. On metrics to assess the transferability of machine learning models in non-intrusive load monitoring. arXiv. 2019 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1912.06200.1912.06200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1912.06200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalmpantis C., Vrakas D. Machine learning approaches for non-intrusive load monitoring: From qualitative to quantitative comparation. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2019;52:217&#x2013;243. doi: 10.1007/s10462-018-9613-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-018-9613-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuzuku Y., Imachi H., Akiba T. Variance-based gradient compression for efficient distributed deep learning. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1802.06058.1802.06058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1802.06058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F.M.A., Abou-Zeid H., Hassan S.A. Enhancing the performance of model pruning in over-the-air federated learning with non-iid data; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Communications Workshops (ICC Workshops); Denver, CO, USA. 9&#x2013;13 June 2024; pp. 487&#x2013;492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowtham L., Annappa B., Sachin D.N. Fedprunet: Federated learning using pruning neural network; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE Region 10 Symposium (TENSYMP); Mumbai, India. 1&#x2013;3 July 2022; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Wan W., Lu J., Hu S., Shi J., Zhang L.Y., Zhou M., Zheng Y. Shielding federated learning: Mitigating byzantine attacks with less constraints; Proceedings of the 2022 18th International Conference on Mobility, Sensing and Networking (MSN); Guangzhou, China. 14&#x2013;16 December 2022; pp. 178&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J., Wan W., Hu S., Lu J., Zhang L.Y. Challenges and approaches for mitigating byzantine attacks in federated learning; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE International Conference on Trust, Security and Privacy in Computing and Communications (TrustCom); Wuhan, China. 9&#x2013;11 December 2022; pp. 139&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan Y., Qu Y., Ni W., Xiang Y., Gao L., Hossain E. Data and model poisoning backdoor attacks on wireless federated learning, and the defense mechanisms: A comprehensive survey. IEEE Commun. Surveys Tuts. 2024;26:1861&#x2013;1897. doi: 10.1109/COMST.2024.3361451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2024.3361451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y., Zhao Y., Yao K. Federated learning backdoor defense based on watermark integrity; Proceedings of the 2024 10th International Conference on Big Data and Information Analytics (BigDIA); Chiang Mai, Thailand. 25&#x2013;28 October 2024; pp. 288&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>