<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41572193</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2407</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The value of 3D contrast-enhanced CT radiomics in predicting response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy for adenocarcinoma of the esophagogastric junction: a two-center study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>259</StartPage><MedlinePgn>259</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">259</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12885-026-15609-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">To investigate the feasibility of 3D contrast-enhanced CT radiomics features to predict response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) for adenocarcinoma of the esophagogastric junction (AEG) and to develop and validate a nomogram to assist in clinical decision-making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The clinical, pathological, and CT data of 239 patients with locally advanced AEG who underwent NAC and radical resection were retrospectively collected between March 2016 and June 2023 from two independent Chinese medical centers. They were randomly assigned to a training cohort, an internal verification cohort, or an external verification cohort. Based on the CT radiomics features after dimension reduction, the radiomics model was constructed using linear discriminant analysis as the classifier to obtain the radiomics score. Clinical characteristics were screened, and multivariable logistic regression was applied to construct the clinical model. The combined model was generated by integrating clinical features and radiomics scores, upon which a nomogram was subsequently developed. Finally, receiver operating characteristic curves, calibration curves, and decision curves were plotted to evaluate the predictive performance, calibration performance, and clinical benefits of each model for the efficacy of NAC in AEG patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Overall, 86 of the 239 patients responded well to NAC. The nomogram was comprised of tumor thickness, lymph node short diameter, and the radiomics score. In the training cohort, the AUC values of the clinical model, the radiomics model, and the combined model for predicting NAC response were 0.771 (95% CI, 0.682&#x2013;0.860), 0.823 (95% CI, 0.742&#x2013;0.903), and 0.894 (95% CI, 0.834&#x2013;0.954), respectively, with the combined model displaying optimal discriminatory power. The combined model also demonstrated satisfactory predictive performance in the internal and external validation cohorts, with AUC values of 0.859 and 0.775, respectively. The calibration curves for the three cohorts showed good agreement between predictions and actual observations. Lastly, decision curve analysis highlighted the clinical applicability of the combined model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The nomogram integrating radiomics and clinical characteristics demonstrated good performance in predicting NAC response in AEG, suggesting its possible role as a decision-support tool for treatment individualization. These preliminary findings warrant confirmation in future studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12885-026-15609-y.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Chenglong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Affiliated Cancer Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu</LastName><ForeName>Wanling</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Mengchen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Pengchao</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yiyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Liming</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Changmao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xuejun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Affiliated Cancer Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450008, China. chenxuejun1967@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Jianbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China. Jianbogao0807@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Imaging Diagnosis and Treatment for Digestive System Tumor, Zhengzhou, Henan province, 450052, China. Jianbogao0807@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82202146</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81971615</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YXKC2021054</GrantID><Agency>Special Funding of Henan Health Science and Technology Innovation Talent Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>242102311173</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development Foundation of Henan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024ZZJCYJ007</GrantID><Agency>Basic Research and Applied Basic Research Project of Zhengzhou Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023HYTP039</GrantID><Agency>Henan Association for Science and Technology Youth Talent Support Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2407</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adenocarcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Computed tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Esophagogastric junction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neoadjuvant therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Response evaluation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol received approval from the institutional review board. Due to the retrospective nature of the study, the requirement for informed consent was waived. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41572193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12911287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-026-15609-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12885-026-15609-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, Laversanne M, Soerjomataram I, Jemal A, Bray F. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold M, Ferlay J, van Berge Henegouwen MI, Soerjomataram I. Global burden of oesophageal and gastric cancer by histology and subsite in 2018. Gut. 2020;69(9):1564&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2020-321600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32606208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Yang K, Zhang W, Chen X, Chen X, Zhang B, Chen Z, Chen J, Zhao Y, Zhou Z, et al. Changes of esophagogastric junctional adenocarcinoma and gastroesophageal reflux disease among surgical patients during 1988&#x2013;2012: A Single-institution, High-volume experience in China. Ann Surg. 2016;263(1):88&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000001148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4679348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25647058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun A, Arnold M, Ferlay J, Goodman KJ, Forman D, Soerjomataram I. Global patterns of cardia and non-cardia gastric cancer incidence in 2012. Gut. 2015;64(12):1881&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2014-308915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25748648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siewert JR, Feith M, Stein HJ. Biologic and clinical variations of adenocarcinoma at the esophago-gastric junction: relevance of a topographic-anatomic subclassification. J Surg Oncol. 2005;90(3):139&#x2013;46. discussion 146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jso.20218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15895452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faron M, Cheugoua-Zanetsie M, Tierney J, Thirion P, Nankivell M, Winter K, Yang H, Shapiro J, Vernerey D, Smithers BM, et al. Individual participant data network Meta-Analysis of neoadjuvant chemotherapy or chemoradiotherapy in esophageal or gastroesophageal junction carcinoma. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(28):4535&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.02279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10553121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37467395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Batran SE, Homann N, Pauligk C, Goetze TO, Meiler J, Kasper S, Kopp HG, Mayer F, Haag GM, Luley K, et al. Perioperative chemotherapy with fluorouracil plus leucovorin, oxaliplatin, and docetaxel versus fluorouracil or capecitabine plus cisplatin and epirubicin for locally advanced, resectable gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (FLOT4): a randomised, phase 2/3 trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10184):1948&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32557-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30982686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ychou M, Boige V, Pignon JP, Conroy T, Bouche O, Lebreton G, Ducourtieux M, Bedenne L, Fabre JM, Saint-Aubert B, et al. Perioperative chemotherapy compared with surgery alone for resectable gastroesophageal adenocarcinoma: an FNCLCC and FFCD multicenter phase III trial. J Clin Oncol. 2011;29(13):1715&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2010.33.0597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21444866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajani JA, D&#x2019;Amico TA, Bentrem DJ, Chao J, Corvera C, Das P, Denlinger CS, Enzinger PC, Fanta P, Farjah F, et al. Esophageal and esophagogastric junction Cancers, version 2.2019, NCCN clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2019;17(7):855&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6004/jnccn.2019.0033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31319389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwatsuki M, Orita H, Kobayashi K, Hidaka S, Arigami T, Kusumoto T, Satake H, Oki E, Tsutsumi S, Tobimatsu K, et al. Phase II study of S-1 and oxaliplatin as neoadjuvant chemotherapy for locally advanced adenocarcinoma of the gastric or esophagogastric junction: KSCC1601. Gastric Cancer. 2022;25(1):180&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-021-01218-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34379229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl M, Walz MK, Stuschke M, Lehmann N, Meyer HJ, Riera-Knorrenschild J, Langer P, Engenhart-Cabillic R, Bitzer M, Konigsrainer A, et al. Phase III comparison of preoperative chemotherapy compared with chemoradiotherapy in patients with locally advanced adenocarcinoma of the esophagogastric junction. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27(6):851&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2008.17.0506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19139439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies AR, Gossage JA, Zylstra J, Mattsson F, Lagergren J, Maisey N, Smyth EC, Cunningham D, Allum WH, Mason RC. Tumor stage after neoadjuvant chemotherapy determines survival after surgery for adenocarcinoma of the esophagus and esophagogastric junction. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(27):2983&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2014.55.9070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25071104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang EP, O&#x2019;Connor JPB, McShane LM, Giger ML, Lambin P, Kinahan PE, Siegel EL, Shankar LK. Criteria for the translation of radiomics into clinically useful tests. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2023;20(2):69&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41571-022-00707-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36443594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Yi X, Pei Q, Fu Y, Li B, Liu H, Han Z, Chen C, Pang P, Lin H, et al. CT radiomics identifying non-responders to neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy among patients with locally advanced rectal cancer. Cancer Med. 2023;12(3):2463&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.5086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9939108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35912919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda S, Kuno H, Hiyama T, Sakashita S, Sasaki T, Kobayashi T. Computed tomography-based radiomic analysis for predicting pathological response and prognosis after neoadjuvant chemotherapy in patients with locally advanced esophageal cancer. Abdom Radiol (NY). 2023;48(8):2503&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00261-023-03938-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37171586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Peng Y, Feng X, Zhao Y, Seeruttun SR, Zhang J, Cheng Z, Li Y, Liu Z, Zhou Z. Development and validation of a computed Tomography-Based radiomics signature to predict response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy for locally advanced gastric cancer. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(8):e2121143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.21143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34410397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HD, Lee JS, Yook JH, Ryu MH, Park YK, Kim JY, Kim YW, Oh SC, Kim JG, Cheong JH, et al. Radiological criteria for selecting candidates for neoadjuvant chemotherapy for gastric cancer: an exploratory analysis from the PRODIGY study. Gastric Cancer. 2022;25(1):170&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-021-01243-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34476643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker K, Langer R, Reim D, Novotny A, Meyer zum Buschenfelde C, Engel J, Friess H, Hofler H. Significance of histopathological tumor regression after neoadjuvant chemotherapy in gastric adenocarcinomas: a summary of 480 cases. Ann Surg. 2011;253(5):934&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0b013e318216f449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21490451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Li L, Chen X, Huang C, Wang R, Liu Y, Gao J. Intratumoral and peritumoral radiomics predict pathological response after neoadjuvant chemotherapy against advanced gastric cancer. Insights Imaging. 2024;15(1):23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-023-01584-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38270724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Liang H, Li Z, Xue Y, Wang Y, Zhou Z, Yu J, Bu Z, Chen L, Du Y, et al. Perioperative or postoperative adjuvant oxaliplatin with S-1 versus adjuvant oxaliplatin with capecitabine in patients with locally advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma undergoing D2 gastrectomy (RESOLVE): an open-label, superiority and non-inferiority, phase 3 randomised controlled trial. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22(8):1081&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(21)00297-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34252374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YK, Yook JH, Park YK, Lee JS, Kim YW, Kim JY, Ryu MH, Rha SY, Chung IJ, Kim IH, et al. PRODIGY: A phase III study of neoadjuvant Docetaxel, Oxaliplatin, and S-1 plus surgery and adjuvant S-1 versus surgery and adjuvant S-1 for resectable advanced gastric cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(26):2903&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.20.02914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham D, Allum WH, Stenning SP, Thompson JN, Van de Velde CJ, Nicolson M, Scarffe JH, Lofts FJ, Falk SJ, Iveson TJ, et al. Perioperative chemotherapy versus surgery alone for resectable gastroesophageal cancer. N Engl J Med. 2006;355(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa055531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16822992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin F, Zhu LX, Ye ZM, Peng F, Chen MC, Li XM, Zhu ZH, Zhu Y. Computed Tomography-Based intratumor heterogeneity predicts response to immunotherapy plus chemotherapy in esophageal squamous cell carcinoma. Acad Radiol. 2024;31(12):4886&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acra.2024.06.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38981774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge LP, Jin X, Ma D, Wang ZY, Liu CL, Zhou CZ, Zhao S, Yu TJ, Liu XY, Di GH, et al. ZNF689 deficiency promotes intratumor heterogeneity and immunotherapy resistance in triple-negative breast cancer. Cell Res. 2024;34(1):58&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41422-023-00909-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10770380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38168642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z, Huang X, Cheng Z, Xu Z, Lin H, Liu C, Chen X, Liu C, Liang C, Lu C, et al. MRI-based quantification of intratumoral heterogeneity for predicting treatment response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer. Radiology. 2023;308(1):e222830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.222830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Zhang J, Li Z, Wei K, Lei Y, Ren J, Wu L, Shi Z, Meng X, Yang X, et al. A CT-based deep learning radiomics nomogram for predicting the response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in patients with locally advanced gastric cancer: A multicenter cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;46:101348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35340629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Li L, Liu S, Chen Y, Liu C, Han Y, Wang F, Zhan P, Zhao H, Li J, et al. Enhanced CT-based radiomics predicts pathological complete response after neoadjuvant chemotherapy for advanced adenocarcinoma of the esophagogastric junction: a two-center study. Insights Imaging. 2022;13(1):134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13244-022-01273-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35976518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C, Jeong DY, Choi Y, Oh YJ, Kim J, Ryu J, Paeng K, Lee SH, Ock CY, Lee HY. Tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte enrichment predicted by CT radiomics analysis is associated with clinical outcomes of non-small cell lung cancer patients receiving immune checkpoint inhibitors. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1038089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1038089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36660547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang XW, Xiao WS, Lei H, Huag QC, Dong YL, Wang F, Qing WP. Risk model and factors for prediction of response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in patients with advanced gastric cancer-a two-center cohort study. BMC Cancer. 2023;23(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-023-10513-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36631788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Li Z, Wang Y, Li Y, Zhang J, Li Z, Tang L. CT radiomics-based intratumoral and intertumoral heterogeneity indicators for prognosis prediction in gastric cancer patients receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Eur Radiol. 2025;35(8):4448&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-025-11430-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39953151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Gao X, Peng X, May Chen MJ, Li Z, Wei B, Wen X, Wei B, Dong Y, Bu Z, et al. Multi-omics characterization of molecular features of gastric cancer correlated with response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Sci Adv. 2020;6(9):eaay4211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.aay4211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7043923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Jia Y, Zhu H, Xing X, Pang F, Shan F, Li S, Wang D, Zhao F, Ma T, et al. Tumor mutation burden is correlated with response and prognosis in microsatellite-stable (MSS) gastric cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Gastric Cancer. 2021;24(6):1342&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-021-01207-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan X, Jia Y, Shan F, Ying X, Li S, Zhang Y, Pang F, Li Z. Comprehensive evaluation of tumor response better evaluates the efficacy of neoadjuvant chemotherapy and predicts the prognosis in gastric cancer - a post hoc analysis of a single-center randomized controlled trial. BMC Cancer. 2025;25(1):401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-024-13372-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11884205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40045265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HY, Yu Y, Wang C, Zhang S, Gao Y, Pan J, Shao J, Lu G, Zhang K, Li W. A transformer-based representation-learning model with unified processing of multimodal input for clinical diagnostics. Nat Biomed Eng. 2023;7(6):743&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41551-023-01045-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37308585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Liang W, Huang P, Chen D, He Q, Ning Z, Zhang Y, Xiong W, Yu J, Chen T. Multi-modal analysis for accurate prediction of preoperative stage and indications of optimal treatment in gastric cancer. Radiol Med. 2023;128(5):509&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11547-023-01625-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37115392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>