<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41844725</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An intelligent controlling in electric vehicle system with integrated DBS and BMS for sustainable solution.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42354-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The adoption of Electric Vehicles (EVs) has accelerated due to ongoing technological advancements, cost reductions, and a growing awareness of environmental issues. However, despite this progress, challenges persist in improving energy efficiency, extending the lifespan of batteries, and ensuring optimal performance under diverse operating conditions. This research focuses on enhancing the performance and overall efficiency of EVs by proposing the integration of a dual battery system managed by an advanced battery management system using MATLAB/Simulink. The key objective is to optimise the distribution of energy across the system, improving energy availability, prolonging battery life, and ensuring efficient energy use under varying operational conditions. The proposed dual battery system utilises dynamic load balancing and real-time energy distribution strategies, enabling better management of power consumption (1.4 W) and improving the overall efficiency (85%) of the EV's propulsion system for the enhanced range of SOC to 60%. The integration of such a system is critical in minimising energy wastage, enhancing the longevity of the batteries, and reducing the frequency of recharging cycles, thereby lowering the environmental footprint and operational costs of EVs. In addition to the dual battery and advanced BMS, the research explores the incorporation of solar panels as a supplementary energy source. This innovation aims to increase the overall energy efficiency of the EV by harnessing solar power to charge the batteries or provide auxiliary power to the vehicle's systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prashant</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, JSS University, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, 201301, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verma</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Rajkiya Engineering College, Mainpuri, Uttar Pradesh, 205119, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Virmani</LastName><ForeName>Rahul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical &amp; Computer Engineering, ABES Engineering College, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, 201009, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Ram Murat</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Electrical Engineering, Lovely Professional University, Phagwara, Punjab, 144411, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pachauri</LastName><ForeName>Sachin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Rajkiya Engineering College, Mainpuri, Uttar Pradesh, 205119, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Jay</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, GL Bajaj Institute of Technology and Management, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh, 201301, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Balkeshwar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Manufacturing Technology, Faculty of Mechanical Technology, FDRE Technical and Vocational Training Institute, 190310, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. balkeshwar.singh@astu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41844725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42354-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42354-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sanguesa, J. A., Torres-Sanz, V., Garrido, P., Martinez, F. J. &amp; Marquez-Barja, J. M. A review on electric vehicles: Technologies and challenges. Smart Cities 4(1), 372&#x2013;404 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmud, K., Town, G. E., Morsalin, S. &amp; Hossain, M. Integration of electric vehicles and management in the internet of energy. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 82, 4179&#x2013;4203 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, I., Vasant, P. M., Singh, B. S. M., Abdullah-Al-Wadud, M. &amp; Adnan, N. Review of recent trends in optimization techniques for plug-in hybrid and electric vehicle charging infrastructures. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 58, 1039&#x2013;1047 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Storandt and S. Funke, &#x201c;Cruising with a battery-powered vehicle and not getting stranded,&#x201d; in Proc. 26th AAAI Conf. Artificial Intelligence and 24th Innovative Applications of AI Conf., Toronto, ON, Canada, Jul. 2012, vol. 3, p. 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Maggetto and J. Van Mierlo, &#x201c;Electric and electric hybrid vehicle technology: A survey,&#x201d; in IEE Seminar Electric, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Vehicles, Durham, UK, Apr. 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, G., Tan, T. &amp; Wang, G. Real-time smart charging of electric vehicles for demand charge reduction at non-residential sites. IEEE Trans. Smart Grid 8(5), 2473&#x2013;2483 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-&#xc1;lvarez, J., Gonz&#xe1;lez, M. A. &amp; Vela, C. R. Metaheuristics for solving a real-world electric vehicle charging scheduling problem. Appl. Soft Comput. 65, 292&#x2013;306 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Nohara, H. Omori, A. Yamamoto, N. Kimura, and T. Morizane, &#x201c;A miniaturized single-ended wireless EV charger with new high power-factor drive and natural cooling structure,&#x201d; In Proc. IEEE Int. Power Electron. Appl. Conf. Expo. (PEAC), Shenzhen, China, Nov. 2018, pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held, M. &amp; Baumann, M. Assessment of the environmental impacts of electric vehicle concepts. In Towards Life Cycle Sustainability Management (ed. Finkbeiner, M.) 535&#x2013;546 (Springer, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Hauser and R. Kuhn, &#x201c;High-voltage battery management systems (BMS) for electric vehicles,&#x201d; In Advances in Battery Technologies for Electric Vehicles, Amsterdam, The Netherlands: Elsevier, 2015, pp. 265&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, N. H. F. et al. Simplified heat generation model for lithium ion batteries used in electric vehicles. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 53, 012014 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nivas, M., Naidu, R. K. P. R., Mishra, D. P. &amp; Salkuti, S. R. Modeling and analysis of solar-powered electric vehicles. International Journal of Power Electronics and Drive Systems (IJPEDS) 13(1), 480&#x2013;487 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. A. Galadima, &#x201c;Arduino as a learning tool,&#x201d; in Proc. 11th Int. Conf. Electronics, Comput. Comput. (ICECCO), Abuja, Nigeria, Sep.&#x2013;Oct. 2014, pp. 1&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1109/ICECCO.2014.6997577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. A. Badamasi, &#x201c;The working principle of an Arduino,&#x201d; in Proc. 11th Int. Conf. Electronics, Comput. Comput. (ICECCO), Abuja, Nigeria, Sep.&#x2013;Oct. 2014, pp. 1&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1109/ICECCO.2014.6997578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y.-J., Khaligh, A. &amp; Emadi, A. Advanced integrated bidirectional AC/DC and DC/DC converter for plug-in hybrid electric vehicles. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 58(8), 3970&#x2013;3980 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan, A., Mohapatra, D. K. &amp; Dash, S. S. Modeling and performance analysis of electric motors for electric vehicle application. Int. J. Power Electron. Drive Syst. 11(2), 803&#x2013;811 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulselvi, S. &amp; Kalaivani, R. Design and implementation of relay driver module for electric vehicle motor control. Int. J. Sci. Eng. Res. 10(5), 1156&#x2013;1160 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. F. &amp; Javaid, N. A review on lithium-ion battery aging mechanisms and estimations for electric vehicles. IEEE Access 9, 33591&#x2013;33613 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi, R. K., Ali, M. S. &amp; Mishra, S. Design and development of powertrain system including motor and relay switching for electric vehicle application. IEEE Trans. Transport. Electrification 7(3), 1965&#x2013;1974 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar, A. M. A., Islam, M. M. &amp; Mahmud, A. Development of a solar powered electric vehicle charging station with integration of vehicle-to-grid technology. IEEE Trans. Transport. Electrification 6(4), 1638&#x2013;1649 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Laserna, A. W., Keil, P., Wolff, N. &amp; Danzer, M. A. Battery state of health estimation: A structured review of models, methods and commercial devices. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 113, 109254 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vural, M., Ceylan, I. &amp; Teke, A. Soft sensors for state of charge, state of energy, and power loss in formula student electric vehicle. Energy Rep. 6, 83&#x2013;90 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmanos, D. et al. Route optimization of electric vehicles based on dynamic wireless charging. IEEE Access 6, 42551&#x2013;42565 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clairand, J.-M., Rodr&#xed;guez-Garc&#xed;a, J. &amp; &#xc1;lvarez-Bel, C. Smart charging for electric vehicle aggregators considering users&#x2019; preferences. IEEE Access 6, 54624&#x2013;54635 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Morozov, K. Humphries, T. Zou, S. Martins, and J. Angeles, &#x201c;Design and optimization of a drivetrain with two-speed transmission for electric delivery step van,&#x201d; in Proc. IEEE Int. Electr. Vehicle Conf. (IEVC), Florence, Italy, Dec. 2014, pp. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buswig, Y. M. Y. et al. Designing a control system based on SOC estimation of BMS for PV-solar system. Int. J. Integr. Eng. 12(6), 148&#x2013;157 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qays, M. O. et al. An intelligent controlling method for battery lifetime increment using state of charge estimation in PV-battery hybrid system. Appl. Sci. 10(24), 8799 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qays, O., Buswig, Y. &amp; Anyi, M. Active cell balancing control method for series-connected lithium-ion battery. Int. J. Innov. Technol. Explor. Eng. 8(9), 2424&#x2013;2430 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qays, M. O., Buswig, Y., Hossain, M. L. &amp; Abu-Siada, A. Active charge balancing strategy using the state of charge estimation technique for a PV-battery hybrid system. Energies 13(13), 3434 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xfc;ksek, G. &amp; Alkaya, A. An adaptive energy management approach for battery-supercapacitor hybrid energy storage system. Bull. Pol. Acad. Sci. Tech. Sci. https://doi.org/10.24425/bpasts.2024.150203 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xfc;ksek, G. &amp; Lale, T. Improved thermal management of lithium-based batteries employing genetic algorithm optimization. Bull. Pol. Acad. Sci. Tech. Sci. https://doi.org/10.24425/bpasts.2024.151378 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadbane, H. E. et al. Energy management of electric vehicle using a new strategy based on slap swarm optimization and differential flatness control. Sci. Rep. 14, 3629 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houssam Eddine Ghadbane, Said Barkat, Azeddine Houari, Ali Djerioui, Hegazy Rezk, Mohamed Louzazni, Optimal Adaptive Fractional Order Integral Sliding Mode Controller-Energy Management Strategy for Electric Vehicles Based on Bald Eagle Search Algorithm, International Journal of Energy Research Volume 2024, Article ID 7844084, 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadbane, H. E. et al. A new energy management strategy for electric vehicles based on optimal adaptive state machine control. Smart Grids and Energy 9, 28 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadbane, H. E. et al. A load following energy management strategy for a battery-supercapacitor hybrid power system implemented with a PIL co-simulation approach. Smart Grids and Energy 9, 32 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadbane Houssam Eddine, Barkat Said, Azeddine Houari, Ali Djeroui, Tedjani Mesbahi, Hadjkaddour Abdelhak, Energy management strategy for hybrid power system implemented with processor in the loop, proceedings in IEEE , 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassef, A. M., Ghadbane, H. E., Sayed, E. T. &amp; Rezk, H. Reducing hydrogen consumption in hybrid electric vehicles using aquila optimization algorithm. Glob. J. Environ. Sci. Manag. 11(2), 695&#x2013;710 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadbane, H. E. &amp; Mohamed, A. F. Optimizing fuel economy in hybrid electric vehicles using the equivalent consumption minimization strategy based on the arithmetic optimization algorithm. Mathematics 13(9), 1504 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>