<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41720858</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biologically inspired neuromorphic-XAI synergy for transparent and low-carbon healthcare intelligence.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10049</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39515-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The exponential growth of artificial intelligence in healthcare has created unprecedented computational demands, contributing significantly to carbon emissions while often lacking transparency in critical medical decisions. Existing neuromorphic explainable artificial intelligence (NEXAI) systems used in healthcare applications suffer from three primary limitations: inadequate integration of energy-efficient neuromorphic processing with real-time explainability mechanisms, lack of validated frameworks for sustainable resource management in clinical environments, and absence of comprehensive evaluation methodologies that simultaneously address diagnostic accuracy, interpretability, and environmental impact. We develop the NEXAI-Health framework by processing continuous spike streams, iteratively sampling spike rates in the range [Formula: see text]&#x2013;520&#xa0;spikes/s, with cycle-to-cycle variations of [Formula: see text]&#xa0;spikes confirming stable neuromorphic firing behavior. Event-driven thresholds are dynamically tuned to [Formula: see text], and simulation sweeps further validate threshold drift within the narrow interval [Formula: see text]. The integrated explainability module processes gradient-based attributions using sample magnitudes [Formula: see text]&#x2013;0.94, internally expanding to per-layer saliency scores [Formula: see text] across representative trials. Power-aware profiling confirms that all spiking computations remain within the Intel Loihi energy specification of 23.6 pJ per event, supporting sustainable deployment. Experimental iterations on 109,446 MIT-BIH heartbeat samples yield mean diagnostic accuracy of [Formula: see text] with explainability scores of [Formula: see text], and projected energy-efficiency gains converging to [Formula: see text] over conventional AI baselines. Statistical validation employs 10-fold stratified cross-validation with Bonferroni-corrected paired t-tests ([Formula: see text]), demonstrating significant improvements over conventional approaches (Cohen&#x2019;s [Formula: see text], [Formula: see text]). The projected neuromorphic energy consumption remains theoretical, with simulated cycles yielding sample values such as 23.6pJ&#x2013;28.2pJ per spike under a modeled firing rate of [Formula: see text]&#x2013;[Formula: see text]. Claims regarding biodegradable substrate integration are likewise conceptual, assuming provisional material constants [Formula: see text]&#x2013;1.34 for tensile&#x2013;thermal coupling. Clinical translation further mandates regulatory approval and structured physician training, while algorithmic correctness is supported through iterative validation on the MIT-BIH dataset (109,&#xa0;446 labeled beats). Ultimately, true clinical viability and hardware-level energy efficiency require evaluation on physical neuromorphic processors under real operational constraints.This study presents a theoretical framework validated through software simulation using publicly available MIT-BIH Arrhythmia Database; no physical neuromorphic hardware implementation, clinical trials, or human participants were involved.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sungheetha</LastName><ForeName>Akey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Alliance University, 562106, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Intelligent Cloud Computing, COE for Advanced Cloud, Multimedia University, Jalan Ayer Keroh Lama, 75450, Melaka, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R</LastName><ForeName>Rajesh Sharma</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Alliance University, 562106, Bengaluru, India. sharmaphd20@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Intelligent Cloud Computing, COE for Advanced Cloud, Multimedia University, Jalan Ayer Keroh Lama, 75450, Melaka, Malaysia. sharmaphd20@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Balusamy</LastName><ForeName>Balamurugan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor and Chairperson, School of Engineering and IT, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Dubai Campus, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mapari</LastName><ForeName>Shrikant</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Institute of Computer Studies and Research, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, India. mshreek@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karthik</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Science and Engineering, Cambridge Institute of Technology, K. R. Puram, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yogarayan</LastName><ForeName>Sumendra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Intelligent Cloud Computing, COE for Advanced Cloud, Multimedia University, Jalan Ayer Keroh Lama, 75450, Melaka, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Information Science and Technology, Multimedia University, Jalan Ayer Keroh Lama, 75450, Melaka, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ECG arrhythmia Detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy efficient AI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Explainable aartificial intelligence (NEXAI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low-carbon diagnostics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromorphic computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable healthcare systems</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: This computational research utilizing publicly available de-identified datasets does not constitute human subjects research as no identifiable private information was collected and no intervention or interaction with living individuals occurred. No clinical trials were conducted, no human participants were enrolled, and no new patient data was generated. All experimental work was performed using publicly available MIT-BIH Arrhythmia Database accessed through PhysioNet.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41720858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13021978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39515-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39515-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ali Nur, M., Abebe, M. &amp; Rajendran, R. S. Handwritten geez digit recognition using deep learning. <i>Appl. Comput. Intell. Soft Comput.</i><b>2022</b>(1), 8515810 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R., Marikkannu, P. &amp; Sungheetha, A. Three-dimensional MRI brain tumour classification using hybrid ant colony optimisation and grey wolf optimiser with proximal support vector machine. <i>Int. J. Biomed. Eng. Technol.</i><b>29</b>(1), 34&#x2013;45 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJBET.2019.096879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A.R., Beaula, R., Marikkannu, P., Sungheetha, A., &amp; Sahana, C. Comparative study of distinctive image classification techniques. In <i>2016 10th International Conference on Intelligent Systems and Control (ISCO)</i> 1&#x2013;8 (IEEE, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A. &amp; Rajesh Sharma, R. Extreme learning machine and fuzzy K-nearest neighbour based hybrid gene selection technique for cancer classification. <i>J. Med. Imaging Health Inf.</i><b>6</b>(7), 1652&#x2013;1656 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R., &amp; Sungheetha, A. Segmentation and classification techniques of medical images using innovated hybridized techniques-a study. In <i>2017 11th International Conference on Intelligent Systems and Control (ISCO)</i> 192&#x2013;196 (IEEE, 2017)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenrayan, V. et al. Effect of powder composition, PTAW parameters on dilution, microstructure and hardness of Ni-Cr-Si-B alloy deposition. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>, 16 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e36087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11378951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R., Gandhi, K.R., Shanmugaraja, K., Sungheetha, A., &amp; Jegan, J. Motion detection using heuristic AI based machine learning approaches. In <i>2024 4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management (ICIPTM)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu, S.K. et al. Analyzing the digital transformation and evolution of financial technology (Fintech) across various industries. In <i>4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management 2024, ICIPTM 2024</i> 1&#x2013;11 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monachan, S. et al. Challenges and opportunities: assessing the impact of gst on msmes and the need for ongoing support. In <i>2024 4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management (ICIPTM)</i> 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R. &amp; Marikkannu, P. An efficient liver segmentation using kernel sparse coding automated (KSCA) approach. <i>ARPN J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 6 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadivukarasi, L. et al. Nurturing trust in human-robot interaction and the crucial role of dialogue and explicit AI. In <i>Trends and Applications in Mechanical Engineering, Composite Materials and Smart Manufacturing</i> 232&#x2013;247 (IGI Global, 2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe, M. Clickbait detection for amharic language using deep learning techniques. <i>J. Mach. Comput. Open Access</i><b>4</b>, 603&#x2013;615 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., Sharma, R., Blake, J., Adere, K., &amp; Shifaw, B. Analysis and identification of gout flares using machine learning. In <i>Diagnosing Musculoskeletal Conditions using Artifical Intelligence and Machine Learning to Aid Interpretation of Clinical Imaging</i> 179&#x2013;194 (Academic Press, 2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jothilakshmi, R., Chinniah, P., Rajesh Sharma, R. &amp; Lakshmi, T. V. Dynamically stabilized recurrent neural network optimized with binary emperor penguin optimization algorithm fostered sentiment classification and information retrieval. <i>Internat. J. Uncertain. Fuzziness Knowl.-Based Syst.</i><b>33</b>(06), 761&#x2013;786 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218488525500254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., &amp; Sharma, R. AI at the edge: merging intelligence and distributed computing. In <i>Embedded Artificial Intelligence</i> 55&#x2013;74 (Chapman and Hall/CRC, 2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., Rajesh Sharma, R., Chinnaiyan, R. &amp; Ghantasala, G. P. AI ML empowered smart buildings and factories. <i>Artif. Intell. Mach. Learn. Ind.</i><b>4</b>, 87&#x2013;105 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A. et al. Early diabetes prediction through multiple machine learning models: a comparative analysis. In <i>Proceedings of 2025 AI-Driven Smart Healthcare for Society 5.0, AdSoc5.0 2025</i> 79&#x2013;84 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengottaiyan, N. et al. Detection and classification of diabetic foot ulcers via cloud-based deep learning approach. In <i>Proceedings of the 2024 3rd Edition of IEEE Delhi Section Flagship Conference, DELCON 2024</i> 1&#x2013;15 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradeep Ghantasala, G.S. et al. Towards a healthier online environment: machine learning for detecting and addressing cyberbullying comments. In <i>International Conference on Parallel, Distributed and Grid Computing, PDGC 2024</i> 310&#x2013;316 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir, M.H. et al. Thyroid cancer prediction using ensembling techniques and multi modal data. In <i>Proceedings - 3rd International Conference on Self Sustainable Artificial Intelligence Systems, ICSSAS 2025</i> 884&#x2013;889 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu, T. et al. AI Powered sentiment analysis of social media presence. In <i>2nd IEEE International Conference on Advances in Information Technology, ICAIT 2024 - Proceedings</i> 1&#x2013;10 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., Rajesh Sharma, R., Mahapatra, S., Tamilarasi, R., &amp; Sam Leni, A.E. Neuromorphic-enhanced smart ECG reconstruction with explainable AI for green healthcare systems. In <i>2nd International Conference on IT Innovations and Knowledge Discovery, ITIKD 2024</i> 1&#x2013;10 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantelay, L.M., Abebe, M., Sharma Rajendran, R., Sungheetha, A., &amp; Sengottaiyan, N. Heuristic pneumonia and tuberculosis detection in X-ray images using convolutional neural networks. In <i>2023 Annual International Conference on Emerging Research Areas: International Conference on Intelligent Systems, AICERA/ICIS 2023</i> 1&#x2013;9 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A. et al. AI-enhanced triboelectric surface analysis for smart urban accessibility pattern detection <i>Procedia Comput. Sci.</i><b>259</b>, 1442&#x2013;1451 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2025.04.099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikary, R. et al. A modular CNN framework for hierarchical mango grading and quality Aassessment. In <i>3rd Odisha International Conference on Electrical Power Engineering, Communication and Computing Technology, ODICON 2024</i> 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titus, R. et al. Evaluation of consumer behavior regarding food delivery applications in India. In <i>4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management 2024, ICIPTM 2024</i> 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh Sharma, R. et al. Bridging the gap: evaluating the symbiotic relationship of cloud computing with data science and data engineering. In <i>Proceedings of the 2024 3rd Edition of IEEE Delhi Section Flagship Conference, DELCON 2024</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengottaiyan, N. et al. Heuristic forest fire detection using the deep learning model with optimized cluster head selection technique. <i>J. Comput. Netw. Commun.</i><b>2024</b>, 6569596 (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A. et al. Adaptive stream processing framework for smart city IoT networks using self-powered photodetector-based data collection. In <i>2nd International Conference on IT Innovations and Knowledge Discovery, ITIKD 2024</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., Rajesh Sharma, R., Mahapatra, S., Tamilarasi, R., &amp; Sam Leni, A.E. HESTStream: a hybrid edge-stream Coptand PReffProcessing framework for sustainable smart cities using adaptive caching and environmental monitoring. In <i>2nd International Conference on IT Innovations and Knowledge Discovery, ITIKD 2024</i> 1&#x2013;3 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathwika, B. et al. Influence of digital transformation on the banking industry. In <i>4th International Conference on Innovative Practices in Technology and Management 2024, ICIPTM 2024</i> 1&#x2013;3 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpagalakshmi, R. C. et al. Adaptive anomaly detection for secure federated learning in IIoT environments. <i>Procedia Comput. Sci.</i><b>258</b>, 536&#x2013;551 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2025.04.289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh Sharma, R. et al. MRI brain tumor classification for multi labeled medical images using machine learning techniques. In <i>2024 1st International Conference on Innovations in Communications, Electrical and Computer Engineering, ICICEC 2024</i> 1&#x2013;2 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilahun, E., Abebe, M., Rajesh Sharma, R., Sungheetha, A., &amp; Sengottaiayn, N. Culture reflecting artistic fashion design using deep learning and assisting custom algorithm. In <i>2023 International Conference on New Frontiers in Communication, Automation, Management and Security, ICCAMS 2023</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh Sharma, R. et al. Segmentation of medical liver image diseases using improved contextual convolutional neural network (COCOn) model. In <i>2024 1st International Conference on Innovations in Communications, Electrical and Computer Engineering, ICICEC 2024</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R.R. et al. Enhancing scalability in blockchain networks: an improved sharding protocol using verifiable random function (VRF) for shard assignment. In <i>International Conference on Parallel, Distributed and Grid Computing, PDGC 2024</i> 58&#x2013;63 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A. et al. A comparative analysis of hematological, lipid profile parameters, and body mass index in male vegetarians and non-vegetarians. In <i>2nd International Conference on Signal Processing, Communication, Power and Embedded Systems, SCOPES 2024</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthik, M. et al. A data-driven crop recommendation system with explainable AI for precision agriculture. In <i>Proceedings of 3rd International Conference on Augmented Intelligence and Sustainable Systems, ICAISS 2025</i> 774&#x2013;779 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungheetha, A., Raihana, A., Rajesh Sharma, R., Sindhu, V., &amp; Mahapatra, S. Accessible Edugaming: fostering inclusive learning through interactive points, leaderboards, and confidence-building features. In <i>2nd International Conference on IT Innovations and Knowledge Discovery, ITIKD 2024</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y.S., &amp; Kim, Y. Recent trend of neuromorphic computing hardware: intel&#x2019;s neuromorphic system perspective. In <i>2020 International SoC Design Conference (ISOCC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederstr&#xf6;m, L. et al. A model based comparison of BiFeO3 device applicability in neuromorphic hardware. In <i>2013 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobin, D. et al. Exploration of novel neuromorphic methodologies for materials applications. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chicca, E., Stefanini, F., Bartolozzi, C. &amp; Indiveri, G. Neuromorphic electronic circuits for building autonomous cognitive systems. <i>Proc. IEEE</i><b>102</b>(9), 1367&#x2013;1388 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2014.2313954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrovici, M.A., et al. Pattern representation and recognition with accelerated analog neuromorphic systems. In <i>2017 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blouw, P., &amp; Eliasmith, C. Event-driven signal processing with neuromorphic computing systems. In <i>ICASSP 2020 - 2020 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</i> 8534&#x2013;8538 (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, Y., Carbajal, A., Escamilla, L., &amp; Pinar, A. Neuromorphic Monte Carlo tree search methods for shortest path interdiction. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abreu, S., &amp; Pedersen, J.E. Neuromorphic programming: emerging directions for brain-inspired hardware. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schemmel, J., et al. Live demonstration: a scaled-down version of the BrainScaleS wafer-scale neuromorphic system. In <i>2012 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</i> 702&#x2013;702 (IEEE, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaya, C. et al. Neuromorphic force-control in an industrial task: validating energy and latency benefits. In <i>2024 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</i> 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeshertz, G., Indiveri, G., Nair, M., &amp; Renner, A. Accurate mapping of RNNs on neuromorphic hardware with adaptive spiking neurons. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. et al. Fast switching serial and parallel paradigms of SNN inference on multi-core heterogeneous neuromorphic platform SpiNNaker2. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L., Ding, Z., Liu, H., Xu, Y. &amp; Su, T. Memristor-based brain-like reconfigurable neuromorphic system. In <i>2021 International Conference on Neuromorphic Computing (ICNC)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, P., &amp; Hu, S. A neuromorphic computing platform with compact neuromorphic core. In <i>2021 IEEE 3rd International Conference on Circuits and Systems (ICCS)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primavera, B.A., Khan, S., Adler, S.R., &amp; Shainline, J.M. Programmable synapses and dendritic circuits for superconducting optoelectronic neuromorphic computing. In <i>2024 International Conference on Neuromorphic Systems (ICONS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, K. et al. A full-neuron memory model designed for neuromorphic systems. In <i>2022 IEEE 4th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence Circuits and Systems (AICAS)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. et al. Evolving neuromorphic systems on the ethereum smart contract platform. In <i>2022 IEEE 1st Global Emerging Technology Blockchain Forum: Blockchain &amp; Beyond (iGETblockchain)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayr, C. et al. A biological-realtime neuromorphic system in 28 nm CMOS using low-leakage switched capacitor circuits. <i>IEEE Trans. Biomed. Circuits Syst.</i><b>10</b>(1), 243&#x2013;254 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBCAS.2014.2379294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25680215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharadwaj, K.A. Emergence of neuromorphic chips to simulate human brain. In <i>2019 3rd International conference on Electronics, Communication and Aerospace Technology (ICECA)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo, N., Madsen, T., &amp; Nikolic, K. Self-learning neuromorphic robot based on reward-driven spiking neural network. In <i>2025 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo, N., Madsen, T., &amp; Nikolic, K. Neuromorphic robotics on conventional low-power CPU hardware. In <i>2025 IEEE 7th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence Circuits and Systems (AICAS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J.H., Wang, C.Y., &amp; An, Y.Y. A survey of neuromorphic vision system: &#x2013;biological nervous systems realized on silicon. In <i>2009 International Conference on Industrial Mechatronics and Automation</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Burgt, Y. Recent advances in on-chip learning with organic neuromorphic circuits. In <i>2025 9th IEEE Electron Devices Technology &amp; Manufacturing Conference (EDTM)</i> 1&#x2013;3 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indiveri, G., Linn, E., &amp; Ambrogio, S. ReRAM-based neuromorphic computing. In <i>Resistive Switching: From Fundamentals of Nanoionic Redox Processes to Memristive Device Applications</i>, Chapter 15 (Wiley, 2016)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;gon-Lours, L. et al. High-conductance, Ohmic-like HfZrO4 ferroelectric memristor. In <i>ESSDERC 2021 - IEEE 51st European Solid-State Device Research Conference (ESSDERC)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plank, J. S., Schuman, C. D., Bruer, G., Dean, M. E. &amp; Rose, G. S. The TENNLab exploratory neuromorphic computing framework. <i>IEEE Lett. Comput. Soc.</i><b>1</b>(2), 17&#x2013;20 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LOCS.2018.2885976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., &amp; Tian, F. GT-free_XAI: a ground truth-free XAI framework for decision interpretation and evaluation. In <i>2025 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brdnik, S., &amp; &#x160;umak, B. Current trends, challenges and techniques in XAI field; a tertiary study of XAI research. In <i>2024 47th MIPRO ICT and Electronics Convention (MIPRO)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugopal, A., Farnaghi, M., &amp; Zurita-Milla, R. Comparative evaluation of XAI methods for transparent crop yield estimation using CNN. In <i>IGARSS 2024 - 2024 IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargagna, F., De Santi, L.A., Santarelli, M.F., Positano, V., &amp; Vanello, N. Bayesian XAI methods towards a robustness-centric approach to deep learning: an ABIDE I study. In <i>2024 IEEE International Symposium on Medical Measurements and Applications (MeMeA)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhiram, A. C. N., Gokul, R. &amp; Keerthimon, P. A human-centric evaluation of XAI methods for sentiment analysis on amazon reviews. In <i>2025 4th International Conference on Advances in Computing, Communication, Embedded and Secure Systems (ACCESS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abeyagunasekera, S.H.P. et al. LISA : enhance the explainability of medical images unifying current XAI techniques. In <i>2022 IEEE 7th International conference for Convergence in Technology (I2CT)</i> 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhijna, M.B., Akul, P., &amp; Kodipalli, A. Leveraging XAI and breakthrough machine learning techniques for trigeminal neuralgia severity classification. In <i>2024 IEEE Region 10 Symposium (TENSYMP)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon, C., &amp; Barr, J. <i>Deep Learning and XAI Techniques for Anomaly Detection: Integrate the Theory and Practice of Deep Anomaly Explainability</i> (Packt Publishing, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supardi, R.S., &amp; Gambetta, W. Knowledge-based credit granting system in indonesia with artificial intelligence and XAI approach. In <i>2023 10th International Conference on Advanced Informatics: Concept, Theory and Application (ICAICTA)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anitha, A., Nair, A., &amp; Kamaraj, B. Brain tumor detection and classification using deep neural network and interpretation using XAI techniques. In <i>2024 IEEE International Conference on Signal Processing, Informatics, Communication and Energy Systems (SPICES)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maneerat, T. XAI Approach to improved and informed detection of burnt scar. In <i>2022 International Conference on Decision Aid Sciences and Applications (DASA)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepulveda, G., Peralta, B., Levano, M., Schwarzenberg, P., &amp; Nicolis, O. Prediction of failure in a first-year degree in a chilean university based on programming support guides under an XAI approach. In <i>2023 IEEE CHILEAN Conference on Electrical, Electronics Engineering, Information and Communication Technologies (CHILECON)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlegel, U., Arnout, H., El-Assady, M., Oelke, D., &amp; Keim, D.A. Towards a rigorous evaluation Of XAI methods on time series. In <i>2019 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision Workshop (ICCVW)</i> 1&#x2013;9 (IEEE, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean, C.M., Ma, X., Ding, T., Xu, K., Chen, Y., &amp; Mo, H. A study of machine learning model&#x2019;s performance for load forecasting based on XAI techniques. In <i>2025 17th International Conference on Computer and Automation Engineering (ICCAE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roshan, K., &amp; Zafar, A. Using Kernel SHAP XAI method to optimize the network anomaly detection model. In <i>2022 9th International Conference on Computing for Sustainable Global Development (INDIACom)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppa, A. &amp; Le-Khac, N. A. Adversarial XAI methods in cybersecurity. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur.</i><b>16</b>, 4924&#x2013;4938 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2021.3117075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shouha, M., &amp; Szics, G. iPIC-XAI: improving PIC-XAI for enhanced image captioning explanation. In <i>2023 14th IEEE International Conference on Cognitive Infocommunications (CogInfoCom)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, C., Wang, M.H., Liu, H., &amp; Chong, K.K.L. Exploring Meibomian gland dysfunction grading: a comparison of machine learning and XAI approaches. In <i>2024 IEEE 2nd International Conference on Image Processing and Computer Applications (ICIPCA)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu, M.C., Chen, T.C.T., &amp; Wu, H.C. Enhancing the understandability and interpretability of type-II diabetes diagnosis using a deep fuzzy neural and XAI approach. In <i>2025 IEEE 15th Symposium on Computer Applications &amp; Industrial Electronics (ISCAIE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez, M.P., &amp; Azqueta-Alz&#xfa;az, A. A no code XAI framework for policy making. In <i>2023 19th International Conference on Distributed Computing in Smart Systems and the Internet of Things (DCOSS-IoT)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, D.M., Kumar, D.R., Reddy, S.N., &amp; Abhilash, A. Interpretable credit card fraud detection using LightGBM and XAI techniques. In <i>2025 International Conference on Computational Robotics, Testing and Engineering Evaluation (ICCRTEE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aechtner, J., Cabrera, L., Katwal, D., Onghena, P., Valenzuela, D.P., &amp; Wilbik, A. Comparing user perception of explanations developed with XAI methods. In <i>2022 IEEE International Conference on Fuzzy Systems (FUZZ-IEEE)</i> 1&#x2013;8 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, C.Y., Chen, J., Markert, K., &amp; B&#xf6;ttinger, K. Rectifying adversarial inputs using XAI techniques. In <i>2022 30th European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaud, E. et al. Consistency of XAI models against medical expertise: an assessment protocol. In <i>2024 IEEE 12th International Conference on Healthcare Informatics (ICHI)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthukumar, P., Murali, N., Dinesh, P., Sundaresan, K., &amp; Harfoush, K. Darknet traffic classification using the XAI framework. In <i>2025 IEEE 22nd Consumer Communications &amp; Networking Conference (CCNC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, J., Zeng, G., &amp; Fang, T. The origin and connotation of low carbon city: a conceptual framework. In <i>2012 Fifth International Joint Conference on Computational Sciences and Optimization</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na, Z., Liu, Y., &amp; Bo, W. Research on green tax promoting the development of low-carbon economy in China. In <i>2011 International Conference on Business Management and Electronic Information</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, R., Li, Y., Sun, J., Zhang, H., &amp; Liu, D. Low-Carbon Economic Dispatch considering carbon capture unit and demand response under carbon trading. In <i>2016 IEEE PES Asia-Pacific Power and Energy Engineering Conference (APPEEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. et al. Multi objective low carbon economic dispatch of power system considering integrated flexible operation of carbon capture power plant. In <i>2021 Power System and Green Energy Conference (PSGEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Yi, J., Lin, W., &amp; Ren, X. Low carbon economic dispatch for integrated energy systems with CCUS power plant. In <i>2024 3rd Asia Power and Electrical Technology Conference (APET)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L., Li, J., Zhou, M., Liao, T., &amp; Cao, Y. Low-carbon economy energy use strategy for parks based on dynamic carbon emission factors. In <i>2022 Power System and Green Energy Conference (PSGEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., &amp; Huang, X. Research on the concept system and construction pattern of low carbon tourism based on low carbon economy. In <i>2011 International Conference on Remote Sensing, Environment and Transportation Engineering</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, P. et al. Research on planning model of low-carbon path for the park taking into account carbon asset value. In <i>2023 2nd Asian Conference on Frontiers of Power and Energy (ACFPE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C.et al. Low carbon economic optimization dispatching of medium and low voltage distribution systems based on carbon emission flow. In <i>2023 8th International Conference on Power and Renewable Energy (ICPRE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Y., Ma, C., Chen, H., &amp; Huang, J. Low-carbon power dispatch model under the carbon peak target. In <i>2021 IEEE Sustainable Power and Energy Conference (iSPEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2021)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. Carbon emission trading and technology innovation for low-carbon emission. In <i>2011 International Conference on Electrical and Control Engineering</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Sun, P., Ji, X., Yang, M. &amp; Ye, P. Low-carbon economic dispatch of integrated energy systems considering full-process carbon emission tracking and low carbon demand response. <i>IEEE Trans. Netw. Sci. Eng.</i><b>11</b>(6), 5234&#x2013;5247 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2024.3420771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Low-carbon economic dispatch of integrated energy system considering expanding carbon emission flows. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>12</b>, 89234&#x2013;89245 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, W. et al. Multi-objective land use optimization based on low-carbon development using NSGA-II. In <i>2013 21st International Conference on Geoinformatics</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, X., Gao, W., Hao, C., &amp; Zhou, W. Low-carbon economy optimal dispatching method considering integrated energy system of carbon capture and storage park. In <i>2023 China Automation Congress (CAC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, W. et al. Development status and technical challenges of new low-carbon technologies for power systems under the dual-carbon goal. In , pp.<i>2024 7th International Conference on Energy, Electrical and Power Engineering (CEEPE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M., Xue, Y., Cai, B. &amp; Xue, F. Co-optimization of carbon reduction and carbon sequestration in power sector toward carbon neutralityy. <i>J. Modern Power Syst. Clean Energy</i><b>13</b>(5), 1&#x2013;10 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, J., &amp; Li, Y. Evaluation of green and low carbon benefits and collaborative optimization of electrical carbon coupling in power systems. In <i>2024 International Conference on Power, Electrical Engineering, Electronics and Control (PEEEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Ning, K., Zhang, Q., Xu, Q., Chen, W., &amp; Yu, X. Low-carbon optimization operation of integrated energy system considering ladder-type carbon trading and carbon capture. In <i>2022 7th Asia Conference on Power and Electrical Engineering (ACPEE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IEEE P3241.01/D5.2. IEEE approved draft standard for using blockchain in low carbon zones evaluation (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Luo, F., Hu, S., &amp; Yang, X. Research on life-cycle comprehensive low-carbon benefits of wind power generation from distribution planning perspective. In <i>2020 IEEE 4th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, X., Zheng, J., Mei, F., Wu, J., &amp; Zhang, Y. Low carbon economic dispatch of integrated energy systems considering stepped carbon trading. In <i>2023 7th International Conference on Green Energy and Applications (ICGEA)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziying, Z., &amp; Shuting, Y. Research on the theory of power system carbon emission flow and Its application in the low-carbon -transition. In <i>2024 6th International Conference on Electrical Engineering and Control Technologies (CEECT)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, L., Ning, D., Li, L., Zhang, B., &amp; Xiao, J. A low-carbon optimization method for electric vehicle charging load under a road-electric coupling network considering carbon emission reduction. In <i>2025 4th International Symposium on New Energy Technology Innovation and Low Carbon Development (NET-LC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J. et al. Calculation of carbon emission of power system based on hydroelectric peak shaving scenario. In <i>2024 7th International Conference on Electronics Technology (ICET)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, G., Liu, P., Cheng, S., &amp; Zhang, X. Investment in low carbon emission under different carbon tax policies. In <i>2012 Fifth International Joint Conference on Computational Sciences and Optimization</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhavaneetharan, L. A comprehensive review of bias detection and XAI techniques in NLP. In <i>2025 5th International Conference on Advanced Research in Computing (ICARC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawoud, K., Samek, W., Eisert, P., Lapuschkin, S., &amp; Bosse, S. Human-centered evaluation of XAI methods. In <i>2023 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW)</i> 1&#x2013;8 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priya Dharshini, S., Ram Kumar, K., Venkatesh, S., Narasimhan, K. &amp; Adalarasu, K. An overview of interpretability techniques for explainable artificial Intelligence (XAI) in deep learning-based medical image analysis. In <i>2023 9th International Conference on Advanced Computing and Communication Systems (ICACCS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gribova, V., &amp; Shalfeeva, E. Cloud technology, infrastructure and computing for manufacturing viable XAI systems. In <i>2024 IEEE International Multi-Conference on Engineering, Computer and Information Sciences (SIBIRCON)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charaabi, H., Mzoughi, H., Hamdi, R., &amp; Njah, M. EXplainable artificial intelligence (XAI) for MRI brain tumor diagnosis: a survey. In <i>2023 International Conference on Cyberworlds (CW)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meena, V., Raghavender, G., Jayakar, S. &amp; Kumar, J.S. Privacy-focused federated learning for mental health data with XAI techniques. In <i>2025 6th International Conference on Data Intelligence and Cognitive Informatics (ICDICI)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamoura, S.C. Explainable AI (XAI) for AI-acceptability: the coming age of digital management 5.0. In <i>2023 International Conference on Networking, Sensing and Control (ICNSC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswar, V. Neuro-symbolic self-explanatory AI (NS-XAI): a real-time framework for transparent and adaptive decision-making. In <i>2025 International Conference on Computing Technologies (ICOCT)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shouha, M. &amp; Szics, G. PIC-XAI: Post-hoc image captioning explanation using segmentation. In <i>2023 IEEE 17th International Symposium on Applied Computational Intelligence and Informatics (SACI)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagua Paz, C.J. &amp; Ramirez-Gonzalez, G. Uso de Inteligencia Artificial Explicable (XAI) en estudios del impacto del ENSO en la agricultura: una revisi&#xf3;n de alcance. In <i>2025 IEEE Colombian Conference on Communications and Computing (COLCOM)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Xu, F., Zou, J., Petrosian, O.L. &amp; Krinkin, K.V. XAI evaluation: evaluating black-box model explanations for prediction. In <i>2021 II International Conference on Neural Networks and Neurotechnologies (NeuroNT)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee, S., Rupe, J. &amp; Zhu, J. XAI for communication networks. In <i>2022 IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering Workshops (ISSREW)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raif, P., Suchanek-Raif, R. &amp; Tkacz, E. Explainable AI (XAI) in healthcare - tools and regulations. In <i>2023 IEEE EMBS Special Topic Conference on Data Science and Engineering in Healthcare, Medicine and Biology</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandava, R. et al. Exploring the role of XAI in enhancing predictive model transparency in healthcare risk assessment. In <i>2025 International Conference on Computational Robotics, Testing and Engineering Evaluation (ICCRTEE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trofimov, Y. &amp; Averkin, A. (2024). Enhancing results with ANFIS and XAI for soil contamination monitoring and public health risk assessment. In <i>2024 IEEE 3rd International Conference on Problems of Informatics, Electronics and Radio Engineering (PIERE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamzah, N., Husin, H.S., Azman, A., and Chuprat, S. Improving usability of explainable artificial Intelligence (XAI) applications through quality assessment using quality model. In <i>2025 International Conference on Metaverse and Current Trends in Computing (ICMCTC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machlev, R., Malka, A., Perl, M., Levron, Y. &amp; Belikov, J. Explaining the decisions of deep learning models for load disaggregation (NILM) based on XAI. In <i>2022 IEEE Power &amp; Energy Society General Meeting (PESGM)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A., Singh, U. K. &amp; Pradhan, B. Enhancing interpretability in deep learning-based inversion of 2-D ground penetrating radar data: an explainable AI (XAI) strategy. <i>IEEE Geosci. Remote Sens. Lett.</i><b>21</b>, 1&#x2013;5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi, L., Kalantar, B., Zaryabi, E.H., Halin, A.A. &amp; Ueda, N. On the use of XAI for CNN model interpretation: a remote sensing case study. In <i>2022 IEEE Asia-Pacific Conference on Computer Science and Data Engineering (CSDE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J.H., Park, S.U. &amp; Hong, S.K. A study on the effectiveness of current data in motor mechanical fault diagnosis using XAI. In <i>2021 24th International Conference on Electrical Machines and Systems (ICEMS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagannathan, J. &amp; Goditi, V.V.S.K. Integration of a hybrid model with XAI for stock price forecasting: a Dashboard-Driven approach. In <i>2024 International Conference on IT Innovation and Knowledge Discovery (ITIKD)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth, S., Pakrashi, A. &amp; Dev, S. Exploring the impact of SAR images on wave height prediction models: a study using XAI. In <i>2024 17th International Congress on Image and Signal Processing, BioMedical Engineering and Informatics (CISP-BMEI)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahuja, R. &amp; Indra, G. Leveraging XAI for discovering crucial semographic, clinical and pathological diabetes mellitus biomarkers. In <i>2024 3rd Edition of IEEE Delhi Section Flagship Conference (DELCON)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore, M. et al. Quantum-assisted SNN-based XAI framework for secure space-based industrial IoT applications. In <i>2025 IEEE Region 10 Symposium (TENSYMP)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheu, R. K. et al. Interpretable classification of pneumonia infection using eXplainable AI (XAI-ICP). <i>IEEE Access</i><b>11</b>, 89234&#x2013;89248 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3255403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mindlin, D. &amp; Cimiano, P. Dialogue-based XAI approaches: exploring the continuum from static explanations to free-form chat interfaces. In <i>2025 19th International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oveis, A.H., Giusti, E., Meucci, G., Ghio, S. &amp; Martorella, M. Explainability in hyperspectral image classification: a study of Xai through the Shap algorithm. In <i>2023 13th Workshop on Hyperspectral Imaging and Signal Processing: Evolution in Remote Sensing (WHISPERS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabassum, S., Parvin, N., Hossain, N., Tasnim, A., Rahman, R. &amp; Hossain, M.I. IoT network attack detection using XAI and reliability analysis. In <i>2022 25th International Conference on Computer and Information Technology (ICCIT)</i> 1&#x2013;8 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, M.S., Lifat, M.A.S., Hasan, R. &amp; Hassan, M. M. Discovering the depths of cotton leaf disease detection: integrating hypertuned residual networks with GradCAM XAI for enhanced understanding and diagnosis. In <i>2024 3rd International Conference on Advancement in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (ICAEEE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gizzini, A.K., Medjahdi, Y. &amp; Ben Mabrouk, M. GRACE: gradient-based XAI scheme for channel estimation in wireless communications. In <i>2024 IEEE International Mediterranean Conference on Communications and Networking (MeditCom)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehlot, N., Malik, S., Jena, A., Vijayvargiya, A. &amp; Kumar, R. XAI-Driven sEMG feature analysis for hand gestures. In <i>2024 Third International Conference on Power, Control and Computing Technologies (ICPC2T)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir, G., Ozdemir, U., Kuzlu, M. &amp; Catak, F.O. Leveraging explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) methods supporting local and global explainability for smart grids. In <i>2024 Global Energy Conference (GEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan, K. S. &amp;Kumaravel, A. Gamification and XAI tutoring structure using Mamdani fuzzy inference systems. In <i>2023 9th International Conference on Smart Structures and Systems (ICSSS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiruvenkadam, K., Ravindran, V. &amp; Thiyagarajan, A. Deep learning with XAI based multi-modal MRI brain tumor image analysis using image fusion techniques. In <i>2024 International Conference on Trends in Quantum Computing and Emerging Business Technologies</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Y., Guo, Q., Xu, S. &amp; Xiong, N. Research on the accounting method of indirect carbon emissions from cross-regional electricity. In <i>2025 4th International Symposium on New Energy Technology Innovation and Low Carbon Development (NET-LC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, S., Wu, Y., Lou, S. &amp; Yin, X. A model for optimizing spinning reserve requirement of power system under low-carbon economy. <i>IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy</i><b>5</b>(4), 1048&#x2013;1055 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2014.2325834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Lu, Z., Cai, Y., Kong, X., Zhang, J. &amp; Hu, J. Low carbon optimization operation of power system considering ecological carbon sink and renewable energy. In <i>2024 IEEE 8th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. Online monitoring of water heating carbon emissions in office building based on carbon emission coefficient method. In <i>2025 4th International Symposium on New Energy Technology Innovation and Low Carbon Development (NET-LC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei-yi, Y. &amp; Bo, Y. Promotion path of low-carbon economy based on low-carbon chain. In <i>2011 International Conference on Information Management, Innovation Management and Industrial Engineering</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L. &amp; Zheng, C. Low carbon policies and coordination in dyadic supply chains. In <i>2014 11th International Conference on Service Systems and Service Management (ICSSSM)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y., Jiang, H. &amp; Wang, B. Dynamics of the carbon storage of terrestrial ecosystems in geological spatial and temporal scales. In <i>2011 19th International Conference on Geoinformatics</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Y. &amp; Yan, X. Innovation of value engineering in low-carbon buildings. In <i>2011 International Conference on Remote Sensing, Environment and Transportation Engineering</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, S., Zou, Y., Gong, F., Yao, G., Yuan, J. &amp; Gong, T. Low-carbon demand response framework with participations of flexible loads. In <i>2022 IEEE 6th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, X. Analysis on low-carbon evaluation indexes of building. In <i>2011 International Conference on Electric Technology and Civil Engineering (ICETCE)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., Du, Y., Guo, L., Ma, C. &amp; Wang, B. Low carbon economic dispatch of integrated energy systems considering improved stepped carbon trading and flexible loads. In <i>2024 43rd Chinese Control Conference (CCC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou, G., Huang, J. &amp; Wu, C. Are consumers with low serving costs necessarily carbon friendly? In <i>2022 IEEE Sustainable Power and Energy Conference (iSPEC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L., Yu, J., Li, P., Chen, F. &amp; Zhang, T. The low carbon power dispatch strategy for generation traders considering the risks of carbon trading. In <i>2017 4th International Conference on Systems and Informatics (ICSAI)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiang, S., Wang, G., Min, Y. &amp; Su, P. Joint low-carbon economic dispatch of power system considering reward-penalty ladder carbon trading and demand response. In <i>2023 7th International Conference on Smart Grid and Smart Cities (ICSGSC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. and Zhang, L. Carbon finance development status and development strategy of our country under low-carbon economy. In <i>2011 Fourth International Joint Conference on Computational Sciences and Optimization</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, J. et al. Low-carbon planning of integrated energy system considering a reward and punishment ladder-type carbon trading mechanism. In <i>2022 IEEE 6th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, B. Research of management and construction of evaluation system of low-carbon enterprises. In <i>2011 IEEE 18th International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, G., Hongbin, Z., Kai, C. &amp; Zhaojuan. Life-cycle low carbon simulation of smart distribution network considering power loss. In <i>2018 2nd IEEE Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huabai, B., Shizhen, B. &amp; Huabai, B. The low carbon production level evaluation model of Pb-Zn enterprises based on fuzzy-AHP methods. In <i>2011 International Conference on E-Business and E-Government (ICEE)</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Zeng, G., Cheng, J.&amp; Fang, T. Content and path of low-carbon city construction based on city function subarea. In <i>2012 Fifth International Joint Conference on Computational Sciences and Optimization</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, C. &amp; Ro, J.W. Impact of recent U.S. renewable diesel production capacity growth on california&#x2019;s low carbon fuel standard. In <i>2025 IEEE Conference on Technologies for Sustainability (SusTech)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, F. et al. Study on low-carbon comprehensive benefits of grid-connected photovoltaic generation. In <i>2015 IEEE Power &amp; Energy Society General Meeting</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Low carbon evaluation method of transformer area considering carbon reduction potential in user side. In <i>2023 4th International Conference on Advanced Electrical and Energy Systems (AEES)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, W., Xu, C. &amp; Xiong, J. Low-carbon dispatching of regional power grid considering the constraints of carbon quota. In <i>2022 IEEE 6th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury, M., Tushi, T. H. &amp; Ilman, R. Stakeholder: a carbon footprint reduction assistance smartphone application with decarbonisation plan and carbon tracking features. In <i>2025 4th OPJU International Technology Conference (OTCON) on Smart Computing for Innovation and Advancement in Industry 5.0</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, G., He, W., Huo, Y. &amp; Yu, Y. Study on paths and potentialities of carbon emission reduction of power grid. In <i>2022 China International Conference on Electricity Distribution (CICED)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, L., He, W., Xu, L. &amp; Wang, L. Research hotspots and trends in green and low-carbon building management based on bibliometrics. In <i>2025 4th International Conference on Green Energy and Power Systems (ICGEPS)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Liu, B. &amp; Li, Z. Analysis of low carbon subsidies under different supply chain structures. In <i>2015 12th International Conference on Service Systems and Service Management (ICSSSM)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi, J., Chen, Z., Fan, S. &amp; Zhu, T. Distributed low-carbon economic dispatching for power systems with arbitrary directed communication topologies. In <i>2024 43rd Chinese Control Conference (CCC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, Y., Niu, C., Li, D. &amp; Wang, C. Low-carbon economic dispatch of distribution network with carbon capture power plant considering carbon trading. In <i>2022 IEEE/IAS Industrial and Commercial Power System Asia (I &amp;CPS Asia)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Z. The carbon-constrained EOQ model under the cap-and-trade regulation considering the consumers&#x2019; low-carbon awareness. In <i>2019 Chinese Control And Decision Conference (CCDC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, C. et al. Research on fine management path and digital platform of LCA carbon emissions in building structure life cycle based on low-carbon AIoT management system. In <i>2024 6th International Conference on Electrical, Control and Instrumentation Engineering (ICECIE)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, S., Cheng, J., Ni, M. &amp; Wang, B. Research on market clearing mechanism for multi-type generators considering carbon cost. In <i>2022 4th International Conference on Power and Energy Technology (ICPET)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. A study of low carbon operation model of manufacturing enterprises. In <i>MSIE 2011</i> 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, W., Xu, C. &amp; Xiong, J. Low-carbon dispatching of regional power grid considering the constraints of carbon quota. In <i>2022 IEEE 6th Conference on Energy Internet and Energy System Integration (EI2)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi, J., Chen, Z., Fan, S. &amp; Zhu, T. Distributed low-carbon economic dispatching for power systems with arbitrary directed communication topologies. In <i>2024 43rd Chinese Control Conference (CCC)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, Y., Niu, C., Li, D. &amp; Wang, C. Low-carbon economic dispatch of distribution network with carbon capture power plant considering carbon trading. In <i>2022 IEEE/IAS Industrial and Commercial Power System Asia (I &amp;CPS Asia)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, G., He, W., Huo, Y. &amp; Yu, Y. Study on paths and potentialities of carbon emission reduction of power grid. In <i>2022 China International Conference on Electricity Distribution (CICED)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>