<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41718587</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combining Non-Invasive Tests of Different Physiological Dimensions Leads to Better Estimation of Muscle Fiber Type Composition in Humans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003959</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Muscle fiber type composition is a sports performance determinant, but its use in sports practice is hampered by the invasive muscle biopsy. We aimed to determine the best non-invasive method or combination of such methods to estimate muscle fiber type composition. We hypothesized that methods measuring different fiber type-specific characteristics, i.e., metabolism, power, contractility and endurance, would complement each other.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty young, healthy and recreationally-to-competitively trained participants (20 men) underwent non-invasive tests and four muscle biopsies: two in the vastus lateralis and two in the gastrocnemius medialis. The average relative area occupied by type II fibers across the biopsies served as the criterion measure (multi-muscle FTarea%). On average, this was calculated based on the fiber type of ~5200 fibers and the cross-sectional area of ~1200 fibers per participant. Participants performed 30-m sprints, squat jumps, a Wingate with blood lactate measurements, isometric and isokinetic knee extensions, a maximal ramp incremental cycling exercise and underwent peripheral electrical stimulation of the quadriceps and a proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy scan to measure muscle carnosine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Multi-muscle FTarea% ranged from 21.2 to 60.1%. Many parameters were significantly associated with multi-muscle FTarea%, but post-Wingate blood lactate concentration showed the strongest correlation (r=0.67; p&lt;0.001). A multiple linear regression model with sex, post-Wingate blood lactate, peak knee extension torque at 300&#xb0;.s -1 scaled to upper leg lean mass, average vastus lateralis and soleus carnosine and singlet contraction time as predictors could explain 68% of the multi-muscle FTarea% variance, confirming our hypothesis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The proposed model which combines non-invasively measured parameters of metabolism, power and contractility can provide a reasonably accurate estimate of vastus lateralis and gastrocnemius medialis fiber type composition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van de Casteele</LastName><ForeName>Freek</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van der Meulen</LastName><ForeName>Lennert</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sablain</LastName><ForeName>Mattice</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Thienen</LastName><ForeName>Ruud</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lievens</LastName><ForeName>Eline</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2549-3369</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derave</LastName><ForeName>Wim</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GASTROCNEMIUS MEDIALIS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IMMUNOHISTOCHEMISTRY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MUSCLE BIOPSY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MYOSIN HEAVY CHAIN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VASTUS LATERALIS</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest and Funding Source: This study was funded by the Research Foundation Flanders (FWO 1S66923N). The authors declare that they have no competing interest. Acknowledgements: This study was funded by the Research Foundation Flanders (FWO 1S66923N). We thank all volunteers who participated in this demanding study. The authors also wish to thank Amanda Gon&#xe7;alvez from the VIB Bioimaging facility for her skilled technical assistance in obtaining the fluorescence microscope images. The contributions of Kim Van Vossel, Julie Hardeel, Jonas Vandecauter, Thibaux Van der Stede, Joeri Gerlo, Davy Spiessens, Febe Ameys, Fien Dujardin, Tadhg Schepers, Bjarne Vercammen, Bart Wouters, Anouk Van Kerrebroeck, Ruben De Saegher, Flore De Muynck, Lotte Hertveldt, Aiko Uyttenhove, Lena Van Heue, Manon Dumon, Bo Blanchaert and Jasper Bert in data collection and/or data analysis are greatly appreciated. Author contributions: FVDC, EL and WD designed the study. FVDC, LVDM, MS and RVT performed the experiments at Ghent University in Belgium. FVDC analysed the data and interpreted the data together with EL and WD. FVDC prepared the figures and drafted the manuscript. All authors critically revised the manuscript. All authors have read and approved the final version of the manuscript and agree to be accountable for all aspects of this work in ensuring that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work are appropriately investigated and resolved. All persons designated as authors qualify for authorship, and all those who qualify for authorship are listed. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no competing interest. The results of the study are presented clearly, honestly, and without fabrication, falsification, or inappropriate data manipulation. The results of the present study do not constitute endorsement by the American College of Sports Medicine. Data availability statement: The datasets used and/or analysed during the current study are available from the corresponding author (EL) on reasonable request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41718587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-01007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>