<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927607</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Probabilistic OPF and LFC of conventional with RES, energy storage and FACTS using DTBO.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43847-4</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Adhit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, NIT, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Dr. B. C. Roy Engineering College, Durgapur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dutta</LastName><ForeName>Susanta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Dr. B. C. Roy Engineering College, Durgapur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswas</LastName><ForeName>Soumen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Sanaka Educational Trust's Group of Institutions, Durgapur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName><ForeName>Anagha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, NIT, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghosh</LastName><ForeName>Siddhartha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, NIT, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banerjee</LastName><ForeName>Sudipta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science Engineering, Symbiosis Institute of Technology, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, India. sudiptab.iitism@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy storage (AEFC and</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FACTS (TCSC, TCPS and SVC) Driving Training Based Optimization (DTBO)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional order proportional integral derivative (FOPID)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Load Frequency Control (LFC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimal Power Flow (OPF)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy (wind and solar)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: In order to ascertain the accomplishment documented in the research report, the writers affirm that they have no specific communications or competing economic considerations. Ethical approval: The research article does not include a number of works that either author has created that deal with mortal fields or animals.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43847-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43847-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, N. &amp; Mitra, J. Reliability of power system with high wind penetration under frequency stability constraint. IEEE Trans. Power Syst. 33(1), 985&#x2013;994 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, N. &amp; Mitra, J. An analysis of the effects and dependency of wind power penetration on system frequency regulation. IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy 7(1), 354&#x2013;363 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunkitti, S., Siritaratiwat, A. &amp; Premrudeepreechacharn, S. Multi-objective optimal power flow problems based on slime mould algorithm. Sustainability 13(13), 7448 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M.&#xa0;Z., et al. Generation fuel cost and loss minimization using salp swarm algorithm based optimal power flow. In 2020 International Conference on Computer Communication and Informatics (ICCCI), 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layth, A. B., Murtadha, A. K. &amp; Jaleel, A. Solving optimal power flow problem using improved differential evolution algorithm. Int. J. Electr. Electron. Eng. Telecommun 11, 146&#x2013;155 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, A. et al. A high-performance crisscross search based grey wolf optimizer for solving optimal power flow problem. Energy 225, 120211 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-sattar, S.A., Kamel, S., Ebeed, M., &amp; Jurado, F. An improved version of salp swarm algorithm for solving optimal power flow problem. Soft Comput. 25, 4027&#x2013;4052 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, M. A. M., Hasanien, H.&#xa0;M., &amp; Al-Durra, A. Solving of optimal power flow problem including renewable energy resources using heap optimization algorithm. IEEE Access. 9, 35846&#x2013;35863 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avvari, R. K. &amp; Vinod Kumar, D. M. A new hybrid evolutionary algorithm for multi-objective optimal power flow in an integrated WE, PV, and PEV power system. Electric Power Syst. Res. 214, 108870 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubbareddy, M., Dwivedi, D., Murthy, G. V. K., &amp; Kotte, S.K. Optimal power flow solution with current injection model of generalized interline power flow controller using ameliorated ant lion optimization. Int. J. Electr. Comput. Eng. 13(1), 1060 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunkitti, S., Siritaratiwat, A., Premrudeepreechacharn, S., Chatthaworn, R., &amp; Watson, N. R. A hybrid DA-PSO optimization algorithm for multiobjective optimal power flow problems. Energies. 11(9), 2270 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamies, M., Elkasem, A.H.A., Hassan, M.H. &amp; Kamel, S. Enhancing frequency stability in diverse power systems with conventional and renewable energy sources based on an innovative LFC and controlled energy storage integration. J. Energy Storage 73, 108960 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen, M. A. M., Hasanien, H.M., Alsaleh, I., Alassaf, A., Zhang, M., &amp; Alateeq, A. Optimal power flow in power systems with renewable energy resources uncertainty including geothermal power plants. Ain Shams Eng. J. 16(12), 103784 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AM Shaheen, Zia Ullah, Mohammed H Qais, Hany M Hasanien, Kian J Chua, Marcos Tostado-V&#xe9;liz, Rania A Turky, Francisco Jurado, and Mohamed R Elkadeem. Solution of probabilistic optimal power flow incorporating renewable energy uncertainty using a novel circle search algorithm. Energies, 15(21):8303, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunkitti, S., Siritaratiwat, A. &amp; Premrudeepreechacharn, S. A many-objective marine predators algorithm for solving many-objective optimal power flow problem. Appl. Sci. 12(22), 11829 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunkitti, S., Premrudeepreechacharn, S. &amp; Siritaratiwat, A. A two-archive Harris Hawk optimization for solving many-objective optimal power flow problems. IEEE Access 11, 134557&#x2013;134574 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichitkrailat, K., Premrudeepreechacharn, S., Siritaratiwat, A., &amp; Khunkitti, S. Optimal sizing and locations of multiple besss in distribution systems using crayfish optimization algorithm. IEEE Access. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfi, H. Presenting a novel hybrid method for dynamic economic/emission dispatch considering renewable energy units and energy storage systems. Evol. Intel. 18(3), 63 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbari, H. &amp; Lotfi, H. A hybrid woa-gwo approach for multi-objective optimization of cost and water consumption in multi-area dynamic economic dispatch with renewable energy and energy storage integration. IET Gener. Transm. Distrib. 19(1), e70178 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossein Lotfi and Mohammad Hasan Nikkhah. Multi-objective profit-based unit commitment with renewable energy and energy storage units using a modified optimization method. Sustainability 16(4), 1708 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouda, P.K., Sahoo, A.K., &amp; Hota, P.K. Optimal power flow including unified power flow controller in a deregulated environment. Int. J. Appl. Eng. Res. 10(1), 505&#x2013;522 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, A.A., Kamel, S., Hassan, M.H., &amp; Ibrahim, A.A. Northern goshawk optimization algorithm for optimal power flow with facts devices in wind power integrated electrical networks. Electric Power Components Syst. 1&#x2013;23 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rambabu, M., Kumar, G.V.N., &amp; Sivanagaraju, S. Optimal power flow of integrated renewable energy system using a thyristor controlled seriescompensator and a grey-wolf algorithm. Energies. 12(11), 2215 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda, A., Tripathy, M., Barisal, A.K., &amp; Prakash, T. A modified bacteria foraging based optimal power flow framework for hydro-thermal-wind generation system in the presence of statcom. Energy. 124, 720&#x2013;740 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman, S., Li, J., Lei, W. &amp; Guvenc, U. Optimal power flow with stochastic wind power and facts devices: A modified hybrid psogsa with chaotic maps approach. Neural Comput. Appl. 32, 8463&#x2013;8492 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, P.P., Arora, P., Mallipeddi, R., Suganthan, P.N., &amp; Panigrahi, B.K. Optimal placement and sizing of facts devices for optimal power flow in a wind power integrated electrical network. Neural Comput. Appl. 33, 6753&#x2013;6774 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, P.P., Suganthan, P.N., Mallipeddi, R., &amp; Amaratunga, G.A.J. Optimal reactive power dispatch with uncertainties in load demand and renewable energy sources adopting scenario-based approach. Appl. Soft Comput. 75, 616&#x2013;632 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, S., Roy, P.K., &amp; Chatterjee, K. Facts-based 3dof-pid controller for LFC of renewable power system under deregulation using goa. IETE J. Res. 69(3), 1486&#x2013;1499 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y., Liu, G.-P. &amp; Wenshan, H. Priori-guided and data-driven hybrid model for wind power forecasting. ISA Trans. 134, 380&#x2013;395 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., He, Y. &amp; Yang, S. A multi-step probability density prediction model based on gaussian approximation of quantiles for offshore wind power. Renew. Energy 202, 992&#x2013;1011 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghamdi, A.S. Optimal power flow of renewable-integrated power systems using a gaussian bare-bones levy-flight firefly algorithm. Front. Energy Res. 10, 921936 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, M.A., Kamel, S., Hassan, M.H., Ahmed, E.M. &amp; Alanazi, M. Optimal power flow solution of power systems with renewable energy sources using white sharks algorithm. Sustainability. 14(10), 6049 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee, A., Dutta, S., Dey, S., Roy, P.K. &amp; Bhattacharya, A. Solving unit commitment problem incorporating integrated renewable energy, plug in electric vehicles and hydrogen energy storage using marine predators algorithm. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 198, 152732 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghaebrahimi, M.R., Golkhandan, R.K. &amp; Ahmadnia, S. Localization and sizing of facts devices for optimal power flow in a system consisting wind power using hbmo. In 2016 18th Mediterranean Electrotechnical Conference (MELECON), 1&#x2013;7 (IEEE, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad, D. &amp; Mukherjee, V. Solution of optimal reactive power dispatch by symbiotic organism search algorithm incorporating facts devices. IETE J. Res. 64(1), 149&#x2013;160 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi, E., Pourakbari-Kasmaei, M. &amp; Abdi, H. An efficient particle swarm optimization algorithm to solve optimal power flow problem integrated with facts devices. Appl. Soft Comput. 80, 243&#x2013;262 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya, B. &amp; Kumar, S. Loadability enhancement with facts devices using gravitational search algorithm. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 78, 470&#x2013;479 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana, A.S., Bajaj, M., &amp; Gairola, S. Optimal power flow solution in smart grid environment using SVC and TCSC. In Advanced Communication and Control Methods for Future Smartgrids, 1&#x2013;22 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, S., Paul, S., Sultana, S., Roy, P.K. &amp; Hazra, S. Contribution of facts devices in probabilistic optimal power flow of conventional, renewable energy sources and electric vehicle using quasi-oppositional artificial hummingbird algorithm. Optim. Control Appl. Methods. 46(6), 2534&#x2013;2563 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, A., Dutta, S., Bhattacharya, A., Biswas, S., &amp; Roy, P.K. LFC based OPF with renewable energy, BESS and FOPID controller using QODTBO algorithm. J. Energy Storage 115, 115782 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchekara, H. R. E. H., Abido, M. A., Chaib, A. E. &amp; Mehasni, R. Optimal power flow using the league championship algorithm: A case study of the Algerian power system. Energy Convers. Manag. 87, 58&#x2013;70 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani, M., Trojovsk&#xe1;, E. &amp; Trojovsk&#x1ef3;, P. A new human-based metaheuristic algorithm for solving optimization problems on the base of simulation of driving training process. Sci. Rep. 12(1), 9924 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, S., Dutta, S., Sarkar, T., Bhattacharya, A., Paul, C., &amp; Roy, P.K. Solving multi-objective probabilistic optimal power flow with renewable energy sources and battery energy storage in transmission networks using quasi oppositional sine cosine algorithm. J. Energy Storage. 122, 116411 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad, N.H., Ali, M.Z. &amp; Suganthan, P.N. Problem definitions and evaluation criteria for the CEC 2017 special session and competition on single objective real-parameter numerical optimization. National University of Defense Technology, Changsha, Hunan, PR China and Kyungpook National University, Daegu, South Korea and Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Technical Report (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derrac, J., Garc&#xed;a, S., Molina, D. &amp; Herrera, F. A practical tutorial on the use of nonparametric statistical tests as a methodology for comparing evolutionary and swarm intelligence algorithms. Swarm Evol. Comput. 1(1), 3&#x2013;18 (2011).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>