<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41664222</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-3305</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Parasites &amp; vectors</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Parasit Vectors</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intelligent identification of medical and veterinary intracellular protozoa by using self-supervised learning.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">98</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13071-026-07257-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Zoonotic diseases pose a major threat to both human and animal health, contributing significantly to global morbidity and mortality. Accurate diagnosis is crucial for effective control and treatment, with microscopic examination serving as the gold standard, supplemented by highly sensitive molecular biology techniques. However, these confirmatory methods require skilled personnel and are subject to inter- and intra-rater variability. An innovative solution lies in artificial intelligence (AI)-powered automated tools, which offer a promising alternative. This study aimed to develop a self-supervised learning (SSL) approach using the Distillation with No Labels (DiNOv2) algorithm to extract features of protozoa from Giemsa-stained blood samples.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The development of self-supervised learning algorithms, including DiNOv2, was based on archived samples of clinically significant and significant veterinary microorganisms. These models were evaluated in comparison to a baseline Vision Transformer (ViT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among the tested SSL models, the DiNOv2-Small version achieved exceptional performance, surpassing 99% accuracy and specificity while maintaining the lowest misclassification rate (0.263). It also demonstrated a high area under the curve (AUC) value of 0.990, underscoring its robust classification capability. Remarkably, even when trained on only 20% of the dataset, the SSL models retained performance levels comparable to baseline models trained on the full dataset. However, further reducing the sample size below 20% led to notable declines in evaluation metrics: accuracy dropped by 5-7%, recall decreased from 37.9% to 35.1%, precision fell from 35% to 25.2%, and the F1 score declined from 31.1% to 21.5%. Additionally, the AUC decreased by 4-11%, while the misclassification rate increased, indicating reduced robustness. A key limitation of this study was the highly imbalanced fine-tuned dataset between classes. Nevertheless, the inconsistent performance observed may be mitigated by employing the larger DiNOv2 model, which improves the F1 score and enhances the model's ability to handle imbalanced data while reducing reliance on labeled data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The proposed method can assist laboratory technicians, particularly in resource-limited healthcare settings. Furthermore, the findings support the potential deployment of this AI-based tool for automated screening in both medical and veterinary applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kittichai</LastName><ForeName>Veerayuth</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaewthamasorn</LastName><ForeName>Morakot</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence in Veterinary Parasitology, Faculty of Veterinary Science, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, 10330, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soiphet</LastName><ForeName>Naruchit</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Innovative Technology, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tongloy</LastName><ForeName>Teerawat</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Innovative Technology, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuwongin</LastName><ForeName>Santhad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Innovative Technology, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boonsang</LastName><ForeName>Siridech</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, School of Engineering, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand. siridech.bo@kmitl.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RE-KRIS/FF68/40</GrantID><Agency>King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang and National Science Research and Innovation Fund (NSRF)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Parasit Vectors</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101462774</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-3305</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data partition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopic examination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-supervised learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supervised learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zoonotic diseases</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: &#xa0;The protocols were reviewed and approved by the Faculty of Veterinary Science&#x2019;s Institutional Biosafety Committee and the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IBC No. 2031044; IACUC No. 2031098) Chulalongkorn University. In this study, we strictly adhered to the university&#x2019;s relevant guidelines and regulations. All procedures were carried out in accordance with the Animal Research: Reporting of In Vivo Experiments (ARRIVE) guidelines. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41664222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12937529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-026-07257-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13071-026-07257-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dyer O. African malaria deaths set to dwarf covid-19 fatalities as pandemic hits control efforts, WHO warns. BMJ. 2020;371:m4711. 10.1136/bmj.m4711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m4711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33268334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Jiang H, Jiang H, Xi H, Chen B, Liu Y, et&#xa0;al. Deep learning for microscopic examination of protozoan parasites. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2022;20:1036&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.csbj.2022.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csbj.2022.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35284048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasetsirikul S, Buranapong J, Srituravanich W, Kaewthamasorn M, Pimpin A. The development of malaria diagnostic techniques: a review of the approaches with focus on dielectrophoretic and magnetophoretic methods. Malar J. 2016;15:358. 10.1186/s12936-016-1400-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-016-1400-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4942956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27405995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnuphapprasert A, Nugraheni YR, Aung A, Asada M, Kaewthamasorn M. Detection of <i>Babesia</i><i>bovis</i> using loop-mediated isothermal amplification (LAMP) with improved thermostability, sensitivity and alternative visualization methods. Sci Rep. 2023;13:1838.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-29066-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36725982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen AHL, Tiawsirisup S, Kaewthamasorn M. Molecular detection and genetic characterization of <i>Anaplasma marginale</i> and <i>Anaplasma platys</i>-like (Rickettsiales: Anaplasmataceae) in water buffalo from eight provinces of Thailand. BMC Vet Res. 2020;16:380. 10.1186/s12917-020-02585-z.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-020-02585-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7542745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33032591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondim M, Dunaj-Ma&#x142;yszko J, Okrzeja J, Majewski P, Czupryna P, Pancewicz S, et al. Detection of Babesia and Theileria species in ticks from North-Eastern Poland. J Travel Med. 2023;30:taad071. 10.1093/jtm/taad071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jtm/taad071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37220879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X-P, Soong L. Emerging and re-emerging zoonoses are major and global challenges for public health. Zoonoses. 2021;1:999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15212/ZOONOSES-2021-0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G, Luo G, Lian H, Chen L, Wu W, Liu H. Application of deep learning in clinical settings for detecting and classifying malaria parasites in thin blood smears. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2023;10:ofad469. 10.1093/ofid/ofad469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofad469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10627339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37937045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Zhai Q, Liu J, Xu X, Hua J. A lightweight deep-learning model for parasite egg detection in microscopy images. Parasit Vectors. 2024;17:454. 10.1186/s13071-024-06503-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-024-06503-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11539555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39501374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiani LE, Filali SE, Benlahmer EH. Exploring Segment Anything Model applications for medical imaging. New York: IEEE; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J, Kalra S, Miri MS. Cluster-based histopathology phenotype representation learning by self-supervised multi-class-token hierarchical ViT. Sci Rep. 2024;14:3202. 10.1038/s41598-024-53361-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-53361-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10853503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kittichai V, Kaewthamasorn M, Chaiphongpachara T, Laojun S, Saiwichai T, Naing KM, et&#xa0;al. Enhance fashion classification of mosquito vector species via self-supervised vision transformer. Sci Rep. 2024;14:31517. 10.1038/s41598-024-83358-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-83358-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11682170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39733133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wessels F, Schmitt M, Krieghoff-Henning E, Nientiedt M, Waldbillig F, Neuberger M, et&#xa0;al. A self-supervised vision transformer to predict survival from histopathology in renal cell carcinoma. World J Urol. 2023;41:2233&#x2013;41. 10.1007/s00345-023-04489-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00345-023-04489-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10415487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37382622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim V, Adaloglou N, Osterland M, Morelli FM, Halawa M, Konig T, et&#xa0;al. Self-supervision advances morphological profiling by unlocking powerful image representations. Sci Rep. 2025;15:4876. 10.1038/s41598-025-88825-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-88825-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11811211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39929956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui B, Islam M, Bai L, Ren H. Surgical-DINO: adapter learning of foundation models for depth estimation in endoscopic surgery. Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg. 2024;19:1013&#x2013;20. 10.1007/s11548-024-03083-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11548-024-03083-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11178563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38459402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnuphapprasert A, Nugraheni YR, Khunmanee S, Kaewlamun W, Kaewthamasorn M. Seasonal dynamics and genetic characterization of bovine arthropod-borne parasites in Nan Province, Thailand with molecular identification of <i>Anaplasma platys</i> and <i>Trypanosoma theileri</i>. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis. 2024;107:102156. 10.1016/j.cimid.2024.102156.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cimid.2024.102156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen AHL, Tiawsirisup S, Kaewthamasorn M. Low level of genetic diversity and high occurrence of vector-borne protozoa in water buffaloes in Thailand based on 18S ribosomal RNA and mitochondrial cytochrome b genes. Infect Genet Evol. 2020;82:104304. 10.1016/j.meegid.2020.104304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2020.104304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Templeton TJ, Asada M, Jiratanh M, Ishikawa SA, Tiawsirisup S, Sivakumar T, et&#xa0;al. Ungulate malaria parasites. Sci Rep. 2016;6:23230. 10.1038/srep23230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep23230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4800408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26996979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kittichai V, Kaewthamasorn M, Arnuphaprasert A, Jomtarak R, Naing KM, Tongloy T, et&#xa0;al. A deep contrastive learning-based image retrieval system for automatic detection of infectious cattle diseases. J Big Data. 2025;12:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-024-01057-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirillov A, Mintun E, Ravi N, Mao H, Rolland C, Gustafson L, et&#xa0;al. Segment Anything. New York: IEEE; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Wang B. Segment Anything in medical images. Natural Communications. 2023. abs/2304.12306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intarapuk A, Bhumiratana A. Investigation of <i>Armigeres subalbatus</i>, a vector of zoonotic <i>Brugia pahangi</i> filariasis in plantation areas in Suratthani, Southern Thailand. One Health. 2021;13:100261. 10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100261.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.onehlt.2021.100261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8121957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutakanni T, Oquab M, Szafraniec M, Vakalopoulou M, Bojanowski P. You don&#x2019;t need domain-specific data augmentations when scaling self-supervised learning. Adv In Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;37:116106&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein R, Lee S, Ward R. Multi-Channel Vision Transformer for Epileptic Seizure Prediction. Biomedicines. 2022;10:1551. 10.3390/biomedicines10071551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10071551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9312955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Ding Y, Qiu RLJ, Wang T, Roper J, Fu Y, et al. Hippocampus substructure segmentation using morphological vision transformer learning. Phys Med Biol. 2023;68:235013. 10.1088/1361-6560/ad0d45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-6560/ad0d45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10690959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37972414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang J, Gorriz JM, Wang S. Deep Learning and Vision Transformer for Medical Image Analysis. J Imaging. 2023;9:147. 10.3390/jimaging9070147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging9070147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10381785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37504824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran MH, Ma L, Mubarak H, Gomez O, Yu J, Bryarly M, et&#xa0;al. Detection and margin assessment of thyroid carcinoma with microscopic hyperspectral imaging using transformer networks. J Biomed Opt. 2024;29:093505. 10.1117/1.JBO.29.9.093505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/1.JBO.29.9.093505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11268383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39050615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oquab M, Darcet T, Moutakanni T, Vo HQ, Szafraniec M, Khalidov V, et&#xa0;al. DINOv2: learning robust visual features without supervision. ArXiv. 2023. 10.48550/arXiv.2304.07193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2304.07193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z, Wang R, Ru D, Peng Z, Huang H, Zhao H, et&#xa0;al. Approximate random dropout for DNN training acceleration in GPGPU. New York: IEEE; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayebi Arasteh S, Misera L, Kather JN, Truhn D, Nebelung S. Enhancing diagnostic deep learning via self-supervised pretraining on large-scale, unlabeled non-medical images. Eur Radiol Exp. 2024;8:10. 10.1186/s41747-023-00411-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41747-023-00411-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10850044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38326501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathilde Caron, Hugo Touvron, Ishan Misra, Herv&#xe9; J&#xe9;gou, Julien Mairal, Piotr Bojanowski, et&#xa0;al. Emerging properties in self-supervised vision transformers. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Visio. 2021: 9650&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen M, Wenderoth L, Sentker T, Werner R. Self-supervision for medical image classification: state-of-the-art performance with ~100 labeled training samples per class. Bioengineering. 2023. 10.3390/bioengineering10080895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering10080895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10451977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37627780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doron M, Moutakanni T, Chen ZS, Moshkov N, Caron M, Touvron H, et&#xa0;al. Unbiased single-cell morphology with self-supervised vision transformers. bioRxiv. 2023. 10.1101/2023.06.16.545359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.06.16.545359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10312751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SC, Pareek A, Jensen M, Lungren MP, Yeung S, Chaudhari AS. Self-supervised learning for medical image classification: a systematic review and implementation guidelines. NPJ Digit Med. 2023;6:74. 10.1038/s41746-023-00811-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-023-00811-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10131505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37100953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>