<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41495147</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing creative writing through AI-powered co-creation with cognitive and emotional outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4407</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4407</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4407</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34416-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This research explored how generative artificial intelligence (AI) tools, specifically a writing assistant powered by large language models like ChatGPT, influence the development of creative writing (CW) skills in intermediate EFL learners, focusing on both cognitive and emotional aspects. The research included 92 male participants who were divided into three distinct groups: The High-AI Support Group, the Low-AI Support Group, and the Control Group (CG). Participants completed pretesting with some validated scales. After the pretest, the High-AI Support Group was provided with comprehensive AI-generated feedback, while the Low-AI Support Group received limited AI support, and the Control Group adhered to conventional writing instruction. After the treatment, posttests were given to all groups, and eight participants from each experimental group took part in interviews. Quantitative analyses revealed that both groups receiving AI support outperformed the Control Group, with the High-AI Support Group exhibiting the most significant enhancements. Qualitative insights revealed that students in the High-AI Support Group demonstrated increased engagement and creativity, attributed to tailored AI feedback that alleviated cognitive load by addressing technical aspects like grammatical accuracy. In contrast, members of the Low-AI Support Group appreciated the collaborative interaction between AI and instructor feedback, which enhanced their confidence, independence, and skills in grammar and writing conventions. In summary, this study emphasizes the importance of AI in enhancing both intellectual and emotional growth for EFL learners, advocating for its incorporation as a valuable resource in educational settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cen</LastName><ForeName>Xinqiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, NingBo University of Technology, Zhejiang, 315211, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shakibaei</LastName><ForeName>Goodarz</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-9804-4273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of English, Ahv. C. , Islamic Azad University, Ahvaz, Iran. goodarzshakibaei@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GH2025609</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Education Science planning project " Empowering Students' Language Learning in Special Education through AIGC"</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014956" MajorTopicYN="Y">Writing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003405" MajorTopicYN="Y">Creativity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="Y">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-powered co-creation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Creative writing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EFL learners</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional engagement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics statement: This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical standards of the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical approval was waived by institutional regulations, as the study involved anonymous, non-invasive educational research with voluntary participation. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to data collection. AI Use Statement: Generative artificial intelligence tools (ChatGPT and Grammarly) were used exclusively for linguistic and stylistic assistance, including improvinggrammar, clarity, coherence, and overall readability of the manuscript. These tools were not used for data collection, data analysis, interpretation of results,or the generation of scholarly content. All intellectual contributions, academic judgments, theoretical framing, methodological decisions, and interpretationsare entirely the responsibility of the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12864931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34416-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34416-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rezai, A., Namaziandost, E. &amp; Hwang, G. J. How can ChatGPT open promising avenues for L2 development? A phenomenological study involving EFL university students in Iran. <i>Computers Hum. Behav. Rep.</i><b>16</b>, 100510. 10.1016/j.chbr.2024.100510 (2024a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chbr.2024.100510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin-Hady, W. R. A., Al-Kadi, A., Hazaea, A. &amp; Ali, J. K. M. Exploring the dimensions of ChatGPT in english Language learning: A global perspective. <i>Libr. Hi Tech.</i><b>43</b> (4&#x2013;5), 1315&#x2013;1328. 10.1108/LHT-05-2023-0200 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/LHT-05-2023-0200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, L. Artificial intelligence in Language instruction: impact on english learning achievement, L2 motivation, and self-regulated learning. <i>Front. Psychol.</i><b>14</b>, Article 1261955. 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.12619 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38023040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkgoz, Y. Exploring poems to promote Language learners&#x2019; creative writing. <i>Procedia - Social Behav. Sciences</i>. <b>158</b>, 394&#x2013;401 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sbspro.2014.12.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maley, A. Creative writing for students and teachers. <i>Humanizing Lang. Teach.</i><b>14</b> (3), 1&#x2013;18 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memarian, B. &amp; Doleck, T. Fairness, accountability, transparency, and ethics (FATE) in artificial intelligence (AI), and higher education: A systematic review. <i>Computers Education: Artif. Intell.</i> 100152. 10.1016/j.caeai.2023.10015 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villegas-Ch, W. &amp; Garc&#xed;a-Ortiz, J. Toward a comprehensive framework for ensuring security and privacy in artificial intelligence. <i>Electronics</i><b>12</b> (18), 3786. 10.3390/electronics12183 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics12183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etikan, I., Musa, S. A. &amp; Alkassim, R. S. Comparison of convenience sampling and purposive sampling. <i>Am. J. Theoretical Appl. Stat.</i><b>5</b> (1), 1&#x2013;4. 10.11648/j.ajtas.20160501.11 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.ajtas.20160501.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlTwijri, L. &amp; Alghizzi, T. M. Investigating the integration of artificial intelligence in english as foreign Language classes for enhancing learners&#x2019; affective factors: A systematic review. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31053 (2024). Article e31053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11109823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38778968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarisayi, K. S. A theoretical framework for interrogating the integration of artificial intelligence in education. <i>Res. Educ. Media</i>. <b>16</b> (1), 38&#x2013;44. 10.2478/rem-2024-0006 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/rem-2024-0006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljabr, F. Gauging the Saudi EFL learners&#x2019; level of awareness and attitudes towards the use of ChatGPT. <i>Inform. Sci. Lett. (ISL)</i>. <b>12</b> (11), Article3100 (2023). https://digitalcommons.aaru.edu.jo/isl/vol12/iss11/20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vashishth, T. K. et al. AI-driven learning analytics for personalized feedback and assessment in higher education. In Using Traditional Design Methods To Enhance AI-driven Decision Making (206&#x2013;230). (IGI Global, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W. &amp; Ouyang, F. The application of AI technologies in STEM education: a systematic review from 2011 to 2021. <i>Int. J. STEM Educ.</i><b>9</b> (1). 10.1186/s40594-022-00377-5 (2022). Article 59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotton, D. R., Cotton, P. A. &amp; Shipway, J. R. Chatting and cheating: ensuring academic integrity in the era of ChatGPT. <i>Innovations Educ. Teach. Int.</i><b>61</b> (2), 228&#x2013;239. 10.1080/14703297.2023.2190148 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14703297.2023.2190148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pack, A. &amp; Maloney, J. Using artificial intelligence in TESOL: some ethical and pedagogical considerations. <i>TESOL Q.</i><b>58</b> (2), 1007&#x2013;1018. 10.1002/tesq.3320 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tesq.3320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vashishth, T. K. et al. AI-Driven Learning Analytics for Personalized Feedback and Assessment in Higher Education. In <i>Using Traditional Design Methods to Enhance AI-Driven Decision Making</i> (pp. 206&#x2013;230). IGI Global. (2024). 10.4018/979-8-3693-0639-0.ch009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezai, A., Soyoof, A. &amp; Reynolds, B. L. Disclosing the correlation between using ChatGPT and well-being in EFL learners: considering the mediating role of emotion regulation. <i>Eur. J. Educ.</i><b>59</b> (4). 10.1111/ejed.12752 (2024). Article e12752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keezhatta, M. S. Understanding EFL linguistic models through relationship between natural Language processing and artificial intelligence applications. <i>Arab. World Engl. J.</i><b>10</b> (4), 251&#x2013;262. 10.24093/awej/vol10no4 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24093/awej/vol10no4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baidoo-Anu, D. &amp; Ansah, L. O. Education in the era of generative artificial intelligence (AI): Understanding the potential benefits of ChatGPT in promoting teaching and learning. <i>J. AI</i>. <b>7</b> (1), 52&#x2013;62 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61969/jai.1337500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitria, T. N. Artificial intelligence (AI) technology in openai ChatGPT application: A review of ChatGPT in writing english essay. <i>ELT Forum: J. Engl. Lang. Teach.</i><b>12</b> (1), 44&#x2013;58 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenAI. <i>ChatGPT: Optimizing language models for dialogue</i> [Blog post]. Retrieved January 2, 2023, from (2023). https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohnke, L., Moorhouse, B. L. &amp; Zou, D. ChatGPT for Language teaching and learning. <i>RELC J.</i><b>54</b> (2), 537&#x2013;550. 10.1177/00336 (2023). 88223 11628 68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu, T. K., Moorhouse, B. L., Chai, C. S. &amp; Ismailov, M. Teacher support and student motivation to learn with artificial intelligence (AI) based chatbot. <i>Interact. Learn. Environ.</i><b>32</b> (7), 3240&#x2013;3256. 10.1080/10494820.2023.2172044 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10494820.2023.2172044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohnke, L. A pedagogical chatbot: A supplemental Language learning tool. <i>RELC J.</i><b>54</b> (3), 828&#x2013;838. 10.1177/00336882211067054 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00336882211067054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, H., Cheng, Y., Yang, J. &amp; Gao, S. AI-powered chatbot communication with customers: dialogic interactions, satisfaction, engagement, and customer behavior. <i>Comput. Hum. Behav.</i><b>134</b>, Article 107329. 10.1016/j.chb.2022.107329 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, A. Y., Lu, O. H. &amp; Yang, S. J. Effects of artificial Intelligence&#x2013;Enabled personalized recommendations on learners&#x2019; learning engagement, motivation, and outcomes in a flipped classroom. <i>Comput. Educ.</i><b>194</b>, Article 104684. 10.1016/j.compedu.2022.104684 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maley, A., Mukundan, J. &amp; Widodo, H. P. <i>Creative Writing. Poems and Short Stories for English Language Learning</i> (Lincom GmbH, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghasab, M. B. English as a foreign Language (EFL) secondary school students&#x2019; use of artificial intelligence (AI) tools for developing writing skills: unveiling practices and perceptions. <i>Cogent Educ.</i><b>12</b> (1). 10.1080/2331186X.2025.2505304 (2025). Article 2505304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, G. Language play, Language learning. <i>ELT J.</i><b>51</b> (3), 224&#x2013;231. 10.1093/elt/51.3.224 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/elt/51.3.224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper, L., Hillis, M., Kubokawa, J. M. &amp; McIlroy, T. Creative writing in Language teaching contexts 2: event report and reflection. <i>J. Literature Lang. Teach.</i><b>11</b> (1), 52&#x2013;60 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, X. An overview of the development of creative writing teaching and research in Mainland China (2009&#x2013;2020). <i>New. Writ.</i><b>19</b> (4), 430&#x2013;467. 10.1080/14790726.2021.1996859 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14790726.2021.1996859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbot, B., Tan, M., Randi, J., Santa-Donato, G. &amp; Grigorenko, E. L. Essential skills for creative writing: integrating multiple domain-specific perspectives. <i>Think. Skills Creativity</i>. <b>7</b> (3), 209&#x2013;223. 10.1016/j.tsc.2012.04.006 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsc.2012.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, X., Guo, K. &amp; Ng, D. T. K. Sudowrite: Co-writing creative stories with artificial intelligence. <i>RELC J.</i> 00336882241250109. 10.1177/00336882241250109 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ula&#x15f;, A. H., Kola&#xe7;, E., Yaman, B. &amp; Sevim, O. Assessing Turkish Language books used for the first and second echelon in primary education in terms OS principles of creative writing. <i>Procedia - Social Behav. Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 147&#x2013;152. 10.1016/j.sbspro.2010.12.128 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sbspro.2010.12.128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckhoff, A. &amp; Urbach, J. Understanding imaginative thinking during childhood: Sociocultural conceptions of creativity and imaginative thought. <i>Early Childhood Educ. J.</i><b>36</b>, 179&#x2013;185. 10.1007/s10643-008-0261-4 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10643-008-0261-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkins, K., Ivanova, K., Marshall, H., Bennett, L. &amp; Anderton, J. Stories and systems: exploring technological impact in complex systems through creative writing techniques. <i>Technol. Forecast. Soc. Chang.</i><b>209</b>, 123800. 10.1016/j.techfore.2024.123800 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2024.123800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabeer, A., Bhat, R. A., Antony, S. &amp; Tramboo, I. A. Enhancing creative writing skills in secondary school students through prompt engineering and artificial intelligence. <i>Forum Linguistic Stud.</i><b>7</b> (3), 800&#x2013;815. 10.30564/fls.v7i3.8511 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30564/fls.v7i3.8511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. T. &amp; Degol, J. Staying engaged: knowledge and research needs in student engagement. <i>Child. Dev. Perspect.</i><b>8</b> (3), 137&#x2013;143. 10.1111/cdep.12073 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdep.12073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27087833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weich, M., G&#xf6;llner, R. &amp; Stalder, B. E. Subject and time specificity of students&#x2019; cognitive, behavioral, and emotional engagement at school. <i>Learn. Individual Differences</i>. <b>114</b>, Article 102511. 10.1016/j.lindif.2024.102511 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archambault, I. et al. Examining the contribution of student anxiety and opposition-defiance to the internal dynamics of affective, cognitive, and behavioral engagement in math. <i>Learn. Instruction</i>. <b>79</b>, 101593. 10.1016/j.learninstruc.2022.101593 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.learninstruc.2022.101593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Eliyahu, A., Moore, D., Dorph, R. &amp; Schunn, C. D. Investigating the multidimensionality of engagement: Affective, behavioral, and cognitive engagement across science activities and contexts. <i>Contemp. Educ. Psychol.</i><b>53</b>, 87&#x2013;105. 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2018.01.002 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2018.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C Engels, M., Spilt, J., Denies, K. &amp; Verschueren, K. The role of affective teacher&#x2013;student relationships in adolescents&#x2019; school engagement and achievement trajectories. <i>Learn. Instruction</i>. <b>75</b> https://doi.org/10.1016/j. learninstruc.2021.101485 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredricks, J. A., Reschly, A. L. &amp; Christenson, S. L. Interventions for student engagement: Overview and state of the field. In J. A. Fredricks, A. L. Reschly, &amp; S. L. Christenson (Eds.), <i>Handbook of student engagement interventions (p. 1</i>&#x2013;<i>11)</i>. Elsevier. (2019). 10.1016/B978-0-12-813413-9.00001-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. Multidimensional structure and measurement invariance of school engagement. <i>J. Sch. Psychol.</i><b>89</b>, 20&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j. jsp.2021.09.001 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsp.2021.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34836574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond, M. &amp; Bedenlier, S. Facilitating student engagement through educational technology: towards a conceptual framework. <i>J. Interact. Media Educ.</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;14. 10.5334/jime.528 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/jime.528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svalberg, A. M. L. Engagement with language: interrogating a construct. <i>Lang. Aware.</i><b>18</b> (3&#x2013;4), 242&#x2013;258. 10.1080/09658410903197264 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09658410903197264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Artificial intelligence in education: A systematic literature review. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>252</b>, Article 124167. 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.124167 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, X., Teng, M. F., Zhang, L. J. &amp; Alamer, A. Exploring AI literacy and AI-induced emotions among Chinese university English language teachers: The partial least square structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM) approach. <i>International Journal of Applied Linguistics</i>. Advance online publication. (2025). 10.1111/ijal.12596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mystkowska-Wiertelak, A. Teachers&#x2019; accounts of learners&#x2019; engagement and disaffection in the Language classroom. <i>Lang. Learn. J.</i><b>50</b> (3), 393&#x2013;405. 10.1080/09571736.2020.1800067 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09571736.2020.1800067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercer, S. Language learner engagement: setting the scene. In Second Handbook of English Language Teaching (643&#x2013;660). (Springer International Publishing, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredricks, J. A., Blumenfeld, P. C. &amp; Paris, A. H. School engagement: potential of the concept, state of the evidence. <i>Rev. Educ. Res.</i><b>74</b> (1), 59&#x2013;109. 10.3102/00346543074001059 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/00346543074001059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiver, P., Al-Hoorie, A. H., Vitta, J. P. &amp; Wu, J. Engagement in Language learning: A systematic review of 20 years of research methods and definitions. <i>Lang. Teach. Res.</i><b>28</b> (1), 201&#x2013;230. 10.1177/13621688211001289 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13621688211001289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner, E. A., Kindermann, T. A. &amp; Furrer, C. A motivational perspective on engagement and disaffection: conceptualisation and assessment of children&#x2019;s behavioural and emotional participation in academic activities in the classroom. <i>Educ. Psychol. Meas.</i><b>69</b> (3), 493&#x2013;525 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0013164408323233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, Y. &amp; Hyland, F. Exploring learner engagement with written corrective feedback in a Chinese tertiary EFL classroom. <i>J. Second Lang. Writ.</i><b>30</b>, 31&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.jslw.2015.08.002 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jslw.2015.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, X. &amp; Lo, Y. Y. Content familiarity, task repetition and Chinese EFL learners&#x2019; engagement in second Language use. <i>Lang. Teach. Res.</i><b>21</b> (6), 681&#x2013;698. 10.1177/1362168816684368 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362168816684368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sari, F. M. Exploring english learners&#x2019; engagement and their roles in the online Language course. <i>J. Engl. Lang. Teach. Linguistics</i>. <b>5</b> (3), 349&#x2013;361. 10.21462/jeltl.v5i3.446 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21462/jeltl.v5i3.446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Wang, Y. Adopting online flipped teaching to improve learner engagement in an english for specific purposes (ESP) course in china: A mixed-methods study. <i>J. China Computer-Assisted Lang. Learn.</i><b>3</b> (2), 335&#x2013;361. 10.1515/jccall-2023-0001 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jccall-2023-0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Li, J. Using the flipped classroom to promote learner engagement for the sustainable development of Language skills: A mixed-methods study. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b> (10), 5983. 10.3390/su14105983 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14105983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C., Hu, W. &amp; Wei, X. From anxiety to action: exploring the impact of artificial intelligence anxiety and artificial intelligence self-efficacy on motivated learning of undergraduate students. <i>Interact. Learn. Environ.</i><b>33</b> (4), 3162&#x2013;3177. 10.1080/10494820.2024.2440877 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10494820.2024.2440877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patac, L. P. &amp; Patac, A. V. Jr Using ChatGPT for academic support: managing cognitive load and enhancing learning efficiency&#x2013;A phenomenological approach. <i>Social Sci. Humanit. Open.</i><b>11</b>, Article 101301. 10.1016/j.ssaho.2025.101301 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, R. Z. <i>Cognitive Load Measurement and Application</i> (Routledge, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweller, J. The role of independent measures of load in cognitive load theory. In (ed Zheng, R. Z.) Cognitive Load Measurement and Application: A Theoretical Framework for Meaningful Research and Practice (3&#x2013;8). Routledge. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates, T., Cobo, C., Mari&#xf1;o, O. &amp; Wheeler, S. Can artificial intelligence transform higher education? <i>Int. J. Educational Technol. High. Educ.</i><b>17</b> (1). 10.1186/s41239-020-00218-1 (2020). Article 42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demartini, C. &amp; Benussi, L. Do web 4.0 and industry 4.0 imply education X.0? <i>IT Prof.</i><b>19</b> (3), 4&#x2013;7. 10.1109/MITP.2017.47 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MITP.2017.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweller, J. Cognitive load theory and educational technology. <i>Education Tech. Research Dev.</i><b>68</b> (1), 1&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s11423-019-09701-3 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11423-019-09701-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschner, F., Kester, L. &amp; Corbalan, G. Cognitive load theory and multimedia learning, task characteristics and learning engagement: the current state of the Art. <i>Comput. Hum. Behav.</i><b>27</b> (1), 1&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.chb.2010.05.003 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2010.05.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albers, F., Trypke, M., Stebner, F., Wirth, J. &amp; Plass, J. L. Different types of redundancy and their effect on learning and cognitive load. <i>Br. J. Educ. Psychol.</i><b>93</b>, 339&#x2013;352. 10.1111/bjep.12592 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjep.12592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36775258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschner, P. A. &amp; Hendrick, C. <i>How Learning Happens: Seminal Works in Educational Psychology and What They Mean in Practice</i> (Routledge, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baddeley, A. Working memory. In <i>Memory</i> (3rd ed., p. 41). Routledge. (2020). 10.4324/97804294496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacmaz, G. <i>Leveraging technology and pedagogy: A multi-study examination of technology, pedagogy and teacher factors in game-based learning environments</i> (Doctoral dissertation, McGill University, Canada). McGill University. (2023). Retrieved from https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dv93d</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plass, J. L. &amp; Kalyuga, S. Four ways of considering emotion in cognitive load theory. <i>Educational Psychol. Rev.</i><b>31</b> (2), 339&#x2013;359. 10.1007/s10648-019-09488-4 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10648-019-09488-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Nooijen, C. C. et al. A cognitive load theory approach to Understanding expert scaffolding of visual problem-solving tasks: A scoping review. <i>Educational Psychol. Rev.</i><b>36</b> (1), 12. 10.1007/s10648-024-09898-1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10648-024-09898-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, A. Developing an AI-based psychometric system for assessing learning difficulties and adaptive system to overcome: A qualitative and conceptual framework. <i>arXiv preprint</i> arXiv:2403.06284. (2024). https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.06284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burr, C. &amp; Leslie, D. Ethical assurance: a practical approach to the responsible design, development, and deployment of data-driven technologies. <i>AI Ethics</i>. <b>3</b> (1), 73&#x2013;98. 10.1007/s43681-022-00178-0 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43681-022-00178-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Gould, T. &amp; Zaki, R. The impact of artificial intelligence on learners and teachers: A mathematics education perspective. In (eds Papadakis, S. &amp; Kalogiannakis, M.) Education, Development and Intervention. <b>23</b>. (Springer. 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, L., Liu, D., Jiang, T. &amp; Xian, Y. The effectiveness of AI on K-12 students&#x2019; mathematics learning: A systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Int. J. Sci. Math. Educ.</i><b>23</b> (4), 1105&#x2013;1126. 10.1007/s10763-024-10499-7 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10763-024-10499-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiver, P., Zhou, S. A., Tahmouresi, S., Sang, Y. &amp; Papi, M. Why stories matter: exploring learner engagement and metacognition through narratives of the L2 learning experience. <i>System</i><b>91</b>, 102260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j. system.2020.102260 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.system.2020.102260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer, J. <i>Creativity and Divergent Thinking: A task-specific Approach</i> (Psychology, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman, J. C. &amp; Baer, J. The amusement park theoretical (APT) model of creativity. <i>Korean J. Think. Problem Solving</i>. <b>14</b>, 15&#x2013;25 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paas, F. G. W. Training strategies for attaining transfer of problem-solving skill in statistics: a cognitive load approach. <i>J. Educ. Psychol.</i><b>84</b> (4), 429&#x2013;434 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.84.4.429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweller, J. Cognitive load during problem solving: effects on learning. <i>Cogn. Sci.</i><b>12</b> (2), 257&#x2013;285. 10.1207/s15516709cog1202_4 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15516709cog1202_4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell, J. W. &amp; Poth, C. N. <i>Qualitative Inquiry and Research Design: Choosing among Five Approaches</i> (Sage, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xf6;rnyei, Z. <i>Research Methods in Applied Linguistics</i> (Oxford University Press, 2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keselman, H. J., Huberty, C. J., Lix, L. M., Olejnik, S., Cribbie, R. A., Donahue,B., &#x2026; Levin, J. R. (1998). Statistical practices of educational researchers: An analysis of their ANOVA, MANOVA, and ANCOVA analyses. Review of Educational Research, 68(3), 350&#x2013;386. https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543068003350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V. &amp; Clarke, V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. <i>Qualitative Res. Psychol.</i><b>3</b> (2), 77&#x2013;101. 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor, C. &amp; Joffe, H. Intercoder reliability in qualitative research: debates and practical guidelines. <i>Int. J. Qualitative Methods</i>. <b>19</b>, 1609406919899220. 10.1177/1609406919899220 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406919899220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahapatra, S. Impact of ChatGPT on ESL students&#x2019; academic writing skills: A mixed methods intervention study. <i>Smart Learn. Environ.</i><b>11</b> (1). 10.1186/s40561-024-00295-9 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiboolyasarin, W., Wiboolyasarin, K., Suwanwihok, K., Jinowat, N. &amp; Muenjanchoey, R. Synergizing collaborative writing and AI feedback: an investigation into enhancing L2 writing proficiency in wiki-based environments. <i>Computers Education: Artif. Intell.</i><b>6</b>, Article 100228. 10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100228 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivcevic, Z. &amp; Grandinetti, M. Artificial intelligence as a tool for creativity. <i>J. Creativity</i>. <b>34</b> (2). 10.1016/j.yjoc.2024.100079 (2024). Article 100079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polakova, P. &amp; Ivenz, P. The impact of ChatGPT feedback on the development of EFL students&#x2019; writing skills. <i>Cogent Educ.</i><b>11</b> (1), 2410101. 10.1080/2331186x.2024.2410101 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2331186x.2024.2410101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, K. &amp; Wang, D. To resist it or to embrace it? Examining chatgpt&#x2019;s potential to support teacher feedback in EFL writing. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>29</b> (7), 8435&#x2013;8463. 10.1007/s10639-023-12146-0 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-023-12146-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, A. M., Shaaban, T. S., Bakry, S. H., Guill&#xe9;n-G&#xe1;mez, F. D. &amp; Strzelecki, A. Empowering the faculty of education students: applying ai&#x2019;s potential for motivating and enhancing learning. <i>Innov. High. Educ.</i><b>50</b> (2), 587&#x2013;609. 10.1007/s10755-024-09747-z (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10755-024-09747-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vygotsky, L. S. &amp; Cole, M. <i>Mind in Society: Development of Higher Psychological Processes</i> (Harvard University Press, 1978).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, R., Jiang, M., Yu, X., Lu, Y. &amp; Liu, S. Does ChatGPT enhance student learning? A systematic review and meta-analysis of experimental studies. <i>Comput. Educ.</i><b>227</b>, 105224. 10.1016/j.compedu.2024.105224 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compedu.2024.105224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karata&#x15f;, F., Abedi, F. Y., Gunyel, F. O., Karadeniz, D. &amp; Kuzgun, Y. Incorporating AI in foreign Language education: an investigation into chatgpt&#x2019;s effect on foreign Language learners. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>29</b> (15), 19343&#x2013;19366. 10.1007/s10639-024-12574-6 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-024-12574-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, S., Chen, P. &amp; Zhang, G. Exploring the impact of the use of ChatGPT on foreign Language self-efficacy among Chinese students studying abroad: the mediating role of foreign Language enjoyment. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b> (21), e39845. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e39845 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e39845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11550636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39524751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, J. &amp; Daniel, B. K. Transforming Language education: A systematic review of AI-powered chatbots for english as a foreign Language speaking practice. <i>Computers Educ. Artif. Intell.</i><b>6</b>, 100230. 10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100230 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugroho, A., Putro, N. H. P. S. &amp; Syamsi, K. The potentials of ChatGPT for Language learning: unpacking its benefits and limitations. <i>Register J.</i><b>16</b> (2), 224&#x2013;247. 10.18326/register.v16i2.224-247 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18326/register.v16i2.224-247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawas, S. ChatGPT: empowering lifelong learning in the digital age of higher education. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>29</b> (6), 6895&#x2013;6908. 10.1007/s10639-023-12114-8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-023-12114-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafazoli, D. Exploring the potential of generative AI in democratizing english Language education. <i>Computers Educ. Artif. Intell.</i><b>7</b>, 100275. 10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100275 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlGhamdi, R. Exploring the impact of ChatGPT-generated feedback on technical writing skills of computing students: a blinded study. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>29</b>, 18901&#x2013;18926. 10.1007/s10639-024-12594-2 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-024-12594-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, C. &amp; Song, Y. Enhancing academic writing skills and motivation: assessing the efficacy of ChatGPT in AI-assisted Language learning for EFL students. <i>Front. Psychol.</i><b>14</b>, 1260843. 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1260843 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1260843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10754989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38162975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi, M., Ebadi, S. &amp; Mohammadi, L. The impact of integrating ChatGPT with teachers&#x2019; feedback on EFL writing skills. <i>Think. Skills Creativity</i>. <b>51</b>, 101766. 10.1016/j.tsc.2025.101766 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsc.2025.101766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci, E. L. &amp; Ryan, R. M. <i>Intrinsic Motivation and self-determination in Human Behavior</i> (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattie, J. &amp; Timperley, H. The power of feedback. <i>Rev. Educ. Res.</i><b>77</b> (1), 81&#x2013;112. 10.3102/003465430298487 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/003465430298487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi, M., Ebadi, S. &amp; Mohammadi, L. The impact of integrating ChatGPT with teachers&#x2019; feedback on EFL writing skills. <i>Think. Skills Creativity</i>. <b>56</b>, 101766&#x2013;101766. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tsc.2025.101766&#x200c; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. Learner emotions in AI-assisted english as a second/foreign Language learning: a systematic review of empirical studies. <i>Front. Psychol.</i><b>16</b>, Article 1652806. 10.3389/feduc.2025.1624272 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12529940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41112531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W., Hew, K. F. &amp; Fryer, L. K. Chatbots for Language learning - are they really useful? A systematic review of chatbot-supported Language learning. <i>J. Comput. Assist. Learn.</i><b>38</b> (1), 237&#x2013;257. 10.1111/jcal.12610 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcal.12610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J., Yu, S., Detrick, R. &amp; Li, N. Exploring students&#x2019; perspectives on generative AI-assisted academic writing. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>30</b> (1), 1265&#x2013;1300. 10.1007/s10639-024-12878-7 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-024-12878-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, D. Impact of ChatGPT on learners in a L2 writing practicum: an exploratory investigation. <i>Educ. Inform. Technol.</i><b>28</b> (11), 13943&#x2013;13967. 10.1007/s10639-023-11742-4 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-023-11742-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little, D. Language learner autonomy: some fundamental considerations revisited. <i>Innov. Lang. Learn. Teach.</i><b>1</b> (1), 14&#x2013;29. 10.2167/illt040.0 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2167/illt040.0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>