<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41415901</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2632-3524</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Palliative care and social practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Palliat Care Soc Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Community engagement in public health palliative care: A comparative ethnographic study of two culturally distinct compassionate communities in Canada.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26323524251400806</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26323524251400806</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26323524251400806</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/26323524251400806</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Compassionate communities are part of an international public health movement aiming to address social determinants of death by fostering supportive environments. Yet, empirical research on community engagement in this field is still limited, particularly the influence of local contexts on engagement patterns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to identify effective engagement practices and contextual factors influencing the development and sustainability of compassionate communities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A comparative ethnographic method was used to examine community engagement processes in two culturally distinct compassionate communities in Montr&#xe9;al (Canada): Centre-Sud and West Island. Data collection included participant observation, semistructured interviews, and logbooks. Informed by developmental evaluation, the analysis was guided by a thematic lens approach and the Ecology of Engagement framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Two distinct, context-sensitive paths to community engagement emerged, shaped by the sociocultural realities of each setting. In Centre-Sud, a grassroots, community-led approach focused on shared leadership and building trust fostered a resilient network that achieved sustainability through the creation of an independent nonprofit organization. In contrast, West Island's institutionally led strategy was a pragmatic response to navigate contextual barriers like preexisting community distrust, achieving sustainability by embedding the initiative within the lead organization via a permanent staff role.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This comparative ethnography demonstrates that success is not defined by a single model but by adapting engagement strategies to local dynamics of trust and power. It highlights that while community-led approaches can foster deep ownership, institutionally led strategies can provide a crucial pathway to sustainability in contexts facing systemic barriers. The study offers a practical framework for practitioners and key lessons for developing evidence-based policy to support compassionate communities in diverse settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lessard</LastName><ForeName>&#xc9;milie</ForeName><Initials>&#xc9;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9040-5797</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychology, Faculty of Social and Political Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcoux</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1652-0150</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Science, University of Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daneault</LastName><ForeName>Serge</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Emergency Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre de recherche de l'Institut universitaire de g&#xe9;riatrie de Montr&#xe9;al (CRIUGM), QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jean</LastName><ForeName>Lise</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Communaut&#xe9; Compatissante Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapointe</LastName><ForeName>Cynthia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montreal Institute for Palliative Care, Teresa Dellar Palliative Care Residence, Kirkland, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weil</LastName><ForeName>Dale</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montreal Institute for Palliative Care, Teresa Dellar Palliative Care Residence, Kirkland, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rouly</LastName><ForeName>Ghislaine</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canada Research Chair in Partnership with Patients and Communities, Centre de recherche du centre hospitalier de l'Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al (CRCHUM), QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sallnow</LastName><ForeName>Libby</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marie Curie Palliative Care Research Department, University College London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kellehear</LastName><ForeName>Allan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-5399-4075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Social Work, Education and Community Wellbeing, Northumbria University, Newcastle, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boivin</LastName><ForeName>Antoine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Emergency Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canada Research Chair in Partnership with Patients and Communities, Centre de recherche du centre hospitalier de l'Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al (CRCHUM), QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Palliat Care Soc Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101754997</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2632-3524</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Developing compassionate communities: Lessons from two different Montr&#xe9;al neighborhoods Developing &#x2018;compassionate communities&#x2019;&#x2014;local networks that support people through serious illness, grief, and the end of life&#x2014;is a shared effort. This research explored the most effective ways to engage communities in this work by comparing two distinct Montr&#xe9;al neighborhoods: the downtown Centre-Sud area and the suburban West Island. We found that there&#x2019;s no single recipe for success. In the downtown Centre-Sud area, community groups took the lead, building a strong, trusted network that eventually became its own non-profit organization to ensure sustainability. In the suburban West Island, a local palliative care residence guided the process, creating a permanent staff role to secure a lasting impact. The key lesson is that the best approach depends on a community&#x2019;s unique character and history. Success comes from adapting the strategy to fit the local reality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community engagement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comparative study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compassionate communities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethnography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">public health palliative care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41415901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12708986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26323524251400806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_26323524251400806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abel J, Kellehear A. (eds). Oxford textbook of public health palliative care. Oxford University Press, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallnow L, Smith R, Ahmedzai SH, et al. Report of the Lancet Commission on the Value of Death: bringing death back into life. Lancet 2022; 399(10327): 837&#x2013;884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35114146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumont K, Marcoux I, Warren &#xc9;, et al. How compassionate communities are implemented and evaluated in practice: a scoping review. BMC Palliat Care 2022; 21: 131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9297657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35854292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Eer L, Quintiens B, Van den Block L, et al. Civic engagement in serious illness, death, and loss: a systematic mixed-methods review. Palliat Med 2022; 36: 625&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11910752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35287517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintiens B, D&#x2019;Eer L, Deliens L, et al. Area-based compassionate communities: a systematic integrative review of existing initiatives worldwide. Palliat Med 2022; 36: 422&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lessard &#xc9;, Marcoux I, Daneault S, et al. How does community engagement evolve in different compassionate community contexts? A longitudinal comparative ethnographic research protocol. Palliat Care Soc Pract 2023; 17: 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patton MQ. Developmental evaluation: applying complexity concepts to enhance innovation and use. Guilford Press, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien BC, Harris IB, Beckman TJ, et al. Standards for reporting qualitative research: a synthesis of recommendations. Acad Med 2014; 89(9): 1245&#x2013;1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geertz C. The interpretation of cultures: selected essays. Basic Books, 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spradley JP. The ethnographic interview. Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lett J. Emics and etics: notes on the epistemology of anthropology. In: Emics and etics: the insider/outsider debate. Sage Publications, 1990, pp. 127&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson RM, Fretz RI, Shaw LL. Writing ethnographic fieldnotes. University of Chicago Press, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramson CM, Gong N. (eds). Beyond the case: the logics and practices of comparative ethnography. Oxford University Press, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin A, Dumez V, Castonguay G, et al. The ecology of engagement: fostering cooperative efforts in health with patients and communities. Health Expect 2022; 25: 2314&#x2013;2327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9615077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35923116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pallium Canada, BC Centre for Palliative Care and Hospice Palliative Care Ontario. Compassionate community evaluation guide, https://www.pallium.ca/resource/compassionate-communities-evaluation-guide/ (2023, accessed 18 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGloma T, Papadantonakis M. The thematic lens: a formal and cultural framework for comparative ethnographic analysis. In: Abramson CM, Gong N. (eds) Beyond the case: the logics and practices of comparative ethnography. Global and Comparative Ethnography. Oxford Academic, 2020, pp. 187&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerubavel E. Generally speaking: the logic and mechanics of social pattern analysis. Sociol Forum 2007; 22(2): 131&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pallium Canada. Compassionate communities sustainability guide, https://www.pallium.ca/resource/compassionate-communities-sustainability-guide/ (2022, accessed 17 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christou PA. How to use artificial intelligence (AI) as a resource, methodological and analysis tool in qualitative research? Qual Rep 2023; 28(7): 1968&#x2013;1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang JA, Wade K, Fiesler C, et al. Supporting serendipity: opportunities and challenges for human-AI collaboration in qualitative analysis. Proc ACM Hum Comput Interact 2021; 5(CSCW1): 1&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rane N, Choudhary S, Rane J. Gemini versus ChatGPT: applications, performance, architecture, capabilities, and implementation. performance, architecture, capabilities, and implementation. J Appl Artif Intell 2024; 5(1): 69&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Office qu&#xe9;b&#xe9;cois de la langue fran&#xe7;aise (OQLF). https://www.oqlf.gouv.qc.ca/ (n.d., accessed 13 December 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
City of Montr&#xe9;al. Montr&#xe9;al in statistics, https://ville.montreal.qc.ca/pls/portal/docs/PAGE/MTL_STATS_FR/MEDIA/DOCUMENTS/CARTE_POPULATION%20ET%20SUPERFICIE%202021.PDF (2022, accessed 16 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Corporation du d&#xe9;veloppement communautaire (CDC) Centre-Sud. Recensement 2021: Portrait du quartier, https://cdccentresud.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/CDCCS_portrait-quartier_2021_LettreUS-VF-avec-compression_1.pdf (2023, accessed 16 September 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKnight JL, Russell C. The four essential elements of an asset-based community development process. What is distinctive about asset-based community processes? Asset-Based Community Development Institute, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros P, Shetty J, Lamaj L, et al. Reported community engagement in health equity research published in high-impact medical journals: a scoping review. BMJ Open 2024; 14(8): e084952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11331902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39134436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo F, Barsanti S, Bonciani M, et al. Managing community engagement initiatives in health and social care: lessons learned from Italy and the United Kingdom. Health Care Manage Rev 2023; 48(1): 2&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9704808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36413650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong T, Ristevski E, Carroll M. Exploring community engagement in place-based approaches in areas of poor health and disadvantage: a scoping review. Health Place 2023; 81: 103026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37084705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malpass A, Le Poidevin A, Bamford A, et al. From trusted intruder to real collaborator: mapping the ecosystem of stakeholders and community assets in a coastal region in England, with a focus on end-of-life care and bereavement support. Soc Sci Med 2025; 365: 117555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39642586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcllveen JM, MacPhail C, Fox M, et al. Caring toward end of life through acute hospital and community partnerships: a scoping review. Palliat Med 2025; 39(3): 346&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11877981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39953768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Donder L, Stegen H, Hoens S. Caring neighbourhoods in Belgium: lessons learned on the development, implementation and evaluation of 35 caring neighbourhood projects. Palliat Care Soc Pract 2024; 18: 26323524241246533. doi:10.1177/26323524241246533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11055489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38682084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abel J, Kellehear A, Karapliagou A. Palliative care&#x2014;the new essentials. Ann Palliat Med 2018; 7(Suppl 2): S3&#x2013;S14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe4;sman M, Nyqvist F, Nyg&#xe5;rd M, et al. Multidimensional civic engagement in later life in 32 European countries-an exploration of the roles of socio-structural resources and welfare state commitment. Res Aging 2025; 47: 1&#x2013;14. doi:10.1177/01640275241285272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12705882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40498958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>