<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41539692</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1447-0756</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of obstetrics and gynaecology research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Obstet Gynaecol Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Novel Nomogram for Predicting Endometrial Malignancy in Postmenopausal Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70182</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70182</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jog.70182</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify clinical risk factors for endometrial malignancy in postmenopausal women and develop a predictive model for early detection and personalized intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study analyzed 1146 postmenopausal women undergoing diagnostic hysteroscopy. Inclusion required: confirmed menopause (age&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;40) with recent endometrial thickness measurement, successful hysteroscopy, histopathological verification, and complete records. Exclusions involved incomplete data, type II carcinoma, hormonally active tumors, or prior hysteroscopy indications. Demographics, clinical features, comorbidities, imaging data, and biomarkers were analyzed. Histology was confirmed via standard pathology. Risk factors were identified through univariate and multivariate logistic regression. The resultant predictive nomogram for endometrial malignancy risk stratification underwent rigorous validation using: (1) receiver operating characteristic curve analysis (discriminative power); (2) calibration plotting (prediction accuracy); and (3) decision curve analysis (clinical net benefit).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 1146 postmenopausal women undergoing diagnostic hysteroscopy, histopathological analysis identified 69 cases (6.0%) of endometrial carcinoma (EC) and 15 cases (1.3%) of atypical endometrial hyperplasia, with the remaining cases (92.7%) demonstrating benign pathology. Multivariate analysis identified seven independent risk factors for EC: elevated fibrinogen and D-dimer levels, hypertriglyceridemia, decreased high-density lipoprotein, postmenopausal bleeding, ultrasonography blood-flow signals, and increased endometrial thickness. The predictive nomogram incorporating these parameters demonstrated outstanding diagnostic performance, with area under the curve values of 0.955 in the training cohort and 0.960 in the validation cohort, indicating excellent discriminative ability for EC risk stratification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We developed and validated a novel 7-indicator prediction model for assessing endometrial malignancy risk in postmenopausal women undergoing hysteroscopy biopsy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Japan Society of Obstetrics and Gynecology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Hongrong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Beijing Daxing District People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ai</LastName><ForeName>Fangfang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Peilin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Beijing Daxing District People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Beijing Daxing District People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Beijing Daxing District People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Liane</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shijun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-0570-6034</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Obstet Gynaecol Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9612761</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1341-8076</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endometrial Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049451" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nomograms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postmenopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015907" MajorTopicYN="N">Hysteroscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004714" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endometrial Hyperplasia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endometrial malignancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postmenopausal</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41539692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jog.70182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>C. Xia, X. Dong, H. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cancer Statistics in China and United States, 2022: Profiles, Trends, and Determinants,&#x201d; Chinese Medical Journal 135, no. 5 (2022): 584&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ai, Y. Wang, L. Zhou, and S. Wang, &#x201c;Clinicopathologic Characteristics and Risk Factors for Endometrial Malignancy in Postmenopausal Women With Endometrial Thickening,&#x201d; Menopause 29, no. 2 (2022): 137&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ai, Y. Wang, Y. Wang, J. Wang, L. Zhou, and S. Wang, &#x201c;Clinicopathological Features of Endometrial Lesions in Asymptomatic Postmenopausal Women With Thickened Endometrium,&#x201d; Menopause 29, no. 8 (2022): 952&#x2013;956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Hippisley&#x2010;Cox, &#x201c;Prediction Models for Endometrial Cancer for the General Population or Symptomatic Women,&#x201d; Critical Reviews in Oncology/Hematology 150 (2020): 102712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Sung, J. Ferlay, R. L. Siegel, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Cancer Statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 71, no. 3 (2021): 209&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Forte, S. C. Cecere, M. Di Napoli, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Endometrial Cancer in the Elderly: Characteristics, Prognostic and Risk Factors, and Treatment Options,&#x201d; Critical Reviews in Oncology/Hematology 204 (2024): 104533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Benito, A. Lubrano, M. And&#xfa;jar, M. Mori, and M. Federico, &#x201c;Management of Endometrial Cancer in Patients Aged 80&#x2009;Years and Older: Identifying Patients Who May Benefit From a Curative Treatment,&#x201d; European Journal of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Biology 242 (2019): 36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Matsumoto, K. Yamaguchi, M. Maruyama, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Characteristic Hysteroscopy Appearance Considerations for Detecting Uterine Endometrial Malignancies,&#x201d; Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology Research 50, no. 4 (2024): 566&#x2013;571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Harika, M. Subbaiah, and D. K. Maurya, &#x201c;Diagnostic Accuracy of Hysteroscopic Scoring System in Predicting Endometrial Malignancy and Atypical Endometrial Hyperplasia,&#x201d; Journal of Mid&#x2010;Life Health 12, no. 3 (2021): 206&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACOG Committee Opinion No. 734 Summary: The Role of Transvaginal Ultrasonography in Evaluating the Endometrium of Women With Postmenopausal Bleeding,&#x201d; Obstetrics and Gynecology 131, no. 5 (2018): 945&#x2013;946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wolfman, O. Bougie, I. Chen, Y. Tang, S. Goldstein, and J. Bouteaud, &#x201c;Guideline No. 451: Asymptomatic Endometrial Thickening in Postmenopausal Women,&#x201d; Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology Canada 46, no. 7 (2024): 102591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Koppikar, A. Oaknin, K. G. Babu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Pan&#x2010;Asian Adapted ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Diagnosis, Treatment and Follow&#x2010;Up of Patients With Endometrial Cancer,&#x201d; ESMO Open 8, no. 1 (2023): 100774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Garuti, S. Angioni, L. Mereu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Hysteroscopic View With Targeted Biopsy in the Assessment of Endometrial Carcinoma. What Is the Rate of Underestimatated Diagnosis? The Results of a Multicenter Italian Trial,&#x201d; Gynecological Surgery 17, no. 1 (2020): 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Abdollahi Fard, P. Mostafa Gharabaghi, F. Montazeri, and O. Mashrabi, &#x201c;Hysteroscopy as a Minimally Invasive Surgery, a Good Substitute for Invasive Gynecological Procedures,&#x201d; Iranian Journal of Reproductive Medicine 10, no. 4 (2012): 377&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Katagiri, M. Iwasaki, S. K. Abe, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Reproductive Factors and Endometrial Cancer Risk Among Women,&#x201d; JAMA Network Open 6, no. 9 (2023): e2332296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wu, Q. Chen, Y. Liu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Predictive Model for Endometrial Carcinoma Based on Hysteroscopic Data,&#x201d; International Journal of Women's Health 15 (2023): 1651&#x2013;1659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. L. Cheng, H. H. Jia, Y. J. Wang, and T. T. Su, &#x201c;Clinical Characteristics of Postmenopausal Patients With Vaginal Bleeding and the Influencing Factors of Endometrial Cancer,&#x201d; Oncology Progress 20, no. 23 (2022): 2429&#x2013;2432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Aune, D. A. Navarro Rosenblatt, D. S. Chan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Anthropometric Factors and Endometrial Cancer Risk: A Systematic Review and Dose&#x2010;Response Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Prospective Studies,&#x201d; Annals of Oncology: Official Journal of the European Society for Medical Oncology 26, no. 8 (2015): 1635&#x2013;1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. den van Bosch, L. Ameye, D. Van Schoubroeck, T. Bourne, and D. Timmerman, &#x201c;Intra&#x2010;Cavitary Uterine Pathology in Women With Abnormal Uterine Bleeding: A Prospective Study of 1220 Women,&#x201d; Facts, Views &amp; Vision in ObGyn 7, no. 1 (2015): 17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Yao, C. Li, and J. Cheng, &#x201c;The Relationship Between Endometrial Thickening and Endometrial Lesions in Postmenopausal Women,&#x201d; Archives of Gynecology and Obstetrics 306, no. 6 (2022): 2047&#x2013;2054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. M. Madkour, &#x201c;An Ultrasound Risk&#x2010;Scoring Model for Prediction of Endometrial Cancer in Post&#x2010;Menopausal Women (Using IETA Terminology),&#x201d; Middle East Fertility Society Journal 22, no. 3 (2017): 201&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Burbos, P. Musonda, T. J. Duncan, S. G. Crocker, E. P. Morris, and J. J. Nieto, &#x201c;Estimating the Risk of Endometrial Cancer in Symptomatic Postmenopausal Women: A Novel Clinical Prediction Model Based on Patients' Characteristics,&#x201d; International Journal of Gynecological Cancer: Official Journal of the International Gynecological Cancer Society 21, no. 3 (2011): 500&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. K. W. Chee, R. M. Koshy, J. Haidey, M. H. Murad, G. Low, and M. P. Wilson, &#x201c;Re&#x2010;Evaluating Endometrial Thickness in Symptomatic Postmenopausal Patients for Excluding Cancer: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of the American College of Radiology: JACR 22, no. 4 (2025): 425&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kaur, S. Qadri, A. M. Nevill, and A. A. A. Ewies, &#x201c;The Optimal Endometrial Thickness Threshold for Prediction of Endometrial Cancer in Postmenopausal Women Without Bleeding Remains Uncertain&#x2010;Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Gynecology Obstetrics and Human Reproduction 53, no. 10 (2024): 102831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Chen, B. Zhai, J. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Systemic Immune&#x2010;Inflammatory Index Predict Short&#x2010;Term Outcome in Recurrent/Metastatic and Locally Advanced Cervical Cancer Patients Treated With PD&#x2010;1 Inhibitor,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 14, no. 1 (2024): 31528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, F. Liu, Q. Cai, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Invasion and Metastasis in Cancer: Molecular Insights and Therapeutic Targets,&#x201d; Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy 10, no. 1 (2025): 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. A. S. van den Bosch, J. M. A. Pijnenborg, A. Romano, I. S. Haldorsen, and H. M. J. Werner, &#x201c;The Role of Fat Distribution and Inflammation in the Origin of Endometrial Cancer, Study Protocol of the ENDOCRINE Study,&#x201d; PLoS One 17, no. 10 (2022): e0276516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. Swanson, N. Potischman, R. J. Barrett, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Endometrial Cancer Risk in Relation to Serum Lipids and Lipoprotein Levels,&#x201d; Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp; Prevention: A Publication of the American Association for Cancer Research, Cosponsored by the American Society of Preventive Oncology 3, no. 7 (1994): 575&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. F. Kho, F. Amant, D. Annibali, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mendelian Randomization Analyses Suggest a Role for Cholesterol in the Development of Endometrial Cancer,&#x201d; International Journal of Cancer 148, no. 2 (2021): 307&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. G. Marin, R. Vladareanu, A. Petca, and A. Filipescu, &#x201c;The Importance of Metabolic Factors in Endometrial Cancer: Evaluating the Utility of the Triglyceride&#x2010;To&#x2010;Glycemia Index and Triglyceride&#x2010;To&#x2010;High&#x2010;Density Lipoprotein Ratio as Biomarkers,&#x201d; Cureus 16, no. 6 (2024): e62099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Bagepalli Srinivas, S. S. Kubakaddi, S. Polisetti, S. Amber, S. Guruvare, and M. Vaman Pai, &#x201c;A Novel Risk&#x2010;Scoring Model for Prediction of Premalignant and Malignant Lesions of Uterine Endometrium Among Symptomatic Premenopausal Women,&#x201d; International Journal of Women's Health 12 (2020): 883&#x2013;891.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>