<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41781892</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2288</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical research methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Res Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Searching smarter, not harder: leveraging AI to enhance literature searches for theory-driven reviews-A methodological case study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12874-026-02814-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Integrating artificial intelligence (AI) into literature searching has the potential to enhance research synthesis by improving the identification of conceptually rich or otherwise difficult-to-locate evidence. Theoretical or conceptual literature reviews, including realist reviews, often involve resource-intensive searches because they aim to trace nuanced ideas, mechanisms, or conceptual relationships across multiple sources. This case study illustrates the use of AI-powered tools to support and streamline such literature searching, using a realist review as an example.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We applied AI tools-Scite and Undermind-in the context of a realist review to facilitate the identification of relevant studies. Seed papers and key informant papers guided the search, and a novel classification system (grandparent, parent, and child papers) was used to systematically organise studies for developing and refining theoretical constructs. Transparent screening procedures and decision-making frameworks were employed to ensure methodological rigour and reproducibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The integration of AI tools supported the retrieval of conceptually relevant literature and helped manage complex datasets. The classification system enabled structured organisation of studies, supporting iterative testing and refinement of theoretical constructs. The workflow demonstrated flexibility and adaptability, suggesting potential applicability beyond realist review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that AI-powered tools can support literature searching, particularly in identifying conceptually relevant studies. However, these tools do not replace the critical interpretive work required by researchers. Human judgement remains essential to assess relevance, evaluate nuanced concepts, and make informed decisions throughout the search process, with AI serving as a valuable adjunct rather than a substitute.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hunter</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7837-7260</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Sports Sciences, Medical School Building, University of Exeter, St Luke's Campus, Exeter, EX1 2LU, UK. rebecca.j.hunter@northumbria.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Communities and Education, Northumbria University, Coach Lane Campus, Newcastle Upon Tyne, NE7 7XA, UK. rebecca.j.hunter@northumbria.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Booth</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4808-3880</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield City Centre, 30 Regent St, Sheffield, S1 4DA, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wood</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1039-1642</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Sports Sciences, Medical School Building, University of Exeter, St Luke's Campus, Exeter, EX1 2LU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NIHR205671</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Res Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2288</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence appraisal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Literature screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Literature searches</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Realist reviews</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Review methodology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41781892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-026-02814-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12874-026-02814-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roth S, Wermer-Colan A. Machine learning methods for systematic reviews: a rapid scoping review. Del J Public Health. 2023;9(4):40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R. Realist synthesis: new protocols for systematic review. Evidence-based policy. 2006:73&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G. Data gathering in realist reviews: looking for needles in haystacks. In: Doing realist research. London: SAGE; 2018. p. 131&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Briscoe S, Wright JM. The &#x201c;realist search&#x201d;: a systematic scoping review of current practice and reporting. Res Synth Methods. 2019;11(1):14&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Harris J, Croot E, Springett J, Campbell F, Wilkins E. Towards a methodology for cluster searching to provide conceptual and contextual &#x201c;richness&#x201d; for systematic reviews of complex interventions: case study (CLUSTER). BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013;13:118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Wright J, Briscoe S. Scoping and searching to support realist approaches. Doing realist research. 2018:147-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duddy C, Roberts N. Identifying evidence for five realist reviews in primary health care: a comparison of search methods. Res Synth Methods. 2022;13(2):190&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates MJ. The design of browsing and berrypicking techniques for the online search interface. Online Rev. 1989;13(5):407&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman S, Wright JM, Nixon J, Schoonhoven L, Twiddy M, Greenhalgh J. Searching for programme theories for a realist evaluation: a case study comparing an academic database search and a simple Google search. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-020-01084-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Carroll C. Systematic searching for theory to inform systematic reviews: is it feasible? Is it desirable? Health Info Libr J. 2015;32(3):220&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borah R, Brown AW, Capers PL, Kaiser KA. Analysis of the time and workers needed to conduct systematic reviews of medical interventions using data from the PROSPERO registry. BMJ Open. 2017;7(2):e012545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Greenhalgh T, Harvey G, Walshe K. Realist review-a new method of systematic review designed for complex policy interventions. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2005;10(1_suppl):21&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mara-Eves A, Thomas J, McNaught J, Miwa M, Ananiadou S. Using text mining for study identification in systematic reviews: a systematic review of current approaches. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherbakov D, Hubig N, Jansari V, Bakumenko A, Lenert LA. The emergence of large language models (llm) as a tool in literature reviews: an llm automated systematic review. arXiv preprint arXiv:240904600. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Ma X, Luo D, Li L, Shi X, Chang X, et al. Automated literature research and review-generation method based on large language models. Natl Sci Rev. 2025;12(6):nwaf169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter R, Gorely T, Beattie M, Harris K. Realist review. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2022;15(1):242&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter R, Booth A, Lamb SE, Williamson E, Hendrick P, Sahota O, et al. Prehabilitation for lumbar spinal stenosis: understanding mechanisms and contexts for enhanced engagement-a realist review. Age and Ageing. In press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter R, Booth A, Lamb S, Williamson E, Hendrick P, Sahota O, et al. Prehabilitation for lumbar spinal stenosis: understanding mechanisms and contexts for enhanced engagement&#x2014;a realist review. Age Ageing. 2025;54(10):afaf311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labcritics. Undermind.ai Review: AI-Driven Revolution in the Literature Review: Labcritics, Lab Tech Review &amp; Marketplace; 2024 [Available from: https://labcritics.com/undermind-ai-review-ai-driven-revolution-in-the-literature-review/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody S. Scite. J Med Libr Assoc. 2021;109(4):707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dada S, Dalkin S, Gilmore B, Hunter R, Mukumbang FC. Applying and reporting relevance, richness and rigour in realist evidence appraisals: advancing key concepts in realist reviews. Res Synth Methods. 2023;14(3):504&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirt J, Nordhausen T, Fuerst T, Ewald H, Appenzeller-Herzog C. Guidance on terminology, application, and reporting of citation searching: the TARCiS statement. BMJ. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2023-078384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyes DR, Sandberg S. Trust, nuance, and care: advantages and challenges of repeat qualitative interviews. Qual Res. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1177/14687941241246159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J, Macaulay AC, Pluye P, Salsberg J, Bush PL, Henderson J, et al. Uncovering the benefits of participatory research: implications of a realist review for health research and practice. Milbank Q. 2012;90(2):311&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickerson RS. Confirmation bias: A ubiquitous phenomenon in many guises. Rev Gen Psychol. 1998;2(2):175&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan A. The conduct of inquiry: methodology for behavioural science. Routledge; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J. Realist synthesis for public health: building an ontologically deep understanding of how programs work, for whom, and in which contexts. Annu Rev Public Health. 2019;40(1):361&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Sommer I, Noyes J, Houghton C, Campbell F. Rapid reviews methods series: guidance on rapid qualitative evidence synthesis. BMJ evidence-based medicine. 2024;29(3):194&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J. Retroductive theorizing in Pawson and Tilley&#x2019;s applied scientific realism. Journal of Critical Realism. 2020;19(2):121&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L, Agrawal R, Singer M, Kannapiran P, De Castro Molina JA, Teow KL, et al. Leveraging artificial intelligence to enhance systematic reviews in health research: advanced tools and challenges. Syst Rev. 2024;13(1):269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwon YN, Kim JH, Chung HS, Jung EJ, Chun J, Lee S, et al. The use of generative AI for scientific literature searches for systematic reviews: ChatGPT and Microsoft Bing AI performance evaluation. JMIR Med Inform. 2024;12:e51187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Liang S, Zhang Y, Chen S, Wang Q, Huang T, et al. Automated medical literature screening using artificial intelligence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2022;29(8):1425&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C, Booth A, Britten N, Garside R. A comparison of results of empirical studies of supplementary search techniques and recommendations in review methodology handbooks: a methodological review. Syst Rev. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-017-0625-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C, Booth A, Varley-Campbell J, Britten N, Garside R. Defining the process to literature searching in systematic reviews: a literature review of guidance and supporting studies. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-018-0545-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A. Searching for qualitative research for inclusion in systematic reviews: a structured methodological review. Syst Rev. 2016. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-016-0249-x.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>