<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41820367</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interfacial configurational entropy tuning strategy enabling liquid alloys for efficient depolymerization of polyolefin waste.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70325-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accumulation of plastic waste presents a global environmental crisis, posing severe threats to ecosystems. Depolymerization offers a promising route for closed-loop recycling of plastic waste. Nevertheless, depolymerizing chemically stable polyolefins remains challenging, yet fails to achieve high light olefin yields and stability. Herein, we propose an interfacial configurational entropy tuning strategy for liquid alloy catalysts, inducing active site interfacial enrichment and optimizing electronic structure. With this strategy, a quaternary GaInNiSn catalyst with medium entropy is developed for recycling polyolefins into light olefins under atmospheric pressure without co-reactant consumption, achieving a space-time yield of 181.5&#x2009;mmol g<sub>cat</sub>&#x207b;<sup>1</sup> h&#x207b;<sup>1</sup>. Mechanistic insights reveal that Ni<sup>&#x3b4;</sup>&#x207b;-Sn<sup>&#x3b4;+</sup> active sites form within the dynamic Ga interface, enabling C-H bond activation to promote &#x3b2;-scission. Furthermore, a photovoltaics-driven depolymerization system is constructed, maintaining light olefin output of 52.8&#x2009;L&#x2009;h&#x207b;<sup>1</sup> over 120&#x2009;hours. Our work unlocks a potent tool for efficient and sustainable plastic waste utilization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chaoping</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Haoyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Pengxuan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry, State Key Laboratory of Fine Chemicals, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Haihao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaonan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry, State Key Laboratory of Fine Chemicals, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jiaming</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0916-4792</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry, State Key Laboratory of Fine Chemicals, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China. zhangxiao@dlut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Dawei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China. dwtang@dlut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2672-3720</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ocean Energy Utilization and Energy Conservation of the Ministry of Education, School of Power and Energy Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China. bjiang@dlut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41820367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70325-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70325-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;ussler, M., Eck, M., Rothauer, D. &amp; Mecking, S. Closed-loop recycling of polyethylene-like materials. Nature 590, 423&#x2013;427 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Highly selective upcycling of plastic mixture waste by microwave-assisted catalysis over Zn/b-ZnO. Nat. Commun. 16, 1726 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer, R., Jambeck, J. R. &amp; Law, K. L. Production, use, and fate of all plastics ever made. Sci. Adv. 3, e1700782 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, H. X. et al. Mining the carbon intermediates in plastic waste upcycling for constructing C&#x2212;S bond. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 146, 18639&#x2013;18649 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, K. et al. Progress and perspective for conversion of plastic wastes into valuable chemicals. Chem. Soc. Rev. 52, 8&#x2013;29 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, M. et al. Triple kill: Fabrication of composites coming from waste face masks, polystyrene microplastics, graphene, and their electromagnetic interference shielding behaviors. Carbon Neutraliza 2, 616&#x2013;628 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, Z. Y. et al. Recycling waste rubber into single-walled carbon nanotubes: Narrow chirality distribution and hydrogen byproduct. Carbon Neutraliza 4, e70059 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. B. et al. Depolymerization of polyesters by a binuclear catalyst for plastic recycling. Nat. Sustain 6, 965&#x2013;973 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, J. M. et al. Hybrid thermo-electrochemical conversion of plastic wastes commingled with marine biomass to value-added products using renewable energy. Energ. Environ. Sci. 16, 5805&#x2013;5821 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, J. J. et al. Efficient solvent- and hydrogen-free upcycling of high-density polyethylene into separable cyclic hydrocarbons. Nat. Nanotechnol. 18, 772&#x2013;779 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, P. et al. Stable interfacial ruthenium species for highly efficient polyolefin upcycling. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 146, 7076&#x2013;7087 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, R. C., Xiao, D. Q., Wang, M., Gao, Y. J. &amp; Ma, D. Solar-driven photocatalysis for recycling and upcycling plastics. Appl Catal. B-Environ. 341, 123357 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimberger, L., Ng, G. &amp; Boyer, C. Light-driven polymer recycling to monomers and small molecules. Nat. Commun. 15, 2510 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Y., Gao, Y. S. &amp; Tang, Y. Sustainable developments in polyolefin chemistry: Progress, challenges, and outlook. Prog. Polym. Sci. 143, 101713 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J. K. et al. Catalytic upcycling of polyolefins. Chem. Rev. 124, 9457&#x2013;9579 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. et al. Low-temperature upcycling of polyolefins into liquid alkanes via tandem cracking-alkylation. Science 379, 807&#x2013;811 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. S. et al. Visible light-triggered depolymerization of commercial polymethacrylates. Science 387, 874&#x2013;880 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, R. L., Mao, S. J., Lu, B., Liu, W. C. &amp; Wang, Y. Efficient upcycling of polyolefin waste to light sromatics via coupling C-C scission and carbonylation. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 64, e202424334 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, Q. Y. et al. Entropy confinement promotes hydrogenolysis activity for polyethylene upcycling. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 62, e202313174 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen, Z. Y. et al. Upcycling of polyethylene to gasoline through a self-supplied hydrogen strategy in a layered self-pillared zeolite. Nat. Chem. 16, 871&#x2013;880 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, Y. X. et al. Photothermal recycling of waste polyolefin plastics into liquid fuels with high selectivity under solvent-free conditions. Nat. Commun. 14, 4242 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, J. Y. et al. Micelles cascade assembly to tandem porous catalyst for waste plastics upcycling. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 63, e202405252 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Q. et al. Depolymerization of plastics by means of electrified spatiotemporal heating. Nature 616, 488&#x2013;494 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvam, E., Yu, K. W., Ngu, J., Najmi, S. &amp; Vlachos, D. G. Recycling polyolefin plastic waste at short contact times via rapid joule heating. Nat. Commun. 15, 5662 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conk, R. J. et al. Catalytic deconstruction of waste polyethylene with ethylene to form propylene. Science 377, 1561&#x2013;1566 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conk, R. J. et al. Polyolefin waste to light olefins with ethylene and base-metal heterogeneous catalysts. Science 385, 1322&#x2013;1327 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y. J. et al. High-entropy approach traditional doping strategy for layered oxide cathodes in alkali-metal-ion batteries: A comparative study. Energy Storage Mater. 79, 104295 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. G. et al. High-entropy nanoparticles: Synthesis-structure-property relationships and data-driven discovery. Science 376, eabn3103 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, M. S. et al. Configuration-entropy-driven electrolyte with anion-enhanced solvation structures for fast-charging sodium metal batteries. Adv Funct Mater, e24686, https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202524686 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upham, D. C. et al. Catalytic molten metals for the direct conversion of methane to hydrogen and separable carbon. Science 358, 917&#x2013;920 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. N. et al. Ternary NiMo-Bi liquid alloy catalyst for efficient hydrogen production from methane pyrolysis. Science 381, 857&#x2013;861 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, S. Introducing the basics of modeling EXAFS spectra in Artemis, http://xrayabsorption.org/tutorials/ (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, J. B. et al. Advanced catalysts for the chemical recycling of plastic waste. Adv. Mater. 37, 202418138 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Q., Hu, S. &amp; Hu, L. Electrothermal synthesis of commodity chemicals. Nat. Chem. Eng. 1, 680&#x2013;690 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. M. et al. Distributed electrified heating for efficient hydrogen production. Nat. Commun. 15, 3868 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz, M. et al. Supported catalytically active liquid metal solutions: Liquid metal catalysis with ternary alloys, enhancing activity in propane dehydrogenation. Acs Catal. 14, 6440&#x2013;6450 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke, R. W. et al. Dynamic crosslinking compatibilizes immiscible mixed plastics. Nature 616, 731&#x2013;739 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, C. X., Diment, W. T. &amp; Chen, E. Y. X. Closed-loop recycling of mixed plastics of polyester and CO<sub>2</sub>-based polycarbonate to a dingle monomer. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 63, e202405083 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. Chemical upcycling of polyethylene, polypropylene, and mixtures to high-value surfactants. Science 381, 666&#x2013;671 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. et al. Complete hydrogenolysis of mixed plastic wastes. Nat. Chem. Eng. 1, 376&#x2013;384 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, P. et al. Identifying the active phase on atomically dispersed catalysts for propane dehydrogenation: Positively charged vs metallic transition metals. Acs Catal. 14, 8602&#x2013;8618 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bercaw, J. E., Hazari, N., Labinger, J. A., Scott, V. J. &amp; Sunley, G. J. Selective methylative homologation: An alternate route to alkane upgrading. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 130, 11988&#x2013;11995 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. M. et al. Alkane activation initiated by hydride transfer: Co-conversion of propane and methanol over H-ZSM-5 zeolite. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 54, 7363&#x2013;7366 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elordi, G., Olazar, M., Artetxe, M., Casta&#xf1;o, P. &amp; Bilbao, J. Effect of the acidity of the HZSM-5 zeolite catalyst on the cracking of high density polyethylene in a conical spouted bed reactor. Appl Catal. a-Gen. 415, 89&#x2013;95 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun, F. F. et al. Voltage-induced penetration effect in liquid metals at room temperature. Natl. Sci. Rev. 7, 366&#x2013;372 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P. X. et al. Rapid-Response Electromagnetic Metamaterial Enabling Round-The-Clock Electrified CO<sub>2</sub> Methanation. Adv Funct Mater, e24133, https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202524133 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monkhorst, H. J. &amp; Pack, J. D. Special points for Brillouin-Zone integrations. Phys. Rev. B 13, 5188&#x2013;5192 (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kresse, G. &amp; Furthmuller, J. Efficient iterative schemes for ab initio total-energy calculations using a plane-wave basis set. Phys. Rev. B 54, 11169&#x2013;11186 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamurthi, V. et al. Structural evolution of liquid metals and alloys. Adv. Mater. 36, 2403885 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polo-Garzon, F. et al. Low-temperature dechlorination of polyvinyl chloride (PVC) for production of H<sub>2</sub> and carbon materials using liquid metal catalysts. Sci. Adv. 10, eadm9963 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuraiqi, K. et al. Unveiling metal mobility in a liquid Cu-Ga catalyst for ammonia synthesis. Nat. Catal. 7, 1044&#x2013;1052 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. Y. et al. Microwave-powered liquid metal degradation of polyolefins. Adv. Mater. 37, 2412539 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, Z. Z. et al. Electromagnetically heating and oscillating liquid metal for catalyzing polyester depolymerization. Adv. Mater. 37, 2502011 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, J. M. et al. Molten Sn solvent expands liquid metal catalysis. Nat. Commun. 16, 907 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. R. et al. Improving the methane oxidation by self-adaptive optimization of liquid-metal catalysts. Angew. Chem. Int Ed. 64, e202421554 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. H., Sharratt, P. N., Garforth, A. A. &amp; Dwyer, J. Catalytic conversion of polyolefins to chemicals and fuels over various cracking catalysts. Energy Fuels 12, 767&#x2013;774 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lov&#xe1;s, P., Hudec, P., Jambor, B., H&#xe1;jekov&#xe1;, E. &amp; Horn&#xe1;cek, M. Catalytic cracking of heavy fractions from the pyrolysis of waste HDPE and PP. Fuel 203, 244&#x2013;252 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. H. &amp; Yang, M. H. Catalytic conversion of commingled polymer waste into chemicals and fuels over spent FCC commercial catalyst in a fluidised-bed reactor. Appl Catal. B-Environ. 69, 145&#x2013;153 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. H. &amp; Yang, M. H. Catalytic pyrolysis of polyolefin waste into valuable hydrocarbons over reused catalyst from refinery FCC units. Appl Catal. a-Gen. 328, 132&#x2013;139 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olazar, M. et al. Influence of FCC catalyst steaming on HDPE pyrolysis product distribution. J. Anal. Appl Pyrol 85, 359&#x2013;365 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eschenbacher, A. et al. Boron-modified mesoporous ZSM-5 for the conversion of pyrolysis vapors from LDPE and mixed polyolefins: Maximizing the C<sub>2</sub>&#x2013;C<sub>4</sub> olefin yield with minimal carbon footprint. Acs Sustain Chem. Eng. 9, 14618&#x2013;14630 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eschenbacher, A., Varghese, R. J., Abbas-Abadi, M. S. &amp; Van Geem, K. M. Maximizing light olefins and aromatics as high value base chemicals via single step catalytic conversion of plastic waste. Chem. Eng. J. 428, 132087 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Z. W. et al. Efficient conversion of polyethylene to light olefins by self-confined cracking and reforming. Nat. Commun. 16, 7964 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tianrui, Bi. et al. Closed-loop recycling of polyethylene to ethylene and propylene via a kinetic decoupling&#x2013;recoupling strategy. Nat. Chem. Eng. 2, 650&#x2013;661 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. Z. et al. Catalytic cracking of polypropylene by using Fe-SBA-15 synthesized in an acid-free medium for production of light hydrocarbon oils. J. Anal. Appl Pyrol 146, 104755 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, D. S., Majerski, P., Piskorz, J., Radlein, D. &amp; Barnickel, M. Production of liquid fuels from waste plastics. Can. J. Chem. Eng. 77, 1021&#x2013;1027 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Encinar, J. M. &amp; Gonz&#xe1;lez, J. F. Pyrolysis of synthetic polymers and plastic wastes. Kinetic study. Fuel Process. Technol. 89, 678&#x2013;686 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, J. D. et al. Coking-resistant polyethylene upcycling modulated by zeolite micropore diffusion. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 144, 14269&#x2013;14277 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, N. M. et al. Chemical recycling of polyethylene by tandem catalytic conversion to propylene. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 144, 18526&#x2013;18531 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>