<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41554798</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current transformer (CT) saturation classification using empirical mode decomposition (EMD) and relevance vector machine (RVM).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5754</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5754</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5754</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35444-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">The fault is taking place in the power system where the saturation of the Current Transformer (CT) is occurring, among other variations of system parameters. Empirical Mode Decomposition (EMD) and Relevance Vector Machine (RVM) detection of Current Transformer (CT) saturation has been found to be a reliable, data-based method of protecting the power system. In this approach, a power system is modelled in PSCAD, with faults being added at various points, fault resistances and fault origin angles to provide a high volume of secondary CT current signals under saturated and unsaturated conditions. The simulated data contains realistic nonlinearities such as partial and severe saturation effects that normally arise after fault commencement. The CT current signals obtained are passed through EMD, which breaks down the nonlinear waveform into a collection of Intrinsic Mode Functions (IMFs). These IMFs bring about concealed oscillatory elements connected to signal distortion as a result of saturation. Empirical properties are obtained from the IMFs, like the energy distribution, instant frequency changes, kurtosis, skewness, and entropy. These characteristics are very sensitive to distortion of the waveforms, and thus are the appropriate signals to show saturation in CT. EMD with RVM technique are proven using MATLAB software as a means of ensuring successful classification of the CT saturation phenomenon. The features are extracted and represent the input to a Relevance Vector Machine (RVM) classifier that is trained on the labelled data to be able to distinguish between saturated and unsaturated cases. The proposed EMD-RVM scheme detects CT saturation within 23.5 ms, making it suitable for fast relay operation. The extracted EMD features provide clear separability between normal and saturated conditions, enabling accurate classification through RVM. A hardware-in-the-loop setup is also prepared for future real-time validation and deployment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-35444-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chothani</LastName><ForeName>Nilesh</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, SoET, Pandit Deendayal Energy University, Gandhinagar, 328007, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vyas</LastName><ForeName>Parth</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, SoET, Pandit Deendayal Energy University, Gandhinagar, 328007, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonawane</LastName><ForeName>Chandrakant</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Institute of Technology Pune, Symbiosis International Deemed University (SIU), Pune, India. chandrakant.sonawane@sitpune.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Centre for Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, Symbiosis International Deemed University (SIU), Pune, India. chandrakant.sonawane@sitpune.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Choon Kit</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering and Quantity Surveying, INTI International University, Persiaran Perdana BBN, Nilai, Negeri Sembilan, 71800, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CT saturation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Current transformer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Empirical mode decomposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power system fault</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Process innovation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Relevance vector machine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: This article contains no studies performed by the authors with human participants or animals.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41554798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12894900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35444-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35444-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allah, R. A., Moussa, S., Shehab-Eldin, E. H. &amp; Hamed, M. N. G. Advanced detection and compensation scheme for current transformers saturation. In: <i>2006 Eleventh International Middle East Power Systems Conference</i>, El-Minia, Egypt, pp. 481&#x2013;486. (2006). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebizant, W., Wiszniewski, A., Schiel, L. &amp; CT Saturation Correction Based on the Estimated CT Saturation Time. Constant. In: <i>2008 IET 9th International Conference on Developments in Power System Protection (DPSP 2008)</i>, Glasgow, 2008, pp. 174&#x2013;179. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, E. S., Chen, T., Bo, Z. Q., Klimek, A. &amp; Yang, M. F. A new method to identify CT saturation based on the time difference algorithm. In: <i>2009 IEEE Power &amp; Energy Society General Meeting</i>, Calgary, AB, Canada, 2009, pp. 1&#x2013;4. 10.1109/PES.2009.5275488</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, X. &amp; Bo, Z. A novel CT saturation identification scheme for differential protection of generators. In: <i>2011 IEEE Power and Energy Society General Meeting</i>, Detroit, MI, USA, pp. 1&#x2013;4, (2011). 10.1109/PES.2011.6039056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak, D. J., Dong, X. Z., Wang, B., Shi, S. X. &amp; Rebizant, W. Approximation of parameters of fundamental component of secondary current distorted by CT saturation. In: <i>12th IET International Conference on Developments in Power System Protection (DPSP 2014)</i>, Copenhagen, Denmark, pp. 1&#x2013;5, (2014). 10.1049/cp. 2014.0113. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak, D. J., Dong, X. Z., Wang, B., Shi, S. X. &amp; Rebizant, W. Approximation of parameters of fundamental component of secondary current distorted by CT saturation. In: <i>12th IET International Conference on Developments in Power System Protection (DPSP 2014)</i>, Copenhagen, Denmark, pp. 1&#x2013;5, (2014). 10.1049/cp.2014.0113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna, A. Application of ATP-EMTP in determination of optimal settings for differential protection IEDs under CT saturation. In: <i>13th International Conference on Development in Power System Protection 2016 (DPSP)</i>, Edinburgh, UK, 2016, pp. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1049/cp. 2016.0101. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwade, A. N., Katti, P. K. &amp; Ghodekar, J. G. Use of Rogowski Coil for accurate measurement of secondary current contaminated with CT saturation in distance protection scheme. In: <i>IEEE 6th International Conference on Power Systems (ICPS)</i>, New Delhi, India, 2016, pp. 1&#x2013;6, (2016). 10.1109/ICPES.2016.7584210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borzooy, A. &amp; Vakilian, M. A new noise-immune method to detect protective CT saturation and its release instants. In: <i>2016 IEEE International Conference on Power and Renewable Energy (ICPRE)</i>, Shanghai, China, 2016, pp. 284&#x2013;287. 10.1109/ICPRE.2016.7871217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, D. D., Mistry, K. D. &amp; Chothani, N. G. Digital differential protection of power transformer using DFT algorithm with CT saturation consideration. In: <i>2016 National Power Systems Conference (NPSC)</i>, Bhubaneswar, India, pp. 1&#x2013;6, (2016). 10.1109/NPSC.2016.7858854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behi, D., Allahbakhshi, M., Bagheri, A. &amp; Tajdinian, M. A new statistical-based algorithm for CT saturation detection utilising residual-based similarity index. <i>2017 Iranian Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE)</i>, Tehran, Iran, pp. 1072&#x2013;1077, (2017). 10.1109/IranianCEE.2017.7985200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilesh Chothani, D. D. &amp; Patel Mistry support vector machine based classification of current transformer saturation phenomenon. <i>J. Green. Eng.</i><b>7</b>, 25&#x2013;42. 10.13052/jge1904-4720.7122 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13052/jge1904-4720.7122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Study on transformer inrush current and CT saturation as well as the impact of their coupling effect on protection. In: <i>2017 IEEE Transportation Electrification Conference and Expo, Asia-Pacific (ITEC Asia-Pacific)</i>, Harbin, China, pp. 1&#x2013;6, (2017). 10.1109/ITEC-AP.2017.8081031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M., Leevongwat, I., Rastgoufard, P. &amp; A Current Transformer (CT). Saturation Detection Method for Bus Differential Protection. In: <i>2018 Clemson University Power Systems Conference (PSC)</i>, Charleston, SC, USA, pp. 1&#x2013;5, (2018). 10.1109/PSC.2018.8664064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseri, F., Kazemi, Z., Farjah, E. &amp; Ghanbari, T. Fast detection and compensation of current transformer saturation using extended Kalman filter. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Delivery</i>. <b>34</b> (3), 1087&#x2013;1097 10.1109/TPWRD.2019.2895802 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2019.2895802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri, A., Allahbakhshi, M., Samet, H., Tajdinian, M. &amp; Seifi, A. Distinguishing between Fault and Inrush Current in Presence of the CT Saturation: a New Method Based on Gravity Center in Time. In: <i>IEEE International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering and 2019 IEEE Industrial and Commercial Power Systems Europe (EEEIC / I&amp;CPS Europe)</i>, Genova, Italy, 2019, pp. 1&#x2013;5, (2019). 10.1109/EEEIC.2019.8783484</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, L., Teoh, C. P. &amp; Voloh, I. CT saturation &#x2014; A simulation study of different detection and blocking algorithms. In: <i>15th International Conference on Developments in Power System Protection (DPSP 2020)</i>, Liverpool, UK, 2020, pp. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1049/cp.2020.0112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delzendeh, M. &amp; Kazemi Karegar, H. Current transformer saturation compensator by using negative voltage feedback. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Delivery</i>. <b>35</b> (3), 1200&#x2013;1208 10.1109/TPWRD.2019.2936449 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2019.2936449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, W. et al. Missing Information Protection Considering Inrush Current and CT Saturation. In: <i>2nd International Conference on Electrical Engineering and Mechatronics Technology (ICEEMT)</i>, Hangzhou, China, 2022, pp. 115&#x2013;120, (2022). 10.1109/ICEEMT56362.2022.9862652</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S. et al. Compensation: A hybrid physical model- and data-driven method. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Delivery</i>. <b>37</b>, 3928&#x2013;3938 (2022). 10.1109/TPWRD.2022.3141550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2022.3141550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chothani, N. &amp; Kumar, S. Enhanced Adaptive Differential Protection using DWT for Transformer Considering CT Saturation. In: <i>2024 3rd International Conference for Advancement in Technology (ICONAT)</i>, GOA, India, 2024, pp. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/ICONAT61936.2024.10774768</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, J., Zhao, M., Lei, Y. &amp; Guan, X. A Novel transient saturation detection method for P-class current transformer using improved hausdorff distance algorithm. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>73</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2024). 10.1109/TIM.2024.3403168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3403168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chothani, N. &amp; Kumar, S. Dynamic Differential Protection for Power Transformer in the Presence of CT Saturation. In: <i>3rd International Conference on Smart Systems for applications in Electrical Sciences (ICSSES)</i>, Tumakuru, India, 2025, pp. 1&#x2013;6, (2025). 10.1109/ICSSES64899.2025.11009837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chothani, N., Kumar, S. &amp; Chaudhary, J. Adaptive Differential Protection of Electrical Busbar considering CT Saturation Detection using Power Spectral Density. In: <i>International Conference on Sustainable Energy Technologies and Computational Intelligence (SETCOM)</i>, Gandhinagar, India, 2025, pp. 1&#x2013;6, (2025). 10.1109/SETCOM64758.2025.10932595</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, S., Chothani, N. &amp; Intelligence, C. Adaptive Differential Protection of Large-Scale Generator Considering CT Saturation Phenomenon. In: <i>2025 International Conference on Sustainable Energy Technologies and (SETCOM)</i>, Gandhinagar, India, 2025, pp. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/SETCOM64758.2025.10932564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danquah, J. O., Mandava, S. &amp; Part, B. Machine learning-based current transformer saturation detection for medium voltage in power grids system. <i>Measurement</i>, (2025). 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdoos, A. A. &amp; Gholamian, S. A. Mohammad Mehdi Azari Takami, A precise scheme for detection of current transformer saturation based on time frequency analysis. <i>Measurement</i><b>94</b>, 692&#x2013;706 (2016). 10.1016/j.measurement.2016.09.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2016.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdoos, A. A. Detection of current transformer saturation based on variational mode decomposition analysis. <i>IET Gener Transm Distrib.</i><b>10</b>, 2658&#x2013;2669. 10.1049/iet-gtd.2015.0906 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-gtd.2015.0906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahi, A., Ramezani, N. &amp; Ahmadi, I. Current transformers&#x2019; saturation detection and compensation based on instantaneous flux density calculations. <i>AUTOMATIKA</i><b>57</b> (4), 1070&#x2013;1078. (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7305/automatika.2017.04.1555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal, K. et al. Intelligent islanding detection framework for smart grids using wavelet scalograms and HOG feature fusion. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 30351. 10.1038/s41598-025-08391-7 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-08391-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12365090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40830356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battula, V. V. R. Comparison of advanced signal decomposition techniques for the classification of PQDs by machine learning algorithms. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 38164. 10.1038/s41598-025-22128-6 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-22128-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12578943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41174065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero, J. F. A. et al. EMD-based data augmentation method applied to handwriting data for the diagnosis of essential tremor using LSTM networks. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>12</b>, 12819. 10.1038/s41598-022-16741-y (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-16741-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9329364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35896618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chothani, N. G. &amp; Bhalja, B. R. A new algorithm for Busbar fault zone identification using relevance vector machine. <i>Electr. Power Compon. Syst.</i><b>44</b> (2), 193&#x2013;205. 10.1080/15325008.2015.1101725 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15325008.2015.1101725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>