<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41803510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1436-5073</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>193</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Mikrochimica acta</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mikrochim Acta</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biosensing technologies for foodborne pathogen detection and healthcare: principles, emerging materials, and intelligent platforms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">231</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00604-026-07976-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Foodborne pathogens such as <i>Escherichia coli</i> (E. Coli), <i>Salmonella</i>, and <i>Listeria</i> monocytogenes continue to pose a major potential threat to global public health and therefore rapid, accurate, and field-deployable detection methods are still extremely desirable. This review describes cutting-edge examples of advanced biosensing platforms for the strategy of detecting these priority pathogens, focusing on clinical detection and highlighting electrochemical, optical, and microfluidic sensing modalities. This has been enabled by recent advances in functional nanomaterials, molecular recognition elements (including aptamers and nanozymes), and surface engineering strategies rendering sensors much &#x2018;smarter&#x2019;/improved in terms of sensitivity, specificity, and behaviour towards complex food matrices. However blending these biosensors with artificial intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) enabled intelligent pattern recognition, real-time analytics, and multiplexing at high-speed, turning traditional detection systems into smart diagnostic devices. We critically review recent case studies in light of biosensor design, signal transduction mechanisms, models of AI, performance validation, and applicability in different food environments. The principal challenges are identified which include matrix interference, instability of biorecognition elements, limitations in scalability, and the need for regulatory standardization. We discuss these with associated mitigation strategies that are technically sound, including ratiometric sensing, microfluidic pre-treatment techniques, explainable AI, and printable electronics. Forward-looking, we discuss biosensors enabled by being self-powered, biosensor hubs with modular pathogen panels, blockchain incorporation, and standardized validation pipelines. This review offers a prospective view toward enabling intelligent, robust, and regulation-ready biosensing platforms for next-generation food safety monitoring through the bridging of technological innovations with practical implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GRAPHICAL ABSTRACT">[Image: see text]</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assudani</LastName><ForeName>Purshottam J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Ramdeobaba University, Nagpur, 440013, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P</LastName><ForeName>Balakrishnan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore, 632014, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>A</LastName><ForeName>Anny Leema</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore, 632014, India. annyleema.a@vit.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>Gina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Applications, Auxilium College, Vellore, 632014, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avthankar</LastName><ForeName>Ankita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Institute of Technology, Nagpur Campus, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, 411057, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiwari</LastName><ForeName>Aditya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Applied Science, Ahmedabad University, Navrangpura, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, 380009, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhaiyya</LastName><ForeName>Manish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering and the Russell Berrie Nanotechnology Institute, Technion Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, 3200003, Israel. manishbhaiyya@ssgmce.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Telecommunication, Shri Sant Gajanan Maharaj College of Engineering, Shegaon, 444203, India. manishbhaiyya@ssgmce.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kulkarni</LastName><ForeName>Madhusudan B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal Academy of Higher Education (MAHE), Manipal, 576104, India. madhusudan.kulkarni@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Austria</Country><MedlineTA>Mikrochim Acta</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7808782</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0026-3672</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Foodborne illnesses caused by E. coli, Salmonella, and Listeria monocytogenes remain a global public health concern, driving the demand for rapid, accurate, and field-deployable detection strategies. This review comprehensively explores advanced biosensing platforms tailored for detecting these priority pathogens, highlighting progress in electrochemical, optical, and microfluidic sensing mechanisms. Integrating functional nanomaterials, molecular recognition elements such as aptamers and nanozymes, and surface engineering techniques has significantly enhanced sensor sensitivity, specificity, and adaptability to complex food matrices. Moreover, the convergence of biosensors with AI and ML has enabled intelligent pattern recognition, real-time analytics, and high-throughput multiplexing. Key challenges, including matrix interference, bioreceptor instability, manufacturing scalability, and regulatory standardization, are discussed.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Listeria monocytogenes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biosensors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrochemical sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food safety monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Foodborne pathogens</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanomaterials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optical sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Point-of-care-testing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41803510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12971809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00604-026-07976-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00604-026-07976-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mather AE, Gilmour MW, Reid SWJ, French NP (2024) Foodborne bacterial pathogens: genome-based approaches for enduring and emerging threats in a complex and changing world. Nat Rev Microbiol 22:543&#x2013;555. 10.1038/s41579-024-01051-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-024-01051-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38789668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaideh S, Olaimat AN, Al-Holy MA, Ababneh A, Shahbaz HM, Abughoush M, Al-Nabulsi A, Osaili T, Ayyash M, Holley RA (2024) The Influence of Technological Shifts in the Food Chain on the Emergence of Foodborne Pathogens: An Overview. Appl Microbiol 4:594&#x2013;606. 10.3390/applmicrobiol4020041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/applmicrobiol4020041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrukh M, Munawar A, Nawaz Z, Hussain N, Bin Hafeez A, Szweda P (2025) Antibiotic resistance and preventive strategies in foodborne pathogenic bacteria: a comprehensive review. Food Sci Biotechnol 34:2101&#x2013;2129. 10.1007/s10068-024-01767-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01767-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12064539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40351726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrucci S, Costa C, Broyles D, Dikici E, Daunert S, Deo S (2021) On-site detection of food and waterborne bacteria &#x2013; Current technologies, challenges, and future directions. Trends Food Sci Technol 115:409&#x2013;421. 10.1016/j.tifs.2021.06.054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2021.06.054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34267423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farid A, Wang Z, Khan MU, Wang P, Wang H, Liu H, Chen Z (2025) Emerging technologies for detecting foodborne pathogens and spoilage microorganisms in milk: Ensuring safety and quality. Food Microbiol 130:104763. 10.1016/j.fm.2025.104763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fm.2025.104763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40210394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S-O, Kim S-S (2021) Bacterial pathogen detection by conventional culture-based and recent alternative (polymerase chain reaction, isothermal amplification, enzyme linked immunosorbent assay, bacteriophage amplification, and gold nanoparticle aggregation) methods in food samp. J Food Saf 41:e12870. 10.1111/jfs.12870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfs.12870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabiraz MP, Majumdar PR, Mahmud MMC, Bhowmik S, Ali A (2023) Conventional and advanced detection techniques of foodborne pathogens: A comprehensive review. Heliyon 9:e15482. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e15482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e15482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10161726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37151686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wankhede PR, Bhuyar D, Zanwar S, Pawar R, Jadhav MR, Gandhewar N, Kulkarni MB, Bhaiyya M, Haick H (2025) Artif Intell Noninvasive Health Diagnostics ACS Sens 10:8217&#x2013;8255. 10.1021/acssensors.5c03171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssensors.5c03171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41165316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiruvengadam M, Kim J-T, Kim W-R, Kim J-Y, Jung B-S, Choi H-J, Chi H-Y, Govindasamy R, Kim S-H (2024) Safeguarding Public Health: Advanced Detection of Food Adulteration Using Nanoparticle-Based Sensors. Crit Rev Anal Chem 0:1&#x2013;21. 10.1080/10408347.2024.2399202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408347.2024.2399202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39269682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kumar Bhagat A, Bhaiyya M, Amreen K, Kumar Dubey S, Goel S (2024) A Machine Learning Approach for Simultaneous Electrochemical Detection of Dopamine and Serotonin in an Optimized Carbon Thread-Based Miniaturized Device. IEEE Sens J 24:21378&#x2013;21385. 10.1109/JSEN.2024.3386655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3386655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya M, Kumar PS, Pattnaik PK (2022) Stereolithography 3D printed electrochemiluminescence platform with random grade graphite electrodes: detection of H 2 O 2 and cholesterol using a smartphone. IEEE Sens J XX 1&#x2013;1. 10.1109/JSEN.2022.3221728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya M, Rewatkar P, Pattnaik PK, Goel S (2023) Novel 3D printed single electrode-based portable and miniaturized electrochemiluminescence platform to detect lactate from human serum. J Micromechanics Microengineering 33. 10.1088/1361-6439/acac3e</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal CM, Kaushik V, Awasthi A, Zalke JB, Palekar S, Rewatkar P, Srivastava SK, Kulkarni MB, Bhaiyya ML (2025) Deep Learning-Enhanced Portable Chemiluminescence Biosensor: 3D-Printed, Smartphone-Integrated Platform for Glucose Detection. Bioengineering 12:119. 10.3390/bioengineering12020119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering12020119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11851613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40001639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu M, Zheng M, Zhang J, Yang X, Zhang Y, Zhang W, Man C, Zhao Q, Jiang Y (2023) Recent advances on emerging biosensing technologies and on-site analytical devices for detection of drug-resistant foodborne pathogens. TrAC Trends Anal Chem 167:117258. 10.1016/j.trac.2023.117258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trac.2023.117258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Shi J, Liu J, Yuan Z, Gao S (2025) Advancing food safety surveillance: Rapid and sensitive biosensing technologies for foodborne pathogenic bacteria. Foods 14. 10.3390/foods14152654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12346877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40807591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya M, Pattnaik PK, Goel S (2022) Smartphone integrated 3D-printed standalone electrochemiluminescence platform for cholesterol detection. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/memea54994.2022.9856548</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya ML, Srivastava SK, Pattnaik PK, Goel S (2023) Closed-Bipolar Mini Electrochemiluminescence Sensor to Detect Various Biomarkers: A Machine Learning Approach. IEEE Trans Instrum Meas 72:1&#x2013;8. 10.1109/TIM.2023.3296819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2023.3296819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav N, Chhillar AK, Rana JS (2020) Detection of pathogenic bacteria with special emphasis to biosensors integrated with AuNPs. Sens Int 1:100028. 10.1016/j.sintl.2020.100028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sintl.2020.100028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya M, Pattnaik PK, Goel S (2021) Portable electrochemiluminescence platform with laser-induced graphene-based u-shaped bipolar electrode for selective sensing of various analytes. IEEE Trans Electron Devices 1&#x2013;8. 10.1109/TED.2021.3066083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobrinetskiy I, Radovic M, Rizzotto F, Vizzini P, Jaric S, Pavlovic Z, Radonic V, Nikolic M.V., Vidic J (2021) Advances in nanomaterials-based electrochemical biosensors for foodborne pathogen detection. Nanomaterials 11. 10.3390/nano11102700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8538910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34685143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Belwal T, Li L, Lin X, Xu Y, Luo Z (2020) Nanomaterial-based biosensors for sensing key foodborne pathogens: Advances from recent decades. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 19:1465&#x2013;1487. 10.1111/1541-4337.12576</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33337098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei Y, He C, Zeng W, Luo Y, Liu C, Yang M, Kuang Y, Lin X, Huang Q (2022) Electrochemical Biosensors for Foodborne Pathogens Detection Based on Carbon Nanomaterials: Recent Advances and Challenges. Food Bioprocess Technol 15:498&#x2013;513. 10.1007/s11947-022-02759-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11947-022-02759-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni MB, Ayachit NH, Aminabhavi TM (2023) Recent advances in microfluidics-based electrochemical sensors for foodborne pathogen detection. Biosensors 13. 10.3390/bios13020246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9954504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36832012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puiu M, Bala C (2020) Microfluidics-integrated biosensing platforms as emergency tools for on-site field detection of foodborne pathogens. TrAC Trends Anal Chem 125:115831. 10.1016/j.trac.2020.115831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trac.2020.115831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelbasset WK, Savina SV, Mavaluru D, Shichiyakh RA, Bokov DO, Mustafa YF (2023) Smartphone based aptasensors as intelligent biodevice for food contamination detection in food and soil samples: Recent advances. Talanta 252:123769. 10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123769</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36041314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S, Sun X, Zhao X (2025) Advances in smartphone-based biosensors for food testing. Curr Opin Food Sci 61:101236. 10.1016/j.cofs.2024.101236. https://doi.org/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cofs.2024.101236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva NFD, Neves MMPS, Magalh&#xe3;es JMCS, Freire C, Delerue-Matos C (2020) Emerging electrochemical biosensing approaches for detection of Listeria monocytogenes in food samples: An overview. Trends Food Sci Technol 99:621&#x2013;633. 10.1016/j.tifs.2020.03.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2020.03.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossettini A, Vidic J, Maifreni M, Marino M, Pinamonti D, Manzano M (2022) Rapid detection of Listeria monocytogenes, Salmonella, Campylobacter spp., and Escherichia coli in food using biosensors. Food Control 137:108962. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.108962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.108962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mkangara M (2023) Prevention and control of human salmonella enterica infections: an implication in food safety. Int J Food Sci 2023. 10.1155/2023/8899596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10506869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37727836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Wolfram A, Desin TS (2024) Advancements in Detection Methods for Salmonella in Food: A Comprehensive Review. Pathogens 13:1&#x2013;18. 10.3390/pathogens13121075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens13121075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11728791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39770335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Zhang Y, Tian F, Liu X, Du S, Ren G (2021) Overview of rapid detection methods for salmonella in foods: progress and challenges. Foods 10. 10.3390/foods10102402</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34681451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aladhadh M (2023) A review of modern methods for the detection of foodborne pathogens. Microorganisms 11. 10.3390/microorganisms11051111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10221273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37317085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos S, Silva V, de Lurdes Enes Dapkevicius M, Cani&#xe7;a M, Tejedor-Junco MT, Igrejas G, Poeta P (2020) Escherichia coli as commensal and pathogenic bacteria among food-producing animals: Health implications of extended spectrum &#x3b2;-lactamase (ESBL) production. Animals 10:1&#x2013;15. 10.3390/ani10122239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani10122239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7761174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S-O, Kim S-S (2021) Bacterial pathogen detection by conventional culture-based and recent alternative (polymerase chain reaction, isothermal amplification, enzyme linked immunosorbent assay, bacteriophage amplification, and gold nanoparticle aggregation) methods in food samples: A review. J Food Saf 41:e12870. 10.1111/jfs.12870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfs.12870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teklemariam AD, Al-Hindi RR, Albiheyri RS, Alharbi MG, Alghamdi MA, Filimban AAR, Al Mutiri AS, Al-Alyani AM, Alseghayer MS, Almaneea AM, Albar AH, Khormi MA, Bhunia AK (2023) Human salmonellosis: a continuous global threat in the farm-to-fork food safety continuum. Foods 12. 10.3390/foods12091756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10178548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37174295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamichhane B, Mawad AMM, Saleh M, Kelley WG, Harrington PJ 2, Lovestad CW, Amezcua J, Sarhan MM, El Zowalaty ME, Ramadan H, Morgan M, Helmy YA (2024) Salmonellosis: an overview of epidemiology, pathogenesis, and innovative approaches to mitigate the antimicrobial resistant infections. Antibiot (Basel Switzerland) 13. 10.3390/antibiotics13010076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10812683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38247636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tack DM, Kisselburgh HM, Richardson LC, Geissler A, Griffin PM, Payne DC, Gleason BL (2021) Shiga toxin-producing escherichia coli outbreaks in the United States, 2010&#x2013;2017. Microorganisms 9. 10.3390/microorganisms9071529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8307841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34361964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrick R, Song J, Fina L, Sawyer C, Jenkins C, King G, Turner D, Thomas D, Williams C (2025) Long-term health outcomes of Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli O157 (STEC O157) infection and STEC-associated haemolytic uraemic syndrome (STEC-HUS), Wales, 1990&#x2013;2020, Pediatr. Nephrol 40:2295&#x2013;2310. 10.1007/s00467-024-06640-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00467-024-06640-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12116988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39904896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Thaker H, Wang C, Xu Z, Dong M (2023) Diagnosis and treatment for shiga toxin-producing escherichia coli associated hemolytic uremic syndrome, Toxins (Basel). 15. 10.3390/toxins15010010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9862836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36668830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn OI, Jenkins C, Greig DR, Neale S, Jorgensen F, Yanshi T, Inns L, Allison L, Browning A, Douglas S, Balasegram (2025) An outbreak of Shiga Toxin-producing Escherichia coli Serotype O145:H28 Associated with Domestic Travel and Consumption of Unpasteurized Cheese, UK, 2023. J Food Prot 88:100470. 10.1016/j.jfp.2025.100470</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfp.2025.100470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39978549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singha S, Thomas R, Viswakarma JN, Gupta VK (2023) Foodborne illnesses of Escherichia coli O157origin and its control measures. J Food Sci Technol 60:1274&#x2013;1283. 10.1007/s13197-022-05381-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-022-05381-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36936116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwu CD, du Plessis E, Korsten L, Okoh AI (2021) Prevalence of E. coli O157:H7 strains in irrigation water and agricultural soil in two district municipalities in South Africa. Int J Environ Stud 78:474&#x2013;483. 10.1080/00207233.2020.1834318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207233.2020.1834318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The global burden of non-typhoidal (2019) Lancet Infect Dis 19:1312&#x2013;1324. 10.1016/S1473-3099(19)30418-9. salmonella invasive disease: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(19)30418-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billah MM, Rahman MS (2024) Salmonella in the environment: A review on ecology, antimicrobial resistance, seafood contaminations, and human health implications. J Hazard Mater Adv 13:100407. 10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popa GL, Papa MI (2021) Salmonella spp. infection - a continuous threat worldwide. Germs 11:88&#x2013;96. 10.18683/germs.2021.1244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18683/germs.2021.1244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morasi RM, Rall VLM, Dantas STA, Alonso VPP, Silva NCC (2022) Salmonella spp. in low water activity food: Occurrence, survival mechanisms, and thermoresistance. J Food Sci 87:2310&#x2013;2323. 10.1111/1750-3841.16152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.16152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35478321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osek J, Lachtara B, Wieczorek K (2022) Listeria monocytogenes &#x2013; How this pathogen survives in food-production environments? Front Microbiol 13. 10.3389/fmicb.2022.866462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9087598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35558128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuytschaever T, Raes K, Sampers I (2023) Listeria monocytogenes in food businesses: From persistence strategies to intervention/prevention strategies&#x2014;A review. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 22:3910&#x2013;3950. 10.1111/1541-4337.13219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.13219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37548605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurtler JB, Gibson KE (2022) Irrigation water and contamination of fresh produce with bacterial foodborne pathogens. Curr Opin Food Sci 47:100889. 10.1016/j.cofs.2022.100889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cofs.2022.100889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnino N, Basak S, Collineau L, Merle R (2025) Pathways of Escherichia coli transfer from animal manure: risks and mitigation in agriculture. Front Public Heal 13:1568621. 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1568621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1568621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12179161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40547474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chawla K, Saxena SS, Agre VC, Sharma A, Piveteau P, Sharma S (2026) Prevalence and dissemination of bacterial human pathogens in agricultural environments: A food safety and health concern. Food Res Int 223:117806. 10.1016/j.foodres.2025.117806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2025.117806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41360524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leone C, Xu X, Mishra A, Thippareddi H, Singh M (2024) Interventions to reduce Salmonella and Campylobacter during chilling and post-chilling stages of poultry processing: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Poult Sci 103:103492. 10.1016/j.psj.2024.103492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psj.2024.103492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10864810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38335673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang S, Chen X, Qu C (2021) Review controlling Listeria monocytogenes in ready-to-eat meat and poultry products: An overview of outbreaks, current legislations, challenges, and future prospects. Trends Food Sci Technol 116:24&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.tifs.2021.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2021.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu T, Meesrisom A, Luo Y, Dinh QN, Lin S, Yang M, Sharma A, Tang R, Zhang J, Jia Z, Millner PD, Pearlstein AJ, Zhang B (2021) Listeria monocytogenes biofilm formation as affected by stainless steel surface topography and coating composition. Food Control 130:108275. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Chen W, Fang Z, Yu Y, Bi J, Wang J, Dong Q, Zhang H (2022) Persistence of listeria monocytogenes ST5 in ready-to-eat food processing environment. Foods 11. 10.3390/foods11172561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9454991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36076746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambrechts K, Rip D (2024) Listeria monocytogenes in the seafood industry: Exploring contamination sources, outbreaks, antibiotic susceptibility and genetic diversity. Microbiologyopen 13:e70003. 10.1002/mbo3.70003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mbo3.70003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11486915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39420711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AC, de Almeida FA, Medeiros MM, Miranda BR, Pinto UM, Alves VF (2023) Listeria monocytogenes: An Inconvenient Hurdle for the Dairy Industry. Dairy 4:316&#x2013;344. 10.3390/dairy4020022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/dairy4020022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iulietto MF, Evers EG (2024) Cross-contamination in the kitchen: A model for quantitative microbiological risk assessment. Risk Anal 44:1156&#x2013;1175. 10.1111/risa.14232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/risa.14232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37806768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai H, Tang Y, Ren F, Jiao X-A, Huang J, 2023) Evaluation of hygiene practice for reducing campylobacter contamination on cutting boards and risks associated with chicken handling in kitchen environment. Foods (Basel, Switzerland) 12. 10.3390/foods12173245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10486554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37685178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kli&#x161;tincov&#xe1; N, Pin L, Pu&#x161;k&#xe1;rov&#xe1; A, Giannino D, Bu&#x10d;kov&#xe1; M, Lambreva MD, Manfredini A, Canfora L, Pangallo D, Pinzari F (2024) From farm to fork: Fungal and bacterial contaminants and their diagnostics in the production steps of ready-to-eat salads. Trends Food Sci Technol 150:104573. 10.1016/j.tifs.2024.104573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2024.104573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbehiry A, Marzouk E (2025) From farm to fork: antimicrobial-resistant bacterial pathogens in livestock production and the food chain. Vet Sci 12. 10.3390/vetsci12090862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12474250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41012787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viazis S, Bazaco MC, Blessington T, Seelman Federman SL, Lindsay M, Minor T, Nork B, Mattioli MC, Marshall KE, Wise ME, Weed B, Haendiges J, Gieraltowski L, Nolte K (2025) An Overview of Farm Investigation Findings Associated with Outbreaks of Shiga Toxin-Producing Escherichia coli Infections Linked to Leafy Greens: 2009&#x2013;2021. J Food Prot 88:100542. 10.1016/j.jfp.2025.100542</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfp.2025.100542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40398571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barola C, Brambilla G, Galarini R, Moretti S, Morabito S (2024) Assessment of the combined inputs of antimicrobials from top soil improvers and irrigation waters on green leafy vegetable fields. Food Addit \&amp; Contam Part A 41:313&#x2013;324. 10.1080/19440049.2024.2306930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19440049.2024.2306930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38295296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konfo TRC, Tchekessi CKC, Baba-Moussa FAK (2024) Status report on innovations and applications of smart bio-systems for real-time monitoring of food quality. Appl Food Res 4:100546. 10.1016/j.afres.2024.100546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.afres.2024.100546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing E, Chen H, Xin X, Cui H, Dou Y, Song S (2025) Recent advances in smart phone-based biosensors for various applications. Chemosensors 13. 10.3390/chemosensors13070221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farber JM, Zwietering M, Wiedmann M, Schaffner D, Hedberg CW, Harrison MA, Hartnett E, Chapman B, Donnelly CW, Goodburn KE, Gummalla S (2021) Alternative approaches to the risk management of Listeria monocytogenes in low risk foods. Food Control 123:107601. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2020.107601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2020.107601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend A, Strawn LK, Chapman BJ, Dunn LL (2021) A systematic review of listeria species and listeria monocytogenes prevalence, persistence, and diversity throughout the fresh produce supply chain. Foods (Basel, Switzerland) 10. 10.3390/foods10061427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8234284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34202947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad MA, Tarawneh H, Abu-Romman S, Akhter N, Rather JA (2025) Emerging analytical techniques for determination of foodborne pathogens and toxins: a review, Discov. Food 5:370. 10.1007/s44187-025-00590-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44187-025-00590-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell VR, Carson MS, Lao A, Maran K, Yang EJ, Kamei DT (2021) Point-of-Need Diagnostics for Foodborne Pathogen Screening. SLAS Technol 26:55&#x2013;79. 10.1177/2472630320962003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2472630320962003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33012245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan E, Amezquita A, Anderson N, Betts R, Blayo L, Garces-Vega F, Gkogka E, Harris LJ, McClure P, Winkler A (2021) H.M.W. den Besten, Guidance on validation of lethal control measures for foodborne pathogens in foods. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 20:2825&#x2013;2881. 10.1111/1541-4337.12746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33960599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinikebria S, Khazaei M, Dervisevic M, Judicpa MA, Tian J, Razal JM, Voelcker NH, Nilghaz A (2025) Electrochemical biosensors: The beacon for food safety and quality. Food Chem 475:143284. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.143284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.143284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39956060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;&#xc1;vila Oliveira B, Gomes RS, de Carvalho AM, Lima EMF, Pinto UM (2024) da Cunha, Revolutionizing food safety with electrochemical biosensors for rapid and portable pathogen detection. Brazilian J Microbiol [Publication Brazilian Soc Microbiol 55:2511&#x2013;2525. 10.1007/s42770-024-01427-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42770-024-01427-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11405362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38922532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas SK, Islam MS, Jia F, Cao Y, Li Y (2024) (Chase) Cao, flexible biosensors for food pathogen detection. Adv Electron Mater 10:2300898. 10.1002/aelm.202300898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aelm.202300898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, Li H, Chen J, Chiu Lai KW, Xiong L, Yang R (2024) Microfluidics enhanced biosensor technology for advancing food safety monitoring. Trends Food Sci Technol 149:104556. 10.1016/j.tifs.2024.104556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2024.104556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guruprasath N, Sankarganesh P, Adeyeye SAO, Babu AS, Parthasarathy V (2024) Review on emerging applications of nanobiosensor in food safety. J Food Sci 89:3950&#x2013;3972. 10.1111/1750-3841.17149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.17149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38847752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad SI, Saleh RO, ali alzahrani A, Vasudevan A, Kareem AK, Prasad KDV, Bhupathi P, Hafsan H, Sead F, Mustafa YF (2025) Advances in colorimetric-photothermal dual-mode biosensors for food safety: Mechanism, applications and challenges, Talanta 128838. 10.1016/j.talanta.2025.128838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40945482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parakh A, Awate A, Barman SM, Kadu RK, Tulaskar DP, Kulkarni MB, Bhaiyya M (2025) Artificial intelligence and machine learning for colorimetric detections: Techniques, applications, and future prospects. Trends Environ Anal Chem 48:e00280. 10.1016/j.teac.2025.e00280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.teac.2025.e00280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan A, Kumar PS, Hemavathy RV, Jeevanantham S, Kamalesh R, Sneha S, Yaashikaa PR (2021) Methods of detection of food-borne pathogens: a review. Environ Chem Lett 19:189&#x2013;207. 10.1007/s10311-020-01072-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-020-01072-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce-Tagoe TA, Bhaskar S, Kavle RR, Jeevanandam J, Acquah C, Ohemeng-Boahen G, Agyei D, Danquah MK (2024) Advances in aptamer-based biosensors for monitoring foodborne pathogens. J Food Sci Technol 61:1252&#x2013;1271. 10.1007/s13197-023-05889-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-023-05889-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11190136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38910921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Wang Y, Lu X (2021) Molecular imprinting technology for sensing foodborne pathogenic bacteria. Anal Bioanal Chem 413:4581&#x2013;4598. 10.1007/s00216-020-03138-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00216-020-03138-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33564924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daramola OB, Omole RK, Akinsanola BA (2025) Emerging applications of biorecognition elements-based optical biosensors for food safety monitoring. Discov Sens 1:3. 10.1007/s44397-025-00003-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44397-025-00003-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Cheng J-H, Ma J, Zhou C, Sun D-W (2025) Elevating nanomaterial optical sensor arrays through the integration of advanced machine learning techniques for enhancing visual inspection of food quality and safety. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 65:3628&#x2013;3649. 10.1080/10408398.2024.2376113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2024.2376113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39015031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Wang H, Lu X, Zheng X, Yang Z (2023) Recent Advances in Electrochemical Biosensors for the Detection of Foodborne Pathogens: Current Perspective and Challenges. Foods 12. 10.3390/foods12142795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10379338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37509887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S-H, You Y (2024) Gold Nanoparticle-Based Colorimetric Biosensing for Foodborne Pathogen Detection. Foods 13. 10.3390/foods13010095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10778349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38201122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younes N, Yassine HM, Kourentzi K, Tang P, Litvinov D, Willson RC, Abu-Raddad LJ, Nasrallah GK (2024) A review of rapid food safety testing: using lateral flow assay platform to detect foodborne pathogens. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 64:9910&#x2013;9932. 10.1080/10408398.2023.2217921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2023.2217921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37350754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintela IA, Vasse T, Lin C-S, Wu VCH (2022) Advances, applications, and limitations of portable and rapid detection technologies for routinely encountered foodborne pathogens. Front Microbiol Volume 13. 10.3389/fmicb.2022.1054782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabi H, Majidi MR, Khaki P, Jahanban-Esfahlan A, de la Guardia M, Mokhtarzadeh A (2022) State of the art: Lateral flow assays toward the point-of-care foodborne pathogenic bacteria detection in food samples. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 21:1868&#x2013;1912. 10.1111/1541-4337.12913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Lan X, Zhu L, Ru P, Xu W, Liu H (2022) PCR Mediated Nucleic Acid Molecular Recognition Technology for Detection of Viable and Dead Foodborne Pathogens. Foods (Basel Switzerland) 11. 10.3390/foods11172675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9455676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36076861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinh KTL, Lee NY (2022) Recent Methods for the Viability Assessment of Bacterial Pathogens: Advances, Challenges, and Future Perspectives. Pathogens 11. 10.3390/pathogens11091057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36145489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azinheiro S, Ghimire D, Carvalho J, Prado M, Garrido-Maestu A (2022) Next-day detection of viable Listeria monocytogenes by multiplex reverse transcriptase real-time PCR. Food Control 133:108593. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang L, Gong J, Shen Q, Yang J, Song C, Liu Q, Zhao B, Zhang Y, Zhu M (2023) Advances in detection methods for viable Salmonella spp.: current applications and challenges. Anal Sci 39:1643&#x2013;1660. 10.1007/s44211-023-00384-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44211-023-00384-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H, Dong K, Rao L, Zhao L, Wu X, Wang Y, Liao X (2020) Quantitative detection of viable but nonculturable state Escherichia coli O157:H7 by ddPCR combined with propidium monoazide. Food Control 112:107140. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2020.107140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2020.107140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thilakarathna SH, Stokowski T, Chui L (2022) An Improved Real-Time Viability PCR Assay to Detect Salmonella in a Culture-Independent Era. Int J Mol Sci 23. 10.3390/ijms232314708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9738789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36499040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Qu B, Lee B (2023) Propidium monoazide-treated, cell-direct, quantitative PCR for detecting viable chloramphenicol-resistant escherichia coli and corynebacterium glutamicum Cells. Genes (Basel) 14. 10.3390/genes14122135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10743000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38136957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Zhang Y, Lin J, Liu Y (2021) Biosensors coupled with signal amplification technology for the detection of pathogenic bacteria: a review. Biosensors 11. 10.3390/bios11060190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34207580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhamied N, Abdelrahman F, El-Shibiny A, Hassan RYA (2023) Bacteriophage-based nano-biosensors for the fast impedimetric determination of pathogens in food samples. Sci Rep 13:3498. 10.1038/s41598-023-30520-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-30520-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9977096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36859463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen MM, Gil J, Brown M, Cesar Tondo E, Soraya Martins de Aquino N, Eisenberg M, Erickson S (2020) Accurate and sensitive detection of Salmonella in foods by engineered bacteriophages. Sci Rep 10:17463. 10.1038/s41598-020-74587-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-74587-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra A, Roy S, Israel Shaikh N, Malave P, Mishra A, Anish Alam M, Ghorpade Y, Rahil Hasan M, Nizam A (2024) Recent advances in multiplex aptasensor detection techniques for food-borne pathogens: A comprehensive review of novel approaches. Biosens Bioelectron X 16:100417. 10.1016/j.biosx.2023.100417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biosx.2023.100417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Liu Y, Yin J, Yue M, Mu Y (2021) Microfluidic devices for multiplexed detection of foodborne pathogens. Food Res Int 143:110246. 10.1016/j.foodres.2021.110246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2021.110246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33992358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Ma C, Du Y, Huang J, Xue L (2025) Microfluidic biosensors for rapid detection of foodborne pathogenic bacteria: recent advances and future perspectives. Front Chem Volume 13&#x2013;2025. 10.3389/fchem.2025.1536928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11815284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shruti A, Bage N, Kar P (2024) Nanomaterials based sensors for analysis of food safety. Food Chem 433:137284. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2023.137284. https://doi.org/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2023.137284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37703589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafi Z, Khan H, Husain A, Khanam A, Alafnan A, Alobaida A, Shahab U, Ahmad I, Ahmad S (2025) Food contamination and the emerging application of nanobiosensors in food safety. J Food Sci 90:e70073. 10.1111/1750-3841.70073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.70073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39949290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S, Han L, Chen M, Pan L, Tu K (2024) Recent progress in nanomaterial-based fluorescence assays for the detection of food-borne pathogens. Sensors 24. 10.3390/s24237715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11644946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39686252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumalasari MR, Alfanaar R, Andreani AS (2024) Gold nanoparticles (AuNPs): A versatile material for biosensor application. Talanta Open 9:100327. 10.1016/j.talo.2024.100327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talo.2024.100327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirzad H, Panji M, Nezhad SAM, Houshmand P, Tamai IA (2024) One-pot rapid visual detection of E. coli O157:H7 by label-free AuNP-based plasmonic-aptasensor in water sample. J Microbiol Methods 217&#x2013;218:106858. 10.1016/j.mimet.2023.106858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mimet.2023.106858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38040292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennacchio A, Giampaolo F, Cafaro V, Cicatiello P, Della Ventura B, Giardina P, Rosanova R, Savoia M, Velotta R, Piccialli F, Piscitelli A (2024) A bacterial biosensor based on gold nanoparticles functionalized by a hydrophobin-chimera and combined with machine learning for user-friendly detection. Sens Actuators B Chem 410:135645. 10.1016/j.snb.2024.135645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2024.135645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Wang Z, Song Y, Yang X, Chen S, Fu S, Qin X, Zhang W, Man C, Jiang Y (2021) A novel smartphone-based colorimetric aptasensor for on-site detection of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in milk. J Dairy Sci 104:8506&#x2013;8516. 10.3168/jds.2020-19905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2020-19905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y, Cai S, Ye Q, Wu Q, Shao Y, Qu X, Xiang X, Zhou B, Ding Y, Chen M, Xue L, Zhu H, Zhang J (2022) Quantum Dot Nanobeads-Labelled Lateral Flow Immunoassay Strip for Rapid and Sensitive Detection of Salmonella Typhimurium Based on Strand Displacement Loop-Mediated Isothermal Amplification. Engineering 19:62&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.eng.2021.03.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2021.03.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L, Jin W, Xiong K, Zhen H, Li M, Hu Y (2023) Nanomaterial-based biosensors for the detection of foodborne bacteria: a review. Analyst 148:5790&#x2013;5804. 10.1039/D3AN01554H</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3AN01554H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37855707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Zhang J, Zheng M, Zhong Y, Yang J, Zhao Y, Wu W, Ye W, Wen J, Wang Q, Lu J (2012) An Aptamer-Based Biosensor for Colorimetric Detection of Escherichia coli O157:H7. PLoS ONE 7:1&#x2013;9. 10.1371/journal.pone.0048999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0048999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3492178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23145045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prattis I, Hui E, Gubeljak P, Kaminski Schierle GS, Lombardo A, Occhipinti LG (2021) Graphene for Biosensing Applications in Point-of-Care Testing. Trends Biotechnol 39:1065&#x2013;1077. 10.1016/j.tibtech.2021.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tibtech.2021.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahmy HM, Abu Serea ES, Salah-Eldin RE, Al-Hafiry SA, Ali MK, Shalan AE, Lanceros-M&#xe9;ndez S (2022) Recent Progress in Graphene- and Related Carbon-Nanomaterial-based Electrochemical Biosensors for Early Disease Detection. ACS Biomater Sci \&amp; Eng 8:964&#x2013;1000. 10.1021/acsbiomaterials.1c00710</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsbiomaterials.1c00710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venegas CJ, Bollo S, Sierra-Rosales P (2023) Carbon-based electrochemical (Bio)sensors for the detection of carbendazim: A Review. Micromachines 14. 10.3390/mi14091752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10536525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei S, Dou Y, Li T (2023) Ultra-sensitive and label-free detection of Escherichia coli O157:H7 using graphene-based field effect transistor modified with heat-denatured casein. Microchem J 193:109049. 10.1016/j.microc.2023.109049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2023.109049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei S, Dou Y, Song S, Li T (2023) Effect transistor-based biosensor for ultrasensitive and label-free detection of &#x3b2;-galactosidase produced by escherichia coli. Biosensors 13. 10.3390/bios13100925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10605438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37887118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revathi D, Panda S, Deshmukh K, Khotele N, Murthy VRK, Pasha SKK (2025) Smart hydrogels for sensing and biosensing &#x2013; Preparation, smart behaviours, and emerging applications &#x2013; A comprehensive review. Polym Test 150:108912. 10.1016/j.polymertesting.2025.108912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymertesting.2025.108912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, di Marco G, Iudin D, Viola M, van Nostrum CF, van Ravensteijn BGP, Vermonden T (2023) Stimuli-Responsive Hydrogels: The Dynamic Smart Biomaterials of Tomorrow. Macromolecules 56:8377&#x2013;8392. 10.1021/acs.macromol.3c00967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.macromol.3c00967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38024154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Zhou S, Zhang Y, Wu H, Li T, Tan L, Gan N, He J (2025) Phage/aptamer dual-encoded hydrogel arrays integrated with microfluidic platforms for simultaneous detection of multiple food pathogens. Talanta 294:128209. 10.1016/j.talanta.2025.128209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2025.128209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40288193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X, Zhou L (2025) Progress, challenge and perspective of hydrogels application in food: a review. Npj Sci Food 9:155. 10.1038/s41538-025-00521-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41538-025-00521-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12304481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40721617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Chen R, Yang S, Li S, Gao Z (2022) Design and application of stimuli-responsive DNA hydrogels: A review. Mater Today Bio 16:100430. 10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9493390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty J, Chaudhary AA, Khan S-U-D, Rudayni HA, Rahaman SM, Sarkar H (2022) CRISPR/Cas-Based Biosensor As a New Age Detection Method for Pathogenic Bacteria. ACS Omega 7:39562&#x2013;39573. 10.1021/acsomega.2c04513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c04513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Lyon CJ, Wang J, Lu S, Hu TY (2023) CRISPR Assays for Disease Diagnosis: Progress to and Barriers Remaining for Clinical Applications. Adv Sci 10:2301697. 10.1002/advs.202301697</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202301697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10369298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37162202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Du P, Shao Y, Wang W, Liu Y, Ma Y, Hu P, Cao J, Wang X (2024) Abd El-Aty, An Innovative and Efficient Fluorescent Detection Technique for Salmonella in Animal-Derived Foods Using the CRISPR/Cas12a-HCR System Combined with PCR/RAA. J Agric Food Chem 72:8831&#x2013;8839. 10.1021/acs.jafc.3c08829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.3c08829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38575365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Miller M, Wang Y-C (2022) Recent advances in CRISPR-based systems for the detection of foodborne pathogens. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 21:3010&#x2013;3029. 10.1111/1541-4337.12956</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35483732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie S, Yue Y, Yang F (2024) Recent advances in CRISPR/Cas system-based biosensors for the detection of foodborne pathogenic microorganisms. Micromachines 15. 10.3390/mi15111329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11596558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39597141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Zeng R, Tian S, Chen S, Bi Z, Tang D, Knopp D (2024) Bimetallic Single-Atom Nanozyme-Based Electrochemical-Photothermal Dual-Function Portable Immunoassay with Smartphone Imaging. Anal Chem 96:13663&#x2013;13671. 10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11339724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39126679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Xu X, Song Y, Huang J, Xu H (2024) Research progress of nanozymes in colorimetric biosensing: Classification, activity and application. Chem Eng J 487:150612. 10.1016/j.cej.2024.150612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.150612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y, Li Y, Li Y, Tian L (2024) Advanced Biological Applications of Cerium Oxide Nanozymes in Disease Related to Oxidative Damage. ACS Omega 9:8601&#x2013;8614. 10.1021/acsomega.3c03661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c03661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10905716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38434816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Tirado E, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Sede&#xf1;o P, Pingarr&#xf3;n JM (2023) Carbon-based enzyme mimetics for electrochemical biosensing. Micromachines 14. 10.3390/mi14091746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10538133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Tang L, Gao F, Li Y, Liu J, Zheng J (2021) DNA-encoded bimetallic Au-Pt dumbbell nanozyme for high-performance detection and eradication of Escherichia coli O157:H7, Biosens. Bioelectron 187:113327. 10.1016/j.bios.2021.113327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2021.113327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Z, Du T, Liang X, Wang X, Zhao L, Sun J, Wang J, Zhang W (2022) Nanozymes for foodborne microbial contaminants detection: Mechanisms, recent advances, and challenges. Food Control 141:109165. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.109165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.109165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L, Li Y, Zhang W, Han X, Wu Q, Xie Y, Fan J, Ma L (2023) Detection Methods for Foodborne Viruses: Current State-of-Art and Future Perspectives. J Agric Food Chem 71:3551&#x2013;3563. 10.1021/acs.jafc.2c06537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.2c06537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitrogiannopoulou AM, Tselepi V, Ellinas K (2023) Polymeric and paper-based lab-on-a-chip devices in food safety: a review. Micromachines 14. 10.3390/mi14050986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10223399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonchamps P-L, He Y, Wang K, Lu X (2022) Detection of pathogens in foods using microfluidic lab-on-chip: A mini review. J Agric Food Res 10:100430. 10.1016/j.jafr.2022.100430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jafr.2022.100430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayan H, Zhou R, Zheng Y, Xue S, Yin L, El-Seedi HR, Zou X, Guo Z (2025) Microfluidic-SERS platform with in-situ nanoparticle synthesis for rapid E. coli detection in food. Food Chem 471:142800. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.142800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.142800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39788011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fande S, Amreen K, Sriram D, Goel S (2023) Microfluidic electrochemical device for real-time culturing and interference-free detection of Escherichia coli. Anal Chim Acta 1237:340591. 10.1016/j.aca.2022.340591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2022.340591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36442949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puiu M, Bala C (2020) Microfluidics-integrated biosensing platforms as emergency tools for on-site field detection of foodborne pathogens. TrAC - Trends Anal Chem 125:115831. 10.1016/j.trac.2020.115831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trac.2020.115831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broten CJ, Wydallis JB, Reilly TH, Bisha B (2022) Development and evaluation of a paper-based microfluidic device for detection of listeria monocytogenes on food contact and non-food contact surfaces. Foods 11. 10.3390/foods11070947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35407034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie M, Chen T, Xin X, Cai Z, Dong C, Lei B (2022) Multiplex detection of foodborne pathogens by real-time loop-mediated isothermal amplification on a digital microfluidic chip. Food Control 136:108824. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.108824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.108824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man Y, Ban M, Jin X, Li A, Tao J, Pan L (2023) An integrated distance-based microfluidic aptasensor for visual quantitative detection of Salmonella with sample-in-answer-out capability. Sens Actuators B Chem 381:1&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.snb.2023.133480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2023.133480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Hu Y, Lu X (2023) Polyethersulfone-Based Microfluidic Device Integrated with DNA Extraction on Paper and Recombinase Polymerase Amplification for the Detection of Salmonella enterica. ACS Sens 8:2331&#x2013;2339. 10.1021/acssensors.3c00387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssensors.3c00387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang X, Shang Y, Ye Q, Li F, Zhang J, Zhou B, Suo H, Chen M, Gu Q, Ding Y, Wu Q (2022) A Salmonella serogroup rapid identification system for food safety based on high throughput microfluidic chip combined with recombinase aided amplification. Sens Actuators B Chem 357:131402. 10.1016/j.snb.2022.131402</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2022.131402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei S, Wang F, Zhang L, Zhao C, Li J, Wang J (2023) A portable smartphone-assisted highly emissive magnetic covalent organic framework-based fluorescence sensor for the detection of Salmonella typhimurium. Sens Actuators B Chem 392:134076. 10.1016/j.snb.2023.134076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2023.134076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei S, Su Z, Bu X, Shi X, Pang B, Zhang L, Li J, Zhao C (2022) On-site colorimetric detection of Salmonella typhimurium. Npj Sci Food 6:1&#x2013;8. 10.1038/s41538-022-00164-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41538-022-00164-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9576709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36253410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang H, Jiang R, Guo X, Cheng J, Chen Y (2022) A Review of IoT-Enabled Mobile Healthcare: Technologies, Challenges, and Future Trends. IEEE Internet Things J 9:9478&#x2013;9502. 10.1109/JIOT.2022.3144400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2022.3144400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Wang Z, Song Y, Yang X, Chen S, Fu S, Qin X, Zhang W, Man C, Jiang Y (2021) A novel smartphone-based colorimetric aptasensor for on-site detection of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in milk. J Dairy Sci 104:8506&#x2013;8516. 10.3168/jds.2020-19905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2020-19905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Q, Chen X, Qi L, Yang H, Wang Y, Zhang M, Huang K, Yuan X (2023) Smartphone readable colorimetry and ICP-MS dual-mode sensing platform for ultrasensitive and label-free detection of Escherichia coli based on filter-assisted separation. Talanta 251:123760. 10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35964515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing G, Li N, Lin H, Shang Y, Pu Q, Lin JM (2023) Microfluidic biosensor for one-step detection of multiplex foodborne bacteria ssDNA simultaneously by smartphone. Talanta 253:123980. 10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36201954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai X, Huang J, Li W, Song Y, Xiao F, Xu Q, Xu H (2023) Portable dual-mode biosensor based on smartphone and glucometer for on-site sensitive detection of Listeria monocytogenes. Sci Total Environ 874:162450. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.162450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.162450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36863591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahari S, Prakashan D, Gandhi S (2023) Immunochromatographic assay for the point-of-care diagnosis of food borne Salmonella strains using smartphone application. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces 226:113319. 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2023.113319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2023.113319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37120932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F, Li W, Wang Z, Xu Q, Song Y, Huang J, Bai X, Xu H (2023) Smartphone-assisted biosensor based on broom-like bacteria-specific magnetic enrichment platform for colorimetric detection of Listeria monocytogenes. J Hazard Mater 459:132250. 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.132250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.132250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37567141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min HJ, Mina HA, Deering AJ, Bae E (2021) Development of a smartphone-based lateral-flow imaging system using machine-learning classifiers for detection of Salmonella spp. J Microbiol Methods 188:106288. 10.1016/j.mimet.2021.106288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mimet.2021.106288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, He X, Zhang T, Zhao K, Xiao C, Tong Z, Jin L, He N, Deng Y, Li S, Guo Y, Chen Z (2022) Highly sensitive smartphone-based detection of Listeria monocytogenes using SYTO9. Chin Chem Lett 33:1933&#x2013;1935. 10.1016/j.cclet.2021.11.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2021.11.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostajabodavati S, Mousavizadegan M, Hosseini M, Mohammadimasoudi M, Mohammadi J (2024) Machine learning-assisted liquid crystal-based aptasensor for the specific detection of whole-cell Escherichia coli in water and food. Food Chem 448:139113. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.139113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.139113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38552467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Z, Luo Y, Wang D, Holliday E, Sharma A, Green MM, Roche MR, Thompson-Witrick K, Flock G, Pearlstein AJ, Yu H, Zhang B (2024) Surveillance of pathogenic bacteria on a food matrix using machine-learning-enabled paper chromogenic arrays. Biosens Bioelectron 248:115999. 10.1016/j.bios.2024.115999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2024.115999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38183791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang R, Park B, Ouyang Q, Ren N (2021) Rapid identification of foodborne bacteria with hyperspectral microscopic imaging and artificial intelligence classification algorithms. Food Control 130:108379. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2021.108379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostajabodavati S, Mousavizadegan M, Hosseini M, Mohammadimasoudi M, Mohammadi J (2024) Machine learning-assisted liquid crystal-based aptasensor for the specific detection of whole-cell Escherichia coli in water and food. Food Chem 448:139113. 10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.139113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.139113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38552467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Gan Z, Zhou X, Chen Z (2022) Accurate classification of Listeria species by MALDI-TOF mass spectrometry incorporating denoising autoencoder and machine learning. J Microbiol Methods 192:106378. 10.1016/j.mimet.2021.106378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mimet.2021.106378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34818574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Xu X, Feng S, Zhang H, Xu L, Jiang H, Sun B, Meng Y, Chen W (2023) Rapid identification of salmonella serovars by using Raman spectroscopy and machine learning algorithm. Talanta 253:123807. 10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2022.123807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi J, Wisuthiphaet N, Raja P, Nitin N, Earles JM (2023) AI-enabled biosensing for rapid pathogen detection: From liquid food to agricultural water. Water Res 242:120258. 10.1016/j.watres.2023.120258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2023.120258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37390659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gmeiner A, Njage PMK, Hansen LT, Aarestrup FM, Leekitcharoenphon P (2024) Predicting Listeria monocytogenes virulence potential using whole genome sequencing and machine learning. Int J Food Microbiol 410:110491. 10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2023.110491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2023.110491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38000216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Cheng Z, Wei X, Chen M, Zhang J, Zhang Y, Xue L, Chen M, Li F, Shang Y, Liang T, Ding Y, Wu Q (2022) Novel method for rapid identification of Listeria monocytogenes based on metabolomics and deep learning. Food Control 139:109042. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.109042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.109042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Wang S, Qiu J, Li M, Li D, Xu D, Li D, Liu Q (2021) Raman spectroscopy combined with machine learning for rapid detection of food-borne pathogens at the single-cell level. Talanta 226. 10.1016/j.talanta.2021.122195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benefo EO, Karanth S, Pradhan AK (2024) A machine learning approach to identifying Salmonella stress response genes in isolates from poultry processing. Food Res Int 175:113635. 10.1016/j.foodres.2023.113635</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2023.113635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38128977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingle RG, Zeng S, Jiang H, Fang W-J (2022) Current developments of bioanalytical sample preparation techniques in pharmaceuticals. J Pharm Anal 12:517&#x2013;529. 10.1016/j.jpha.2022.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpha.2022.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9463481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue L, Jiang F, Xi X, Li Y, Lin J (2023) Lab-on-chip separation and biosensing of pathogens in agri-food. Trends Food Sci Technol 137:92&#x2013;103. 10.1016/j.tifs.2023.04.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2023.04.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai K, Nonnenmann MW, Rohlman D, Baker KK (2023) Development of shortened enrichment methods for detection of salmonella typhimurium spiked in milk. ACS Food Sci \&amp; Technol 3:831&#x2013;837. 10.1021/acsfoodscitech.2c00310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsfoodscitech.2c00310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10204049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena S, Sen P, Soleymani L, Hoare T (2024) Anti-fouling polymer or peptide-modified electrochemical biosensors for improved biosensing in complex media. Adv Sens Res 3:2300170. 10.1002/adsr.202300170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adsr.202300170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu D, Doldur AN, Cavdar D, Ozkan G, Ceylan FD (2025) Current methodologies for assessing protein&#x2013;phenolic interactions. Discov Food 5:331. 10.1007/s44187-025-00573-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44187-025-00573-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akka&#x15f; T, Reshadsedghi M, &#x15e;en M, K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7; V, Horzum N (2025) The role of artificial intelligence in advancing biosensor technology: past, present, and future perspectives. Adv Mater 37:2504796. 10.1002/adma.202504796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202504796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40522091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Dekker M, Heising J, Zhao L, Fogliano V (2024) Food matrix design can influence the antimicrobial activity in the food systems: A narrative review. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 64:8963&#x2013;8989. 10.1080/10408398.2023.2205937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2023.2205937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37154045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizinti C, Soulis D, Kourti D, Geka G, Kokkinos C, Thompson M, Nemtsov L, Speliotis T, Economou A (2025) Microfabricated electrochemical aptasensing chip modified with dual-function antifouling linker for single-drop label-free assay of oxytetracycline in milk. Microchim Acta 192:527. 10.1007/s00604-025-07387-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00604-025-07387-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12304045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40719766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kogularasu S, Lin W-C, Lee Y-Y, Huang B-W, Chen Y-L, Chang-Chien G-P, Sheu J-K (2024) Advancements in electrochemical biosensing of cardiovascular disease biomarkers. J Mater Chem B 12:6305&#x2013;6327. 10.1039/D4TB00333K</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4TB00333K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38912548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kourti D, Geka G, Nemtsov L, Ahmadi S, Economou A, Thompson M (2024) Electrochemical aptasensor with antifouling properties for label-free detection of oxytetracycline. Sens (Basel) 24. 10.3390/s24175488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11398099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39275399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engku Abd Rahman ENS, Irekeola AA, Yusof NY, Yean CY (2026) Enhancing food safety: A systematic review of electrochemical biosensors for pathogen detection &#x2013; advancements, limitations, and practical challenges. Food Control 179:111603. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2025.111603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2025.111603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Liu X, Xiong Z, Wang G, Ai L (2024) Research progress on detection of foodborne pathogens: The more rapid and accurate answer to food safety. Food Res Int 193:114767. 10.1016/j.foodres.2024.114767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2024.114767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39160035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonker M, Sahore V, Woolley AT (2017) Recent advances in microfluidic sample preparation and separation techniques for molecular biomarker analysis: A critical review. Anal Chim Acta 986:1&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.aca.2017.07.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2017.07.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5657502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28870312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Sharma A, Ahmed A, Sundramoorthy A.K., Furukawa H, Arya S, Khosla A (2021) Recent advances in electrochemical biosensors: applications, challenges, and future scope. Biosensors 11. 10.3390/bios11090336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8472208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34562926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Wang X, Ren J, Lin F, Wu J (2022) Recent advances in acoustofluidic separation technology in biology. Microsystems Nanoeng 8:94. 10.1038/s41378-022-00435-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41378-022-00435-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36060525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Huang K, Cheng N (2023) Recent advances in nanozyme-mediated strategies for pathogen detection and control. Int J Mol Sci 24. 10.3390/ijms241713342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10487713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37686145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Zhou S, Wang G, Yun Y, Liu G, Zhang W (2021) Nanozyme applications: a glimpse of insight in food safety. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 9. 10.3389/fbioe.2021.727886</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8421533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadian S, Kumari P, Shukla S, Narayan R (2023) Recent advancements in machine learning enabled portable and wearable biosensors. Talanta Open 8:100267. 10.1016/j.talo.2023.100267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talo.2023.100267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Yang T, Wang J-H (2024) Recent advances in sensor arrays aided by machine learning for pathogen identification. Sens Diagn 3:1590&#x2013;1612. 10.1039/D4SD00229F</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4SD00229F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovakimyan G, Bravo JM (2024) Evolving strategies in machine learning: a systematic review of concept drift detection. Information 15. 10.3390/info15120786</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C, Gadgil SU, Lee S-I (2025) Transparency of medical artificial intelligence systems. Nat Rev Bioeng. 10.1038/s44222-025-00363-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44222-025-00363-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhou J, Wang H (2024) Bioreceptors as the key components for electrochemical biosensing in medicine. Cell Rep Phys Sci 5:101801. 10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J-W, Kurosawa S, Aizawa H, Wakida S, Yamada S, Ishihara K (2003) Comparison of stabilizing effect of stabilizers for immobilized antibodies on QCM immunosensors. Sens Actuators B Chem 91:158&#x2013;162. 10.1016/S0925-4005(03)00082-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0925-4005(03)00082-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14609060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta U, Gupta V, Arun RK, Chanda N (2022) Recent advances in enzymatic biosensors for point-of-care detection of biomolecules. Biotechnol Bioeng 119:3393&#x2013;3407. 10.1002/bit.28251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.28251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36207787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L-C, Wang E, Tai C-S, Chiu Y-C, Li C-W, Lin Y-R, Lee T-H, Huang C-W, Chen J-C, Chen WL (2020) Improving the reproducibility, accuracy, and stability of an electrochemical biosensor platform for point-of-care use. Biosens Bioelectron 155:112111. 10.1016/j.bios.2020.112111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2020.112111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Luo D, Zhang Y, Niu X, Liu H (2025) Smart Health Monitoring: Review of Electrochemical Biosensors for Cortisol Monitoring. Adv Healthc Mater 14:2404454. 10.1002/adhm.202404454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adhm.202404454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40099568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Shen J, Qin Y, Hayilati B, Yao J, Zhang M Research progress on the application of aptamer optimization technology and portable sensing devices in food safety detection. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr (n d) 1&#x2013;33. 10.1080/10408398.2024.2436647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39625446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spring SA, Goggins S, Frost CG (2021) Ratiometric electrochemistry: improving the robustness, reproducibility and reliability of biosensors. Molecules 26. 10.3390/molecules26082130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villalonga A, P&#xe9;rez-Calabuig AM, Villalonga R (2020) Electrochemical biosensors based on nucleic acid aptamers. Anal Bioanal Chem 412:55&#x2013;72. 10.1007/s00216-019-02226-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00216-019-02226-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31912182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshmukh MT, Wankhede PR, Chakole N, Kale PD, Jadhav MR, Kulkarni MB, Bhaiyya M (2025) Towards intelligent food safety: machine learning approaches for aflatoxin detection and risk prediction. Trends Food Sci Technol 105055. 10.1016/j.tifs.2025.105055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaiyya M, Panigrahi D, Rewatkar P, Haick H (2024) Role of Machine Learning Assisted Biosensors in Point-of-Care-Testing For Clinical Decisions. ACS Sens 9:4495&#x2013;4519. 10.1021/acssensors.4c01582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssensors.4c01582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11443532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39145721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik S, Singh J, Saini K, Chaudhary V, Umar A, Ibrahim AA, Akbar S, Baskoutas S (2024) Paper-based sensors: affordable versatile and emerging analyte detection platforms. Anal Methods 16:2777&#x2013;2809. 10.1039/D3AY02258G</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3AY02258G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38639474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenani H, Saeidi M, Rastkhiz MA, Bolghanabadi N, Aghaii AH, Orouji M, Hatamie A, Simchi A (2024) Challenges and Advances of Hydrogel-Based Wearable Electrochemical Biosensors for Real-Time Monitoring of Biofluids: From Lab to Market. A Review. Anal Chem 96:8160&#x2013;8183. 10.1021/acs.analchem.3c03942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.analchem.3c03942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38377558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P, Mahajan P, Kaur R, Gautam S (2020) Nanotechnology and its challenges in the food sector: a review. Mater Today Chem 17:100332. 10.1016/j.mtchem.2020.100332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtchem.2020.100332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32835156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng R, Zhu Q, Long T, He X, Luo Z, Gu R, Wang W, Xiang P (2023) The innovative and accurate detection of heavy metals in foods: A critical review on electrochemical sensors. Food Control 150:109743. 10.1016/j.foodcont.2023.109743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2023.109743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awlqadr FH, Altemimi AB, Qadir SA, Hama Salih TA, Alkanan ZT, AlKaisy QH, Mohammed OA, Hesarinejad MA (2025) Emerging trends in nano-sensors: A new frontier in food safety and quality assurance. Heliyon 11:e41181. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e41181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e41181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11728908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39807502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen DHH, El-Ramady H, Prokisch J (2025) Food safety aspects of carbon dots: a review. Environ Chem Lett 23:337&#x2013;360. 10.1007/s10311-024-01779-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-024-01779-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohkam M, Sadraeian M, Lauto A, Gholami A, Nabavizadeh SH, Esmaeilzadeh H, Alyasin S (2023) Exploring the potential and safety of quantum dots in allergy diagnostics. Microsystems Nanoeng 9:145. 10.1038/s41378-023-00608-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41378-023-00608-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10656439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38025887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Cui X, Li N (2022) Smartphone-based mobile biosensors for the point-of-care testing of human metabolites. Mater Today Bio 14:100254. 10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35469257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra A, Patra S, Srivastava V, Uzun L, Mishra YK, Syv&#xe4;j&#xe4;rvi M, Tiwari A (2022) Progress in paper-based analytical devices for climate neutral biosensing. Biosens Bioelectron X 11:100166. 10.1016/j.biosx.2022.100166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biosx.2022.100166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath S (2024) Advancements in food quality monitoring: integrating biosensors for precision detection. Sustain Food Technol 2:976&#x2013;992. 10.1039/d4fb00094c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4fb00094c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naresh V, Lee N (2021) A review on biosensors and recent development of nanostructured materials-enabled biosensors. Sensors 21. 10.3390/s21041109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasiewska LA, Juska VB, Seymour I, Burgess CM, Duffy G, O&#x2019;Riordan A (2023) Electrochemical nucleic acid-based sensors for detection of Escherichia coli and Shiga toxin-producing E. coli&#x2014;Review of the recent developments. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 22:1839&#x2013;1863. 10.1111/1541-4337.13132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.13132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Xu L, Li Y (2021) Biosensors for rapid detection of Salmonella in food: A review. Compr Rev Food Sci Food Saf 20:149&#x2013;197. 10.1111/1541-4337.12662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.12662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira DA, McLamore ES, Gomes CL (2022) Rapid and label-free Listeria monocytogenes detection based on stimuli-responsive alginate-platinum thiomer nanobrushes. Sci Rep 12:21413. 10.1038/s41598-022-25753-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-25753-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9741594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36496515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counihan KL, Tilman S, Chen C-Y, He Y (2025) Detection of live shiga toxin-producing escherichia coli with long-read sequencing. Int J Mol Sci 26. 10.3390/ijms26052228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11901022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40076850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakrishnan P, Anny Leema A, Jothiaruna N, Assudani PJ, Sankar K, Kulkarni MB, Bhaiyya M (2025) Artificial intelligence for food safety: From predictive models to real-world safeguards. Trends Food Sci Technol 163:105153. 10.1016/j.tifs.2025.105153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2025.105153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawnikar V, Patel M (2025) Biosensors in wearable medical devices: Regulatory framework and compliance across US, EU, and Indian markets. Ann Pharm Fran&#xe7;aises 83:637&#x2013;648. 10.1016/j.pharma.2025.02.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharma.2025.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40020872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G. (2021) Grand challenges in biosensors and biomolecular electronics. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 9. 10.3389/fbioe.2021.707615</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Duncan TV (2021) Challenges and potential solutions for nanosensors intended for use with foods. Nat Nanotechnol 16:251&#x2013;265. 10.1038/s41565-021-00867-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41565-021-00867-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33712739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talreja RK, Sable H, Chaudhary V, Kadian S, Singh M, Kumar M, Kishore J, Chaudhary V, Khosla A (2024) Review&#x2014;Challenges in Lab-to-Clinic Translation of 5th/6th Generation Intelligent Nanomaterial-enabled Biosensors. ECS Sens Plus 3:41602. 10.1149/2754-2726/ad9f7e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/2754-2726/ad9f7e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>