<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41675946</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2321-4856</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Saudi journal of medicine &amp; medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Saudi J Med Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of Routine Hematological and Biochemical Parameters to Predict Clinical Outcomes in Community-acquired Pneumonia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>56</StartPage><EndPage>62</EndPage><MedlinePgn>56-62</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/sjmms.sjmms_473_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) is a major cause of hospitalization and mortality, especially among elderly individuals and those with chronic comorbidities. Identifying reliable prognostic markers at the time of hospital admission remains a clinical challenge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the prognostic value of routinely measured hematological and biochemical parameters, specifically lymphocyte count, serum albumin, procalcitonin, neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR), and C-reactive protein (CRP)/albumin ratio (CAR), in predicting in-hospital mortality and length of stay in patients with CAP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This retrospective, single-center cohort study included all adult patients hospitalized with radiologically and clinically confirmed CAP between September 2022 and September 2023. Demographic, clinical, and laboratory data were collected. NLR and CAR were calculated based on admission values. Statistical analyses included group comparisons, correlation analysis, and ROC curve analysis to determine prognostic accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 526 patients were included (mean age: 66.2 years; 53.5% female), of which in-hospital mortality occurred in 9.5%. Non-survivors had significantly lower lymphocyte and albumin levels and higher CRP, procalcitonin, NLR, and CAR values (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). ROC analysis showed that lymphocyte count (AUC = 0.794) and albumin (AUC = 0.787) had the highest predictive accuracy, followed by procalcitonin (AUC = 0.774), NLR (AUC = 0.715), and CAR (AUC = 0.710). CRP and WBC showed lower discriminative power. Significant positive correlations were observed between CRP, procalcitonin, NLR, CAR, and length of hospital stay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Lymphocyte count, serum albumin, procalcitonin, NLR, and CRP/albumin ratio are significant prognostic markers for mortality and prolonged hospitalization in patients with community-acquired pneumonia. These routinely available parameters may aid in early risk stratification and clinical decision making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Saudi Journal of Medicine &amp; Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karakaya</LastName><ForeName>Sibel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Chest Diseases, Sancaktepe &#x15e;ehit Prof. Dr. &#x130;lhan Varank Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parmaksiz</LastName><ForeName>Elif Torun</ForeName><Initials>ET</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Chest Diseases, Sancaktepe &#x15e;ehit Prof. Dr. &#x130;lhan Varank Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tun&#xe7;ay</LastName><ForeName>Eylem</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Chest Diseases, Sancaktepe &#x15e;ehit Prof. Dr. &#x130;lhan Varank Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ko&#xe7;ak</LastName><ForeName>Nagihan D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Chest Diseases, Sancaktepe &#x15e;ehit Prof. Dr. &#x130;lhan Varank Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Saudi J Med Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101675905</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2321-4856</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Albumin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C-reactive protein/albumin ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community-acquired pneumonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">length of stay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymphocyte count</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">procalcitonin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41675946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12890234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/sjmms.sjmms_473_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">SJMMS-14-56</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Metlay JP, Waterer GW, Long AC, Anzueto A, Brozek J, Crothers K, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of adults with community-acquired pneumonia: An official clinical practice guideline of the American Thoracic Society and Infectious Diseases Society of America. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200:e45&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6812437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;&#x131;narka H, Yurt S, Tanr&#x131;verdi E, U&#x11f;ur Chousein EG, Turan D, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m Z, et al. Post-discharge short-term mortality in hospitalized patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Haydarpasa Numune Med J. 2020;60:417&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prina E, Ranzani OT, Torres A. Community-acquired pneumonia. Lancet. 2015;386:1097&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7173092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26277247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekin A, Wireko FW, Gajic O, Odeyemi YE. The neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio and outcomes in hospitalized patients with community-acquired pneumonia: A retrospective cohort study. Biomedicines. 2024;12:260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10886607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38397862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuikel S, Pathak N, Poudel S, Thapa S, Bhattarai SL, Chaudhary G, et al. Neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio as a predictor of adverse outcome in patients with community-acquired pneumonia: A systematic review. Health Sci Rep. 2022;5:e630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9060320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35509390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma Y, Thompson C, Zinellu A, Shahi R, Horwood C, Mangoni AA. The role of the neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio in predicting outcomes among patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Clin Med (Lond) 2025;25:100278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11731571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39672544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hur I, Ozkan S, Halici A, Abatay K, Usul E, Cetin E, et al. Role of plasma presepsin, procalcitonin and C-reactive protein levels in determining the severity and mortality of community-acquired pneumonia in the emergency department. Signa Vitae. 2020;16:61&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Sun W, Dai D, Liu Y, Li Z, Tian Z, et al. Prediction value of procalcitonin combining CURB-65 for 90-day mortality in community-acquired pneumonia. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2021;15:689&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33336607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikawa D, Nishi M, Takasu C, Kashihara H, Tokunaga T, Higashijima J, et al. The role of neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio on the effect of CRT for patients with rectal cancer. In Vivo. 2020;34:863&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7157857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32111796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zy&#xfc;rek BA, &#xd6;zmen &#xd6;, &#xd6;zdemirel T&#x15e;, Erdo&#x11f;an Y, Kaplan B, Kaplan T. Relation between neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio and primary tumor metabolic activity in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma. Clin Respir J. 2018;12:646&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27768834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad Ganaie Z, Aqel Y, Almaalouli B, Alsarkhi LN, Kabir Dar A, Maali Abusal A, et al. Association between elevated neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio and mortality risk in community-acquired pneumonia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2025;17:e93292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12554325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41146762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng DY, Zou XL, Zhou YQ, Wu WB, Yang HL, Zhang TT. Combined neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio and CURB-65 score as an accurate predictor of mortality for community-acquired pneumonia in the elderly. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:1133&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo B, Sun M, Huo X, Wang Y. Two new inflammatory markers related to the CURB-65 score for disease severity in patients with community-acquired pneumonia: The hypersensitive C-reactive protein to albumin ratio and fibrinogen to albumin ratio. Open Life Sci. 2021;16:84&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33817301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunutsor SK, Laukkanen JA. Serum C-reactive protein-to-albumin ratio is a potential risk indicator for pneumonia: Findings from a prospective cohort study. Respir Med. 2022;199:106894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavalaga-Zegarra HJ, Palomino-Gutierrez JJ, Ulloque-Badaracco JR, Mosquera-Rojas MD, Hernandez-Bustamante EA, Alarcon-Braga EA, et al. C-reactive protein-to-albumin ratio and clinical outcomes in COVID-19 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Trop Med Infect Dis. 2022;7:186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9414550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36006278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao L, Gong C, Liao J, Xie C, Shen X, Cheng Y. Dynamic trends of albumin-to-C-reactive protein ratio: A prognostic &#x131;ndicator in elderly patients with community-acquired pneumonia. J Inflamm Res. 2025;18:4195&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11930240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40125077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Bao J, Shang Y, Zhang Y, Yin L, Yu Y, et al. Prognostic value of serum albumin levels and respiratory rate for community-acquired pneumonia: A prospective, multi-center study. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0248002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cilloniz C, Peroni HJ, Gabarr&#xfa;s A, Garc&#xed;a-Vidal C, Peric&#xe0;s JM, Bermejo-Martin J, et al. Lymphopenia is associated with poor outcomes of patients with community-acquired pneumonia and sepsis. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8:ofab169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8231373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34189165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acehan S, G&#xfc;len M, I&#x15f;&#x131;kber C, Kaya A, Unlu N, et al. C-reactive protein to albumin ratio is associated with increased risk of mortality in COVID-19 pneumonia patients. Cukurova Med J. 2021;46:1449&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozbay S, Ayan M, Ozsoy O, Akman C, Karcioglu O. Diagnostic and prognostic roles of procalcitonin and other tools in community-acquired pneumonia: A narrative review. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023;13:1869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10253144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Kim I, Kang BH, Um SJ. Prognostic value of serial neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio measurements in hospitalized community-acquired pneumonia. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0250067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8049261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33857241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>