<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41863083</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychological Readiness Is Related to Force Production Asymmetry, but Not Biomechanical Asymmetry After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19417381251400367</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19417381251400367</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381251400367</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381251400367</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Reinjury rates and suboptimal outcomes after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction (ACLR) may be influenced by reduced psychological readiness to return to sport (RTS) and asymmetries in quadriceps strength and jump-landing biomechanics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">ACL-Return to Sport after injury (ACL-RSI) scores, quadriceps performance, and jump landing biomechanics would be significantly associated; the ACLR group would show lower ACL-RSI scores, lower quadriceps peak torque (QuadPT) and rate of torque development (RTD), and different peak knee abduction and extension angles/moments compared with healthy controls; and those with high quadriceps function would have significantly greater ACL-RSI scores than healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Case-control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Military academy cadets cleared for full sports participation after ACLR were compared with matched healthy controls. Psychological readiness was assessed using the ACL-RSI scale. Quadriceps performance was measured by QuadPT and RTD, both expressed as limb symmetry indices (LSIs). Jump-landing biomechanics were analyzed via 3-D motion capture, focusing on peak knee abduction angle/moment LSI and peak knee flexion angle/moment LSI. Pearson's correlations assessed relationships among time since surgery, psychological readiness, quadriceps performance, and biomechanics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study included 35 participants after ACLR (mean time since surgery, 19.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;9.6&#x2009;months) and 22 healthy controls. In the ACLR group, ACL-RSI scores were correlated strongly with QuadPT LSI (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.64) and RTD LSI (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.55). No significant correlations were found between the ACL-RSI and jump-landing biomechanics. Participants after ACLR had significantly lower ACL-RSI scores and greater frontal plane biomechanical differences than controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Psychological readiness was related to quadriceps performance but not with jump-landing biomechanics. Participants after ACLR exhibited lower psychological readiness and altered frontal plane biomechanics compared with healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Sports medicine clinicians should address reduced psychological readiness to RTS and jump landing biomechanics symmetry in patients recovering from ACLR.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crowell</LastName><ForeName>Michael S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1025-0380</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Scranton, Scranton, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor University - Keller Army Community Hospital Division 1 Sports Physical Therapy Fellowship, West Point, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pitt</LastName><ForeName>Will</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Army - Baylor University Doctoral Program in Physical Therapy, Fort Sam Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Florkiewicz</LastName><ForeName>Erin M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor University - Keller Army Community Hospital Division 1 Sports Physical Therapy Fellowship, West Point, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Sciences Department, Rocky Mountain University of Health Professions, Provo, Utah.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borawski</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Special Operations Wing, Hurlburt Field, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Jamie B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor University - Keller Army Community Hospital Division 1 Sports Physical Therapy Fellowship, West Point, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction graft-type</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular symmetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological readiness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) report(s) no potential conflicts of interest in the development and publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41863083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13005753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381251400367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aglietti P, Giron F, Buzzi R, Biddau F, Sasso F. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: bone-patellar tendon-bone compared with double semitendinosus and gracilis tendon grafts: a prospective, randomized clinical trial. J Bone Joint Surg. 2004;86-A(10):2143-2155. doi: 10.1016/S0276-1092(08)70172-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0276-1092(08)70172-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty-five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543-1552. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashigbi EYK, Banzer W, Niederer D. Return to sport tests&#x2019; prognostic value for reinjury risk after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(6):1263-1271. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber-Westin S, Noyes FR. One in 5 athletes sustain reinjury upon return to high-risk sports after ACL reconstruction: a systematic review in 1239 athletes younger than 20 years. Sports Health. 2020;12(6):587-597. doi: 10.1177/1941738120912846</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120912846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barfod KW, Feller JA, Hartwig T, Devitt BM, Webster KE. Knee extensor strength and hop test performance following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2019;26(1):149-154. doi: 10.1016/j.knee.2018.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2018.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakeney WG, Ouanezar H, Rogowski I, et al. Validation of a composite test for assessment of readiness for return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the K-STARTS test. Sports Health. 2018;10(6):515-522. doi: 10.1177/1941738118786454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738118786454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohu Y, Klouche S, Lefevre N, Webster K, Herman S. Translation, cross-cultural adaptation and validation of the French version of the Anterior Cruciate Ligament-Return to Sport after Injury (ACL-RSI) scale. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2015;23(4):1192-1196. doi: 10.1007/s00167-014-2942-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-014-2942-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borawski J, Brindle RA, Florkiewicz E, et al. Psychological factors are related to neuromuscular asymmetries after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Sports Health. 2025;17(2):262-271. doi: 10.1177/19417381241246754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381241246754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11569558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38716758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bram JT, Magee LC, Mehta NN, Patel NM, Ganley TJ. Anterior cruciate ligament injury incidence in adolescent athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(7):1962-1972. doi: 10.1177/0363546520959619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520959619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Wang L, Dong S, et al. Abnormal lower limb biomechanics during a bilateral vertical jump despite the symmetry in single-leg vertical hop height in athletes after ACL reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(2):23259671241230989. doi: 10.1177/23259671241230989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671241230989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38414664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Wang L, Dong S, Ding Y, Jia S, Zheng C. Can symmetry of single-leg vertical jump height represent normal lower limb biomechanics of athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Sports Health. 2024;16(4):596-605. doi: 10.1177/19417381231190119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381231190119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11195865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobian DG, Knurr KA, Joachim MR, Bednarek AL, Broderick AM, Heiderscheit BC. Does it matter? Isometric or isokinetic assessment of quadriceps strength symmetry 9 months after ACLR in collegiate athletes. Sports Health. 2025;17(2):365-373. doi: 10.1177/19417381241247819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381241247819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11569695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobian DG, Koch CM, Amendola A, Williams GN. Knee extensor rate of torque development before and after arthroscopic partial meniscectomy, with analysis of neuromuscular mechanisms. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(12):945-956. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2017.7310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.7310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28992769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowell MS, Brindle RA, Miller EM, Reilly N, Ford KR, Goss DL. The effectiveness of telehealth gait retraining in addition to standard physical therapy treatment for overuse knee injuries in soldiers: a protocol for a randomized clinical trial. Trials. 2023;24(1):672. doi: 10.1186/s13063-023-07502-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-023-07502-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Paolo S, Ito N, Seymore KD, et al. Hop distance symmetry moderately reflects knee biomechanics symmetry during landing but not for controlled propulsions. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(8):956-964. doi: 10.26603/001c.121599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.121599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11392465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39268226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faleide AGH, Magnussen LH, Strand T, et al. The role of psychological readiness in return to sport assessment after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(5):1236-1243. doi: 10.1177/0363546521991924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546521991924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175-191. doi: 10.3758/bf03193146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering Statistics Using IBM SPSS Statistics. 4th ed. London: Sage Publications; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi A, Zahediasl S. Normality tests for statistical analysis: a guide for non-statisticians. Int J Endocrinol Metab. 2012;10(2):486-489. doi: 10.5812/ijem.3505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ijem.3505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3693611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill VS, Verhey JT. Athletes continue to show functional performance deficits at return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2024;40(8):2309-2321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38220029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder-Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):804-808. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4912389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart HF, Crossley KM, Culvenor AG, et al. Knee confidence, fear of movement, and psychological readiness for sport in individuals with knee conditions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2024;54(4):234-247. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2024.12070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2024.12070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38284344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ithurburn MP, Paterno MV, Ford KR, Hewett TE, Schmitt LC. Young athletes with quadriceps femoris strength asymmetry at return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction demonstrate asymmetric single-leg drop-landing mechanics. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(11):2727-2737. doi: 10.1177/0363546515602016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515602016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ithurburn MP, Paterno MV, Thomas S, et al. Change in drop-landing mechanics over 2 years in young athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(11):2608-2616. doi: 10.1177/0363546519864688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546519864688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31373856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ithurburn MP, Thomas S, Paterno MV, Schmitt LC. Young athletes after ACL reconstruction with asymmetric quadriceps strength at the time of return-to-sport clearance demonstrate drop-landing asymmetries two years later. Knee. 2021;29:520-529. doi: 10.1016/j.knee.2021.02.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2021.02.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33756262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AK, Palmieri-Smith RM, Lepley LK. Contribution of neuromuscular factors to quadriceps asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2018;53(4):347-354. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-463-16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-463-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29652169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston PT, McClelland JA, Webster KE. Lower limb biomechanics during single-leg landings following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(9):2103-2126. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0942-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0942-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29949109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwik P, Florkiewicz E, Benedict T, Mason J, Morris J, Crowell M. Assessing the relationship of psychological sport readiness, single-leg vertical jump, and non-sagittal single-leg hops to quadriceps strength after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(8):942-955. doi: 10.26603/001c.121597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.121597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11297365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39100937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Pietrosimone B, Cormier ML. Quadriceps function, knee pain, and self-reported outcomes in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2018;53(4):337-346. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-245-16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-245-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29667429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisee C, Lepley AS, Birchmeier T, O&#x2019;Hagan K, Kuenze C. Quadriceps strength and volitional activation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Health. 2019;11(2):163-179. doi: 10.1177/1941738118822739</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738118822739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Losciale JM, Ithurburn MP, Paterno MV, Schmitt LC. Passing return-to-sport criteria and landing biomechanics in young athletes following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2022;40(1):208-218. doi: 10.1002/jor.25110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maletis GB, Cameron SL, Tengan JJ, Burchette RJ. A prospective randomized study of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a comparison of patellar tendon and quadruple-strand semitendinosus/gracilis tendons fixed with bioabsorbable interference screws. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(3):384-394. doi: 10.1177/0363546506294361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546506294361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagelli CV, Hewett TE. Should return to sport be delayed until 2 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Biological and functional considerations. Sports Med. 2017;47(2):221-232. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0584-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0584-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5226931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27402457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedder VJ, Raju AG, Moyal AJ, Calcei JG, Voos JE. Impact of psychological factors on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Sports Health. 2024;17(2):291-298. doi: 10.1177/19417381241256930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381241256930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11569572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39041333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Adjei J, Rauck RC, et al. How much do psychological factors affect lack of return to play after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? A systematic review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(5):232596711984531. doi: 10.1177/2325967119845313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967119845313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31205965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens BD, Mountcastle SB, Dunn WR, DeBerardino TM, Taylor DC. Incidence of anterior cruciate ligament injury among active duty U.S. military servicemen and servicewomen. Mil Med. 2007;172(1):90-91. doi: 10.7205/MILMED.172.1.90</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7205/MILMED.172.1.90</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17274274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padua DA, Marshall SW, Boling MC, Thigpen CA, Garrett WE, Jr, Beutler AI. The Landing Error Scoring System (LESS) is a valid and reliable clinical assessment tool of jump-landing biomechanics: the JUMP-ACL study. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(10):1996-2002. doi: 10.1177/0363546509343200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509343200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19726623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Flynn K, Thomas S, Schmitt LC. Self-reported fear predicts functional performance and second ACL injury after ACL reconstruction and return to sport: a pilot study. Sports Health. 2018;10(3):228-233. doi: 10.1177/1941738117745806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738117745806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5958451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29272209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Schmitt LC, Ford KR, et al. Biomechanical measures during landing and postural stability predict second anterior cruciate ligament injury after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38(10):1968-1978. doi: 10.1177/0363546510376053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510376053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4920967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, Taheri P, Forkel P, Zantop T. Return to play following ACL reconstruction: a systematic review about strength deficits. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2014;134(10):1417-1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25091127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan B, King E, Richter C, Webster K, Falvey E. A comparison of anterior cruciate ligament - return to sports after injury (ACL-RSI) scores of male athletes nine-months post-ACL reconstruction with matched uninjured controls. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;38:179-183. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.05.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31170646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe C, Jacobs C, Hoch J, Johnson DL, Noehren B. Test batteries after primary anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review. Sports Health. 2022;14(2):205-215. doi: 10.1177/19417381211009473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381211009473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33896240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeqi M, Klouche S, Bohu Y, Herman S, Lefevre N, Gerometta A. Progression of the psychological ACL-RSI score and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective 2-year follow-up study from the French prospective anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction cohort study (FAST). Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(12):232596711881281. doi: 10.1177/2325967118812819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967118812819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30574516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders TL, Maradit Kremers H, Bryan AJ, et al. Incidence of anterior cruciate ligament tears and reconstruction: a 21-year population-based study. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(6):1502-1507. doi: 10.1177/0363546516629944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516629944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt LC, Paterno MV, Ford KR, Myer GD, Hewett TE. Strength asymmetry and landing mechanics at return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(7):1426-1434. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda Y, Matsushita T, Shibata Y, et al. Association between meeting return-to-sport criteria and psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10(5):23259671221093985. doi: 10.1177/23259671221093985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671221093985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9096206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA. Evaluation of the responsiveness of the anterior cruciate ligament return to sport after injury (ACL-RSI) scale. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(8):232596712110312. doi: 10.1177/23259671211031240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671211031240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34423062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA, Lambros C. Development and preliminary validation of a scale to measure the psychological impact of returning to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Phys Ther Sport. 2008;9(1):9-15. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2007.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2007.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Hewett TE. What is the evidence for and validity of return-to-sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(6):917-929. doi: 10.1007/s40279-019-01093-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01093-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Nagelli CV, Hewett TE, Feller JA. Factors associated with psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(7):1545-1550. doi: 10.1177/0363546518773757</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546518773757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6598700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29718684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Benjaminse A, Lemmink K, Gokeler A. Passing return to sports tests after ACL reconstruction is associated with greater likelihood for return to sport but fail to identify second injury risk. Knee. 2020;27(3):949-957. doi: 10.1016/j.knee.2020.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2020.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Benjaminse A, Seil R, Lemmink K, Zaffagnini S, Gokeler A. Low rates of patients meeting return to sport criteria 9 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective longitudinal study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(12):3636-3644. doi: 10.1007/s00167-018-4916-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-018-4916-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6267144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29574548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellsandt E, Failla MJ, Snyder-Mackler L. Limb symmetry indexes can overestimate knee function after anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(5):334-338. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2017.7285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.7285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5483854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28355978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, Stanfield D, Webster KE, Myer GD. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(7):1861-1876. doi: 10.1177/0363546515621554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515621554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26772611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wren TAL, Mueske NM, Brophy CH, et al. Hop distance symmetry does not indicate normal landing biomechanics in adolescent athletes with recent anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2018;48(8):622-629. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2018.7817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2018.7817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29602303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Xu Y, Wang S, Wang S, Xu W. Quadriceps strength and psychological readiness are associated with multiplanar knee kinematics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Gait Posture. 2023;101:101-105. doi: 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2023.02.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2023.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36773479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>