<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41466927</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating Custom and Transfer Learning Convolutional Neural Networks for Pneumonia Classification Under Data Scarcity and Low-Compute Conditions for Under-Resourced Environments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97959</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97959</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97959</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97959</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pneumonia is an infectious disease that causes many deaths across the world. By accurately and efficiently recognizing pneumonia from images using machine learning, we can facilitate faster treatment. Yet, in under-resourced environments, there is often a lack of training data, high-quality images for training, as well as a lack of high computing power. As such, we aim to investigate and address these issues. In this paper, we deployed and tested different convolutional neural networks (CNNs), optimizing them to use fewer resources. We simulated the low training image count, low image quality, and low compute power, using a Raspberry Pi and the Pneumonia Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology (MNIST) dataset with 64x64 images. We were able to achieve accuracies of 95%&#xa0;for our laptop-trained, quantized model&#xa0;and 94%&#xa0;for our P100 quantized model. The F1 scores, as well as the recall for the pneumonia class, were also evaluated to provide additional insights into the performance of the models.&#xa0;Furthermore, we were&#xa0;able to obtain&#xa0;a rounded average latency of 1.46 milliseconds (ms) for our P100 quantized model, with a rounded model size of 1.45 megabytes (MB). Our work allows for an accurate diagnosis of pneumonia with limited resources.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Chen et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Andy L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Science, Monta Vista High School, Cupertino, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheek</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samradi</LastName><ForeName>Morteza</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cnn</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-resource environments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pneumonia classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">raspberry pi</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transfer learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41466927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12744362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deep learning applications in medical image analysis. Ker J, Wang L, Rao J, Lim T. IEEE Access. 2018;6:9375&#x2013;9389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pneumonia in Children.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2022. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/pneumonia https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/pneumonia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revised WHO classification and treatment of childhood pneumonia at health facilities.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2014. https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/38cf9b2a-5d7d-49de-a27b-46d5ac4fc387/content https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/38cf9b2a-5d7d-49de-a27b-46d5ac4fc387/content</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pneumonia.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/fastats/pneumonia.htm https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/fastats/pneumonia.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence (AI) and global health: how can AI contribute to health in resource-poor settings? Wahl B, Cossy-Gantner A, Germann S, Schwalbe NR. BMJ Global Health. 2018;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6135465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beede E, Baylor E, Hersch F, Lurchenko A, Wilcox L, Ruamviboonsuk P, Vardoulakis LM. Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. New York, US: Association for Computing Machinery; 2020. A human-centered evaluation of a deep learning system deployed in clinics for the detection of diabetic retinopathy; pp. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benchmark analysis of representative deep neural network architectures (Preprint) Bianco S, Cadene R, Celona L, Napoletano P. arXiv. 2018:0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cococi AG, Armanda DM, Felea II, Dogaru R. 2020 International Symposium on Electronics and Telecommunications (ISETC), Timisoara, Romania. New York, US: IEEE; 10.1109/ISETC50328.2020.9301102. Disease detection on medical images using light-weight convolutional neural networks for resource constrained platforms; pp. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searching for MobileNetV3 (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Howard A, Sandler M, Chu G, et al.  https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.02244 arXiv. 2019 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ShuffleNet V2: practical guidelines for efficient CNN architecture design (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Ma N, Zhang X, Zheng HT, Sun J. https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.11164 arXiv. 2018 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogaru R, Dogaru I. 2019 6th International Symposium on Electrical and Electronics Engineering (ISEEE), Galati, Romania. New York, US: IEEE; 2019. BCONV - ELM: binary weights convolutional neural network simulator based on Keras/Tensorflow, for low complexity implementations; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Classification of pneumonia, tuberculosis and Covid-19 from chest X-ray images using convolution neural network model. Kiche J, Mwaniki I, Orowe I, Weke P. https://erepository.uonbi.ac.ke/bitstream/handle/11295/167491/KICHE%20JOHN%20OPIYO.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y. Int J Stat Probab. 2024;13:42&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12290982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40717839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Densely connected convolutional networks (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Huang G, Liu Z, van der Maaten L, Weinberger KQ. https://arxiv.org/abs/1608.06993 arXiv. 2018 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>(MedMNIST+) 18x standardized datasets for 2D and 3D biomedical image classification with multiple size options: 28 (MNIST-Like), 64, 128, and 224 (Dataset)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Jiancheng Y, Rui S, Donglai W, et al.  https://zenodo.org/records/10519652 Zenodo. 2024 </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Simonyan K, Zisserman A. https://arxiv.org/abs/1409.1556 arXiv. 2015 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MobileNetV2: inverted residuals and linear bottlenecks (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Sandler M, Howard A, Zhu M, Zhmoginov A, Chen LC. https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.04381 arXiv. 2019 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EfficientNet: rethinking model scaling for convolutional neural networks (Preprint)  [
Sep;
2025 
];Tan M, Le QV. https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11946 arXiv. 2020 :0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B M, S S, T V, K SS, R SS, R SA. Proceedings of the International Conference on Smart Data Intelligence (ICSMDI 2021) Rochester, New York: SSRN; 2021. Pre-trained convolutional neural network model based pneumonia classification from chest X-ray images.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xception: deep learning with depthwise separable convolutions (Preprint)  [
Aug;
2025 
];Chollet F. https://arxiv.org/abs/1610.02357 arXiv. 2017 :0.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>