<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41508645</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A study on the nutritional intake status and nutrition awareness of Korean national athletes with disabilities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>83</StartPage><EndPage>91</EndPage><MedlinePgn>83-91</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2025.0038</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study was conducted to provide basic data for nutritional strategies to enhance athletic performance in athletes with disabilities by analyzing their nutritional intake, sport-specific comparisons, and awareness of nutrition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 26 athletes (17 males, 9 females; average age = 40.67 years) participated in the study. All foods consumed over three days were recorded using the CANPRO program (version 6.0). Demographic characteristics, nutritional awareness, and perceived importance of nutrition were assessed through a Google Form questionnaire. Data were analyzed with SPSS (version 23.0) to compute means and standard deviations, with statistical significance set at p &lt; .05. Participants included athletes from the following sports: badminton (n = 6), shooting (n = 1), swimming (n = 2), powerlifting (n = 6), judo (n = 1), athletics (n = 1), table tennis (n = 7), and wheelchair rugby (n = 2).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The average daily energy intake was 2,096.03 kcal for male athletes and 1,680.57 kcal for female athletes, with no significant sex-based differences in caloric or nutrient intake. Among sports, wheelchair rugby players (n = 2) showed the highest average intake (2,524.49 kcal), followed by powerlifters (n = 6) at 2,323.9 kcal, and badminton players (n = 6) at 1,926.09 kcal, indicating that strength- or power-focused sports require higher energy consumption. All participants agreed that nutrition is closely linked to athletic performance, and about 73% believed it directly affects performance. Additionally, 88% recognized the need for professional nutritional education.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of the study can serve as foundational data to establish future nutritional strategies for athletes with disabilities.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ji Young</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science Laboratory, Korea Institute of Sport Science, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sung Yeon</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science Team, Korea Paralympic Committee, Icheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sung Mi</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Adapted Physical Education, Hanshin University, Osan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>An</LastName><ForeName>Young Hwan</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science Team, Korea Paralympic Committee, Icheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes with disabilities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition awareness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional strategies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">para sport</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41508645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12784040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2025.0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2025.0038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Powers SK, Howley ET, Quindry J. Exercise physiology: Theory and application to fitness and performance. 8th ed. New York, NY: McGraw-Hill; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MH, Anderson DE, Rawson ES. Nutrition for Health, Fitness &amp; Sport. 12th ed. McGraw-Hill Education; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi A, Rothschild JA, Santos HO, Hamidvand A, Koozehchian MS, Ghazzagh A, ..., Podlogar T. Nutritional strategies to improve post-exercise recovery and subsequent exercise performance: A narrative review. Sports Med. 2025:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12297025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(3):543&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor IV LW, editor. Nutritional guidelines for athletic performance: the training table. CRC Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Wilborn CD, Taylor L, Campbell B, Almada AL, Collins R, ..., Antonio J. ISSN exercise &amp; sport nutrition review: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHO S. Optimal Nutrition For Sports and Exercise. Korean J Community Nutr. 2002;7(3):410&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astrup A. Macronutrient balances and obesity: the role of diet and physical activity. Public Health Nutr. 1999;2(3a):341&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10610071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenstein J, Roberts SB, Dallal G, Saltzman E. High-protein weight-loss diets: are they safe and do they work? A review of the experimental and epidemiologic data. Nutrition reviews. 2002;60(7):189&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12144197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S, Kim J, Cho W. The Effect of Skeletal Muscle Mass and Growth Hormone, Testosterone, Insulin Like Growth Factor-1 by the Protein Supplements Intake Period during to Resistance Exercise. J Korea Soc Wellness. 2017;12(2):371&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Kerksick CM, Campbell BI, Cribb PJ, Wells SD, Skwiat TM, ..., Antonio J. International society of sports nutrition position stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14(1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korean Nutrient Intake Standards. Ministry of Health and Welfare; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K, Jung H, Kang H. The effects of different diet patterns on muscle injuries due to high-intensity exercise. Exerc Sci. 2015;24(2):133&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M. The Review on Nutritional Management for Competitive Weight Control Athletes. J Coach Dev. 2005;7(4):3&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerrish HR, Broad E, LaCroix M, Ogan D, Pritchett RC, Pritchett K. Nutrient intake of elite Canadian and American athletes with spinal cord injury. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(7):1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5685078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madden RF, Shearer J, Parnell JA. Evaluation of dietary intakes and supplement use in paralympic athletes. Nutrients. 2017;9(11):1266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5707738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29160809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islamoglu AH, Kenger EB. Nutrition considerations for athletes with physical disabilities. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2019;18(7):270&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31283628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D. T, Erdman K. A, Burke L. M. Position of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, Dietitians of Canada, and the American College of Sports Medicine: nutrition and athletic performance. Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics. 2016;116(3):501&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney S, O&#x2019;Connor H, Michael S, Gifford J, Naughton G. Nutrition knowledge in athletes: a systematic review. International journal of sport nutrition and exercise metabolism. 2011;21(3):248&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21719906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeoung B, Kim J. Analysis and evaluation of nutritional intake and nutrition quotient of Korean athletes with disabilities in the Tokyo paralympic games. Nutrients. 2021;13(10):3631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho CO, An YW, Kim SY. Survey on Nutrition Consumption and Perception for Conditioning Management of Paralympic Athletes in Korea. Korean J Sport. 2022;20(2):671&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey R. L. Overview of dietary assessment methods for measuring intakes of foods, beverages, and dietary supplements in research studies. Current opinion in biotechnology. 2021;70:91&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8338737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33714006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Verest M. T. E, Salath&#xe9; M. Minimum days estimation for reliable dietary intake information: findings from a digital cohort. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2025;79:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12537485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40702309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S, Lee H, Kim K. Physical Characteristics and Dietary Patterns of Strength Athletes; Bodybuilders, Weight Lifters. Korean J Community Nutr. 2007;12(6):864&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaoutis G, Alepoudea M, Tambalis KD, Sidossis LS. Dietary intake, body composition, and nutritional knowledge of elite handball players. Nutrients. 2024;16(16):2773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11357219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoyama H, Deguchi M, Hongu N. The role of diets and dietitians for para-athletes: A pilot study based on interviews. Nutrients. 2022;14(18):3720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9505573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36145095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krempien JL, Barr SI. Risk of nutrient inadequacies in elite Canadian athletes with spinal cord injury. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;21(5):417&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deguchi M, Yokoyama H, Hongu N, Watanabe H, Ogita A, Imai D, ..., Okazaki K. Eating perception, nutrition knowledge and body image among para-athletes: Practical challenges in nutritional support. Nutrients. 2021;13(9):3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grams L, Garrido G, Villacieros J, Ferro A. Marginal micronutrient intake in high-performance male wheelchair basketball players: A dietary evaluation and the effects of nutritional advice. PLoS One. 2016;11(7):e0157931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4934691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27383836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price M. Energy expenditure and metabolism during exercise in persons with a spinal cord injury. Sports Med. 2010;40(8):681&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20632738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham-Paulson TS, Perret C, Smith B, Crosland J, Goosey-Tolfrey VL. Nutritional supplement habits of athletes with an impairment and their sources of information. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25(4):387&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25811415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figel K, Pritchett K, Pritchett R, Broad E. Energy and nutrient issues in athletes with spinal cord injury: are they at risk for low energy availability? Nutrients. 2018;10(8):1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30104487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Choi GR, Kang M. Exploring the Experience of Participation in International Para Sport Competitions of Elite Wheelchair Athletes. Korean J Adapt Phys Act. 2024;32(1):169&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flueck JL. Nutritional considerations for para-cycling athletes: a narrative review. Sports. 2021;9(11):154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8625771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34822353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae M, Lee H, Kim J, Lee S, Jin J. A systematic review: Improving athletic performance in disability sports. Korean J Adapt Phys Act. 2020;28(4):57&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J. Application of Demand-Oriented Support Model for the Performance Enhancement of the Sports for Disabled. Korean J Adapt Phys Act. 2019;27(4):57&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertig-Godeschalk A, Ruettimann B, Valido E, Glisic M, Stoyanov J, Flueck JL. Energy availability and nutritional intake during different training phases of wheelchair athletes. Nutrients. 2023;15(11):2578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10255248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37299541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S, Lim Y, Jung I. Nutrition Knowledge and Needs of Nutrition Education in Sports Instructors and Preliminary Instructors of Para-Athletes. Asian J Phys Educ Sport Sci. 2023;11(2):101&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh A, Shin J. Analysis of the status of support system for improving the performance of national Taekwondo athlete with disabilities. Korean J Adapt Phys Act. 2022;30(1):101&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>