<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41393671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Return to Play After Achilles Tendon Rupture: Comparing Operative and Nonoperative Approaches in Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e96783</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e96783</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e96783</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.96783</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Achilles tendon rupture is a debilitating injury with significant implications for athletic performance and career longevity. Historically, operative repair was considered the gold standard, but advances in early functional rehabilitation have challenged this paradigm, with non-operative management demonstrating comparable rerupture and functional outcomes. This narrative review synthesizes evidence comparing operative and nonoperative strategies in athletes, emphasizing rehabilitation, return-to-play (RTP) outcomes, and long-term sequelae. Operative repair offers marginal advantages in preserving tendon length and explosive power but carries surgical risks such as adhesions and wound complications. Nonoperative management, utilizing modern functional protocols, achieves comparable rerupture rates and patient satisfaction while minimizing operative morbidity. It appears that the quality of rehabilitation and early management offers promising results in RTP, comparable to those of surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Fada et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fada</LastName><ForeName>Laith</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Alabama College of Osteopathic Medicine, Dothan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzorana</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Alabama College of Osteopathic Medicine, Dothan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grand</LastName><ForeName>Zachary A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Florida International University Herbert Wertheim College of Medicine, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacobs</LastName><ForeName>Greg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Medicine, Alabama College of Osteopathic Medicine, Dothan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">achilles tendon rupture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-operative rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">operative management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to play</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41393671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12701767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.96783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clinical diagnosis of Achilles tendinopathy with tendinosis. Maffulli N, Kenward MG, Testa V, Capasso G, Regine R, King JB. Clin J Sport Med. 2003;13:11&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12544158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining components of early functional rehabilitation for acute Achilles tendon rupture: a systematic review. Zellers J, Christensen M, Kj&#xe6;r I. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31803789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical versus nonsurgical treatment of acute Achilles tendon rupture: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Soroceanu A, Sidhwa F, Aarabi S, Kaufman A, Glazebrook M. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94:2136&#x2013;2143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23224384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interventions for treating acute Achilles tendon ruptures. Khan RJ, Fick D, Brammar TJ, Crawford J, Parker MJ. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonoperative or surgical treatment of acute Achilles&#x2019; tendon rupture. Myhrvold SB, Brouwer EF, Andresen TK, et al. N Engl J Med. 2022;386:1409&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individualized treatment for acute Achilles tendon rupture based on the Copenhagen Achilles Rupture Treatment Algorithm (CARTA): a study protocol for a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Hansen MS, Vestermark MT, H&#xf6;lmich P, Kristensen MT, Barfod KW. Trials. 2020;21:399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increasing incidence of acute Achilles tendon rupture and a noticeable decline in surgical treatment from 1994 to 2013. A nationwide registry study of 33,160 patients. Ganestam A, Kallemose T, Troelsen A, Barfod KW. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24:3730&#x2013;3737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Professional athletes&#x2019; return to play and performance after operative repair of an Achilles tendon rupture. Trofa DP, Miller JC, Jang ES, Woode DR, Greisberg JK, Vosseller JT. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45:2864&#x2013;2871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28644678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute achilles tendon ruptures: incidence of injury and surgery in Sweden between 2001 and 2012. Huttunen TT, Kannus P, Rolf C, Fell&#xe4;nder-Tsai L, Mattila VM. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2419&#x2013;2423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achilles tendon loading during running estimated via shear wave tensiometry: a step toward wearable kinetic analysis. Reiter AJ, Martin JA, Knurr KA, Adamczyk PG, Thelen DG. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56:1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11096059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38240495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achilles tendinopathy: current concepts about the basic science and clinical treatments. Li HY, Hua YH. Biomed Res Int. 2016:6492597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5112330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advances in microscopic studies of tendinopathy: literature review and current trends, with special reference to neovascularization process. Jaworski &#x141;, Zabrzy&#x144;ska M, Klimaszewska-Wi&#x15b;niewska A, Zieli&#x144;ska W, Grzanka D, Gagat M. J Clin Med. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35329898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining the profile: Characterizing cytokines in tendon injury to improve clinical therapy. Ellis I, Schnabel LV, Berglund AK. J Immunol Regen Med. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8932644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metabolic syndrome and tendon disease: a comprehensive review. Lai C, Li R, Tang W, et al. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2024;17:1597&#x2013;1609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38616994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet rich plasma injection for acute Achilles tendon rupture: PATH-2 randomised, placebo controlled, superiority trial. Keene DJ, Alsousou J, Harrison P, et al. BMJ. 2019;367:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6863552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31748208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Operative versus nonoperative treatment of acute Achilles tendon ruptures: a multicenter randomized trial using accelerated functional rehabilitation. Willits K, Amendola A, Bryant D, et al. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2010;92:2767&#x2013;2775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21037028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Operative treatment versus nonoperative treatment of Achilles tendon ruptures: systematic review and meta-analysis. Ochen Y, Beks RB, van Heijl M, et al. BMJ. 2019;364:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes and complications of open versus minimally invasive repair of acute Achilles tendon ruptures: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Attia AK, Mahmoud K, d'Hooghe P, Bariteau J, Labib SA, Myerson MS. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:825&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34908499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anatomic relationship of the sural nerve when performing Achilles tendon repair using the percutaneous Achilles repair system, a cadaveric study. McGee R, Watson T, Eudy A. Foot Ankle Surg. 2021;27:427&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An anatomical and cadaveric study examining the risk of sural nerve injury in percutaneous Achilles tendon repair using the Achillon device. Porter KJ, Robati S, Karia P, Portet M, Szarko M, Amin A. Foot Ankle Surg. 2014;20:90&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24796825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open versus percutaneous repair in the treatment of acute Achilles tendon rupture: a randomized prospective study. Gigante A, Moschini A, Verdenelli A, Del Torto M, Ulisse S, de Palma L. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2008;16:204&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18066530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation regimen for non-surgical treatment of Achilles tendon rupture: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Dai W, Leng X, Wang J, Hu X, Ao Y. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24:536&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early functional rehabilitation compared with traditional immobilization for acute Achilles tendon ruptures : a meta-analysis. Liu X, Dai TJ, Li BL, Li C, Zheng ZY, Liu Y. Bone Joint J. 2021;103-B:1021&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34058871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining components of early functional rehabilitation for acute Achilles tendon rupture: a systematic review. Zellers JA, Christensen M, Kj&#xe6;r IL, Rathleff MS, Silbernagel KG. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7:39871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31803789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to play and functional outcomes following treatment of acute Achilles tendon ruptures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bak BM, Seow D, Teo YZ, Hasan MY, Pearce CJ. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2024;63:420&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38296023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open versus minimally-invasive surgery for Achilles tendon rupture: a meta-analysis study. Gatz M, Driessen A, Eschweiler J, Tingart M, Migliorini F. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2021;141:383&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological factors change during the rehabilitation of an Achilles tendon rupture: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Slagers AJ, Dams OC, van Zalinge SD, Geertzen JH, Zwerver J, Reininga IH, van den Akker-Scheek I. Phys Ther. 2021;101:580&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8697845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34636920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of platelet-rich plasma in the treatment of Achilles tendon disease. Huang D, Vithran DT, Gong HL, et al. World J Orthop. 2023;14:485&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37377997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of acute Achilles tendon ruptures: a review. Yang X, Meng H, Quan Q. Bone Jt Res. 2018;7:561&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6215245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fear of movement/(re)injury in chronic pain: a psychometric assessment of the original English version of the Tampa scale for kinesiophobia (TSK) French DJ, France CR, Vigneau F, French JA, Evans RT. Pain. 2007;127:2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16962238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearable sensor and machine learning accurately estimate tendon load and walking speed during immobilizing boot ambulation. Kwon MP, Hullfish TJ, Humbyrd CJ, Boakye LA, Baxter JR. medRxiv . 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10593749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minimally invasive versus open repair for acute Achilles tendon rupture: meta-analysis showing reduced complications, with similar outcomes, after minimally invasive surgery. Grassi A, Amendola A, Samuelsson K, et al. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2018;100:1969&#x2013;1981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30480601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cost-effectiveness of operative versus non-operative management of acute Achilles tendon ruptures. Koltsov JC, Gribbin C, Ellis SJ, Nwachukwu BU. HSS J. 2020;16:39&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6974171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Achilles tendon total rupture score (ATRS): development and validation. Nilsson-Helander K, Thome&#xe9; R, Silbernagel KG, Thome&#xe9; P, Fax&#xe9;n E, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:421&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17158277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical vs. nonoperative treatment for acute Achilles' tendon rupture: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Fan L, Hu Y, Zhou L, Fu W. Front Surg. 2024;11:1483584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11617549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39640199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ALR-RSI score can be used to evaluate psychological readiness to return to sport after acute Achilles tendon tear. Shitrit E, Valentin E, Baudrier N, et al. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:4961&#x2013;8496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10598148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quantitative ultrasound assessment of the Achilles tendon under varied loads. Sahr M, Sturnick DR, Nwawka OK. J Ultrasound Med. 2018;37:2413&#x2013;2418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29516536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearable approaches for non-invasive monitoring of tendons: a scoping review. K&#xe1;rason H, Ritrovato P, Maffulli N, Boccaccini AR, Tortorella F. Internet Things J. 2024;26:101199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achilles tendon assessment on quantitative MRI: Sources of variability and relationships to tendinopathy. McNish R, Lohse K, Pruthi S, Hastings MK, Zheng J, Zellers JA. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11081531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38712745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>