<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41929647</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2169-7574</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Plastic and reconstructive surgery. Global open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Future of Resident Unionization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e7536</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e7536</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e7536</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/GOX.0000000000007536</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Burnout is a recognized phenomenon among residents and attending surgeons in the United States, resulting in physical and mental exhaustion. Residents see a reduction in working hours as being essential to deal with this issue. Consequently, residents have unionized to improve collective bargaining power and advocacy with employers to achieve their aims. Unionization has proved controversial and spawned generational conflict within the profession. Older attending surgeons suggest that such unionization demeans the profession, as it is at odds with their sense of vocation and "nostalgic" professionalism. Residents and younger attending surgeons are not prepared to make the same commitments as their predecessors given the increased work-life balance they crave, reflecting the new societal norm. The United States must heed the lessons from those who have traveled this road previously. In the United Kingdom, working hours have significantly reduced in recent decades, requiring moves away from apprentice-style resident training towards a more remote shift pattern style of working. This has resulted in unintended consequences: (1) disruption of the "hidden" curriculum through which professionalism was previously taught and (2) an isolated and demoralized resident workforce. This tension reflects a breakdown in the social contract among medicine, society, and government that, if not addressed in the United States, may result in continued discord, as recently manifested by resident strikes in the United Kingdom. Looking forward, United States training programs should ensure that any changes in working hours must maintain teamwork between residents and attending surgeons, not only for their own well-being but also for that of their patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fitzgerald</LastName><ForeName>Aidan M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Plastic Surgery, Royal Hallamshire Hospital, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levin</LastName><ForeName>Lawrence Scott</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pennsylvania Health System, Philadelphia, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101622231</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2169-7574</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors have no financial interest to declare in relation to the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41929647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13043255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000007536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">GOX-D-25-00591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro RVE, Martuscelli OJD, Vieira AC, et al. Prevalence of burnout among plastic surgeons and residents in plastic surgery: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2018;6:e1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6181492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30324054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khansa I, Janis JE. A growing epidemic: plastic surgeons and burnout&#x2014;a literature review. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019;144:298e&#x2013;305e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31348370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombs DM, Lanni MA, Fosnot J, et al. Professional burnout in United States plastic surgery residents: is it a legitimate concern? Aesthet Surg J. 2020;40:802&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31621825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ghunaim TA, Johnson J, Biyani CS, et al. Surgeon burnout, impact on patient safety and professionalism: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Surg. 2022;224:228&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34974884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khullar D. Burnout, professionalism, and the quality of US health care. JAMA Health Forum. 2023;4:e230024&#x2013;e230024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36961455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koljonen JL, Ruffolo AM, Neumeister MW, et al. Strategies to improve resident wellness in plastic surgery training. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2024;12:e5858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11150031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38841530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prendergast C, Ketteler E, Evans G. Burnout in the plastic surgeon: implications and interventions. Aesthet Surg J. 2017;37:363&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28207037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Unda NA, Mehta I, Chopra S, et al. Global Resilience in Plastic Surgery Study (GRIPS): resilience is associated with lower burnout rates. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2023;11:e4889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10085483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37051210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart AM, Crowley C, Janis JE, et al. Survey based assessment of burnout rates among US plastic surgery residents. Ann Plast Surg. 2020;85:215&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32349078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrau D, Janis JE. Physician burnout: solutions for individuals and organizations. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2021;9:e3418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S. The lasting legacy of a case that was &#x201c;lost&#x201d;. Penn State Law Review.
2014. Available at {L-End}
http://www.pennstatelawreview.org/penn-statim/the-lasting-legacy-of-a-case-that-was-lost/. Accessed December 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith M. Should surgical residents unionize? General Surgery News.
2000. Available at {L-End}
https://www.generalsurgerynews.com/In-the-News/article/12-20/Should-Surgical-Residents-Unionize/61397. Accessed December 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brajcich BC, Chung JW, Wood DE, et al. National evaluation of the association between resident labor union participation and surgical resident well-being. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2123412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8411294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34468754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeitouni F, Attaluri PK, Wirth PJ, et al. State of physician unionization. J Surg Educ. 2024;81:929&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38749815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JJ. White coats should not have union labels. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:431&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10666438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Money SR, O&#x2019;Donnell ME, Gray RJ. In the time of significant generational diversity&#x2014;surgical leadership must step up. Surgeon (Edinburgh). 2014;12:3&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24090677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald A. Medical professionalism and the social contract: an intergenerational study. EdD thesis on the internet.
University of Sheffield. Available at {L-End}
https://etheses.whiterose.ac.uk/28811/. 2020. Accessed December 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruess RL, Cruess SR. Expectations and obligations: professionalism and medicine&#x2019;s social contract with society. Perspect Biol Med. 2008;51:579&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobucci G. Junior doctors in England strike for 10th time as pay dispute rumbles on. BMJ. 2024;384:q500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38408768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen MA, DiazGranados D, Dietz AS, et al. Teamwork in healthcare: key discoveries enabling safer, high-quality care. Am Psychol. 2018;73:433&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IWTR Taskforce. The Implementation of the Working Time Directive and Its Impact on the NHS and Health Professionals. The Royal College of Surgeons of England; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Surgeons of England. Improving surgical training; proposal for a pilot surgical training programme.
Available at {L-End}
https://www.rcseng.ac.uk/library-and-publications/rcs-publications/docs/improving-surgical-training/. 2015. Accessed December 15, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>