<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41874806</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-9229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discover nano</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discov Nano</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-powered finger motion sensing for piano training based on the ionic hydrogel triboelectric nanogenerator.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">82</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s11671-026-04511-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Wearable sensing technologies have attracted increasing attention for real-time monitoring of human motion and physiological activities. In this study, a PTPAVI-Al<sup>3+</sup> ionic conductive hydrogel-enabled triboelectric nanogenerator (PA-TENG) is designed as a multifunctional platform capable of converting mechanical stimuli into electrical signals for energy harvesting and autonomous finger joint motion sensing during music training. The PTPAVI-Al<sup>3+</sup> ionic conductive hydrogel electrode features a hybrid architecture composed of a poly(vinyl alcohol) (PVA) framework and a covalently crosslinked poly(acrylamide-co-1-vinyl-3-butylimidazolium bromide-co-itaconic acid) (PA-VBI-IA) network, in which tannic acid (TA) and Al<sup>3+</sup> ions cooperatively generate a dense supramolecular interaction network. This hierarchical structure endows the hydrogel with high stretchability, strong self-adhesion, excellent ionic conductivity, anti-swelling behavior, and mechanical robustness. A nylon/polydimethylsiloxane triboelectric pair is employed to assemble a vertical contact-separation PA-TENG, delivering a peak open-circuit voltage (V<sub>OC</sub>) of 1080.6&#xa0;V, a short-circuit current (I<sub>SC</sub>) of 74.5 &#xb5;A, and a maximum power output of 2.1 mW. Moreover, the PA-TENG enables accurate, self-powered monitoring of finger joint motion and applied force during piano training, demonstrating its potential for wearable sensing, skill training, and human-machine interaction applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xuemei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Music, Jinzhong University, Yuci, 030619, China. zxm@jzxy.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mi</LastName><ForeName>Yimian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Conservatory of Music, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, 32611, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>J20231257</GrantID><Agency>Teaching Reform Project of Higher Education Institutions in Shanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Discov Nano</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918540788706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-9229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ionic conductive hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Piano training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triboelectric nanogenerators (TENGs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wearable sensor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study involved non-invasive experiments with human participants and posed no foreseeable risk. Ethical approval was formally waived by the Ethics Committee of Jinzhong University, as the experiments only involved non-invasive wearable sensing for finger motion monitoring during piano training, without any clinical intervention or collection of identifiable personal data. All procedures were conducted in accordance with the institutional guidelines of Jinzhong University and relevant national regulations governing human-subject research. Consent for publication: Consent to publish is not applicable. Informed consent: Informed consent was obtained from all participants involved in the study. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41874806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13013774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11671-026-04511-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s11671-026-04511-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kim CY, Lee J, Jeong EY et al. Wireless technologies for wearable electronics: a review. Adv Electron Mater. 2025:2400884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Zhu Z, Zhang H, et al. Painting a high-output triboelectric nanogenerator on paper for harvesting energy from human body motion. Nano Energy. 2018;50:571&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2018.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei R, Li H, Chen Z, et al. Revolutionizing wearable technology: advanced fabrication techniques for body-conformable electronics. npj Flex Electron. 2024;8(1):83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41528-024-00370-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Zhu Z, Zhang H, et al. Milk-based triboelectric nanogenerator on paper for harvesting energy from human body motion. Nano Energy. 2019;56:400&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2018.11.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Kim DH, Lu N. Introduction: wearable devices. Chem Rev. 2024;124(10):6145&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38773952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Zhu Z, Fu J, et al. A triboelectric nanogenerator based on waste tea leaves and packaging bags for powering electronic office supplies and behavior monitoring. Nano Energy. 2019;60:61&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2019.03.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Tian Y, Fu J, et al. Transparent and stretchable high-output triboelectric nanogenerator for high-efficiency self-charging energy storage systems. Nano Energy. 2021;87:106210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Huyan C, Wang Z, et al. Conductive polymer based hydrogels and their application in wearable sensors: a review. Mater Horiz. 2023;10(8):2800&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3MH00056G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37204005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Chen B, Liu Y, et al. Recent advances in conductive hydrogels for electronic skin and healthcare monitoring. Biosensors. 2025;15(7):463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bios15070463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12293953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40710112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-D&#xed;az A, V&#xe1;zquez AS, V&#xe1;zquez E. Hydrogels in soft robotics: past, present, and future. ACS Nano. 2024;18(32):20817&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.3c12200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11328171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39099317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zhang D, Wang Z, et al. Ultrastretchable, self-healing conductive hydrogel-based triboelectric nanogenerators for human&#x2013;computer interaction. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2023;15(4):5128&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c17904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36658100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan K, Cao X, Wang J et al. Self-healing and adhesive eutectogels with dual conductive networks for multimodal health monitoring and human-computer interaction. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2025:138786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40865133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Tang H, Fu J, et al. A high strength triboelectric nanogenerator based on rigid-flexible coupling design for energy storage system. Nano Energy. 2020;67:104259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2019.104259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy R, Afshari A, Jain S, et al. Advances in conducting nanocomposite hydrogels for wearable biomonitoring. Chem Soc Rev. 2025;54:2595&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4CS00220B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39927792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Li X, Tu Y et al. Robust supramolecular conductive hydrogels based on silk fibroin and wool keratin for stretchable, self-healing, and adhesive strain sensors. Chem Eng J. 2025:165954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Xia K, Fu J. Pinching a triboelectric nanogenerator using soft pottery for powering electronics. Smart Mater Struct. 2019;28(8):085036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-665X/ab2430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Xu Z. Applying a triboelectric nanogenerator by using facial mask for flexible touch sensor. Sens Actuators A: Phys. 2021;331:112710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2021.112710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Cao J, Wan R, et al. PEDOTs-based conductive hydrogels: design, fabrications, and applications. Adv Mater. 2025;37(7):2415151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202415151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39711276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Xu C, Chen X, et al. Advances in electrically conductive hydrogels: performance and applications. Small Methods. 2025;9(4):2401156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smtd.202401156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39529563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daso RE, Posey R, Garza H, et al. Standardized Electrochemical Characterization of Conductive Hydrogels. Adv Funct Mater. 2025;35(42):e08859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202508859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Wang Y, Fu Y, et al. Healable and transparent ionic conductive hydrogels based on PNATF as multiple-signal sensors. ACS Appl Polym Mater. 2025;7(4):2529&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsapm.4c03794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Sun Y, Wang S, et al. Body temperature-triggered adhesive ionic conductive hydrogels for bioelectrical signal monitoring. Chem Eng J. 2024;498:155195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.155195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei T, Wang Y, Zhang Q, et al. Ultra-stretchable and anti-freezing ionic conductive hydrogels as high performance strain sensors and flexible triboelectric nanogenerator in extreme environments. Nano Energy. 2024;126:109633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei D, Lv S, Zuo J, et al. Engineering versatile bi-network ionic conductive hydrogels wearable sensors via on demand graft modification for real-time human movement monitoring. Chem Eng J. 2024;496:154176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.154176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Chen L, Liu F et al. Multifunctional ionic conductive hydrogels based on sodium carboxymethyl cellulose and poly (ionic liquid) for high-performance supercapacitors and sensing applications. Polymer. 2025:128966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou K, Wang M, Meng C, et al. Enhanced mechanical strength and stretchable ionic conductive hydrogel with double-network structure for wearable strain sensing and energy harvesting. Compos Sci Technol. 2024;255:110732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2024.110732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara L, Sher M, Khan M, et al. Dually-crosslinked ionic conductive hydrogels reinforced through biopolymer gellan gum for flexible sensors to monitor human activities. Int J Biol Macromol. 2024;276:133789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.133789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38992556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Lin X, Wang Z, et al. Multiple hydrogen bonds enable high strength and anti-swelling cellulose-based ionic conductive hydrogels for flexible sensors. Chem Eng J. 2024;480:148318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.148318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Zhu Z, Zhang H, et al. Cost-effective triboelectric nanogenerator based on teflon tape and conductive copper foil tape. Microelectron Eng. 2018;199:114&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mee.2018.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Zhu R, Ni Q, et al. Functional tactile sensor based on arrayed triboelectric nanogenerators. Adv Energy Mater. 2024;14(44):2403289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202403289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo WT, Lei Y, Zhao XH, et al. Printed-scalable microstructure BaTiO3/ecoflex nanocomposite for high-performance triboelectric nanogenerators and self-powered human-machine interaction. Nano Energy. 2024;131:110324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Hao Y, Luo P, et al. A Faraday cage-inspired triboelectric nanogenerator enabled by alloy powder architecture for self-powered ocean sensing. Energy Environ Mater. 2025;8:e70040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eem2.70040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed T, Gao Y, So MY, et al. Diamond-structured fabric&#x2010;based triboelectric nanogenerators for energy harvesting and healthcare application. Adv Funct Mater. 2024;34(48):2408680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202408680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee G, Kang H, Yun J, et al. Integrated triboelectric nanogenerator and radiative cooler for all-weather transparent glass surfaces. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):6537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-50872-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11297326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39095384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Yang S, Lu J et al. Intrinsic static&#x2013;dynamic triboelectric pressure sensor enabled by charge excitation and 3D gradient engineering for intelligent dual-mode control. Chem Eng J. 2025:170270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Song J, Wang K. Research progress and prospects of liquid&#x2013;liquid triboelectric nanogenerators: mechanisms, applications, and future challenges. ACS Appl Electron Mater. 2024;7(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaelm.4c01729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Guo D, Tuo L, et al. One meter triboelectric nanogenerator for efficient harvesting of meter-scale wave energy. Adv Funct Mater. 2024;34(42):2406775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202406775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Zhu Z, Fu J, et al. Multifunctional conductive copper tape-based triboelectric nanogenerator and as a self-powered humidity sensor. IEEE Trans Electron Devices. 2019;66(6):2741&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TED.2019.2911637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin S, Chang T, Abir SSH, et al. One-step fabrication of functionalized electrodes on 3D-printed polymers for triboelectric nanogenerators. Nano Energy. 2024;129:110082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Yu M. Highly robust and efficient metal-free water cup solid&#x2013;liquid triboelectric nanogenerator for water wave energy harvesting and ethanol detection. Chem Eng J. 2025;503:157938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.157938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MAM, Zhu W, Bowen CR, et al. Triboelectric nanogenerators for wind energy harvesting. Nat Reviews Electr Eng. 2024;1(7):453&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44287-024-00061-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Du H, Yang H, et al. A rolling-mode triboelectric nanogenerator with multi-tunnel grating electrodes and opposite-charge-enhancement for wave energy harvesting. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):6834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-51245-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11315932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39122713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zhang D, Mao R, et al. MoS2-based charge trapping layer enabled triboelectric nanogenerator with assistance of CNN-GRU model for intelligent perception. Nano Energy. 2024;127:109753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Yu M, Luo Y, et al. All-foam intrinsic triboelectric static and dynamic pressure sensor with a standardized DC/AC measurement method for industrial robots. Nano Energy. 2025;139:110953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Shan C, Fu S, et al. Efficient energy conversion mechanism and energy storage strategy for triboelectric nanogenerators. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):6558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-50978-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11297214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39095412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Tang R, Zeng F et al. Self-layered triboelectric nanogenerator for ultrahigh electricity supply. Adv Mater 2025;38:e14186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202514186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41074234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang H, Peng L, Yang Q, et al. Triboelectric nanogenerator for high-entropy energy, self-powered sensors, and popular education. Sci Adv. 2024;10(48):eads2291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.ads2291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11606449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39612344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Fu J, Xu Z. Multiple-frequency high-output triboelectric nanogenerator based on a water balloon for all-weather water wave energy harvesting. Adv Energy Mater. 2020;10(28):2000426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202000426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasanna APS, Anithkumar M, Kim SJ. Hybrid triboelectric nanogenerators: Revolutionizing the energy harvesting through material diversity and device architecture for different applications. Nano Energy. 2024;131:110253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhao Z, Zhang B, et al. Superior charge density of triboelectric nanogenerator via trap engineering. Adv Funct Mater. 2025;35(14):2416944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202416944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Kumar A, Jain A, et al. Nanograting-assisted flexible Triboelectric Nanogenerator for active human motion detection. Nano Energy. 2024;131:110318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Thapa A, Pramanik S, et al. Graphene-infused sustainable rubber-based triboelectric nanogenerator for real&#x2010;time human motion monitoring. Small. 2024;20(46):2404771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202404771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39109931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu Y, Xu S, Sun P, et al. Scale production of a stretchable fiber triboelectric nanogenerator in customizable textile for human motion recognition. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2024;16(47):65348&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.4c15137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39545818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Deng Y, Li J et al. Stretchable, anti-freezing, self-healing, and degradable high-performance conductive hydrogel-based triboelectric nanogenerator for energy harvesting and human activity recognition. Mater Today Energy. 2025; 102013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Yu M, Zhang H, et al. Triboelectric nanogenerator based on well-dispersed and oxide-free liquid metal-doped conductive hydrogel as self-powered wearable sensor for respiratory and thyroid cartilage signal monitoring. Nano Energy. 2025;134:110530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta B, Bano S, Singh R. High-performance silver nanoparticles embedded conductive PVA hydrogel for stretchable wearable triboelectric nanogenerators. J Power Sources. 2025;632:236271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M, Zhang H, Yang Q, et al. Rapid preparation of tough, anti-freezing, and conductive hydrogel via lignin-Fe<sup>3+</sup>&#x2009;self-catalytic system for extreme environment-resistant triboelectric nanogenerator. Chem Eng J. 2025;505:159105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.159105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Du C, Zhu Z, et al. Sliding-mode triboelectric nanogenerator based on paper and as a self-powered velocity and force sensor. Appl Mater Today. 2018;13:190&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmt.2018.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X, Zhu L, Wang YC, et al. A flexible multifunctional triboelectric nanogenerator based on MXene/PVA hydrogel. Adv Funct Mater. 2021;31(38):2104928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202104928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Liu G, Wu J, et al. High-strength dual-network hydrogels with chain-growth enhancement for multifunctional flexible sensors, triboelectric nanogenerators, and EMI shielding. Chem Eng J. 2025;519:165710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.165710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Li C, Sun W, et al. A controlled biodegradable triboelectric nanogenerator based on PEGDA/laponite hydrogels. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2023;15:12787&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c22359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana SMS, Zahed MA, Islam MR, et al. Metal-organic framework and molybdenum oxide doped highly negative hybridized triboelectric material for self-powered and continuous monitoring of biosignals. Chem Eng J. 2023;473:144989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.144989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana SMS, Faruk O, Islam MR, et al. Recent advances in metal-organic framework-based self-powered sensors: a promising energy harvesting technology. Coord Chem Rev. 2024;507:215741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana SMS, Wang ZL. Recent advances and prospective strategies for improving the performance of triboelectric nanogenerators. Coord Chem Rev. 2025;543:216914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>